<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236602302.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>I am from the US and will speak in terms of our first amendment, but it likely has parallels to Canada

The largest thing you must remember, we have a freedom *of* religion. It is not a freedom *from* religion. 

You cannot expect individuals to *stop* being religious when they go places or serve in governmental roles. People's faith is part of them. 

What the US 1st amendment protects is three fold. It protects an individuals right to practice their religion. It prevents the state from creating a singular 'state' religion. And it protects against the unequal treatment of religions. 

You will note, there is not a 'wall' between church and state here. Even the most cursory look at history will show no such wall exists or has existed in the past. Congress and many legislatures still open with a prayer for instance. 

Where does that bring us. 

To your point. In the US, a rule preventing a person from wearing a religious symbol would need to pass significant scrutiny with substantial justification to pass. 

An example - a ban on specific types of clothing/jewelry for machine operators while operating machines would likely stand up. (where an entanglement hazard exists). A ban on these outside the hazard area would not.

I don't see any scenario where you could ban cross necklaces, or the like worn by students in a school. 

Now we move onto 'prayer rooms'. This is asking a slightly different question for legality. Basically, is there an establishment here. In a generic space open to all, that answer would be no. Therefore, having this in place is not a violation. It would instead be viewed as a student accommodation - much like any other space not directly required would be.

You might ask why we would want these? Well, it comes back to the core purpose of school - which is to educate students. If adding this moves the goal of education forward for some students, then it is likely a useful item to have.

My last point is really my opinion. I come to the conclusion, especially seeing this rehashed on reddit, that 'secularism' itself can constitute many tenets of a 'religion'. The zeal to eliminate other beliefs systems in favor of a 'secular' belief system carries with it many of the same concepts that the US first amendment was seeking to prevent. To this point, Atheism in the US is actually considered a religion and afforded the same protections as other religions. 

I think you need to be extremely careful pushing 'secularism' here lest you run afoul of the same ideas you purportedly want to prevent. The comments about prohibiting others from wearing religious symbols speaks volumes of how you wish to establish 'secularism' in this place. After all, how does a cross necklace interfere with the mission of a public school? Where is justification that you should prevent it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236610676.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Other countries protect the state from the church. I undertsand the 1st amendement says otherwise, but I don't think it should.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236627009.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Care to address your push for secularism here? 

Why prohibiting a 'cross necklace' is good policy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236638526.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Keep your religion at home, don't flaunt it in public, nobody wants to see that. French people support it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236677319.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>You don't get to make that requirement. Especially since it can be readily stated *you are pushing your religious views on everyone in this policy*.

That is the point of freedom of expression. People have it.

Governments and government instutions are not allowed to simply ignore it.

I notice you keep referring to the French. You do realize France has **no bearing on Canada** right?

You would also know if you did any research on France that there is a freedom of expression there as well. How it is litigated is a matter of France. 

If your reference is to Hijab's, you might understand that a legitimate security interest is present and that argument put forth for preventing them. That though is *vastly different* than preventing a student from wearing a cross necklace. Somethings you are not realizing.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freedom_of_religion_in_France</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236947563.0" user="Enderules3" delta="False">
    <text>Keep your secularism at home, don't flaunt it in public, nobody wants to see that. 

Keep your sexuality at home, don't flaunt it in public, nobody wants to see that. 

Keep your nationality at home, don't flaunt it in public, nobody wants to see that.

Keep your politics at home, don't flaunt it in public, nobody wants to see that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237163453.0" user="Vaffanculo28" delta="False">
    <text>And do you feel the same way about students identifying as LGBTQ+? Repression is unhealthy, in any form. Simply wearing a necklace, hijab, etc. is not infringing upon anyone’s rights. School *should* be a students safest place to express themselves. Now, I 100% believe schools should not enforce a morning prayer or anything similar. Offering a prayer room is not enforcing anything, but rather allowing students to access those resources, if they *choose* to do so. Just as a student can choose not to use those resources. 

Imagine trying to enforce a “no hijab” rule. Outside of the obvious arguments against this, my main concern is that you would actively be repressing those students from freedom of expression and religion. You’re also taking away social and cultural learning opportunities among the students who could benefit from learning about it. Repressing the rights of students in school is no better than the countries “forcing” women to wear hijabs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237382412.0" user="astro-gazing" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think schools should have prayer rooms, but this is a bad argument. School time IS for learning, but generally people should be able to wear and talk about whatever they want to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237498725.0" user="A_Notion_to_Motion" delta="False">
    <text>Because we have freedom of expression. Wear whatever you want as long as it isn't hurting anyone and isn't too distracting for a school setting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238205019.0" user="idkman0485" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom of religion also means churches, mosques and more have protections from the states oppressive heel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237214250.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It is not freedom from religion.

Every court ruling that has unanimously and publicly affirmed *freedom of religion also results in people’s freedom from religion* disagrees with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237234182.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>If this is the conclusion you have drawn, you need to go back and read these court cases again. You are not getting the correct meaning.

I am willing to bet you are mistaking the concept of 'establishment' here from 'individual expression'.

If anything, the caselaw strongly *supports* the individuals right to religious expression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237706952.0" user="Hero_of_Parnast" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The largest thing you must remember, we have a freedom of religion. It is not a freedom from religion. 

We have both, actually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237795167.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. While it is true there is no avenue for compulsion of participation in religious activities, we don't have a guarantee that any individual will be free from seeing religious activities or be free of impact from other's religious beliefs. 

If there was truly a 'freedom from religion', then there would be avenue's to prevent others from exercising their religious beliefs in a way that would expose individuals to it.  And that is just not the case. 

The case law simply does not support this claim. Bremmerton is the most recent example. Individuals retain their rights to exercise their beliefs, even when acting as public servants. In the past 5-10 years, there have been numerous SCOTUS cases talking about the intersection of religion with government. It is worth a read to understand the nuances and how/where lines are drawn. 

If your definition of 'freedom from religion' is solely limited to compulsion of participation, I would agree. But, most people making this claim don't limit this to 'compelled participation'. It extends far beyond, much like the original posters claims. They want *any* religious item eliminated, whether they are impacted or not. They expect politicians to *not* follow their religious ideals in policies. None of these *additional* ideas are supported in any case law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237867529.0" user="Hero_of_Parnast" delta="False">
    <text>Freedom from religion means I don't have to be religious. That's the accepted definition. I have never, in my 19 years as an atheist, heard *anyone* say it means that I don't have to see religion around me.

Your claim that those of us advocating for freedom from religion are fighting to destroy crosses or whatever is simply false. Not even the Freedom From Religion Foundation fights for that.

One thing you actually got right is that we think elected officials shouldn't use religion in their policymaking. That's true. If you do get elected to public office and you are religious, you need to separate those two things. No public servant should be showing favoritism towards one religion. Anyone who does that is choosing not to represent the public fairly, and should resign their post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237989281.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Freedom from religion means I don't have to be religious. That's the accepted definition. I have never, in my 19 years as an atheist, heard anyone say it means that I don't have to see religion around me.

In which case, I agree with your comment. This is very much in line.

&gt;Your claim that those of us advocating for freedom from religion are fighting to destroy crosses or whatever is simply false. Not even the Freedom From Religion Foundation fights for that.

Except in practice, there are people who *are* advocating freedom from religion to destroy war monuments with religious features.

https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/02/us/politics/supreme-court-cross-war-memorial.html

It may be a case of bad associations, but the language used is similar.

&gt;One thing you actually got right is that we think elected officials shouldn't use religion in their policymaking.

But we are talking about a person here and their beliefs are based on the individuals as whole whole. Those religious beliefs are part of the whole and a fairly significant part. The concept that they are 'taboo' merely because of the religious roots is inherently problematic. After all, you have no problems with the alternative belief so long as it does not have religious roots. It is that disparate treatment that is of issue.

They were elected based on their policy ideals and those consisted of some based on religious tenets they hold. They are not 'separable'. 

As for the 'preferential' treatment of one religion over another, we have a guard rail here called the establishment clause. This is actually more broadly known as 'disparate treatment' and works for both religious and non-religious individuals. Government should not favor nor disfavor any organization based solely on religious affiliation and government should not be in the business of promoting any religion. 

I am personally quite happy with where the US is right now in this regard. Both the activist 'anti-religion' folks and the 'religious' folks aren't too happy. Both want more of their preferred ideology and are upset they aren't getting it which to me is indicative that a balance is being struck. Maybe not perfect, but still pretty good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238156682.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>Being from Quebec but having lived in the US for over a decade, I have to say the entanglement and influence of religious institutions, especially far right Christians, into politics is exactly what Quebec is trying to prevent. Not exactly in the best ways, but I also wouldn’t say the US is in a good spot right now in this regard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238345343.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>I agree it is an incredibly thorny issue. 

One problem I see and can point to it in your comment is the conflation of individuals and institutions. Individuals who are elected/appointed into public service positions are being conflated with 'institutions'. 

There is a distinctly different standard for individuals as opposed to institutions with individuals have far more freedoms. 

The really thorny challenge is the long history of religious institutions providing services that are now being provided by non-religious institutions. This is the area with the greatest litigation recently - the intersection between secular functions provided by religious organizations. Right behind this is the intersection of secular rules into religious organizations - especially around employment and insurance law. 

For example, the Catholic church is an employer. What employment law applies to the Catholic church? Can the ACA mandate the church provide insurance for contraceptives that is against the religious teachings? 

There just are not easy clean answers here. 

Mind you, I understand what Quebec is seeking, I just think they are going about it in the wrong ways. I think they should be focusing on the student needs and if the 'prayer rooms' were not as inclusive as they needed to be, they should be improved to better serve the needs of more students rather than be eliminated. 

For instance, around me, they are creating 'sensory' rooms. These are designed to help those with autism regain focus but are open to any student. This could serve the 'prayer' function as well as the special needs function. (or just a place to allow a student to stop, reflect, and compose themselves. It's about serving the needs of students here to try to get academic success.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242941894.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>I think this decision was taken thinking of the institution first:

By enabling prayer rooms, it puts schools, which are supposed to be secular, in a position of managing/policing their use. At face value, it seems like a non-issue. However, it *can* put the school in a position where it would privilege one religion over another or over secular principles like equality between sexes. One example cited in the media when they enforced this rule was an instance where Muslim boys did not want girls praying at the same time in the same room. What do you do then? Instead of putting schools in such situations, they decided not to accommodate.

This might seem drastic, especially in contrast to your sensory room example, but remember that schools in Quebec are all public and centrally governed. It doesn’t do well at managing on a case by case basis in its current form, but that’s also what ensures the minimum standard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243574644.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it is definitely a thorny issue.

The problem (at least in the US) is, schools are a mandated by law location for kids to be. As such, reasonable accommodations must be made. I am not sure the simple 'removal' policy would meet the requirement to provide 'reasonable accommodations'.

Canadian law may be different in what requirements exist for mandated school attendance and mandated 'accommodations'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238592798.0" user="Hero_of_Parnast" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Except in practice, there are people who are advocating freedom from religion to destroy war monuments with religious features.

There's a difference between a government putting up a monument supporting a specific religion and the people around me wearing cross necklaces. That's not freedom from religion, it's simple separation of church and state.

Why is it necessary that the monument be a cross? There's nothing inherently Christian, or even religious, about remembering the fallen. How do we know there weren't non-Christian troops that we're commemorating? That's pretty disrespectful to any potential members of that group.

There's a paywall, so I can't read the article. It can get a little tough when discussing historical items, but there's nothing tough about having 40-foot crosses on public property. Don't do it. Move it.

&gt;But we are talking about a person here and their beliefs are based on the individuals as whole whole.

Then they shouldn't run for office. If someone is unable to perform their duties as a policymaker, then they shouldn't become a policymaker at all.

Now, if your religion influenced you to do your duty, then that's all good. The problem is if religion is compelling you to act outside of the law and morality, like these motherfuckers hurting trans kids. That's not okay.

&gt;The concept that they are 'taboo' merely because of the religious roots is inherently problematic. 

It's not taboo. People can believe whatever they want. The problem comes when that belief influences policymaking in a way that is detrimental to the people.

&gt;After all, you have no problems with the alternative belief so long as it does not have religious roots.

What alternative beliefs?

&gt;As for the 'preferential' treatment of one religion over another, we have a guard rail here called the establishment clause. This is actually more broadly known as 'disparate treatment' and works for both religious and non-religious individuals. Government should not favor nor disfavor any organization based solely on religious affiliation and government should not be in the business of promoting any religion. 

Yet it still happens. It is legal now to discriminate on religious grounds in some circumstances. You don't want to serve a trans customer? Well, that's your Christian right! You don't want to sell contraceptives? That's all good!

Fuck man, abortion is illegal in some states! That's a religious matter!

&gt;I am personally quite happy with where the US is right now in this regard. Both the activist 'anti-religion' folks and the 'religious' folks aren't too happy. Both want more of their preferred ideology and are upset they aren't getting it which to me is indicative that a balance is being struck. Maybe not perfect, but still pretty good.

Removing religion from government and enforcing Christianity are wildly different. You can't both sides this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238979358.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;There's a difference between a government putting up a monument supporting a specific religion and the people around me wearing cross necklaces. That's not freedom from religion, it's simple separation of church and state.

Except the topics are linked. You may not personally hold all the views, but they are very much linked with the 'freedom from religion' comment.

&gt;Why is it necessary that the monument be a cross?

History. When it was erected, this debate did not exist. It is literally WW1 monument, put up almost 100 years ago.

Now it is an issue.

Here is another link

https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2019/02/20/cross-shaped-war-monument-puts-supreme-court-crosshairs/2792388002/

That is my point. You may see the 'Freedom from religion' being not at all intertwined with this issue, but others don't. 

&gt;Then they shouldn't run for office.

I am going to guess you are not quite sure exactly what you are saying here.

Literally, the take away message is that any ideas with any religious basis cannot be applied in any governance. That a person who is religious is fundamentally barred from office. This is blatantly wrong and a claim made here is such a blatant attempt to disenfranchise people/ideas that I think I must assume you didn't intend it. 

People are allowed to express any ideas they want from any source. People are allowed to run for office and if their ideas are popular, are allowed to implement them as policy - provided they don't run afoul of the guard rails the Constitution provides.

If you truly believe religious people should be barred from participating in government or their ideas must be explicitly barred because of 'religious' origin, then that is one of the most fundamentally anti-democratic things I can imagine anyone advocating. It is straight up Nazi level shit and I don't use that term lightly. As I said, I don't think you actually intended this meaning but this is exactly what your statement leads to. 

&gt;Now, if your religion influenced you to do your duty, then that's all good. The problem is if religion is compelling you to act outside of the law and morality, like these motherfuckers hurting trans kids. That's not okay.

You do understand this is not a universally held position *at all*. Your idea of morality does not match others. As for acting outside the law, that is whole point of being a lawmaker. To create the laws the people want. That is literally the entire point of elections where the majority opinion gets elected to pass legislation.

I would suggest you consider many people opposed to a law around trans/kids issues actually fully believe in their hearts they are looking out for kids. They are not acting in bad faith even though you disagree with them. 

&gt;What alternative beliefs?

Any given policy that cannot be tied to a religious holding. If being against 'gay marriage' is a religious holding that is now verboten, then you are default advocating for 'gay marriage'. 

Choose any topic in the culture way and you have given yourself a 'cancel' button for the opposition to your ideas. Just label it 'Religious' and your concept above allows it to be dismissed. 

&gt;Yet it still happens. It is legal now to discriminate on religious grounds in some circumstances. You don't want to serve a trans customer? Well, that's your Christian right!

Actually, I would encourage you to go read the proper cases. The media has done a very poor job explaining this to you.

The latest case, 303 creative, was really about compelled speech. Can the government, through anti-discrimination laws, compel individuals to create expressive speech for which they disagree with based on deeply held beliefs. 

It is not a generic license to discriminate. A store is not allowed to stop selling Cherrios to LGBT people. For this exemption to hold, it must be an individual, and it must involve expressive work. 

Basically, you cannot compel an artist to paint a picture they don't want to paint based on their deeply held beliefs using the concept of protected classes and anti-discrimination.

It is actually a much narrower ruling than you have been led to believe.

&gt;Fuck man, abortion is illegal in some states! That's a religious matter!

It does not have to be. There are people against abortion who are not religious. 

&gt;Removing religion from government and enforcing Christianity are wildly different. You can't both sides this.

Actually, you must. You are never going to remove religion from government because the people in government have the right to free exercise. They get to bring their entire beliefs with them, which includes religious values.  Also, the law *should* bar attempts to make Christianity the 'enforced' religion. There are actually very few actual attempts at this.

You just have to be very careful here. It is very difficult to prove something is or is not a religious item. Most people like to take their preferred culture war topics and claim the opposition is 'religious' when there is no clear evidence that it is the case. 

For instance, is Robbery religious? Is it wrong to steal something from someone? The reason I ask is that I can clearly point to the 10 commandments here and claim it is religious. By this standard of absolutes, it would then be impossible to make theft illegal less you enforce 'Religious' concepts. 

Where that leaves us is in a conundrum. The answer though is pretty simple. Everything is assumed to be secular unless it can be proven conclusively that the item in question is exclusively religious in nature. This is a very high bar to clear. This is how a moment of silence rather than opening prayer happened. This is why prayer in school (teacher led) is not allowed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237749298.0" user="SciGuy013" delta="False">
    <text>Extremely irrelevant to invoke the first amendment and unrelated American case law in a discussion about Canada, a different country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237909561.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>It's as if you completely failed to read this line:

&gt;I am from the US and will speak in terms of our first amendment, but it likely has parallels to Canada

It's almost as bad at the OP who was talking about Canada but responded with 'But France said this'........</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237780033.0" user="Jaderholt439" delta="False">
    <text>This is James Madison, in his Remonstrance against Religious Assessments-

“If Religion consist in voluntary acts of individuals, singly, or voluntarily associated, and it be proper that public functionaries, as well as their Constituents shd discharge their religious duties, let them like their Constituents, do so at their own expence. “

He’s talking about what the first amendment means.

“Constitution of the U. S. forbids everything like an establishment of a national religion. The law appointing Chaplains establishes a religious worship for the national representatives, to be performed by Ministers of religion, elected by a majority of them; and these are to be paid out of the national taxes. Does not this involve the principle of a national establishment, applicable to a provision for a religious worship for the Constituent as well as of the representative Body, approved by the majority, and conducted by Ministers of religion paid by the entire nation.”

Yes, they open w/ a prayer. They probably shouldn’t. Madison and Jefferson cover all of that. The very first motion in the continental congress was “Should we open w/ prayer?” It’s was voted against.

There is a wall between church and state, or as the man who wrote the constitution put it, “between govt and ecclesiastical bodies”.

You can argue w/ James Madison or Thomas Jefferson all you want, but they wrote down exactly what the 1st amendment means. Read Madison’s Detached Memoranda and his Remonstrance. They said chaplains and prayer by govt reps were against the spirit of the first amendment. He gave a 15 point argument on why not one penny should ever b spent on anything religious, especially schools. (My fav is bc politics is corrupt by nature and if you mix religion w/ it, it will b corrupted too.)

I mean, to get out from under religious rule was the whole point of the US.

https://press-pubs.uchicago.edu/founders/documents/amendI_religions64.html

https://candst.tripod.com/tnppage/qmadison.htm

Oh btw, people/kids should b able to practice their religion openly. If a school has a room set aside for that, that’s not a bad thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237901611.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are not fully understanding this distinction.

I set out stating the 1st amendment lays out three main function

- It provides individuals the free exercise of religion

- It prevents the state from creating a religion (establishment)

- It prevents the state from treating one religion more or less favorably than any other.

When you view the comments above, this is clearly talking about the establishment issues. 

But, that is not the end of the story. Government and religion are not something that can be wholly and completely separated. There is significant case law dating back literally centuries. I very quick survey found a case in 1817 about Pennsylvania regulating the working on Sundays and a Jewish man. 

The reality is the idea of a 'wall' is just not rooted in reality. There exists the individual right to free exercise of religion and the intersection of government ideas. Hobby Lobby comes to mind where you have a question of whether a business owner can be compelled to provide insurance to employees covering items (abortion) that were against the owners deeply held beliefs. You have cases were religious organizations are involved in secular activities or have secular employees. 

There is very much *not* a wall between church and state when analyzed in any detail. That is why I can readily cite SCOTUS cases helping draw the line here.

https://www.mtsu.edu/first-amendment/encyclopedia/case/105/free-exercise-of-religion

If there was such as easy concept as a 'wall' as you suggest, those cases listed above wouldn't be needed.

And I'll leave you with one more:

A church is looking to hire a new minister. Are they subject to the same anti-discrimination laws as secular businesses? Must they consider hiring individuals whose lifestyle blatantly conflicts with church teachings? Or taking a different tact, could a church terminate an employee in a ministerial capacity who violates the church teachings but also is a member of a protected class (LGBT+)?

Now you see where the 'wall' concept breaks down in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239646806.0" user="fredleung412612" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;but it likely has parallels to Canada

Canada does not have an equivalent of the First Amendment. Its version of the *Bill of Rights* is known as the *Charter of Rights and Freedoms* has only been in force since 1982. It guarantees the freedom of expression and freedom of religion, but also has a clause allowing governments to shield *Acts* from judicial review so long as the law is put before the relevant legislature again every five years. 

Due to its complicated history with the English, Québec has used this clause more than anyone else to periodically acclaim the "distinctiveness" of their society. Most recently, the clause was used by the government of Québec to ban certain civil servants from displaying ostentatious objects of religious belief as well as to severely restrict the presence of the English language in public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239964635.0" user="Mammoth-Phone6630" delta="False">
    <text>Look at the Treaty of Tripoli (1796), Article 11. 

It pretty much sets, if not a wall, at least a fence between church and state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240485147.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>It really does not. 

What you are discussing is *Establishment*. 

That is a very different issue than the free exercise issue which this is. If anything, it supports the third principle that the US cannot favor nor disfavor any religion over any other.

This is all very different than the 'wall' idea. The US is not a Christian nation. So what. I never claimed it was. There is the uncomfortable fact that the US is majority christian though. None of this means that interactions between the state and religious groups don't happen and there are not explicit protections in place around this.

I mean, look at the SCOTUS cases dealing with the 1A and Free Exercise and Establishment of religion. These go back essentially to the founding. I found a reference to a case in 1817 about a law against working on Sundays in Pennsylvania.

There hasn't been a 'wall' in our history and it is flat out wrong to claim there was. SCOTUS has been defining limits here for centuries. 

The problem is individuals are in play and individuals have a right to free exercise of religion. It is literally impossible to avoid entanglements with religion here because it involves individuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240590738.0" user="Mammoth-Phone6630" delta="False">
    <text>You said it, “the problem is people”. 

All of those SCOTUS cases were decided by a very small amount of people. 

You’re talking about the country as it is, which isn’t the same as how it should be according to laws passed. 

And how is a country that, as you said, “legislatures open with prayer” and “is majority Christian” not a de facto Christian nation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242516563.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; All of those SCOTUS cases were decided by a very small amount of people. 

Those particular individuals are likely some of the very best educated when it comes to law, Constitutional interpretation, and legal reasoning. 

I notice you went directly to attacking the idea or 'people making decisions' rather than attempting to address the core concern about individual rights as applied in society.

&gt;You’re talking about the country as it is, which isn’t the same as how it should be according to laws passed. 

If you believe this is in error - file a lawsuit. The problem is, what you *want* is not actually what the law states. Every one of those cases I mentioned have extensive legal justification presented with the decision. 

&gt;And how is a country that, as you said, “legislatures open with prayer” and “is majority Christian” not a de facto Christian nation.

Yes - because those items are not mutually required. A legislature can open with a 'prayer' and can be 'majority christian' without being an officially 'Christian' nation. Nowhere in US law is Christianity *established* as the nation's religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240302387.0" user="Thanosismyking" delta="False">
    <text>Would you fight this hard to protect the rights of a Scientologist ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240440793.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>The answer is yes. And I don't consider myself personally religious either.

I don't belong to a church and don't attend any formal religious services.

There is an old saying from the ACLU. They spend (or spent) a lot of time working on the 1st amendment protecting the rights of distasteful groups. To protect the rights of everyone means spending a lot of time protecting the rights of bad groups. That's why they protect the KKK's right to march/meet. 

Protecting religion is similar. I may not agree with everything religious people do, but the principles under which it stands is something I wholly and fully agree with. It means I have to defend the likes of Westboro Baptist to maintain the principles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240462330.0" user="Thanosismyking" delta="False">
    <text>I admire the absolutist conviction but I personally don’t see the benefit of religion in modern day society.  Religions only impede progress. Look at Iceland for example they eliminated Down syndrome but progressive stances like that would never fly in countries bogged down by religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240514590.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I admire the absolutist conviction but I personally don’t see the benefit of religion in modern day society.

And others don't see the benefit of *not* having religion. You point to impediment to progress and they point to going down the wrong paths. 

All of this is merely political opinions. There is not an objective correct answer here.

What we do know is that our nation has placed free speech and free exercise of religion as essential priorities to be protected. 

&gt;Look at Iceland for example they eliminated Down syndrome

Yes - by *abortion of fetuses*. If you don't understand how that could be viewed as modern day eugenics, then I don't know what to tell you. 

I would personally far rather live in a country where religion, even fundamentalist, was protected than in a country where unpopular ideas were allowed to be suppressed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243993011.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;To this point, Atheism in the US is actually considered a religion and afforded the same protections as other religions.

How? It's a lack of religion. Does the government regulate TV being off or static as a TV channel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244299069.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>This explains it pretty well

https://www.mtsu.edu/first-amendment/article/1318/atheism

&gt;The establishment clause not only prohibits governments from directly establishing a religion, but also prohibits them from favoring one religion over another or religion over nonreligion.

There is more to this but in law, atheism gets the same protections as other 'religions' especially with respect to free exercise and non-establishment principles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244473356.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>To me it seems like the amendment acknowledges atheism and protects it not as a religion but as a separate entity:

The establishment clause not only prohibits governments from directly establishing a religion, but also prohibits them from favoring one religion over another or religion over nonreligion.

I don't know how the courts seem to push atheism as a religion even though it's not said to be one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245252904.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>To me, the courts treating it as 'religion' makes it quite easy to ensure it is treated as any other 'religion' is treated. Specifically as it relates to deeply held beliefs that have distinct and identifiable parallels in religion. 

When you make things 'Separate', they don't always end up 'Equal'. In this approach, there is no 'Separate' so there is less concern for disparate treatment. 

&gt;I don't know how the courts seem to push atheism as a religion even though it's not said to be one.

I would think about this differently. The courts are classifying ideas with respect to protections under law. By using this classification scheme, it provides clear direction to all parties on what is and is not protected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245431333.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it all boils down to "It makes it easier for the courts even though atheism is absence of beliefs". Or it could just boil down to those laws being written in a time where atheism wasn't understood as well as it is now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247920210.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>No, it is really the first one. It is far easier to consider atheism in the context of it being a 'religion' when it comes to analyzing the protected aspects and the law. 

I would point out in many respects, atheism does tick many of the boxes for religion. Nowhere is it written that belief in a 'god' is required for it to be 'religion'. It may be very different than most religions, but that really does not matter. The parallels for deeply held beliefs exist. 

So in the context of law, it makes a lot of sense to treat this in this way. I seriously doubt there is any ambiguity in what Atheism actually is.

And realize, this is actually a good thing. It explicitly extends protections from the 1A to atheism. (which it should).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253132907.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The parallels for deeply held beliefs exist.

But it's a lack of those beliefs. Either way it's just easier for the courts because the courts and the government prefer temporary shortcuts instead of addressing the matter conclusively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253645202.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, it is not. You are over defining deeply held beliefs to be forced to include 'a god'.

If I asked you how the world began, you can have very deeply held beliefs that have nothing to do with a 'God' existing. That is what the article meant to 'parallel beliefs'. 

Substitute morals and ethics. Same thing. They don't have to originate in 'god' to be considered deeply held. 

By explicitly making this determination, it guarantees deeply held beliefs not rooted in 'traditional religion' receive equal protection under the law and the 1st amendment. The same framework used to determine if an item is a 'deeply held belief' for religion is also applied to 'atheism' as well. That is what is meant by courts treating atheism as a religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253780668.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>noun: religion  
the belief in and worship of a superhuman power or powers, especially a God or gods.  
"ideas about the relationship between science and religion"

There is no worship nor belief in the superhuman/supernatural in atheism. Atheism is the absence of such belief. Is a television being off a TV channel? Nope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253815600.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Go back and read through *WHY* this is treated this way legally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253853367.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>I understand why it's treated this way (because it's easier for the courts). I don't like the reason why but I understand it. Not hard to figure out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253867073.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>Are you claiming atheism should have *less* protection in the 1st amendment then?

Because that is EXACTLY why the courts (SCOTUS) has stated it should be treated likely a religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253888561.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>When the fuck did I say that? What I would like is for atheism to be treated on the same equal footing as religion under the law without being branded as such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253939777.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; When the fuck did I say that? What I would like is for atheism to be treated on the same equal footing as religion under the law without being branded as such.

You do understand *why* they say to treat it as 'religion' right? That is guarantees equal protection that way. Or are you completely ignorant of the various legal tests used to determine what is and is not a deeply held belief? That explicit language is directions for how lower courts are to approach things and consider things. Stating Atheism must be considered as a 'religion' here is clear concise direction for which tests to use when approaching questions of deeply held beliefs. 

It's not like anyone there does not understand what atheism is and they aren't 'branding' it anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253992664.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>So all I got from this is what I've already said:

I understand why it's treated this way (because it's easier for the courts). 

I don't like the reason why but I understand it. 

I would prefer if atheism would be treated on the same footing as religion but is acknowledged as being different from it.

Again not hard to figure out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
