<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="38" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237437620.0" user="Jaderholt439" delta="False">
    <text>This is James Madison, in his Remonstrance against Religious Assessments-  

“If Religion consist in voluntary acts of individuals, singly, or voluntarily associated, and it be proper that public functionaries, as well as their Constituents shd discharge their religious duties, let them like their Constituents, do so at their own expence. “

He’s talking about what the first amendment means.

 “Constitution of the U. S. forbids everything like an establishment of a national religion. The law appointing Chaplains establishes a religious worship for the national representatives, to be performed by Ministers of religion, elected by a majority of them; and these are to be paid out of the national taxes. Does not this involve the principle of a national establishment, applicable to a provision for a religious worship for the Constituent as well as of the representative Body, approved by the majority, and conducted by Ministers of religion paid by the entire nation.”

Yes, they open w/ a prayer. They probably shouldn’t. Madison and Jefferson cover all of that. The very first motion in the continental congress was “Should we open w/ prayer?” It’s was voted against. 

There is a wall between church and state, or as the man who wrote the constitution put it, “between govt and ecclesiastical bodies”.

You can argue w/ James Madison or Thomas Jefferson all you want, but they wrote down exactly what the 1st amendment means. Read Madison’s Detached Memoranda and his Remonstrance. They said chaplains and prayer by govt reps were against the spirit of the first amendment. He gave a 15 point argument on why not one penny should ever b spent on anything religious, especially schools. (My fav is bc politics is corrupt by nature and if you mix religion w/ it, it will b corrupted too.)

I mean, to get out from under religious rule was the whole point of the US.

https://press-pubs.uchicago.edu/founders/documents/amendI_religions64.html

https://candst.tripod.com/tnppage/qmadison.htm</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237448203.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care what a slaveowner thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237620499.0" user="Jaderholt439" delta="False">
    <text>Shit, I meant that as a response to someone, not to you.


You don’t care what a slave owner thought? What about a rapist? Or a murderer? Or just a bully? Or just a really unpleasant person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237723121.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine how ridiculous i would soind to you if we discussed current social topics from another country using Indonesian independence leaders words or Bulgarian poet slaveowners.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
