<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236874079.0" user="nyxe12" delta="False">
    <text>Children are legally obligated, generally, to go to school. Certain religions also obligate that followers do certain things, such as prayer at specific times of day.

If children are legally obligated to be somewhere for most of the day, there should be the ability to engage in cultural and religious practices within reason that school conflicts with, especially when those practices do not interfere with the education of non-religious or differently religious students. Someone wearing a cross necklace OR a hijab does not meaningfully interfere with other students ability to learn.

If we legally mandate all children must be in school (which is good, kids should have an education), but also mandate they CANNOT participate in specific important cultural or religious practices, it is very easy for schools to be used as a vector for religious/cultural oppression against minority groups, especially when there often *is* casual inclusion of the nation's more common/"acceptable" religions. (Just look at how boarding schools were used as part of cultural genocide against indigenous americans historically.) If kids are all getting Christmas off as a holiday, that is inclusion of the practices of Christian/Catholic/associated denominations, but in many Christian-dominant places we don't acknowledge this because of how normalized Christmas as a national holiday is. Why is it valid for a Christian holiday to disrupt the education of all students by having them fully out of school for a day, but not for a Muslim student to have a quiet room to go pray in for 10 minutes?

Having a quiet space for a student to go to for a few minutes out of the day to pray, not guided or enforced by school staff, is not enforcing religion upon students, it is only allowing them an accommodation to participate in their religion, which for many people is a very important facet of their lives that isn't turned off when you step into a school building.

Also, this is one of those religious discrimination issues that primarily impacts Muslims but on paper looks "unbiased" because the wording is vague and can be argued to apply to all, but in reality clearly only impacts certain groups of students. Christian children do not need a prayer room to take a brief break in to pray, because Christianity does not include several short daily prayers that involve physically laying on the ground. This ban was created in reaction to an accommodation for Muslim students.

From [this article:](https://montrealgazette.com/news/quebec/groups-challenge-quebec-school-prayer-ban-in-court) A prayer room was implemented in a school by request of students who before this had been praying outside but occasionally had weather interfere and wanted a place indoors due to weather issues. Now a spokesperson is suggesting students should just straight-up leave school and go try to pray at Tim Hortons. How does THAT benefit their education?

Further, the article notes something important - now some students are afraid of being punished if school officials find out they pray while in school, even if doing so quietly. How does *that* help to learn better? Is punishing participation in religion (or even just the fear of being punished, given how unclear it is if they will be punished) fostering a positive learning environment for religious students?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238197676.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238197927.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/atkhan007 – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250733286.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238233236.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>I think the difficulty around this topic is to know where to draw the line. 

Does freedom of religion imply the state mist *accommodate* so everyone can practice their religion unhindered? I don’t know that it does, or that it should.

Does freedom of religion mean you can adhere to and practice whatever religion and not be persecuted? Most certainly. Does it absolve you from being accommodating towards other societal agreements? I don’t think so. 

Vivre ensemble is a two-way street. Religious rights are important, but should they prime over any other right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238390988.0" user="Huffmanstinks" delta="False">
    <text>Generally I think the line is easily drawn where your religion interferes with someone else's liberty

Allowing a kid to pray doesnt hurt other kids who arent of the same religion. But obviously a religion requiring blood sacrifice would hurt others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238419514.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think it’s as simple as that. These are public schools, with a limited budget, and a lot of demands on how the resources should be allocated. 

There was already a lot of outcry on the lack of proper ventilation when students were getting back to school towards the end of Covid. The question is what’s the best use of these rooms for all students. When should religious accommodations take priority over other priorities?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239377067.0" user="Dreamergal9" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn’t allowing students to simply use a room that is empty/not in use during prayer times suffice? Similar to how students are allowed to use certain classrooms for club activities at certain times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240629883.0" user="Curunis" delta="False">
    <text>This is literally what actually happens. Some random teacher would be sitting inside during lunchtime recess because they were marking or they were eating their own lunch and didn't mind a few Muslim students bringing in prayer mats, praying, then going outside to play. 

I genuinely do not understand where people are getting this idea that all these schools had some kind of dedicated room for prayer and religious activities only. What kind of schools are these people going to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243028742.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>I think that is what a prayer room would be. But then again, even if it’s not a dedicated space that only serves this purpose, I’m not aware of any student activity happening in a school that doesn’t require some form of supervision. Who do you appoint? Who keeps track of what room is available when? Who ensures the space is maintained as multi-faith/egalitarian? I think it could be done, but to say it doesn’t create something else for the school to manage is also not exactly true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244363643.0" user="EggRocket" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that monitoring this room would be some gigantic task, the majority of the people using it are going to be Muslims who'd probably have at most two prayers in a school day staying for a total of ten minutes. You probably don't even need a dedicated person, some teacher can probably just poke in from time to time. I can't think of any other religion which would use a multi-faith room on a daily basis, not to say that they shouldn't or can't, just that they won't. 

&amp;#x200B;

All a school needs for a prayer room is a clean room. You can have the kids bring their own rugs and their little community will handle that. The devout Christian students can put their Bible's next to the Qur'ans on some bookshelf or whatever. 

&amp;#x200B;

But if you have around two dozen kids who are obligated by their faith to pray and can help them meet that obligation with relative ease, then yes, we should do it. Of course some obligations are not possible- we aren't giving students the month of Ramadan off because they need to fast. But we should do what's within our power to accommodate everyone. 

&amp;#x200B;

If we can make safe-spaces for teens, we can make prayer rooms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240043895.0" user="beesnteeth" delta="False">
    <text>This is ridiculous. Do you honestly think that schools use every single classroom, meeting room, study room, gymnasium, auditorium, changing room, computer lab, cafeteria, office, and break room non-stop from 7AM to 7PM, Monday through Friday?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243034055.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>See comment below.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238744492.0" user="nyxe12" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Does freedom of religion imply the state must accommodate so everyone can practice their religion unhindered? I don’t know that it does, or that it should.

I don't think that it necessarily and always does - but I do think explicitly **banning** religious participation, particularly when it's a person who is obligated to be in a certain place that conflicts with a (very short) religious prayer obligation, is objectively in opposition to freedom of religion. The issue is that these accommodations had been implemented willingly and in response to students going "hey, we usually pray outside at lunch for 10 minutes, but sometimes it rains, can we have a room where we can go if we need to do that?". 

I also think that when a religious accommodation is relatively minor and not affecting anyone else, it may as well be granted. If a Christian student were to say they needed to be able to preach the bible to every classroom once a week to "save" other students, that would obviously be obtrusive and disruptive to other students, and is not a core principle of the student's religion that they are culturally/religiously obligated to adhere to. Muslim students doing a 10-15 minute prayer \~2 times a day is really no more disruptive than a student leaving the classroom to go to the bathroom, and it is a basic expectation that followers practice the daily prayers - there are also guidelines and norms around implementing accommodations in the workplace for working Muslim adults in many countries, so I don't see why school aged children uniquely should have to be concerned they're going to be punished/explicitly banned from a brief prayer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239092182.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;not a core principle of the student's religion that they are culturally/religiously obligated to adhere to

How would you or the government designate that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241176156.0" user="HippyKiller925" delta="False">
    <text>What right is implicated by compulsory primary education sponsored by the state?

This doesn't seem to be right versus right, but rather right versus good idea that's not essential nor bears the indicia of a right</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243071249.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>The right to be educated in a religiously neutral environment where equality between sexes/religion/races/etc prevails. 
Asking schools to manage availability of private spaces for prayer in such a way that they remain multi-faith/egalitarian can be more complex than it seems, and they decided this was not something the schools should have to manage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243440704.0" user="HippyKiller925" delta="False">
    <text>Then it's not religiously neutral, they're placing religions that are less complex to manage over ones that are "more complex". It's like saying that kids shouldn't get special ed because "they decided this was not something the schools should have to manage". 

If they can't manage to respect children's rights then they shouldn't make education compulsory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243661420.0" user="ohcalix" delta="False">
    <text>You can adhere to moral relativism if you want, I don’t. If it’s impossible, or even made difficult, to share a prayer room on the basis of any type of exclusionary belief, I don’t think that’s something that should be endorsed. 

Individualism reigns supreme today, and it’s been good for religious rights. But it came at the cost of being able to promote more universalist principles. I think nobody has the moral authority to proclaim which is better, so a society should be able to choose to lean more towards one side than the other without being told it’s outright wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243687082.0" user="HippyKiller925" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, that's all well and good. But then also don't make a law requiring them to go somewhere.

It's not moral relativism at all .. if the government wants to force people to do something just by nature of being alive then it needs to make appropriate accommodations. If it can't or won't accommodate, then don't force people to do unnecessary things.

You just want completely unchecked government power to force children to do unnecessary things and then also force them to give up their religious and cultural practices</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239037430.0" user="Teeklin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Someone wearing a cross necklace OR a hijab does not meaningfully interfere with other students ability to learn.

It absolutely does.

You are introducing illogical fairy tale nonsense into the school equation.

Unless it's also cool for the teacher to call out, dissect, and tear apart every dumb thing about both of those religions to the entire class when they are spotted.

Otherwise you are introducing only one side of the conversation to the kids while saying that it's not legal to call out or single out that side of the conversation because it's "protected."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239400393.0" user="nyxe12" delta="False">
    <text>If a different student is so deeply distracted by a student wearing a scarf around their head or a necklace that they can barely see, that kid must have some hell of attention issues.

Neither of those things is even a conversation, it is literally someone sitting there wearing an article of clothing that is not inflammatory.

A teacher taking time out of the class to dissect religion is absolutely more distracting and takes away from the educational experience of all than someone wearing a cross. Good lord.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239728439.0" user="Plusisposminusisneg" delta="False">
    <text>Should schools also ban all education on trans people, or kids being transgender? Gender theories seems like a illogical belief system to the majority of people, yet most tolerate it to some degree.

&gt;You are introducing illogical fairy tale nonsense into the school equation.

A kid expressing themselves or adhering to a certain culture in school is not introducing something to the "school equation". Kids are not grey blobs with no personality or upbringing, diversity and personal expression means people will exist differently from other kids.

&gt;Unless it's also cool for the teacher to call out, dissect, and tear apart every dumb thing about both of those religions to the entire class when they are spotted.

Why would it be "cool" for teachers to single out a students habits or culture and bully them in front of the class? Are you a socially stunted in some way? Have you been diagnosed with some sort of disorders? I think you should get checked out, I am genuinely afraid that you might have a personality or social disorder.

Like seriously, I get that you are an super cool edgelord but have you even thought about this for two seconds beyond your knee jerk reaction to own the stupid fairy tail believers?

&gt;Otherwise you are introducing only one side of the conversation

A kid expressing themselves or having a culture that you personally disapprove of is not the school endorsing or propagandizing that view.

&gt;while saying that it's not legal to call out or single out that side of the conversation because it's "protected."

It shouldn't be legal for teachers to "single out" kids and bully them for their culture and their heritage, no... 

All "sides of the conversation" should be "protected" like that, you sociopath. Never have kids, get treatment.

I swear you redditors are the kinds of assholes who would call a three year old an idiot for believing in santa and scream at them for their stupid fairy tale beliefs in your effort to prove your "intellectual" superiority.

Good job big guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249790854.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>So should schools only teach STEM subjects and in a cold logical way in grey classrooms to keep the nonsense out?

Also I understand your point about both sides but I don't think the way to go about the other side is a teacher metaphorically-Mad-Eye-Moody-vision-ing some kid's small cross necklace that for all we know was a family heirloom and then proceeding to call the kid to the front of the class and then launch into some hours long tirade of debunking every illogical thing about their religion with maybe even a few ad hominem attacks at their family for believing it thrown in</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
