<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236593678.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;why would you allow religion in schools

Education as we know it began as a religious project. European universities were invented by Catholic clergy. Buddhist and Hindu clergy independently invented a university system in India. Confucianism was and is a massive advocate for education. Even in a secular country like the United States many of the most prestigious institutions of higher learning were created with religious goals in mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236597004.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>So?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236619763.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Religion was a part of education from the beginning. You need to provide strong evidence as to why it’s incompatible. The burden of proof is on you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236625813.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Because religion and state institutions should not mix.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236733572.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Why? They’ve mixed successfully for centuries to the benefit of the population. Prove that their interaction is so harmful that it justifies infringing in fundamental rights to self expression and self association.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237238456.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>If you look at our population right now and things evangelicalism has been beneficially mixed into US culture you’re fucking insane</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237321955.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Evangelism is the absolute least of our problems. It’s not even in the same category of bad that nimbyism, destructive subsidies, and climate change are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237228065.0" user="BarryMkCockiner" delta="False">
    <text>You have to be a troll, no way you are a real person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237343969.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>Why don’t we bring back ***the mandated Lord’s Prayer*** in schools then? Religion clearly is something that’s a part of our culture, is it not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237448689.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn’t be the worst idea. Humans need structure and I’d rather it be a religion that’s survived 2,000 years than the VULT of consumerism that’s pushing humanity towards environmental catastrophe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237736310.0" user="Hero_of_Parnast" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. Absolutely not.

I am an atheist. I will not be praying at a school. Mandated prayer is a terrible fucking idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237750716.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re an atheist than it’s merely a lack of a belief. Why even care? Will Hitchen’s ghost haunt you or something</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237788794.0" user="Hero_of_Parnast" delta="False">
    <text>You're assuming that the only reason for not wanting to pray is spiritual. I don't want to pray because I don't want to. Why should my religious identity be valued less than a Christian's?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237846942.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>For the same reason that a bald dude’s hairstyle isn’t relevant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237901962.0" user="Hero_of_Parnast" delta="False">
    <text>But your mandated prayer would have to be of a certain religion. So how do you choose? Because it wouldn't just be disrespecting me, it would also disrespect people of faiths other than your chosen one.

It opens a whole fucking can of worms.

And a bald dude still deserves to have his baldness respected, and not have people trying to force wigs on him that he doesn't like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237482012.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>If I’m a satanist should I be allowed to perform satanic blood rituals at school?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237521818.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Can you prove it is your sincerely held belief and that not practicing blood rituals is in fact an undue burden on your religious beliefs? (Since most satanists profess to be atheists the answer should most likely be no)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237566238.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t need to prove your sincere beliefs to declare your religion. The thing about a religion is you can just say you’re a member of it and there is no “religion police” that determines your sincere beliefs.

If a Jew eats a piece of bacon, are they no longer considered Jewish? Or are his beliefs no longer sincere?

If a muslim takes a sip of alcohol is he no longer considered a muslim? Or are his beliefs no longer sincere.

If a Christian does not love his neighbor as he loves himself is he no longer considered a Christian? If so then many Christians wouldn’t pass this test.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237578851.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Those would be examples of people sinning rather than not holding religious beliefs. That’s orthogonal to whether someone believes something. I don’t take satanists or pasatafarians silly not because they act immorally according to their precepts; I don’t take them seriously because they directly admit they are not serious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237607347.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t matter what you think, it matters what the law says

You’re suggesting that satanists and pastafarians have to have a higher standard of “sincere beliefs” than Muslims Jews or Christian’s. While the later can just say they are a Muslim or a Jew without having to prove sincere belief. 

Freedom of religion means it’s equally valid to be a Muslim as it is to be a satanist</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237702258.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>A dumb rule imho</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237739206.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>Who gets to determine which religions are valid?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237762255.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>Courts could trivially discern when religions are made as protests or parodies. The satanic temple was self admiringly made just to cause legal trouble and protests.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237821582.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>Courts can’t just decide what is a religion and what is not. They have to follow the law as written. In the US the first amendment is clear:

“Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof;”

As such the government can’t say that satanism or pastafarian isn’t a valid religion, because that would be a violation of the first amendment.

Even if the established church of Satan have declared themselves to just be atheist, I could say I am a member of the “new” church of satan, which we actually do believe in the</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237842930.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn’t even be opposed legally to the actual satanists wanting rights (however distasteful I find it) I just have a problem with the bad faith</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
