<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237018073.0" user="PhasmaFelis" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.

That's a hell of a rhetorical device. "Everyone agrees with me, except people who don't, and they don't count because they disagree with me." Can't beat that!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239453359.0" user="Kudgocracy" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely the words of someone who's open to changing their view.  Also, "whose".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239807129.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>That is because hijab exist to shame women and to control women. Hijabs are not a good thing in any way.  They are a sign of abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240061882.0" user="gingenado" delta="False">
    <text>Thank the white Christian God that we have nothing that shames or controls women in the west!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240073312.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Forced clothing is abuse regardless of the religion.  But Islam tries to force all their BS in public as they dont understand that no one will support their women abuse.  Muslims are clueless to all of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240872169.0" user="banana_assassin" delta="False">
    <text>There are also women who choose to wear it though and they should have the right to choose that.

It is not always forced. They see it as a form of modesty.

Personally I think it's making the choice for them not to wear it is also bad. I think we should make every effort to make sure people are not being forced into wearing it, but also not be forcing them not to if that's how they choose to express themselves.

For some people it is the same as covering a navel or shoulders.

I am an atheist. I just think people should be able to express their religion of it doesn't extend to hurting the rights of others. For example you can wear your cross or hijab to school but you can't ban books that I or my kid want to read because that extends to my rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243315755.0" user="Subt1e" delta="False">
    <text>Hijab is a symbol of oppression 

It stops being a symbol of oppression when it becomes a choice

And it becomes a choice when women can take it off in every country in the world without being harassed, beaten, raped or killed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250212654.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Some women want to wear the Hijab out of a sincere religious conviction.


I don't see why Saudi Arabia's human rights abuses should cause us to have a few of our own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247291431.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>In islam it is forced. Just the reality of it.    If a women says they are wearing it because of "religion" requires it then they 100% are being forced to wear it.    
It is no different than if you were forced to wear a swastika from nazis, but then you say you chose to wear it.  No one is going to believe that you were not forced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250157082.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>There were PLENTY of people who willingly wore the swastika.

Adolf Hitler, for example. Wittmann, Himmler, Goering and a thousand other war criminals.



Do you really believe that not a single woman WANTED to wear the Hijab?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251644305.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Your point of view is disturbing that you think it is OK to force people to wear something just because a very small few would choose to wear it.  WTF is wrong with you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252678278.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not forcing women to wear a Hijab. 

You are forcing women to not wear a Hijab.


Yes, the Hijab is ultimately about control and whatnot, but many women do genuinely desire to wear it. You will argue they they are Stockholmed into it, but it is still something they believe.


Also, by banning the Hijab, what do you do for those students who are forced by their parents to wear a Hijab? Thier parents just take them out of school. 

Secularism win, Muslim women are now barefoot in the kitchen!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257012115.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Muslim women are forced to wear a hijab.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241095170.0" user="HardlightCereal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Forced clothing is abuse regardless of the religion.

You mean like forcing girls to take off their hijabs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247296883.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>You just ban the hate and discriminatory clothing so their parents cant make them wear it anymore at least at school.  
You would be protecting them from being forced to wear it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250139584.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>What if a woman wants to wear a Hijab?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251653678.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>When they learn that most women are forced to wear them and it is a sign of women abuse then they wont want to wear it.  
They will get over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252682325.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Glad that Muslim Women have you to tell them what to think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257010603.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Muslim women are forced to wear them to submit to their men.  
If you ban it then  their man can no longer make them wear it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260049516.0" user="nidhoggrdragon" delta="False">
    <text>Christianity is just as bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240792792.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe burqa or niqab, but anytime spent in the Middle East and you would realize that hijab has a function. Secular women wear it, men also wear head coverings there. It's actually much cooler keeps dirt out of your hair etc. When I was overseas and family saw pictures, they would ask if they made me wear the head scarf. And I was like, heck no you would want to wear it too if you were there. Way more comfortable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247266906.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>The hijab is purely a symbol of control of women.  It has no function beyond letting a women know they are not free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247694764.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>I have visited and lived in many Middle Eastern countries. To be honest I never found out whether they would force me to wear it or not because I always chose to wear it, because as I stated a moment ago, it serves a function. It keeps you cool, it keeps the dirt out of your hair, I'm not Islamic but I also wear them in the US depending on the time of year and where I am at.       
Plenty of people who are not Islamic choose to wear head scarves, the culture I am from generally wear headscarves for non-religious reasons. 
So you wear 100% wrong. Head scarves do you have a function beyond religion and control. And hijab it's just what Islamic people call head scarves.     
Now burqa and niqab (the ones which cover a woman's face) I definitely about control and religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43248088413.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>If you lived in middle eastern countries then you know they are not good for women and they are forced to wear them.   Thank you for admitting this.  
I talk to people daily that live in SA and several middle eastern countries so you cant pretend it is any different. I know many people who moved their families there and how their wives and daughters were treated outside the special gated american neighborhoods for workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250137354.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Some women are.

Some women wear it out of sincere religious conviction.


How can we dare force the second group to not wear something they want to wear?

Also in the case of the first group the only result is going to be them being forced to not go to school - which isn't what we want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251595070.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I don't think that this person is interested in an honest discussion. I do know plenty of women who are not being forced to wear it, they choose to. They made a broad statement that hijab only functions as oppression, and now they are trying to change the argument into Middle Eastern cultures oppress women (which is generally true, but Christianity is quite similar to Islam and quite oppressive to women also)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251662320.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>When these women learn that the hijab is a sign of abuse and used by bad people to control women then they wont want to wear them. 
Education is what is needed on it.  
If some really uneducated stubborn women lies and says they want to wear it by their own choice, well they will get over it. 

Hijabs are a sign of hate and have no business being in schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251582458.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>The argument we are having is not "do Middle Eastern countries treat women well". That's an entirely different topic, that I have not stated my opinion.     

The argument we are having is: does the hijab only exist for religious oppression? And I am stating that the answer is clearly no, hijab is another name for head scarf, and many people, including myself wear it for non-religious reasons completely of our own choosing.        

Stop being dishonest and trying to turn the argument into something it is not just because you are wrong. You stated that hijab has no function other than oppression. You are wrong. Hijabs (also known as head scarves) I won by people for non-religious functional reasons (keeps you cool or warm,  keeps you out of the elements, keeps dirt out of your hair etc)      

I believe you are thinking of perhaps burqa (a full body covering that exposes only the eyes) or niqab (a face covering that can be attached to a headscarf to cover the face except for the eyes.      
These garments do not have a function outside of modesty. They are used as oppression, and in some instances women wear them out of internalized misogyny, because they've been taught to be ashamed of their own face showing, and in other cases women wear them because they have deep religious convictions. (I've never worn burqa or niqab, so if I am wrong and they serve a function outside modesty please lmk)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251633581.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>99.99999% of hijabs are for controlling women and are a sign of abuse.  
The .00001% that actually wants to wear one for other reasons will get over it.   
Regardless there is no point for a symbol of hate to be in a school.  
There is no reason why a school should tolerate discrimination under the fake reason of religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251781131.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>No. You don't get to just make up numbers and state it like it is a fact. You can't be dumb enough to think that made up statistics can actually be used as a point in an argument?

Women in my culture wear head scarves all the time and it has nothing to do with religion, modesty or oppression. It's functional and it's also now used as fashion. And we certainly make up more than .00001% of the population (let alone head scarf wearing population) so you are flat out wrong!            
  
 We are not arguing whether hijab should be allowed in school. We are not arguing whether women are treated well in the Middle East or not. The argument literally was you stating: hijab served no function other than oppression.       

And I told you you are flat out wrong, and gave plenty examples to prove my argument. Your arguments have been composed of straw Men and made up statistics 😂. Sorry but that's not the way a discussion between adults works. If you have some actual evidence to support your statement (that hijab/headscarf are ONLY used for oppression) I'm still waiting to hear it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257045830.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Hijabs are for abuse and control by islamic men.  
Not sure why you are OK with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260789009.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>Oh look another straw man argument!!    
Let me reiterate, in case it is genuinely poor reading comprehension on your part.            

We are NOT arguing whether Arabic men use headscarves to control and abuse women.    

Your argument was: The ONLY purpose of a head scarf is to control and abuse women.       

I argued back and said that is completely untrue, my culture wears head scarves for non-religious reasons, the reason that my culture wears them is because they are functional (they keep you cool or warm depending the season and they keep your hair clean) and also fashion.        

Your statement, that headscarves are only used for abuse and control of Arabic women by Arabic men was categorically false. Because head scarves are used by MANY cultures around the world that are not Islamic or middle eastern, and they have a function and a purpose. And honestly I find your erasure of these cultures (between 10 and 20% of the world's population last time I checked) pretty damn offensive. You are being gross.        
     
Apparently women only exist to you when they support whatever ridiculous statement you are making. And if they don't support whatever statement you stupidly made and stood behind, then they must be ".0000001% of the population and have to get over themselves".          

And I really don't want to hear another peep out of you unless it is in direct response to the argument we are actually having, I will put it in all caps so you can see it clearly:      

**YOU STATED THAT THE ONLY FUNCTION OF HEAD SCARF IS FOR ARABIC MEN TO OPPRESS ARABIC WOMEN.**

you are WRONG. Women in my culture, who are not Middle eastern, where headscarves for non-religious reasons of function and fashion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264229448.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Hijabs are forced on women as part of the abuse that is done under islamic rules. Women are 2nd class citizens in islamic countries and forced to be submissive. You dont want that shitty abusive culture into Canada or in schools.  
It is crazy that you are in support of abusing women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264279348.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>It's crazy that you are racist against black people, and that you ignore the existence of black women because they don't support your anti headscarf agenda</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264477446.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>LOL, hijabs have nothing to do with black people or any skin color or race. Sounds like you are racist by bringing up race in a conversation that has nothing to do with race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264823671.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264822969.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241876251.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>If its forced then yea. But what's the problem if they want to wear it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247311099.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>If they are islamic then they are being forced to wear it.  That is a requirement of the religion.  
But because a hijab is primarily a hate symbol, you just ban it for everyone.   The .00001% that wear it for non-religious reasons will get over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249270666.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>I've met some muslim feminists that do want to wear it. You cant generalize like this. Even if they are 0.0001 that wear it for non religious reasons or that is the % of women that indeed wants to wear it, you cannot ban them from wearing it as it hinders freedom of expression 

And because it's a requirement of a religion doesnt mean it's by force. Like Christianity it's a requirement not commit adultery but that shit is broken literally all the time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250218873.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>And why is it such a bad thing if they do it for religious reasons?

As long as they are not being forced, why do I care WHY they want to wear something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250357450.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>You replying to the wrong person orr?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250395715.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>No.


I think that a good reason to allow the Hijab is BECAUSE the person wearing it has a sincere religious belief.


We want people to interact with society (especially school) and allowing them to be comfortable is part of that.


If it doesn't come at any cost to the school, I don't see any argument for banning religious clothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250477042.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be replying to the wrong person because I agree with you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251702524.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>You can generalize that because in Islam that is its sole purpose.  
It is used as a sign of abuse and control of women.    

The very few uneducated women that wants to ignore the reality of a hijab and say they want to wear it, will get over it.  

Your strange view here would be trying to argue that everyone should be allowed to wear swasticas because a few ignorant people choose to wear them.   You make no sense.   
It is not correct to make an argument like that as you can always find uneducated people that will ignore reality and chose to do something stupid.   

Based on your logic OSHA would not exist as there are idiots out there that choose to not follow safety rules.  
Drivers licenses wont exist as there are idiots out there that choose to drive without having a license.  
Abusing women is OK as there are women out there that choose to be abused.    

Grow up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252323035.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The very few uneducated women that wants to ignore the reality of a hijab and say they want to wear it, will get over it.

How do you know they are uneducated? They are many well educated women that want to wear it. Do you have a source for this claim?

&gt;Your strange view here would be trying to argue that everyone should be allowed to wear swasticas because a few ignorant people choose to wear them. 

Its wild you are comparing swastikas to a hijab. Please which genocides and racial superiority ideology did hijab pose,m

&gt;Based on your logic OSHA would not exist as there are idiots out there that choose to not follow safety rules.
Drivers licenses wont exist as there are idiots out there that choose to drive without having a license.

What does this even mean? This is completely different.

&gt;Abusing women is OK as there are women out there that choose to be abused.

You keep comparing things that have harm. What harm is a hijab by itself causing? A hijab doesnt hit women does it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257033194.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Women in islam are forced to wear hijabs.  Only someone uneducated that is ignorant to the abuse would wear one voluntarily.  
Islam has committed lots of genocide and believes in racial superiority. It has been that way since Islam was created in 600AD.  

You need to grow up and stop defending abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257908079.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Women in islam are forced to wear hijabs. Only someone uneducated that is ignorant to the abuse would wear one voluntarily.

"Anybody that doesn't do what I think is right is uneducated and ignorant" is not the catch you think it is. What abuse does a hijab perpetuate by itself?

&gt;Islam has committed lots of genocide and believes in racial superiority

Citations needed. And dont go bring in shit that happened before the Mongols lmfao

&gt;You need to grow up and stop defending abuse

Again, listen to Muslim women that want to wear it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264222308.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Hijabs are forced on women as part of the abuse that is done under islamic rules.  Women are 2nd class citizens in islamic countries and forced to be submissive.  You dont want that shitty abusive culture into Canada or in schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43266537488.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, that's why you now force women not to wear it. Superb analysis.

Btw, middle east is not the only country with a substantial Islamic population.

Many of them in Africa, South East Asia and central Asia are not forced to wear it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260054536.0" user="nidhoggrdragon" delta="False">
    <text>Why do they want to wear it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43260503963.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Why does that matter?. They want to,it doesnt hurt anyone. Case closed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245494631.0" user="PhasmaFelis" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who went to high school, I'm extremely skeptical of anyone who passes rules on what kind of hats kids are allowed to wear "for their own good." I was told I couldn't wear a bandanna to hold my hair back because "it's a gang sign." Same guy tried to tell me I couldn't wear a trenchcoat to school in winter because I was using it to "carryi contraband." (He saw me take an apple out of my pocket.)

I don't see this as any different. People get off on making kids conform, so they make up reasons why it's *actually* righteous and good for them. And *nothing* gets people more righteously prudish than someone else's religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43247341447.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>99.99999% of those with hijabs are forced to by men in their religion for control.  
The .000001% that want to wear it for non-religious reasons/for fun will get over it being banned.    They will understand that it is a hate symbol and be OK with it being banned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250223359.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>99.99999% of stats are made up on the spot.


The absurdity of you picking 7 9s means you have no idea what you are even talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251639060.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Because the real answer is basically 100%, but you idiots will find 1 idiot somehwere that says they chose this.  Thus the 99.99999% makes perfect sense.  I guess you cant math.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252632273.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>You really think that of the 900 million Muslim women only 90 genuinely believe that Allah wants them to wear head coverings?

There are genuinely more people who believe in Satan clause than 90. Way more.


Glad the Muslim Women have you to tell them what they think</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257017030.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Allah does not require the head coverings. It is men on earth, who are muslims, that require women to wear hijabs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252054616.0" user="PhasmaFelis" delta="False">
    <text>Google "I choose to wear hijab." There are plenty of examples, and thoughtful explanations by the women wearing them.

I understand you're concerned that women are being abused. It's good to make sure that women have the choice. But women are actually capable of making their own choices, given the option. Pretending that everyone wearing a hijab is a helpless victim in need of a hero to snatch the scarf from her head is just as patronizing as the men who think every woman is a helpless victim who needs to be protected by a hijab.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254142156.0" user="asteriskall" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, the best way to change this would be to incorporate the Muslim immigrants into the larger society. Do you think bans on their traditions would help? If anything, these bans would cause them to double down on their traditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257006527.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>It is a ban on an abusive hateful act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43257214197.0" user="asteriskall" delta="False">
    <text>I acknowledge that strict modesty culture is harmful. However, these bans won't actually help. I'd argue it's very important for their children to go to and feel comfortable in the public schools in order to make them part of the larger community. It would be even worse if they become more insular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264164058.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Bans of abusive things are good for a school.  
Kids have a place outside of the home where they get to experience not being abused.   it is way more comfortable for everyone in the school.  

Would you allow other kids to open carry guns in school when that is not an abusive act like a hijab?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264286768.0" user="asteriskall" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the kids recognize the harm it does to them? I don't think so. That's the entire point of indoctrination.
I'm confused what the analogy you are trying to draw with the guns is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264471036.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>Kids do and will recognize that school is as safe space.  
The point is to block abusive indoctrination from being brought in from home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264725251.0" user="asteriskall" delta="False">
    <text>If they are taught at home that it's right to wear a hijab then do you think the school telling them that they are straight up not allowed to helps? Again, you don't seem to get how indoctrination works. In order to prevent it you need a more subtle approach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43264808710.0" user="PossessionMiddle2420" delta="False">
    <text>They are taught at home that women must be submissive and must wear what the man makes them wear.  
Why are you OK with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240783372.0" user="Updoot4yoot" delta="False">
    <text>Ahhh the "no true Frenchman" fallacy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243312471.0" user="Helmet_Icicle" delta="False">
    <text>Second only to "I am rubber and you are glue" as a dialectical technique</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
