<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="61" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43238674429.0" user="Yushaalmuhajir" delta="False">
    <text>Even ISIS allowed Christians the right to practice their religion in their own homes, churches and schools.  But let’s be real, you are like every milquetoast white nationalist/muh Europa type  who’s afraid of being called racist (lol coward), and takes this position of caring about Muslim women (yes, I can tell it’s hijab that’s bothering you, funny you mention it more than any other religious garb).  

Congratulations bro, you’re even more extremist than ISIS.  And may your daughter or granddaughter become Muslim and wear hijab ameen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238995759.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Even ISIS allowed Christians the right to practice their religion in their own homes

Im surprised by the fryed-brain mentality that would make you say such stupidty and feel morally as the snarky commenter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239460217.0" user="Yushaalmuhajir" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not lying though.  Muslims are forbidden from interfering with religious activities of Christians snd Jews living under the covenant with the Muslim state, and ISIS (even though illegitimate) knows this (it’s common knowledge among Muslims actually).  Did they do some evil shit?  Absolutely, but the level of hypocrisy here is astounding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43248225686.0" user="DarkAquilegia" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;ISIS (even though illegitimate) knows this

It may be known, but is it practiced?
Human rights watch has considered isis actions towards other ethnic, religous groups to be genocide. 

I guess exterminating, trafficking, enslaving of those with other religious beliefs or ethnic groups is considered respecting and not interfering with them?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
