<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236664074.0" user="PainterSuspicious798" delta="False">
    <text>This isn’t a real CMV lol OP has good points made and replies “nah”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236786536.0" user="Powerful-Union-7962" delta="False">
    <text>That just means that no-one has successfully changed their view yet. Could be that their view is too strongly held, but personally I agree with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236819712.0" user="ghjm" delta="False">
    <text>You're only supposed to post here if you're open to having your view changed.  OP obviously isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236829277.0" user="Powerful-Union-7962" delta="False">
    <text>So people are only supposed to post weakly held views here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236919371.0" user="Curunis" delta="False">
    <text>No, but they have to actually be willing to explain their reasoning (rule 1 calls for this) and consider alternate explanations. If they come in here and post a normative statement of "x should be y" and the only rationale they give after being asked is "because, x should be y" and "because I think so" changing their view is literally impossible. 

In this thread, OP has been asked multiple times why they think what they do, or what they think the benefits of this policy might be, and their responses have included things like "Keep your religion at home, don't flaunt it in public, nobody wants to see that," or "School is not a temple," which are just statements of opinion themselves. Commenters can reply with their own opinion statements but that's obviously not going to change anyone's mind!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236930423.0" user="Powerful-Union-7962" delta="False">
    <text>Yes agreed, OP should take more time refuting the arguments put forth. That would be the rest of their day taken up though, but they did post this, soooo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237017554.0" user="Curunis" delta="False">
    <text>Yes exactly. They posted it, like you said, and the whole point of this sub is to engage with people's arguments and try to debate them. If they weren't willing to do that, they shouldn't have posted. 

Several commenters have already engaged in good faith and written their reasoning in reply only to get some low effort one-liner opinion statements in response, which is sort of indicative that OP doesn't really want their opinion changed to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236868601.0" user="refep" delta="False">
    <text>He’s not saying why he disagrees tho, he’s just going « nah »

Anyways, secularism is the separation of the state and religion. Meaning the government or state cannot push any religion onto its citizens. The banning of people from practicing their religion has nothing to do with secularism since people not practicing their own religion when they’re not carrying out any official function is not secularism. That’s just suppressing religion like the USSR or the CCP. 

It’s just a push for state sponsored atheism, hidden under the guise of being « secular ».</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236911795.0" user="Powerful-Union-7962" delta="False">
    <text>There is an argument for saying that anyone posting on here needs to take the time to explain why attempt to change their mind has failed.

As for separation of church and state, the comparison to the USSR etc. isn’t valid for multiple reasons. OP isn’t saying religion should be banned, just that it should be practised in private and no special allowances (prayer rooms, time off, etc.) should be made. School in my opinion should be the great equalizer, all kids no matter what their socio-economic, ethnic or religious background should be treated equally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236955246.0" user="refep" delta="False">
    <text>I understand your point about religion not being banned here, but I would argue there is nothing unequal about providing religious accommodation. Wouldn’t treating them equally mean allowing everyone the same opportunity? If someone asks for a bathroom break and you provide it, does it mean you’re not treating the people who don’t have to go to the bathroom unfairly?

Similarly, if a Jewish student asks for time to pray, or a Hindu does, or a Muslim does and you offer them all the same opportunity, is that unfair? What if you allow atheists to take time off to practice mindfulness meditation or something like that? I don’t think it’s particularly unequal to provide accommodation. It’s not considered unfair when schools provide accommodation for people with say peanut allergies? Banning peanuts from cafeterias is far more draconian than allowing some kids to pray without having them impose their belief systems on another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237059724.0" user="Powerful-Union-7962" delta="False">
    <text>As soon as an allowance is given on the grounds of religious belief that creates hierarchy and division. In some schools in Canada Muslim students leave for prayers on Friday afternoon, often not coming back afterwards (not surprising). In effect this means Fridays afternoons off. Fair?

Where would it stop? If a child being raised by Plymouth Brethren demanded separate lunch rooms, would that be ok? Or if X religion wanted a separate water fountain because Y religion use the communal one? 

As I said, it should be the great equalizer. Everyone gets treated the same, no allowances for religion, politics, wealth or ethnicity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237192936.0" user="refep" delta="False">
    <text>The thing to note is that western society is already set up to accommodate Christianity because well, their societal rules were set up at a time when religion was much more prevalent in society. Muslims go to the mosque to pray on Fridays, while Christians go to church on Sunday. There is a reason why Sunday is a weekend in all western nations. It allows Christians to attend their religious functions without interfering with their work. In some Muslim countries, the weekend is Friday-Saturday for a similar reason, with Sunday being the start of the work week. So just as a byproduct of the society we find ourselves in, banning students from praying on Friday has a disproportionate effect on just one minority group.

Also, in a secular school, even if accommodation is given to Muslim students to pray on Friday doesn't mean that the schools will stop teaching while those students are out praying. In this case, students themselves would be responsible for getting caught up on the material, since they absolutely can be tested on material taught while they miss school. It is not an advantage for them. If anything, the students who stay in school would be the ones benefiting.

Of course any accommodation has to conform to federal law. You should not be able to claim the right to do something if it infringes on the rights of someone else. X religion demanding separate water fountain because they wouldn't want to share a water fountain with "the filthy followers of religion Y" would infringe upon the rights of the followers of religion Y so it would not be allowed. There is a healthy middle ground to be found where you can accommodate requests which do not cause harm to others, while forbidding those that do. How would you determine what causes harm and what doesn't? Well, just follow the charter. Would this accommodation infringe upon the charter rights of another student? If yes, then it should not be allowed. Else it should be fair game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237030643.0" user="zerowangtwo" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by treated equally? Are you against school lunch subsidies for low income families? How about special ed classrooms? Accommodations for ADHD?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237262176.0" user="Equal-Thought-8648" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; all kids no matter what their socio-economic, ethnic or religious background should be treated equally.

Are other children being denied rooms to address their needs? 

We're in agreement that others should be treated equally - but this appears to be the *opposite* of equal treatment for those who are being specifically targeted and denied.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250339820.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying we need to ban religion, I'm just saying that a person should not be allowed to act out their sincerely held religious obligations that only effect themselves.

They are arguing that people should be forced to remove religious clothing.

I don't think there is a good reason to force someone to show me a part of their body they would much prefer hidden. Even if it is just their hair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237176247.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Same here.  And I wouldn’t waste my time on arguments that aren’t productive, so “nah” seems fine as a response</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238200522.0" user="idkman0485" delta="False">
    <text>OP has made basically no points and people criticise him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245515885.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
