<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="102" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43243668448.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="False">
    <text>I strongly disagree with the french stance here. Banning hijabs or failing to accommodate daily prayers isn't just secular... it's anti-religion. It is literally preventing them from practicing their religion. How is that not a form of religious oppression? I know that the hijab is seen as an oppressive symbol, but the choice should still be up to the individual. Similarly, in some religions men are required to have beards and forcing them to shave would also be problematic. Finally, I don't see why prayer rooms are controversial... regular daily prayer is a part of their religion and has nothing to do with promoting their religion to other people. 

The error here is applying the standards of one religion as the default. Just because Christians don't require special hats or prayer rooms, doesn't mean that we should base our accommodations off of that. In this case, the secular rules don't impact (most) Christian's ability to practice their faith, but they do impact other religion's ability to practice their religion, leading to a disparate impact. 

This is like saying that having a staircase is equal because everyone is allowed to use them. But obviously, someone in a wheelchair can't physically use a staircase even if it is available to them to use. In order for someone in a wheelchair to have equal access to a facility, that facility needs to make an accommodation like a ramp or an elevator. Similarly, for religions to have equal ability to practice their religion, then society should make some reasonable accommodations. BTW, Christians benefit from these as well when it comes to religious holidays and access to the bible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244951603.0" user="kwamzilla" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I strongly disagree with the french stance here. Banning hijabs or failing to accommodate daily prayers isn't just secular... it's anti-religion. It is literally preventing them from practicing their religion. How is that not a form of religious oppression? 

This is it, really.

Secularism would be allowing them to practice their religion as long as it's not impacting on others.

There might be a stance against **requiring** a prayer room etc, but banning it is literal oppression. Why do they need to be banned? Who does that help and how?

Your wheelchair/staircase example is a great one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
