<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="81" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43240194702.0" user="leavinlikeafather" delta="False">
    <text>While I advocate for secularism, part of secularism IS to give others the freedom to practice their religion. While I agree that teachers don't have the right to force religious practices on their students (leading them through prayer, for example), a student should be able to individually practice their religion as long as it doesn't hinder anyone else.

Where I live, children are legally required to receive an education, and many parents cannot afford to homeschool their child so they are stuck with sending their kid off to a public school. A student should not be obligated to sacrifice their faith for 8 hours a day due to something they are forced to attend -- that is absolutely insane. I don't know how you get to the point where students where Kippahs or cross necklaces bother you.

The point of a religious private school is that they are allowed to enforce religion on the students, and public schools letting their students express their religion is not that at all. Part of the purpose of school is to not only learn academics, but to also become better versed with social tactics and interaction with other humans. This instilled tolerance includes people of other religions, and banning students from openly expressing their faith does a disservice to not only the student themself, but others. Also, making students take off articles of clothing required by their faith will no doubt instill a deep anxiety in them, and hinder their ability to do their work because they aren't honoring their God(s) in the way they are supposed to. The reason why secularism is the best way to go is because it does not force an agenda on anyone, and that includes allowing individual students to express their specific religion. The last thing a non-secular society wants is for people to showcase a rainbow of all differing religions.

I'm more concerned with fearing if an armed shooter will barge in and fill my sibling up with lead, but you do you, I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254901577.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>Don't know why this got downvoted</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255314544.0" user="leavinlikeafather" delta="False">
    <text>I think I was a little mean, but I don't have much patience for these people lmao</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
