<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="89" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43241190506.0" user="wellz-or-hellz" delta="False">
    <text>There is a difference between allowing students to express their religious beliefs and schools forcing religion on students. I agree there should be no prayer rooms or any sort of religious endorsement/indoctrination in schools but if a student wants to dress in a way that symbolizes their religion, they should be free to do so. It’s discrimination on religious grounds to not allow them too. I mean, by this same logic are atheists not allowed to have a group to discuss their beliefs. I am an atheist myself and I still think kids should freely be able to express their religious beliefs in school. I just don’t think teachers should teach children from a religiously biased standpoint, or force them to take part in prayer or display any religious symbols at school(that includes prayer rooms).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254917441.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>I think there should be prayer rooms tbh. You can even just make it accessible for atheists/agnostics by marking it as a "alone space". That's really all a prayer room would work like. Sure, folks might use it to pray, but at the end of the day that's all it is(correct me if I'm wrong)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254942347.0" user="wellz-or-hellz" delta="False">
    <text>Let’s not call them prayer rooms then. Let’s just call it a recreational space where kids can pray or not if they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255844083.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>As they should be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
