<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236996671.0" user="iRecapt" delta="False">
    <text>Forcing kids to take their crosses or hijabs off is just as bad as forcing an atheist to pray. The point if freedom, if a student wants to express their religion they should have the freedom to do so, just as an atheist should have the freedom to not follow anything that has to do with religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237370094.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>We literally don’t have **unlimited freedom** in the exact way you’re pretending we do though.

Most high schools have a *no hats* policy. Judges can’t put on a Black Sabbath t-shirt before they go to bang the gavel. 

In order to be consistent with this incredibly arbitrary standard of “freedom” you’ve presented, why the hell would we allow companies and government agencies to enforce a *professional dress code* at all? 🤷🏻‍♂️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237804383.0" user="iRecapt" delta="False">
    <text>Because religious freedom is in almost every western constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238556063.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>Not every western country has the same arbitrary protections across the board.

In France, for instance, they have religious freedom enshrined in their constitution but they don’t consider being fully masked in public to be any more an “expression of religious freedom” as wearing a ski mask in a bank.

Suffice it to say, the idea of *religious freedom* doesn’t mean you get every chaotic permissibility you want just because you claim it’s “of your religion.”</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
