<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="104" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43244218823.0" user="EggRocket" delta="False">
    <text>There are tons of religious people in the world. Islam is the world's second biggest religion. I'm an ex-muslim, I don't like Islam, but I don't want to live in world where all the Muslims leave to go to Saudi Arabia because our schools don't accommodate their children. There's enough animosity, we should be working to lessen it not amplify it. 

&amp;#x200B;

Say we do take away the prayer rooms (prayers which they are obligated to preform on threat of eternal torture) and their hijabs. We ban prayers at school or traditional clothing because we don't want religion in our schools, as you want. Why do we think that this will somehow lead to better education? If parents do screw off to the Middle East or SEA because the West didn't accommodate them, are their kids somehow going to get a better education? It'll lead to worse educational outcomes, I can totally foresee a decline in female muslims being educated in the West from such laws, though if you banned praying from schools to universities Muslims across the board would suffer in education, the last thing you want someone to suffer in to prevent radicalization.

&amp;#x200B;

Religion is a core part of people's identity, you can't ban it without shunning them. Unless you want atheist schools, people will always bring their culture and faith with them wherever they go.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
