<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236631501.0" user="willthesane" delta="False">
    <text>are you in favor of telling students what they must wear? the clothing restrictions you are imposing(hijabs, turbans, crosses, yamika's) seem a little harsh, if you allow freedom to wear clothing, you must also allow children to wear the religious clothes they wish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236634604.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, most countries have school uniforms, and it's been proven to be a good thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236721501.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>That's not true. 

https://news.osu.edu/school-uniforms-dont-improve-child-behavior-study-finds/

"Despite the belief of many parents and teachers, school uniforms don’t seem to have any effect on young students’ behavior or attendance overall, a new national study found.

But students who attended schools requiring school uniforms did report lower levels of “school belonging” in fifth grade than did students in schools without uniforms."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239057166.0" user="JR_Al-Ahran" delta="False">
    <text>But… they’re so convenient. You wear the same thing everyday. Roll out of bed. Throw on the pants, shirt, sweater, and you’re done. Get 5 or so of each and you do the laundry every week. Not to mention you just buy them like 2 size too big at the beginning of the year and you unravel them as you grow. Only have to buy 1 set for however many years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236756775.0" user="CathanCrowell" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, it was not. It's still beging discussed today if should be school uniforms allowed. I think not because it limited individuality and I do not see reason why to limited individuality from young age. Cons is supposed to be equality, but we are living in 2023, we do not need cloths to show our money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237721895.0" user="willthesane" delta="False">
    <text>Would you be opposed to students performing their prayers at a lunch break in the cafeteria?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237267967.0" user="CertifiedLumpen" delta="False">
    <text>We **already tell students what to wear.**

Most high schools have a no hat policy. Judges have a strict dress code as well, they aren’t just allowed to wear a Black Sabbath t-shirt before they go to bang the gavel.

How is *any of this* about “freedom”?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237788239.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>Schools have dress codes . My school said that girls couldn’t wear spaghetti straps or skirts that were shorter than what their arms could reach.

Could I declare that my religion required me to wear miniskirts and tube tops to get around this dress code?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240011735.0" user="WARNING_Username2Lon" delta="False">
    <text>Many schools have a no hats policy. This doesn’t not apply to Hijabs or Kippah’s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240799769.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>But if a student says he belongs to the church of derek jeter should he be allowed to wear a ny Yankees cap for religious reasons?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242739385.0" user="beans_and_noodles" delta="False">
    <text>It’s fun to pretend that context doesn’t matter, but it does. That is not an established religion with any indication that there is a deep personal connection behind it. Islam is a minority religion that is established and we know for a fact that those who practice it are deeply connected to it on a spiritual level. Wanting to wear a New York Yankees cap is a purely aesthetically driven desire and there is no child who will experience significant stress over not being able to wear it. If such child existed, then they should be able to wear the hat, if it can be reasonably determined that they do experience significant stress from being prohibited from wearing it. It really is that simple, if a kid is being deprived of something that is extremely important to their identity to the point that it stresses them out significantly, they shouldn’t be deprived of that thing if there is no risk/harm involved to others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243146303.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>Who determines what is an “established religion”? The government? The government cannot make any laws defining what is or is not a religion, per the first amendment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243173929.0" user="lipring69" delta="False">
    <text>There was a case where a woman claiming to be a “pastafarian” demanded she take her drivers license photo with a spaghetti strainer (only religious headwear was allowed) she sued the state of Massachusetts and won.

So there is precedent that any religious clothing exemptions are valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243971890.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>What is an established religion? Why is there any difference between someone feeling deep affection towards a sports team than towards a fictional being in old texts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239300050.0" user="PavWrestlinGifs" delta="False">
    <text>This was where OP lost me, I’m a Sikh who used to have a turban, when I went to school my turban had 0 effect on anything lol why the fuck would it not be allowed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250303943.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;why the fuck would it not be allowed

Brown people scary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240713547.0" user="cryptic-fox" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. I don’t understand why OP would have a problem with that? So what if a student wants to wear a hijab or a cross or a turban or a kippah? Let them wear what they want and mind your own business. I wonder what happens to OP when they see people wearing any of these things lol.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
