<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236777338.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats.

Secularism goes both ways. Just as you cannot force religion into schools, you cannot, and must not be allowed to, prevent people from expressing their own faith individually. 

France is wrong to ban hijabs, it oversteps the "wall of separation" between religion and state.

(Also, what the fuck is with "jew hats"?)


If a prayer room is non-denominational, and religion is not part of the curriculum (outside of social studies etc) then what's rhe problem?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236986751.0" user="Curunis" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; what the fuck is with "jew hats"

If anything, this little bit from OP is a pretty great example of how forcing observant people to hide their observance leads to ignorance, I'd figure. It sounded like dismissive/condescending scorn to me, and I'm not particularly religious (I'm agnostic Jewish).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237077589.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely read it as "that silly little hat Jews wear", which leads me to believe that OPs argument is coming from a place of scorn toward religious observance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241883819.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;cannot, and must not be allowed to, prevent people from expressing their own faith individually.

Considering how harmful religion is. I would say otherwise</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241893124.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>You can stop people from expressing religion but then you no longer get to call yourself a free society. Sorry, can't have it both ways. 


Religion, when influencing politics, is poisonous. When it's personal, it's none of mine or your business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241895814.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Free society doesnt exist. Doesnt exist now and it will never exist. This isnt the wilderness</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241920172.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>A perfectly free society doesn't exist so we shouldn't try to make it one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242056602.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Try and make something impossible ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242062428.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>We can get it as close as we can, yes. 

By your logic, we might as well just disregard any rights people have in a society, if we can never get it perfect anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242076108.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We can get it as close as we can, yes.

So back to my original point that free society isnt a thing.

&gt;By your logic, we might as well just disregard any rights people have in a society, if we can never get it perfect anyways.

Blatant misuse of my point. Because I advocate for ban of one thing (in this case religion) doesnt mean I advocate for the ban of all other things (human rights)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242087335.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>The basis for your banning of religion is that "a free society is not possible anways". I'm simply pointing out that that logic can be used to ban anything that we would see as a right in a free society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242093158.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>No, my basis for banning religion was the harm it caused and continue to cause. You then brought in free society as to why we shouldnt do that. From which I said that free society isnt a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242102491.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Right. And I could want to ban, for example, the right to assembly because protesters might make a mess. If you tell me that we don't ban protests in a free society, it's not good enough of me to say "well a free society is impossible anyways so go ahead and ban those protestors".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242123004.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Saying we shouldnt ban protest because we are in a free society doesnt mean anything. They are no actual valid reason why it shouldnt be banned. 

I mean I can say let's not criminalize pedophilia because we are a free society. From which you can reply with actual studies to show how pedophilia is physically and emotionally harmful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242139477.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>If you can point to me the harm being done by a kid being able to pray privately in school, then maybe your comparison to pedophilia will be less batshit insane?

&gt;Saying we shouldnt ban protest because we are in a free society doesnt mean anything. They are no actual valid reason why it shouldnt be banned. 

Yet they are banned in dictatorships all over the world. So there are *reasons* why to ban them, just not reasons you accept as valid because you want to live in a...free society where you can protest!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242152966.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, how about the kids that are being radicalized by religious texts?. The ones that makes kids hate queer people and think women role is a caregiver? 

&gt;Yet they are banned in dictatorships all over the world

Yea, because there is an actual reason. Not "oh a free society does this or that" literally no criteria for judging a free society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242171100.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Yea, because there is an actual reason. Not "oh a free society does this or that" literally no criteria for judging a free society.

What reason do they have over there that would not be applicable over here?

&gt;Sure, how about the kids that are being radicalized by religious texts?. The ones that makes kids hate queer people and think women role is a caregiver? 

I'm not religious and I don't like religion. But to ban religion from being practiced is authoritarian, and I dislike authoritarianism even more than I dislike religion, maybe you don't agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242192320.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What reason do they have over there that would not be applicable over here?

They dont want their populace revolting against them. See am actual reason

What is the reason why a liberal democracy shouldnt ban protest? Well because a protest allows people to express their views to the government they voted in. See, another actual reasons.

&gt;But to ban religion from being practiced is authoritarian, 

Still waiting on why its actually authoritarian. If I say drunk driving is bad, then dont go on to explain why it's bad then I may just be wasting my time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242211728.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;They dont want their populace revolting against them. See am actual reason

Our government could just as easily frame any protest as a revolt against them and ban them on that basis. Why should we be allowed to protest and not them?

&gt;Still waiting on why its actually authoritarian. If I say drunk driving is bad, then dont go on to explain why it's bad then I may just be wasting my time

If I have to explain to you why banning the free expression of religion is authoritarian, then I'm wasting my time. What you need is a refresher on basic civics. 

You need to learn your times tables before we can talk about calculus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242319253.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Now being condescending because you cannot clearly explain your reasoning.

Good day to you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242324517.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm being condescending because your remarks merit condescension.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242330474.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Wont bother myself with bad faith discussions but whatever helps you sleep at night

I do hope your religious fundamentalists are paying you for this props👍</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242334422.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm an atheist who abhors the impact of religion in society. I'm just not an authoritarian. That's where you and I differ.

Also I thought you were already done with this discussion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242338559.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Sure buddy 🤚🏾. Clearly never seen the impact of religious fundamentalism🤚🏾

Western atheism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242358393.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Dude it's fine to be an authoritarian, just don't pretend not to be one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242362359.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>And it's fine to be a religious fundamentalist. Just dont pretend not to be one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242368669.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Except I'm a secular atheist. You're actually an authoritarian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242372497.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Except I'm a social Democrat, you are actually a religious fundamentalist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242382581.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Well no, because social democrats don't ban religion, and I've not said anything that would even remotely suggest religious fundamentalism.

You're defended religious bans and defended authoritarian regimes banning protests. You're *actually* an authoritarian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242388023.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Social Democrats in the west maybe

&gt;defended authoritarian regimes banning protests.

Point me where I did this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242405271.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;They dont want their populace revolting against them. See am actual reason

"Well *they* have a real reason to ban protests!" 

&gt;Social Democrats in the west maybe

It's a fundamental part of having a democracy, it doesn't matter where you are. Which is going back to the basic civics gap here. This comment just shows how we're talking about algebra but you still need to learn how to multiply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242420116.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Well they have a real reason to ban protests!"

It's very funny that me explaining the reasoning of authoritarian countries banning protest is seen as me defending the action but in that same comment I explained a reason why liberal democracies shouldn't ban protests and that isnt seen as me defending liberal democracies😹

&gt;It's a fundamental part of having a democracy,

Banning harmful tendencies is also a part of democracies👍🏽

&gt;back to the basic civics gap here. This comment just shows how we're talking about algebra but you still need to learn how to multiply.

This is coming from the guy that thinks explaining the reasoning for something is defending the actions of that thing😹😹. Pls</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43242496283.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Lol okay buddy. Anyways. Have a good one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244169103.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; No, my basis for banning religion was the harm it caused and continue to cause



Alcohol causes harm. Shall we ban that too?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244352362.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>One mostly causes harm to themselves, the other mostly causes harm to others. Different things here buddy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244389555.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>Alcohol most definitely harms others to a noticeable extent. Every bottle you buy perpetuates an industry that kills millions. Alcohol poisoning, drunk driving, violence, cancer.....


Even the people who drink alcohol "responsibly" arguably have blood on their hands from supporting such an industry.


And the most affected members of any religion's negative effects, tend to be adherents of that religion. Buddy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244404395.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Alcohol poisoning, drunk driving, violence, cancer.....

Proving my point that most of the victims of alcoholism are the themselves. (Cancer and alcoholic poisoning)

&gt;And the most affected members of any religion's negative effects, tend to be adherents of that religion. 

Are you under the impression this makes it better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244431449.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Proving my point that most of the victims of alcoholism are the themselves. (Cancer and alcoholic poisoning)


Drunk driving kills other people. violence kills other people. And perpetuating the alcohol industry *makes it an option, allowing it to hurt other people*. 


There is no such thing as a solely personal choice. Every dollar you spend in alcohol, is a dollar the alcohol industry can use to crank out more poison.



&gt;Are you under the impression this makes it better?


In following with your (imo flawed) notion that "drinking mostly hurts the drinkers so its not so bad", religion mostly hurts the religious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244481127.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Drunk driving kills other people. violence kills other people.

Not nearly as the deaths from alchohol related deaths. 13k die from drunk driving while over 100k die from alchohol related issues

As for violence, there isn't any reliable way to measure this.

&gt;In following with your (imo flawed) notion that "drinking mostly hurts the drinkers so its not so bad", religion mostly hurts the religious.

Laughable comparison as this would work if the victims are actually the ones perpetrating the action which isnt the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244781916.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Not nearly as the deaths from alchohol related deaths.



And yet still quite a few. How many is intolerable?


Also, that statistic seems off it appears to be more like [200,000](https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/alcohol-related-road-casualties-official-crash-statistics.pdf)




&gt; Laughable comparison as this would work if the victims are actually the ones perpetrating the action which isnt the case.





Do you think that people who are frequently victims of religious harm arent perpetuating (actively in many cases) the religion? 




And furthermore, by the standard of "Im doing this to myself", if a woman chooses to wear a hijab, or a man a turban, who does it affect but themselves?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244924954.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>I was using US stats. This stat is for 45 countries. 

&gt;Do you think that people who are frequently victims of religious harm arent perpetuating (actively in many cases) the religion?


They are and so? They are the victims but not perpetrators. If most of the victims of religious fundamentalism was the people perpetuating religious fundamentalist then I wouldnt have a matter with it. This is even further elongated due to how brainwashing religion tends to be. No one is feeding a child alchohol or encouraging kids to drink like. Cant say the same for how religion is enforced to people.

 &gt;if a woman chooses to wear a hijab, or a man a turban, who does it affect but themselves?

In a vacuum and it's own nothing is wrong with it but religion is not about clothes being worm</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244971524.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I was using US stats. 

Why limit it to that?

&gt;They are and so? They are the victims but not perpetrators. If most of the victims of religious fundamentalism was the people perpetuating religious fundamentalist then I wouldnt have a matter with it.


I mean it kinda is. Harm from religious practices tends to effect religious people. 




&gt;No one is feeding a child alchohol or encouraging kids to drink like. 


You may be very sheltered, or this may be a geographical thing. But many people most definitely do feed their kids alcohol, allow their children to consume alcohol, tacitly accept alcohol consumption and encorage kids to drink, actively or passively.


&gt;In a vacuum and it's own nothing is wrong with it but religion is not about clothes being worn


It is, for many religions. Its just not **only** that. 


And if its about perpetuating harmful beliefs and practices....again, alcohol consumption does that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245034475.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You may be very sheltered, or this may be a geographical thing. But many people most definitely do feed their kids alcohol, allow their children to consume alcohol, tacitly accept alcohol consumption and encorage kids to drink, actively or passively.

It happens but it is socially shamed, unlike religion 

&gt;Why limit it to that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245086438.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You may be very sheltered, or this may be a geographical thing. But many people most definitely do feed their kids alcohol, allow their children to consume alcohol, tacitly accept alcohol consumption and encorage kids to drink, actively or passively.

It happens but it is socially shamed, unlike religion 

&gt;Why limit it to that?

Nothing, but it still shows the gap between drunk drivers and alchohol related deaths 

&gt;I mean it kinda is. Harm from religious practices tends to effect religious people.

Are the religious fundamentalists killing themselves?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245143392.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It happens but it is socially shamed and even illegal, unlike religion.




Its not illegal in many places, and in even more places it isnt enforced to any degree. Giving your baby alcohol to help them sleep is a practice in numerous areas. 


&gt;You can radicalize your kid using extremist religious texts and boom you have a religious fundamentalist which isnt illegal 

And you can drink in front of a child, and boom, you have a child who thinks drinking (especially to excess) is acceptable. Which also isnt illegal. 





Hell drinking to excess is arguably more acceptable than many strains of religious fundamentalism in many places.



And once again, as long as its "in house" who is it hurting?


&gt;Nothing, but it still shows the gap between drunk drivers and alchohol related deaths 


No, why limit it to the US?


&gt;Are the religious fundamentalists killing themselves?


No. Theyre accepting and perpetuating abuse, repression, and marginalization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249261598.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;not illegal in many places, and in even more places it isnt enforced to any degree. Giving your baby alcohol to help them sleep is a practice in numerous areas.

Which places isnt it illegal? Most places literally ban stores from selling to children and if an outsider discovers you give children alchohol, you can be socially ostracized.

&gt;And you can drink in front of a child, and boom, you have a child who thinks drinking (especially to excess) is acceptable. Which also isnt illegal.

Yea, except you are not giving the kids drinks now are you? Here you are forcing them to practice the religion. Completely different

&gt;And once again, as long as its "in house" who is it hurting?

If alcoholics mostly kill other alcoholics I would still find a problem with it alchohol and say it should be banned. 

&gt;No, why limit it to the US?
1. Literally first page shows sources coming from the US since developed countries are where you can find reliable data

2. More than 2 million die from alchohol related deaths except accidents 


3. Accidents most of the time kills or injures the alcoholic driver so again, supporting my point

&gt;No. Theyre accepting and perpetuating abuse, repression, and marginalization.

Good, so they aren't the victims then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249307801.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Which places isnt it illegal?


France for one and numerous other countries allow minors to drink in the prescence of an adult.


But this goes beyond law here. Numerous countries have people imbibe their first drink as a child, law be damned. **Law** and **custom** arent the same thing.



&gt;Yea, except you are not giving the kids drinks now are you? Here you are forcing them to practice the religion. Completely different



Not really. You raise them in a religion, in the same way you raise them to believe drinking is acceptable. You dont sit the kid down generally and say "you will be following X religion" its just done from their birth.


In the same way, you dont actively try and encourage your kid to drink, but its taken as a given that drinking is an acceptable practice, if not as a child, certainly when theyre older.



Both are methods of indoctrination, passive or no. 





&gt;If alcoholics mostly kill other alcoholics I would still find a problem with it alchohol and say it should be banned. 

Yes because...

&gt; Literally first page shows sources coming from the US since developed countries are where you can find reliable data


There are numerous global statistics.


&gt;More than 2 million die from alchohol related deaths except accidents

&gt;Accidents most of the time kills or injures the alcoholic driver so again, supporting my point



How is that supporting your point? You think religious fundamentalism *never* harms the fundamentalist?









&gt;Good, so they aren't the victims then.


How so? If a woman is beaten or subjugated because of religion, but she believes in that religion, is she not a victim?

If not, the victim list of religious fundamentalism and religion drops considerably.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249526526.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;France for one and numerous other countries allow minors to drink in the prescence of an adult.

Source? Cus what I see is 18

&gt;Not really. You raise them in a religion, in the same way you raise them to believe drinking is acceptable.

Literally all ads, schools and even parents tell kids. DO NOT DRINK.  Kids that do, do it with fear of being caught even. It is only taken as an acceptable practice when they get older. Not when they are still young. Unlike religion.

&gt;Both are methods of indoctrination, passive or no.

Except one is regulated by law and custom while the other is not.

&gt;Yes because

But it doesnt happen so...

&gt;There are numerous global statistics.

Waiting on one that shows the victims of alchohol are mostly non alchoholics

&gt;How is that supporting your point? You think religious fundamentalism never harms the fundamentalist?

Never said it doesnt. But most of the harm is done to the others. Alchohol harm is mostly done to the alchoholic

&gt;How so? If a woman is beaten or subjugated because of religion, but she believes in that religion, is she not a victim?

She is, which brings me back to the topic of indoctrination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249572345.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Source? Cus what I see is 18



To buy. In the presence of adults its younger. And culturally, that 18 isnt even adhered to outside the prescence of adults.



&gt;Literally all ads, schools and even parents tell kids. DO NOT DRINK. Kids that do, do it with fear of being caught even. 


And once again, this is a very American-centric/sheltered view of the world. While binge drinking isnt explicitly encouraged, there isnt really a *safe* level of drinking especially for kids and young adults, and everything else in our culture encourages drinking.


&gt;Waiting on one that shows the victims of alchohol are mostly non alchoholics


Again, why exactly does that matter?



Whats the threshold for it being a problem? In a case of harm, why doesnt the rate matter and not the number?


&gt;Never said it doesnt. But most of the harm is done to the others. Alchohol harm is mostly done to the alchoholic


And their kids, and their spouse, and any potential victims they hit while driving, and you are under the common misconception that being harmed by alcohol is only the purview of alcoholics. Its not.


There is no biologically non-detrimental amount of alcohol to ingest. **Drinking** alcohol is detrimental in and of itself.


&gt;She is, 

Even if she perpetuates it?

&gt;which brings me back to the topic of indoctrination.

And once again, we are perfectly ok with showing drinking as a good thing, encouraging it, inundating people with the concept, from the day theyre born. And it kills far more people. 


Why allow alcohol to exist? Why not shame anyone who drinks? Theres no benefit to them, or society, arguably its a net drain on resources.


Why shouldnt we view people who drink as backwards, foolish, and a bad influence on children?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43249957219.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And once again, this is a very American-centric/sheltered view of the world. While binge drinking isnt explicitly encouraged, there isnt really a safe level of drinking especially for kids and young adults, and everything else in our culture encourages drinking

Literally lived in Nigeria for 15 years😭. All beer says "dont drink under the age of 21" boldly written on it. They are ads for it and schools teach it. Acting like this doesnt happen is funny 

Yes, they are people that disregard these laws but thats literally all laws. Doesnt make my point less valid that drinking is regulated

&gt;To buy. In the presence of adults its younger.

"Legal drinking age is 18" in France...what are you on about again? Just show a source man

&gt;Again, why exactly does that matter?

Because you were the one that brought up drunk driving killing people more than alchoholics when I said that alchoholism kills mostly alchoholics.

&gt;Whats the threshold for it being a problem? In a case of harm, why doesnt the rate matter and not the number?

If the number of external people being harmed by alchoholism is higher than the number of alchoholic then it's a problem. So in this case if drunk driving kills more bystanders than alchoholic poisoning then it's a problem. But since this isnt true and the alchoholic related deaths harms the alchoholic more then I have no qualms with it.

&gt;And their kids, and their spouse, and any potential victims they hit while driving, and you are under the common misconception that being harmed by alcohol is only the purview of alcoholics

Firstly, alchoholics are also victims of drunk driving. They more often than not get harmed. This is not the same as religious fundamentalists. And even if true the number that dies from drunk driving isnt nearly as close as those for alchoholic poisoning

&gt;Even if she perpetuates it?

Yes, due to how widespread indoctrination is.

&gt;And once again, we are perfectly ok with showing drinking as a good thing, encouraging it, inundating people with the concept, from the day theyre born

With regulations that it should done responsibly and criminalizing under age drinking. And it is also socially shamed. Carry a drink to a school and you will likely get warned. Carry a bible to a school and no one bants an eye
Maybe same should be done for religion.

&gt;Why not shame anyone who drinks?

Anyone that wants to harm themselves is free to do so</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43251424187.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Literally lived in Nigeria for 15 years😭. All beer says "dont drink under the age of 21" boldly written on it. They are ads for it and schools teach it. Acting like this doesnt happen is funny



Yes and custom frequently overrides law. We clearly don't take it seriously. What is the value of a law that is ignored?



&gt;"Legal drinking age is 18" in France...what are you on about again? Just show a source man

[Minors accompanied by an adult can indulge in alcohol](https://www.moretimetotravel.com/the-legal-drinking-age-in-france/#:~:text=Carding%20in%20France,-Consistent%20with%20the&amp;text=(It%20is%20not%20advisable%20to,moderation%2C%20when%20with%20their%20family.)

&gt; If the number of external people being harmed by alchoholism is higher than the number of alchoholic then it's a problem




Again, why is the *rate* the problem? If the rate of people harmed by religious fundamentalism was mostly religious fundamentalists, is that acceptable?


&gt;Firstly, alchoholics are also victims of drunk driving. They more often than not get harmed. 



Again with "alcoholic". It's not just alcoholics. **Drinking** in general is bad for you. 




Many people affected by alcohol negatively aren't alcoholics.




&gt;With regulations that it should done responsibly and criminalizing under age drinking. And it is also socially shamed. Carry a drink to a school and you will likely get warned.


Because it's against the law (and teachers are professionally obligated to follow it), outside of school regulations, and considered disruptive. 


&gt;Carry a bible to a school and no one bants an eye Maybe same should be done for religion.

You bring a book extolling the virtues of alcohol though, nobody bats an eye. Yet in publishing and purchasing that book, you help perpetuate a culture and industry that kills millions.


 


&gt;Anyone that wants to harm themselves is free to do so



Precisely. And it doesn't really matter what the knock on or wider societal effects are right?



So, if somebody can drink, contribute to the wider social acceptability of drinking, and help perpetuate a clearly harmful practice, why shouldn't people be religious, contribute to the wider social acceptability of religion, even if it is a harmful practice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252427036.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>Accompanied by their parents. Not adults. 

&gt;Yes and custom frequently overrides law. We clearly don't take it seriously. What is the value of a law that is ignored?

The law is the only reason we dont see more kids being alchoholic. People steal eventhough they are laws against stealing. It just isnt as bad in the absence of laws.

&gt;Again, why is the rate the problem? If the rate of people harmed by religious fundamentalism was mostly religious fundamentalists, is that acceptable

Because I literally said earlier that if harms yourself or most likely to harm yourself then I dont care. Your body. 

If the people passing homophobic laws for exampe mostly applied to themselves then I dont care.

&gt;Again with "alcoholic". It's not just alcoholics. Drinking in general is bad for you.

Many people affected by alcohol negatively aren't alcoholics

Most are still alchoholics soo.

&gt;Because it's against the law (and teachers are professionally obligated to follow it), outside of school regulations, and considered disruptive.

Which Is why I'm saying it should apply to religion to reduce harm

&gt;You bring a book extolling the virtues of alcohol though, nobody bats an eye. 

Are you bringing in the book to teach about how good alchohol is?

&gt;help perpetuate a culture and industry that kills millions.

Most of which that affects themselves.

&gt;Precisely. And it doesn't really matter what the knock on or wider societal effects are right?

More like you cant really control every individual character.

&gt;So, if somebody can drink, contribute to the wider social acceptability of drinking, and help perpetuate a clearly harmful practice, why shouldn't people be religious, contribute to the wider social acceptability of religion, even if it is a harmful practice?

I'm tired of repeating myself. They perpetuate the harmful practices but they are likely to suffer from it the most!. The alchoholic is the one that will die from liver failure. Not the innocent kid on the block

Religion however can do just that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43252656791.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The law is the only reason we dont see more kids being alchoholic. People steal eventhough they are laws against stealing. It just isnt as bad in the absence of laws.


Seems that the best thing to prevent kids being alcoholic would be to...stop selling alcohol.


&gt;Because I literally said earlier that if harms yourself or most likely to harm yourself then I dont care.


So the people who arent the perpetrators who are harmed are what, collateral damage?




&gt;Most are still alchoholics soo.


Theyre not. Alcoholism is a subset of problem drinking.


&gt;Which Is why I'm saying it should apply to religion to reduce harm


So you wish to make the exercise of religion among minors illegal? How?


&gt;Are you bringing in the book to teach about how good alchohol is?


Given I havent been in school for a while, doubtful. Would you take the book away from the kid?



&gt;More like you cant really control every individual character.


Course you can. Ban the production, distribution and sale of alcohol. Make it a source of societal shame. Create a culture where drinking of any kind is seen as backwards, harmful and primitive. 



&gt;I'm tired of repeating myself. They perpetuate the harmful practices but they are likely to suffer from it the most!. 



And I am also repeating myself **why does that matter**?


Using your logic a *million* innocent people could suffer and die, children included from alcohol spurred neglect, abuse, and accidents, but all thats ok if **two million** alcohol abusers die.


You see how that sounds?





Not to mention the alcoholic was an innocent kid on the block at one point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258519437.0" user="Sandy_hook_lemy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Seems that the best thing to prevent kids being alcoholic would be to...stop selling alcohol.

To kids? I can completely agree and we already have laws for that. Ofc some people still break it but which law isnt? Point is that the law has reduced the times It happens.

&gt;So the people who arent the perpetrators who are harmed are what, collateral damage?

Victims?

&gt;Theyre not. Alcoholism is a subset of problem drinking.

Taking a drink once a month isnt giving you alchohol poisoning or making you drunk drive.

&gt;So you wish to make the exercise of religion among minors illegal? How?

Banning religious practices?

&gt;Given I havent been in school for a while, doubtful. Would you take the book away from the kid?

Umm yea? 

&gt;Course you can. Ban the production, distribution and sale of alcohol. Make it a source of societal shame. Create a culture where drinking of any kind is seen as backwards, harmful and primitive.

Again, mostly harms yourself to I dont care about it.

&gt;And I am also repeating myself why does that matter?

Because it's your freedom to do what you want with your life?

&gt;Using your logic a million innocent people could suffer and die, children included from alcohol spurred neglect, abuse, and accidents, but all thats ok if two million alcohol abusers die

Well yeaa. Murder or perpetuating harm on someone is several times worse than perpetuating harm on yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43259524878.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; To kids?




To anyone. 

&gt;Victims?


Exactly. Why allow these victims to exist?

&gt;Taking a drink once a month isnt giving you alchohol poisoning or making you drunk drive.


But it is harmful to people. And allowing it to exist allows it to harm more people.





&gt;Banning religious practices?


How? You're going to penalize a kid for praying? 



&gt;Umm yea?


On what grounds?

&gt;Again, mostly harms yourself to I dont care about it.



And again, perpetuating the prooiferation of alcohol hurts more than you.


Why is it that you treat religion as a social phenomenon  but treat the acceptance of alcohol as an individual one?



&gt;What does this even mean? I just said Murder or perpetuating harm on someone is several times worse than perpetuating harm on yourself.



It is. I am saying that is a practice in aggregate also hurts people other than yourself, even if it mainly hurts the perpetrator. And the fact that it hurts other people to a significant extent seems like it should be unacceptable wholesale.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243960151.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>Problem is religious people influence politics regardless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244020887.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Well they can't do so using religious arguments. If they want to advance something, they must do so using non-religious arguments, even if they are religious themselves. 

What you're advocating for is tantamount to eliminating/prohibiting religion altogether, which is not only impossible, but could only be attempted through authoritarian means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244296069.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Well they can't do so using religious arguments. If they want to advance something, they must do so using non-religious arguments, even if they are religious themselves.

You must see how contradictory to real life this statement is especially in the US in recent years. Sky daddy twats continuously use "moral stances" to advance religious agendas into politics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244352599.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Again, to the extent that the argument goes "because of god", its not valid. Even the most fervent religious nuts need to come up with a non-religious argument for anything they want to advance. 

If you want to eliminate religion altogether as an underlying motivation, then you'd have to eliminate religio  entirely, which, again, is impossible and can only be attempted through authoritarian means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244502762.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Again, to the extent that the argument goes "because of god", its not valid. Even the most fervent religious nuts need to come up with a non-religious argument for anything they want to advance.

Do they though? Like with abortion or trans people most of what they pass and vote for comes from "moral stances". Or what about religious groups funding politics?  

&gt;If you want to eliminate religion altogether as an underlying motivation, then you'd have to eliminate religio  entirely, which, again, is impossible and can only be attempted through authoritarian means.

If we can't fully eliminate it then we should limit it as much as possible in the public sphere and that's what France did. You will not be able to fully eliminate the cults from the community but you can try and make them as fringe a motivation as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244562985.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>For something like abortion, the arguments being put forth is that the fetus has a life of its own. That's not a stance that you need to be religious to have (although if your religion says that all unborn count as life, then you'll adhere to it). The argumentation itself is non religious. You can't pass a law because it says so in the bible.

Besides, talking about underlying religious pretexts is besides the point. The things public officials wear are surface level. If you want to talk about underlying beliefs, then what you really seem to be arguing for is that religious people should be banned from holding office, which is a whole other kettle of fish. 

&gt;If we can't fully eliminate it then we should limit it as much as possible in the public sphere

You can do that. You can do anything if you have enough power. Just don't pretend it's not an authoritarian thing to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245276567.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For something like abortion, the arguments being put forth is that the fetus has a life of its own. That's not a stance that you need to be religious to have (although if your religion says that all unborn count as life, then you'll adhere to it). The argumentation itself is non religious. You can't pass a law because it says so in the bible.

The argument did and has historically sprung up from religious people and their understanding of religious texts and that's why I mentioned it in particular. 

&gt;Besides, talking about underlying religious pretexts is besides the point. The things public officials wear are surface level. If you want to talk about underlying beliefs, then what you really seem to be arguing for is that religious people should be banned from holding office, which is a whole other kettle of fish.

If I could, I would definitely think of banning them from holding office based on the grounds of mental instability (sky daddy shit is insane) but I would not because they are a good chunk of the population, that's not very democratic and we would lose as a collective society a ton of benefits from the extra ideas. What I would do is truly make them separate their religion from their posts in public office by banning them from showing their faith during public affairs.

&gt;You can do that. You can do anything if you have enough power. Just don't pretend it's not an authoritarian thing to do.

Fuck, then everything is authoritarian. The government telling you to not drink and drive is authoritarian even though you are a danger to everyone else on the road.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245311938.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If I could, I would definitely think of banning them from holding office based on the grounds of mental instability (sky daddy shit is insane) but I would not because they are a good chunk of the population, that's not very democratic and we would lose as a collective society a ton of benefits from the extra ideas.

So close. You almost got there.

&gt;Fuck, then everything is authoritarian. The government telling you to not drink and drive is authoritarian even though you are a danger to everyone else on the road.

We've been at this for hours and you still have not given a single example, even a hypothetical one, of how someone in office wearing a cross or a hijab would cause harm to anyone, or how you would draw a straight line between them wearing something and them proposing some law that favors their religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245382369.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So close. You almost got there.

Nope I did get there. I would not ban them outright, I would ban them from representing their faith while representing the people as that would not be what the government is supposed to do. That's not truly secular and I would actually like to enforce that.

&gt;We've been at this for hours and you still have not given a single example, even a hypothetical one, of how someone in office wearing a cross or a hijab would cause harm to anyone, or how you would draw a straight line between them wearing something and them proposing some law that favors their religion.

It's more of a "You're supposed to be a government official representing a secular government, not a religious faith while in office" deal. And with how poisonous and infectious religion can get I'd rather my officials not have religious symbolism on them while in office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245432059.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I'd rather my officials not have religious symbolism on them while in office.

"I'd rather not" is not a good enough reason to deny someone a basic civil right in a democratic society. It sound to me like you'd prefer some kind of benevolent dictatorship. 

&gt;Nope I did get there. I would not ban them outright, I would ban them from representing their faith while representing the people as that would not be what the government is supposed to do. That's not truly secular and I would actually like to enforce that

They are representing their voters, who voted them into office knowing their religion. Wearing something does not make you a "representative" of that faith, just a member of one. 

I'm an atheist, and I abhor religious influence in politics, but I'm also a big fan of democratic values, and you're shitting all over a basic one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250293456.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Now Muslim girls don't go to school.


Secularism win?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43243954559.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;France is wrong to ban hijabs, it oversteps the "wall of separation" between religion and state.

Isn't that for public officials? That seems to be enforcing the separation of religion and state by saying "Hey, since you represent the state in your capacity, you can't wear religious garments".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244009512.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>And in schools.

Even for public officials though, it's wrong to ban it. The separation deals with the establishment of policy or favoritism towards a religion. 

Infringing on any individual's ability to express their faith is an overstep by the government, its not a secular thing to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244337449.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And in schools.

There might be an argument in schools so long as no taxpayer money goes into funding religious activity of any sort in schooling (and that probably why people are pissed about prayer rooms).

&gt;Even for public officials though, it's wrong to ban it. The separation deals with the establishment of policy or favoritism towards a religion.

Nope, so long as the separation affects all religions I think it's alright. I'm paying you with my taxpayer money to represent the government in a secular manner then I expect you to not take any religious stance in your clothing while you are in office.

It's harsh but this limits have to be put in place because religious people are horrible when there isn't a measure of control to keep state and religion separate. 

&gt;Infringing on any individual's ability to express their faith is an overstep by the government, its not a secular thing to do.

Not while in public office. To me, that separation trumps the religious ability to express their faith in office or during official hours. It's a very secular thing to do if you are actually enforcing secularism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244444963.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;To me, that separation trumps the religious ability to express their faith in office or during official hours. It's a very secular thing to do if you are actually enforcing secularism.

Except it's not a separation, then is it? A separation is not unilaterally. It's I don't tell you what to do, and you don't tell me what to do.   Not I don't tell you what to do, and you ban me from expressing my religion. 

That's not a separation, nor is it secular (seeing as how secularism means separation)

&gt;I'm paying you with my taxpayer money to represent the government in a secular manner, and I expect you to not take any religious stance in your clothing while you are in office.

They are elected by whoever their constituents are, or appointed by those elected to office, and you don't get to tell people what to wear. Plenty of officeholders I'd love to get rid of using the excuse of "my taxes pay your salary", but that's not how things work.  

If they are not using their official position to advance religious beliefs (and no, wearing a cross or a hinab does not constiture advancing a belief or a policy based on a belief), then it's none of our fucking business what they choose to wear. 

&gt;religious people are horrible

Many are, most are not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244650475.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Except it's not a separation, then is it? A separation is,  BY DEFINITION, bilateral: It's "I don't tell you what to do, and you don't tell me what to do". It is not " I don't tell you what to do, but you get to ban me from expressing my religion".

Nope, it's a separation between state and religion. We are separating all (as many as possible) aspects of religion from state functions. One of the state's functions is to represent as many people as possible and religious symbols interrupt that principle in public office. 

So it's more like "I don't tell you what to worship as a state but you don't worship while in charge of state functions because you report to your people who have decided that that is the way it is".

&gt;They are elected by whoever their constituents are, or appointed by those elected to office, and you don't get to tell people what to wear. Plenty of officeholders I'd love to get rid of using the excuse of "my taxes pay your salary", but that's not how things work.

Oh but you should be in charge and have a say in how the government is using your money. Now while you can't expressly get rid of people in office, that's because all members of that constituency voted in that person. 

Now in a matter affecting everyone like religion vs democratic state, democratic state wins out because the state is supposed to reflect the people and one of the most important pillars of that state is complete (or as complete as possible) separation of religion from public office and the running of the government. 

Thus logically this would also extend to the wardrobe people wear in office during office hours as they represent the community not the faith during that time.

&gt;If they are not using their official position to advance religious beliefs (and no, wearing a cross or a hijab does not constiture advancing a belief or a policy based on a belief), then it's none of our fucking business what they choose to wear.

But it is as it's part of the representation of the people. Especially since wearing religious items can constitute or be seen as trying to advance religious beliefs over others which is what secularism is against. 

&gt;Many are, most are not.

History has shown me that I'd rather not take that chance and would much rather the state take firm action against religion than pussyfoot around it and end up in a state like Iran or have religious violence like Sweden had a while ago or the many, many other times religious people have done stupid shit because of their sky daddy issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244751005.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We are separating all (as many as possible) aspects of religion from state functions. One of the state's functions is to represent as many people as possible and religious symbols interrupt that principle in public office. 

Yes, the *functions* must be separated of course, but you'd have an incredibly difficult time trying to explain how wearing a cross necklace constitutes a function of government, or how they interrupt the function of government in *any way whatsoever* beyond just pissing off people like you. 

&gt;but you don't worship while in charge of state functions because you report to your people who have decided that that is the way it is".

If it doesn't bleed into the actual policy, it does not matter what or who they worship. That's lunacy. 

Anyone with enough power can "decide that is the way it is", doesn't make it compatible with the principles of free democracy.

&gt;Now in a matter affecting everyone like religion vs democratic state, democratic state wins out because the state is supposed to reflect the people and one of the most important pillars of that state is complete (or as complete as possible) separation of religion from public office and the running of the government. 

You're setting up a false dichotomy. Banning people from wearing a hijab or a cross is not a victory of the state over religion, because the state was not threatened by it. It would have no effect on the *actual policy*. 

I agree that the separation of religion and state should be absolute, that is not the same thing as saying that noone in government should be religious. You're cutting out a massive segment of the population from representation if that is the case.

&gt;But it is as it's part of the representation of the people. Especially since wearing religious items can constitute or be seen as trying to advance religious beliefs over others which is what secularism is against. 

Wearing a religious symbol in your daily life, on your person, is just not "advancing" religion in the sense of spreading it, or its ideas. Its just something you wear as a member of that faith. Secularism is the prevention of religion from being part of public policy, its not the elimination of religious life. This is just a poor understanding of the concept.

&gt;History has shown me that I'd rather not take that chance and would much rather the state take firm action against religion than pussyfoot around it and end up in a state like Iran or have religious violence like Sweden had a while ago or the many, many other times religious people have done stupid shit because of their sky daddy issues.

The state can take "firm action" if it wants, very firm action. Again, doesn't mean it's not an authoritarian thing to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245222990.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Yes, the functions must be separated of course, but you'd have an incredibly difficult time trying to explain how wearing a cross necklace constitutes a function of government, or how they interrupt the function of government in any way whatsoever beyond just pissing off people like you.

Like I said one of the functions of government is representation of the people in a secular manner and these symbols interrupt that. If you are in public office then you are a representative of the state and the state is secular. If you want to be religious that's fine but not during public office hours. Some things officials can't do as society has elevated them to the position of public representative and this should be one of them. 

&gt;If it doesn't bleed into the actual policy, it does not matter what or who they worship. That's lunacy.

Exactly so they should keep it to themselves while in public office and by that they shouldn't wear anything that represents a certain cult. They are a neutral party representing the people. 

&gt;Anyone with enough power can "decide that is the way it is", doesn't make it compatible with the principles of free democracy.

Free democracy has decided that state (and everything regarding the state) and religion should be kept separate. Thus no religion as much as possible in all state affairs including religious values and representation.

&gt;You're setting up a false dichotomy. Banning people from wearing a hijab or a cross is not a victory of the state over religion, because the state was not threatened by it. It would have no effect on the actual policy.

No that's not a false dichotomy because there are actual examples of the state being threatened by religious forces throughout history like in Iran for instance. No one is banning people from wearing a cross or a hijab period, the state is banning wearing those **items during state affairs and hours.** 

Now if you wanted to talk about how France wanted to ban wearing the hijab in public in general we might agree on government overreach but if you are holding a public office there are certain responsibilities you have and one of them is to be a true representation of the secular state.

&gt;I agree that the separation of religion and state should be absolute, that is not the same thing as saying that noone in government should be religious. You're cutting out a massive segment of the population from representation if that is the case.

I never said they should be cut out. I said that they should check their religion at the door during public representation at work hours. For example a congressman can still be deeply religious but once they enter the house of Congress that shit should be left at the door. **You are a representative of a secular state so act like it.**

&gt;Wearing a religious symbol in your daily life, on your person, is just not "advancing" religion in the sense of spreading it, or its ideas. Its just something you wear as a member of that faith. 

No, you are representing those ideas and that would be different it was just a random joe but if you are in government, you have more responsibilities and greater societal impact than others. Thus you should not represent those ideas during public governmental affairs, simple as that.

&gt;Secularism is the prevention of religion from being part of public policy, its not the elimination of religious life. This is just a poor understanding of the concept.

Nope, this is the true full realization of the concept without taking any liberties for any religion.

&gt;The state can take "firm action" if it wants, very firm action. Again, doesn't mean it's not an authoritarian thing to do.

There's a difference between completely banning religion and banning religious affairs and garments while one is in public office (with their private lives being unaffected) and is currently representing the people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245294020.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Like I said one of the functions of government is representation of the people in a secular manner and these symbols interrupt that. 

Representing them in a secular way just means not letting religion infiltrate policy. Anything beyond that is beyond the realm of secularism. 

&gt;If you are in public office then you are a representative of the state

Actually, you're a representative of the people who elected you to office.

&gt;No that's not a false dichotomy because there are actual examples of the state being threatened by religious forces throughout history like in Iran for instance. No one is banning people from wearing a cross or a hijab period, the state is banning wearing those items during state affairs and hours. 

? Iran is a theocracy. It did not become that way because some people were wearing hijabs and it snowballed. That's just not relevant in any way to this discussion.  

&gt;You are a representative of a secular state so act like it.

*Not letting religion influence policy IS acting like it. That's it.* 

If you tick THAT box, you're secular, no matter what you choose to wear. That's just the way it is, you're doing mental gymnastics trying to add more to the definition. 

&gt;No, you are representing those ideas and that would be different it was just a random joe but if you are in government, you have more responsibilities and greater societal impact than others.

You're not "representing" those ideas, you're merely showing that YOU believe them, not that anyone else should, not that anyone else will be made to, not that your beliefs about it will influence anything else. 

&gt;For example a congressman can still be deeply religious but once they enter the house of Congress that shit should be left at the door.

Yes, it should. Them wearing a cross doesn't mean they have not left it at the door, as long as they're not advocating for it in policy. 

You keep dancing around this point. 

&gt;Nope, this is the true full realization of the concept without taking any liberties for any religion.

No, actually it isn't. Secularism is bilateral by definition,  full stop. What you're advocating for is something else entirely, but it isn't secularism. It's just religious elimination. 

Secularism is something else. 


&gt;There's a difference between completely banning religion and banning religious affairs and garments while one is in public office (with their private lives being unaffected) and is currently representing the people.

Religious *affairs* can and should be banned from government. Religious *garments* are not religious affairs. And to the extent that some people MUST wear those garments, what you are saying is that members of that religion cannot be in government, even if nothing they would do would show preference to their religion. 

It's still authoritarian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245406921.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>I've realized we will never agree on this topic no matter what and you'll defend the religious even though it's not truly secular as they are still representing their faith in their office and that's against what government is supposed to do. So I'm out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245446366.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not to blame for the fact that you misunderstand the basic principle of secularism.

It's a *wall of separation*, one does not influence the other, full stop. 

See ya.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250294720.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Its also for schoolchildren.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43253119724.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>That I can't agree with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
