<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="116" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43264121846.0" user="mehra_mora55" delta="False">
    <text>Here my comment was deleted, in which it was written that students should not be forbidden to wear crosses, hijabs and other religious attributes, since this is part of their personality, I don’t know why they did it.  
  
I just wanted to add that I have read comments that say that the prayer room is just a room where Muslims can pray if they want to. To be honest, at first I thought that the "prayer room" is a place where students are taken to pray, regardless of their desire, as part of some school activities.  
  
Actually, I don't see anything wrong with that. If a student does not want to pray, then he simply will not go there. If he wants to, he will do it anyway, only without a room it will probably take place in some inappropriate place. Religion should not be forced by the school, but forbidding students to be religious is wrong.  
  
The author also writes that France forbids wearing hijabs, and this does not outrage anyone, but firstly, it probably outrages Muslims, and secondly, it, for example, outrages me, because it is stupid to forbid wearing any part of clothing. In my culture, women may wear headscarves in different situations when they go to church, or if it is cold or hot outside, or if they are visiting the forest.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
