<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="83" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43240600128.0" user="These_Library3215" delta="False">
    <text>I believe public schools should be religiously neutral; neither supporting nor opposing any religious viewpoint. That would imply permitting students and staff to freely express any religion they may hold and practice it without restraint. Accommodating this requires prayer rooms and acceptance of religious attire.
What Quebec is doing is not religious neutrality, but state atheism, as they are implicitly promoting the non-religious viewpoint and suppressing all others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254904761.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254904814.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/USA_Ball – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
