<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="82" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43240216051.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>Yes OP you ate right especially those high demand conservatives. They want EVERYONE to conform to their religion and that is just dumb.
I'm sure they would feel the same way if we were trying to force something they feel is every bit as abhorrent as we feel that their religion is. 
Why do WE have to follow their rules when we don't believe what they believe??
Organized religion is just crap now we have all kinds of loonies passing on whatever they will and call it a religion. And the good ones never call them out for their false prophets ENOUGH!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43254963214.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>🤡</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255724764.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>Bahaha the only ones who don't know their clowns is the conservative republican cultists... your 1 opinion vs 4 opinions that trump is guilty and will not vote for him. That why your party is dying and no matter who you put forth will lose. America has had it with republican bullshit lmao I can't wait til you emotional people start realizing it... it will be AMAZING!!!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255826006.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not a Republican but go off dude</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256082912.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>Frankly idc what you are. Trump humpers comes in all shapes and sizes. Either way it makes no difference to me dude</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256241744.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how politics ties into this. It's the basic human right to freely practice your religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43258574676.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>Conservatives have put their mark on it. We have a HUGE issue with CONSERVATIVE high demand religions that are rampant with abuse! They don't care if they abuse women and children only that they stump for them politically AND donate. The republicans in America have a huge hard on for money and power and no longer care about ALL Americans just their party only. And no to mention it is the conservatives who have waged war on public schools. Their schools get public school funds which takes away the public schools budget. Esp here in AZ we have the stupid voucher system and we also rank 45 in American education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43259043542.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>That's crazy but I still don't know how a basic human right relates to politics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43255874553.0" user="USA_Ball" delta="False">
    <text>I mean honestly I'll probably vote Republican in the next election(I'm a swing voter) but I'm trying to figure out where politics plays into the human right to practice religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43256070569.0" user="Either_Operation7586" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, only people who are trump humpers would lol. Anyone else is going to vote for the party that is NOT infatuated with Huter Bidens dick nor legislate WITHOUT wasting taxpayers' money! And just look at ALL the evidence against trump and the indictment... they just deny it. History will not be kind to you trump humpers hahaha and I am soooo here for it!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
