<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="47" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43237893014.0" user="Scrungyscrotum" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;[...].no caps that jewish people wear (Sorry I don't know how to spell it).

First of all, "Jew cap" is a derogatory term. Secondly, googling "Jew cap" will give you the correct spelling of the proper term. Pretty ironic that you complain about something you believe corrupts the education of youngsters, when your ingenious atheistic self seems to have been absent when they taught fundamental information sourcing. 

Now, to the meat of it: Are you fucking retarded? How could you possibly argue against religious expression, which I assume you find primitive and oppressive (correct me if it's for a different reason), and in the same breath argue against human rights? You know that freedom of religion is a human right according to the UN, right? Banning the right to express one's religion in a way that does not harm others is a very, very dangerous premise. 

As long as they don't violate others' rights, we have the moral obligation to allow anyone to practice their beliefs freely and in an unrestricted manner. If you're offended by a cross on someone's neck, that's kind of a you problem. 

It's also very impractical. You know that you can't force someone to stop believing by forcing "facts" and "logic" down their throat, right? Those who abandon their religion usually go through a very intimate process that they have to lead themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245572251.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
