<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236977529.0" user="schrutefarmbeet" delta="False">
    <text>“Jew hats” 🫥</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238231465.0" user="Caracalla81" delta="False">
    <text>I did nazi that part.  He must have edited.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238897983.0" user="firefury605" delta="False">
    <text>He clarified that he doesn't know how to spell the word for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239015256.0" user="Mu-Relay" delta="False">
    <text>It's too bad that there's not some worldwide search tool at their fingertips that could help them. For giggles, I googled "jew hats" and it gave me the spelling of Yarmulke as the second result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239048785.0" user="firefury605" delta="False">
    <text>Bro sometimes people just take the lazy route if we know our message will get across either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239087030.0" user="Doctor__Proctor" delta="False">
    <text>And even most people I've seen don't bristle at "Yamaka" or something, because at least there's an attempt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238984223.0" user="TheRealTravisClous" delta="False">
    <text>I love attending my annual jew meetings just to get the new hats /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240642047.0" user="Curunis" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe he was talking about the [judenhut](https://communityflavorpack.fidercdn.com/static/images/attachments/8p2L9cd1QJw0O0uDYHlLS8spBgLBk4bLl35WMxiuxEoEnv2VlYN8HOCcaTGGAww4-images.png?size=200) all along? 

/s in case it wasn't clear ofc</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
