<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="105" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43244931866.0" user="kwamzilla" delta="False">
    <text>Can you clarify what would be needd to change your view?

Just on prayer rooms:

* This then means those students need to find alternative spaces for this, meaning it's more disruptive to their learning
* They may not be safe in alternative spaces and it's likely more disruptive to have children finding spaces to pray (if they do)
* For more fundamentalist families, this may create tension and lead to the children being widthdrawn and potentially even radicalised
* This legitimises attacks/ridicule etc on said students in the eyes of those with bigoted views already
* It can further amplify "othering" 

&amp;#x200B;

Yes some of those might be a bit "slippery slope"-y/extreme but these things do happen. Especially in areas where those children might be a minority.

And we can differentiate between a cross necklace and a hijab or even a turban as one is an actual article of faith while the other is just someththing that a person wants as an extra, outward display of faith. (Yes there's nuance but it is unfair and bad faith to compare requirements to optional displays).

Also, plenty of people who's opinions matter are still pretty outraged about the French decision. It's incredibly dismissive - and perhaps shows a degree of unconscious bias - to suggest that the many people who feel strongly about it's opinions "don't matter".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
