<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236526350.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Doing that wouldn’t prepare kids for the real world. It would be better to teach every religion, and say this is what various people in the world believe, and some don’t believe in anything. Pick what works for you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236532442.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>You teach about religion, but keep it out of the schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236554446.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Where are kids supposed to learn about other religions ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236558296.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>School.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236563584.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>What are you even talking about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236750462.0" user="RusticMachine" delta="False">
    <text>He’s not against teaching religion in schools, he’s against practicing religion in schools.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236953854.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>And practically how are you going to stop someone from doing something in their head?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238165980.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>It seems OP is against having  designated spaces at school  for it, not what happens in your head that no one knows about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238244172.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>What’s the difference? Same action and unless you go into a prayer room you don’t see them pray</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239311334.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>I think their issue is with turning a public space (secular classroom) into a religious space.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239416706.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>They’re not in the classroom, it’s another room, a prayer ROOM.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239547580.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>Right, a room in a secular school dedicated to a religious practice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239573304.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>And what’s bad about that? It’s like a religious building in a secular city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239581462.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think cities are secular, are they? My kids' school is secular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239791747.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Depends if your country has a state religion. How is the school secular, but not the city?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239826413.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>The public school system where I live is 100% secular, but you can choose to send your kids to a religious school if you want religion in the classroom. The city has no such requirement (you have to follow/practice X religion to live here).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239864866.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>And what does the room do if any one can go there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240136835.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>That wasn't your question though. Your question was how can a school be secular if the city is not. I explained that where I live if you want religion in school, you have the choice to choose a religious school. If you don't want religion, you choose the public program.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240166092.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>So only rich religious kids then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240198807.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>Religious school where I am is free (subsidized), so no. It would cost me the extact same to send my kids to Catholic school or Public School.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240016050.0" user="WARNING_Username2Lon" delta="False">
    <text>He is also against students wearing hijabs to school. Or kippahs. Or any religious garb.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240140362.0" user="janearcade" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't respond to that because I didn't see it, only that that they said classroom in a secular school shouldn't be converted to prayer rooms.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
