<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236978724.0" user="automatic_mismatch" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; no hijabs

I know this not the main point of the post but forcing people to show part of their body they feel is private is really gross.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43240791434.0" user="exum23" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah , I am at a loss.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43241839507.0" user="Rs3account" delta="False">
    <text>This is the first time I heard this argument. Thank you for sharing it. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43270698320.0" user="bastothebasto" delta="False">
    <text>It's a shitty argument that rests on manipulating words to make it seem worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43270709516.0" user="bastothebasto" delta="False">
    <text>It's a non-argument that rests on this type of negative phrasing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43244012361.0" user="BeastPunk1" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, you got me. I despise religion but you got me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43250316489.0" user="Coolshirt4" delta="False">
    <text>Mfw President Quinten Tarentino banns socks and closed toe shoes 😔😔😔</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
