<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236508286.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;no jew hats

Jesus Christ dude. 

People who aren't extremely authoritarian understand that making reasonable accommodations for religious practices is essential to ensure freedom of expression. Allowing prayer in dedicated spaces on site is a reasonable accommodation.

Why are you opposed to freedom of expression?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236516600.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not, but just because I support it doesn't mean you can do it anywhere. Wanna practice religion? Do it on your own time. Check the reddit threads on this issue, people saying what you're saying got downvoted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236624121.0" user="SleepBeneathThePines" delta="False">
    <text>Arguments aren’t right just because they’re popular though. Reddit may just be full of idiots.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236655645.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>The whole point of the dedicated spaces is to provide a place to pray on your own time. You also mentioned banning religious symbols but you didn't address that part of freedom of expression. How can you say you're not opposed to freedom of expression if you're in favor of banning religious symbols?

Why do I care what Reddit says by the way? Reddit could just as easily be opposed to freedom of expression in the same way you are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236668714.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Let me put it to you like this. I support the right for you to protest, but I'm not gonna met you hold one in my bathroom. Time and place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236684194.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>It appears you're implying two things both of which don't make much sense.

1. You're implying here that you personally own the public schools in Quebec. I assure you, you do not.

2. The government doesn't have to respect freedom off expression. I assure you, it does outside of authoritarian hell holes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237038942.0" user="zerowangtwo" delta="False">
    <text>You *might* have a slightly better argument if compulsory education wasn't a thing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236695794.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;check Reddit threads on this issue, people saying what you’re saying get downvoted

This is probably the single worst heuristic out there. Redditors are fucking stupid, especially when it comes to religion, law, politics, philosophy, science, mathematics, basic hygiene, taste, relationship advice…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236811816.0" user="Womblue" delta="False">
    <text>This is actually hilarious lol, "I'm right because the people who said what you said got downvoted in a different thread"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237365117.0" user="ToranjaNuclear" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Check the reddit threads on this issue, people saying what you're saying got downvoted.

Ironic since you're being downvoted to hell on your own thread lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237186222.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Because religion is divisive and polarizing, especially nowadays.   That expression can lead to problems.  Has no place in the school</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237312318.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I do not believe it is true that practicing one's religion by oneself is divisive and polarizing. 

I do believe that religious expression can lead to problems but only when the expression comes in the form of insisting that someone who doesn't follow the religion performs a religious practice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237882327.0" user="KosherSushirrito" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like people who have a negative reaction to any religious expression are the problem here, rather than the religious individual.

Religion will be in schools, because students have a religion whether you like it or not. The least we can do is accommodate them to a reasonable degree so that everyone receives the same level of education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238323100.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly I just want it completely gone to piss off conservatives.  Otherwise I can care less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238446464.0" user="KosherSushirrito" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Honestly I just want it completely gone to piss off conservatives

Have you ever considered that, when describing the polarization caused by religion, you're really just describing yourself, and are unwilling to consider yourself as the problem?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238474040.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Nah.  Fuck that.  Just need the conservatives to go</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239055582.0" user="KosherSushirrito" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Nah

Speaks for itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239182204.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>Shhhhh.

I’m basking in my awesomeness and you’re ruining the vibes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239445512.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245586100.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238568039.0" user="Independent_Sea_836" delta="False">
    <text>So you're willing to make children feel uncomfortable and unwelcome in school, during a time that is already taxing on their mental state, just to piss off people you don't agree with? Does that sound familiar to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238772102.0" user="Terrible_Lift" delta="False">
    <text>It not being able to pray makes a child feel that uncomfortable the parents have caused a problem already</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238871342.0" user="Independent_Sea_836" delta="False">
    <text>So your solution is to punish a child for their parents' actions?

You know that parents don't get to choose to not send their children to school, right? And that not everyone can afford private schools? So really, it's mostly children from low-income families that are being punished. 

In addition, Jewish and Muslim private schools aren't nearly as common as Christian private schools. So that narrows the options even more for religious children that aren't part of the majority religion. 

So it seems to me that all this does is hurt poor and minority families.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43245584870.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43527080342.0" user="Maleficent-Drummer19" delta="False">
    <text>So is politics and sports</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237439613.0" user="sluuuurp" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously, OP thinks it would make them look too considerate if they googled “Jew hats” and instead used the actual word. They’re proud of their ignorance and want to share it with all of us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237473029.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>Why people are still practicing bigoted and hateful, barbaric ideas from the past? why we let parents to brainwash and groom their children into a cult? religions server zero purpose in modern word, they belong to the past, they should be forgotten.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237643300.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why people are still practicing bigoted and hateful, barbaric ideas from the past?

Because historically not letting people practice bigoted and hateful, barbaric ideas (so long as they do not infringe upon the rights of others) has had worse outcomes for society. 

&gt;why we let parents to brainwash and groom their children into a cult?

Because historically not allowing parents to brainwash and groom their children into a cult has had worse outcomes for society.

&gt;religions server zero purpose in modern world , they belong to the past, they should be forgotten.

Religious people obviously disagree and that is an opinion. Most religions that have ever been do belong to the past. 

Even if they are forgotten new religions would arise to replace them. It is better to learn of all religions to draw the obvious conclusion that no specific religion is true. Many people are simply incapable of not believing in "higher power(s)".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237753119.0" user="Drakayne" delta="False">
    <text>What history? most of the western countries are in a far better place because they became more secular and they distanced themselves from religion, just look at Europe and north America and compare it to the middle east. and some of them (western countries) actually are  becoming worse (like Sweden that i live in) because of religion and some of the immigrants that are bringing thier bigoted religions to the civilization and force it to people and commit terror acts. (and before you even accuse me of racism, I'm a middle eastern immigrant, quite ironic, right?) , you have no idea what you talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237793546.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; What history?

We can take pretty much any time in history up to literally today and we can find extreme religious persecution. It simply happens.
&gt;most of the western countries are in a far better place because they became more secular and they distanced themselves from religion

I don't disagree whatsoever but you must understand that it is important this happens naturally and that it must not be imposed upon the population via government intervention. 

&gt;some of them (western countries) actually are becoming worse (like Sweden that i live in) because of religion

You're scapegoating religion. If it wasn't religion people would find other reasons to be shitty. 

&gt;some of the immigrants that are bringing thier bigoted religions to the civilization and force it to people and commit terror acts

This isn't a thing. I mean terrorism is a thing but you literally cannot force someone to be in a religion in any western country (honestly anywhere that isn't a theocratic state). 

&gt;you have no idea what you talking about.

Well luckily I don't care whether you believe I know what I'm talking about or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237981523.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>My take is-- and this is more a of a US perspective, so Canada might come by it some other way-- the religious protections are there mostly because if _everyone_ doesn't get _some_ leeway to go on with their fervent but ill-founded woo-woo shit, then one particular brand of fervent but ill-founded woo-woo shit is liable to start strongarming everyone else into buying their brand. It's not so much that the fervent but ill-founded woo-woo shit is _right_ or even _necessary_, just that the fervency leads people to heinous ends to press it and the ill-foundedness makes it hard to argue a definitive conclusion to settle the matter, so it's better to just let the people have theirs and normalize tolerance so that any one trying to steamroll the others is taboo.

Basically, religion is here, it's tenaciously held, and you're more liable to impose the strongest one than eliminate it entirely by trying to force it out, so keeping the pressure-relief valves open and the temperature low is the least-worst option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238419804.0" user="apophis-pegasus" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Why people are still practicing bigoted and hateful, barbaric ideas from the past?



The same reason why people still drink alcohol. Because its part of their background and banning it didnt work.


&gt;why we let parents to brainwash and groom their children into a cult?


For one cult has a specific modern meaning, and for another the same reason why we let parents drink in front of kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43237887348.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Why are you opposed to freedom of expression?

Because that's not OP you're asking. It seems you've taken to interrogating the cardboard cutout of an "extremely authoritarian" person you stood up.

If you're going to try and ram that "extremely authoritarian" shoe on OP, you've got to at least spell out how it fits, not just set it up with "I've *totally* worked it out off-screen that this is authoritarian and opposing free expression" then knocking it down with "So why are you so against free expression, OP?".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43238601416.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I've totally worked it out off-screen that this is opposing free expression and extreme authoritarianism is the only justification a person could have

I'm curious as to what you think it is OP is advocating for if it isn't precisely this? Because if I could summarize it I would use this exact sentence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43239981593.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>Re-reading it, I realize I was focusing on the "No prayer rooms" CMV topic and missed the key paragraph you were referring to regarding the "No religious accoutrements" idea. (Old Reddit on Mobile, so I didn't have it right in front of me to look back on). The prayer rooms issue alone wouldn't be authoritarian-- just a matter of accommodation or not-- and that's all I was thinking of, but re-reading all that bit about "No religious items allowed"... Yeah, if you're banning innocuous accessories, that's affirmative authoritarian.

My bad. Previous statement withdrawn.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
