<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="57" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43238372412.0" user="taleasoldastime96" delta="False">
    <text>How can you ask someone to leave a part of themselves at home? Would you make the same argument for workplaces? We’re here to work and not to practice our religion. We’re at the grocery store to shop and not to practice our religion. Pretty soon, you’re being asked to be an entirely different person when you’re at home than when you’re in public. But I don’t stop being a Christian when I leave my house or when I leave the church building. I am a Christian all the time, and to deny me the ability to practice that religion in public is to ask me to be someone that I’m not. 

Now I’m not going to bind that on someone else. If I pray at a table in a restaurant, I’m not going to ask the person next to me to join me. But I’m going to do it because it’s what I believe I should do. It doesn’t hurt anyone. I doubt anyone would even notice unless they looked over at my table. Are you going to tell a student that they can’t quietly pray to themselves for their lunch?

And of course this must be extended to all religions, up to and including the right to practice no religion at all. If someone wants to wear a hijab, I am not a Muslim but I will support their right to do so, just as I would hope that they would support my right to be a Christian. 

You get into dangerous territory when you ask people to give up a part of themselves while they’re in public. What does it hurt you if someone prays or wears a cross necklace? They’re not interfering with your life. They’re not asking you to participate. They’re merely being who they are.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
