<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43322918793.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>Would your view be any different if a good part of the press advocated for the opposite of what you agree with? If there were papers that advocated against human rights and to harm others under the guise of reporting the news? Or take your lynching example, how about if the papers reported on the lynchings from the point of view of advocating for the lynchings and calling for more? Would you still support those papers reporting in such a manner or would you rather they report on it as a disinterested third party as much as possible? The biggest problem with advocacy is one can advocate for anything, it certainly won’t always go your way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323614376.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If there were papers that advocated against human rights and to harm others under the guise of reporting the news?

They already do. That's why it's so important for us to take a stand. Evil prevails when good men do nothing.

&gt;Or take your lynching example, how about if the papers reported on the lynchings from the point of view of advocating for the lynchings and calling for more?

They basically did when they tried to be neutral. That's the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323966598.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>So you support papers that advocate for what you call evil? You think that kind of advocacy in support of evil should be prioritized with journalists as well?

They are not effectively the same thing. How can they both have been openly in support of lynchings and attempting to be objective? Failing while attempting to be objective is a far cry for openly advocating for a given position. I am asking if you would prefer if they had been openly in support of lynchings as in advocating for more lynchings?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43324231163.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So you support papers that advocate for what you call evil?

No, but if they can't be silenced, the next best thing is to advocate in the opposite direction.

&gt;Failing while attempting to be objective is a far cry for openly advocating for a given position.

It didn't help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43324263637.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>Would not the best thing be for journalists to do their best to report the news objectively rather than have teams that spew differing opinions about events based on their own views? Why not leave it for the editorials? 

You claimed it was the same thing. Are you walking that claim back now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43324711992.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Would not the best thing be for journalists to do their best to report the news objectively rather than have teams that spew differing opinions about events based on their own views?

How would you do that?

&gt;Why not leave it for the editorials? 

Fox admitted in court they're full of shit. It didn't seem to make a difference. 

&gt;You claimed it was the same thing. Are you walking that claim back now?

The result is the same. Lynch mobs don't need other people to be pro lynching. They just us to not oppose them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
