<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43329380979.0" user="katzvus" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think “objectivity” is really possible. Journalists will always have to make subjective judgments about what’s worth covering, which words to use, and so on. 

And I don’t think advocacy journalism is bad necessarily. It’s ok to have people offering their opinions. 

But I do think it’s valuable to have major news outlets that are striving for accuracy and fairness, without pushing some agenda. The goal of a traditional news outlet is to provide its readers / viewers with accurate information about important events. Advocates are not really trying to inform — they want to accomplish some other goal, like getting some policies enacted or helping one party attain power. 

That doesn’t mean the traditional outlets are perfect or even “objective.” But at least they aren’t deliberately trying to trick me or mislead me. So I like to read opinions too. But I do think it’s valuable to read outlets that are primarily trying to inform, not push an agenda.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
