<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43325395483.0" user="TheAlabamaJedi" delta="False">
    <text>There is so many things wrong with what your saying I don't know where to begin. 

First you have to respect your audience. If you don't you will lose credibility with everyone who isn't inclined to agree with you.

Then there is the moral an ethical concern.  A journalist isn't God. Journalists are not infallible. Journalists are wrong all the time. 

Once a Journalists decides to eschew objectivity they are operating off the premise that they are right and more importantly that they know better than their readers would if they trusted them with that information.  

Let me give an example of how this could go wrong.  The Montgomery riverboat brawl that recently made the knees.

Imagine if you can that there was not any video. A journalist who isn't being objective could describe it as this. 

"A large brawl broke out on the Montgomery River dock when. At one point the fighting had ended, but escalated even further once a group of black men aggressively approached a couple white guys and women on a boat. 

One particularly violent black man was assaulting defenseless white people by swing a large metal object at them.

One woman who had already be rendered unable to stand to a viscious and cruel blow to the head. 

Despite a police officer seeing the entire incident  involving the potentially lethal weapon and the man was not charged at the scene and afterward the Montgomery police only charged the black man with disturbing the police when it seemed like attempted murder or assault with s deadly weapon were other possible charges.

No other black people were charged with a crime:however, multiple white people were singled out by the Montgomery police and charged with assault."

Nothing in that theoretical story is a lie. It is 100% facts all the way.  Just like you didn't feel like the newspaper should report on the motivations of the lynch mob, My story didn't cover the motivations of the black mob.

In reality anyone who has seen that video knows that my non-objective recanting of events completely mischaracterises what actually took place.

You may say well I never would lead my audience the wrong direction the way your example did. 

You may not, but other non objective Journalists would. Plus it's really elitist to think journalist should decide whats right and make sure other people end up agreeing with them. 

Lastly I will end with this. I once heard a visiting preacher that I had never seen before stand before my church during a revival, and tell the teenagers and young kids there to not read the Bible. He explained that some had been reading on their own and had misunderstood some things.  

He then said that he was a preacher chosen by God to preach the word and that God has gifted him with understanding that they don't have. He then said "don't worry about reading the Bible. I will interpret it and tell you anything you need to know". And at some point he talked about to many voices confusing kids and just listen to your preacher.

And to brag on myself a bit, I am proud to say I stood up furious with anger and rebuked him. 

I told all the kids there to ignore everything that man had just said because he wad wrong in every way. 

They should be reading the Bible and questioning everything he says, because even preachers can be wrong, and they should not put all their faith in one single man. They should ask an assortment of people for help understanding the Bible and they should do their own research. 

The point of that spill is to say that it's extremely arrogant to feel that your superior to others and that this other information about a newsworthy event might confuse them and cause them to be deceived.  You will decide what they need to know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43326164905.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>I wanted to go over a few of these points

&gt;First you have to respect your audience. If you don't you will lose credibility with everyone who isn't inclined to agree with you.

Advocacy doesn't disrespect the audience, rather, it respects the author. It allows the reporter to fully express their own opinion.

&gt;Then there is the moral an ethical concern. A journalist isn't God. Journalists are not infallible. Journalists are wrong all the time.

This is the exact point that advocacy helps. An objective reporter still has bias, he just presents it as the truth. Advocacy allows the reporter to fully state his position.

For the example you gave, it is possible that article will be written. However, if the author is prioritizing advocacy, they better know the bias they have. Also, another reporter can give the other side of the story. There will always be two sides, the difference is that advocacy allows the reader to accurately determine the stance of the reporter beforehand.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
