<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43322913917.0" user="Callec254" delta="False">
    <text>Unless we were there witnessing the event personally, we're already at the mercy of the reporter's personal biases.  Unless you've met XYZ politician in person, literally everything you know about them has been filtered for you through that lens.  They don't even have to "lie", per se, they can just simply choose to report, for example, when a politician *they* don't personally like commits a crime, and then ignore it when a different politician they do personally like commits the same crime.

So I'd argue that it already is this way, to the point that it substantially distorts the truth, and that this is just as often used for evil as for good, if not more so - and that you're just simply *told* that it's for good, with no way to effectively verify anything for yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323061961.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>However, advocacy articles are often in the opinion sections of news websites. They clearly express to the reader that and article is an opinion or it is clear to see that they are advocating for something. On the other other hand, objective reporting cannot get rid of all bias, it just creates hidden bias that is presented as the absolute truth. Often this can be more dangerous then advocacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323124279.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;, it just creates hidden bias that is presented as the absolute truth

I take that as a failure of the consumer. Perhaps every newspaper should have the front page have a sub-headline that says Opinion Section lol.

I believe the opinion section often is separated so that they can publish articles that they can launder through the lense of it being someone else's opinion. 

They can often claim that the person's opinion doesn't reflect that of the newspaper as an entity, which is also disingenuous because they chose to run the opinion piece. 

So how do you do both? Just get rid of the opinion section?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323156094.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>I believe most of the front news headlines are the hidden bias objective articles, and the opinion articles are true advocacy, as the openly advocate. So just have every writer clearly state their position before each article.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323211720.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>what if they don't hold a position either way or at least they're unaware of their own biases for or against a certain topic

what about articles that don't really have overt positions I mean we're operating under the assumption that objectivity doesn't exist but there are topics that wouldn't need that caveat or where it could cast doubt on the facts you present 

in that little section what would you write in an article about the Hawaiian fires for example? you're reporting THAT something happened your implicit yet real biases aren't something you're likely thinking about when writing it 

should they say that their inclusion of extreme weather articles stems from an intent to represent climate and climate change adjacent news?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43326189936.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that every person has bias and an opinion on both sides for most topics. Obviously, for numbers reporting it's hard to advocate for something, but in the majority of news article the writer has an opinion on the topic.

Why am I being downvoted, I don't think I'm being rude :(</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
