<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43322961765.0" user="DayOrNightTrader" delta="False">
    <text>But that's already what happens now. Journalism is not done by people who just love the truth and want to spread it. It's done by people who want to promote certain ideas, influence politics, economy, society, decision-making.

Right wing media advocates for right wing ideas, left wing media advocates for left wing ideas, etc.

I just don't understand your point, what you're advocating is already practice widely. Also, the word you use for it, advocacy, is just a euphemism. The correct word for it is propaganda.  According to the [Cambridge Dictionary](https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english/propaganda).

&gt;Propoganda - information, ideas, opinions, or images, often only giving one part of an argument, that are broadcast, published, or in some other way spread with the intention of influencing people's opinions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43322985072.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>Advocacy from American Psychological Association is: “Speaking or acting on behalf of an individual or group to uphold their rights or explain their point of view.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323021970.0" user="DayOrNightTrader" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever you call it, advocacy or propaganda. It's how media already works.

Conservatives want to fix the issue with abortion, they make media that spreads information that prioritizes fixing the issue over being objective.

Liberals want to fix the gun issue, so they make media that spreads information that prioritizes fixing the issue over being objective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323736378.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that they both frame themselves as right, without considering the bias that they have. If they were clear that this was their opinion and clearly stated their position, people could make more educated decisions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43326098834.0" user="DayOrNightTrader" delta="False">
    <text>If they wee clear, they'd be less effective at "advocacy". If you want to focus on advocacy, you need to avoid telling people that you're biased, and that your goal is to lobby decisions, and not "keeping you informed".

People like thinking that they have agency, and make their own judgements</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43326172528.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>I believe every person has bias, and there is no way to completely get rid of it. The difference is advocacy allows you to take a clear stance on a topic. Objective reporting can lead to unintentionally or subconsciously leaving out facts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43326198412.0" user="DayOrNightTrader" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree that everyone has bias, I also don't think publicly admitting it is a good idea, if you look for maximum advocacy.

Because people don't like to think they are being brainwashed and manipulated, people like to think they had received balanced analysis of a given situation and made THEIR OWN decision.

Claiming that you're objective helps advocacy more, than admitting the truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323662139.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>The APA doesn't speak for journalists. Also, they are hardly an authority for word definitions outside the field of psychology.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
