<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43322855553.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>That isn’t what CJR explains. It says, in an editorial by its managing editor:

&gt;American journalism’s honeymoon with objectivity has been brief. The press began to embrace objectivity in the middle of the nineteenth century, as society turned away from religion and toward science and empiricism to explain the world. But in his 1998 book, Just the Facts, a history of the origins of objectivity in U.S. journalism, **David Mindich argues that by the turn of the twentieth century, the flaws of objective journalism were beginning to show. Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.”**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43322901282.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't the managing editor use this to show the dangers of objectivity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43322954828.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>You have several flaws in just this part of your view:

* You misread “flaws… were beginning to show” as “some benefit of objectivity that haven’t found yet” as if objectivity is flawed, rather than it has flaws. That isn’t the conclusion of the article you cite. 

* You misquoted a book from 1998 used as an example as the view of the Columbia Journalism Review and cite the author directly. 

* You added parts about mob justice and one-for-one balanced facts not in the source. 

* You failed to disclose the explanation of the CJR as really, an editorial by an individual. 

This is an example of how advocacy screws up a perfectly good argument. If you simply let the source speak for itself, and quoted it directly without adding your voice or misappropriating its voice as your own, the argument would be more sensible. 

Instead it makes little sense and looked suspicious to me (CJR explains objectivity is flawed and has few if any benefits OP can see?), so merely clicking through your link demonstrated your argument was driven by advocacy rather than the facts of the source.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323038072.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't the quote directly support my position?  "objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation” 

I wasn't able to get the quote directly from the author, and instead used a third party who was able to read the book as a source. If objectivity is flawed, doesn't that prove that advocacy should be preferred?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323085678.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>No, it merely offers a view that objectivity has flaws that were developing by the 20th century. It doesn't conclude objectivity is flawed, which is your view, nor does it state advocacy should be the preferred alternative. It being the managing editor's opinion.

Objectivity also doesn't mean balanced. It means, for example according to the BBC, [several paragraphs of guidance](https://www.bbc.com/editorialguidelines/guidelines/impartiality/guidelines). It doesn't mean one for one, both sides reporting, nor should it because as the BBC and Columbia Journalism Review and Columbia Journalism School note, objectivity favors the status quo. Advocacy, obviously, does not. One approach does not fit all, but one approach would be wrong to do if done all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43323190171.0" user="anonymous68856775" delta="False">
    <text>I still believe that advocacy should be favored. Objectivity shouldn't be altogether eliminated, but writers should be able to not only express their opinions, but to try and make sure the reader knows of the bias they have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43327183794.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Advocacy-based news, like Fox News, is part of what's ruining society. News should be news, and op-eds should be op-eds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43326547571.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; objectivity favors the status quo. Advocacy, obviously, does not. 

Nothing could be further from the truth. Reporting on wealth inequality, poverty, climate change, pollution, rich people not being held accountable for their crimes, etc. etc. clearly does not favor the status quo.

While a lot of advocacy does, from the partisan "everyone's racist" to the "libruls are groomers". It's meant to be divisive, to keep people from seeking real policy solutions, focusing instead on irrelevant bs.

No, it's not obvious that advocacy does not favor the status quo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43329214270.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;objectivity favors the status quo

\&gt;A Columbia panel holds a central principle up to the light:

\&gt;

\&gt;Lowery, who is Black, focused on how the banner of objectivity has served the status quo. “There’s not a single day in most cities that the local mainstream newspapers properly, fairly, accurately cover the Black community, the immigrant community, the gay community,” he said. He ascribed this failure to the lack of distinction between “subjective” and “objective” journalists. “It’s a bunch of people telling themselves they’re objective journalists and then writing their opinions into the news, and doing so by deciding what stories they cover and what stories they don’t cover.” Objectivity, said Lowery, “has always been wielded to silence people who do not fit with the politics of the people who own and operate the newspapers.”

On the other hand, the publisher of the NYT responds at CSJ:

\&gt;Critics on the left also argue that supposedly objective journalists are anchored to a point of view, but in this case one that privileges a straight white male perspective and the status quo. This critique takes many forms, but often centers on the belief that notions like objectivity—the very idea of it, not just the failure to achieve it—exist to maintain and insulate existing power structures from change or scrutiny.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43329406284.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>Neither of these arguments are true. 1st one is essentially just criticism of subjectivity, 2nd one is just highlighting issues that bar objectivity from being achieved. It's "impossible" to be 100% objective, doesn't mean we shouldn't aspire to be objective.

This argument in a logical extremes advocates for propaganda to push for change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43330332228.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>They’re arguments that aren’t mine. My point was that they’re from sources that don’t represent the CJR, the school, and as in the second quote, the publisher Schlesinger doesn’t represent the Op Ed board or the Times itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43330605340.0" user="Rodulv" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you mean.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
