<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43345759491.0" user="RandomRecorder753" delta="False">
    <text>These are two different domains that you've already a hard time to entangle, but which really shouldn't be mixed.

The point of reporting is to tell people what actually happened, while the advocacy is a creative writing exercise where you work with the facts to create a compelling story/narrative/theme with the intend to get people to perform a particular action or to refrain from performing that action. 

And when it comes to getting information and thinking for yourself you should probably stay far away from activism because as said their prime objective is to get you moving and the most effective way of doing that is by providing you with a narrative that leaves you no choice but to act even at the cost of lying and distorting facts or omitting them.

Now it's generally hard to entangle the two because no matter how much they try to be neutral you'll see the events happening through the eyes of the reporter, there's no way around that. 

Though if they do a good job you can read left and right wing publications and you should still get some informational value out of them. If it's all spin and activism and no facts or barely scratching the definition of "technically not 100% false", you'd actually waste time and get dumber listening to them and you'd actively create division and bubble formation because it's impossible to connect to people outside of your propaganda narrative. 

Seriously purely advocacy focused reporting and lobbyism is essentially FOX NEWS, Alex Jones, Sinclair Media Group and other outlets that can only be described as trash. To call them "journalism" is an insult to any journalist and people listening to them get actively misinformed on issues.

Also objectivity does not mean that you have to adhere to some sort of hyper neutrality. As said it's borderline impossible to not insert your own bias into things, whether it's through the style of reporting, the topics covered or not covered, the attention to particular details or the omission of others. That all being said, if you make a claim you'd be required to cite evidence, if you propose a reason you should cite evidence for that and so on. You should either have your facts well researched (as far as that is possible with timely reporting), to set them straight as soon as you find out that things have changed and to specify the credence you have for a particular proposition or assumption. So caution about baseless assumption and only daring about stuff with a solid backing. 

Those should be standards for the profession of journalism and people who do not conform with that should not be allowed to bear that label. It's one thing to be a commentator and to voice your opinion but that should be a different position from a reporter or journalist. One is known to be biased and that's ok if that is stated upfront and people know what they get, the other is meant to provide a fact based picture of events with minor and if so, well sourced, personal bias and failure to do so is a critical failure and should not be able to be brushed off as easily as it is currently done. 

And with regards to those negative examples of "objectivity". What makes you think that journalist would only take the position of the victim? Chances are you could also get the KKK perspective journalism engaging in a victim blaming narrative. Not to mention that "neutrality" does not necessarily mean objectivity. If the facts point in one direction, then omitting that disproportionality is a form of bias as well. Like how FOX pretended the debate about climate change is still open by continuously hosting events with Bill Nye and a changing array of lunatics.

If it's a violation of constitutional rights you don't have to pretend as if it isn't. That's still different from being activism. 

The other problem is that you're expecting too much from journalists. Like they're not supposed to be thought leaders of political factions, if they are then they can build up an expertise on at most a handful of issues and would be entirely clueless on the rest but expected to report on them as well. Which would have abysmal consequences for the quality of journalism. No it's ok if they just report and others do the commentating on the facts, but it's important to know as much facts as possible so as to know when they are omitting stuff, when they are exaggerating and when it's actually what happened.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
