<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2527848653.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15t0ki5/cmv_advocacy_should_be_priorized_over_objectivity/">
    <title>CMV: Advocacy should be priorized over Objectivity in the Free press</title>
    <original_poster>anonymous68856775</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have heard many people talking about how the job of the press is to remain objective, giving the truth to let the citizens decide for themselves what to believe. However, I believe the opposite. 

First of all, I define Advocacy as a genre of journalism that combines reporting with a point of view, allowing for the writer to express their opinion. Objective reporting is trying to report on facts without distortion.

One of the major purposes of a free press is to be able to articulate criticism is to utilize that power to hold democratic powers accountable. In order for a democracy to function effectively, the ability and persistence of criticism is absolutely necessary. Therefore, the press has a duty not simply to inform, but to take a stance on given issues, allowing Amercians to be exposed to a myriad of opinions, and hold their government accountable. 

Prioritizing advocacy in media reporting and journalism plays a crucial role in protecting human rights by giving a voice to those being harmed and also alerts the audience to injustices. Advocacy transforms a reporter from a mere communicator of information into a motivator for action, allowing for human rights to be upheld. 

An example can be seen in early America. Columbia Journalism review [explains](https://archives.cjr.org/feature/rethinking_objectivity.php) that in the attempt to be objective about lynchings, news sources would cover the murder of a man by the mob, and also cover the reason for the mob’s murder. They wouldn’t mention that lynching was immoral, they simply gave reasons for and against. They then go even further, citing a book on objectivity in the press, “Mindich shows how “objective” coverage of lynching in the 1890s by The New York Times and other papers created a false balance on the issue and failed “to recognize a truth, that African-Americans were being terrorized across the nation.

Objectivity can only tell us what is happening - Advocacy lobbies to fix the issue. If someone is stealing a car, merely observing that fact is not enough. Advocacy is crucial to change.

I wonder if there is something wrong in my logic somewhere, or if there is some benefit of objectivity that haven't found yet.

  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43329362538.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Here's the problem:

1. I may be an advocate for diminishing exposure to knowledge about suffering of some class of people, or believe that class is _rightfully_ underrepresented.  Advocacy _suppresses_ the truth as much as it exposes it.  Isn't the treatment of people _a fact_ and we can decide if it's good or bad?  Why should we be comfortable with _suppression_ of information by those we rely upon for access to it?  You are beholden to media's control over the channels of information so don't you want to know that they aren't hijacking that for advocacy you'd disagree with were you to know the whole story?

2. You conflate "presenting both sides" with "objectivity".  Academics often talk about this problem in science reporting where they find the 1 of 100 scientists to present the counterargument to the 99 which makes it seems like a 50/50 issue when in reality it's a 99/1 issue.  This isn't _objectivity_ this is _advocacy for conflict_, and in my mind is the result of _shitty, advocacy driven journalism_ it's just that what is being advocated for is nothing anyone wants other than advertisers and those who sell eyeballs.  You say it well - we failed to recognize the truth, which is to say...we had bad journalism, not that an effort to be objective failed.  There MUST be a layer that tells us that a. the lynching happened and b. there are multiple sides to the story that we should see.  To lay onto journalism the need to both present information AND to contextualize it into values is to take away from commentators and social movement leaders and all that the role _they should have_.  If we simply are willing to whitewash the truth in the name of our own agenda then we haven't improved journalism, we've ended it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
