<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2540223393.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/160dswx/cmv_mr_krabs_is_a_terrible_business_owner/">
    <title>CMV: Mr. Krabs is a terrible business owner</title>
    <original_poster>CandyBroker</original_poster>
    <original_post>Mr. Krabs founded the Krusty Krab with am ambition of selling Krabby Patties and, in part, in opposition to Plankton and the Chum Bucket. 

Though Mr. Krabs has kept his husiness together through the years, thanks in no small part to SpongeBob, he is a terrible manager and overall business owner. 

He tried to charge SpongeBob and Squidward $10 for breathing (among other things), seemed hesitant about hiring his star employee until he and Squidward were almost murderer by a school of ravenous anchovies, sold said star employee to the Flying Dutchman for $0.63, fired two loyal employees over simple labor disputes, and has tried to profit off business avenues that either flopped (Krusty Krab 2 never comes up again, nor Krabbyland) or rightfully got him in a world of hurt (selling those rainbow Krabby Patties that turned all the fish characters the rainbow). 

He also blew $100,000 on a first date with Mrs. Puff and keeps all his money in his mattress. And his prized secret Krabby Patty formula in his single protection office Vault everyone seems to know about. 

Eugene Krabs doesn't have entirely bad business sense, but it is questionable to say the least.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43390928835.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>except that apart from the chum bucket and maybe 5 of so one off businesses its the only business we see in the show, the rest are all houses.  so objectively he is likely one of the if not the greatest businessman in bikini bottom</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43390966931.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>We see other businesses like the movie theater, the Sea Needle (the Space Needle charges you to go up), and customers reference other restraunts. There are even food critics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392809487.0" user="No_clip_Cyclist" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;and customers reference other restraunts. There are even food critics

Who says those businesses survive long enough to compete? Seems Mr. Crabs has the seen on lock down with competitors not surviving long as we never see anything continues outside of the outlier that is the Chum bucket and Fancy!. 

Kelpshake was the only concern except that was self inflicted as Mr. Crabs banned outside drinks. The only thing that saved them the drinks side effects. Maybe if Stinky Burgers stayed open Mr. Crab might have had competition.

This revolving door would have also had lend it's self to food critics as there would be a healthy supply of restaurant options openings up but as it would turn out some critics like Bubble Bass were more just "influencers" offering exposer as compensation and when that didn't give them a free meal they resorted to fabrications of bad service. 

Then theres Gene Scalp which is hard to call a food critic as he is just a Bikini Bottom news field reporter who becomes a food or movie critic when the news needs to pad time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391069456.0" user="slimdrum" delta="False">
    <text>Plankton has a buisness</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392720900.0" user="No_clip_Cyclist" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;except that apart from the chum bucket

He did say that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
