<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2540223393.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/160dswx/cmv_mr_krabs_is_a_terrible_business_owner/">
    <title>CMV: Mr. Krabs is a terrible business owner</title>
    <original_poster>CandyBroker</original_poster>
    <original_post>Mr. Krabs founded the Krusty Krab with am ambition of selling Krabby Patties and, in part, in opposition to Plankton and the Chum Bucket. 

Though Mr. Krabs has kept his husiness together through the years, thanks in no small part to SpongeBob, he is a terrible manager and overall business owner. 

He tried to charge SpongeBob and Squidward $10 for breathing (among other things), seemed hesitant about hiring his star employee until he and Squidward were almost murderer by a school of ravenous anchovies, sold said star employee to the Flying Dutchman for $0.63, fired two loyal employees over simple labor disputes, and has tried to profit off business avenues that either flopped (Krusty Krab 2 never comes up again, nor Krabbyland) or rightfully got him in a world of hurt (selling those rainbow Krabby Patties that turned all the fish characters the rainbow). 

He also blew $100,000 on a first date with Mrs. Puff and keeps all his money in his mattress. And his prized secret Krabby Patty formula in his single protection office Vault everyone seems to know about. 

Eugene Krabs doesn't have entirely bad business sense, but it is questionable to say the least.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43391378464.0" user="BrokenManOfSamarkand" delta="False">
    <text>I can't help by feel the numerous typos and grammatical errors here suggest you wrote this in some sort of anti-Krabs frenzy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392503884.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>It's Reddit. Not much sense in proof reading when half this site doesn't know proper grammar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392866806.0" user="No_clip_Cyclist" delta="False">
    <text>Ya I'm always amazed at how many people expect me to be as precise as I am doing my engineer when I'm not engineering (for lack of wanting to describe what I actually do)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43393810943.0" user="BrokenManOfSamarkand" delta="False">
    <text>The guy wrote husiness!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43394430041.0" user="Scene_Screen146" delta="False">
    <text>No. I admire you for being able to put down your “engineer” role when you’re not being one. A lot of them don’t know how or can’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43394433096.0" user="Scene_Screen146" delta="False">
    <text>….my Father-in-law 😠</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
