<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2540223393.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/160dswx/cmv_mr_krabs_is_a_terrible_business_owner/">
    <title>CMV: Mr. Krabs is a terrible business owner</title>
    <original_poster>CandyBroker</original_poster>
    <original_post>Mr. Krabs founded the Krusty Krab with am ambition of selling Krabby Patties and, in part, in opposition to Plankton and the Chum Bucket. 

Though Mr. Krabs has kept his husiness together through the years, thanks in no small part to SpongeBob, he is a terrible manager and overall business owner. 

He tried to charge SpongeBob and Squidward $10 for breathing (among other things), seemed hesitant about hiring his star employee until he and Squidward were almost murderer by a school of ravenous anchovies, sold said star employee to the Flying Dutchman for $0.63, fired two loyal employees over simple labor disputes, and has tried to profit off business avenues that either flopped (Krusty Krab 2 never comes up again, nor Krabbyland) or rightfully got him in a world of hurt (selling those rainbow Krabby Patties that turned all the fish characters the rainbow). 

He also blew $100,000 on a first date with Mrs. Puff and keeps all his money in his mattress. And his prized secret Krabby Patty formula in his single protection office Vault everyone seems to know about. 

Eugene Krabs doesn't have entirely bad business sense, but it is questionable to say the least.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43391615663.0" user="PainterSuspicious798" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re speaking purely of him as a business owner I’d say he actually is very successful.

Homie has so much money I remember episodes of him swimming in money. Either he is doing something illegal or he is managing to make insane profit on only one restaurant with 2 employees that for some reason haven’t quit yet (squidward)

The fact the krabby patty is so recognizable and relevant to bikini bottom also speaks for itself. The fact squidward hadn’t eaten one at one point seemed shocking to other people. Once he ate one he also couldn’t stop eating them. So with all that said he has a very good product he’s selling. 

I know it seems silly to have his formulate in a safe but I’d say if it ain’t broke don’t fix it. There’s been countless attempts to steal and it it’s never gotten leaked, so he’s doing something right there.

He gives the customers what they want and gouges them at the same time. (Adding 0’s to prices wheb the opportunity arises) Remember, they serve burgers but he made his two employees deliver their one and only pizza he made on the fly. Not great for his employees but customer satisfaction is the priority because he knows that’s where his money comes from. That’s business 101.  

He quite literally found the perfect sweet spot of a recipe that is beloved by literally everyone, a business that can be run efficiently on the wages of two employees, and fending off numerous attempts from people trying to overtake him. The man is a business genius.

Yes, sorry I’m high af</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392326343.0" user="giovanny2214" delta="False">
    <text>I believe a man almost died and lost his computer wife for the secret krabbie patty formula</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392531434.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the customer who ordered that pizza would agree he was highly satisfied (given the ending). 

Also the Krabby Patty's success is in large part SpongeBob. He outcooked the god of the sea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392957017.0" user="No_clip_Cyclist" delta="False">
    <text>Except [Jim](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fCnob-ZeXFo) was the best fry cook the Krusty crab has ever had back when it had class. He was so good he became a transoceanic name in higher culinary society.

So good that Mr. crabs told him there was one thing that made him better was he was cheap.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
