<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2540223393.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/160dswx/cmv_mr_krabs_is_a_terrible_business_owner/">
    <title>CMV: Mr. Krabs is a terrible business owner</title>
    <original_poster>CandyBroker</original_poster>
    <original_post>Mr. Krabs founded the Krusty Krab with am ambition of selling Krabby Patties and, in part, in opposition to Plankton and the Chum Bucket. 

Though Mr. Krabs has kept his husiness together through the years, thanks in no small part to SpongeBob, he is a terrible manager and overall business owner. 

He tried to charge SpongeBob and Squidward $10 for breathing (among other things), seemed hesitant about hiring his star employee until he and Squidward were almost murderer by a school of ravenous anchovies, sold said star employee to the Flying Dutchman for $0.63, fired two loyal employees over simple labor disputes, and has tried to profit off business avenues that either flopped (Krusty Krab 2 never comes up again, nor Krabbyland) or rightfully got him in a world of hurt (selling those rainbow Krabby Patties that turned all the fish characters the rainbow). 

He also blew $100,000 on a first date with Mrs. Puff and keeps all his money in his mattress. And his prized secret Krabby Patty formula in his single protection office Vault everyone seems to know about. 

Eugene Krabs doesn't have entirely bad business sense, but it is questionable to say the least.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43390910824.0" user="heyknauw" delta="False">
    <text>He doesn't keep all his money in his mattress. He has rooms and rooms stocked to the walls in $$ bills, gold coins, and diamonds and gemstones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43390943720.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>Which are easy pickings in a burglary or armer robbery. Still seems like poor financial sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43390969584.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>Completely unrelated to his business owning skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391020337.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think financial sense relates to business sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391051449.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>His own personal poor finance skills are independent from his money making skills. Which is clear because of his continued wealth. If you pissed away your money like mad but were always constantly strapped with tons of cash. 

That's an indication that your skills at business management outweight your failings of your personal finance. If you're making SO much money that you can afford to be poorly managing your finances that's a good indicator of a healthy source of reliable income. 

As far as I know this hasn't ever come back to bite him in the ass and has been wealthy the entire time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391132777.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>I already awarded a delta. I will note that mob of rainbow fish did beat the tar out of him. And the anchovies almost killed him, he so cut it close</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391172412.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>that being said, he did get paid from the anchovies, per google 

I don't recall him having any part in them arriving so you can't say that was his doing as a business owner. Though he did hire spongebob and he handled it 

and to a tiny tim song if I remember correctly 

I don't recall the rainbow fish</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391280922.0" user="CandyBroker" delta="False">
    <text>The anchovies paid? I don't recall that. They started thrashing when Squidward asked them to form a singular line. The rainbow fish were from the Pretty Patties he sold.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43391344308.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>according to reddit and a youtube link (I didn't check admittedly) they left behind a big bag of cash

I vaguely remember the cut away to the sack of cash now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43394421917.0" user="Scene_Screen146" delta="False">
    <text>He’s got shark security</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392353517.0" user="pokepat460" delta="False">
    <text>He is not rich. There's a whole episode where he earns his millionth dollar. He's comfortable but by no means hold and gemstones money</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392704812.0" user="No_clip_Cyclist" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair he said 1 millionth dollar. Which by Marriam Websters. A dollar in 5) has a possible definition of :money obtained from a specific source. Example is The tourism dollar.

That could be seen as bills of other notes like Thomas Jawfish, Abraham Longfin, Andrew Jackfish, Ulysses S. Grayling, or even Ben freshwater. Then there's the almighty [Theodore Razorfish](https://youtu.be/brOMVdqr-zc?si=3pc_YY707sxgBdf4&amp;t=4) ($500 bill).

Who knows maybe most people pay in Freshwaters. I also would not put it past crabs to factor in net operating costs in his figures making that his net one millionth he earned not received.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43392719368.0" user="pokepat460" delta="False">
    <text>There are multiple instances of money in SpongeBob and its always dollars, never other currencies like you suggest. Furthermore from the context of the episode, he's clearly celebrating having made $1million in his life. Not "I'm already fabulously wealthy but now in this particular currency I've made 1 million"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
