<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43429183191.0" user="Maestro_Primus" delta="False">
    <text>How exactly is the [marshmallow experiment](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford_marshmallow_experiment) unethical or morally questionable?  Its a simple experiment that helped to identify capacity for reasoning and delayed gratification.  It is still discussed today in terms of the "correct" response and that discussion itself provides insight into mass psychology.  Its a great experiment. The issue is that the Pit of Despair and Prison Experiment were flawed from the beginning and provided no real insight into humanity or development for the field.  They are just famous for being cruel and pointless.  The Trolley Problem is less a hypothetical psychology experiment and more a real life decision people have to make regularly at higher levels of government and business.  It deserves to be discussed and considered.

It is easy to call out those headline making experiments and assume all of the science is like that, but the vast majority of psychology experiments are simple, boring, and informative.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
