<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43428182654.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;the field of study which needs to understand how the brain works **needs a sacrifice of morals** to progress quickly.

Does the field *need* to sacrifice its morals? Or, did the morals of the past become outdated, and now we look back at how things were once done and find them immoral? 

Also, how familiar are you with the current state of psychological research? Here is a list of [Breakthroughs and Discoveries in Psychological Science] from 2020. How many have your heard of? How many seem like the result of "unethical and morally questionable experiments"? How likely is it that you are basing your knowledge of psychology and its progress on sensationalism from over 40 years ago, and not on the current state of affairs?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
