<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43428050137.0" user="BainterBoi" delta="False">
    <text>Can we make this CMV a bit better, more easily arguable and especially quantified.  


\- What is classified as fucked up? What is not fucked up?  
\- Is your view about the conflict of how immoral some procedures have been and the state of the field today? Or do you think that immorality has no place in study field that tries to study brains? Is there something in this field that merely suffers from this immorality that does not apply to others? Are other studies also "fucked up"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428141500.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>-Fucked up refers to the immorality of the most popular and generally more innovative experiments done in the field


Nowadays ethical associations exist in colleges and universities to classify what is morally not 'fucked up

For me, "Causing irreversible damage to a creature for better research" is fucked up.

-My view is specifically about how niche "ethically good" experiments are today and how stagnated research is because of the moral associations.


-I want to shed light on the fact that immorality is the key to innovation in this field.

-Other fields generally allow experiments on humans like vaccination and medicine.


But 

Psychology these days disallows experiments on humans in most regards further slowing innovation.




Other experiments, There are plenty I just mentioned the ones that popped up in my mind. These "fucked up" experiments are so popular that a simple Google search will give hundreds of sites giving many examples in graphic detail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428175934.0" user="BainterBoi" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm okay, so if I read this right your view is that psychology today should continue these ethically-questionable ways of researching humans, and current study of psychologics handicaps itself by limiting these morally questionable studies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428233969.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>My view is that human experiments and such should be allowed to a specific extent but not until it causes "irreversible damage" to humans.


For example the shock expirements where they only used audio.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428420443.0" user="late4dinner" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree with the majority of your argument, but shock studies with humans can be and [are still carried out](https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2008-19206-001). Even using [real shock](https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2012-25093-001) in some cases. The ethics boards that regulate psychological research haven't banned potential harm in research, they just require that the benefits outweigh the costs of the work (with some other limitations as well).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428489753.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>I want to change my viewpoint on this topic but a general lack of knowledge and awareness in my fellow peers and myself about any popular discoveries in this field being much lesser than other fields makes me stick to this viewpoint.

But given the responses, I completely agree that research is being done but media seems to not want to bring it to light because it's not sensational</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
