<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43428100630.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>You know that the experiments you mentioned are a huge part of why psychology has really rigid ethical standards for research today right? Psychologists have actually been some of the most strident advocates for ethical constraints in research for deacdes and the American Psychological Association was instrumental in the implementation of institutional review boards for research ethics.

Before I became a nurse I got my masters in psychology, and taught research methods in psychology at the University level. We did an entire week of lessons just on ethical constraints in research. I had to make changes to my thesis study out of ethical concerns, not because I was going to harm anybody, but because I had not been specific enough about the "risks" and need for consent on my consent form (to be clear, my thesis was on in-group/out-group formation and had participants listen to audio recordings of people speaking different languages, the "risks" were entirely remote if not completely hypothetical).

Not to mention, most of the so-called "ground breaking" studies you referenced have not actually been treated that way by most serious psychological researchers (with the possible exception of Milgrim in some contexts, but that's mostly because it happened so soon after WWII).  Academics have harshly criticized both the value and ethics of the Stanford prison experiment since it occurred, Harlowe is widely considered to be a terrible person who did mostly pointless research (as a result of his own depression), and the Trolley Problem experiments (at least the ones I'm aware of) were done under strict ethical constraints and showed little sign of harming participants while not being particularly groundbreaking.

So I honestly don't know where you get the perception of psychology and psychological research that you have, except maybe from reactionaries and some popular media.  It doesn't seem like you got your ideas from actual academics and psychologists, because they generally do not share your view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428738907.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>You are completely right that I am mostly unaware of Psychology as a whole on the subject matter.

The reason I said it was groundbreaking was that I have seen in most of myself and my peers that we had a general idea of the bad experiments because of how popular they were.

I ignorantly considered being popular to the layman as being groundbreaking.

The reason why I even posted this was the lack of awareness of the better Expirements and the details that you shared being available in my general surroundings.

It felt to me that since much noise was not being made about psychology and there was a stigma about it in my area due to its overpopular evil experiments, there are fewer innovations and developments occurring</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428918263.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>Well has your view now changed?  If so, you should award a Delta to the person who changed it.  If not, what is still preventing you from changing your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43429099184.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>Yup I did award it. Thank you for reminding me, much appreciated</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
