<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43443361509.0" user="HappyChandler" delta="False">
    <text>Devil’s Advocate here:

They already did that for airfares. Sites have to show you the all in cost. Well, the cost with no options. 

That’s when the airlines unbundled, so now, you pay extra to check bags. You pay extra for seat assignments to sit with your family. You pay extra for carry on, even. 

So for a hotel, you’ll get the room rate. But it won’t include a bed, a shower, etc. “Oh, you want a door? That’s not included in economy, you can upgrade to the privacy package.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43443730599.0" user="LiteratureSentiment" delta="False">
    <text>That would be great if those options were real, but the issue is it's a bait and switch where the low price option doesn't actually exist. You can't get a room without a shower or doors, so it's just deceptive to have that as a fee instead of the main price.

Car dealerships do this with base models. They're never available because they don't actualy make money on those, but they get peiple inside talking about a low price and then push them to a more expensive vehicle with sales tactics.

Nobody should support this crap</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446196861.0" user="HappyChandler" delta="False">
    <text>Ten years ago you wouldn't think that you could buy a plane ticket without checked or carry on allowed. Even Ryan Air let you carry on a bag. But here we are!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43444866911.0" user="Minister_for_Magic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That’s when the airlines unbundled, so now, you pay extra to check bags. You pay extra for seat assignments to sit with your family. You pay extra for carry on, even.

Don't confuse correlation with causation. Unbundling started with deregulation during the Reagan era. There's a great [Behind the Bastards series](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8bmGff5f-Ug) that lays out how one gigantic asshole led the way on this. But it was essentially the Wal-Mart strategy of offering no frills (and fucking over unions!) to offer the cheapest cost at the shittiest experience.

Airlines still break out a ton of "fees" during checkout that are literally **the cost of doing business**. It's nonsensical to see a "fuel surcharge", "airport fee", and other such bullshit broken out when that is all basic COGS.

Does your favorite paid web app charge you a "hosting fee", "AWS fee", and other such bullshit? Of course not! You pay $X/month and that is all you see (plus sales tax)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446181165.0" user="HappyChandler" delta="False">
    <text>I only see those other fees on airfares in the small print -- I see the out the door advertised price, because that's the law. They always included airport fee -- that's how much goes to the airport, not something made up. 

The breakdown of the fare doesn't matter. It just matters that when you compare different fares, you can actually get the advertised price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446398175.0" user="kerouacrimbaud" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; They already did that for airfares. Sites have to show you the all in cost.

Idk if that's true across the board. I literally bought a UA ticket 20 min ago, and the 150 ticket was met with a 40 add-on for "fees and taxes" right where I had to put in my payment info. Flight was advertised at 150, but it was really 190.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
