<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43448146523.0" user="SuchResponsibility84" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, no, your luxury purchases are slightly more expensive than you initially expected. Even though the final charge is disclosed before you purchase, you had to pay attention, oh, the injustice, we should definitely make it a priority of governance to protect you from this you poor lamb. 

Goddamn, people. Get some fucking perspective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455677924.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
