<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43441606271.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>Say 2 people are purchasing the same product which cost $100 in different places. 

Person A lives in location A which requires farther shipping, but they are also willing to pay more for 1 day shipping. 

Person B lives in location B, which is closer to the shipping point, so they purchase standard shipping.

In addition, Location A had a lower tax rate than location B.

So it ay look something like this:

&amp;#x200B;

**Person A Price**

Product: $100

Shipping: $30

Tax: $10

Total: $140

**Person B Price**

Product: $100

Shipping: $10

Tax: $15

Total: $125

&amp;#x200B;

There is a $15 difference with these 2 people alone. Now do that for hundreds of people ordering from hundreds of locations. How can a business possibly calculate the cost for all these variables before they get the information from the customer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441629633.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>I addressed this exact example in my original post.

&gt; If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442330998.0" user="KamikazeArchon" delta="False">
    <text>Most of the fees you're unhappy with are also variable, so they would still not be displayed up front.

And if they're not variable now, they'd be made variable. Member vs non member prices, etc.

I agree with the dislike of the business model, but I don't think posting the prices in a different way is going to be a significant difference. Regulating the fees themselves would be more effective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442512711.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>Most if not all fees are variable to some extent so how do you expect all the prices to be shown? Say a store advertises a product for $100. They include the tax price which makes it $110. But I have a coupon that makes the product 30% off. So now which price are they supposed to advertise? The original price with the tax or the coupon price with the tax?

Also how many people are going to go to the place, pay the advertised price for the product then look at their receipt and complain that they were overcharged and they never agreed to pay $30 extra for a resort fee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43443333810.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>Do you realise that 100*0.7*1.1 is the same as 100*11*0.7</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43444439863.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>What does this have to do with my comment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43445558714.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; So now which price are they supposed to advertise?

The answer is it doesn’t matter</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448690558.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>That directly goes against OPs view. If the price doesn’t matter then don’t complain</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450938392.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>My bad I misunderstood your original comment.

Which price are they supposed to advertise? The final price with tax without the discount. The coupon should be applied at the end because its specific only to you.

What kind of fee/tax is variable? The only variable fees I have ever seen in my life are shipping fees and these are always advertised as cost + shipping cost</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446887973.0" user="Maestro_Primus" delta="False">
    <text>No it is not.

* 100 x 0.7 x 1.1 = 77
* 100 x 11 x 0.7 = 770</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43443705167.0" user="LiteratureSentiment" delta="False">
    <text>Pull out a calculator do that math on the end price bud, it's gonna blow your mind</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43444430275.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>Product price + (Product price x tax rate) = Final price

No coupon = 100 + (100x.1) = $110

Coupon = (100x.3) + ((100x.3)x.1) = $77

What exactly is supposed to blow my mind here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446541864.0" user="LiteratureSentiment" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to think the coupon price is somehow affected. It's not, it's 77 whether you apply thr tax before or after</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448560443.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>No I don’t and I have no idea how you got that. Because I’m not comparing when you apply the coupon I’m comparing if you apply the coupon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43449077137.0" user="LiteratureSentiment" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't apply the coupon, the final price would be 110. If you do apply it, it would be 77.  There's nothing to be confused about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446451464.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most if not all fees are variable to some extent so how do you expect all the prices to be shown? Say a store advertises a product for $100. They include the tax price which makes it $110. But I have a coupon that makes the product 30% off. So now which price are they supposed to advertise? The original price with the tax or the coupon price with the tax?

I'm not sure what your point is. If you have a 30% discount voucher, it will knock down the total price by 30% regardless of it has the tax included or not included. 

&gt;Also how many people are going to go to the place, pay the advertised price for the product then look at their receipt and complain that they were overcharged and they never agreed to pay $30 extra for a resort fee.

Nobody is stopping to put in the small print: "The price includes tax, resort fee, whatever". In any case having to pay the advertised full price and then later finding out how it is split should be a much smaller annoyance than finding out later than you will have to pay more than the price that you saw in the advertisement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442149385.0" user="Pac_Eddy" delta="False">
    <text>OP is referring to any and all fixed unavoidable costs. Shipping is not that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442316939.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is this cost can still shift. Maybe if you spend a certain amount that cost is reduced. It would still be very complicated and confusing to list every single possible price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442329083.0" user="Pac_Eddy" delta="False">
    <text>Don't list every single possible price. Just the fixed unavoidable costs. Like I already said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442394135.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>So...the price of the product only...which is exactly what the op is arguing against</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442401728.0" user="Pac_Eddy" delta="False">
    <text>You need to reread OPs post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446510265.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>That there are other fixed unavoidable costs that some sellers do not include in the advertised price. 

For instance a booking fee. If you book a ticket through some portal and they slap a fixed booking fee on top of the ticket price, they should not list the ticket price without the booking fee as you can't get the ticket without paying the booking fee and that fee is always the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448686353.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? At that point you are buying 2 products. If you’re being charged for 2 products but are only notified of one that’s less transparent

Example: You go to ticket master site and buy a ticket for $125 which includes the booking fee. The problem is that you believe you’re paying $125 for the ticket but you’re not. You’re paying $100 for the ticket and $25 for the booking fee. Meaning you possibly could buy the ticket in person for less but are unaware of the actual value of the ticket alone.

Then what if it’s a flat fee per booking rather than per ticket? So whether you but 1 ticket for 5 tickets the fee remains the same. How do you advertise the price of all those tickets while also including the booking fee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453728963.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>You really don't care what the hypothetical ticket that you have no access could cost. What matters to you is if the ticket is more valuable to you than the money you have to pay for it. And for that the most important information is "how much is the total price of the ticket".

The $100 ticket price is completely imaginary. You can see that best with airline tickets, where people can sit next to each other having paid very different prices for the tickets. There is no "true" ticket price but only the one that you pay including all the fees.

If you buy a ticket to an event from the black market, it doesn't matter to you that ticket has some number printed on it. No black market scalp will advertise their tickets with that price and then just state "oh, there is also the markup fee of $100 on the ticket". And that markup is actually not even flat but can easily change depending on the demand. So, why shouldn't same apply to normal ticket sales?

Yes, I agree with you that if the booking fee is per transaction and not per ticket then you shouldn't add it to ticket prices, but that's a different thing than what I'm talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447308717.0" user="NaturalSelectorX" delta="False">
    <text>This is about things that are tacked on and don't change. If there is a resort fee, it should be rolled into the advertised room price. The Ticketmaster "convenience fee" should be rolled into the advertised price. Restaurants that add percentage-based surcharges should roll them into the food prices.

The overall point is that you should be able to compare things easily. All hotels in the same area have the same taxes and regulations to follow. They shouldn't be able to lure you in and sneak an extra fee right before checkout.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442882866.0" user="SoloTraveller1161" delta="False">
    <text>Reread the original post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446990051.0" user="BaziJoeWHL" delta="False">
    <text>I live in Hungary, we have X% sales tax, I pretty often order from Germany through Amazon, they have a different sales tax  
after I set my delivery location, all the prices change to display in my local currency with my local tax included and under it listed all the delivery options clearly stated with their price, I dont have to go to check-out to see the tax and delivery prices</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
