<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43442236456.0" user="Umbrage_Taken" delta="False">
    <text>I'll take it a step further and say they should mandate that prices for anything should have to include all sales tax up front as well.  Gas includes everything up front. Other goods and services should too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446902898.0" user="Xystem4" delta="False">
    <text>The reason this isn’t done is because each state has different sales tax (some don’t have it at all), so for things sold in multiple states (most things) they’d need to adjust the pricing, which is a lot more work than it is to do the same thing in other countries where this isn’t the case. 

Personally I’d still be in favor of doing that though, it’s not an infeasible amount of extra work</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447471971.0" user="Erit1566" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but in physical stores, the prices can be adjusted by the store owner</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447485043.0" user="Xystem4" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I’m with you. I don’t think it’s unreasonable to expect a store owner to price things appropriately and do the tax math themselves.

An issue for companies is that they couldn’t then make products “nice numbers” like $x.99 (because the tax would make the displayed value different in every state), but that’s manipulative shit anyway and as a consumer I couldn’t care less.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
