<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43441422009.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>It depends where you’re going. It’s a convenience thing. If you go to a tourist location (a resort), with services, expect to pay for them. That’s really it. Resorts offer Wi-Fi, concierges, notaries, faxes, transport, baggage handling, tours, and all manner of things to make your trip easier. In a place like Disney or Hawaii, you stay in a resort. You pay a fee. 

If you don’t want this, don’t stay in a resort. Stay in a business or extended stay hotel. You won’t receive these “complimentary” services. Or if you do, you pay per service. That’s really the choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441442133.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>If a resort wants to charge $130/night, I have no issue with that.

My issue is asvertising a rate of $100/night and  not disclosing the extra $30 fee upfront.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441491432.0" user="mortalviperkillsquad" delta="False">
    <text>I understand. But they’re advertising the services apart from the lodging. Common sense dictates that in the minority of locations that do this—resorts in vacation places, and minority of chain locations—those services have a cost beyond the room rack rate. 

When you pay per night, you’re paying for the room. It used to be you paid for internet, or had loyalty from staying so long had status that it was “complimentary.” The expense never went away at the resort: you paid for the room. They sliced off the non-room rate, and made more hotels to attract clients more in line with that property. 

At a Courtyard, business travelers aren’t paying resort fees in Orlando. But at a Marriott there, you probably are. Because it’s really a “property:” travelers expect an experience. They don’t expect just a room like a Courtyard or Residence Inn. 

That people don’t realize what they’re looking at, by just picking the price, is that really the fault of the business? They offer 10 different properties in Orlando. You pick the resort by Disney. The resort has the fee, the fee covers the non-room extras. You can easily pick the other 9 properties that cost $4 more a night but didn’t. 

Should they also go to your house, hold your hand on your mouse, and scroll on Marriott.com/about and read to you the differences between the levels of products in Orlando like Roxy Hotels targeted for hostels and JW Marriott for old luxury folk?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441520669.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>These services are generally not separate.  You generally can’t decline a resort fee anymore than you can decline the local hotel tax.

If fees are standard and everyone is expected to pay them, they should appear in the advertised rate.

Basically, if the hotel front page says $99/night, that should be the FINAL price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442567571.0" user="zacker150" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If fees are standard and everyone is expected to pay them,

The entire point is that not everyone pays resort fees.

The following people don't pay resort fees:

* Business travelers
* People with elite status at the hotel (for example Hyatt Globalist)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442587639.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that counts.   A hotel might give a 10% discount to the military or AAA members.

I don't think that is the same thing as advertising a $100 room rate, and then hitting everyone else with a $10 "non-military" fee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442695869.0" user="zacker150" delta="False">
    <text>Historically, business travelers have made up the majority of guests at hotels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43443392111.0" user="uUexs1ySuujbWJEa" delta="False">
    <text>If the room costs $200 plus an unavoidable $50 resort fee, then the room does not cost $200. It costs $250. Advertising it as less than $250 is wilfully deceptive and anti-consumer, plain and simple.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
