<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43442329456.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.

In other words, they are literally showing you the exact price before you checkout.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442388156.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, which is why they should be advertised for $70.

My point is the advertised price should match the checkout price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442419446.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>I get that you'd prefer it that way, but what legal basis do you have to claim that your preference should be a legal requirement?

Are you being defrauded somehow? Did the checkout screen say $40 but you were charged $70?  Or did it say $70 right in front of your eyes before you clicked "Complete Purchase"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442434281.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>Because I believe we should enforce truth in advertising in price, just as we do with other features of a product.

If you advertise a cheeseburger for $1 and someone walks into your store and asks for that cheeseburger, you shouldn't be able to say "oh, actually those are $2"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442443369.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you should. As long as you say it before you hand them the cheeseburger and demand the $2, yes, you should. As long as they have a chance to refuse it at that price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442471438.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>Why?  Why should we allow businesses to intentionally lie about their products and services in advertisements?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442485496.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Circling back, you do see the "This is going to cost you exactly $70.12" part before you hit "Accept", right? 

So you're not being lied to? 

The full answer is that the base price is the actual fee for the ticket, what the production company is charging. The face value of the product itself. The fees are what you are paying Ticketmaster for facilitating the transaction. 

In a similar way, you get Doordash. The price of the sandwich is $8. In addition to that, you pay Doordash a fee for delivering it. Same thing. It makes sense for them to be listed separately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442494455.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; So you're not being lied to? 

Yes, I was.  The advertisement was a lie.  They advertised something that did not exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442522482.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, there was. But you're not buying it from a restaurant. You're buying it from a third-party vendor who is charging an extra fee for getting you the cheeseburger. 

If you walk up to the box office of the venue where the concert is, I bet they will sell you the ticket for its face value. I know ours will. 

But you're not buying the burger from the restaurant. You're buying it from Doordash. So you're paying the $1 for the burger, indeed, as advertised. And then you're paying Doordash for bringing it to you. That's not false advertising. That's paying for a service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442552994.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If you walk up to the box office of the venue where the concert is, I bet they will sell you the ticket for its face value. I know ours will

They used to a decade ago, but now they charge the extra fees at the box office too.  So, really it’s impossible to get the tickets for the advertised price of $49.  There are going to be mandatory fees.  All they do at the box office now is order it from the same website.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442587686.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I completely understand why you would prefer it that way, but you haven't made any kind of case why it should be legally required. No one is being lied to. You are shown the exact amount, to the penny, before you agree to the purchase. So you cannot claim that you were defrauded in any way whatsoever. It even breaks down the cost so you can see exactly WHY it was that much. 

You're trying to get the government to force something for your own convenience and preference, and to be frank, that's an inappropriate use of the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442646896.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; No one is being lied to

As I said, you are being lied to in the advertisement.   

Imagine I look at the newspaper and see an ad for a steak dinner for $10 at a local restaurant.   If I drive over there, I see another sign outside that says, "Come in and order the $10 steak dinner".   I sit down and look at the menu, it says "Steak Dinner:  $10"

The waiter comes over, and I ask for the steak dinner.  They say "Oh yeah, just so you know, that's actually $30"

In my mind, that is fraud, and should not be allowed.  It's similar to bait and switch, which is also illegal (as it should be, in my mind).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442684264.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, I have to duck out, but I'll try one last time.

Your analogy is bad. It's not accurate. You need to look at this correctly.

You're dealing with two different businesses. It's not a restaurant. It's Doordash.

If you get on Doordash, it's going to say that the steak dinner is $10, just like it is at the restaurant. But when you go to order it, they're going to say "That'll be $10 for the steak dinner, plus $3 for us delivering to you, plus $1 for a mandatory emissions charge we have to pay, plus $1 more for the processing of this order. So it's going to be $15. IS THAT OK?"

$45 IS the ticket price. That never changed. That's how much Taylor Swift gets. The rest is what you're actually paying for with Ticketmaster. You're paying for their services, which they tell you the price of before you agree to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451053899.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>Lets assume the delivery fee is variable per customer but the emissions fee is constant per steak and the processing fee is constant per order

The cost of the steak should be advertised as the steak + the emissions fee. I can understand the delivery fee and the processing fee being separately listed/calculated because these are not specifically attached to the product. But the emissions fee here would be tied to the product.

Using your ticket analogy, yes the ticket is $30 and yes the service fee is $15, but the customer is not buying just the ticket from this vendor, the customer is buying the ticket AND the service and the service should therefore be advertising it as such. The exception here I guess would be if the service fee was constant regardless of how many tickets you were buying.

But overall, all vendors should really bake in all their operating costs into the base price of their products anyways. Its not like supermarkets charge you “rent fees” and “staff hire fees”. These are all baked into the product costs. It should be WYSIWYG</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451626330.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>As a person, I agree. I think we just have very different bars for when one should be allowed to literally force someone else to comply with their preferences. Sure, I'd prefer it that way, too. But I don't see that as anywhere close to a good enough reason to say "So I'm going to legally require you to do what I want".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451645364.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>I think it comes down to that the prices advertised are not what you are ultimately paying and that is misleading. Important to note that they aren’t LYING, its just MISLEADING, and therefore, the law should still protect consumers from these often hidden charges</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451671504.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>And that's why I brought up the confirmation. You really can't claim they're very hidden or that you're being tricked. Yeah, maybe you're disappointed, but no one is deceiving you. It tells you as clear as day how much you're about to pay. If it said $30 right there at the end, next to the confirmation button, and then $45 showed up on your statement, I'd be right there with you, but that's not what happens.

You are very well informed when you make that purchase. The law would be an overreach for nothing but your own convenience, not your protection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451688516.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>Curious which country you are from?

Humour me, how would you feel if you sat at a restaurant that had all their food prices on the menu but had a sign saying “10% surcharge applies on all food ordered”

Would you consider this to be something that SHOULD be illegal or would you still consider this to be ethical or not misleading?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451844362.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Bit different with a restaurant because by the time you are presented with the bill (assuming you don't mean counter service), you really can't opt out at that point. You already consumed the product, right?

Now for counter service, I think the analogy is good. One of those fancy screens on the register, it pops up with all the food and then "10% convenience fee". Yeah, I'd be annoyed af, but I wouldn't ever push for that to be illegal. Because I can just leave. And that's what I'd probably do.

Don't stray far from the reality here for the analogy. The ticketmaster fee isn't hidden on some sign tucked away in the corner. We're all very aware of the fees, and again, it shows you right there in bold print how much you're about to be charged. How you got to that point isn't nearly as relevant. You click a button that says "I agree to pay $125.78". You really can't claim to have been misled at that point. Because you can walk away with no penalty whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451866195.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>For my scenario, I mean assuming this “service charge” is advertised on the window and the menu etc, its clear before you order that they’re just gonna tack on an extra 10% on whatever you purchase before you order. Would this still be fair, going with what you said?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452097140.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>If it's clearly visible, including on the menu? Sure. California does that constantly. There are like 7 fees for various things tacked onto something as simple as an ice cream cone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452389435.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>I guess this explains why this doesn’t bother you because we actually have laws that prevent this in Australia. Theres just no reason for things like this besides misleading customers and blowing up prices</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454063889.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>I think I was pretty clear about my general philosophy on this, so I'm confused how it's still not making sense.

Whether I have a personal issue with it or not isn't the determining factor for whether or not someone should be legally compelled to do something. I don't think government exists to force every last desire of the majority onto everyone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454355516.0" user="h0t_d0g_water" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not asking for whether you would have a personal issue with this, I’m asking if you think this is right or wrong, more along the lines of morally or ethically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454429623.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure how that's a different question, but thank you for rephrasing.

Neutral? I don't think it's helping you or hurting you. It just...is. It's like asking if I think it's ethical for a restaurant to play a certain type of music. I might not like it, but so what?

You're being shown the exact price for something that's purely a luxury in the first place, and can walk away from with no obligation. You just wish they'd show you that price slightly sooner.

Let's stop throwing around "ethical" like we're talking about them using slave labor or something. This isn't even a first world problem. It's a middle class, first world annoyance at worst.

And I appreciate that we have different cultural context on this. It's one of the neat things I like about traveling. But I much prefer the law just staying out of such things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446938023.0" user="BaziJoeWHL" delta="False">
    <text>wait, are you really defending false advertisment ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43449305504.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>On a subreddit where the sole point is to challenge an expressed view? Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442599496.0" user="really_random_user" delta="False">
    <text>Gonna defend OP there, he's basically advocating for what EU law states, when buying anything at a store (the price tag is what you pay (though the price may be lowered in like a promotion)

And any advertised "starting from price" is the base, no frills option, but can be purchased for the shown price

Options can be added, but they must be clearly shown
And at checkout you get a breakdown of the price with all the fees (that would be added in the usa)

Also with eink labels, prices can be centrally managed to account for local sales taxes.
Price labels aren't a complicated thing, it's just greed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442618409.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; And at checkout you get a breakdown of the price with all the fees

Which is exactly what you get in the US. 

Y'all need to stop treating Ticketmaster like it's the supermarket. They are not the vendors of the tickets. The venue/production are. Ticketmaster is a third-party. What you are paying them for is not the ticket, but their interface. That's what the fees are for, and they could not be more clearly indicated. 

And there is literally a single button you can click, right there on the Ticketmaster page, that shows exactly what you're asking for. The price with all fees included as you're browsing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442723582.0" user="really_random_user" delta="False">
    <text>So what if they're a third party?!
Advertising a price that actually cannot be paid by the consumer should be plainly illegal. It means you can't easily compare options (and with ticketmaster's  behavior, there aren't)

Their job is to connect the venues that their parent company owns, to the customer, for the artist who basically doesn't have much choice. ( as Live nation owns most large concert venues, and blacklists)

When I book a flight, on skyscanner or google shows 60€, it means i can book a (randomly allocated) seat on that flight, I'm not going to reach checkout and get hit with mandatory airport fees, atc fees, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43443282966.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; And there is literally a single button you can click, right there on the Ticketmaster page, that shows exactly what you're asking for. The price with all fees included as you're browsing.

Probably because they were coerced to make that change by the federal government.

https://www.reuters.com/world/us/ticketmaster-live-nation-agree-all-in-prices-part-biden-war-junk-fees-2023-06-15/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43444186547.0" user="haefler1976" delta="False">
    <text>Wanted to say this. Since the EU has taken initiative, I feel a lot more safer when booking f.ex. flights. No more additional fees after selecting offer and price. It‘s a lot more transparent.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
