<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450297841.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>"ACAB" stands for "All Cops Are Bastards" not "All Cops Are Bad People." The slogan expresses moral condemnation of the decision to become and remain a cop. It is not asserting that literally all police officers engage in brutality, or that all police officers are racist, or even that all police officers are out to get you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450404997.0" user="Sea-Scratch8800" delta="False">
    <text>What's the difference between a bastard and a bad person? Aren't those synonymous?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764117296.0" user="Parfait-Tiny" delta="False">
    <text>Nope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450542720.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>Given that you are differentiating bastards from bad people, please provide your definition of “bastard”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450562623.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>In this context, as I already said, it indicates a negative moral judgement: specifically, moral condemnation of the decision to become and remain a cop. More broadly "bastard" is used as a generalized term of abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450970941.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>Cops are cops is a tautology. 

What are the criteria to be a bastard? To have done something morally condemnable? If so, bastardization is universal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450993163.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>You're making this more complicated that it is. It's just an expression of moral condemnation of the decision to become and continue to work as a cop. There's no need to involve tautologies or criteria.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451037612.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not the one who decided that the phrasing should be “all cops are bastards”. 

You know how we can make this even simpler than that? Change it to “being a cop is morally condemnable”. 

Jeez, that was easy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451059131.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>"All cops are bastards" is fine. The meaning is straightforward from the context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451174856.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>It’s clearly not fine because you’ve been asked multiple times what it means. 

The purpose of words is to communicate. If people don’t know what you mean, your choice of words sucks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453208746.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't this require one to make a convincing empirical argument that each of the 14,000 precincts in America regularly engages in immoral behavior? Are precincts not separate and distinct in how they operate in their own localized regions?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
