<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="84" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43457663670.0" user="Chicago_Synth_Nerd_" delta="False">
    <text>I think what gets lost in translation is that #notallcops is like #notallmen. ACAB isn't necessarily a literal indictment against every single cop; it's social commentary on the inequalities of the justice system. 

The frustration is valid too. When it's established that law enforcement has no constitutional right to investigate and prevent crime it reinforces how powerless vulnerable communities feel. 

To make an analogy, after every single mass shooting event in the United States and the topic of gun control gets discussed, conservative voices offer a counter narrative and blame mental health as a cause. Yet, many of those same voices do very little to improve the mental health issues that our communities face and in some instances, pursue policy that makes things worse. 

The lack of credibility that law enforcement has in the United States should be considered worrisome to law enforcement as that rift furthers our societal divisions. We should be seeing more rhetoric from law enforcement about them recognizing the issue and taking more concrete steps to resolve the inequalities, especially racially motivated inequalities, in their enforcement of the law.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
