<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43451234447.0" user="TiredOfDebates" delta="False">
    <text>There does appear to be a near universal system of blatant corruption, in at least one facet: “Friends of Police license plates.”  People connected to an officer can get “FoP tags”.  There is an “unspoken” rule that says if you have FoP tags, you are now above traffic law enforcement.

Every last cop that has participated in that system is technically corrupt, as they are engaging and participating in a system of selective enforcement.

They don’t *mean for it to be corrupt, but that’s just how it is.*

This is different from the popular idea of corruption, which usually features outright brutality, but selective enforcement and preferential treatment is by far the most common form of corruption.

I can’t think of a single person who would even deem it reasonable for a police officer to end up on the shit list after he writes the district chief’s wife/daughter a speeding ticket.  But that is just the normalization of corruption.  We’ve been kind of brainwashed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453280473.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;“unspoken” rule

You mean conjecture?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456640561.0" user="One-Watercress-3428" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you commenting under everything being aggressive at the end of the day this is an issue that affect the lives of marginalized communities. your sitting up here treating it like it’s some kind of hate campaign against cops.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
