<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="50" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43455152300.0" user="ImabackoutFr" delta="False">
    <text>okay so heres a little of my bias

during elementary, my dads leg was broken when a police cruiser door was closed on it. the cop was let go, and after about 5 years he settled for 30 k. the lawyer took a third of that money. my limited understanding is that there was a domestic dispute, sure my dad has a mouth on him (sometimes he makes me wanna break the other leg, lol)... 

of course this isnt all cops

as someone that looks hispanic, ive noticed police be a bit more rough/stern with their tactics with my peers, from threats to tase if you do anything or "GET ON YOUR KNEES" being the first thing they say, usually clutching a gun. Nothing where we had the cops called on us, but rather them just trying to learn who's who. Often when I feel I am being honest/straight up, I'm getting the questioned like where's the heroine? or not being believed, stopped for fitting the description, not wearing a seatbelt, etc. I'd rather not get into the times i've seen and experienced what I believe to be excessive force. complaints are investigated of course, but still rarely lead to disciplinary action. Kind of makes you feel like your word is worthless when you see an outright lie/fabrication in your paperwork, or on the news. My dad actually signed some stuff saying he wouldnt go to the news. but i look like a hispanic male, and i work construction so i can look scruffy so i get it. thats my experience that i am perceived as a threat sometimes. not a violent guy tho.

if a cop pulled me out a burning car tho i'd feel different. its a different experience. they are certainly capable of heroic acts and necessary. cops can get in their feelings and do things and then say they are just following training tho. they are people too and individuals. cant blame them. they are all capable of something heroic as well. 

i do feel as if i were an attractive female, ran around in 3 piece suits in a mercedes benz, etc they'd treat me more like a human being. i guess its not the cops that bother me so much, its that interactions with them can land you in some cruel and inhumane places. Someone in Fulton County just died of bed bugs. It's easier than you think to get caught up in the system and forgotten. But again who you are in the society matters more than it should. 

As a Jacksonville resident, we are still reeling from the recent racial shooting sparking gun/racial debates on the radio. Last night, the pro gun advocate mentions a story from our local history. At the landing, a black man killed a white man in self defense. The man was placed in the county jail as a white lynch mob began to form. The black community stood their ground with lever action rifles on every corner of the downtown area. An abolitionist writer said that the winchester lever action rifle should have a place in every african american home. Then, the governor passes a law saying you can only have that particular firearm withg a permit. The first gun control legislation enacted in the state. The permits were issued to whites only, of course. 

If the police arent there to protect your rights, and instead can execute you on the spot if you are a 'dirty rotten wiggler', yeah you might believe ACAB. So although America is a place where you can be any religion anything you wanna be, certain lifestyles are gonna come with more scrutiny/attention from law enforcement than others. Freedom aint free tho. It's a complicated issue that will vary based on your personal experience. At the end of the day, we all rely on these 'services'.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
