<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450636964.0" user="tryin2staysane" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes.

We get it, you wish you could commit crime and get away with it. Personally, I don't. Don't lump everyone in with yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453271333.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Can you name a civlization in human history that didn't have some kind of police force? No? Hm. Do you think there might be a reason for that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454233789.0" user="tryin2staysane" delta="False">
    <text>Can you name a civilization in human history that had no murders? Guess all murder is good.

But seriously, what is your point? Absolutely no one has been calling for abolishing all police, so you sound like an idiot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455418783.0" user="youngsurpriseperson" delta="False">
    <text>No I don't really wish I could commit crimes except for stealing money so I could like, get food and a house. My mind has already been changed but if you were trying to change my mind then you didn't have to be a jackass about it. There's literally a whole section in this sub that explains why you shouldn't be hostile when trying to change one's mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455426496.0" user="tryin2staysane" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, that's still you wanting to commit crime. You can't say "No, I don't want to commit crime, except for this crime I want to commit".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456377479.0" user="youngsurpriseperson" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I did say it, but you're missing the point. Without cops, more people would commit crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
