<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450287027.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

How many cops do you think agree with this?&gt;97</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450354609.0" user="youngsurpriseperson" delta="False">
    <text>You tell me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450366869.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if there are any survery results, and I'm not sure how truthful people would be on the subject anyway. 

But I'm going to say that most would not (my dad had a cop-adjacent job when I was a teen so I heard more than usual). And if they support that behavior. . .? 

Well, up to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453136760.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>I have a pretty good survey. How many minneapolis officers resigned or spoke out against Derek Chauvin in the wake of the killing of George Floyd?

Spoiler: it was zero</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455431369.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>Not only did they not speak out but every available officer including officers from surrounding areas came to *preemptively* protect the guy's house. Who wasn't home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450670989.0" user="tryin2staysane" delta="False">
    <text>How often do you see other cops speaking out when there's a publicized police brutality situation? Next time you hear about one that seems particularly egregious, go check out the cop subreddits and see how many cops think it was justified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451909081.0" user="Formal-Macaroon1938" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;How often do you see other cops speaking out when there's a publicized police brutality situation?


I've seen it a few times on video. Then the cop that spoke up is either treated like a pariah or gets disciplined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452090065.0" user="tryin2staysane" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453130525.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Then the cop that spoke up is either treated like a pariah or gets disciplined.

Assuming they aren't straight up murdered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456360882.0" user="Nematode_wrangler" delta="False">
    <text>And that teaches the new cops to toe the line, or they may not receive backup when they need it. It's like employment insurance. Plus, if they're new to policing, how likely are they to put in an official complaint about a more senior cop? They're more likely to shut up about any criminal activity of other 'members' and either keep their head down or decide that this is how policing works and they take on the criminal behavior. Thus, the behavior is reinforced and continued.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455412804.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>Do they have department-wide code words to switch off the body cams together.

"Are you red?". "you on right now?"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
