<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="65" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43456029021.0" user="Character-Taro-5016" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with the typical policeman or sheriff is that they don't know the law or their place in the justice system.  They think they have authority where they actually have none.  A cop has absolutely zero authority over anyone until a crime has been committed yet they attempt to exert control by demanding ID, forcing compliance with "policy" as opposed to the law.  Unfortunately, over time the nature of the typical police force is a construct of systematic indoctrination of policemen to be tough guys or girls who can swoop into situations and solve them, but they do so with very little understanding of the law that pertains to the situation.

Every single day cops are fired or even jailed because of their actions.  They need to be taught de-escalation and basic civil rights.  Not all situations have an immediate need for physical intervention.  They often-times need to slow down, find a superior, and discover what the law is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
