<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43451750260.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>So, I'm from Minneapolis.

The last cop of the George Floyd case just got sentenced. 

His defense was "Hey, I was just there directing traffic, it wasn't my collar, so I didn't get involved, I just did traffic control."

This is why ACAB. This failure of a human being stood next to someone getting murdered and didn't notice because the guys doing the murdering wore the same uniform he does.

Look at the story of the cop who pepper sprayed a 9 year old.

No one arrested him for child abuse, even though he was surrounded by cops: https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/you-did-it-yourself-officer-tells-9-year-old-girl-n1257630

All cops aren't bad because they all do bad things. All cops are bad because the s-called good ones almost never stop the bad ones, or arrest them for their crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453202898.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't it still unclear that Floyd was actually murdered? Don't we even have conflicting coroner's reports about whether his death was caused by asphyxiation or some other reason (like a drug overdose)? If two coroners can't even agree, can you blame a cop who wasn't even looking for not knowing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455489967.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>It's only unclear to people who are easily fooled and can't understand the nuanced difference between a true expert and a mercenary.

If you find yourself saying "both sides" a lot lately, you will probably have difficulty parsing out the differences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455595119.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>What information convinced you that the cororner report that disagrees with your perspective is corrupt?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455621135.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>Money. Described him as a mercenary for a reason. A mercenary is someone who fights for money not duty or ideology.

Simply understanding the term mercenary would have avoided you needing to ask this question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455651636.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Isn't it still unclear that Floyd was actually murdered?

It's so unclear, they just figured they'd convict the guy of murder to be safe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455721833.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Even if the grant the premise that Floyd was "murdered" (as in, Chauvin *knew* he was actively killing Floyd), can you explain why this case should be representative of the 800,000 police working in America and the 61 million police interactions per year? That's where I'm still a bit unclear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455881568.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>You don't need to "grant that premise". Chauvin was convicted of murder on April 20th, 2021. 

&gt; an you explain why this case should be representative of the 800,000 police working in America and the 61 million police interactions per year, 98.4% of which do not involve force or even the threat of force?

I did not make that argument. It is, however, worth mentioning that at the time of murdering Floyd, Chauvin had already been the subject of many complaints, a number of which bear striking similarity to the way he eventually murdered George Floyd. Yet he was still acting under the cover of authority at the time of the murder. 

It might also interest some to look into the DoJ's [report on the Minneapolis Police Department and the City of Minneapolis](https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-finds-civil-rights-violations-minneapolis-police-department-and-city) seem to indicate Chauvin's actions are part of a larger pattern of abusive use of force and  unlawfully discriminates against minorities, to name only two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456613620.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You don't need to "grant that premise". Chauvin was convicted of murder on April 20th, 2021.

Is the idea that juries are infallible? Does that also mean that when police are found not guilty by juries, as they [often are](https://www.cnn.com/2017/05/18/us/police-involved-shooting-cases/index.html), that these decisions are also always necessarily correct?

&gt;Finally, it stands to reason that all police interactions include the threat of force

They can, but they don't. Technically speaking, any of us can use violence at any time, in any interaction as well. The only difference is that it's usually not lawful for us to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43462665299.0" user="AndrenNoraem" delta="False">
    <text>Are you serious right now? Are you this reluctant to admit other people are murderers, or just cops?

*It is on video*. You could go watch it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43464842228.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think a cop would commit murder as it's legally defined (with conscious intent) while being filmed. You're free to disagree. My opinion has been stated and I will not discuss it further.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43458723033.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Even if the grant the premise

Derek Chauvin was convicted of murder. He is a murderer. Your inability to state this without caveat is deeply dishonest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459245646.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Do you accept all jury decisions uncritically? For example, when juries find cops accused of misconduct or brutality [not guilty](https://www.cnn.com/2017/05/18/us/police-involved-shooting-cases/index.html)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459320488.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, no I don't, but as many other users have pointed out to you Derek Chauvin is definitely guilty of murder. To not believe so at this point is purposeful blindness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459342345.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>That's cool you have an opinion. I do too. My opinion is that a cop wouldn't intentionally murder someone while being filmed from 12 different angles in broad daylight with a crowd. But I guess you think that's stupid.

Manslaughter? Sure. Murder? No.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459357418.0" user="akcheat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That's cool you have an opinion. I do too.

Right, but yours is unsupportable by any kind of fact or morality. So sure, you have an opinion, but it's a factually incorrect one. 

&gt;But I guess you think that's stupid.

Yes, considering police do that all the time. Why do you think police aren't brazen enough to just kill people in broad daylight? It hasn't been filmed enough for you at this point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43464086361.0" user="SeymoreButz38" delta="False">
    <text>The fact chauvin was convicted despite the system's favor reinforces his guilt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456017325.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>No, it is not unclear at all.  No there are not conflicting reports. There are however, ignorant people  


Scientific America's piece "[George Floyd's Autopsy and the Structural Gaslighting of America"](https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/voices/george-floyds-autopsy-and-the-structural-gaslighting-of-america/) might help you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43466787134.0" user="AscendantDragon" delta="False">
    <text>The cause of death was not the cop though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43468066628.0" user="kingpatzer" delta="False">
    <text>Did you read the article. It absolutely was.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
