<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450350017.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>You can be a cop and a good person, but as a cop your role in society is largely about maintaining unjust systems of power. For example protecting the property of people who own more than they need at the expense of people whose needs aren't being met. Cops will hapily come over and stop homeless people from sherltering in a mall or brutalise protesters.

Sure cops do some crime fighting, and you can point to times the police have helped, but that's only part of the story. For example you'd need to look at the impact of a justic system revolved around punishing people instead of reforming them. You can look at the issues caused by using an armed responce force as the default responce to mental health emergencies or drug issues.

Also it's important to point out that it's not just the cops who do police brutality that are 'bad cops' its the cops that enable those cops and protect them from punishment that make the system worse, or the cops who actively attacks the cops who are trying to reform the system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450732164.0" user="yaboiw00dy24" delta="False">
    <text>Yea but even everything you just described isn't about the cops it's about the system. The legal system is absolutely trash yes, but pretending that cops main job is "maintaining unjust systems" then I'm just gonna have to disagree with you. 

I've met a cop tht had to kill someone to save hostages, he saved 6 people and still hates himself for taking that one life to do so. 

I've met a cop that quit the force because he felt like everyone hated him and he'd never hurt a soul. 

I've met a cop that brings food any time he has to deal with homeless transients.

If all you see in cops are bullies that are "happy" to kick homeless people out of shelter than I'd say that says a lot more about you and your mindset than anything else. 

Their job is to stop and prevent crimes. It's not their fault that crime has such a massive umbrella.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450807887.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Their job is to stop and prevent crimes. It's not their fault that crime has such a massive umbrella.

So for example if homosexuality was illegal would you say cops couldn't be blamed for arresting hay people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456038885.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>If homosexuality was illegal and a cop arrested someone for it, then no, the cop should not be blamed.

The cop is doing his job, even if he disagrees with it.

In fact, that right there is a core component of a cop's job.  If a cop disagrees with his state's stance on citizens carrying firearms (say, in Texas currently), he has to shut his mouth on it, and NOT arrest people for having weapons.  Because it's not against the law.

If he believes weed should be legal, but lives in a state that has no legalized it, it is still his job to arrest people caught with marijuana.

If you is pro-choice, but lives in a state that has criminalized abortion, he still has to arrest people who get abortions.

The arrest is just the first step in our legal system.  And people who are unjustly arrested because of unjust laws are not doomed.  They have recourse through the legal system and appeals.  If a law is unconstitutional, our courts can and will strike the law down, thereby allowing the officer to no longer be responsible for immoral actions.

But so long as he wears the badge, he is required to do some things he may not personally agree with.  But at the same time, he may be trying his best to do more good than harm.  The guy arresting a homosexual may also do foot patrol through a community with many gay couples, and avoid abusing or antagonizing them - so that he knows that they get the police protection they deserve as long as they are not caught "being the gay".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456111823.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>So the cops are just following orders?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456179790.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>Which is legitimate until the laws they are following are shown to be war crimes.

It really is that simple.  You follow orders.  There's a system for the laws creating those orders to be changed.

Now, if you replaced "arrested" with "shot dead", then I'd say the cop is responsible for not taking action.  Or if the cop knows that everyone he arrests are going to be killed without trial.

But simply arresting someone to be processed justly through the laws as written in his state/country?  Yes, it's his job to just follow orders, and it does not make him bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456255934.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Which is legitimate until the laws they are following are shown to be war crimes.

So the standard your holding cops to is 'better than a warcrime'?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456328515.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>No, I expect cops to do their jobs, regardless of their political viewpoints.

I don't care whether they are pro-life or pro-choice, I expect them to act in accordance with the laws in their state.

Even if I dislike it, that means I also would expect them to arrest someone for homosexuality if the state they were in had passed a law making it illegal.  Though I would very much expect that law to be struck down when those arrested under that law appeal it to a higher court.

If you as a cop disagree with the laws of the state you are in, you need to suck it up, move out, or stop being a cop.  You don't define your own law to enforce.

UNTIL doing so becomes a war crime.  But as long as the justice system is designed to still give whoever you are arresting a fair trial, you do the job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456337848.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But as long as the justice system is designed to still give whoever you are arresting a fair trial, you do the job.

Designed to or actually does?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456442181.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>Get back to me when you have an actual argument and not just straw men in the wind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456648072.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think a strawman is? And I'm happy concluding here unless you want to defend the idea that people get a fair trial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456669652.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>A strawman is a point/argument presented to distract from the original argument.

Instead of arguing about what I said, you're bringing up points full of hyperbole and twisting what I said into a gross misrepresentation.

Whether people get a fair trial is an argument for another thread, and is irrelevant to my point.  You can't actually discuss the point I made, so you are attempting to derail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43465831711.0" user="crackpotpourri" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize this is how things like the Holocaust happened, don’t you? “Just follow orders no matter what you personally think?”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764084324.0" user="Parfait-Tiny" delta="False">
    <text>Again, that’s the WHOLE POINT. You just made an excellent argument FOR ACAB.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43460386251.0" user="UnevenGlow" delta="False">
    <text>Rose colored glasses are so soothing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43463928552.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/UnevenGlow – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal%20UnevenGlow&amp;message=UnevenGlow%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/-/jyr6wnf/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764076611.0" user="Parfait-Tiny" delta="False">
    <text>The cop is just doing his job. That’s the ENTIRE POINT of ACAB. Their job is to enforce all laws. Not all laws are just. It’s their JOB to BE a bastard at times. Cops who arrested Rosa Parks, were just doing their job. If someone was ever arrested for being at the wrong water fountain, the cops were just doing their jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451142596.0" user="andrea_lives" delta="False">
    <text>It's their fault for enforcing unjust crimes. They could choose to not be cops and spend 100% of their work time doing something that helps people. You bring up homelessness so lets use that as an example. They chose to wear a badge that requires them by their very job description to harass homeless folks trying to sleep, or disrupt organizations like food not bombs that feed them, or evict single mothers, when they could be working for a nonprofit to help those homeless folks or any number of good causes. Hell, they could just choose any other field that is neutral instead of actively harmful to people. If the system is unjust and you choose to support that system, you don't get to say that it's not your fault when you follow orders that make people's lives worse or support the system that orders your fellow officers to make others' lives worse. 

Want to be a hero? Be a firefighter or ambulance driver. Want to help homless folks? Work for a nonprofit that helps people get housed and get the support they need. Want to prevent deaparate people from turning to armed robbery? Work somewhere that helps those people avoid situations where they are so deaparate they risk jail to get their material needs met. 

ACAB is about the job itself requiring you to be a bastard, regardless of how pure of geart you are. You are required by your job to do systemic harm. Not doing that harm requires dodging your job description. Not contributing value to the organization that does. Not legitimizing the corrupt system that does that even when you don't wabt to participate. 

Are there better and worse cops? Sure. I am sure plenty even think they are making a difference, and some of those may be right. But all cops help a bastard organization, and being part of a bastard organization makes you by extension a bastard. You could help the world so many other ways, but your ticketing, asset seizures, ect... that you are required to do as part of your job duties does support the organization and therefore the people who are doing the bastardly action.

You can't put the fire out from inside the house.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455756702.0" user="itwastwopants" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, per the supreme Court their job ISN'T too stop or prevent crime.

They don't have to do anything if they see someone getting stabbed, shot, robbed, or anything else.

ACAB</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451557405.0" user="RoozGol" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You can be a cop and a good person, but as a cop your role in society is largely about maintaining unjust systems of power. 

Marxist garbage detected. Aborting....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454665866.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453196857.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;as a cop your role in society is largely about maintaining unjust systems of power.

I'm always a bit puzzled when I see someone make arguments like this. What do you think a typical cop's day consists of? What specific things do you believe cops do on a daily basis to "maintain unjust systems of power"? Please explain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456072657.0" user="MannItUp" delta="False">
    <text>They enforce laws that are largely punished by monetary means, this disproportionately affects those without means as any slip up or unjust intervention by the police could be life ruining, while it's a mild inconvenience to others.
Additionally the way they are deployed and respond, heavily patrolling and targeting poorer areas while not responding to calls for help from the same community, or having delayed responses.
The unjust systems of power are geared to protect the wealth of the upper class and the police absolutely enforce that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456118706.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for articulating that for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456651685.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;They enforce laws that are largely punished by monetary means,

What would be a better punishment for petty crimes, in your opinion? Jail time?

&gt;this disproportionately affects those without means

Why is this the fault of the police? People choose to commit crimes. Before you make the argument that poor people are shoplifting to feed their starving families, you should take a look at [the things shoplifters actually steal](https://www.retailresearch.org/shoplifters.html). The only food items people tend to shoplift are packaged meats and cheese, which are considered luxury goods and can be resold for a profit.

&gt;as any slip up or unjust intervention by the police could be life ruining

Not true for most misdemeanors. But even if it causes trouble in your life, maybe don't commit crimes? Just a thought.

&gt;Additionally the way they are deployed and respond, heavily patrolling and targeting poorer areas while not responding to calls for help from the same community

Should police not go where crime is the most densely concentrated? If cops go to crime-ridden neighborhoods, you say they're overpolicing. If they don't, you say they're racist. They can't win, can they?

It might serve to ask Black people what they think. As it turns out, [80% of Black Americans want the same or more police presence in their neighborhoods](https://news.gallup.com/poll/316571/black-americans-police-retain-local-presence.aspx). There might be a good reason for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457443489.0" user="MannItUp" delta="False">
    <text>Don't really feel the need to debate you, just answering your previous question. Have a good one bud.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459031821.0" user="PlentyBeginning7835" delta="False">
    <text>Are you kidding? You think enforcing property rights is unnecessary? That’s completely insane. 

Cops are there to enforce, not to reform. Totally different world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459154908.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>And some of the things they enforce are harmful. For example I'd say it's harmful to enforce the property rights of a company to own water sources that should be avalible for everybody so that they can charge for something people need to live.

There's also an important distinction between personal property that individuals have, private property that companies own and public property that the goverment owns for the people. 

&gt;Cops are there to enforce, not to reform. Totally different world.

So I'll ask you the same I asked someone else, if it was illegal to be gay would cops arresting gay people be acceptable to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459194204.0" user="PlentyBeginning7835" delta="False">
    <text>No it wouldn’t, because we have human rights. Lmao. Comparing stealing peoples property with violating human rights. Nice. Good thing we don’t do either. 

Cops don’t write the law either, bud.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459287594.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>So what rights do you think people should have?

Do you think people should have the right to buy all the insulin in the world and then sell it for whatever price they want? If someone did this do you think people trying to steal the insulin to distribute it to everyone who needed it for free should be arrested?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459522387.0" user="PlentyBeginning7835" delta="False">
    <text>Do some research on property rights. They are essentially the reason for all progress. 

Property isn’t patented, it’s just not comparable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459564374.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do some research on property rights. They are essentially the reason for all progress.

If you don't want to back up your claims I'm happy to conclude here.

&gt;Property isn’t patented, it’s just not comparable

That doesn't really address the question, but if you want me to use a different example then food would work, or any resource people need to survive. Do you think that people should be able to buy themselves a monopoly on something other people need to live and then force other people to pay them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459613569.0" user="PlentyBeginning7835" delta="False">
    <text>Also not patented. These aren’t a one size fits all subject. Taking away the ability to own and invest in property would literally fuck everything. 

That’s like me telling you the sky is blue and you wanting me to back up my claims. What I’m saying is an objective fact, not my job to educate you. You are holding all the information and history in the palm of your hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459647414.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That’s like me telling you the sky is blue and you wanting me to back up my claims. 

Which you could easily do in the case of the sky being blue. 

&gt;What I’m saying is an objective fact, not my job to educate you.

Of course you don't have to respond, but for now all you've done is claim what you're saying is a fact without giving any good reasons why people should believe you. Like it's not even clear what you mean by litterally fuck everything? Are we talking human extintion or the collapse of civilisation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459722795.0" user="PlentyBeginning7835" delta="False">
    <text>Civilization. Let’s just say your dollar and your retirement and lifestyle ain’t going</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459134307.0" user="katyushas_boyfriend" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; For example protecting the property of people who own more than they need at the expense of people whose needs aren't being met

Why do you think others are responsible for ensuring that your needs are met?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43459185475.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I just have a preference for fewer people starving or being homeless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43460473905.0" user="katyushas_boyfriend" delta="False">
    <text>Virtually no one starves in developed countries and many if not most homeless people are that way because of substance abuse issues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
