<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450340068.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>American cops don’t save people from getting killed. I wouldn’t spontaneously commit a felony if police weren’t there. Would you? 

American cops at the end of the day are here to make society feel safe (they do a terrible job at it) but catching “bad guys” and exacting revenge. 

If you look at the basic functions, there’s no difference between police and satan if you follow a Christian religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450428578.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>The only reason US is even borderline safe is because of police. They are a huge deterrent to crime. 

And it's funny people in one breath will say cops don't catch criminals then in another breath will say we have 25% of the world incarcerated. So which one is it? 

Look at the violent crime charts from 1980 till 2020. Why do you think it fell? Probably due to good law enforcement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450521759.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>No, not probably due to good law enforcement. Best evidence suggests it was phasing out leaded gasoline:

https://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2018/02/an-updated-lead-crime-roundup-for-2018/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450544220.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Riiiiiiiight. It had nothing to do with law enforcement. We just happened to lock up a  bunch of hopeless scumbags and crime fell off a cliff. But it was all leaded gas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450556486.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>Law enforcement has been a constant. You made a claim specifically about the relative drop in crime from 1980-2020. Some very nice scientists went and figured out why that occurred. We should be appreciative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450570926.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I'm sure leaded gas was one of the reasons. So was strict law enforcement. The whole reason for the tough on crime act was because crime was out of control in certain parts of United States</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450586194.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>Out of control...why? Again, diligent research has shown us why. It wasn't because we weren't tough enough on crime. It was because an environmental hazard was fucking with people's neurological development.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450627886.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>It was because we had too many criminals running around. That's why we started giving them stiff sentences. Ask any police officer. 80% of your crime comes from like 20% of the individuals you arrest. They just repeat over and over and over and over. They don't fucking learn. As soon as we started handing out stiff sentences to those losers. Crime stats started improving. It's not rocket science. Some people need to be locked up for their own good and for ours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450676371.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>You're just restating the dogma you subscribe to. The fact remains: addressing the root cause (lead) accounts for the reduction in the crime rate over the time period you're trying to make a claim about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450700160.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>As are you. You don't believe it was law enforcement. You're 100% convinced it was lead. Because you don't understand how law enforcement works. And have this really strange belief that law enforcement has nothing to do with crime stats. It's all lead!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450842524.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>You're welcome to present counter-evidence. 

"Bruce Western of Harvard University found that a 10% decrease in crime rate occurred with a 10% increase in incarceration, and ultimately the 90% drop in crime from 1993 to 2001 would have happened without the prison boom experienced by the U.S. as a result of “tough on crime” policies."

https://empowermissouri.org/tough-on-crime-tough-on-children-is-tough-on-everyone/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451786619.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think... Maybe... if we had a better justice system... that focused on rehabilitation... instead of revenge... we wouldn't have the recitivism rates that we do?

My wife had a friend who got locked up for pot. The prison let him get a pharmacy tech certification, then when he got out, he couldn't get a job because he had a drug related criminal history. Make it make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451985217.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>No rehabilitation is a myth. Most people in prison don't change. They come out and do the same shit. Especially the particularly egregious one's. 

We already spend a ton of $ trying to rehabilitate them. Often for not. 

We give people plenty of 2nd and 3rd chances. By the time someone is in prison they've gotten multiple convictions. Very unusual to go to prison on your first offense. 

Yes some people learn their lesson. The overwhelming majority of people don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452081015.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>[Really?](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1344622309000674)

Have you considered that your belief is unfounded in reality and not supported by data?

There are many socio-economic factors that go into why crime is the way it is, and also that it is unfairly assessed. A poor person is more likely to go to prison than a rich person, for example. Sometimes people turn to crime out of desparation for things like food or housing insecurity. Perhaps if we addressed actual societal problems that lead to crime, we wouldn't have as much of a problem as we do. 

Even without fully addressing these issues, simply reforming the prison system would have drastic improvements. [Norway](https://www.firststepalliance.org/post/norway-prison-system-lessons) had recitivism rates comparable to modern U.S. rates before they reformed their prison system, and now they have some of the lowest rates world wide. 

But hey, if you want to continue living in this delusion that rehabilitation is a myth and there is no way to fix a person, that's your problem, just don't drag the rest of us down with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453233328.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Let me ask you something: why do you think Singapore has one of the lowest crime rates in the world? Did you know they have very draconian laws and punishments for crimes like littering? Do you think maybe that has something to do with it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453293063.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>I was responding to a comment about a specific crime rate trend in the U.S.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454982866.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Is the idea that harsh criminal punishments have been shown to work elsewhere in the world, but this wouldn't work in the U.S. for some reason?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457494679.0" user="nekro_mantis" delta="False">
    <text>Define "work."

Did you know that Cybercrime is non-existent in Amish settlements? 😱

Did you know that if you kill everyone in a city, that city's crime rate will subsequently drop to zero? 🥶

Like, sure, if your nation's system of governance is *so strict* and economic life is *so demanding* with no wiggle room for negative feedback against the panopticon-induced paralysis that it's [effectively killing your populace in slow motion](https://asia.nikkei.com/Spotlight/Society/Singapore-fertility-rate-hits-new-low-putting-focus-on-housing-prices), then, granted, you may get some nominally pristine crime stats. But...my guy...that's not really the point.

Not to mention, just because something can be implemented in other nations with very different cultures, doesn't mean it is even feasible or would be similarly "effective" in the U.S.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450548132.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>There’s no point in talking if you can only skim the surface of topics like you just did but I’ll indulge out of ego. 

Does the U.S. have the worst police out of any developed country since the U.S. has the most crime? They don’t deter that much then. 

We have 25 % of the worlds incarcerated population. I don’t feel unsafe because somebody smoked weed in Louisiana and is prison now. A woman getting an abortion doesn’t scare me. Do you think she’s coming after you getting an abortion? Correlation is not causation. 

Do you know that’s the specific reason violent crime fell? Or can you admit there’s multiple things that influence who wants to commit crime. But let’s look at statistics and let’s say I’m a deranged violent criminal. I have over a 50% chance of murdering someone and getting away with it. All I have to do is be a slightly above average murderer and I’ll never see jail time. How is that a great deterrent? Obviously it’s not because there are a lot of murderers in the U.S. because people for whatever reason think police are gods.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450590332.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Does the U.S. have the worst police out of any developed country since the U.S. has the most crime? They don’t deter that much then.

US has a ton of criminals. Criminality is a big part of the urban culture. We need more cops. 

&gt;We have 25 % of the worlds incarcerated population. I don’t feel unsafe because somebody smoked weed in Louisiana and is prison now. A woman getting an abortion doesn’t scare me. Do you think she’s coming after you getting an abortion? Correlation is not causation.

If you actually looked at who is in prison. You would see that it's habitual offenders. You have to be convicted something like 10-11 times on average before you spend a day in prison. These are people that belong there. Not your regular weed smokers or someone getting an abortion. These are people who commit crime non stop. Of which we have a lot in US.

&gt; All I have to do is be a slightly above average murderer and I’ll never see jail time. How is that a great deterrent? Obviously it’s not because there are a lot of murderers in the U.S. because people for whatever reason think police are gods.

It's still a lot better than doing nothing. Imagine if we stopped enforcing laws. Do you think it would make us a safer place? If some city decided to stop enforcing theft laws for instance. Do you think it would make it safer to conduct business there? Of course not. All the businesses would just shut their damn doors. You need law enforcement and deterrents work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450628338.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Why does the U.S. have a ton of criminals? If police were good we wouldn’t have them. 

It’s not 10-11 times to be in prison, but let’s go with your metrics. Should we arrest everyone the first time for life since they’ll just do it again according to you?

Police can only do so much to deter. Luckily criminals are mostly disorganized here, but there’s 0 reason why a cartel couldn’t overtake a U.S. city at any point if they chose to. They have enough weaponry and can fight an insurgent type of battle that would deter people from joining the police. The way to lower the crime rate is to provide a society where people don’t want to commit crime regardless if police are there or not. 

The vast Majority of the US crime is because of the American mentality. That’s what needs to change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450685880.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It’s not 10-11 times to be in prison, but let’s go with your metrics. Should we arrest everyone the first time for life since they’ll just do it again according to you?

You're not understanding. If you studied how many times an average person has to be convinced in order to see 1 day in prison. You'd get a number between 10 and 11. Meaning if someone is in prison they are a habitual offender.

&gt;Police can only do so much to deter. Luckily criminals are mostly disorganized here, but there’s 0 reason why a cartel couldn’t overtake a U.S. city at any point if they chose to.

They would all get obliterated. You underestimate the firepower our law enforcement has. They wouldn't last a day. Not to mention our population is armed to the teeth. 

&gt;Why does the U.S. have a ton of criminals? If police were good we wouldn’t have them.

US is very uneven. Places line Norway, Sweden, Denmark. They are very even. Not too many super low IQ people. Not too many super high IQ people. US on the other hand is very uneven. You have some of the most talented people on the planet living in US. and you have 1000s upon 1000s of totally useless people. That are being dragged along by the massive amount of talent we import here through the immigration system. And before you think I'm racist a large chunk of that talent is from India and China. 

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ethnic_groups_in_the_United_States_by_household_income</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450715045.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Our country is armed to the teeth which means they are too bro. How do you not understand that? Our law enforcement has firepower but that only takes you so far.

So the US provides bad people that we need to import smart people in order to have the country function? Wild take bro. I’m done lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450740497.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>If the Narco cartel took over a city. Let's say on the border somewhere. Within about 5-6 hours that place would be completely surrounded by 1000s of law enforcement and possibly the National Guard. It would turn into a giant hostage situation. Similar to Waco.

More than likely eventually most of them get killed. 

That's just how it goes. If you think it can go any other way you simply don't understand how this country works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450777698.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Yes that’s exactly what would happen you’re correct. But let’s say every major cartel did that in every major city in Texas as an example. Do you think law enforcement and the state national guard would be enough? Remember they would just get killed like sinaloan cops do. 

Also with Waco everyone was in a house so it was clearly identifiable. It would be more accurate to compare it to Afghanistan, and I’m sure you know how that turned out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451863269.0" user="bacc1234" delta="False">
    <text>The reason violent crime fell is so much more complex than simply saying tougher policing. In some cities, yes, violent crime decreased when more police were added. However, in some cases, cities decreased their police force and violent crime decreased. If you asked a researcher whether they thought police were a significant deterrent, the most they would probably say is that they are a slight deterrent. However, a lot of them would also probably say that it’s unclear if the benefits are worth the downsides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451995545.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>What down sides? Safer streets? Less criminals to worry about?

There's practically no down sides to more police. We should always FUND the police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452083577.0" user="bacc1234" delta="False">
    <text>Increased police violence and decreased public trust in police. Plus it uses resources that could be used to fund much more beneficial programs. 

If you want to decrease violent crimes, investing in mental health, rehabilitation, and education is more beneficial than increased police. It honestly might be better to spend the money on street lights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452191209.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>There is no more beneficial program towards reducing crime than police. Almost all police violence is aimed at violent criminals. That is a good thing. That is the only language those shit birds understand.

Decreased public trust comes from race grifters who blow any situation they can latch on out of proportion. When's the last time we had a Saint George situation. Bet they are just praying for another cop to fuck up. It's already exceedingly rare. For every cop fuck up that kills some violent criminal 10000 of them kill each other.

Increased police is by far the best approach. If safe streets is what you're after</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452600400.0" user="Majestic-Pair9676" delta="False">
    <text>“Increased police is by far the best approach. If safe streets is what you’re after”

- Xi Jinping</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452834073.0" user="bacc1234" delta="False">
    <text>Spending money on the programs I mentioned would most likely do a better job of reducing crime than spending that money on more policing. Criminal justice experts are more likely to recommend programs like those than increased police. 

Based on your rhetoric though I’m guessing nothing I say will change your view on this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452604047.0" user="Majestic-Pair9676" delta="False">
    <text>This is a VERY CCP and VERY Russian thing to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453823795.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Ok so China and Russia are right about law enforcement. They are still dead wrong about many other things. Russia has the foreign policy of a total idiot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453934275.0" user="Majestic-Pair9676" delta="False">
    <text>Considering I have been to both St Petersburg and Hong Kong, and I personally know people who have been kidnapped and brutalized by Russian and Chinese police for protesting, I’m not inclined to believe you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453976831.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>You're the one who was praising them. I don't have any love for China. And I escaped Kyiv 1 month before Russia invaded. So I certainly don't have any love for the country I was born in (Russia). They can both go fuck themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454031063.0" user="Majestic-Pair9676" delta="False">
    <text>1. Exactly where and when was I praising the CCP and Russia?

2. By that standard, do not endorse policies in America that you yourself would not tolerate in Russia. No I don’t care what you think of black American culture. Nothing justifies police corruption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454058766.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>You said Russia and China have an intelligent approach to law enforcement. Maybe not in those words. 

I live in America. Not only do I tolerate aggressive policing. I think it's a very good thing. Criminals are mostly bullies. They only understand force. No other language is even capable of getting through to them. You can't be nice to people who always see being nice as a sign of weakness.

It's like Putin. Only understands force. He is a typical criminal. Just happens to be in power. We often talk about how appeasing people like Putin is a terrible idea. Yet want to structure our law enforcement on appeasement of low lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454093029.0" user="Majestic-Pair9676" delta="False">
    <text>“Ok so China and Russia are right about law enforcement. They are still dead wrong about many other things. Russia has the foreign policy of a total idiot.”

No. YOU SAID THIS.

I do not tolerate the corrupt, brutal police conduct in my ancestral home (China), so why would I tolerate it in my adopted country (USA)?

PUTIN IS THE POLICE. HE IS THE STATE. You know damn well he was Deputy Mayor of St Petersburg. You know damn well you are repeating HIS RHETORIC TO CRIME. You know damn well what Russian police are like! You SHOULD know how it worked in Russia - crime did NOT go down! It just got moved. Why the hell would you want to emulate Putin’s policies in America?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453237579.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Are you familiar with the criminal justice system in Singapore? They have one of the lowest crime rates in the world. Why do you think that is? Do you think maybe their draconian punishments have something to do with it? Or is that just a coincidence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453431842.0" user="bacc1234" delta="False">
    <text>I think that it’s irrelevant to the conversation because the conversation is not about the criminal justice system in Singapore. What is far more relevant is the research that has been done on the criminal justice system in the US, which you could read a bit about in my previous comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454977211.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>Is the idea that harsh criminal justice systems result in much lower crime in other places in the world, but that isn't true in the United States because...reasons?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457772985.0" user="bacc1234" delta="False">
    <text>The idea is that we have seen what happens when police forces are increased or decreased in the US. If you don’t like that it isn’t as straightforward as “more police = less crime” then I’m sorry, you can either accept that or deny reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450562537.0" user="Attackcamel8432" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, people clearly commit crimes and hurt others...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450580973.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Yea they do, but how often do police prevent murders? Not often or else the murderers won’t exist. Same with assaulters of any other type cold criminal. 

If they were good, they wouldn’t have to catch criminals. They would make people not want to do it in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450728625.0" user="Attackcamel8432" delta="False">
    <text>I mean... we have no idea how many murders the police prevent, because they don't happen. Same with any other crime. Obviously police have some serious institutional problems, but we can't say they have no role in preventing crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450743570.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>They have somewhat of a role in preventing it, but they don’t want to do that in lots of cities. Just look at how high profile European cops look and how many blacked out undercover cars and uniforms we have here. Cops in Europe are bright so you know they are there, and don’t commit the crime. Cops here are hidden and want to catch you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
