<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="106" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43460717531.0" user="BenedrylBooferBro" delta="False">
    <text>ACAB is stupid and is de-incentivizing good people from becoming cops… which means less good cops. It’s gen z social media cultured bull shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43493481714.0" user="xXCisWhiteSniperXx" delta="False">
    <text>I think cops dying in "training accidents" may be an important factor.

https://www.google.com/amp/s/abcnews.go.com/amp/US/lapd-officer-died-training-reporting-sexual-assault-attorney/story%3fid=91057347</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43493595815.0" user="BenedrylBooferBro" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not surprised, I’m sure this happens occasionally… what happens more often is being relocated to worse neighborhoods or jobs, or all kinds of ways the departments turn on them if they speak up.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
