<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450483579.0" user="AC-Carpenter" delta="False">
    <text>Would you make the same argument for Nazis?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453267572.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>What do Nazis do in practice? Now compare that to what the modern American police force does in practice. Do you see why that's a silly comparison?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455264504.0" user="AC-Carpenter" delta="False">
    <text>In practice, American police function to protect property, as did the slave patrols they were based on. Police take more property value than all burglars and thieves combined. Police murder more than 3 citizens per day on average. Police run over peaceful protestors, tear gas them, brutalize them, commit rape, abuse their spouses at a 40% higher rate than anyone else, they lie to you, extort you, surveil you, and prey on the communities they ostensibly exist to protect.   


So, no, I don't see why the comparison is silly. That you do demonstrates either profound ignorance or a desire to protect the fascist ideology you hold dear. I will not respond to you again, as you neither deserve your hateful position to be recognized nor was my question posed to you. Go try to convince someone else that booth leather is a delicacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455601074.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;American police function to protect property,

Do you have a breakdown of the number of crimes police respond to? Additionally, should police not protect the private property of citizens?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457978358.0" user="philiacat011" delta="False">
    <text>dam he went silent</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457951763.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; In practice, American police function to protect property, as did the slave patrols they were based on.

Why do people always cite the thing about the slave patrols as if, like (pardon my exaggeration for effect), current cops were immortals so stuck in their ways they overarrested black people because they literally still saw them as runaway slaves</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
