<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="91" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43458374746.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? 

No, I don't. I know a few cops and I believe them to be fundamentally decent people  outside their profession. I do believe most cops will protect other cops over anyone else, though. Even the ones I count as friends. They might not be racist but they'll cover things up for the ones that are. Hence, all cops are bastards.

The issue isn't that some cops are racis. In any group, there are some people that will eventually present as assholes, sometimes dangerous assholes. The issue is police departments protect these people. The culture of policing is very us vs them which only exacerbates the problem.
 
Let's put this way, I'm less appalled that *a singular cop* killed an unarmed black man over a counterfeit twenty then I am that he was still able to do after having numerous complaints filed against him and being involved in another police killing. I'm more appalled that after the numerous complaints against him, him being involved in several shootings and one killing, he was deemed appropriate to be a training officer to new cops. This is a man who was supposed to teach other cops how to behave...ACAB.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
