<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="99" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43459582765.0" user="Oldkingcole225" delta="False">
    <text>ACAB because the individual has little to no power within the institution that they work for. 

&amp;#x200B;

To make an extreme example purely for the sake of argument: imagine a genuinely good person who works at a concentration camp. Even if you tried to make the conditions better, you probably would ultimately still be doing more harm than good because there would only be so much power you can have working for that institution.

&amp;#x200B;

To get around this you can define good relative to the world around you: If you're better than the other people, then you're good. This may be the correct approach, but it would also require you to weigh the value between working for an evil institution and trying to make it good from the inside, and working against the evil institution and trying to make it good from the outside.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
