<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450864805.0" user="CliffExcellent123" delta="False">
    <text>"ACAB" doesn't mean "every cop is evil as an individual".

Many cops are perfectly nice people in their private lives.

It means they're bastards because by definition they're supporting a corrupt institution, willingly or otherwise.

Cops that call out bad cops get fired or harassed out of the force. By definition, the cops who stay in the force are either actively taking part in police brutality and corruption or at least not doing much about it.

Their participation in the force allows the brutality and corruption to continue because the bad cops can point to those cops and say "see, we're not evil, we have good cops like this guy".

And by allowing that to happen, they are a bastard... in their role as a police officer. What they are like as people is irrelevant.

Like, in the UK, there was recently a case of a police officer raping and murdering a woman while on duty. His fellow police officers knew he was capable of something like this, because he was literally nicknamed "The Rapist". Even the "good cops" knew he was sexually abusive, and they kept working with him anyway. Which means that they weren't actually good cops at all. 

If there are even a few bad cops, then the system as a whole is broken because the public can no longer trust you. The public isn't going to be happy that there's only a 1 in 1000 chance that this particular officer will murder them. 

When a police officer engages in racist brutality, do you think the person getting beat up cares if the police officer standing by and watching it happen is personally racist or not? No, they don't. They care that they're not doing anything about it. What they believe in their heart of hearts is of no use to anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451274560.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Cops that call out bad cops get fired or harassed out of the force. By definition, the cops who stay in the force are either actively taking part in police brutality and corruption or at least not doing much about it.

So if you don't get fired and/or harassed was the bad cop not bad or are you not good for stopping him</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456131007.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>So, let's take an example precinct.

A town of 50,000 with 50 police officers has had 0 reports of police brutality or any other corruption in the past 50 years.  There are no officers serving in the force that have any record of those kinds of complaints.

The police department is employed directly by the city, and none of the cops have ties to any other police, except that they have the same job description.  These cops do not even belong to a police union (or, if they do, the union only represents cops in this city).

In this city, are these 50 officers good or bad?  They do their job.  They are not overlooking other bad cops.  They are not enabling bad cops.  They are not associating with bad cops.

If you believe they are bad cops, then what action(s) can these 50 cops take in order to become good cops?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
