<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450459611.0" user="ecchi83" delta="False">
    <text>If 9 cops see 1 cop violate multiple laws that they are supposed to follow as cops bc it protects society from having an unaccountable police force, and none of those cops turn in that 1 cop, aren't those 9 cops "bad"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452434685.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>If 1 of those 9 turns that 1 in are the other 8 bad for not doing it because that 1 got there first and what about if e.g. assuming your total of 10 cops is all there is in that precinct or w/e for "spherical chickens in a vacuum" reasons 5 cops see 1 cop violate those laws and 4 are otherwise occupied with other things other places are those 4 as guilty as you might consider the 5 for not turning that bad cop in because they weren't there to see the lawbreaking</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453140782.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If 1 of those 9 turns that 1 in are the other 8 bad for not doing it because that 1 got there first

But this doesn't happen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43458003360.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't asking a question about what happens or doesn't, I was dealing with hypotheticals (otherwise I wouldn't have been acting as if this was all about a nonexistent 10-cop precinct) and the purpose of said hypotheticals was trying to determine what the bounds are for what counts as not turning them in because according to some ACAB people the only way there could be good cops is if all good cops everywhere rose up en masse to simultaneously turn in all bad cops everywhere as otherwise if anything keeps them from turning any bad cop in, from being otherwise occupied to jurisdiction to even just someone else turning them in first, that means they're part of the problem and bad cops too</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43462679668.0" user="AndrenNoraem" delta="False">
    <text>A conspiracy in which guilty people go unpunished and whistle-blowers are killed or otherwise silenced, I think definitely should count. [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank\_Serpico](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Serpico) for an example.

[https://starherald.com/news/state-regional/crime-courts/former-lpd-sgt-angela-sands-wins-whistleblower-award/article\_d2bb2568-600b-5be3-ac03-0cfddea75b0c.html](https://starherald.com/news/state-regional/crime-courts/former-lpd-sgt-angela-sands-wins-whistleblower-award/article_d2bb2568-600b-5be3-ac03-0cfddea75b0c.html)

[https://www.wwltv.com/article/news/crime/state-police-whistleblower-fired-for-speaking-out-about-ronald-greene-beating/289-31a00e5d-25a7-4286-8535-f0df006bab1e](https://www.wwltv.com/article/news/crime/state-police-whistleblower-fired-for-speaking-out-about-ronald-greene-beating/289-31a00e5d-25a7-4286-8535-f0df006bab1e)

There are a couple more that took me literally like 5 seconds to Google.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43467045524.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't saying cases of conspiracy didn't exist I was saying it isn't proof of conspiracy if not every cop everywhere knows what every other cop everywhere is doing 100% of the time. And really, one of my hypotheticals was about if if someone turned in a bad cop does that make everyone else a bad cop for not getting there first, does that mean everyone would have been conspiring to hang back and let one guy do it instead of somehow arresting him en masse</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
