<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="56" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43455593010.0" user="Happy-Load3736" delta="False">
    <text>The concept isn't that every single cop will beat you and scream racist remarks.

The concept is, we know this is something that is widespread. We know this is systemically assisted and the perpetrators are given paid vacations and little else as punishment. We know that while not universal it is very common.

Because of that, those not participating directly but also doing nothing to stop or change any of it are considered guilty by association in the same way that if you walk in to a gas station with your friend, and your friend robs the gas station while you stand around looking at slushies, then yoy both drive off...you're an accessory to the crime and will also go to jail.

Since the corruption of cops is very widespread, it's hard to find a precinct where there isn't some degree of this happening. By association, the non-bad cops who allow the bad cops to keep doing what they're doing are accessories and thus guilty as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
