<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450377171.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Not every cop is racist. But every cop chooses to be a cop, and so they choose to work for a racist system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450540640.0" user="Business_Cheesecake7" delta="False">
    <text>Racist system? wtf are you on about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450589152.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Policing, especially in countries where 'ACAB' is a common statement, is racially biased. Minorities are frequently over policed. Everyone who signs up to be a cop knows this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450617091.0" user="Business_Cheesecake7" delta="False">
    <text>Well yeah, that's in sketchy neighborhoods with lots of gangs and stuff. Outside of that, in stuff like regular urban patrolling and highway/interstate patrolling, there is no "racial bias". It's not like all cops share some similar DNA that makes them racially biased. Saying that the policing system is racist gives off the same vibes that saying "obesity as a medical term is a slur and fatphobic" does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450633791.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's very much also highway and interstate patrolling. [Traffic stops become less racially biased when the police can't see the race of the people driving.](https://news.stanford.edu/2020/05/05/veil-darkness-reduces-racial-bias-traffic-stops/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453260151.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Minorities are frequently over policed.

This is always an interesting argument. A couple things to think about. The police should go where they're needed, right? These happen to be minority neighborhoods for whatever reason. This is probably why [80% of Black Americans want the same or more police presence in their neighborhoods.](https://news.gallup.com/poll/316571/black-americans-police-retain-local-presence.aspx)

It's interesting that so many people have this weird idea like cops just stroll through black neighborhoods and arrest people for no reason. That must be your belief, right? Because if you agreed that black people are being arrested *justly,* then you wouldn't make this argument. Then the police are just doing their jobs and focusing their resources where they're needed most. A disparity in the races being arrested is just that, a disparity. There may be some other reason why so much more crime occurs in minority communities, but that's another question. Like one might wonder why gang membership in America is [85-90% Black or Hispanic](https://nationalgangcenter.ojp.gov/survey-analysis/demographics) (scroll to bottom). But you can't really blame the cops for that unless you have some kind of convoluted explanation I haven't heard before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455933846.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But every cop chooses to be a cop, and so they choose to work for a racist system.  
&gt;  
&gt;Everyone who signs up to be a cop knows this.

Even if they sign up to be a cop in a city, county, state, or country where racism is NOT common from the position of power?  Where racial profiling is not a weekly, or even monthly occurrence?

You are dealing in absolutes, and that's the exact issue here.  There are good cops, and good precincts.  You don't hear about them on the news, because "nothing racist happened today" isn't a headline that gets viewership/readership.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
