<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450720616.0" user="KamikazeArchon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested.

And who should do that?

Other cops.

Who isn't doing that?

Other cops.

&gt;But come on, not every cop is bad.

Every good cop quickly either stops being good, or *stops being a cop*. Good cops get fired.

The core of the issue is this: one cop engages in brutality. Ten other cops watch and don't do anything about it.

ACAB is essentially the assertion that those other cops are also bad cops. Yes, even if they're sometimes saving lives and stopping crimes. Standing by and watching the brutality - and not attempting to stop it - makes them bad cops.

And virtually all cops do that. The ones that do try to stop brutality (and sexual assault, and other bad things) rapidly get fired (there are plenty of examples of this). All the ones that are left are the ones who are willing to ignore the bad things happening.

And, uniquely, cops are the only part of society where "I couldn't do anything about it" is expressly *not* a defense. Police explicitly have a monopoly of violence. They have weapons and the express authorization to use them to protect the people. Literally every cop that sees another cop commit brutality, sexual assault, etc. *can shoot that cop* (or taze them, or handcuff them, or in general, *physically* take action). That's what they're *for*. If they're not doing that, then they're bad cops. And, as we clearly see, they're not doing that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451267976.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>But the problem is a lot of how a lot of ACAB arguments are framed make it sound like e.g. if one cop stopped an incident of brutality from another cop every other cop in the precinct (if not every other cop in the country because I swear some ACAB people talking about "how cops should act if they could be good and still be cops" forget jurisdiction exists) is a bad cop for technically standing by even though they were only standing by because that one cop got there first and they couldn't all simultaneously stop the one bad guy</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
