<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450525910.0" user="Injuredmind" delta="False">
    <text>Timely one, as here in Ukraine we have an ongoing discussion on recent incident in city of Dnipro. Drunk guy was speeding, swapped places with a passenger after being chased by police, then got out of the car without permission and assaulted policemen, resulting in traumatising a woman officer and got shot by her fellow officer. Officer who shot the guy is now a suspect of excessive use of power. 
Society divided into two groups, one says cop was doing what he had to do, as drunk driver obviously was ignoring the law and was a threat to everyone on the road and then to a police officer he assaulted, that may have ended in him seizing her weapon or killing her. The second group says that it was an excessive use of power and policeman shouldn’t have killed the drunk driver.
I stand with the group one, as it feels right to me that officer protected his partner and he had all the reasons to use lethal power in this situation.
What do you think?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
