<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="100" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43459621358.0" user="AdFun5641" delta="False">
    <text>ACAB

There is a phrase cops love when talking about the incidents that bring ACAB back into the media.  That phrase is "It's just one bad apple".  This phrase is so very correct.

One bad apple spoils the bunch.

They have been saying "One bad apple" since the 1980's with the brutal beating of Rodny King.

They should be kicking the bad apples out to prevent the spread of rot.  But they don't.  They circle the wagons and protect the bad apples.

40 years of keeping the bad apples and the bunch is spoiled.

\&gt;Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired

But they don't.  They keep that cop and fire the one trying to out the bad apple.  ACAB

\&gt;Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested.

But they don't.  They keep the bad apple and fire the one trying to arrest the armed thug.  ACAB

\&gt; And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But trying to stop racism in the police as police just gets you fired.  They keep the bad apple over the good cop every time.  This is why ACAB</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
