<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="77" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43457413847.0" user="elinder10" delta="False">
    <text>Prefacing this by saying I live in the US, my life experiences and political knowledge are focused in the US, and I'm speaking from those experiences  and about the US only. 

ACAB because there's literally no way to 100% be a good cop. My boyfriend's uncle was a cop for 25 years. He was a "good" cop. He got sergeant, and then never moved up again because he refused to look the other way when other cops did shit things. He tried his best to speak up when other officers were abusing their power. Nothing came of it except threats to his job security, so eventually he... stopped bothering. He became another complicit cog in the system. He never did anything "bad", but he stood by and stopped attempting to intervene when others would be racist towards the heavily Latino population in his town, he stopped trying to punish cops for attempting to get street racers to crash even though it's illegal and resulted in two deaths. He stopped speaking up at all. The reality is that racist/abusive/violent/even just generally, mildly shitty cops do not get punished 98% of the time. They do not get fired. They get put on administrative leave (often paid) and then reinstated or shuffled to another precinct when the heat dies down. And if you're a cop who's not racist/abusive/violent/generally shitty, you have two choices: speak up every time you see something go wrong, which is often, and deal with never moving up and potentially losing your job, or stay silent and complicit. The ones who speak up stop being cops. The ones who give in are bastards, no matter how good they may be-- they're contributing to the problem because they'd rather get paid than find another career. 

The way to unbastardize cops and policing would be to get rid of qualified immunity entirely and hold cops to a higher standard than the general populace. There's no reason not to; if they're expected to uphold the law, they should be held to a higher standard than your average joe, or else what's the point? 

My personal experiences with cops went like this: I got raped. Went to the police because I thought it was what I was supposed to do. Was grilled 3x, which was extremely traumatizing especially considering I was still a child. All i asked of them was to give me fair warning if/when they brought in the guy who did it, because I was afraid he would retaliate against me. They did not do that. They called me one day, 3 months later when i was at work, and I asked "hey, if this is bad news can you wait because I'm at work", and the cop spoke over me to tell me they were dropping my case and there was nothing they could do and to "stay away from him in the future". Threw up in the sink at work and had to deal with managing mounting hysteria for the next three hours; they could have just told me after, but why the hell would they care, lmao?

Two months after that they tried to have me arrested for trespassing/stealing copper from abandoned buildings in my hometown, despite the fact that I was living a half hour away and attending college at the time. The reason? I had donated my old semi-used sketchbooks to the homeless shelter that summer, and one of the dudes who got one of the sketchbooks had been stealing the copper and had left the sketchbook in the building. They did not believe me when I said that I had donated them. I spent a lot of time volunteering at the homeless shelter that summer and working with homeless people, many of whom were drug addicts. During the time I was interrogated I was explicitly told that's why they considered me a criminal and were trying to get me arrested. Because I bothered to try to help homeless people and didn't see drug addicts as inherently evil/ "bad news" or some shit equivalent.

Eventually they found the guy and he fully admitted to both the stealing and ownership of the sketchbook. I did not get an apology. The cop who interrogated me \*came to my job\*, interrogated my manager for my work schedule, and then showed up on my shift to try to talk to me, very clearly wanting me to say "it's fine" or "don't worry about it" but also refusing to apologize for how he treated me for the crime of \*seeing homeless people as people\*.  The same cop later that year would wait outside of my job every day because he had a personal vendetta against one of my (nonwhite) coworkers who had been very protective of me the day that he came to my job to try and find me, and was trying to get him arrested for MONTHS. After every shift he would stop him and search him and find nothing. Eventually I made a point of waiting after work to give the guy a lift home, because I felt really bad for him and couldn't believe the cop's behavior. Last year that same cop got awarded by the precinct for "exemplary policing". Lol. 

Other highlights of cops in my area: There is one town whose cops are known for being so extremely racist that it's essentially still a "sundown town" for nonwhite people. Mixed families will not bring their kids to the park because it's across from the police building and they will be harassed. Cops in another town near my college killed a guy having a mental health crisis; he was on the third floor balcony with a knife threatening suicide, and cops shot him from the ground, there was no reason for it. The cop who shot him is still there. They also killed a teenager on a dirtbike for a traffic violation by ramming him. The state cops right now are under investigation for falsifying thousands of traffic tickets, all for nonexistent people who were labeled as "white" in the system which beyond getting the cops responsible a fat bonus check for nothing, also covered up racist policing/rate of stopping nonwhite drivers at far higher rates than white drivers. My sister and I both got stopped for broken taillights in my town and had little dangly charms hanging from the driver mirror; no tickets. They never even mentioned them. I didn't even know it was technically illegal until my nonwhite coworker (the one being harassed by the cop) was stopped for nothing and ticketed for having rosary beads. 

Anyway. Not all cops are bad people, but ACAB, because the system is broken, and there's no way to change it from the inside. You just end up working alongside murderers and racists and scumbags and anyone who does that for a paycheck is a bastard, regardless of whether their own behavior is good or bad.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
