<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450293422.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>There were thousand of people in the Nazi party. I'm sure as individuals some of those people were good, never harmed or killed a jew. Does that mean all nazis aren't bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450323688.0" user="No-Pineapple-3819" delta="False">
    <text>Police officers are not comparable to Nazis</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450353053.0" user="youngsurpriseperson" delta="False">
    <text>True, and I think both of you are right. Not all Nazis were bad, frankly they became Nazis because they were afraid I believe. Nobody becomes a police officer because they're afraid, and that's one of the many reasons why officers≠Nazis</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450360820.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have an answer to the question?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450335734.0" user="BainterBoi" delta="False">
    <text>They had harmful ideology. What harmful ideology police has? Wtf is this analogy xd</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450373185.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>[https://www.aclu.org/issues/racial-justice/race-and-criminal-justice/racial-profiling](https://www.aclu.org/issues/racial-justice/race-and-criminal-justice/racial-profiling)

[https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/report-black-people-are-still-killed-police-higher-rate-groups-rcna17169](https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/report-black-people-are-still-killed-police-higher-rate-groups-rcna17169)

[https://www.murphyfalcon.com/uncategorized/how-common-is-it-for-police-to-plant-evidence-in-baltimore/#:\~:text=Planting%20evidence%20means%20to%20establish,wrongfully%20convicting%20an%20innocent%20person](https://www.murphyfalcon.com/uncategorized/how-common-is-it-for-police-to-plant-evidence-in-baltimore/#:~:text=Planting%20evidence%20means%20to%20establish,wrongfully%20convicting%20an%20innocent%20person).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450395236.0" user="BainterBoi" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, they still lack common, harmful ideology that labels the whole party. Just belonging to nazis attached you to certain ideology, that is literally idea of political party?

Just belonging to police force definitely does not attach you to ideology of  racial profiling or evidence planting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450466401.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Yes, they still lack common, harmful ideology that labels the whole party. 

Who is they? The Nazis or police? Because in order to be Nazi you must hold lean towards the political and social view of Nazis

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Just belonging to police force definitely does not attach you to ideology of racial profiling or evidence planting.

Of course it does when that is what police are trained to do. You think over policing in predominately poor neighborhoods with people of color happen by accident? What about the loads of cops who were fired for reporting misconduct or abuse? How about all those cops in Atlanta who caught the "Blue Flu" and refused to work because they didn't like the verdict of a case? The culture of the "Thin Blue Line" is a very real thing and you must abide by it if you want to make the career of being a police officer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450499757.0" user="BainterBoi" delta="False">
    <text>No you absolutely don’t have to abide it, not in any first world countries at least. Polices don’t  automatically subscribe publicly to certain ideologies as party members indeed do.

There is clear contradiction in your statement even. You state that individuals went as far as getting themselves fired in order to report misconducts. You provided a concrete example of individual cops who clearly did not subscribe to shady things going on with apparently part of the police forces.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450574848.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;No you absolutely don’t have to abide it, not in any first world countries at least. Polices don’t automatically subscribe publicly to certain ideologies as party members indeed do.

Literally you don't, but you're much more likely to find yourself being given the worst assignments, passed over for promotions, or even out of a job. So anyone who wants to be a cop long term will abide by the 'Thin Blue Line". Cops themselves have admit it's a thing

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;There is clear contradiction in your statement even. You state that individuals went as far as getting themselves fired in order to report misconducts. You provided a concrete example of individual cops who clearly did not subscribe to shady things going on with apparently part of the police forces.

Yes and those people were fired meaning they are no longer cops. No contradiction there at all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450595072.0" user="BainterBoi" delta="False">
    <text>So your point is that those people were bastards as they were trying to change the system and were cops at the time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450673711.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>No they were bastards because they were initially supporting the system. But because they took a firm stand against the system they were removed from the system resulting in them no longer being cop thus no longer being bastards</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452486348.0" user="sailorbrendan" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Just belonging to police force definitely does not attach you to ideology of racial profiling or evidence planting.

https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2021/08/11/police-training-warrior-mindset-killology/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453225419.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;https://www.aclu.org/issues/racial-justice/race-and-criminal-justice/racial-profiling  
&gt;  
&gt;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/report-black-people-are-still-killed-police-higher-rate-groups-rcna17169

Disparity is not evidence of oppression. By this logic, Kindergarten Teaching and Nursing are oppressive to men because women dominate the field.

&gt;link about police in Baltimore planting evidence

There are 14,000 police precincts in the United States. Evidence of wrongdoing at one is not evidence for any other of the precincts. It doesn't even necessarily damn that precinct, because this bad behavior is done by individuals, who can be removed and replaced.

&gt;So police encounters are more likely to leave low-income people of color feeling unsafe, and influxes of white residents in low-income communities of color are resulting in more and more quality-of-life complaints that bring the police into these communities—at least 92.5 percent of all quality-of-life complaints

That's interesting because [80% of Black Americans want the same or more police presence in their neighborhoods](https://news.gallup.com/poll/316571/black-americans-police-retain-local-presence.aspx). Also, I'm not sure that someone "feeling unsafe" is an empirical argument or based in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453977042.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not gonna respond to this with anything of substance because not only did you fail to respond with substance to the links I’ve posted and just said “nuh uh”, you didn’t even take the time to completely read the article you’ve linked which doesnt support the comment you’ve made</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450371515.0" user="Sea-Scratch8800" delta="False">
    <text>Your statement is a contradiction. If all Nazis are bad, then no one who was a Nazi could have been good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43450402020.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>I think no matter how good a Nazi is, they are still inherently bad because they are a Nazi giving support to an unjst and racist system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455910117.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>If you weren't a Nazi, you were vulnerable.

People joined while the Nazis were in power just to protect themselves and their families.

Sure, you supported the system.  But not due to any inherent badness.  And the moment the threat was gone, they ditched the party, and never actually shared it's ideology.

If you believe people are evil for being coerced into something simply because they want to protect their children, you're going to find evil everywhere.

Hell, using that logic you can argue that every service technician working for Comcast is evil because they support the massive corporate greed and customer exploitation that the company is known for.  Even if they just want to earn enough $$ to put food on the table for their family, and ran out of other options.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455960218.0" user="RseAndGrnd" delta="False">
    <text>How many people has Comcast killed?

And by your logic very few people can be considered bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43456061945.0" user="Educational_Ebb7175" delta="False">
    <text>By my logic, you must take evil actions to be evil.  Just being a serf in an evil Kingdom does not make you evil, like your logic allows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457922093.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If you weren't a Nazi, you were vulnerable.
&gt; 
&gt; People joined while the Nazis were in power just to protect themselves and their families.
&gt; 
&gt; Sure, you supported the system. But not due to any inherent badness. And the moment the threat was gone, they ditched the party, and never actually shared it's ideology.
&gt; 
&gt; If you believe people are evil for being coerced into something simply because they want to protect their children, you're going to find evil everywhere.

And many people who make the "you would have been a Nazi if you lived in that era of Germany" arguments seem to forget that even if you'd still have been you enough to make that comparison you likely would have been that kind of Nazi yet they frame the arguments like you'd be so high up the party you'd e.g. be getting handwritten Christmas cards from Hitler</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43453212191.0" user="Busy_Law1778" delta="False">
    <text>What evidence convinced you that each of the 14,000 police precincts in America engage in immoral behavior on a regular basis? Especially similar to Nazis?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
