<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="137" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44127895013.0" user="Medical-Addition1188" delta="False">
    <text>These arguments are logically sound
The reason all copscare criminals isn't hard to understand.
Now , im not a fan of " all  " in anything because its lazy and nothing is absolute
But there is a good argument that all cops serving are criminals.
First , The Blue Wall Of Silence  , to cover for other cops crimes is basically a criminal conspiracy and to ignore the crimes committed by cops whike you are a cop is not only criminal , its immoral and unethical.
Byt we can simplify. Every cop lies on the stand,  usually its lying by omission and they know they are lying . That is perjury , so at minimum all cops commit perjury. But its easier. Any cop that blows the whistle on other cops is harassed,  bullied , ultimately fired and blackludted by other cops
So good people dont last as cops 
Irs really thst simple  , if they are on the job they are keeping quiet and lying on stand. I haven't mentioned how they " help witnesses fill in the blanks " which is responsible for most false conviction 
All cops on the job  are criminals , its so easy to prove that nobody i know argues againstvthat statement and I am in philosophical circles 
If i tried to say that not all cops are criminals in a discussion I'd be ripped apart all night , ridiculed and maybe even uninvited to the next event</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
