<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450501407.0" user="Mr___Wrong" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, ACABs.  Let me give you an analogy.  I was a teacher for 32 years.  If one of my fellow teachers was abusing a kid, what am I supposed to do?  Maintain the thin chalk line and not turn them in?  Or have some integrity and realize you're there to serve and protect, not cover-up.

Every cop is a bastard because they don't stand up for what's right-they stand up for their buddy.  That's bullshit.  No difference between that and a teacher trying to cover for another teacher who is abusing or whatnot.  Imagine if cops turned in other cops for the crap they pull, that shit would end overnight.  Until they do, fuck all cops.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43451562805.0" user="RoozGol" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Every cop is a bastard because they don't stand up for what's right-they stand up for their buddy. 

Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452128134.0" user="itssbojo" delta="False">
    <text>32 years of students taught by a dumbass…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454658971.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43454659734.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/itssbojo – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20itssbojo&amp;message=itssbojo%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/-/jym9wna/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452523741.0" user="bigbobbybeaver" delta="False">
    <text>Schools are definitely not innocent of covering up malfeasance.

Or churches. Or politicians. Or colleges. Or sports. Or corporations. It's not just cops.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43452640345.0" user="Majestic-Pair9676" delta="False">
    <text>Police can kill you, or get you killed. The tragic case of Uvalde, Texas not very long ago has illustrated this.

Police Unions need to be dismantled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43455456260.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>See Mom two wrongs really do make a right!!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43461969673.0" user="bigbobbybeaver" delta="False">
    <text>Because that's what I'm saying. Learn better comprehension skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43463707064.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure how old you are. Generally speaking for adults when someone brings up reflexively and response to someone's point is generally considered a rebuttal.

If you're not trying to make a rebuttal don't offer counter evidence in the middle of a discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43466585392.0" user="bigbobbybeaver" delta="False">
    <text>My point is, it's not just cops, it's a human problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43457972971.0" user="philiacat011" delta="False">
    <text>you can say this about literally anything</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
