<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="51" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43455191927.0" user="chemicalrefugee" delta="False">
    <text>You can either be a good person or a good cop.

If you are a good person then you want to help people. You want reasonable responses to things not back and white rules that do a lot of harm. But that isn't what you get handed as a cop.  
For a person to be a 'good cop' they have to do as they are told without question. They must work inside of the existing system, following the rules &amp; doing as they are told. This will also most definitly harm innocent people. They will send innocent people to jail and let guilty people go in order to keep the DA's convition rates high. A good cop has to enforce all the rules. If you become a cop you have to take an oath to enforce the law without favoritism. Doing that makes you a bad person because the law is wrong.  


The US system is overwheminly racist and 90% of convictions come from coerced plea deals that used to be unconstitutional. You cannot be a good person and be a part of that system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
