<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="69" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43456372132.0" user="SuchPerfectPeace" delta="False">
    <text>disclaimer: this isnt necessarily to convince anyone !!! moreso to explain the full reasoning as to why acab isnt necessarily black/white thinking 

acab essentially means that all cops working under the system are bad, because the system is fundamentally flawed. pretty much any cop that isnt bad, will be fired. 

the reason why i personally disagree with the idea that cops prevent crime, is because by statistics they dont. if you have ever had a bad mental health episode and someone called the cops on you, you get treated like a criminal. while the main reason that serial killers walk free for so long and are able to continue a string of crimes is due to police negligence, oftentimes blatantly ignoring evidence just due to it pointing to a white person. 

not to mention the 40% statistic, about how 20% of spouses of cops REPORT domestic abuse. which is presumably a low ball considering the amount of people who wouldnt feel safe to report it etcetc. 

unfortunately a lot of this stuff can be found easily and so before anyone gets on my ass 20% [1](https://leadstories.com/hoax-alert/2021/06/fact-check-studies-put-the-rate-of-officer-perpetrated-domestic-violence-between-5-percent-and-40-percent.html) [2](https://sites.temple.edu/klugman/2020/07/20/do-40-of-police-families-experience-domestic-violence/) || crime "prevention" [1](https://www.justice.gc.ca/eng/cj-jp/state-etat/2019rpt-rap2019/p7.html) [2](https://www.reuters.com/legal/government/police-are-not-primarily-crime-fighters-according-data-2022-11-02/) [3](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kidnapping_of_Jaycee_Dugard#Missed_rescue_opportunities) || victim blaming/firing good cops [1](https://toronto.ctvnews.ca/toronto-cop-who-tweeted-about-alleged-workplace-sexual-harassment-to-be-fired-1.6382330) [2](https://nypost.com/2020/07/02/massachusetts-detective-fired-over-anti-cop-instagram-post/) || people all around not feeling safe or happy w cops [1](https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/pub/85-002-x/2020001/article/00014-eng.htm) [2](https://www.publicsafety.gc.ca/cnt/rsrcs/pblctns/2015-r034/index-en.aspx) || stats \[death\] [1](https://www.statista.com/statistics/585152/people-shot-to-death-by-us-police-by-race/) [2](https://www.statista.com/statistics/1362796/number-people-killed-police-us/) ||   
(sorry for mainly canadian resources, the us is a lot more sticky about hiding their stats)

once again, this isnt to convince anyone. just to explain the reasoning behind it as someone in leftist circles</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
