<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="109" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43461071013.0" user="Ok-Investigator3257" delta="False">
    <text>I always hated ACAB, from what I can tell there are 2 different types of peaceful protest in the US. Those aimed at institutions, and those aimed at groups of people (the rich, white people etc.). People generally don't mind protests against institutions (like say policing) nearly as much as they mind protests aimed at the people. We saw both during the height of the BLM protests.

I would argue that the initial Colin Kappernick protests were aimed not at the institution of policing, but at the society that enabled and incentivized the system to behave they way it did. Because it asked individuals to look in the mirror and take some responsibility for what was going on you got a lot of negative feedback considering it was just one dude on a football field. 

So let's look at those incentives. America is a pretty seriously violent society. Understandably we don't like violent crime, so the people in power just want it to "go away". By which I mean they want their constituents to stop thinking it is bad. Those same constituents want to not raise taxes. See the thing is that per capita America has about 1/6th the total number of officers compared to most of western Europe, and they get about 1/6th the training. Now let me ask you if you are understaffed, and under trained, and your bosses keep telling you to just "do your job and make the problem go away". What do you do? Well you might ask for more manpower, and training, but that costs money, and no one wants to pay for it. Well...force is a great manpower multiplier. One violent cop can keep a lot of people in line. So someone tries that, and the system looks up and sees that no one cares. No one told them to be violent, but it works, and no one is telling them NOT to, and other options keep getting actively denied because of money, so violence wins. 

&amp;#x200B;

ACAB is'nt really the problem. The problem is in the mirror. Systems respond to incentives. Expecting the system to be superhumanly moral in response to incentives that push it to be violent isn't realistic, and the blame lies IMO more with those laying out incentives than the institution under those incentives.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
