<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43450365240.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think every cop is out to get me. 

However, every cop does sign up to support the laws, and if the laws are evil, that creates some difficulties. Consider, say, working as a cop in Nazi Germany. You're going to have some moral dilemmas by the nature of the job. Perhaps a particularly moral individual can subvert the system and do good with it, but it is very, very easy to end up passively supporting injustice in numerous small ways. 

There was a clearly unjust police killing near me. I don't think every cop in the department wanted that to happen or was there. I do think that every cop fell into line to not contradict the official story, and to excuse not showing the warrant or body cam footage. It's been years now, and neither is out. 

Logically, this makes trusting the entire department difficult. Someone willing to at least contribute a little bit to covering up a murder is not a reliable ally.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
