<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="123" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43464813496.0" user="doodlebilly" delta="False">
    <text>My little Brother is a cop I love him with all my heart, regardless ACAB and I mean it.
Cops engage in an overwhelmingly powerful social system that coerces them into behaviors that benefit said system, regardless of an individual's good intentions. Social systems and pressures within the police departments affect the way laws are enforced and  how officers conduct themselves when enforcing. Not every asshole cop starts as an asshole, they engage with a system that slowly rewarded their behaviors until they became the asshole cop. Policing is a brutal occupation that takes way more than it gives and turns nice kids into violent thumbs that will shoot your dog. 

ACAB is a way for us non cop folks to apply our own social pressure for change. You can't change a powerful system like policing by becoming a cop. Mounting social pressures is one of the only tools we have. Friends don't let friends become thumbs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
