<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43451923946.0" user="Wyrdeone" delta="False">
    <text>It should be ACBB - all cops become bad.

The ones who don't last aren't cops anymore, and the ones that stay in get polluted by their lopsided experiences.

All cops should have a 3-month rotation between active policing and community service. It's much, much harder to hate people you know. It's easy to hate a group of people if all your interactions with them in the past year have been negative. If every black man you met last month was stealing something or shooting someone, you might get biased too. 

Y'all gotta remember that cops mostly deal with criminals. They don't usually get called to cookouts where everybody behaving and having fun. It's rare when a cop, in their daily routine, gets to hang out with folks and develop bonds and appreciate their humanity.

I've personally known one good-hearted individual who joined the force because he wanted to do good. He left after a year and a half because he couldn't take the pressure of being surrounded by a bunch of nazi fucks. I've also known a couple of normal guys who joined the force and after several years of service became unrecognizable. They devolved.

The lure of power is real, and experience bias is real.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
