<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="97" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43459222531.0" user="lone-lemming" delta="False">
    <text>There are bad cops. Cops that commit crimes.  Cops who are hateful and violent and don’t help people. those cops are bad. 

Every cop that doesn’t stop a bad cop thats committing a crime is also a cop that’s not doing their job. 
Cops who aren’t doing their job are also bad cops.
  “But maybe they don’t know who the criminal cops are?” Is the next question. 

But All you need to do is look up domestic violence among police statistics to know that there’s too many cops coming crimes for the rest of them to know. 

Every day a bad cop goes to work next to a good cop, is a day that two bad cops go to work side by side. 
A cop that’s bad one day is a bad cop from then on. Just like a murderer is a murderer every day after he kills someone and a thief stays a thief.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
