<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="108" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43460963016.0" user="Hidobot" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine there are two police officers. One is named Johnny, and the other is named Tom.

Everyone loves Johnny. He's very courteous and kind, he goes out of his way to support people and to protect the community, he even volunteers at an animal shelter on his time off. Absolutely no one thinks he's a bad person in any way, and he's the kind of person you want to be trusted with authority.

Tom is mean. He uses his authority as a police officer to intimidate people into giving him what he wants, he doesn't care about the precinct at all, and sometimes he even hurts people during arrests more than he needs to, such as by slamming them into walls or roughly tackling them when he doesn't need to. Johnny doesn't like Tom.

Imagine there's no other officers like Tom in the department, but there are 100 of Johnny. Most people like the cops named Johnny, but the commissioner for the department will not fire Tom for whatever reason. The police explicitly have the authority to enforce public order and the law with whatever means they deem necessary, including killing suspects.

So essentially, no matter how much actual good the department does, they still let Tom have a gun and a badge and the same authority as every other officer, and if he messes up and shoots the wrong person, the most that can happen is he gets fired. Tom is held by the same rules as every other officer, and the police as an institution are supporting Tom.

I trust officers like Johnny not to shoot people, and to be honest the police officers I have spoken to are fine as people. Some have been kind to me and I have never personally been abused by a police officer, though some of my friends and acquaintances have. My point in this story is that no matter how kind an individual officer is, they're still letting people like Tom have a gun and authority to enforce the law.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
