<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2550857978.0" index="42" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/166pqm2/cmv_not_all_cops_are_bad_people_and_people_who/">
    <title>CMV: Not all cops are bad people and people who believe ACAB suffer from black and white thinking</title>
    <original_poster>youngsurpriseperson</original_poster>
    <original_post>I get it, police brutality is a thing and there is plenty of video evidence of it. Police brutality is bad and any cop who does something like hide their badge or turn off their camera should be fired. Any cop who engages in brutality should be arrested. And racist cops are obviously bad too.

But come on, not every cop is bad. Sure the meaning of "to protect and serve" may have dwindled down over time, but come on, do you really believe that every cop out there is racist? Do you really believe that cops are out to get you? And without cops, many people (including you) would be committing crimes. You might be dead without cops, even though some of them have shot innocent people.

I have never seen any good argument against my view, even though apparently it's seen as bad. I don't get it. Is ACAB just an exagerration or am I missing something? Please help change my view on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43452893317.0" user="WornOutMeatCurtins" delta="False">
    <text>Staunch believer that ACAB. And when I say it, I mean ALL of them. 

The day they sign up, they are fully aware they are going to work for a corrupt system.  

They are aware the police unions are responsible for getting cops that belong in prison, free, and working at new departments. 


They are willing to ignore a fellow cop that breaks laws they have or would arrest others for.

The police hold an astronomical amount of power the  could destroy lives on a whim.  Seriously.  A lot of people out there can't afford to miss work being paycheck to paycheck. 1 chance encounter with a pissy cop could easily land someone unjustly arrested. Without the ability to make bail they could set in jail for months resulting in eviction, repossessions, job loss, even loose their kids to DCF.  Even if found not guilty they a free looking at having to completely start over. Many people will, even if innocent plee on a lesser charge just to avoid months longer waiting on trial.


And who holds a cop accountable?  No one.  No one will look at the case and say "oh weird better investigate this"
A multitude of Cort rulings have determined that police are not even under an obligation to work in favor of citizens they police, nor are they required to know

They could fix the system they work for. If there weren't a majority bad apples, why would a majority good want to work under a system that's so easily abused and corrupted?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
