<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="102" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511624134.0" user="AstuteButIgnored" delta="False">
    <text>No, there isn't. The only people who whine about this, in my experience, are Latin Americans. As a Mexican-American, I just have to say that you never see a Candian claiming to be American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512656866.0" user="blurplesnow" delta="False">
    <text>It's not whining when it's true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513012569.0" user="wad11656" delta="False">
    <text>This has got to be the stupidest thing I've read in a long time.

 I've never whined about something I didn't believe was true. You are a literal idiot. Already proven by the fact that you're one of the annoying losers OP is talking about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513161505.0" user="Discosm" delta="False">
    <text>But it is true though. Latin americans are americans just as a german is european.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513362026.0" user="TheCupOfBrew" delta="False">
    <text>No, you're being dishonest on purpose. 

The region is literally named North America. What others call it shouldn't matter more than us, the people who live here.

I haven't ever encountered any Mexican or Canadian people who were ever confused when they heard "American". It's quite literally South Americans trying to push that ahit onto everyone for no reason.

The continent argument doesn't even make sense cause then how are Europe and Asia different continents? The Americas are connected by a thing strip of land.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514282543.0" user="CaliperLee62" delta="False">
    <text>If you wanted to insist you could call a German *Afro-Eurasian,* but you'd usually sound stupid for doing so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515097831.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513084912.0" user="WaterWorksWindows" delta="False">
    <text>When speaking about an “American” it refers to the country “United stated of America” not the continent(s) of “the Americas”. People refer to and ask about your nationality, not your continent of origin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515096833.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
