<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="218" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512641815.0" user="aphel_ion" delta="False">
    <text>I think of a lot of this is a language thing. In Spain, Estadounidense (unitedstatesian) is the proper word for it, and it’s used a lot by regular people. So if I’m speaking I’m Spanish I’ll often use that word to refer to myself. 

In English there is no word other than “American” to describe people from the United States. When anybody says “American” everybody knows exactly what it means. Nobody in the English speaking world, under any circumstances, would ever describe Shakira or Lionel Messi as Americans. 

If someone is trying to teach you a foreign language or are introducing you to their culture, I would defer to them and use the words that they use. If however they’re trying to tell you that in English saying “American” is wrong and disrespectful, they can go pound sand.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
