<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="264" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513199422.0" user="jakeofheart" delta="False">
    <text>It’s just like with a few other things, it sends the message that you folks assume that the world revolves around y’all.

It’s like “American soccer”. Or “the World Champions” of the USA.

Imagine if a European country hijacked the adjective European. What are the other ones then?

You came up with a name for [residents of each of your 50 states](https://statesymbolsusa.org/symbol-official-item/national-us/state-resident-name/all-state-residents?utm_content=cmp-true) and [your biggest cities](https://www.popsci.com/diy/resident-nickname-most-populous-us-cities/?amp). Demonyms.

But coming up for a national adjective is too much work?

In Italian for example, they use the adjective “statunitense” (unitedstatesian) for you folks. That’s a mouthful all right, but at least it shows that it is not impossible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
