<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510837124.0" user="Fermi_Amarti" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't anything particularly wrong with you individually doing it. I mean if you want to know where the problem probably occurred was when the found fathers named our country the United States of America like the rest of North and South America didn't exist. And then chose to use American. I mean we were only tiny 13 states in 2 continents back then. But yes it is consensus now. But names sometimes do come and grow. Indian -&gt; Native American. Black, Negro. Consensus does change so I don't think "that's the way it is" is always a good way. But American is so cemented and the US has such a central role in the world still it seems unlikely that the cultural dominance will be dislodged anytime soon. Historically they might have also been called by their states. English called them Yankees for awhile. But yeah unless we change the name of the country. Nothing much else will likely stick. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demonyms\_for\_the\_United\_States</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
