<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510285871.0" user="Criminal_of_Thought" delta="False">
    <text>As a clarification question, does your view extend to describing the US with an English-language adjective in a context that doesn't specifically refer to a person? For example, the word American in "American English", "American cheese", "American movies", or "the American dream"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511786751.0" user="thomash363" delta="False">
    <text>No, it was in referring to myself as an American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513249172.0" user="GorillaBrown" delta="False">
    <text>That's a noun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513660497.0" user="thomash363" delta="False">
    <text>“I am American”

Go to sleep</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513304797.0" user="SnowedOutMT" delta="False">
    <text>In Canada they didn't know what I was talking about when I said American Cheese. They only knew it as Kraft singles. I thought that was odd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513918148.0" user="5l4" delta="False">
    <text>We don’t import US cheese in Canada because we have strong dairy protectionism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513923000.0" user="nacnud_uk" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's not cheese. Plastic, that would be closer. I understand why they didn't get it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514228219.0" user="RogueTwoNineSeven" delta="False">
    <text>I mean Kraft singles *specifically* are “not cheese”. (They are “cheese product” meaning they are made *from* cheese. Along with dairy and other ingredients.)

However, there does exist “American Cheese” and it is in fact “real cheese”. Next time you’re at a deli (especially with boars head) Try their “American cheese”. It’s like someone took Kraft singles and elevated it. I can’t confirm but I’m pretty sure places like In N Out use “Real American Cheese” and not Kraft singles. It’s similar, as it’s creamy and easy to melt. Great on burgers. But the taste and texture is much better than Kraft.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514838259.0" user="Valiant_Strawberry" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve personally always been a big fan of land o lakes American cheese from the deli, it’s what I grew up on. Kraft singles horrified me even as a child</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517279050.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>It's not plastic.  It's just shitty mass produced cheddar and Colby that's been emulsified using sodium citrate (sour salt).

You can make it yourself at home out of better cheeses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514105043.0" user="bijon1234" delta="False">
    <text>That's how they're marketed here. Similar to how Kraft Mac &amp; Cheese is called Kraft Dinner (KD) in Canada.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515373459.0" user="JoeDawson8" delta="False">
    <text>We wouldn’t have to eat Kraft Dinner…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515674608.0" user="SnowedOutMT" delta="False">
    <text>But we would eat kraft dinner, we'd just eat more!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515097089.0" user="RealHumanUserNotABot" delta="False">
    <text>Processed cheese</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
