<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43508540994.0" user="PandaDerZwote" delta="False">
    <text>"Ideologically pure", "Centrist", "Echo Chamber" etc are all meaningless without any concrete examples.  
The way you put it, it is easy to agree with you, but if you don't name any specifics, you haven't really said anything.  

&gt; I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome.

&gt;Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.  

I mean, what are we talking about here? Is the difference in believe whether or not VAT should be 4 or 5%? Is the believe whether or not we should forbid homosexuality and introduce conversion therapy? Anything inbetween?  
There are certainly situations in which people make an elephant out of the smallest of differences, but there are also situations in which an unreconcileable difference exists and one side claims that "Well they don't like me because I don't share EVERY opinion with them".  
Without clarifying which opinion this is about, you can't make any statement about it.  
Is it just a detail? Or is it actually something that you can't agree on?  

&gt;  Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

&gt; I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber.  

Again, does this actually happen? Is there such a thing as such a single issue voter that they actually disregard every other of their opinions? I mean, there are "single issue voters", but they don't hold other believes that are strong enough to swing one way or the other to any meaningful extend. That is their thing. They are not hardcore Republican in every metric but because they think a $15 minimum wage sounds fair, they vote Democrat.  
The devil is once again in the detail.  

&gt; To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.  

To make a real argument here, I'd suggest you present an example of what you're talking about. Like an actual case in which someone disregards 90% of their beliefs to vote for someone they have 10% in common. In which there is really some miniscule detail someone obsesses over that means they are not voting for someone they are otherwise in agreement with.  
Because in most cases, this is a sentiment rather than the reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509100937.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying the change happens overnight, or even in one election cycle. I am saying it's possible that over time, people's beliefs can change to mirror those of the people around them. Do you believe this is not possible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509410329.0" user="PandaDerZwote" delta="False">
    <text>You're not answering my post in any way</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509593968.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>This is an answer to the section about single issue voters. I am saying this is not the only scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509692988.0" user="PandaDerZwote" delta="False">
    <text>That was just a side tangent and example, not a core point of my post, please address the meat of the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510248951.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I will do so tomorrow, it's quite late in this time zone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513785890.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, I'm awake again. My argument is not that people will become "single issue voters" over that one issue. My argument is that if people (not politicians but ordinary people, and I should have clarified that better) start excluding anyone who does not agree with every single one of their political beliefs, those who would automatically have voted for them might start finding themselves surrounded by people with very different ideas. Over time this can create a big change. 

Here's an example. I am anti-censorship. Both major parties are very pro-censorship right now. So technically I don't belong in either camp. But if Party A exclude me because I don't believe in censoring X, and they think that means I am in favor of X, and Party B are very annoyed that I don't want to censor Y but talk to me anyway, which one has more power to influence my viewpoints from that point onward? I think it's Party B.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514384396.0" user="PandaDerZwote" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Alright, I'm awake again. My argument is not that people will become "single issue voters" over that one issue. My argument is that if people (not politicians but ordinary people, and I should have clarified that better) start excluding anyone who does not agree with every single one of their political beliefs, those who would automatically have voted for them might start finding themselves surrounded by people with very different ideas. Over time this can create a big change.   

I know, thats why I didn't say that they might become single issue voters, I described single issue voters as the closest to what you're describing and why it's not actually the way you portrait it as.  

&gt; Here's an example. I am anti-censorship. Both major parties are very pro-censorship right now. So technically I don't belong in either camp. But if Party A exclude me because I don't believe in censoring X, and they think that means I am in favor of X, and Party B are very annoyed that I don't want to censor Y but talk to me anyway, which one has more power to influence my viewpoints from that point onward? I think it's Party B.  

Well is that actually happening? Is there actually someone who is angry at you because you don't want to censor someone while another party has the same opinion on the matter but doesn't care if you do?  
I want a real example, a situation in which a party is in actuallity doing that. Disregarding people that they otherwise agree with over one thing (that isn't utterly worth disagreeing over once you spell it out)  
Your argument can range from "Why are they making a fuss about such nonsenese?" to "No actually, this isn't just some thing you can "agree to disagree" on."  
But without a real example, you can pretend that the former is the case, while from my experience, the latter is actually what is happening most of the time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
