<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="332" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513946124.0" user="hareofthepuppy" delta="False">
    <text>I do think it's a strange thing that we've taken the name of the continent we live on and use that to refer to ourselves, but I hadn't thought of it so much in terms of imperialism as much as just being vague. On one hand everyone knows what I mean if I say I'm American, but on the other hand it seems like someone from France or Germany saying "I'm European", which is true, but usually not what people are asking.

If Spain started calling itself "the United States of Europe" and then referred to themselves as "Europeans", that wouldn't be wrong, but it sure would be strange.

Anyone living in the Americas (North and South America) can reasonably call themselves "American", it is a true statement. 

So from that perspective I don't know about it being wrong per se, just strange and inaccurate in a literal sense, however everyone knows what you mean.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
