<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43508448391.0" user="Torin_3" delta="False">
    <text>Can you find any specific examples of this phenomenon?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508488055.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>E.g. most Democratic-leaning spaces will not tolerate someone who says that all LGBTQ people are child groomers, even if that person otherwise agrees with other Democratic policies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508614486.0" user="Mront" delta="False">
    <text>See, this is a different issue - this isn't a "point of view", this is a *lie*.

I don't think it's "ideological purity" to expect people to not push outright lies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508736917.0" user="ragepuppy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;See, this is a different issue - this isn't an opinion or a point of view, this is a lie.

Not if the person saying it believes its true - a statement is only a lie if it is presented as true while the speaker knows it is false. If the falsehood is not known to the speaker when they way it, it isn't a lie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508793388.0" user="Mront" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, sure.

I don't think it's "ideological purity" to expect people to not push outright *falsehoods*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509036487.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like this obscures the issue a bit. It matters that the claim is a lie, sure, but what's really scary is how genocidal it is. Ask a conservative what outcome would be fair for a pedophile to receive, and those outcomes will not be particularly friendly. Hell, ask a progressive and the answer probably won't be that radically different. This is as opposed to something like flat earth, a claim that I would say is even more clearly and blatantly false, but which is not really frightening in the same way. One could theoretically imagine a flat earther showing up at a communist clam bake and not getting immediately booted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509093148.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>But who decides what a lie is? I've seen what it's like in echo chambers and people end up believing some absolutely insane things with all their hearts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509141264.0" user="Mront" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; But who decides what a lie is?

Objective reality. I'm not talking about opinions, or debatable stuff - I'm talking about *facts*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509571145.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Objectively, are humans sexually dimorphic?

Except that's a political question now, so each side believes something different about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508718064.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>Nearly half of REPUBLICANS are in favor of gay marriage while independants are at like 75%. To say that "LGBTQ are child groomers" is some sort of centrist position is completely out of sync with reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509027161.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think anybody here said that "LGBTQ are child groomers" is some sort of centrist position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509089987.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That is an absurd statement, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508647542.0" user="Maktesh" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP, but a fine example is seen in JK Rowling. 

She has been a lifelong liberal progressive, but the moment she stated her opinion that "transgender women aren't the same as biological women" and that " biological women should have some of their spaces protected" (paraphrasing), she was essentially declared anathema and *persona non grata* by other liberal progressives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508730714.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>If someone was liberal in every way except for "interracial marriage should be illegal" then would it be wrong of liberal progressives to reject that person?

If JK Rowling was a liberal progressive except for her position on, like, coal subsidies, she wouldn't be persona non grata. Some issues are non-negotiable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509549868.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Which ones, specifically?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509982545.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>transphobia, homophobia, racism, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510044813.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That's interesting, because nuclear energy or diplomatic relations with China could literally be life or death for our species. 

Now I agree that bigotry is bad. But do you think we lash out so strongly against it when we see it because bigotry is a part of humanity? Before you argue with that, note that people from every demographic and every time in history are and have been bigots. Not everyone, but almost everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510305472.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about how important the issue is. Determining the best way to extract 5000 people from a burning building is life or death. "Is it okay to make fun of a 5-year-old for being an orphan?" is not. Yet I could very easily befriend someone who disagrees with me on the former while I'd want nothing to do with someone who thinks it's cool to bully a five-year-old orphan.

If that does not make sense to you then I don't think there is anything I could possibly say to make you understand or change your mind. At some point the difference between right and wrong should become obvious. It's not solely about what's at stake. There's a difference between negotiating logistics versus negotiating basic human decency. I will debate the former. I will not debate the latter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510467345.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't want to be friends with that person either. But if someone else did, I would not judge them, because I don't believe in guilt by association.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510502705.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, so let's say you go the park and see someone you know at a picnic table with 12 people in full-blown Nazi gear. There's a flag next to the table. The person says they don't agree with Nazism. He is simply friends with this group of people in spite of their Nazi beliefs.

You are cool with this person? No guilt by association?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513732689.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't consider this person to be a Nazi unless they actually held those beliefs. Maybe I am an extremist on this issue, but I really think people should only be judged as individuals, if at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516868933.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>I did not ask if the person is a Nazi. I asked if there is guilt by association.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508837171.0" user="zhibr" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;but the moment she stated her opinion ... she was essentially declared anathema and persona non grata by other liberal progressives

Was she really? Sounds like a huge exaggeration.

I'm not actually familiar with what happened, but I'd imagine it went more like: she expressed the view, someone tried to say that this is not ok because of reasons x and y, she didn't accept that and expressed it again, someone else tried to convince her with something else, she didn't accept that either and expressed it again... repeat more and more angrily, rigidly, unconditionally. 

When someone doesn't accept the explanations that are drawn from the purportedly common value set, people begin wondering whether that person actually has the same value set.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509029015.0" user="PercentageMaximum457" delta="False">
    <text>I know a little bit about the JKR incidents. First, she’s been called out for racism many times. Many Jewish folks consider her portrayal of goblins to be antisemitic. Cho Chang’s name, along with a few others, aren’t real names. CC is specifically Japanese and Chinese, the Mandarin version actually chose to change the name, and it has been compared to Ching Chong. Then there was the whole “house elves like being slaves. Silly little Hermione, trying to fight for their rights.” This received very little attention.

 What did receive attention was JKR saying, “if you see the characters as POC, that’s fine with me!” She was called very progressive for that. 

The trans issues were a bunch of small comments over the years. Then people found out that she wrote a different book involving a bad stereotype of a trans woman. JKR’s pen name shared similarities to a transphobe. Her comments have gotten worse over time. 

Finally, lesbians have said that JKR’s defense of them is not a good defense, but actually lesbophobic. That she uses them as a shield from criticism. 

This is all I can remember.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509083408.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Hermione is the self-insert, which makes me wonder whether her trying to liberate the house-elves was a metaphor for trying and failing to get a woman to leave an abusive relationship.

I agree that JKR is not very good at coming up with Chinese names, though. Which is weird because usually old Scottish ladies are great at that.

It might be helpful to hear specifically which comments were controversial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509193118.0" user="PercentageMaximum457" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest, I have little interest in hunting down her every comment. I recommend finding her Terf Wars manifesto, or searching for “JKR receipts.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509655165.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Found it. Among other things, she said "trans rights are human rights". Was this offensive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509075088.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>If anything this was an understatement. She wrote an essay about how women are female and female-only spaces should exist. It wasn't necessarily hateful because she did not express hatred toward anyone, but she certainly said things that people did not want to hear. Then a lot of people threatened to murder her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509111457.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this was an exaggeration, except that this probably did not happen at the exact same moment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514497322.0" user="zhibr" delta="False">
    <text>Seeing the descriptions by other people, it is a huge exaggeration. It repeats the trope that all the liberals considered someone fully on their side, but the very moment they said something against the dogma, all the liberals immediately turned against them like rabid dogs. It's a trope used to paint all of progressivism as a cult. 

No such thing happened. There were numerous little incidents that piled up, made both JKR and numerous different people challenging her getting more frustrated across many years, until it became public enough that most people realized what are her actual values and begun criticizing her more than praising.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514923306.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I remember liberals (myself among them) defending her when Trump supporters burned her books because she basically called him a fascist... this wasn't all that long before she wrote her controversial essay, was it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43526606920.0" user="zhibr" delta="False">
    <text>So what? It's perfectly normal to defend her about things where it's justified, and simultaneously criticize her about things where that's justified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43508988753.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>Look I hate twitter and the twitter left as much as the next person. They do mob people often on flimsy evidence.

But that is an extreme simplification of the whole JK drama.

Yes it started that small - and the critics were likewise a small handful of people. but she has doubled down and doubled down and doubled down. She released a manifesto and has worked with several organisations that hold similar beliefs in order to further those beliefs. She has made many more statements than just those two - and has continued to make this an extended part of her online statements and activism. The situation has heated up over a long period of time.

Similarly her critics have become more with time. Whether you attribute this to a response to her statements or a smear campaign - it has only grown more divisive.

In addition her statements were ones that (if followed to their conclusion) affect others' lives - namely the lives of trans women and cis women - but also heavily impact trans men and (to a lesser extent) cis men. These are issues that are likely to rile up a lot of feeling in people. Like someone else said - had it been an opinion on coal subsidies then that is something which doesn't have as direct an affect on others' lives.  

These are amongst the best analyses and discussions I know of - from someone who was herself declared *persona non grata* by the same people;

[J.K. Rowling | ContraPoints](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EmT0i0xG6zg) [The Witch Trials of J.K. Rowling | ContraPoints](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7gDKbT_l2us)

**I'm not making this comment to convince you one way or the other on JK. What I am trying to show is that she is an active agent in her own divisiveness.**

There are plenty of people who simply make a single similar statement (or repeated low level statements) who do not get this hate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509088927.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I've noticed that men (Mike Pence!) generally receive less hatred for making the same or worse statements. Am I imagining this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509138728.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>We all know how Mike Pence feels about stuff. It would make the news if he *didn't* make those statements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509541490.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I just don't get why the same people who were unconcerned by the death threats against JKR (rightly) criticized the mob that shouted "Hang Mike Pence"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509624147.0" user="Various_Succotash_79" delta="False">
    <text>There's a lot of difference between internet yahoos saying things and an angry real life mob saying things. 

But are you even sure those are the same people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509776854.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. There is a difference, and I am guessing that these are the same people. But am I wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510168006.0" user="orhan94" delta="False">
    <text>Mike Pence wasn't targeted by the mob because of his awful views and wishes, he was targeted because he wouldn't try to legitimize a coup (that he had no power to legitimize).

You can't not see the difference in contexts.

Like I'm totally down with Pence dying. Good riddance, that's a better world right there without that fucking clerofascist walking around. The existance of people wanting to kill him doesn't concern me, but the existance of a reactionary violent mob hellbent on committing treason and a coup in the US to establish an illigetimate fascist in power concerns me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510216857.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I'm glad people see that Pence is awful. I am really scared of what would happen if he became President.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509143374.0" user="GenericUsername19892" delta="False">
    <text>There’s a realllllly low bar for bigotry amongst loud christians when it comes to lgbt *shrugs*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509184581.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and no. Comparing JK to Mike Pence is not exactly a fair comparison. He is an anathema to liberals/the left for a bunch of reasons but he isn't really touchable because he is on the other side. Every lib/lefite can agree "fuck Mike Pence", but pointing out problems within a group is often louder because it causes more hurt feelings.

 Comparing JK to Graham Linehan is probably a better comparison. 

Graham Linehan has a similar background to JK - nominally progressive other than his opinions on trans people. He has wound up utterly disgraced. He has done and said many things - very much at first NOT being an issue but dying on the hill, refusing to self reflect and refusing to change. He has turned the heat up on his arguments as much or more than others have hated on him for it. And it has wound up with people not booking him (he is a comedian) anymore, cancelling his shows (because they don't want to host him) - and the most sad for everyone one of his wife divorcing him and taking the children.

**Again I'm not saying this in order to tell you what to think but - he has been the agent of his own downfall as much as anyone else - he has obsessively pursued this for years now and pinned his career to it. The backlash has negatively affected him, granted, but its not like he didn't court it.**

I can't find a good source because everything I look up is him defending himself and complaining about being cancelled. The best I could find off the top of my head was by The Serfs Times who has done comedy-news stories on him whenever he makes a big oopsie; [Few Weeks Old Video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XJBLOACLSKg&amp;pp=ygUYZ3JhaGFtIGxpbmVoYW4gdGhlIHNlcmZz) [1 Year Old Video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t9EtCIkBJxE&amp;pp=ygUYZ3JhaGFtIGxpbmVoYW4gdGhlIHNlcmZz) [2 Year Old Video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XJBLOACLSKg)

**HOWVER**

What you have identified is real. Women tend to get more criticism whenever they are seen as doing something wrong than men. This is a known part of misogyny.

This extends beyond the the debate around trans people and is a society wide thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509529015.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>What he said is WAY worse than what JKR said, so I think it's a really good example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509223491.0" user="Jacked-to-the-wits" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, it kind of sounds like you're making OP's point. JK started out progressive,  started making comments that were somewhat reasonable, but not left enough for many. When she was basically pushed out of the tent, she found other groups that aligned more with her views and it has actually pushed her to be more radical in her views. That seems like exactly the thesis OP proposed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509322367.0" user="page0rz" delta="False">
    <text>"Progressives" progress? Damn, what's up with that?

150 years ago, it was "liberal" and "progressive" for a white man to believe that, although their basic animalistic nature procludes them from ever being a part of a civilized society, black people still probably shouldn't be slaves simply because it's bad for the white slave owners. Times change, and it's natural for people who, you know, are performing the literal dictionary definition of being a conservative to get left behind. It would be absurd to expect anything but that to happen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509475722.0" user="Jacked-to-the-wits" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're missing the point. JK's views themselves became more radical. It's not that the world changed and she didn't, she changed. We will never know exactly why, but the harsh reaction to her early tweets could have played a part in that. I think I remember that one of her first tweets said something about how she empathizes with trans people and would march alongside them, but..... I don't think her tweets today have the same tone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509666010.0" user="page0rz" delta="False">
    <text>You can't really say she changed. She voiced her opinion after the topic presented itself. It's not like she wasn't a terf for the 40 odd years before then, but nobody was talking about trans rights within earshot, so</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510086508.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>In her essay, the one that started the whole thing, she actually said she loved trans people, that trans lives matter, that trans rights are human rights, that she empathizes with trans women... she said a bunch of other stuff too. But it almost seems like receiving thousands of death threats can change the way someone experiences empathy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510337173.0" user="page0rz" delta="False">
    <text>Not to be a total reductionist, but there are plenty of racists who say they actually love black people. I'm sure she did "love" trans people, as long as doing so required zero thought or effort on her part, and said trans people stayed in their lane. Ask any trad catholic or anti choice activist and they'll tell you they love and respect women, too. There are Christians who run conversion therapy groups who say they love gay people and just want to help them. Just saying, "I respect trans people," means very little, and it means less than nothing when you're doing it while writing an anti-trans essay</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510426474.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Is it possible that she believed everything she said in her essay?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510692913.0" user="page0rz" delta="False">
    <text>Is it possible someone can be a bigot while not thinking they are a bigot?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513716352.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That wasn't an answer to my question, but to answer your question, yes.

However, I think we are talking about her words here, not her actions. She's a writer; she doesn't seem to physically do a lot of things.

Howe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509416583.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe...

Though my point is that these people often push themselves out as much as are pushed out. 

Humans just like to bicker.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510110385.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>This is a really divisive issue because one side sees themselves as protecting trans people, a vulnerable group, and another side sees themselves as protecting women, also a vulnerable group. Some people belong to both groups, no matter which side you agree with. And I truly understand both viewpoints, and why people on both sides are willing to let the end justify the means. How can we resolve this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510318541.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>That's precisely the point I am trying to make so I think we are in agreement there :)

My solution is try to point out to people that there isn't the perceived conflict of interest there - that this can be a win-win situation.

My hot take that both sides will disagree with is that neither side is right about their definitions of women. Both are working off faulty understandings of linguistics. One is creating a self referential loop that doesn't actually identify the ways that people use the world in reality - but the other is viewing the dictionary as if it is some infallible text and ignoring the fact that words change and people use the same word differently. 

To the anti-trans crowd I wish they'd see that their fears have been stoked so far that they have been driven into jumping at every shadow and that most of the things they claim are happening aren't happening. And to the pro trans crowd I wish I could emphasise that most people do not have strong opinions and that's okay.

I definitely have a side that I think is more wrong. But the thing is that this while culture war is blown way out of proportion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510444872.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I think we may be in complete agreement. I believe there is a possible solution which involves creating a greater number of spaces (not for restrooms, they don't matter much anyway, but why not build more shelters and prisons?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510603963.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>I think more gender neutral toilets would fix most of the issues.

Allow people somewhere to safely go in that awkward part of transition where you don't quite fit in the new ones, or the old ones. 

The prison thing seems largely fixable by having trans wards/sections available.

The thing is that trans people aren't an immense threat. And once a transition is most of the way complete many can blend in to the extent going to the old toilets  they used to use is far far far far more uncomfortable for everyone involved. So I don't think banning them from the toilets of their gender is a good idea - but the vast majority of trans people I know are mindful of others and would prefer to use a gender neutral one if they believe their appearance might cause someone distress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513709509.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Gender neutral toilets are a good idea, in addition to the ones that already exist. And I think once someone has physically transitioned, there is absolutely no reason to exclude them from even a high-security place like a prison or shelter. Trans wards could work, or I have another idea that could be effective. What if we had five spaces (just for prisons and shelters): AMAB, AFAB, men, women, and NB? Everyone would have two options, one that matches their sex and one that matches their gender. Because that's the debate, isn't it? Some people want to be with only their own sex, and some people want to be with only their own gender. This way people could make their own choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515715409.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What if we had five spaces (just for prisons and shelters): AMAB, AFAB, men, women, and NB?

I don't hate this idea but it would spread already think resources even thinner.

IRT to shelters;

Men already suffer from a massive lack of access to shelters.

And how would you ensure that there are enough shelters that accept trans women. Perhaps you could step in and demand that if a shelter is the own in its area it must be a women one not an AFAB one.

The NB one would (categorically) be underattended - perhaps it could be unisex?

However please read these as nitpicks - this is the sort of problem solving that I think COULD work to find some level of solutions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515839470.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I think the rule should be that if there is an AFAB shelter, there must also be an inclusive women's shelter. Then TERFs will pay to build both of them.

The NB one should of course be unisex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515856754.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah...

That could work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509495423.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>This does seem to be an example of it. And once people are labelled 'irredeemable', there is no incentive for them to ever come back to the tent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509548050.0" user="RoozGol" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;but she has doubled down and doubled down and doubled down

How did she dare oppose my pious beliefs? 

Where did I hear that before?

 was it from the Crusaders, inquisitors, Soviet commissars, or ISIS Jihadists?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509705018.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say "how dare". 

My point is that she did push back - that she didn't compromise her beliefs either so pinning this on one side for not compromising on their beliefs is hypocritical.

I have my opinion and biases on the subject - but those are secondary to my point that each side in this discussion is equal in the fact that it will not give ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509745784.0" user="RoozGol" delta="False">
    <text>Is she a radical now? Because she believes a 300 lbs mam with a footlong penis is not a woman?
Why does she have to compromise? When for the Woke, it only means: fully agree with me or get canceled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509912985.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>Aahahahahahhaha

That's the funniest image ever. Are you really expecting trans women to have skyscrapers down there? And really, a fat joke?

The long and short of it is that most people do not have strong opinions on trans people either way. Or they have a grab bag of opinions that don't strongly fall on either side.

Please listen to me when I say this - I am not calling her radical because she doesn't agree with me 100% - I am saying that her opinions are quite different from the baseline norm. They may be versions of opinions plenty of people have but her advocacy for them goes massively above and beyond what the average person does. That is the only thing I am trying to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510150172.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>The baseline norm for which country, and which demographic? For old Scottish ladies? She probably is fairly representative of them. But if we are talking about young Americans, she would seem extreme compared to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510372398.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>[These are the Statistics I am most aware of - from the UK](https://yougov.co.uk/topics/society/articles-reports/2022/07/20/where-does-british-public-stand-transgender-rights) \- what it shows is that people are (as expected) a mixed crowd with plenty of "don't know" answers.

And my personal experience (albeit not Scotland but a similar-ish rural area of Britain) is that middle aged ladies are largely a bit confused, have some likely "yucky" opinions, but are overall supportive and helpful. And my experience of UK cities is that people couldn't give a toss - you're just a random faceless person on the street they will never see again.

Again not going to deny that they have some opinions that could be labelled "transphobic" but they aren't going to pin their image on it - and when faced they might push back but not as hard as JK and most online trans-opposing people have.

The actual harmful bigots are the loud minority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510411375.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>So are you saying that JKR thinks the same thing as most people from her demographic, but the difference is that she isn't afraid to express that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510572302.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>No.

I am saying she represents a minority of people who strongly hold these opinions. 

Most people aren't afraid but flexible. They might have an opinion similar to JK but they are open to discussion, flexibility, edge cases (which is what trans people are), exceptions. They also just don't consider it that important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513725096.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>So the difference is that she is more inflexible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510122839.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That is an interesting point. When someone says something that people try to censor, and they do not allow themselves to be censored, we call it 'doubling down'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509782426.0" user="Maktesh" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But that is an extreme simplification of the whole JK drama.

I mean, did you think that it was supposed to be a comprehensive discussion on Rowling?  

I simply listed her as an example of the type of situation OP described: A person who is cast out of their "group" because of their disagreement over a line item in the ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509933248.0" user="wibbly-water" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough.

&gt;A person who is cast out of their "group" because of their disagreement over a line item in the ideology.

Though I am trying to say that that's not quite how it happened. Its a long and now storied saga of both her and critics both turning up the heat. 

Originally it was a line item drama and would likely have been a footnote but now it is far more fractious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509008097.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>She's the most prominent figure of an international hate movement. I would, in fact, expect her to be excluded from leftist spaces on this basis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509069060.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I would think that title would go to Mike Pence, the most transphobic person I can think of and someone with an extraordinary amount of political power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509110479.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>I can't even think of wacky transphobic stuff Mike Pence has said offhand. I have no doubt he has, but it's not his main thing, or the thing he's most famous for. On the other side, you don't see TERFs going around with "IstandwithMikePence" in their bios. I would say he's also just a less famous guy. Vice president for four years versus one of the most successful writers in the world? Nah, I'd say Rowling is definitely queen of the TERFs. Not the one with the most hateful rhetoric, but the big figurehead of the movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509560909.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Mike Pence doesn't even pretend to be a feminist. I think he hates gay and trans people for religious reasons. Didn't he try to legalize conversion therapy? That's lot worse than picking a controversial pen name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509669509.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>All the more reason that he wouldn't be as much of a figurehead for TERFs, really. Transphobia has a bit of an international split between English style, which forwards itself as more liberal and rooted in some kinda civil rights claim, and American style, which has its foundation in evangelical conservatism. There's obviously crossover, what with stuff like the LGB Alliance hanging out with the Heritage Foundation, thus the international movement thing, but they're kinda distinct. Notably, I would generally expect an English TERF to at least claim an opposition to Pence, whereas an American evangelical might be more chill with Rowling. An interesting aspect of the schism is that TERFs tend to be more single issue assholes, and that single issue is not repellant to American conservatives.

Anyways, if you want a ringleader for American transphobia, I'd probably just go with Trump or DeSantis. Trump for being king of the party and a pretty important figure in the right getting so intense about this stuff, and DeSantis for being probably the second biggest conservative and going real deep on culture war transphobic nonsense. DeSantis is probably the right pick. Definitely more prominent, powerful, and centering of transphobia than Pence is.

As for the comparison of badness? That's not how you find the figurehead. If you just want the most intense messaging from a vaguely top end figure, I'd probably go with Posie Parker. But, like, Rowling going by Robert Galbraith doesn't even make the list when it comes to her nonsense. I think she might just have plausible deniability on that one. How much do you know about her transphobia? There's a lot of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509761466.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like she is of two minds on the issue. On the one hand, some of the people she supports truly are transphobic, but is it because she agrees with them or is she just objecting to censorship? Then she says stuff like "trans rights are human rights"... Why say that if she doesn't mean it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509800329.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>She doesn't just support some transphobic people. She says a bunch of weird transphobic stuff. Like, if you check her Twitter, it's mostly weird transphobic stuff at this point. Some of it supporting awful transphobes, including Posie Parker, and some of it her own personal messaging. But literally it's just most of her output at this point. I expect she doesn't view herself as transphobic, and would similarly like to project that non-transphobic image out into the world, but her nonsense really speaks for itself on this account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509817123.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Can you give me an example? I really can't decide if I think she is transphobic or not. The jury has been out for years. You legitimately could change my mind. I don't like to join mobs and I've resisted joining this one, but I will believe anything if there is enough evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509921843.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>This is a [pretty solid reference guide](https://archive.ph/2RJaC) for Rowling's weird ass transphobic essay. The essay includes lots of weird nonsense, including support for people like Magdalen Berns and Maya Forstater, pushing of weird nonsense like ROGD, and weird arguments in general.

As I said though, it's just all over the place. Like, her pinned tweet right now reads:

&gt; Men defining what a woman is, what women should and shouldn’t fear, what women should and shouldn’t say, what rights women should be fine with giving up and, of course, what constitutes ‘real’ misogyny: get a bloody mirror. That’s real misogyny, looking right back at you.

Which, "men defining what a woman is" is referring to the idea of defining trans women as women., and the rest of the items are broadly of a kind. A few below that she's directing people to watch Julie Bindel's podcast. Decidedly not simply trying to protect her free speech, and Bindel is a notable TERF. The next tweet that isn't about one of her books is celebrating the loss of trans charity Mermaids in some kind of case, and she tosses out a fun "identifies as" joke. Then there's another thing about the Mermaids case, and then a thing about Lia Thomas. 

I dunno. It's just kinda endless. I'm a bit shocked because I think she might have actually gotten worse. I mean that in the sense that I feel like she used to have a more even split between weird transphobic garbage and, like, book stuff, whereas now she'll toss out ten transphobic things in a row and separate that out with two tweets about her new book. What're you looking for here? I'd advise actually looking at her twitter profile because it's pretty wild.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510009728.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting. So she started out as moderate, then people hated her for being moderate, and now she is much more extreme?

An almost perfect example of the phenomenon I was trying to describe in my original post. I thank you.

I do notice, though, that people always seem to need an explanation as to why the stuff JKR says is bad. She never actually comes out and says "I don't like trans people" or anything like that, does she? Why do you think that is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510085596.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>Probably because she isn’t stupid and knows that pushes away anyone who doesn’t openly hate trans people. It’s the Lee Atwater playbook ([source](https://www.thenation.com/article/archive/exclusive-lee-atwaters-infamous-1981-interview-southern-strategy/tnamp/)). She may also genuinely believe that she doesn’t hate trans people - most bigots don’t believe they’re actually outright *hateful* themselves, but still profess bigoted beliefs. “I’m not racist, I just don’t think races should mix! I don’t hate black people, I just have concerns about violence against white women” or “I don’t hate gay people, I just want to preserve traditional marriage!” Etc etc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510207706.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Both explanations potentially make sense. I think almost everyone is more bigoted than they realize. I don't feel like I am racist, for example, but statistically I probably am and just don't know it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510096237.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Interesting. So she started out as moderate, then people hated her for being moderate, and now she is much more extreme?

Not really sure how you got there. She started out being kinda transphobic in a way that non-trans people were mostly unaware of, and she got some attention for it but not a ridiculous amount. The people critical of it would probably have been more than happy for it to be unreflective of her politics. It really got more intense later when she started strongly supporting Maya Forstater, who was just incredibly transphobic, and then even moreso when she published the gross ass essay. She has had ample opportunities between then and now to learn some basic stuff, get people on her side, and stop being ridiculously transphobic.

All in all, I think it's kinda bizarre to blame Rowling's transphobia on people who are interested in there being less transphobia. It seems a lot more sensible to blame her and the transphobes in her orbit.

&gt;I do notice, though, that people always seem to need an explanation as to why the stuff JKR says is bad. 

I did not require an explanation as to why the stuff she says is bad. 

&gt;She never actually comes out and says "I don't like trans people" or anything like that, does she? Why do you think that is?

Cause she's marginally talented as a writer? A lot of bigots don't come straight out like, "I am the queen of bigot borough." Really, it's more unusual for them to do that, especially if they're on the more famous side of things. Kinda curious if you agree at this point that she's real transphobic, in any case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510197495.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe she is transphobic. It's not for me to judge, and it's not really important to the original debate, but it's an interesting question. I can definitely see why people think she is. But I cannot say what is in her heart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510223044.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not really sure why you wanted a bunch of evidence if you didn't want to come to some variety of answer on the matter. As for what's in her heart? I don't really care all that much about that. She says and does transphobic stuff. That's what being transphobic is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510240400.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I thought it was hating and fearing trans people. Isn't that the definition? That's why I feel like I can't judge someone I don't know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510310012.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>Kinda? But conceptualizing it as some aspect of a person's soul is pretty counterproductive. Transphobia, racism, sexism, these are things you do. You enact bigotry. It is, frankly, why bigotry matters in the first place. Cause, seriously, why would we even care about bigotry if we could only access it through reading someone's mind?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510454487.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That's why I never understood this name-calling. But if transphobia is an action, is it something a person needs to physically do? Or are words enough?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510480266.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>Words are an action. Especially when you're a super famous writer whose anti-trans words get quoted by GOP senators. But also otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513752333.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>A very interesting idea. I suppose in a way, words are actions. 

Here's a question: if someone says a thing, and someone else does something bad based on that, to what extent is the first person responsible for what the second person did?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513836986.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>Probably somewhat? Like, you'd want to evaluate the intention of the comment, whether it was meant to incite violence or whatever, and you'd also want to evaluate the plausible expected outcome of the comment, whether it was reasonable to assume it would lead to violence. Like, the song Helter Skelter meets neither criteria. It wasn't seemingly intended to cause violence, and someone listening to the song would not expect it to do so. So, no real moral culpability for Charles Manson. But if you look at something like Lauren Southern's body of work, the whole White genocide/great replacement thing, then there seems to be a more straightforward thread of culpability between that and the Christchurch mosque shootings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514948609.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>OK, so if for example someone says "Person X deserves to die" and someone goes and kills that person... is there culpability?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517333770.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>Well, how plausible is it that someone will follow through on that one? If we're talking about a crime boss surrounded by their underlings, then maybe that's a statement that's both literal and actionable. If we're talking about a kid who just did badly on a particularly hard test, then it is incredibly unlikely to be literally meant or doable by those who hear it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517343749.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>What about someone who goes on the Internet and tells god knows who or how many people that it's a good idea to murder person X?

I think it's hard to establish culpability in this case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509672179.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>to be clear, JKR is not the figurehead of the anti-trans movement because she "picked a controversial pen name". See here: [https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/comment/jzkgqxb/?utm\_source=share&amp;utm\_medium=web2x&amp;context=3](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/comment/jzkgqxb/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509742495.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>So she supports someone who has messed up views, and that's worse than actually having those views and using political power to enact them? This feels like a double standard. Mike Pence is worse, more transphobic, more dangerous by any possible standard or stretch of the imagination. Why are we ignoring how scary he is? He could be the next POTUS.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509856831.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>I mean Mike Pence absolutely is not going to be the next president of the United States lol. Absolutely no way he wins a GOP primary after Jan 6. In any case though yeah he’s a worse person for sure I guess, but that doesn’t make JKR not worthy of opposition. JKR, at the moment, has more cultural and political power by virtue of her wealth and immense following. Pence, by contrast, does not currently hold elective office and is running a doomed presidential campaign. He’s also not unique in his beliefs - he essentially is in tandem with the rest of the GOP, who are vehemently opposed by anyone who supports trans people. I guarantee you everyone in the trans/trans-supportive community is extremely worried about the GOP taking power. 

Another point about JKR that is important is her ties to liberal politics - her campaigning therefore has sway over left-wing parties, which is obviously very concerning. If the people JKR supports get their views ingratiated into the left-wing parties, then trans people are *extra* screwed since there isn’t even a party they can vote for to keep themselves safe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509064766.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>They burned her books because she wrote about witches, then they burned her books because she said Trump was fascist, then they burned her books because she said women were female. I wonder what they will burn her books for next.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509554255.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>This is an incredible whitewashing of JK Rowling's current actions and views.  
She actively supports Kellie-Jay Keen both financially (she’s offered to pay her legal fees, unclear if accepted) and by promoting her on her social media repeatedly.  
Who is Kellie-Jay Keen? In essence, she's the most prominent (and in my opinion, one of the most vile) anti-trans activist in the current political landscape. Kellie-Jay Keen wants all trans people eliminated - preferably through “therapy” but she also casually hopes that trans women who could get uterus implants would die, calls for the sterilization of trans men, and believes that trans people should not be allowed to hold any “public-facing position” or general position of power. She has immensely conspiratorial views about trans people, believing that they have infiltrated every level of government and have stopped the general public (who she believes all invariably hate trans people) from calling them out. She also has direct ties to both conservative/anti-abortion groups in the states and Nazis who talk about “the Jewish billionaires funding the trans movement”.  
Video documenting all of KJK’s statements and history, along with JKR’s support of her: [https://youtu.be/JBy93QX7ysE](https://youtu.be/JBy93QX7ysE). In addition, here's some background on the other people JKR supports/cheerleads: [https://youtu.be/Ou\_xvXJJk7k?si=WIGwRojA5F\_QXljx](https://youtu.be/Ou_xvXJJk7k?si=WIGwRojA5F_QXljx)    
To be clear, KJK is not subtle about any of these claims, has not retracted any of them, and makes a point of never apologizing. Nevertheless, JKR directly supports her as the up and coming face of the anti-trans movement.  
In addition, here is some more evidence of JKR supporting KJK, if you don't feel like watching the video: [https://www.assignedmedia.org/breaking-news/j-k-rowling-tweets-support-for-activist-embroiled-in-nazi-controversy](https://www.assignedmedia.org/breaking-news/j-k-rowling-tweets-support-for-activist-embroiled-in-nazi-controversy)  \- Also includes a particularly nasty tweet where she implies trans women are dangerous, calling them "trans-identified men" (a turn of phrase used exclusively by anti-trans folk) and stating that they commit more sex crimes per capita than men. If you're wondering why this is transphobic, I would ask you to consider if repeating "despite only making up 13% of the population, black people commit 50% of violent crime" with no context, in response to "black people are not dangerous" is racist. In my opinion, it is. Said stat for trans women is immensely flawed, relying on extraordinarily small sample sizes and failing to account for trans women who came out after committing said crimes \[making them obviously not representative of out trans people\].

TL/DR: saying that JKR's views boil down to "trans women aren't the same as cis women" (a completely uncontroversial point) is incredibly misinformed at best and actively deceitful at worst. She is the figurehead for an eliminationist movement and has no qualms with supporting people who express those desires publicly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510173275.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I am not sure "trans women aren't the same as cis women" is an uncontroversial viewpoint. Didn't people try to cancel Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie for saying something very similar? (Of course, she is not only a woman of color but from a country other than the USA, so there may be a reason people wanted to silence her for saying something relatively innocuous.)

But you make a fair point. Perhaps JKR is more transphobic than I had thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510249030.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not familiar with her but on a brief skim of her Wikipedia page it seems she supported JKR’s essay (which I believe you’ve been given a link going through why it’s wrong and professes anti-trans views) and recently said in an interview “So somebody who looks like my brother – he says, ‘I’m a woman’, and walks into the women’s bathroom, and a woman goes, ‘You’re not supposed to be here’, and she’s transphobic?”, which is a very leading question. I don’t think it’s as cut and dry as you said. The initial discussion point appeared to be when she was asked “are trans women women?” And she responded “trans women are trans women” which implies “no”. She later clarified to the uncontroversial view. No one legitimately believes that trans women and cis women are 100% identical, that’s obviously absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510279560.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>No one believes that? I am sure that someone somewhere does. There are probably people who would want to cancel you for saying trans and cis women are different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510320692.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>Okay let me adjust to "no one of any real importance" believes that trans women and cis women are 100% identical. E.g. no major activist organization, no prominent media figure, etc. A few randoms on twitter might have said something dumb but I'm pretty sure you know what I mean. 

of note - "trans women are women" != "trans women are identical to cis women" just so we're all on the same page.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510432934.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>In your opinion, how are trans women different from cis women?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510492684.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>Trans women (generally) have XY chromosomes. Cis women (generally) have XX chromosomes. Some (importantly, not all) trans women will also have differing genitals to cis women, and of course cis women will (generally) have a uterus and ovaries, which trans women do not have. I do not believe any of this is controversial.

What I do not believe is that those biological differences imply that trans women should not be included in the larger category of woman, or that they should be barred from the women's spaces they use today without (statistically relevant) issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513744213.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, that's a very reasonable answer. So my question is, what does the word 'woman' mean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513835087.0" user="Judge24601" delta="False">
    <text>In the simplest terms, women = cis women and trans women - for which I believe the definition for either is fairly obvious.

Cis woman - an adult human assigned female at birth, who has not transitioned.

Trans woman - an adult human not assigned female at birth, who has transitioned to female. 

You could get a little fuzzy with either of these two definitions (what about intersex women? What precisely defines ‘transition’?) but this is a simple, easy to understand definition that doesn’t get lost in the weeds, and also has the benefit of being thuddingly obvious. We all know what a cis woman is. We all know what a trans woman is. Woman is just the superset of those two sets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512295882.0" user="Maktesh" delta="False">
    <text>Your obsession over this woman is astounding. You're writing a sermon over a passing comment in conspiratorial Q-Anon fashion. 

Most of your comment consists of accusations and name-calling, leading me to question quite a bit about your stance.  

The detachment from what was said is laughable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510105642.0" user="orhan94" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; She has been a lifelong liberal progressive

Being a shitlib with "girlboss" feminist rhetoric doesn't make you a progressive firebrand when your two most defining political stances have been against a more class-based leftist Labour Party under Corbyn, and against trans people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
