<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43509075265.0" user="PercentageMaximum457" delta="False">
    <text>Politics is an issue people get heated about because it often involves human lives, rights, or personal identities. It’s hard to stay neutral when we’re discussing whether or not a person gets to live/live freely. 

It’s also hard to ally with someone who insults you. Humans are a social species, not a logical one. The backfire effect is unfortunately very strong, and no one wants to feel attacked/rejected. 

That said, sticking to your principles doesn’t require attacking people. You can state your firm belief without insulting others. (They may take it as an insult anyway, but that is on them.)

When entering a new space, it’s important to remember that you are a newcomer. They have established ideas and protocols, and you must decide if you want to follow them or form your own group. It’s not wise to attempt to change them to suit you, nor is it often possible. They should keep in mind that you do not know the established ideas and protocols, and give you grace. By respecting each other’s positions, a group can remain “pure” without harming others, and you can decide to join, ally with them occasionally, or find someone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509629287.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>The real problem is when both parties truly believe they are protecting the same group from destruction by proposing opposite policies. How can that be resolved?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
