<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="105" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511648104.0" user="Entropy_Drop" delta="False">
    <text>Im from Argentina.  And I would describe myself as american. Are you against that use of the word?.

Because the problem is not in the name, but the exclusion it implies. When a north-american argues that I'm not american, I take it as an insult to the sovereignty of my land, to the ideals of San Martin, who free south-America from the spanish monarchy. You and me both are citizents of a free country, and our ancestors fought for that freedom. 

And in that war, with those revolutionary ideas in mind (fighting against the monarchy, against opression) a word was needed to define us all, free people of America. Its natural that both our people choose "american" as that word. Its was and still is identifier of our freedom, our strength.

Until here, all good. But at the moment of naming the United States of America, you claim possesion of the word "America". Finders keepers. Then changed the name of the old America continent to "The Americas". What is "The americas"? It means nothing to me. 

North-americans are not the owners of the "America" word. Its the word of my continent, we are all "americanos". And excluding me from that name is an attack on my identity and my history.

So yes, I agree with your german teacher. I have no solution, I offer no english translation of "estadounidense". But the point still stands.

Yo soy americano, le duela a quien le duela. Viva la patria grande carajo!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512306640.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>*American* and *Americano* are different words in different languages. Your country's revolutionaries did not say "We are Americans." They said "Somos Americanos." In Spanish, *Americano* can refer to somebody from either of the Americas. In English, *American* almost always refers solely to people from the US. Ask a Canadian if they're American and they'll almost certainly say "No, I'm Canadian."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512871944.0" user="Flipadelphia26" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. Not you’re American.  I asked Messi when I saw him in Miami, he confirmed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512968616.0" user="ophmaster_reed" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And I would describe myself as american. Are you against that use of the word?.

Yes. You are South American, not American.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
