<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510593544.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve encountered this discussion traveling in Central and South America, and it always feels like some attempt at a logic trap to get a *zinger* in on American tourists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511201997.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>People in central and south America genuinely consider themselves to be "American", as in from the Americas, so they are confused as to why people from the US would call themselves that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511226962.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. Lots of people who takes the free online Harvard computer science class list on their LinkedIns and resumes that they “attended Harvard.”  I mean yeah, they aren’t lying or anything, but….</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511250028.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>A Colombian is American just like a German is European.

If there was a country called "The United States of Europe" and their people went to Italy and called themselves European, the locals would say "Uh yeah, me too."

It's literally the same situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511331107.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>Yup like I said, they aren’t lying but….</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511337113.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>It's not anything at all like what you said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511384562.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>They’re leaving out a delineation in their self description to obfuscate continental origin from nationality. It’s like someone from Buffalo describing themself as simply a  “New Yorker,” to make people think they may be from NYC. They aren’t lying, but they aren’t being fully accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511450258.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>They aren't obfuscating anything. In Spanish someone from the US is "estadounidense" and an "americano" is someone from the continent of America. 

Calling yourself "americano" in Spanish is just the incorrect term to use even though it's a direct translation from English.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511475037.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that’s cool, but everyone knows what it really means vs the technicality of translation. That’s why this conversation is even occurring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512559107.0" user="sindelic" delta="False">
    <text>There isn’t a continent called America, there is a North America and a South America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511415643.0" user="DrazaTraza" delta="False">
    <text>It’s more accurate to say that a colombian is south american like a german is european.  What you were trying to say would be more like a german calling themselves eurasian as that’s the word for the combined continents of russia and asia like how the Americas are both North and South America combined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511532961.0" user="NeuroticKnight" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;A Colombian is American just like a German is European.

More like British is European, yes they might be in European continent, but not European Union, when someone says they have a European Visa, they are not meaning visa from Turkey or Russia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511574013.0" user="Disdain690" delta="False">
    <text>No, yours is a made up situation. Maybe it wouldn't be weird if there was actually a country named that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511347257.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>Oof… Your reading comprehension and general cognitive ability is subpar for a human being</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511425547.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>Cool.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511396770.0" user="Entropy_Drop" delta="False">
    <text>Rhis is exactly the problem.
We are Americans, part of the "patria grande", free and sovereign thanks to the military genius of San Martin, who defeated Spanish armies not only in Argentina, but in the whole southern continent.
The meaning of "americano" in south america is linked to that idea of freedom, for the whole continent. It's not a lie nor a joke. I'm disgusted by your comment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511628497.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>And the use of American as the demonym for the United States predates San Martin’s liberations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511917250.0" user="Entropy_Drop" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but the first use of the name was in naming the continent "America". We didn't invent the name, neither you.

Its a non-consequitur. I despite this kind of discusion, where I explain my argument, and someone comes along and pretentiously adds a single obvious fact, then drops the mic as if he was dropping the most convincing argument ever. Pfff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511384782.0" user="unidentifiedfish55" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know how relevant this is (because it's only based on 4 years of high school Spanish), but Spanish has a word "Americano" which means "Ameircan" and a separate word, "Estadounidense", which means "belonging or relating to the United States of America"...or, essentially, United States-an.

So, coming from the point of view of someone where both of these words exist, it makes sense why they may be confused. While from the point of view of someone that speaks English (where United States-an doesn't really exist as a term), it would make sense why they'd be confused at their confusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511413187.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>That's exactly it. I call myself an American in English but I wouldn't say I'm americano in Spanish. A lot of tourists, like the guy I'm responding to, don't get this though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512175773.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>I get it just fine. In Spanish I say soy de Los estados unidos.  Any time this conversation occurs  with someone it is in English, which is why I don’t lend much credence to your lost in translation rationalization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512254442.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>If you understand Spanish then you're just an asshole for thinking they are obfuscating about being American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512285920.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, if you want to play like you’re lost in translation, that’s cool for you bro.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512303815.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>You're also an asshole for comparing South Americans who call themselves American to people who took a free online course and say they attended Harvard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512323789.0" user="stiffneck84" delta="False">
    <text>Oh no…say it ain’t t so</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511745719.0" user="A_bleak_ass_in_tote" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So, coming from the point of view of someone where both of these words exist, it makes sense why they may be confused at you using the word "American".

More than confusion, I think it's also the principle of it. As an American citizen who spent his childhood in Latin America I can tell you there's a sense of entitlement in some American tourists that rubs locals the wrong way, exacerbated by the bitter history between the US and Latin America during the red scare years. So when someone calls themselves an American in Spanish (americano) it pushes all the wrong buttons. 

You can see this entitlement in some of the comments here. A lot of people are saying that whoever doesn't like it can pound sand, rather than trying to understand the cultural differences and the context of why it's an issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512358423.0" user="kenatogo" delta="False">
    <text>As an American, I feel like it's a legitimate complaint to ask people to say "estadounidense" when speaking Spanish and not "americano". I'm on board with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512959599.0" user="OscarGrey" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on what the locals prefer. If I'm in Spain or a region of South America that uses "Americano" that's what I'm using.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513234456.0" user="kenatogo" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, I'll go with whatever the local custom in the local language is, since I'd like folks to do the same for us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513731303.0" user="MyNameIsAirl" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really think it's entitlement for people to want to choose what they are called. It seems more entitled to decide you are the arbiter of what people are called and start renaming groups without their input. I mean sorry our nation shares a name with the continents but you don't get to demand we go by a different name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515720870.0" user="unidentifiedfish55" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;  that rubs locals the wrong way

Shouldn't there also be some expectation of tolerance of American culture/language? Realization that the term "United States-an" doesn't really exist in English so if they say "American" they accept it or "Americano" they kindly correct them, rather than getting upset about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513305248.0" user="ParmAxolotl" delta="False">
    <text>I've tried to come up with an alternate name for us, to respect people who don't want us to hog the "American" title, but it's hard to find something that sounds nice. Yankee and Gringo are derogatory, and Yankee also specifically implies someone from the Northeast. Usonian, Statian, or other terms like that feel unnatural and forces. My current pick is 'Merican.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511639882.0" user="sarcazm" delta="False">
    <text>But people from the United States and Canada are from North America. So I don't understand how people in Central America or South America would be more or less American than people from the U.S.?? It's all America?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511670394.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's all America?

Yeah, that's exactly the point they are making. They don't think it's wrong for people from the US to call themselves American. They just also consider themselves American. 

In Spanish, the word for someone from the US is "estadounidense". An "Americao" is someone from the continent of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511641595.0" user="AstuteButIgnored" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like a them problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511710509.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>It's a language problem. In Spanish "americano" is not the right term to refer to someone from the US. Most US tourists don't understand that though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512157707.0" user="Warm-Belt7060" delta="False">
    <text>We’re not talking about americano though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511961444.0" user="FoxFogwell" delta="False">
    <text>Well what is confusing? If central and South Americans call themselves American, why shouldn’t North Americans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512137282.0" user="Warm-Belt7060" delta="False">
    <text>No they don’t</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513374685.0" user="GorillaBrown" delta="False">
    <text>Especially since the common descriptor of someone from the USA in Spanish is Estadounidense. 

Los hispanohablantes en España y América Latina usan el término estadounidense para referirse a personas y cosas de Estados Unidos (de Estados Unidos), mientras que americano se refiere a los continentes en su conjunto .
https://en.wikipedia.org › wiki › A...
Americano (palabra) - Wikipedia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511347214.0" user="grandpaRicky" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, it's definitely is a bunch of sour grapes. We've been, and are going to be Americans.

However, I think the world is past ready for some serious discussion about the effects of and remedies to colonialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511529025.0" user="Maximum_Poet_8661" delta="False">
    <text>It’s bc it basically is. And the crazy part is, tons of people from LATAM will also refer to themselves as “Americans”. they just don’t like it when people from the US do, bc at this point very few people think anything but “US” when someone uses the term “American” and they get pissy about that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552908902.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
