<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="214" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512625547.0" user="DGDPapiChulo" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for pointing this out. I don’t believe we should refer to ourselves as Americans when there are so many countries in the americas. There’s no alternative because the lineage of the U.S. were too dumb to think of something so now we settle for something ignorant like American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513508454.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>We did it because we were the First Nation to declare independence in the Americas, so it came naturally🤷‍♂️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521521171.0" user="DGDPapiChulo" delta="False">
    <text>You realize there were tons of different people living in the americas? Ones that did not need to declare independence because they were not held to to a place of servitude to begin with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521585789.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>Notice how I used the word nation. Most of the tribes were not, and still are not considered nations. The only exceptions are the Inca and Aztecs, and even then, irs a loose definition. 


I should’ve said non-native nation, but of course, the natives hardly consider themselves Americans, since “America” is a European word, they most likely would prefer to call themselves a memeber of their tribe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523697358.0" user="DGDPapiChulo" delta="False">
    <text>The Aztec empire was on par with the Spanish empire when we consider their technical and agricultural ability. If it’s a cultural trait for non European peoples to not recognize themselves as European, maybe just maybe it’s a cultural trait for Europeans to be arrogant and claim “America”.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
