<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510770590.0" user="One-Organization970" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't another effective way to convey one's nationality that doesn't sound weird to say, and so I shall continue to be an American. If there's confusion then I can specify, in the same way that someone who's Georgian might occasionally have to clarify that they mean the state/country rather than the country/state.

This whole critique really boils down to opening up the term. If Canadians, Mexicans, and central/south-Americans started referring to themselves as Americans too then it would potentially force people from the US to clarify. Still probably not though, because of context clues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511025357.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Did they offer an alternative term that doesn't sound stupid to say?

That would be counterproductive.  the point is to make up a reason to call americans assholes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511539574.0" user="NeuroticKnight" delta="False">
    <text>I just reply , i dont blame you, if I was from your country, id call myself American too, and it puts them on a weird loop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514176692.0" user="wadeinc" delta="False">
    <text>You can say you are from the States, the United States, or the USA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514425800.0" user="weedbeads" delta="False">
    <text>Is "US Citizen" too jank?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516063304.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>That's even more of an exclusionary term than American lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552980293.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
