<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="222" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512673633.0" user="LetsTalkFV" delta="False">
    <text>**Exhibit #1** Your Honour: the Publisher's Note of the "North American Edition" of [Eats, Shoots &amp; Leaves](https://www.amazon.ca/Eats-Shoots-Leaves-Lynne-Truss/dp/1592402038/) sold in Canada:

&gt;Publisher's Note  
  
Lynne Truss's  *Eats, Shoots &amp; Leaves*  has been reprinted exactly as it was in its original British edition, complete with British examples, spellings and, yes, punctuation. Any attempt at a complete Americanization of this book ***would have been akin to an effort to Americanize the Queen of England:*** futile and, this publisher feels, misguided. Please enjoy this narrative history of punctuation as it was meant to be enjoyed, bone-dry homour and cultural references intact, courtesy of Lynne Truss and all of us here at Gotham Books.

**Exhibit #2** Your Honour:  The original Canadian Constitution is the [British North America Act](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/British_North_America_Acts), which established the Dominion of Canada in 1867.

**Exhibit #3** Your Honour: At the time this book was published Queen Elizabeth II was Canada's (British North America) [Head of State](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monarchy_of_Canada). 

Thus, there is no need to "Americanize the Queen of England" as she was already the Monarch and Head of State of a very sizeable portion of North America.  Just not "America" as claimed by you Yanks.

  
I trust your post is partly trolling, just to see who'll bite. Hat tip - well done, Sir. However, we get this sh\*t in Canada all the time.  I presume the rest of the countries in North and South America do as well.  Not exactly your fault - it's really ours (*and the idiot Publisher from Gotham Books and his ilk*).  We should have been speaking up about this long ago.  But it does contribute to the world-wide dislike of people from the U.S. who come across like they think they're the centre of the universe.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
