<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="201" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512437636.0" user="NicksIdeaEngine" delta="False">
    <text>I can't prove that using the term American somehow harms others. My only argument is that this is something vague enough to where you can be technically correct while still creating a negative perception of yourself when you interact with people from other countries.

Most US citizens probably won't care if you call yourself American. Quite a lot of people from other countries may not care. For whatever reason, some people care, so if you have any professional ambitions which have you crossing paths with people from other countries, it might be in your best interest to at least be ready to switch terminology depending on who you're around.

Saying something like "I'm from the United States" is nearly as effortless as saying that you are an American. Even if you call yourself an American around people from other countries and they don't speak up about your word choice, they could start seeing you as being less respectful. Whether other people's opinions matter to you is your choice, but if you do have professional ambitions which results in lots of international interaction, You run the risk of being viewed as unprofessional or uneducated by not making a simple switch of terminology.

It's important to realize that words do not have static meaning, both through time and across the globe. A seemingly innocent term can wind up being interpreted very differently in other parts of the world. Strict definitions only matter so much. In the end, people will remember the colloquial meaning of the words you use rather than technical definitions or intent.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
