<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="131" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511833837.0" user="IssaLeroy" delta="False">
    <text>interesting, literally everyone refers to me as ‘american’ when i’m in europe. when people ask i usually just say “i’m from the states” though. idt i’ve ever referred to myself as american.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514542329.0" user="Kevincelt" delta="False">
    <text>I tend to refer to myself as American when living in Germany at least.  It’s also what I put down on government documents for my nationality, so at least in my experience calling yourself American is entirely uncontroversial where I am.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515459260.0" user="IssaLeroy" delta="False">
    <text>regardless, i think your friends were being a bit sententious about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516240413.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>I generally refer to myself as an American in most contexts, but when someone asks me what country I'm from, I always say "the United States" or "the U.S." This is specifically only when referring to the name of the country itself, though. I don't know why, but saying "I'm from America" just feels grating on my ears.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
