<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="411" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43517057677.0" user="New_Literature_5703" delta="False">
    <text>I've had this argument with so many people. I'm Canadian and I'm not American, I have no desire to call myself American, I do not identify with that label, and I cannot see myself ever wanting to call myself that.  Additionally I have members of my family who were born in Mexico. They also do not think of themselves as "Americans".

Germans seem to have a big issue with this. A friend of mine once met a German man and started dating him. She brought him over to Canada for a visit and he was so excited to go to Toronto. He told me that it was his "first American city" he had visited. I had to pull him aside and tell him never to say that ever again because if certain people heard him say that they might actually start a fight with him. He got so flustered and argued with me. Like we don't get to self-determine our own identity.

People who insist on calling people from N/S America "Americans" are disrespectful assholes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
