<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510766757.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>Mexico's official name is the United States of Mexico, they call themselves Mexican.

Brazil is the Federative Republic of Brazil, they call themselves Brazilian.

Dominion of Canada, Canadian

Almost every country in the world uses the same rules for what they call themselves. America is no different.

I don't see why anyone would identify more with their continent than their country, or why anyone would have a problem with this. Sounds like people who just want to complain about America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511003130.0" user="juant675" delta="False">
    <text>United Mexican states*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511293084.0" user="miraj31415" delta="False">
    <text>Estados Unidos Mexicanos*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512015405.0" user="hominumdivomque" delta="False">
    <text>people have a problem with it because America Bad (upvotes to the left btw)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512319758.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>Which part of America are we complaining about? That's a big CONTINENT! 

The difference is that the Republic of Brazil means "Brazil is a Republic" and "United States of America" means "These states are united on the CONTINENT of america"  

I'm not saying you are not American, you are! But you share the name with people from Canada to Argentina, they are also American. 

A more fitting name would be US Americans. Because just Americans is way too broad and could be about other 35 countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512444501.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>Very few countries teach that North and South America are one continent. Zero English speaking countries do. 

The most common word to refer to U.S. citizens in south America is "Americanos", they have every right to change that if they want. But especially in English speaking countries, everyone calls us American. No Canadian or Mexican would ever call themselves American. It's a silly thing to make an issue out of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512681780.0" user="SirErickTheGreat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; "United States of America" means "These states are united on the CONTINENT of america"

No, it doesn’t. For most of not all English-speaking countries, there is no such thing as a singular continent called “America” but are rather separated as North America and South America. I understand that many Latin American countries adopt a different model for how they divide continents, but Americans do not adopt that model so it is inapplicable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512879851.0" user="TickTock_Times" delta="False">
    <text>The US is America.

The other countries are a part of the Americas, with an S. Very different fundamentally despite only having a letter difference. There is no singular continent referred to as America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513044512.0" user="NopityNopeNopeNah" delta="False">
    <text>Hey, so I’m a US citizen, and my SO is a Latina immigrant. From her country’s perspective, both continents are America. Since we all live in them, we’re all Americans. She is patriotic to her home country, but she also feels a connection to other American countries, and feels a pride there.

The USA, coincidentally, has held an economic and political stranglehold over much of South and Central America for over a century. They violently overthrew the government of my SO’s country, and instituted an authoritarian dictatorship. And this isn’t a distant past; her parents were alive during this dictatorship. 

Are people from the US wrong for calling themselves Americans? I don’t believe so. It makes sense when you take into account the name of our country.

Are people from other American countries wrong for being upset about residents of USA calling themselves Americans? I don’t believe so. This can be taken (maybe deservedly so) as another attempt at hegemony over the continents. 

I’m not saying you have to stop calling yourself American. But maybe listen to the people around you, and be sympathetic to what they say. There’s enough pain in the world already, we should try to act with kindness and understanding wherever we can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513153312.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>I believe it is wrong to tell other people what they should call themselves especially when it's in a language that your home country doesn't speak. It's our identity, and has been since before any latin American countries existed. It's not just what we call ourselves either, it's what every English speaking country calls us. It's arrogant and certainly not kind to tell someone what they should or shouldn't call themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514356243.0" user="DaRealMVP2024" delta="False">
    <text>I think most intelligent people know how to use a word depending on language and context. No one culture is right or wrong about this, it’s just different</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513857886.0" user="hareofthepuppy" delta="False">
    <text>Because Mexico, Brazil and Canada aren't continents</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514239899.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, just like America :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514362736.0" user="DaRealMVP2024" delta="False">
    <text>To be honest, it is arrogant for the European Union to call themselves that. They don’t represent all of Europe, not even close.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514400824.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>Really? I haven't seen them doing that, but that's really shitty if they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515304015.0" user="AuroraHalsey" delta="False">
    <text>I see it a lot when it comes to /r/europe and Britain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515404505.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so they're salty the U.K. left the union?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515996346.0" user="AuroraHalsey" delta="False">
    <text>Some of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518276615.0" user="hareofthepuppy" delta="False">
    <text>Actually there are two of them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514177021.0" user="wadeinc" delta="False">
    <text>Dominion of Canada is not on a continent called 'North Canada', Mexico is not on a continent called 'North Mexico'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514421852.0" user="weedbeads" delta="False">
    <text>The issue there is that none of the other examples you gave are names of continents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514893689.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>Neither is America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517400950.0" user="minotaur-cream" delta="False">
    <text>Kind of interesting cause in spanish we refer to the U.S. as Estados Unidos which means unites states, and when you refer to someone from the U.S. you say Americano.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517477093.0" user="CheeseIsAHypothesis" delta="False">
    <text>I always thought Estadounidense was more common, do you mind if I ask what country you're from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517508228.0" user="minotaur-cream" delta="False">
    <text>I am from the US but I live 5 min from the border and was raised mexican and went to mexico like every weekend lol. All my fam is down there. 

I've never heard Estadounidense, maybe its more proper way to say it in Spain or other parts of the Spanish speaking world?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552979369.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
