<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="31" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510937815.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

*Within the United States* it is.  "The Americas" refer to the continent, plain and simple.  The fact that we tend to think about ourselves primarily and not our national neighbors is a.) reasonable and natural and b.) not a good reason to claim "American" as "our" word.  It's a self-centered thing to do, and of course it doesn't make sense to someone in Europe who, unlike us, does not think of this continent as just one country.

&gt;If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

Alternatives are easy.  "U.S. citizens", "People from the US", or even awful bullshit terms like "USonians" or "United Statesian".

You're probably thinking "all of those sound worse than 'American'", and I gotta say, I agree completely.  That doesn't automatically make "American" our word or change its meaning, though... but there certainly are alternatives.

As for how it harms other people in the Americas, there's no clear cut, direct harm anyone is going to be able to point to.  In an abstract way, the self-centered thinking that "american" represents is bad for non-americans, but there's no smoking gun for harm.  There doesn't need to be, either.  Again, the harm caused by a word doesn't impact its meaning or accuracy.  It doesn't sound like your European classmates were claiming any kind of direct harm, either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511142699.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>Within the United States? More like *within the English speaking world*. Ask somebody from Toronto if they're American and they'll say "No, I'm Canadian."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511153208.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>You might be right, but the English speaking world is still not the whole world.  Just because the word is understood doesn't mean it's accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511265711.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>We're literally arguing over what a word means in English. That a cognate in another language might have a different meaning is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511316701.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>The example that raised this discussion was from non-English speakers.  English isn't all that matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511380864.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like it was non-English speakers trying to enforce the conventions of their language on English. Unless they were arguing over use of the word *Amerikaner* rather than the word *American*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511590518.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>You're not really disputing my actual point, which is that English isn't all that matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511614678.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>Okay yeah so. What does that have to do with the meaning of the English word *American* ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511707425.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>I already wrote out my arguments in response to the OP.  You can refer to those.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511917322.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that *American*, *Amerikaner,* and *Americano* are cognates, but there are in fact different words in different languages. Just because *Americano* in Spanish might refer to anyone from either of the Americas, doesn't mean that *American* in English must have the same exact meaning. Why would a German's opinion matter when it comes to the meaning of English word? It would be equally absurd if I said to somebody in another language, "No, the way you're using this word in your own language is wrong, because in my language we have a similar word, but it means something different." No where did I say only the English language speaking world matters, so I don't know why you brought that up (it's almost as if you're not engaging with what I'm saying). But if we're talking about what a word means *in English,* it does not matter one bit what somebody from Germany or Argentina or Mongolia thinks what it should mean, because it's not their language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511368310.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>Read again what he wrote 🤡</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511466732.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>Let me break this down for you because you don't seem to be very sharp. *American* is a word in English. There are cognates in other languages, such as *Americano* in Spanish. In English *American* refers to somebody from the United States. This is true in the US. It is true in Canada. It is true in the UK. It is true in Australia. An English speaker would generally not refer somebody from Canada or Mexico or Paraguay as being American. In Spanish *Americano* refers to anybody from the Americas. Although they are related word, they are different words in different languages with different meanings. If we're talking about what an English word means, then no, the Spanish speaking word isn't relevant at all. Congrats on figuring out emojis by the way. Makes you sound real smart and mature.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514605583.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>Buddy you are obviously incredibly slow and simply incorrect. 

The guy you responded to referred to “the English speaking world” and you fail to even name every country in it (typical US American). He also never referred to the countries in which English is the first language of most people, that’s just your poor reading comprehension showing. He said the “English speaking world”, which is everyone speaking English in the world and that’s a lot of people not from those four countries you named. And most of those people do not equate America with the USA. 

American literally means from the Americas. It’s named after Amerigo Vespucci (probably news to you) who (another shocker) even went to middle and South  and Middle America first. The double continent “America” is named after him and thus even though it is understood as to mean “US American” it is simply imprecise. Again: It is just interpreted as meaning “from the US”. However, that is not entirely correct. 
Of course a Canadian is American. North American to be precise. Like you. Just as a Jamaican is American, South American. 
You are simply to slow, weak minded, intellectually inferior and lazy to use your own language properly and precisely. But well you are US American so that’s to be expected 🤡</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515505156.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know what asyndeton is? It's a rhetorical device where you intentionally omit a conjunction from a list. It has the effect of implying that the list is incomplete. It's pretty obvious my list was not supposed to be complete. Go ahead. Ask a Canadian if they're American, and see what they say.  


I see you're very proud of your third grade history knowledge. I'm sure your mother is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517775374.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>Lol just ignoring my argument because I clearly outmatched you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43527780667.0" user="Blazed-and-Confused5" delta="False">
    <text>Least racist europoor</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43529344490.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>People from the US don’t constitute a unique, single race. So it’s not racist to say “all US Citizens are uneducated trash.”
While this is hardly true, it seems to be the case for you as an individual as you don’t even understand the meaning of the most famous -ism there is. Scum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43530632506.0" user="Blazed-and-Confused5" delta="False">
    <text>"I can insult and generalize entire nationalities because you're actually a collection of races and not just one! Checkmate American!"

Lmao another racist europoor, don't you have a Romani to accuse of theft or something? Though i get it, an ethnically diverse society is an alien concept to most Europeans 

You are a walking snobbish European stereotype btw, have you ever tried talking like a normal person? People might find you less annoying, because I promise no one reads your comments and thinks you're intelligent lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43532018034.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>I just easily dismissed your weak ass insult by calling me racist, which is simply not the case. I surely am Anti American (like about 90% of the world outside of the US) but not racist. You obviously don’t know the meaning of the term. 
Your idiotic straw man citation shows your stupidity really well. 
I never stated that “I can insult entire nationalities because youre actually a collection of races…” I simply said doing so isn’t racist.
It is obvious that I can insult entire nationalities without any reason. However unless a nation is largely homogenous in its ethnicity (unlike Ameriweak) it’s not racist to call it and it’s inhabitants worthless trash.
I am disgusted by how uneducated, weak minded, intellectually inferior, fat and poor the average American is.

“Normal person” and “intelligence” out of a filthy American mouth xD I said it before but it’s like getting advice on how to sprint from a paraplegic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43534352581.0" user="Blazed-and-Confused5" delta="False">
    <text>Lmfao epitome of a eurotard cringelord

Literal embodiment of 🤓 touch grass loser, assuming you don't need a license to do so over in your impoverished little peninsula riding America's coattails</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43534616114.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>Ah buddy your lack of self esteem and confidence shows.
You know well how the US is a shit hole in comparison to our paradise. It’s not a matter of opinion but a verifiable fact. 
Crime rate through the roof, World's largest imprisoned population (both in numbers and as percentage of population), greatest gap between rich and poor among developed nations. Also greatest gap between top earners and bottom earners in the same company.
Most expensive health care system, while being the only country without universal health care in the developed world. Abortion abolished, racism against anything non white, religious fundamentalism, hate crimes, police brutality, 18th century gun laws, Trump, obesity, Anti-intellectualism, military worshipping. The list goes on.

I’m looking forward to trumps second term. He will thoroughly fuck your nation again and we will be watching from the other side of the Atlantic and eat our superior food, enjoy our superior education, bathe in our superior culture (well you don’t have one), laugh in more than one language and watch that shit hole burn. Really hoping
For another civil war to tear that shit down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43534725795.0" user="Blazed-and-Confused5" delta="False">
    <text>🤓</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43535027768.0" user="EntertainerNew1952" delta="False">
    <text>Little lost clown &lt;3</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43565686279.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43553066508.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511305027.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>See, the problem is, we are speaking our language, in our country, when we refer to ourselves as American.   The fact that anyone else might have an issue with that is an attempt at cultural dominance.   Ridiculous, but true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511584430.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>You're just repeating the premise of the CMV, you're not really engaging the arguments I made.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513922799.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>Sure I did.     


It isn't that Americans are telling Mexicans they can't use estadounidense when referring to citizens of the United States of America when speaking Spanish.   It's that some Spanish speakers get upset when the term American is used in English.    That's their attempt at enforcing their cultural values on us, not the other way around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511220218.0" user="SuperMazziveH3r0" delta="False">
    <text>American doesn't have to be "our" word to refer to us as Americans. The same way individuals in European nations can refer to themselves as Europeans while being citizens of specific countries. 

We are US citizens residing in the Americas, hence "Americans." 

But I understand the opposing view point where "American" is commonly used as a moniker for a US Citizen. You don't really find Canadians and Mexicans referring themselves as Americans very often in most contexts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511436281.0" user="Roadshell" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Within the United States  
&gt;  
&gt; it is.  "The Americas" refer to the continent, plain and simple.  The fact that we tend to think about ourselves primarily and not our national neighbors is a.) reasonable and natural and b.) not a good reason to claim "American" as "our" word.  It's a self-centered thing to do, and of course it doesn't make sense to someone in Europe who, unlike us, does not think of this continent primarily as just one country.

"The Americas" are two continents.  If referring to someone from North America you say "North American" and if referring to a South American you say "South American."  There are few if any situations in which you'd collectively refer to residents of the western hemisphere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513552277.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Edit: It’s rude to downvote when you disagree

Bro… what do you think the point of a downvote is? It’s there for a reason, I’m gonna downvote you because I very much disagree with your argument, hence why the button is there in the first place</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515248701.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>It's for comments that don't contribute to the discussion, but comments you don't like.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
