<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="143" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511961089.0" user="spicygingerpotato" delta="False">
    <text>Are we discounting common usage? Or is the usage only common in the US?

Virginia, Pennsylvania, and Massachusetts are officially Commonwealths "of" (Commonwealth of Virginia, etc). Nobody refers to themselves as citizens of the commonwealth, do they? They are just Virginia's, etc.

We refer to our nationality in the same manner, I think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513913055.0" user="Aminilaina" delta="False">
    <text>People in MA use the “Commonwealth” thing sometimes because anything using the state name is a mess and a half. We use Bay Stater the most though or we identify as a New Englander or a Bostonian if you’re close enough to Boston to count. 

Massachusettsan is I *think* the official one but I’ve never heard someone use it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517427889.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure the technical term for people from Massachusetts is "massholes"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517973542.0" user="Aminilaina" delta="False">
    <text>yes yes, we are proud of that one</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
