<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511766856.0" user="Mysterious-Maybe-184" delta="False">
    <text>I have two sets of beliefs in politics. I have a set of policy issues and a set of morality issues. I won’t compromise morality issues to attain policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513692705.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Which morality issues are important to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524067202.0" user="Lindsaypoo9603" delta="False">
    <text>See, I will. I don't care. Policy is more important to me and always has been except for when I was a kid</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43525648481.0" user="Mysterious-Maybe-184" delta="False">
    <text>It depends what your view of morality is. Banning abortions goes against my moral beliefs. Banning books and history goes against my moral beliefs. I will never vote for someone who uses religion to justify their policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43525813716.0" user="Lindsaypoo9603" delta="False">
    <text>Yea I'm not for any of that either. I don't think abortion should be banned but the 14 week time frame to get one unless it's rape or incest is reasonable to me. They shouldn't be aborting whole fetuses unless it poses a risk of death or severe damage to the mother. If u don't want it get it done before ur showing for God sake. But I also still don't vote based on any of those issues. I care about policy n money. Everyone is suffering right now, even my multimillionaire sister can't flip any of her houses cause they have to pay interest rates now and the market is not a buyers market rn and her husband died in 2021 and my nieces deserved the life they had. My dad was forced to retire cause of covid lockdowns but luckily he has 2 million in cash in savings alone but who warned us that long lock downs would result in an unlivable economy? Trump did. What is everyone dealing with rn? Unlivable prices and economy n it's honestly making me feel suicidal n I HAVE family money so i can't imagine how other ppl r feeling. It's a fucking mess. Everyone was gonna get covid either way so it was stupid to be locked down so long thanks to the left now we r living in worse economy than Bush recession. I can't do it anymore. And the crisis at the border? What the fuck. Handle it like Trump was my God. It's a mess. Now all I can think of is Marty Huggins in "the campaign" movie where he runs against Will Ferrell. Lol "it's a maesss"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43526068026.0" user="Mysterious-Maybe-184" delta="False">
    <text>I’m sorry to hear about your BIL and your nieces.  I’m sorry your dad was forced to retire. I’m being serious. That really does suck. 😞</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43526191058.0" user="Lindsaypoo9603" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you 🩷</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
