<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="211" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512609589.0" user="turnipqueen618" delta="False">
    <text>Boy howdy do we Americans have our issues and it’s important to be mindful of our nation’s contributions to history, the shameful as well as the positive. However, I think this is a damned if we do, damned if we don’t situation. Americans receive a lot of backlash (rightfully so) when we describe ourselves as Irish, Italian, Lithuanian, or what have you to people who actually live in or have emigrated from those places. Because we’re such a melting pot and because our country is so young, it’s difficult for a lot of people to identify with what it means to be “American,” and so we often tend to identify with where our families originated generations ago —especially those of us whose families have maintained those French, Scottish, etc. traditions. As someone who has traveled outside the US, I’ve been very warmly welcomed in most places by most people, but I have also encountered people who love to ridicule Americans as we are, admittedly an easy target. If your classmates and professor had no constructive or alternative suggestions, they can pretty much shove off as far as I’m concerned. We can do better when we learn better, but it’s not entirely clear exactly what the problem is or how exactly it’s destructive to call ourself Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
