<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="163" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512157008.0" user="lockieleonardsuper" delta="False">
    <text>Should just go by Seppo instead of American like Aussies use

Yank = Septic Tank = Seppo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512177612.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>ngl that sounds retarded</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512198595.0" user="lockieleonardsuper" delta="False">
    <text>It's a joke mate, usually said in jest 

Also thats a horrible word to use</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512276241.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>FFS you are gonna lecture me when your well thought out insult in jest is to call someones culture shit how rich</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512292851.0" user="lockieleonardsuper" delta="False">
    <text>Haha it's not an insult, it's been used since WW2 at least as an endearing nickname for Americans. It's not serious, have some sense of humour</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512335035.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>yank humor is outrage hope you enjoyed lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512345902.0" user="lockieleonardsuper" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it well know in Australia that Americans have a very different sense of humour</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512373749.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>almost like its a big country im sure the 80,000 americans there appease to you lot a lot more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43553052999.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43553048792.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
