<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="185" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512304895.0" user="Low-Inspection5024" delta="False">
    <text>Just explain the natural order of the world and how American superiority rules the majority of the developed world. The American Eagle is already soaring over Europe and soon everyone will consider themselves an American, you're just helping them get used to the ring of it. /s 

Objectively speaking American is technically correct when referring to a citizen from the United States of \*ahem\* America. The United States is officially known as The United States of America and there isn't another country on the continent that is a conglomerate of united states nor begins with the words "united states". So to request anything other even if they didn't know where you're from is to play stupid for the sake of trying to make some bold and brave stance against the imagined evil imperialistic United States. Any foreigner who tries to tell an American what they should call themselves out of the fear of imperialism is unironically practicing a classic feature of "imperialism."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
