<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510498362.0" user="LochFarquar" delta="False">
    <text>I think "wrong" is difficult here in that these are relatively minor semantic issues, and I'm not sure that either using "American" or objecting to our use "American" is morally right or wrong.  But I think there's a reasonable discussion to be had about what's the best approach.

The United States of America, as a name, simply makes this awkward. 

On the one hand, many countries have similar names with \[Government Description\] \[Location\] as the formula, and the people are then denoted by location. People from the Republic of Korea are referred to as Korean, people from the People's Republic of China are referred to as Chinese, etc. So, it makes sense that we're Americans on that formulation.

On the other hand, it would be odd if people from a particular country in Europe referred to themselves as European and expected everyone else to acknowledge and agree that "European" referred to people from that country and not everyone from the continent of Europe. And I expect there would be extra offense if that country in Europe was generally viewed by its neighbors as using its outsized military and economic power to exert its influence over the rest of Europe.

&gt;citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact.

This is true in English and as determined by people from the USA. It's not universally true (e.g. in Mexico we're Estadounidense, not Americanos). If the view is that we've presumptuously claimed the title that should belong to others in the Americas as well, the fact that it's what we call ourselves becomes circular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511167801.0" user="oroborus68" delta="False">
    <text>God bless Vespucci Land. We are Vespuccians!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511231113.0" user="notrandomonlyrandom" delta="False">
    <text>Wow this really went off the rails.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511320394.0" user="kindall" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of Mexico, their actual name is literally Spanish for "The United States of Mexico." If they get to call themselves "Mexico," I don't see why the United States of America can't go by "America."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513831006.0" user="hareofthepuppy" delta="False">
    <text>Because "The United States of Mexico" includes all of Mexico (as far as I'm aware), but there are a ton of other countries in the Americas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514127371.0" user="andolfin" delta="False">
    <text>Mexico (the country) is named after a rather large valley around Mexico city. It would be like calling the USA the United States of the Chesapeake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516709359.0" user="kindall" delta="False">
    <text>But it's not the United States of the Americas</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511333404.0" user="brntGerbil" delta="False">
    <text>What's your opinion on calling us USAaians? That seems to be the closest fit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515680397.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>No need to drag Asia into this fight too</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511348962.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Every time I’ve been to Mexico I’ve only been called an Americano, can’t say I’ve ever heard Estadounidense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511497146.0" user="Americanski7" delta="False">
    <text>The only people offended are some university students in Chile.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512631770.0" user="blurplesnow" delta="False">
    <text>That could depend on where you visited.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511358140.0" user="Disdain690" delta="False">
    <text>What are you even going on about? The USA is the only country in the hemisphere with 'America' in the name. That's why we're referred to as Americans without it being confusing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511448831.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; On the other hand, it would be odd if people from a particular country in Europe referred to themselves as European and expected everyone else to acknowledge and agree that "European" referred to people from that country and not everyone from the continent of Europe. 

If there was a reason for it and the inertia behind it-- which is to say, there was a country named "The Great Nifty Republic of Europe", and it'd been around for a significant part of the current structure of Europe as a whole, such as the US is-- I don't think it'd be that odd. It'd have already been worked out and the ambiguity worked around for some time. Doubly so if it was as prominent on its continent as the US is on North America.

Granted, what I'm saying is kind of a tautology-- "If it was the same, it'd be the same"-- but I suppose the point is that you can't really compare plunking down a hypothetical country in an already-identified Europe with a country that grew up with its name for practically as long as there were the modern set of countries on the continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513776534.0" user="shazzwackets" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; If there was a reason for it and the inertia behind it-- which is to say, there was a country named "The Great Nifty Republic of Europe", and it'd been around for a significant part of the current structure of Europe as a whole, such as the US is-- I don't think it'd be that odd.

It's called the European Union, and it would perhaps be offensive if ***EU citizens*** monopolized the term "European".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514870340.0" user="SuperFLEB" delta="False">
    <text>The EU's only been around since about the 1960s, and even less time than that with the name and identity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511452776.0" user="JustForTheMemes420" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair in Mexico I’ve heard people use americanos too since the other is harder to say, it’s like saying bolígrafo instead of pluma</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512262289.0" user="ExtremeNuance" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve always wondered too like, what are we supposed to call our country when we’re abroad? I knew that “America” was a controversial term, so whenever I said where I’m from I would say “I’m from the United States” but I remember a couple people who I had a language barrier with being confused by that (this was in Northern Europe), and they didn’t understand when I said USA or US either; it wasn’t until I said “I’m from America” that they seemed to understand. 

I want to be as respectful as possible, but at a certain point if you can’t communicate clearly then that’s not gonna work. So like…what are we supposed to do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513340663.0" user="SchnitzelTruck" delta="False">
    <text>Just say American. As someone who travels a ton, many countries call us some variation of "american". The root of this post is also total bullshit because Germans call Americans Amerikaner.... Hypocritical outrage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515040688.0" user="bremidon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I knew that “America” was a controversial term

It's not.  There are some midwits trying to make it sound like it is, but that is more of an example of people not having anything better to do with their time than anything of merit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513358601.0" user="StealthLSU" delta="False">
    <text>Except to those of us Americans, America is not a continent so a country trying to call themselves European doesn't equate. 

We have north and south America. Also you never hear anyone say American when referring to the continents. At most, I've heard people say they are from the Americas, but even that is rare. 

I think the Americas have never been seen as anything close to as monolithic as Europe when referencing them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513860358.0" user="Mysterious_Spell_302" delta="False">
    <text>If there was a country called the United States of Europe, and it was the first country to be formed on the continent of Europe, and its people were known as Europeans before any other country had formed on that continent, then the people from other countries who objected to the citizens being called Europeans would absolutely either just seem like cranks itching for a fight or like people who don't understand how time works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513879532.0" user="AssassinWench" delta="False">
    <text>I guess my confusion is, why does it matter what people from the US call themselves in English compared to what people from Spanish-majority countries call Americans in Spanish? 

Pulling from a completely different country, in Japan they say アメリカ人 (America + Person) and they don't associate/confuse that with people from Central or South America....</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
