<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510164170.0" user="VesaAwesaka" delta="False">
    <text>What we would call them if not American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510215930.0" user="MansfromDaVinci" delta="False">
    <text>Usians</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510230924.0" user="arBettor" delta="False">
    <text>Poor Asian-Usians</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510291865.0" user="NicklAAAAs" delta="False">
    <text>I genuinely can’t imagine writing this and not feeling like an idiot lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510289989.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>USAdians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511014580.0" user="juant675" delta="False">
    <text>This may feel wrong to you but in me country we call them Yankee</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511363095.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>Which is VERY offensive to large sections of the United States population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511563935.0" user="Impossible_Nature_63" delta="False">
    <text>It is? Must be a regional thing. I don’t know anyone who would give a shit about being called a yankee. I live in the mountain west for reference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511666943.0" user="sadmaps" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I live on the west coast and have never once been offended when referred to as a yankee or yank, is it supposed to be offensive? Why? Lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511701210.0" user="Impossible_Nature_63" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it is seen as a pejorative for Americans in other parts for the world. At least that is what a bit of light googling suggests.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512106914.0" user="MicrowavedPuppies" delta="False">
    <text>It’s just people from the South who might get offended.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513905085.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>Mostly the South, but conservatives across the country.  Yankee is slang for someone from the NE, most strongly associated with NY and Mass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513932031.0" user="Aminilaina" delta="False">
    <text>Someone from MA will kill you for calling them a Yankee if they’re Irish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511822281.0" user="Major_Pressure3176" delta="False">
    <text>Other comments said "Yankee" is offensive in the South.

I mean, if they want to be *proud* of the Civil War...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512754074.0" user="SirErickTheGreat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Which is VERY offensive to large sections of the United States population.

To be fair, many Americans including some presidents say things like “shit-hole countries” to refer to impoverished nations so we really don’t have a leg to stand on when it comes to feeling offended.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513187507.0" user="WinPeaks" delta="False">
    <text>That's not how that works at all. Just because some of our people are offensive dicks doesn't mean that we don't get to be mad when other people are offensive dicks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513928769.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>It's offensive dicks all the way down!   


But yes, absolutely concur.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511452062.0" user="librarygoose" delta="False">
    <text>And see, if I was out and about on vacation and someone called me a Yankee I'd think they were a dick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513022938.0" user="OscarGrey" delta="False">
    <text>The term "yankee" as a generic term for Americans in British English predates the Civil War.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516078878.0" user="librarygoose" delta="False">
    <text>It's does yes. Buts it's always been insulting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511821359.0" user="thomash363" delta="False">
    <text>Yankee within the United States is something people south of the Mason-Dixon Line refer to people from the north as.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512931059.0" user="ophmaster_reed" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, and it not meant as a nice term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513517993.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a derogatory term

You wouldn’t call someone from Germany a “Barbarian” or “Hun” since that’s what they used to be called by people who really didn’t like them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515257939.0" user="juant675" delta="False">
    <text>Well but we kind of do we call them Aleman wich was  one of the germánico tribes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511479359.0" user="No_Signature_1893" delta="False">
    <text>Usonians</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
