<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43514162995.0" user="mphofourtiredeyes" delta="False">
    <text>While I think it’s a generally true statement that ideological purity tends to correlate with worse electoral outcomes, I think I can a) explain some of the reasons why people are willing to accept that trade off and b) argue that the trend is not guaranteed to eventuate every time. A lot of this comes down to the fact that while you’re welcome to unpack it further, I do believe that your echo chamber logic is not really where most voters are approaching politics from either way.

I would just contest from the first paragraph the idea that they have more in common with their opponents than the centrist. I’m not American but assuming they’re likely the most mutually comprehensible example here - eg Bernie Sanders and his supporters and Joe Manchin and his kind of voters broadly align on a) we should expand govt spending and b) we’re not keen on rolling back lots of rights. Neither are in agreement with the large majority of Republicans. Would have to hear more to understand where this claim is coming from.

“Voting for people who hate you” I think is an inaccurate framing of voting. You don’t vote for other voters, you vote for politicians. Politicians are incentivised to get votes or get out, and so they try to convince you they like you and want your vote and downplay disunity on their side. For sure it’s true some voters are repelled by others on their side, but I think it stands to reason most people vote based on what they’re voting for, not as an instinctive reaction to things they can’t change. Especially because if you don’t vote for a side you likely vote for the alternative, and presumably the alternative are more unpalatable for the reasons I just laid out there earlier.

I agree that that’s an apt analysis of echo chambers that do exist. I think the logic you lay out aptly explains why most people don’t have much to do w echo chambers hostile to them. The average swing voter is not joining Truth Social or in a mutual aid and socialist rifles Discord. There’s not a pathway for them to get there and seriously engage with, and therefore backlash against, those ideas in the first place. 

I understand your use of echo chambers is broader here, but most people sit within mainstream spaces both by the definition of the word and because of the incentives for politicians etc to appeal to swing voters. I’ll engage with the example you’ve given, but I think it’s largely a philosophical hypothetical not reflective of most voters.

(Because voters a) do not engage with politics much, b) are reasonably happy with life, and c) have an idiosyncratic view set, live in a world where everybody else has an idiosyncratic view set, and can live with and accept that.)

There’s a missing mechanism from your example. Just because I open a gate to everyone and say “you’re all welcome in my Free Pony Party”, doesn’t mean everybody walks in to my echo chamber (even if they’re not thinking of voting for me yet). 

The missing mechanism is why voters would buy into these spaces just because they’re open. What you lay out clearly shows a lack of incentive to join, because they agree on hardly anything, and obviously by comparison less than in the echo chamber they were previously in. 

I think this feeds into my earlier arguments: most voters stay away from echo chambers on their own side and on the opposing side, too, and so while there’s a correlation with not voting directly for a politician who holds the views of the echo chamber on your side, it’s weak because a) the alternatives are worse and b) most people vote. 

To move more to the real life side of things, I think what a lot of these relatively detached and abstract arguments miss is the visceral ways in which a “lack of ideological purity” often means more concrete things IRL. The Democrat coalition in the US largely excludes politicians and perspectives which support restricting abortion rights. You can come up with somebody who agrees on 9/10 things, but they will be against a key right of half of Democrat voters, and abortion rights have clearly been a buoy for Democrat vote totals recently despite setting a more ideologically pure bound than sitting on the fence and not taking a stance on, eg, whether democrats should run candidates who support forcing people to give birth. 

Moving fully into the realm of the real, “purist” arguments can work for three reasons. One is that they provide a clear alternative that theoretically more open approaches can fail to provide because they’re wishy washy and vague. Jeremy Corbyn in 2017 ran the most radical Labour campaign in a generation or two, but what he stood for was clearer than the Tories and so he gained votes from a more centrist campaign two years prior while they lost with a more centrist leader than two years prior. 

Two is that politics is not always a clear left-right. Donald Trump ran a very purist campaign in 2016 from a certain point of view: he did not moderate his line or deviate from his positions he stated in the primary like most candidates did. Yet polls showed because of his idiosyncratic, hardline positioning on issues like trade and immigration that most voters actually rated him as more moderate than Hillary Clinton, a notorious triangulator who cut to the centre after the primary was done! 

Three is that you need to weigh up opportunity costs between reaching out to voters who don’t agree with you on everything versus turning out those who do. Persuasion is usually the right move, but sometimes the centre ground is either too difficult to reach (baked in perceptions, cost of advertising, your base would turn on you) or you actually already have enough to win. 

Until the 80s the Democratic Party was the dominant party in the USA and most voters were registered Democrats. It made more sense for candidates like JFK and especially LBJ to run on liberal programs than to play the game of economic moderation, because to do so might have won a few soft Republicans but would have been an unnecessarily risky trade off on the Democrat base. 

All of this is amplified when you consider the role of parties is not just to win elections but to, uh, run the government and look after people. Expanding the tent can make it likelier that you win the first election. Governing on compromise decisions with less decisive policy making and more time and resources given to placating those not already on your side can leave you with fewer concrete achievements and a less clear program of government. These long term trade offs are not often considered in politics or by the public but they are far more real than positions on a piece of paper.

I hope some of these thoughts are insightful and feel free to share more of your own!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
