<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="78" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511454122.0" user="drewling390" delta="False">
    <text>Here’s an analogy that I’ve found helpful. If someone is from Buffalo, New York, they are a “Buffalonian” in the city-sense and a “New Yorker” in the state-sense. Someone from New York, New York is a New Yorker in the city and state sense. Either group is ok to call themselves a “New Yorker”, but may find it helpful to expand in what sense they mean that. A Buffalonian shouldn’t be offended by a New York City-er to call themselves a New Yorker.

Similarly, someone from Chile is a “Chilean” in the country-sense, and “American” in the continent-sense. Someone from the USA is “American” in both senses. Either group is ok to call themselves “American”. However, some Chilean’s or other Latin Americans have a complicated relationship with the imperialism of the USA and consider the use of “American” as another way of imperializing the continent. I don’t agree with that perspective, but I can see where they come from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512284589.0" user="iamgr0o0o0t" delta="False">
    <text>That is a helpful analogy!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512699299.0" user="1Shadowgato" delta="False">
    <text>This makes no sense, our identity is not based on what part of the continent we are from, we don’t go telling people we are “South Americans” is there but we don’t recognize it unless you are speaking of the region. Brazilian is Brazilian, Peruvian is Peruvian, American is American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513711343.0" user="Varyxos" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, that's true, the US definitely has an oversized share of public consciousness, anywhere in the world.

But in South America, it has shaped the lives and history of the entire continent through imperialism, and still does through neocolonialism.

Taking issue with calling people from the USA, Americans, I think stems from a feeling of not being recognised as different, independent and important states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514282909.0" user="1Shadowgato" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t have to do with any of that, it literally boils down to the fact that our countries are not named “America”. We are all aware in some shape or form that America has destabilized the region, but again, is  not something that just hover over us like a dark cloud. We have too much to worry about to be hyper fixated on “America bad”. 

And if this was not the case, then why is there such a high volume of immigration to the U.S from central and South American countries?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514473973.0" user="Varyxos" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that people focus on "America Bad", whatever that means. Just that US interference is the cause of a lot of the destabilisation in the region (and the world). That's something that people recognise in general.

Also the reason why there's immigration is usually economic. If moving to the US offers the possibility of supporting your family, the fact that the US extracted the ressources of your country, and is responsible in part for the lack of opportunities in your country, is unlikely to sway you significantly enough to decide against moving. 

Also, my own mother taught me to say estadounidense (and gringo) instead of americano. It's not an invented sentiment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512710900.0" user="Seantwist9" delta="False">
    <text>You shouldn’t call yourself a new Yorker unless you’re from the city</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512997615.0" user="Tymptra" delta="False">
    <text>Well someone from Chile would actually be a South American. The continental/regional designations exist...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513272664.0" user="ParmAxolotl" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure most Latin American school teach that America is a singular continent. I've been told by quite a few people from there that they view the separation of North and South America as an imperialist invention of the US. Make of that what you will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515380736.0" user="Arcturus1981" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps you’ve had one teacher say that, but I seriously doubt there are a majority of teachers anywhere debating the 7 continents.  Of course the separation of North America and South America is an invention, all borders are inventions for a myriad of reasons. 

North and South America are not political borders, they’re geographical borders made up by humans and our nature to compartmentalize and organize things… such as the land masses of the globe. A perfect example of how irrelevant they are to any one nation is that there is no hard line border between Europe and Asia.  If they were political borders there would be a line designating what territory is in which continent.  So, how does categorizing countries as South American benefit the US as opposed to including them in North America, or having one big America?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515404863.0" user="ParmAxolotl" delta="False">
    <text>I haven’t gone to school in Latin America, only in the US, but I know this from online friends and from my family from down south. There’s some maps I’ve found explaining that apparently most of the world uses the 7 continents model you’re familiar with, but the Hispanophone word mostly used a 6 continent model. The English Wikipedia page for continents claims there are 7, but the Spanish one claims there are 6. In post-Soviet states, they mostly use a model of 6 continents that considers Eurasia as one, but North and South America as distinct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515753218.0" user="Arcturus1981" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they do that though and how can the explanation be that it’s an imperialist invention when it wouldn’t benefit the “perpetrators”?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515764411.0" user="ParmAxolotl" delta="False">
    <text>Been told it separates the USA from the majority of Latin America or something like that

Tbf the average person seems to think South America starts at the Rio Grande so maybe that’s how this idea started</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515797571.0" user="Arcturus1981" delta="False">
    <text>Strange. But, I mean, if they want to call it one continent they have every right to, just like anyone can call it 2: North and South.  Again, it’s all arbitrary and made up by humans.  What I can’t understand is how they teach it has anything to do with imperialism. I can’t believe that most people would accept that at face value and not expect a logical explanation.  Even one devised by propaganda wouldn’t make sense because there is no benefit for the US to do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522022640.0" user="ParmAxolotl" delta="False">
    <text>Oh wait I remember the explanation I heard now. That the border between North and South was placed between Panamá and Colombia to encourage Panamá to revolt so that America could build the canal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515912305.0" user="Tymptra" delta="False">
    <text>Well it's not our fault they teach things incorrectly because of their own sense of nationalistic pride. North and South America are clearly separated and are even on their own continental plates...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513328182.0" user="NSA_Wade_Wilson" delta="False">
    <text>As a Canadian, I don’t like being called an American. We never refer to people from the Americas here as Americans. Just like we don’t refer to people as Eurasian</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513815180.0" user="620minime" delta="False">
    <text>I’ll add that in English there’s no word for “United Statesian”, but is Spanish there is: “estadounidense”. I had friends in Chile not know the our country was called “United States of America” they just thought we were called “The United States.”  This lead to confusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513817716.0" user="Mysterious_Spell_302" delta="False">
    <text>It would be imperialistic if it hadn't already been a thing way before Chile became a country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513858022.0" user="civicvirtues" delta="False">
    <text>Buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo Buffalo buffalo.

Iykyk.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513985419.0" user="Comfortable-Class576" delta="False">
    <text>In Spanish, what you call “American” is referred as “Unite Statean” / “Estadounidense”. And American is only used for the Americas. Also, I was taught that the Americas is a single continent “America”. Just so you understand where this is coming from. So in Spanish, American is equivalent to European and “Estadounidense” for example to German, that is why Latinos may get offended, it is a translation issue in my opinion. Not sure how they say this in German.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514185126.0" user="charliehorse8472" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's a pretty useful analogy except for the fact that it doesn't acknowledge the time line of how these places were named, which I feel is a valid point when arguing who has the right to use a name. The state of New York was named after the city so people from Buffalo should have no gripes with New Yorkers using it because it was theirs first. The United States on the other hand was named after the continent that it was on, which to some others living on the same continent seems kinda pretentious. If the French decided to rename their nation to the European federation and started referring to themselves as Europeans solely rather than French it would probably perturb their neighbors as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515036220.0" user="penguin_torpedo" delta="False">
    <text>New York City has more people than the rest of the state. The USA doesn't have more people than the rest of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515889289.0" user="drewling390" delta="False">
    <text>That is true, but I don’t think that prevents those groups from using “New Yorker” or “American” any less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517559768.0" user="BestPaleontologist43" delta="False">
    <text>That must be a small minority of people who I wouldnt bat an eye to. Guatemalan people dont really feel this way en masse, but we do have select dummies, usually first generations who come back from the USA, who feels this way. Most people too busy trying to live their lives or in the countryside, survive, to think about social issues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
