<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="257" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513124815.0" user="Insightseekertoo" delta="False">
    <text>I'll get voted down here, but those of us who live in the USA are US citizens from the US. Calling us Americans is arrogant since there are 34 other countries in the Americas. Saying we're Americans is saying that the US is the most important country in both North and South America. US citizen vs. American is a courtesy and a gesture of respect. It just takes a little humility, empathy, and awareness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513495748.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t get the argument tbh. We gained independence before any of those nations, so we naturally called ourselves “The United States of America” since we were the only independent, non-native (although the natives are very hard to consider nations at the time we became independent) Nation

There’s no other name for our country besides our states names. You’ll never get even a small majority of people to go by “United Statesmen” or “Statesmen” or “Unitedian”, and in English we naturally use that form when talking about someone from their country “French, English, Belgian, German, etc.”

We aren’t going to change our country name, so why care so much about it? 


Finders keepers, eh?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513933619.0" user="Insightseekertoo" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying first come, first served. I think a few native Americans would like a word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516463307.0" user="Insightseekertoo" delta="False">
    <text>Calling ourselves Americans is just another form of colonialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516675210.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>Mhm, keep telling yourself that buddy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517419335.0" user="Insightseekertoo" delta="False">
    <text>My dude, Brazil was colonized by Portugal in the 1500s. I mean if you want to claim "Independence" as a measure of "Rightness" they get the award.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
