<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="389" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43514940384.0" user="_crash_nebula_" delta="False">
    <text>Late answer but here’s a non-north american take. Here in Brazil, people don’t usually refer to people from the US as “americans” (“americanos”, in portuguese), we prefer “estaduninense”, which would roughly translate to “united-statesian” which is gramatically correct in portuguese, funny enough. From an outsider perspective, specially coming from a country that is commonly bellitled and stereotyped by ppl from the US, yes, it is weird and arrogant of you guys to refer to yourselves as the entire continent, and yes, it is 100% reminiscent of the fact that you guys feel like you are the protagonists of the world, and that’s because you do feel like that, deep down. Who wouldn’t? Through neo-colonialism, sabotage, slavery and the military-industrial complex you guys have forcefully put yourselves in such position to the detriment of all other countries and the fact that you guys feel the need to refer to yourselves as “americans” is very symbolic and true to how you guys see yourselves in comparison to other american countries.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
