<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="70" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511400879.0" user="Yellowdog727" delta="False">
    <text>It literally just makes sense with the name of the country. No other country in the Americas has the word "America" in their name.

Canada = Canadian

Mexico = Mexican

Venezuela = Venezuelan

Colombia = Colombian

El Salvador = Salvadoran

But apparently United States of America can't go by "American"? What are we supposed to call ourselves - US'ers? United-statesians?

People in the UK generally call themselves "British", "Scottish", "Welsh", or "Northern Irish" because it sounds stupid to say "UK'er" or "United Kingdomian"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511882104.0" user="BrutusJunior" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;People in the UK generally call themselves "British", "Scottish", "Welsh", or "Northern Irish" because it sounds stupid to say "UK'er" or "United Kingdomian"

Call them Charles' subjects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513529356.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>“Presidentials” or “The Presidents Men” sounds pretty badass tbh</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
