<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="49" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511169498.0" user="Writing_is_Bleeding" delta="False">
    <text>What is the alternative, did they give you one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511830183.0" user="Cortadew" delta="False">
    <text>Us citizen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511934797.0" user="Writing_is_Bleeding" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's what I would say if I was traveling abroad. I might say, "American, U.S., Oregonian," to make things perfectly clear, depending on where I am and who I'm talking to. Reading the room I might add, "Did NOT vote for Trump." 

If they start by asking if I'm "American" I would probably say, "Yes, from Oregon." The last time I traveled outside of the US was in 2003, to British Columbia, and I think we got asked that a few times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511969029.0" user="Cortadew" delta="False">
    <text>I was kinda joking but as a Chilean I think the discussion is pretty dumb, I personally have no problem with people from the USA calling themselves 'americans' I think some people here get butthurt over something so trivial, so I kinda agree with most people here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512578163.0" user="Writing_is_Bleeding" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I prefer to be culturally sensitive, as well as not looking like an ignorant 'Murican, so I'm always open to suggestions. I know the rest of the world is looking at us with side eye, for good reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515965357.0" user="Cortadew" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is you can do some effort in that direction but you can't please everyone, you can't expect anyone to not be butthurt over anything you do and as a latin american I think my fellow countrymen get upset over this which I think is so dumb.

Also I think you shouldn't feel sorry for the dubious US government actions  unless you support them of course.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
