<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="108" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511680196.0" user="nikoboivin" delta="False">
    <text>Proving how the use of the word American harms other ls from the Americas is incredibly easy.  Just watch how quickly Canadians or any other english-speaking citizen of the continent will dissociate from the baggage of hatred, bigotry and stupidity that the word has internationally and you’ll see why it’s offensive.

I’d love for people to refer to me as American the same way I can refer to Europeans, but there’s no way I’m letting anyone imply I might be from the US of A so yeah, the appropriation of the term is, indeed, hurtful cause it absolutely soils it internationally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512313727.0" user="SagewithBlueEyes" delta="False">
    <text>My friend, where are you from? Cause if you think the US alone has baggage, you might want to open a text book of your own country.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
