<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="283" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513367681.0" user="Skea_and_Tittles" delta="False">
    <text>Black American here. Half Sicilian, the rest is a mix of various African and European countries. As Donald Glover once phrased it when talking about white folks who like to tout what percentages of X and Y they are when race comes up, “You see, this spooky thing called slavery happened, so our whole heritage was erased”. 

Well, I eventually was able to get a DNA test and learn about my heritage. But, the “One Drop” rule is still an unspoken rule in our society, so I’m always deemed black, or African American, despite most of my genetic makeup being Sicilian. 

My answer to this is that, while I am perfectly fine considering myself black, I am *American*. That’s it. The family that I know is American. They worked hard in this country, paid their taxes, fought our wars, and furthered their line here. Despite its flaws Im proud to be from this nation and I have no problem taking ownership of being called American. Not African American, not anything else, just *American*. Life is simpler that way and not only do I not mind, I’m proud of it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
