<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="109" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511681477.0" user="UnevenSleeves7" delta="False">
    <text>That would also suggest that you aren’t from the Americas yourself, so I guess I don’t get their side very well either.  It’s true that when I introduce myself to foreign friends on the internet and whatnot I say that I live in the United States and most commonly I refer to America as *the US* but I don’t see how it would offend someone for me to call myself an American, I’m from here, the Americas.  I once had a friend come up from Chile and he’s the reason I say *the US* now, he made it important to me to make that distinction, but because of your posts I now realize that he was also saying not to call myself American in that same breath, or maybe he was more specifically saying that I shouldn’t say I’m from America, as even as white as I am I may confuse someone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
