<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510213141.0" user="Bodoblock" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's just a cultural difference, especially to Latin Americans. I've noticed in Latin America that there seems to be a lot more cultural cohesion (even if there is tension) between the countries of the Americas, from Mexico down to Argentina.

They all view themselves as parts of American countries, but with Latin heritage. Individually they are Colombian, Guatemalan, Peruvian, etc. But they fall into the larger whole of being part of the Americas.

So some do take some offense to the idea that those of us from the US refer to ourselves as "Americans", as if we have claim to the term to ourselves exclusively. Especially given the historical precedence of the Monroe Doctrine and American involvement in Latin America as if this region were ours to dictate as we wish.

To that end, I think it's fine to call ourselves Americans. Culturally, we understand that this name does not imply dominion over all the Americas. 

But when you're with company that does take offense to this -- especially given the history of American imperialism -- I think it'd be polite to understand the cultural difference and respect that difference. Especially if you're in their home. I would say being respectful of cultural idiosyncrasies is a nice thing to do and purposefully ignoring that is actually wrong.

In the case of Germany, however, I do find that odd and I think your classmates just have a stick up their ass. In Latin America, be polite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510421415.0" user="TSN09" delta="False">
    <text>This glosses over the fact that Americans don't have another term for themselves. They are the United States of America. If you ask them not to be American, it's quite literally asking a Mexican not to call themselves Mexican. There is no alternative.

So while normally... Yeah be understanding and accommodate for others, there is no way to accommodate here. It's unfair to expect Americans to rescind their one and only name just to accommodate for a sensitive ass Latin American who doesn't understand what they mean, and this is coming from a Mexican.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510528327.0" user="Iwantmy3rdpartyapp" delta="False">
    <text>Right? Like, should I call myself Italian-American? I'm really more Irish than I am Italian even though I have an Italian name, and I know people who are way more mixed than I am, so how are we supposed to refer to ourselves?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510686827.0" user="Unyx" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of these people will say "United Statesian" which is just too clunky of a term. In Spanish the term (estadounidense) rolls off the tongue a bit better.

Frank Lloyd used the term "Usonian" back in the day and I do kind of like that one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510909107.0" user="Terpomo11" delta="False">
    <text>Usonano!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510911815.0" user="Double_Abalone_2148" delta="False">
    <text>“United Statesian” an abomination of the English language and shouldn’t be used at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511573874.0" user="Ecurbx" delta="False">
    <text>Just "Statesian" isn't too bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511736023.0" user="IronFFlol" delta="False">
    <text>That’s worse</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511764702.0" user="Moomoomoo1" delta="False">
    <text>maybe "Stater" is less clunky but it's still bad</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511767202.0" user="Masonjaruniversity" delta="False">
    <text>United Statesian has Futurama vibes for sure</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513399040.0" user="paddy_________hitler" delta="False">
    <text>I'll start calling myself United Statesian when they start calling themselves Latinx.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510943244.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>I find "united statesian" to be offensive.  we don't refer to our country as "these united states" anymore.  we haven't for closer to 2 centuries than one.  

the reason it's offensive is that we had a whole-ass civil war, still the bloodiest in our history, with scars that have yet to fully heal, over weather we were a single nation or a group of them.

we became "Americans" when, among other things, we left savery behind in the process of becoming one nation out of many.  that process was a traumatic as any birth; a bunch of Europeans telling us how to refer to ourselves is an amusing example of continuing colonialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510995517.0" user="Unyx" delta="False">
    <text>What's the connection between "United Statesian" to "these United States?" I don't see what one has to do with the other. If I called myself United Statesian I don't see how it implies anything about "the" United States vs "these" United States. The denonym would apply to either.

&gt;a bunch of Europeans telling us how to refer to ourselves

It's usually people in Latin America, I've found.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511159951.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What's the connection between "United Statesian" to "these United States?"

It implies that we are not one people, but a group of aligned nations.  again, we had an entire war about this.  the National Identity that came out of it was not just from one side winning, but from northerners and southerners taking advantage of their new post war social networks and expanded worldview to create one of the largest economic expansions in our history.  The growth of that shared American identity is one of the main reasons reconstruction managed to improve anything; especially after Abraham Lincoln had a bad night at the theater.

&gt;It's usually people in Latin America, I've found.

That removes the component of knee-jerk colonizing, but it doesn't make it any more right.  also, knowing humans, I'd bet that a lot of the same people who insist on calling Americans "united statesians" get offended by the word "Latinx"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511217107.0" user="Unyx" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It implies that we are not one people, but a group of aligned nations.

I really don't see how the term does that. It's literally just United States-ian. Someone from the United States. Just like someone from Canada is Canada-ian. Canadian.

I think it's a bit of a stretch to infer some sort of commentary on the unity of the US as a single polity from that word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511255105.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;United States-ian. Someone from the United States. Just like someone from Canada is Canada-ian. Canadian.

Calling someone from the United States of America "United States-ian"  is not like Calling someone from the Dominion of Canada Canadian.  it's like calling someone from Canada a "Dominionist"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511797760.0" user="Unyx" delta="False">
    <text>I think we'll just need to disagree on this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512009543.0" user="Smokeya" delta="False">
    <text>What the person your disagreeing with is trying to say is that by saying American we are one and by saying United Statsian we are divided into groups or states which isnt what we are or have been for a long time. A large enough of us dont really think that way. Like i may tell people im from my state but i dont consider myself to just be from my state i consider myself a American and i believe most people from here think similarly to that. We think on the larger scale when it comes between state or country level. I dont know of anyone in the US who would claim their state over the country though im sure there are some. We do have some people who like myself think their state has better laws to some extent or does things better than other states but there are states with better laws and enforcement of laws than others such as California often does some things right and various states when it comes to marijuana legalization currently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512042514.0" user="Unyx" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;United Statsian we are divided

But like.... it's the name of the country. And the word "United" is right there. Don't get me wrong I think the term is silly but this particular objection is just nonsensical to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512120588.0" user="Smokeya" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but their argument which i sort of agree with myself is that we fought a war over this very issue as a bunch of states and its better to be a bunch one country (americans) than a bunch of united states. Personally i just think that staties or united statians or anything like that sounds stupid compared to americans and also there are a lot of countries that could just as easily be called the same since there are quite a few out there more who have the words "united states of" or some form of it all over the world while only a handful on this side of the world that have america in it and they all have some other words they can use to call themselves besides america already so it shouldnt even be a issue to begin with. The whole argument is moot in my opinion. Just some people arguing cause they feel like we are getting something over on them they want for some reason while not thinking about how we dont have as many options as they do at the same time. Its silly. Id personally tell someone who said such things to me to f' right off with that shit especially since i personally cant do crap to change it anyways and like how it is as it is already. So to me thems fighting words hah.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512074164.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>That name (DoC) hasn’t been used since the mid 1900s. Everyone everywhere refers to the United Stares of America as the “US” and sometimes as the “USA”. 

Even *Americans* (sic) do so. It seems to be more or less split between “America” and “US” or “USA”.

So I don’t think that analogy holds water.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514176594.0" user="veeyo" delta="False">
    <text>Right, most people call the country the US but Americans, the people, will always either say they are from the US or if using a specific demonym they say American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514878431.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>Hey I learned a new word today, thanks !</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511351625.0" user="ChrysMYO" delta="False">
    <text>Its similar to the debate we have internally when Conservatives argue "You know the the US is a Republic, not a democracy". The embedded implication is that states like Texas, Virginia and Florida are peers arguing amongst themselves and the Federal government is just a body they use for certain functions. 

In reality, we fought a war to clarify that this is a Central Federation. "We're all American" is a linguistic that institutionally applied to emphasize this reality. Emphasis on the *states* can bring up that context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512086777.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>OR … we’re all “United statesians”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514500714.0" user="openup91011" delta="False">
    <text>Of what?  Mexico? Or America?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512087325.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>OR … we’re all “United statesians”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514511901.0" user="hermajestyqoe" delta="False">
    <text>Then people need not stretch American to have some stupid kind of meaning, and we can return to our normal daily routine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511272184.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>United Statesian has the same problem.  Mexico is the United Mexican States.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511448407.0" user="cornstock2112" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah so does the USA have dominion over every country that is a United States of.... By the same logic it's equally unusable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511691776.0" user="Griffin-T" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder if that's because in Spanish the word is "estadounidense" which would literally translate to "united statesian." A lot of words don't translate literally, but native speakers will still understand what you mean. That doesn't make it the "correct" word or one that native speakers would/should use in that situation.

That being said, imo language is just a tool for communication. So if you understand someone well enough to "correct" their grammar/spelling/pronunciation. They communicated well enough that it doesn't need correcting (outside of things like schoolwork/professional writing, obviously).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511731967.0" user="Possibly_Parker" delta="False">
    <text>idk i think most people don't care if you're speaking english and say American, it's just that there's a different word for it in Spanish. It's like if a German said they were Dutch - not offensive, just dumb.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511305597.0" user="ChrysMYO" delta="False">
    <text>Its a linguistic reversal of the term "LatinX". Like no matter the intentions behind it, its completely foreign to the target population speaks. 

Likewise, applying "unitedstatesian" when it linguistically just doesn't apply seems culturally aloof while well intentioned. Just as you point out in one instance. Language is often more embedded in context than given credit for. Someone from the US shouldn't expect latin x to work. And someone from Europe shouldn't expect Unitedstatesian to work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512891223.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Its a linguistic reversal of the term "LatinX". Like no matter the intentions behind it, its completely foreign to the target population speaks. 

These fuckers couldn't even make us adopt the *metric system* and they think we're going to start calling ourselves "unitedstatesian" because they say so?...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513908240.0" user="0theHumanity" delta="False">
    <text>Latinx contra patriarchia....tambien latin@ y latine fueron contemplados, donde estabas en la universided durante esta conversacion juevón? Es pura machismo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517231880.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Latinx contra patriarchia....tambien latin@ y latine fueron contemplados

Contemplado por quien?  ¿Latinoamericanos o gringos?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43543329793.0" user="0theHumanity" delta="False">
    <text>Todo el mundo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511917277.0" user="mpmagi" delta="False">
    <text>"United Statesian" doesn't imply a plural "United States". "United States" the country is considered a singular noun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511977472.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>it puts the emphasis on the states, not our common identity as Americans.  it's not how we think of ourselves, and I can't think of a single country that is referred to that way.

we don't call brazilians "federales", for example.  nor do we call folks from china "people's republicains".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512005943.0" user="mpmagi" delta="False">
    <text>I'm all for the term "Americans", I'm just drawing a line between "these United States", which is as you say: a callback to pre Civil War attitudes, and "United Statesian"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510988681.0" user="bigdon802" delta="False">
    <text>I just say I’m a Vermonter. Way more fun, and specific enough to be useful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511456818.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing against you personally, but when people say this *in certain contexts* I find it quite obnoxious. Like when you're on a tour or something and everyone goes around and says where they're from, and you hear "Guatemala, Germany, Australia" and then when it gets to the American they say their state or sometimes even their city. It's sort of like they're saying that America is so important that everyone else from every other country should know the US's states. Again, nothing against you personally, but just needed a minute on my soapbox.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511623543.0" user="TheNicholasRage" delta="False">
    <text>So what you're saying is its impossible to make everyone happy so it's not worth fretting over?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511717124.0" user="Possibly_Parker" delta="False">
    <text>i mean if someone went "im from new south wales" or "im from monterrey" then i would go yeah cool and if I didn't know where it was (because i feel like that would be the followup) then I would ask and find out. pretty simple</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511919039.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>But they don't. That's the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511950293.0" user="Possibly_Parker" delta="False">
    <text>Elaborate?

By choosing to find that behavior obnoxious, you are planting your feet and saying that even if everyone did announce their state or territory you would find it obnoxious.

Unless your argument is that you find something harmless obnoxious because it's slightly different from an arbitrary custom?

Tell me what your point is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517524154.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that *generally, from my experience*, a person from Monterrey would not say "I'm from Monterrey." They would probably say "I'm from Mexico" (unless they're in Mexico or like very southern US where that information is more descriptive). Because, *generally from my experience*, there is not an assumption that people know the different states of your country.

&gt;By choosing to find that behavior obnoxious, you are planting your feet and saying that even if everyone did announce their state or territory you would find it obnoxious.

I genuinely don't understand how you got this from what I said. But yes, I prefer that people say their country as it provides more information. For example, if someone says "I'm from Lower Silesian," I wouldn't gain new information about where they're from, because I don't know the voivodeships (learned a new thing today) of Poland. Whereas if they say "I'm from Poland," now I know more information that will make it easier for me to approach that person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513444628.0" user="edingerc" delta="False">
    <text>What about when being more specific makes a huge difference?  Like when someone says they're a Texan, instead of an American?  Texan is far more descriptive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517389607.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>Texan might be more descriptive to you, but maybe not to people from other places in the world. For example, I don't know the differences between the Chinese provinces of Guangdong and Hainan. As far as I can tell from Wikipedia they are very different, so a person from China or nearby countries might find that differentiation helpful, but on the other side of the world it's actually less helpful because now you don't know what country they're from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511751901.0" user="local_gaming_lore" delta="False">
    <text>Many of our states are larger and more populous than many nations, many are vastly more influential than many nations. The US is roughly the size of Europe, it isn’t hard to see why a person would want to say their state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512266234.0" user="bigdon802" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, many states are larger an more populous than those countries. And the culture in them isn’t the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512708967.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>China has 15 provinces that are larger than the largest US state. But have you ever heard a person travelling in another country say "I'm from Shandong"? Or do they just say "I'm from China"?

And implying that other countries don't have as much cultural variation in them as the US is kind of wild. India has a population that is 4x that of the US (1.39 billion people) living across 28 states and 8 Union territories. Do you think that their food, culture, dress, festivals, etc. don't vary?

Hell, I live in Canada, which is a 12th of the size of the US population wise (though we could totally kick your butt in a land area competition!!), and there are two provinces directly next to each other that are dramatically different in culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514527487.0" user="hermajestyqoe" delta="False">
    <text>To answer your first paragrapg... yes...? Lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514977244.0" user="bigdon802" delta="False">
    <text>You’re reading an awful lot into what I’m saying. I’m not implying that other countries don’t have cultural variation. I’m also not saying people from other countries don’t or shouldn’t identify themselves by region or smaller political entity before country. I often meet Québécois who identify themselves as such, as well as Nova Scotians(or even as Cape Bretoners.) 

As to your other references: no, China doesn’t have 15 provinces larger than the largest US state. They have 0 provinces larger than the largest US state. They have either 1 or 0 *autonomous regions* larger than the largest US state, depending on how you’re measuring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517307165.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;As to your other references: no, China doesn’t have 15 provinces larger than the largest US state. They have 0 provinces larger than the largest US state.

I'm talking about population in response to your statement "I mean, many states are larger an more populous than those countries."

&gt;And the culture in them isn’t the same.

This is why I said what I said about cultural variation. Because how I'm reading what you're saying is that because Alabama and California are so different, it's valuable to say the state. Maybe I am misreading what you said.

&gt;I often meet Québécois who identify themselves as such, as well as Nova Scotians(or even as Cape Bretoners.)

I'm a bit curious as to where (in terms of geography) you've met these people. This has not personally been my experience, and I think it's reasonable to use state/province when you're close to home. (Also Québécois are a bit different; there are quite a few people from Quebec who don't feel like they are Canadians, so they wouldn't identify themselves as such.)

At the end of the day, this is my opinion based on my experiences from meeting people all around the world. You have your own opinion, as obviously you've had different experiences. We can continue to debate it, but I'm not sure there's much movement here given that our opinions are based on our own experiences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517486293.0" user="bigdon802" delta="False">
    <text>Where do I meet Québécois and Nova Scotians who refer to themselves that way? Vermont, Maine, and Massachusetts mostly. But in general I’d prefer if people were always more specific. If I ask someone from the UK where they’re from I’m hoping they’ll say Wales, Scotland, Cornwall, or wherever else rather than just “the UK.” I’d much rather the Frenchman tell me he’s from Brittany or Languedoc than “France.” But whatever, no worries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517586031.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>Vermont, Maine, and Massachusetts are across the border from Quebec and very close to Nova Scotia. So I would assume that they can introduce themselves by their specific province and that information would mean something to you (and the other way around).

If I met a person from France and they said they were from Languedoc, I wouldn't like that because I've never heard of Languedoc, so I don't actually know where they're from.

Also just to make sure we're envisioning the same scenario, I'm not talking about meeting someone one-on-one and shaking their hands. I'm talking about a tour bus where everyone goes around and says where they're from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512394411.0" user="Icestar1186" delta="False">
    <text>Saying you're from the USA is about as geographically specific as saying you're from Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512591786.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>If we're talking strictly geography, then I am from the second-largest country in the world and I say I'm from Canada. Russia and China are both ahead of the US, and I (anecdotally) have never met anyone from either that doesn't just say their country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514524702.0" user="hermajestyqoe" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, the reality is Americans can't win and everyone will find something to clutch pearls about. In discussions when Americans aren't present, people will pearl clutch about something else. People like clutching their pearls because it validates their own choices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517089263.0" user="thisisnotalice" delta="False">
    <text>You can win. Just say, "I'm from the US, more specifically from Maine."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511046829.0" user="idkwhatuwantfromme69" delta="False">
    <text>But Mexico is Estados Unidos Mexicanos so should we can then estadoudinese</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511448093.0" user="Yellowdog727" delta="False">
    <text>Right.......and everyone refers to them as Mexicans...ignoring the "Estados Unidos" because it's more of a pain to say

So for the United States of America, everyone says "Americans" because it's more of a pain to say "United States of...."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513407473.0" user="paddy_________hitler" delta="False">
    <text>This also extends to China -- nobody calls them "People's Republicans."

I mean, Taiwan also lays claim to the Chinese name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511453285.0" user="4011isbananas" delta="False">
    <text>I vote for Appalachian or Greater Appalachian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511562025.0" user="gugabalog" delta="False">
    <text>What about “Stater” or being a “Unit”(ed)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511616516.0" user="cubelith" delta="False">
    <text>I think "Statian" is pretty decent as well. While there are technically other countries made of states as well, they do have viable names they use normally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512030756.0" user="thoomfish" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it that nobody who gets angry at use of language and demands it be replaced can ever come up with something that isn't 2x more awkward to say?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512103958.0" user="Jamesmateer100" delta="False">
    <text>Usonian

That sounds like a name for a person from a mythical and magical medieval kingdom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510785194.0" user="md24" delta="False">
    <text>Amerix the a is feminine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510806656.0" user="scottishbee" delta="False">
    <text>Fun fact: "Mexicans" actually hail from the "[United Mexican States](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexico#Government_and_politics)".

So I guess the problem isn't that we took "American" from the "United States of America", it's that the country is named after the continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511055480.0" user="idkwhatuwantfromme69" delta="False">
    <text>Or is the continent named after the country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511099372.0" user="SnarkyGamer9" delta="False">
    <text>The country is named after the continent(s).

The country was named in the late 1700s, the continent in 1507.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511582185.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511582278.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Qwert200 – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512429094.0" user="zodiactriller" delta="False">
    <text>Is this a serious question?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511652984.0" user="GhostLemonMusic" delta="False">
    <text>My Mexican friends used to tease me about this very thing. "You say that you're American, well so are we. You call yourself North American, but so are we. You say that you are from the United States, well we are too".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512125081.0" user="RealLeoPat" delta="False">
    <text>When I was living in the USA, I mentioned that I was also American, and this guy threatened to punch me in the face and "call the cops on me to deport my illegal ass". I was on a student visa, not that it matters here.

I think you will just find people willing to get into an argument anywhere in the world, regardless of you being right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514052119.0" user="488566N23522E" delta="False">
    <text>yeah, this happened to me too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514263977.0" user="JustHereForPoE_7356" delta="False">
    <text>I hope OP sees this.

This is the kind of American some people think of when they hear any US citizen proclaim themself an American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514880349.0" user="spacedman_spiff" delta="False">
    <text>We just think of them as assholes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515021953.0" user="bremidon" delta="False">
    <text>Gee, coming from Germany, I hope that this does not make it ok to see all Germans as \*that\* kind of German.

Dumb take.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515265241.0" user="JustHereForPoE_7356" delta="False">
    <text>Of course it doesn't, and I didn't mean to say that it is ok to view everyone who calls themselves an American as a xenophobe.

What I was getting at in my (too) brief comment was that although it may not be wrong to call yourself an American, it may still be unwise to do so. Especially if you do it militantly and unapologetically. A sizable number of non-US-citizens might take offense. Know you audience, read the room.

Just like it is unwise for a German to perform suspicious gestures with their right hand held out in the air, lest they want to be seen as \*that\* kind of German.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515302307.0" user="MrPlaysWithSquirrels" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that’s kind of dumb, since Americans don’t have another term to call themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515330922.0" user="JustHereForPoE_7356" delta="False">
    <text>One could use simple workarounds for the situations this comes up in:

"I am Mexican."

"Nice to meet you, I'm from the USA."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515339121.0" user="MrPlaysWithSquirrels" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but it’s a needless workaround when the judgment is unwarranted in the first place. I can’t change the country I’m from and don’t need to be apologetic about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515491959.0" user="JustHereForPoE_7356" delta="False">
    <text>As I wrote in another comment, I don't think it's wrong to call yourself an American. I'd just advise to know your audience and read the room. Sometimes it will be unwise although not wrong.

Sure, using a workaround is "needless" in the strictest sense - as are all courtesies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515729841.0" user="MrPlaysWithSquirrels" delta="False">
    <text>I hear what you’re saying—truly—I just feel that in this case, it’s on the party offended more than the offending party. If someone is offended by me calling myself an American, a wholly true and unoffending statement, then they’re just applying opinions to me that I can’t control. It’s like me saying I’m gay, and a homophobe telling me to know my audience and watch how I phrase myself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516040116.0" user="JustHereForPoE_7356" delta="False">
    <text>I think we're on the same page here. It may well be more on the offended party.

I'm not sure it's best to think about this in terms of who is to blame, though. Doing so will help you to feel justified and to stand your ground. And if that is what you need to do, this is the way to go. It often is.

If you are looking for the best outcomes for yourself in a social sitiuation though, going along with the sensitivities of others (be they justified or not) may be the way to go. If you can stomach the cost, that is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516126628.0" user="MrPlaysWithSquirrels" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah; we are on the same page.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511702684.0" user="fdar" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; it's that the country is named after the continent

They have the same name, but so what? Washington is both a state and a city, so is Victoria (in different countries) and there's countless names of cities that are reused all over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513323639.0" user="scottishbee" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, poor word choice.  I don't see it as a "problem", more like the *confusion* stems from the country name itself. 

But like you said, hardly the only place like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516506383.0" user="carissadraws" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah like do we think that people from the state of Georgia get mad at people from the country of Georgia calling themselves Georgians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513147090.0" user="yogert909" delta="False">
    <text>Yea I was trying to think of another word to use and the only thing I came up with is “United“.

Most people take the name of their country as how the describe themselves.  Canadians, Mexicans, Guatemalans, Russians, Ukrainians, French…the list is long.  The only people I can think of who are not named after their country are Dutch.  Maybe certain ethnicities, but then they still usually qualify it with the country they are from e.g. Russian Jew or Crimean Tatar.

I think your classmates were trying to be edgy college students and find every reason to find fault, especially since you’re an easy target because you’re American.

Personally I’ve started saying I’m “from the states” because I don’t like nationalism at all and I don’t like to be defined by the country I grew up in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513368591.0" user="scottishbee" delta="False">
    <text>The pedantic could still say "but wHicH STatEs?", see: United Mexican States.

Also, aside from the Dutch (TIL: named after the language!), the only other ones I could think of were the Soviets. "Soviet" being a political term, and adopted (to lesser degrees) outside the USSR.

I actually like saying "American", mainly because for most other countries the nationality is tightly tied to the ethnicity.  Even multi-ethnic countries, the nationality can be a sticking spot (see: Chinese).  "American", like "Soviet" I suppose, is rare in that it can be applied to any who adopt it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514473203.0" user="MolochDe" delta="False">
    <text>Is US-American really that uncommon? It's short, easy to say and starts of with USA which is something people love to chant anyway</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514825432.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>No, and it sounds hella weird. It’s just American</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514862615.0" user="MolochDe" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I'm guilty for slipping back to American often enough but whenever I'm with an international crowd (e.g. any doctorate program) it seems appropriate to be specific. In German the wording "Us-Amerikaner" is pretty common and doesn't come of weird. Just immagine how dumb it would be if there was a nation called Europe in Europe.  
Sure currently people tend to understand American as Us-citicen but that is because of historical reasons and language changes with the change starts slowly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514967958.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>It’s less about distinguishing the continent and the people, which should be easy to do and is just some butt-hurt Latin Americans. It wouldn't be dumb, just different. The point is that we use “American” to accommodate them because that’s what they call themselves. How offensive would it be if I called you alemão? What if I went to Germany and called everyone there “Alamanne”? Would you like that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516152581.0" user="MolochDe" delta="False">
    <text>You got that wrong, if I come visit you and you tell your peers "He's alemão" then I'd be fine with it. If you tell them "He's German" i'm fine with that too, even though I'm clearly Deutsch xD  
Hypothetically if the world famous city New York was called "America" and everyone would instantly assume you are from that particular City if you say your American that wouldn't be great right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516332643.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>Say I’m in Germany, speaking German, would you be ok if I addressed you as this https://de.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alamannen, since that’s the equivalent of how we refer to German people in my language? What if I called you German instead of “Deutsche” in German? And even if you’re ok with that, are you sure that other people would be ok with that? Americans just want to be called what they’re used to and how they identify themselves as. 
And yes, in that scenery that you described, it would be a bit confusing but that could be easily solved. I’m from Brazil, and we have two cases similar to that example. We’ve got São Paulo (state) and its capital São Paulo (city), and Rio de Janeiro (state) and its capital (city). Granted, they have different demonyms, but people will usually say “I’m from Rio” or “I’m from São Paulo”, and then specify where exactly they’re from. It works, and you respect their decision of calling themselves and their state/city whatever they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517902537.0" user="MolochDe" delta="False">
    <text>But I'm a European and you are American but in my case no one would be surprised I'm from Germany.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518108039.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>Fair. But go with South American then</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515031786.0" user="bremidon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;In German the wording "Us-Amerikaner" is pretty common and doesn't come of weird.

Don't fib.  It's very weird.  You will hear it, but it's not common at all.  If someone says they are "Amerikaner", everyone knows what is meant unless they are terminally pedantic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516076319.0" user="MolochDe" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but in the future that might change. Sure Latin America weren't such large global players (for sinister reasons) but they become more relevant while the US declines slowly in a way that an American identity can form that isn't just the USA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516045657.0" user="yogert909" delta="False">
    <text>It’s uncommon enough that I’ve never heard it once in my life.

Regarding USA and the chanting, that’s a strong mark against it because I hate that nationalist shit with a passion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516493082.0" user="carissadraws" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; it’s that the country is named after the continent 

Okay but I don’t think you’ll see a group of people as angry about New Zealanders calling themselves New Zealanders despite living on the continent of Australia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511017501.0" user="WizeAdz" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's unfair to expect Americans to rescind their one and only name just to accommodate for a sensitive ass Latin American who doesn't understand what they mean, and this is coming from a Mexican.

Depends on the context, and which language we are speaking at the moment.

If I'm speaking Spanish, I'll be polite in Spanish.  Since my Spanish is pretty rudimentary, I'd probably try for a formal/polite tone and claim to be un ciudadano de los estados unidos.

In English, though, I'm an American because that's how we say it in English.

If I'm speaking in German (I'm not proficient), I'll say it however the Germans say it - and as politely as possible.

The point of language is to communicate and be understood.  I'll adapt my language however I have to make the points I need to make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511396475.0" user="lexx1414" delta="False">
    <text>In Spanish you would say “Soy un estadounidense.” It means the same thing :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511033444.0" user="Alexandur" delta="False">
    <text>I think the most elegant alternative would be US American, although that still doesn't exactly roll off the tongue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511035901.0" user="jasondbg" delta="False">
    <text>I vote to start calling them Staties (state - ees)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511494520.0" user="Yellowdog727" delta="False">
    <text>Which is even more stupid and vague (and also a butchery of the English language)

There's numerous other countries that are officially called something with "states", for example, Mexico.

It would be stupid to call people from the UK "Kingies"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511598958.0" user="jasondbg" delta="False">
    <text>United can be used since that’s in United Kingdom as well. Can we use “of”? Ofers or ofs?

Or how about get that creativity cap on and make up a whole new name. Gunland or something?  Maybe go outside the box and name it like the cat from Dr McNinja and be the country “ice cream cake” or the country Darren. Just a random first name. 

Oh make it a lottery!  Everyone can buy a ticket for a dollar. As many as you like, all the money can go to finally funding universal healthcare and the country is just named after you. Imagine for just a dollar you could have people saluting the flag of Yellowdog727.  

Bring some damn whimsy back to the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511810467.0" user="CheapManualLabor" delta="False">
    <text>I vote we change it to Country McCountface</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511814690.0" user="jasondbg" delta="False">
    <text>This is the bold vision that the country needs!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511545266.0" user="Chuchulainn96" delta="False">
    <text>Only if we also change the standard greeting to ahoy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511702361.0" user="OtherThumbs" delta="False">
    <text>In Massachusetts,that's what State Troopers are called.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511727742.0" user="cumming2kristenbell" delta="False">
    <text>It’s always so weird when people want to change things that don’t need to be change.

Americans is fine.

South Americans don’t need it because they all live in countries that have specific names (unlike the United States of America which is basically a country called America within the continent of America)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511746592.0" user="jasondbg" delta="False">
    <text>And I am Canadian which is also in North America.   Also it’s kind of embarrassing y’all couldn’t come up with someone original. 

Hey if that is alright with you that’s cool. The name has been pretty tainted already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511824594.0" user="cumming2kristenbell" delta="False">
    <text>You said it yourself. Canada has a name: Canada.

America is the only country with America in the name. That’s why we call ourselves Americans.

No one alive came up with the name. It happened because originally each state was like a small country unto itself (people forget places like Italy are both countries and states. So “the United States of America” is about the same as “the European Union”)

It’s only a dumb name if you ignore all the history around it and the fact it was meant to represent that this was a bunch of smaller countries coming together.

The same with the United States (which has also been referred to as the The Union of states during the civil war)

In another timeline states like Texas and California could just as easily be countries called Texas and California. They are even literally bigger both in land mass and population than many countries in the world.

Like I said state/country are almost interchangeable. So United (Countries) of America isn’t embarrassing at all.

Just like United States of Mexico isn’t embarrassing.

“We” (they) had no way to know at the time that those smaller countries would ever truly be one when they were always more of a confederacy.

And it’s probably weird for them to want a brand new name post civil war just to avoid stuff like this a century and a half later</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512958036.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>There weren't any other countries in the Americas at the time...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513123272.0" user="fauxpolitik" delta="False">
    <text>You are only Canadian because your “Upper Canada” and “Lower Canada” united and had a common name to coalesce around. The history of the US is a union of states which basically acted as independent colonies prior to independence, indeed there was nothing really differentiating a colony like Quebec from a colony like New Jersey despite only a select number of colonies joining in rebellion against the crown. This is why there is not a unique name, people identified with their colony (and later state) and this concept of an American identity was similar to the concept of a European identity today. The early version of the US government was essentially a confederation just like the EU, so it’s natural that a more cohesive and unique denonym never came about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511117571.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>The term is United Statesian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513171419.0" user="TSN09" delta="False">
    <text>Nah.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515299551.0" user="milkhotelbitches" delta="False">
    <text>Hate it if you want but it does exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517439481.0" user="TSN09" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, don't care.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515123505.0" user="BananiaIdiotalandia" delta="False">
    <text>no, this is used only by leftlists trying to denigrate the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511255116.0" user="Slushcube76" delta="False">
    <text>Lets just change our name to something cooler tbh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511421872.0" user="Yellowdog727" delta="False">
    <text>"You can't call yourself British. It's culturally insensitive to Irish people because they live in the British Isles too, especially given the history of brutal colonialism in the empire. From now on, you have to call yourself United Kingdomian"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511594571.0" user="tescovaluechicken" delta="False">
    <text>Irish people consider the term "British Isles" as a Colonial term, created by the British to indicate ownership over Ireland, so that example doesn't make sense. An Irish person will never use the term British Isles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511711219.0" user="Galladaddy" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that would be sacrilegious to do that. Might as well go back to using the fecking pound sterling at that point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514819672.0" user="paulbrock2" delta="False">
    <text>Is there an Irish term to describe the islands or is lumping them together at all frowned upon?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511729808.0" user="Yellowdog727" delta="False">
    <text>"America" is also a colonial term which evolved shortly after Columbus's first expedition. It's not a native word</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512116478.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but you’re not using it to describe the territory of somebody else that you have (tried to) ruled.

It’d be like if the US called Japan “the US Islands of the Pacific” and got upset that the people there, offended by the term, continued to called themselves Japanese.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514199398.0" user="crater_jake" delta="False">
    <text>Right… Lets just rename every place on Earth after whoever got there first</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514322316.0" user="DivideEtImpala" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;An Irish person will never use the term British Isles.

What if they're from Northern Ireland? Would they still never use the term, or are they not Irish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515045967.0" user="clairebones" delta="False">
    <text>Slightly complicated question lol - the people in NI who identify as British/UK citizens often do call it the British Isles, the people who identify as Irish generally don't, the people who don't have a strong identity in either direction might or might not use it depending on context. I mean we have a literal city that people will give different names to based on their personal cultural identity (Derry/Londonderry), you get used to being able to use it as a bit of a hint of someone's politics/culture/background if it comes up. (source: am Northern Irish)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514489909.0" user="hermajestyqoe" delta="False">
    <text>The point is anyone can say anything. It's a word, get over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513364991.0" user="Greg_the_wooden_Leg" delta="False">
    <text>This is such a good comparison, thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513553250.0" user="runtheroad" delta="False">
    <text>People from Ireland shouldn't be able to call themselves Irish because people from Northern Ireland are Irish too and it's arrogant to assume all Irish people live in Ireland.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516550402.0" user="carissadraws" delta="False">
    <text>One could make a similar argument about New Zealand and Australia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511501936.0" user="solid_b_average" delta="False">
    <text>I was thinking this same thing. OP should have asked this German what they think folks from the USA should be called. I’d be willing to bet they would not have had an answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511512052.0" user="Kan169" delta="False">
    <text>I use Stater. It feels less entitled.  We could just be 'us'. That would cause confusion at all. /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511512864.0" user="Kan169" delta="False">
    <text>I use Stater. It feels less entitled.  We could just be 'us'. That would cause confusion at all. /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511528162.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I mean you can just say "I'm from the US."

Also, I can't speak for any given person, but I strongly suspect the majority of people upset about this "people from the US shouldn't call themselves American" thing would also resist the development of an alternative term specifically referring to people from the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512014217.0" user="SagewithBlueEyes" delta="False">
    <text>Because it nonsense. Why should Americans have to change what they are called, which is well known around the world btw, because some Argentinian is mad because they are also American but in a different sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513877127.0" user="debladblazer" delta="False">
    <text>Because it can be confusing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513957898.0" user="SagewithBlueEyes" delta="False">
    <text>No, it isn't. Literally everyone knows exactly what you mean when you say "I'm American." You are just trying to be offended over nothing. This is a non-issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514110531.0" user="debladblazer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not offended, I'm sorry if it came over that way. I'm just saying it can be confusing as American is both used for the continent and the country. 

If I told you I had five American friends, it's unclear what I'm talking about. So I have to specify, I have 1 friend from the US, two from Ecuador, one from Canada and one from Haiti.

Sometimes you don't want to or can't specify so therefore it would be useful to have a specific term from people from the US.

Especially when talking about customs from America (continent) it is difficult as it often spans multiple countries. For example; "corn is a staple of American diets". In this sentence, how would I know if I'm talking about the continent or the country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514143532.0" user="SagewithBlueEyes" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't unclear though. To the entire world excluding pompous South Americans, American means someone from the US. I am a German-American and have never once across Europe or ME had an individual not understand when I said my father was an American. 

Beyond that, there isn't a continent called America. There is South America and North America. Central America is a geographic region within North America. When speaking about both, you use The Americas. Of you say America outside of The Americas, people think the US. This is just a ridiculous idea that people get confused. They don't and that fact is only being denied because it doesn't fit a narrative. To actually suggest Americans should call themselves something different is absurd. 

Also, offended probably wasn't the correct word but I couldn't pinpoint the exact word I was looking for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514194771.0" user="debladblazer" delta="False">
    <text>There is not an established definition of what constitutes a continent. There are many ways of categorising them and most categorize America as one continent (think, for example, of the Olympic rings). There is no one right way to categorize them.

I am not aware of any narrative you're talking about, I never mentioned it. I don't know any South Americans so if you think I'm part of some group or whatever, I'm not. It seems like you're just arguing with ghosts that are not here.

I agree with you that people from the US can call themselves American. I'm just saying it might be confusing in some circumstances like the ones I stated before. It may not be confusing to you, as you never think of a country except your own anyway, but to some others it is.

Please consider the sentence "corn is a staple of the American diet". To someone that doesn't know anything about America (country or continent), how could they know that I'm talking about the whole continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514228294.0" user="SagewithBlueEyes" delta="False">
    <text>That is the equivalent of saying "fish is a staple of the Asian diet." What Asian? Kazakhstan? Mongolia? Egypt? Sri Lanka? Israel? You can make any vague and ambiguous statement and try pawning it off as an example. The fact is, people understand American as from the US. To suggest otherwise is just dishonest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514244703.0" user="debladblazer" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not equivalent. Fish is not a staple of the Asian diet, it is only a staple in some Asian countries and not others. 

Equivalent would be to say "rice is a staple of the Asian diet" which is very clear and anyone would understand. No one would by mistake think that I meant that it is only a staple in India.

The sentence "corn is a staple of the American diet", however, is unclear. It could refer to the continent or the country. Some people may, by mistake think that I meant it is only a staple in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514836835.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Because it is nonsense. Why should Americans have to change what they are called, which is well known around the world btw, because some Argentinian is mad because they are also American but in a different sense.

Look, the issue here is very clearly that some people from the US (I suspect you're among them, based on your response here) are defensive about the perception that people think they're morally bad for calling themselves "American." 

This is why people are talking in circles. Because one person will be like "but the term is ambiguous" and the other person will be like "But I'm not a bad person!" and that's not going to be useful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513180549.0" user="TSN09" delta="False">
    <text>It still isn't fair.

Having to give up your national "identifier" because it clashes with someone's continental "identifier"? Country comes before Continent, they can seethe all they want, it literally doesn't matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514765788.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>But this is an entirely different point.  If the issue is fairness, you shouldn't act like the issue is simply that there isn't another word for people from the US.

Your original comment, the one I replied to, sounds eminently reasonable, but clearly it's not the real issue. Because if it was, you'd be perfectly okay with using some new term if one became commonplace.

And this should make you pause and raise an eyebrow, right? It's noteworthy when there's an impulse to avoid the central issue and instead give a reasonable-sounding but irrelevant argument instead. Why do this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517433619.0" user="TSN09" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment comes across really exhausting, I don't want to speak to you anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523237139.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>It's fairly exhausting for you to give an argument ("There's no convenient other terms!") and then immediately reveal it doesn't actually matter to you ("...But I wouldn't use one if there were!")  So I guess we're just a couple of tired buddies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511659152.0" user="Antisocialite99" delta="False">
    <text>I'm United Statesian! 

It just roools of the tounge doesnt it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512125300.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>It would if that’s what you wouldn’t have known your whole life</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512508872.0" user="Antisocialite99" delta="False">
    <text>Its ironic that your post is one of the most clumsily worded things I've ever read and most surely does not just roll off the tongue. 

It would if thats what you wouldn't have known your whole life. Jesus, Tell me english isn't your first language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512549272.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>It’s just quick typing and auto-correct gone wrong man, take a deep breath and consider toning down the histrionics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512562942.0" user="Antisocialite99" delta="False">
    <text>Huh autocorrect makes me use wrong words, and typos make me misspell them, neither explain putting together the clumsiest sentence I've ever heard, which is undeniably pretty ironic considering the topic and the point you were trying to make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512662971.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>Antisocial indeed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512722365.0" user="Antisocialite99" delta="False">
    <text>No it's anti socialite. 

Lighten up Francis. You gotta admit that sentence was a nightmare and it's kind of funny.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511987427.0" user="BreathingHydra" delta="False">
    <text>It's funny seeing the alternative names people come up with for Americans though lol. I don't think I've ever actually seen a good one, they're all either really stupid sounding like Statsians, or a complete mouthful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515127323.0" user="BananiaIdiotalandia" delta="False">
    <text>this is used only by leftlists around the world trying to denigrate the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512176792.0" user="PhysicsCentrism" delta="False">
    <text>In English sure. In castellano estadounidense is a very widely used and accepted word. Other alternatives would be gringo or yanqui although those can be viewed as slurs. Don’t use americano to call yourself a US citizen when estadounidense exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513006189.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>Typical imperialist USA mindset, trying to claim "estatounidense" as if the Estados Unidos Mexicanos didn't exist.  /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515130986.0" user="BananiaIdiotalandia" delta="False">
    <text>this horrible world "estadunidense" is used only by leftlists trying to denigrate the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514163194.0" user="The_Quibbler" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I can't believe this dumb argument still exists. Of course there is North and South America. Those are *continents*. When we talk about where we're from, we use our *nationality*. Brazilians and Canadians would never refer to their continent in this context. With the USA, "America" is right there in the goddamned name. Of the *nation*.

*Maybe* you could argue about Central America, but again, the region consists of different nations, that while somewhat unified, are independent of each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517318287.0" user="DanFlashesSales" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;This glosses over the fact that Americans don't have another term for themselves. They are the United States of America. If you ask them not to be American, it's quite literally asking a Mexican not to call themselves Mexican. There is no alternative.

It also glosses over the fact that the name "American" was used for us long before the USA existed.  If you look at historical documents from before the revolution they still call us Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510483689.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I refer to North AND South Americans as "Americans".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512169152.0" user="jceez" delta="False">
    <text>I refer to people from North America as North Americans and people from South America  as South Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513685771.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I do that too sometimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511011255.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;some do take some offense to the idea that those of us from the US refer to ourselves as "Americans"

What do they call people from the US?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511086865.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>In Spanish the term is 'estadounidense', which would loosely translate to 'United Stateser', but there is no truly equivalent term in English.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511208836.0" user="Writing_is_Bleeding" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;estadounidense

It's 6-7 syllables, so it's a little cumbersome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511345796.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>Estadounidense flows pretty well in Spanish.

-ense is a suffix that indicates "from xyz place" e.g. canadiense = Canadian, costarricense = Costa Rican so it is a normal word in Spanish, but again there is no equivalent word in English</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511708467.0" user="Major_Pressure3176" delta="False">
    <text>But the average word has more syllables in Spanish, so it is not as big of a difference. "Americano/a" has 5, just one less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511962785.0" user="Writing_is_Bleeding" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so it's easier for a Spanish-speaker. I'll have to work on it, especially if I travel to a Spanish-speaking country. Damn! I really wish us estadounidense had been required to learn multiple languages in grade school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513290230.0" user="gon_ofit" delta="False">
    <text>Fine, gringo then</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516464074.0" user="Writing_is_Bleeding" delta="False">
    <text>That's better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511404991.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Which makes no sense since they’re also United statesers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511512961.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>Afaik the only nations in the Americas that have "united states" in the title are the US and Mexico (United Mexican States), pretty much all the others are Republic of XYZ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511518425.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Right and all of them go by the name at the end and not republic of or United States of, so by their own logic so should we, no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511571614.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>Sadly logic and language don't always go hand in hand. If there was a Republic of America they'd likely be having a similar linguistic issue, especially if it was culturally distinct and had imperialist tendencies like the US.

Either way, the proper term for someone from the US in English is 'American' and in Spanish is 'Estadounidense.'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511592926.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but logically speaking that would also refer to Mexicans</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511747796.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you're saying, but I wouldn't call it logical because then two countries would share a demonym.

Consider also that languages do not follow logical patterns in word formation. Here are some examples from English: people from Germany are German (drop the trailing vowel), from Guatemala are Guatemalan (add an 'n'), from France are French (change 'a' to 'e' and second 'e' to 'h'), from Portugal are Portuguese (replace 'al' with 'uese'), and from the Netherlands are Dutch (literally the only letters in both are 't' and 'h').</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511799995.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>It’s logical because they share a demonym and hence would lead to confusion. Boy do I love linguistics though and you’re right they don’t follow a logical pattern, at least to me as someone who isn’t studied in linguistics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511869579.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>I desperately wish languages followed consistent logical patterns! It'd make them much easier to learn. Irregular verbs make conjugating a nightmare, and for some reason some of the most common words end up being irregular!

(I'm looking at you 'ir' ["to go" in Spanish] which in the first person can conjugate to 'voy', 'fui', 'iré', 'iba', 'vaya', or 'fuera' depending on case [present, past, future, etc])</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512123518.0" user="skahunter831" delta="False">
    <text>Is that "the" term, or is it just "a" term? Like, who actually uses that phrase?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512747281.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>As far as I am aware 'estadounidense' is the preferred term in Central and South America. I don't think it is common in the US, and it might be uncommon in northern Mexico. I have no clue about Spain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512782951.0" user="skahunter831" delta="False">
    <text>Just curious, what's informs your awareness?  Are you from or have you spent time in those areas?  Personal experience?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513228108.0" user="WhoopingWillow" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you!

I had to learn Spanish for a job in the military. The school they send you to is run by native speakers from many different countries. They teach you the major language and cultures of your target region.

All of my teachers were adamant that you use 'estadounidense' to avoid awkwardness. Almost anyone would understand what you mean if you called yourself americano/a but it is poor form and could deeply offend some people.

As another example, here is the Spanish version of [usa.gov](https://usa.gov) which uses the word. (Ctrl+F 'estadounidense')</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512145254.0" user="Puzzleheaded_Fold466" delta="False">
    <text>It also works well in French. États-Uniens. It’s 4 syllables like American, and it rolls off the tongue quite naturally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511710869.0" user="OtherThumbs" delta="False">
    <text>The French call us les Americains (Americans).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511147487.0" user="secderpsi" delta="False">
    <text>This was what I wanted to write. Thank you. My experience is from traveling in Latin America and regardless of what anyone thinks, it bothers them. I like to be respectful and it's easy to just say I'm a U.S. citizen or I'm from the U.S.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511314294.0" user="LettuceUpstairs7614" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Studied in Chile and it *absolutely* bothered people if you referred to yourself as American. Actually, the first time I heard this complaint from a Chilean, I hadn't even said "soy americana", I said "soy estadounidense" but they still popped off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511494389.0" user="SpiceEarl" delta="False">
    <text>Unpopular opinion in Chile, but they're being a bunch of little bitches who need to get over themselves. Why? Because The United States of America is the only country with America in the name. It just happens to be the name given to the continents as well. Unless they want to refer to themselves as South American, rather than Chilean, they can pound sand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511749445.0" user="cumming2kristenbell" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly

It’s not a matter of thinking we own all of the American continents.

It’s the fact that we’re the only country with America in the name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512136292.0" user="skahunter831" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I said "soy estadounidense" but they still popped off. 

That makes no fucking sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512332459.0" user="KatieCashew" delta="False">
    <text>Right? Why bother trying to please someone who is determined to be offended?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512335048.0" user="KatieCashew" delta="False">
    <text>Right? Why bother trying to please someone who is determined to be offended?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515002348.0" user="Acrobatic_Bother4144" delta="False">
    <text>By United States you’re referring to the United States of Mexico right?

Using “US” or “United States” instead of “American” is the dumbest thing I’ve ever heard. We’re not even the only United States in North America. The truth is that there is no alternative to American which is somehow “more technically correct” and still makes sense to anyone at all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511453175.0" user="NoRepresentative3533" delta="False">
    <text>I'll generally accommodate people but there is exactly one term for people from my country and you're asking me not to use it because it's also claimed by another group.

If we look at history, people have been using "American" to refer to people from the USA since the time of the American Revolutionary War. If people want to use another term in their language, they're free to, but you can't accuse me of colonialism while also demanding I change how my native language works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513872363.0" user="Moist_Network_8222" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If we look at history, people have been using "American" to refer to people from the USA since the time of the American Revolutionary War. If people want to use another term in their language, they're free to, but you can't accuse me of colonialism while also demanding I change how my native language works.

Yeah, "American" was used to refer to US citizens before any other country in the New World declared independence. It's very much how the English language works at this point.

In my (very bad) Spanish I use "estadounidense," because Spanish is a different language with a different understanding of region names.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511453337.0" user="Deto" delta="False">
    <text>I'm curious - do the people of Latin America refer to themselves as "Americans" conversationally?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511467059.0" user="Fantastic-Cable-3320" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I think it's just a cultural difference, especially to Latin Americans.

Yes, and in South America, people from the USA are commonly referred to as "norteamericanos" (North Americans) without regard to Canada or Mexico. If you're from Canada, you're Canadian, if you're from Mexico, you're Mexican, if you're from the USA, you're "norteamericano." Go figure.  

The more official term is "estadounidense" (united statesian), which is also technically inaccurate, because there exists the United States of Mexico too. 

So yeah, it's all cultural.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515137810.0" user="BananiaIdiotalandia" delta="False">
    <text>this ridiculous word "estadunidense" is used only by leftlists trying to denigrate the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516322790.0" user="Fantastic-Cable-3320" delta="False">
    <text>username checks out</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517109868.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511746566.0" user="Altruistic-Custard59" delta="False">
    <text>A German with a stick up their ass? Never</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511991258.0" user="SagewithBlueEyes" delta="False">
    <text>Mate, what tf are we supposed to call ourselves? United Statesians? Our country is literally The United States of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515145750.0" user="BananiaIdiotalandia" delta="False">
    <text>leftlists use this word, "estadunidense" (United Statesians), at all Latin American Countries, Portugal and Spain to denigrate the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512360256.0" user="amortized-poultry" delta="False">
    <text>Also Latin Americans do not recognize a difference between the North American and South American continents. So to them, the continent is "America". I feel like it's tectonically inaccurate, but that's probably the bigger reason why they have a problem with Americans calling ourselves "Americans".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513028788.0" user="girumaoak" delta="False">
    <text>We mostly think there is only 1 continent (America) and it's divided in 3 sections: North, Central and South America</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514876972.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>“We mostly think” who? In Brazil, we’re taught that there are two tectonic plates. Say “the Hispanics” or whatever</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517711744.0" user="girumaoak" delta="False">
    <text>where are you from specifically?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514380878.0" user="AdrianWIFI" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's entirely accurate. The continent is America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514750003.0" user="usercybercode" delta="False">
    <text>We’re 2 different continents, with our own tectonic plate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514868397.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>Brazilians actually do, and it varies in Brazil. It might be the same in other countries. Stop generalizing, latchino</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513165074.0" user="spong3" delta="False">
    <text>In Spanish you would refer to someone from the US as estadounidense. In English ??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513991414.0" user="Hollocene13" delta="False">
    <text>Agree. I’ve traveled on most continents, and I’ve never had anyone argue with this that wasn’t Latin American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514979168.0" user="1Commentator" delta="False">
    <text>Agree that the euros have no right to comment here.

Regarding Latin America, I tested this out and started introducing my Mexican friends as American. Turns out they don’t like it because they know the connotation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
