<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510746243.0" user="TechnicalAnimator874" delta="False">
    <text>Look mate, I’m canadian, and it doesnt hurt me. Calling dibs on the whole continent’s name for your nationaly just makes you all sound douchy. Which kinda fits the image y’all are getting of being egotistical.

I guess what I’m trying to say is that as far as your fellow northern neighbor is concerned, hurts your image more than it hurts my feelings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511165007.0" user="ogjaspertheghost" delta="False">
    <text>Why did you refer to yourself as Canadian and not as an American from Canada?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511481208.0" user="Disdain690" delta="False">
    <text>This comment makes you sound douchy. Way more than anyone referring to themselves as American. Only a dumb person would think we're claiming the entire continent, especially when the name of the continent is in the name of the country. It's not that serious dude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511603295.0" user="TechnicalAnimator874" delta="False">
    <text>Wait maybe that sounded harsher than I meant. Like it’s not that big a deal at all. But I mean he asked, and I feel like that may be why it’s « controversial ». The US appears to the rest of the world as a country that boasts a lot IMO. And that kinda gives the same image. Didnt think I’d be taken as mad about this or anything sorry y’all if that came out wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511831870.0" user="Secure-Recording4255" delta="False">
    <text>Personally I think it comes across as more egotistical to say that a country needs to change its name for its citizens because it doesn’t fit other countries languages.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
