<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="196" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512367049.0" user="somandfeelies" delta="False">
    <text>Did you nod, tell him that you're Estados Unidon like he said and continue on with a conversation that actually mattered?

If they feel that attached to their colonial heritage, they're welcome to call themselves whatever they want. I personally feel fairly attached to ours. 

The very term America is spectacularly imperial in heritage and that has incredibly little to do with what the colonies became or our eventual interventions in South America for bananas, canals and political capital. 

I don't know what they want us to call ourselves, but if they don't mind the confusion, they're more than welcome to form a socio-political trading bloc and call it the Southern United States to be spectacularly obstinate. The other countries of the world might question the legitimacy of such a named political entity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
