<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511007031.0" user="Gaoji-jiugui888" delta="False">
    <text>Europeans love whinging because America took the top spot in the world off them. I don’t care, as an Australian. That’s the common way to say it in English. What do they think you should call yourself? United States of American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512064696.0" user="boats_of_canals" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno man, united statesian has a nice ring to it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512860308.0" user="ophmaster_reed" delta="False">
    <text>No it does not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513005642.0" user="OscarGrey" delta="False">
    <text>It's Latin Americans complaining about this 99% of the the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513204947.0" user="EagleSzz" delta="False">
    <text>almost every European country call people from the US 'americans' , or some local version of that. This is just a shit post. There is no need to bash the europeans for a made up claim by OP</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514516065.0" user="concretecannonball" delta="False">
    <text>Easiest way to spot an American is when they start spouting weird world domination propaganda lol why’re you guys so obsessed with the “top spot”? Top in what exactly? Military spending? Imprisonment of your own people? Medical debt?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514519720.0" user="Gaoji-jiugui888" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not American</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552989199.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
