<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="291" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513452974.0" user="Fathoms_Deep_1" delta="False">
    <text>Czech Republic: not called ‘Republicans’- Called Czechs

State of Israel: not called ‘Staters’- Called Israeli

Kingdom of Belgium: not called ‘Kingdomers’- Called Belgian

Commonwealth of Australia: not called ‘Commonwealthians’- Called Australians

We’re called Americans since we were really the first Independent, non-native Nation in the Americas, so we named ourselves the United States of America. There’s not much else we can really call ourselves, it’s always been ‘American’ ever since we got our independence

I’m proud to call myself an American, and I would probably ask the teacher “there’s a good chance if you’re from SA, you consider yourself ‘Latino’ or ‘Hispanic’- which both come from the relationship those national had from Spain, but you shouldn’t call yourselves that due to colonialism/imperialism and disrespecting the native people the Spanish slaughtered to put you where you are today”

Sorry, sometimes as a history major weird debates like this one get me riled up. I think your teacher is objectively wrong, mainly because it’s our actual country name and there is no other name (besides the states) for our land area</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
