<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="84" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511488045.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>FYI - there’s no continent called “America”. We have North America and South America. Going by the logic of many commenters here, the term American would refer to literally half of the world and not even a particular continent. Also quite funny using Mexico as an example calling Americans United staters in Spanish when they’re also from United States yet call themselves mexican.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512670491.0" user="blurplesnow" delta="False">
    <text>Mexico isn't a continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512673385.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Neither is America 🤷🏻‍♂️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512736923.0" user="SirErickTheGreat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; FYI - there’s no continent called “America”.

Correction, there’s no continent called “America”…*in the English-speaking world*. There’s no universal definition for what comprises a continent so countries largely adopt arbitrary models to their liking. I agree that Latin Americans and others around the world shouldn’t be holding others to their arbitrary standards but thought I should make that clarification.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512738031.0" user="nevesnow" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is, in Latin American countries, we are taught our whole lives that there is one continent: America. North and South America are subdivisions of the continent. 
I was very surprised when I came to the US and learned that here it is taught different. 
I believe much of the confusion comes from that, different education. Neither are necessarily right or wrong, they are just different viewpoints. 

Continents as per Latin Americans: África, Antártida, América, Ásia, Europa e Oceania.

Continents as per US: Asia, Africa, North America, South America, Antarctica, Europe and Australia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512747716.0" user="nevesnow" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is, in Latin American countries, we are taught our whole lives that there is one continent: America. North and South America are subdivisions of the continent. I was very surprised when I came to the US and learned that here it is taught different. I believe much of the confusion comes from that, different education. Neither are necessarily right or wrong, they are just different viewpoints.

Continents as per Latin Americans: África, Antártida, América, Ásia, Europa e Oceania.

Continents as per English speaking countries: Asia, Africa, North America, South America, Antarctica, Europe and Australia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512904819.0" user="ordinary_kittens" delta="False">
    <text>Yup, this is really 100% it, and as a Canadian, I was also initially confused until I learned more.

English-speakers (or at least, the ones I know in my country) get incredibly confused at the idea that we would be considered to live on a continent called "America", as to us there is no continent called "America". If you had to refer to both North and South America, you would say "The Americas", much in the same way that you could say "Eurasia" if you were referring to both Europe and Asia.

So I didn't understand why people would argue online about it, or make comments like "it's so weird how Canadians will deny the fact that they're Americans." To us, there are no continents named America, only a country south of us which refers to itself as America for short.

But it's really just as logical to call the continent "America". There's no reason it wouldn't or couldn't be named America in other languages. Both views make perfect sense, as you say, and neither one is more correct than the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512907484.0" user="runtheroad" delta="False">
    <text>The idea that Europe and Asia are separate continents but North and South America are one is hilarious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513161571.0" user="WinPeaks" delta="False">
    <text>THANK YOU!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
