<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="125" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511805697.0" user="Ok_Cantaloupe_7423" delta="False">
    <text>Also: 

Calling the USA “America” is FINE. 

Most countries have longer names they do not use, why call America, The United States of America, when Germany doesn’t say Federal Republic of Germany? 

I hear the argument of “well America is a continent not a country” this is WRONG. Despite anything you’ve been taught in grade school, in nearly every way that can be used to define a continent, there is no combined “America”. There is North America, and South America. 
They are on different tectonic Continental plates, they are separated by water (I do not care it’s a canal) and they have a near dividably different language and culture barrier with a few exceptions. 

No one is genuinely confused when you say American, and they do not wonder “what country in the Americas you’re from” they are being dickheads.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
