<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510417699.0" user="CCCyanide" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is, imagine you want to refer to all inhabitants of the American continent. How do you proceed without people confusing it with US citizens ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510498094.0" user="CommodorePuffin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The problem is, imagine you want to refer to all inhabitants of the American continent.

Which continent? There are two: North America and South America. In either case, you'd say "North Americans" or "South Americans."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510508859.0" user="CCCyanide" delta="False">
    <text>At least in my country, it is generally agreed upon that America is a single continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510550815.0" user="CommodorePuffin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;At least in my country, it is generally agreed upon that America is a single continent.

We'd call that the "Americas" (plural). Different counties and regions have differing continental models, which probably leads to a lot of the conflict about these terms online.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510569272.0" user="CCCyanide" delta="False">
    <text>Fair. 
 
Adding to another comment in the section, we usually refer to US inhabitants (in my country, at least) as "US-ians", which, I will admit, sounds pretty bad in English.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510559503.0" user="Mr_Kittlesworth" delta="False">
    <text>Does your country also agree that Europe, Asia, and Africa are one continent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510576811.0" user="CCCyanide" delta="False">
    <text>Some people do think that. And they invented terms for it, instead of taking existing ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510709130.0" user="Mr_Kittlesworth" delta="False">
    <text>The only people who think the americas are one continent are people who don’t speak English primarily. 

Meanwhile, the UK, Canada, Australia, and most importantly, the United States, all call people from the US “Americans.”

Why would a dubious geographic choice made by non-English-speaking nations be a good reason to change how Americans are described in English?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510732959.0" user="eloel-" delta="False">
    <text>Eurasia is a popular enough continent description. Eurasia+Africa, I've not heard though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510644617.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>there was a CMV about this like two hours ago ha</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514417651.0" user="CommodorePuffin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;there was a CMV about this like two hours ago ha

There's practically a CMV about this topic every week!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513225677.0" user="lancea_longini" delta="False">
    <text>In that case in English when we refer to the two continents and use that name it is called the Americas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513083801.0" user="NopityNopeNopeNah" delta="False">
    <text>That is a cultural belief, not a scientific one. Literally, continents are an arbitrary term of definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510522120.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>"people from the americas"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510557460.0" user="CCCyanide" delta="False">
    <text>Why not the other way around then ? Name US people "people from the US", and leave the rest of the continent alone. 
 
Reminder that the USA do not own and did not create America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510595861.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>why not add an S to america

&gt;Reminder that the USA do not own and did not create America.  


obviously</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511072072.0" user="Gaoji-jiugui888" delta="False">
    <text>There are two American continents and they have specific names. So you’d call them South Americans or North Americans. There is no continents simply called “America”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511321373.0" user="Orion113" delta="False">
    <text>A reminder that Romance speakers do not own and did not create America either. America is an Italian word, applied to the continents by the Europeans who invaded and conquered them, bringing to them a variety of conqueror's languages and cultures, including Germanic and Romance.

&amp;#x200B;

One could argue using the word America at all is insulting to native cultures. Many Indigenous groups today refer to North American as Turtle Island, for instance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511027262.0" user="juant675" delta="False">
    <text>But there is only 1</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511349437.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on where you come from and what you are taught.   But at the very least North America and South America are on different continental plates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512968028.0" user="runtheroad" delta="False">
    <text>New Worlders</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
