<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510207631.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>I call people from the US US Americans. I call people from South America South Americans.  They are Americans but with qualification. So I when I refer to people from the United States of America, I usually use US Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510268701.0" user="jrssister" delta="False">
    <text>Why would you ever have to refer to people from South America as South Americans when you could just say Brazilian, Argentinian, Colombian, etc.?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510280931.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>I use South Americans when I refer to them collectively. Of course I can be more specific, but at the UN, where I work sometimes, we collectively refer to representatives from South America, South Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510301299.0" user="jrssister" delta="False">
    <text>That makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510327287.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>I guess diplomatic culture is much more specific with how we refer to our colleagues. We always say US Colleagues instead of American colleagues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510415797.0" user="NunnaTheInsaneGerbil" delta="False">
    <text>What would you call a Canadian, then? Canadian Americans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510428671.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>Canadians are Canadians, because it’s a specific attribute to a nation state of Canada.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511457518.0" user="NunnaTheInsaneGerbil" delta="False">
    <text>I will admit, I find it a bit strange to specifically append American to everyone from the Americas except for Canadians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510458045.0" user="CommodorePuffin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What would you call a Canadian, then? Canadian Americans?

That term generally refers to someone who's a dual-citizen, and most Canadians I know would find it insulting (or at least very annoying) to be called "American" since a big part of Canada's culture seems to be based on "not being the same as the US."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511443407.0" user="NunnaTheInsaneGerbil" delta="False">
    <text>I know lol, I'm Canadian, I was just asking op to clarify cause their thought process seemed interesting to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510549346.0" user="Mr_Kittlesworth" delta="False">
    <text>Americans wouldn’t ever - ever - say “US Americans.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510563758.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>No, but you guys say “In the US” or “I’m from US” or “I’m from the States” or “USA! USA!” 

So accordingly that’s what we use to describe them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510577015.0" user="Mr_Kittlesworth" delta="False">
    <text>I agree we use different descriptions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510749479.0" user="Familiar_Cow_5501" delta="False">
    <text>“Im not making stuff up”

….next sentence literally stuff made up</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511046359.0" user="Gaoji-jiugui888" delta="False">
    <text>Hey mate, they totally work in the UN, they know stuff!!!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512780114.0" user="YaReformedYaBetcha" delta="False">
    <text>Ikr. “The U.N” a.k.a the club certain countries want, but the U.S pays for all their activities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513615744.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>Not my problem. US created it and we are following their order.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513623913.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. We are precise. Nobody in the diplomatic world refer to USA as just America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513654071.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I worked in 7 countries and met with diplomats from over 100 countries including U.S. diplomats and U.S. citizens. Overwhelmingly, people use U.S. than America when they refer to themselves. I only heard them use “America” when they talk about culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511433492.0" user="Disdain690" delta="False">
    <text>I can assure you they all still refer to themselves as American. Saying we're from the US doesn't change that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513639955.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>You’ll be surprised. When they say American, it’s usually cultural. They come from the United States and it’s much much rare to hear someone to say “I’m from America.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511944988.0" user="rewanpaj" delta="False">
    <text>no we says we would say we’re american</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513716542.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>You’d be surprised. People from US have diverse ways of identifying themselves to the outside world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511258950.0" user="feto_ingeniero" delta="False">
    <text>Do you refer to Mexicans as North Americans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513721143.0" user="lonelypeloton" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, we use Mexicans.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
