<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="192" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512348899.0" user="Itball" delta="False">
    <text>"American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact."
Do you have anything to support this or want to clarify what you mean by official?
As you've noticed many people don't think this is an ordinary and natural use of the word. 

I don't think the use of this term in this way itself does any genocides or whatever so I don't imagine your mind will be changed based on what you've said. 
But it's worth considering if it's historically accurate or why some people might think it's a bit edgy given historical background. 

For the record I generally refer to people from that country as americans but I'm not going to pretend that word comes from a pretty place or that there's nothing controversial about it</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
