<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510187445.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>there is no other country with the word america in it's name, this is simply the logical choice

I will challenge this by saying that I don't think this enough of a common viewpoint for you to worry about it. From another thread earlier today, I saw many european people say that "american" is simply what THEY use to refer to people from the US. 

at best it could be seen as erasing the other countries (figuratively)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510483172.0" user="CommodorePuffin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;there is no other country with the word america in it's name, this is simply the logical choice

Exactly. Besides, when countries like Iran shout "Death to America!" are they referring to both continents? Hell no. So unless the entire world agreed on a single term (which seems unlikely) then "American" is probably the best choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510953633.0" user="WizeAdz" delta="False">
    <text>So much context &amp; knowledge is required to interpret language....

...No wonder my Computer Science professors couldn't handle natural language processing back in the 1990s.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516574007.0" user="carissadraws" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a good point to bring up</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510922378.0" user="WizeAdz" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;there is no other country with the word america in it's name, this is simply the logical choice

That's true in English, but not in Spanish.

In Spanish, America refers to the continent, and Estados Unidos de América is a nation that happens to be on the continent.

Bilingual English / Spanish speakers can keep this straight without too much trouble.

But asserting that America the USA is only true in English-speaking countries, and isn't accurate in a truly global context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510931886.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Which country has "America" in the name that isn't the United States?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511009915.0" user="merry_go_byebye" delta="False">
    <text>What country other than South Africa has Africa in its name? Do we expect to call someone African and think we are referring to South Africa?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511022649.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>If they want to start using it as their demonym that might make sense. Over time you could see that happening, but it might be awkward at the beginning.

Americans aren't at the beginning. That's already the accepted term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511141228.0" user="gs2017" delta="False">
    <text>The accepted term by them. Not by the people they are disrespecting by appropriating the name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511213369.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, but nobody else has it in the name. Given that the US was named pretty early on they had ample opportunity to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511252270.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>It's our name.   Again, slowly for the people at the back of the class - no other country in the world has the word 'America' in it.   They are the ones being imperialistic, claiming that because they use that term for one continent (which is funny, because North and South America are clearly on different continental plates)  that no one can use that name for their nation.   Except ours has, from the very beginning, and is the oldest extant nation on the continent, whether you believe it is America or the Americas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511513314.0" user="NeuroticKnight" delta="False">
    <text>You change your name, since you are the one hung up about imperialism and colonialism, why do you want to be called after a European explorer, if you see them as colonizers and not founders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511082634.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Still different, it’s directionally named after the continent. West Virginians are West Virginian not Virginian.

If they were the United South African States they’d be in the same dilemma.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511109294.0" user="pdx619" delta="False">
    <text>Central African Republic (sort of, African vs Africa)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511121362.0" user="merry_go_byebye" delta="False">
    <text>Fair. Thanks for curing me of my ignorance lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511126444.0" user="pdx619" delta="False">
    <text>Lol I had to look it up. I figured there had to be at least one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511495484.0" user="NeuroticKnight" delta="False">
    <text>There is also an African Union, which is a kinda EU style or at least ambitious African Union. 

Words can be gray, Israel for example is a preffered partner of European Union, and Morroco is a candidate EU state, 

50 years from EU can include neighboring african states, and theyd have European passports, but wont be Europeans or will be idk</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511467448.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>No we call them “South Africans”, just like we’d cal someone from North America “North American”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511086178.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>Why does that matter when "America" is the name of the landmass itself? 

Every other continent uses the continent's name to encompass something from there, OP himself used "European" to describe a group of people, "African" and "Asian" are also used, only "American" is specific to those in the US. 

No other country in the Arabian peninsula is called "Arabia" apart from Saudi Arabia, but we still call their people "Saudi" or "Saudi Arabian", not "Arabian" and much less "Arab".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511092312.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Because nobody else is using the name for their country specifically. They have their own names.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511124089.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but the point isn't to use the name to call the people of another country, but to use it to call the people of the American continent. 

Like I said with my Saudi Arabia example, no single country was using "Arabian", but because the region itself is called "Arabia" we differentiate by using "Arabian" for the things in that region and "Saudi"/"Saudi Arabian" when specifying Saudi Arabia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511217606.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>The point is to use a demonym that works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511257165.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>Which "American", due to the fact that it would also be what one would come something that comes from the Americas (notice that I couldn't use a denonym here), doesn't. 

Can you really blame that the people that spent the last 6 decades having governments overturned by the US (sometimes for something as simple as to sell bananas for cheap) see the US calling itself "America" and its people "Americas" as a threat?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511354393.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Except the idea is pushed less by Latin Americans and way, way, way more by Europeans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511407366.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's pushed by Latin Americans as well and even more strongly, to a point that the denonym in Spanish is "estadunidense" ("unitedstatian"). 

I don't think that I have ever encountered an European (interesting how there's a word to refer to the people of Europe) that used "American" as something related to the Americas instead of the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511455147.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>The thread started with a European pushing the idea. Up and down this thread there are people talking about the blatant disregard from Europeans.

And the demonym in Spanish is "Americano/a."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511542670.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>I saw that, but even if Europeans also push this, Latin Americans do too. 

I don't know about the denonym in Spain, but the one used in Latin America is "estadunidense", you can see that - for instance - by going to the USA Wikipedia page in Spanish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511579094.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Funny, "Americano/a" was always the word my Spanish teachers used, and only one grew up in the US. 

Regardless, I don't see the need to bend the demonym used in English and many, many other languages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511625789.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>You are free to check for yourself, you can read news articles from Latin American countries, for instance. 

Well, the need is that the US isn't alone in this landmass and shouldn't be able to simply take it. I doubt that the US will decide to change, but be aware that many others in that same landmass are not in agreement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511640570.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Regardless, the other options in English that have been proposed are just awful sounding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511677109.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>So people can say "West Virginian" or "South Korean" but "US American" is too much? Go with Yankee then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511720299.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Ha! The South will hate that one.

But "West Virginian" is definitely more natural than "US American." Even German, language of cumbersome compound words, agrees on that count.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511337109.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; use it to call the people of the American continent.

Which one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511429494.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>Latin Americans are taught that America is a single continent, not two. Since there isn't an international norm that strictly defines what is a continent, there is no right theory, so that is valid. But if you want I can specify as "members of the OAS".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511399845.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>In English, there isn't an American continent.   There are two American Continents, one North America, one South America.  


So someone might be from South America or the Carribbean, but if you refer to someone as 'American' most would know you mean someone from the United States of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511455784.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>There is no “American continent” people from the United States referred to by continent would be North Americans, as would others from North America. Someone from Mexico isn’t American, they’re North American</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511517913.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't a specific international convention that separates continents, so there are different theories that are taught in different places. 

The main theory (used in Latin America and Europe, for instance) is that America is one single continent. This has been the main theory for a long time and the US only started to teach differently when it wanted to separate itself from "the third world". That's why there are only five rings in the Olympic flag.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511536915.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>The Olympic flag also leaves out Antarctica yet recognizes it as a continent nonetheless. Further, the majority of the world population uses the 7 continent model</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511598943.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>The Olympic flag includes only the inhabited continents, which they explain on their official website[website](https://olympics.com/en/news/which-colour-represents-asia-in-olympic-rings) 

And the 6 continent model is used in many countries in Europe, most of Asia, and all of Latin America. What matters most is the definition most used in America(s) itself, though. The seven theory only started to be taught in the US until WII, when the US wanted to push the "three worlds" theory and not be seen in the same continent as so many third world countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511624727.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>And the UN specifies 6 geographical populations delineating between North America and Latin America, if we’re going by international organizations grouping populations. China and India teach the 7 continent model, along with numerous other countries the US included. I fail to see what’s wrong with using the term used by the majority</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511669102.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>The UN geoscheme isn't even a standard for the UN System (as said by the UN itself). It isn't that it's wrong to teach one or the other, but to say that using "American" isn't an issue is to ignore why Latin America has a problem with that usage in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511307466.0" user="Whatever-ItsFine" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why does that matter when "America" is the name of the landmass itself?

It's not, though.  There are two continents:  North American and South America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511479329.0" user="viniciusbfonseca" delta="False">
    <text>Continents are arbitrary, there isn't a single convention that is followed (although Asia, Europe, and Africa have a mostly defined separation accepted by all) and actually the theory that America is a single continent subdivided into North, Central, South and Caribbean is the one taught in most of Latin America. Even the US taught this until recently, but then it wanted to try to separate itself from the "third world". 

Tell me something: how many rings are there in the Olympic flag?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512021687.0" user="calimeatwagon" delta="False">
    <text>Except they are called "Arabs"...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511548593.0" user="WizeAdz" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Which country has "America" in the name that isn't the United States?

Determining "America" vs. "The Americas" by context clues alone is confusing, especially when you're conversing with people who aren't native English-speakers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511627399.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but if they're trying to get their read on what they read, that's their problem.

Language is full of context that can be difficult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511585877.0" user="Chuchulainn96" delta="False">
    <text>It's not just in the name of the country, America is literally the name of the country. United States only refers to the form of government for the country of America. Just like how United Kingdom refers to the form of government for the combined countries of England, Scotland, and Northern Ireland.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510995176.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;In Spanish, America refers to the continent, and Estados Unidos de América is a nation that happens to be on the continent of America.

That's...exactly the same as how it works in English...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511094790.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao he tried</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552990925.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511127974.0" user="gs2017" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if you need it spelled out in simpler terms, there is a whole continent bearing the name America. Hence the imperialism and the disrespecting other people from the Americas when you appropriate the name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511162235.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>Don't worry, that's obvious. The commenter I replied to is the one who doesn't understand that it works the same in English as in Spanish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511250475.0" user="Roadshell" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Well, if you need it spelled out in simpler terms, there is a whole continent bearing the name America.

Two continents</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511320960.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>not to mention referring to "people from the americas" undermines the argument that people call the whole hemisphere america.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511332620.0" user="Roadshell" delta="False">
    <text>I can think of very few situations in which anyone would need to refer to all people's of the western hemisphere at once such as to need a word like "Americans" to refer to all of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511687889.0" user="Eponymous_Doctrine" delta="False">
    <text>we have a word for that.  it's "Pan-American".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511156932.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>He's saying that it's only the logical choice in English. I don't know how it works in other languages, but in Spanish the correct demonym is "estadounidense", not "americano", which technically could refer to anybody from the Americas. That said, "americano" is used more and more to refer to "estadounidenses" in vulgar speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511216525.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn’t use the term “correct” here. Can’t really be a third-party and dictate what’s correct</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511241231.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Who's the third-party?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511274668.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Whoever said it should be estadounidense as a term to call Americans</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511316445.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, it's not so much that someone said it, but rather that it is/was the common usage. If you go that route, bad grammar could never be "incorrect".

More importantly, unlike English, many other languages do have academies that determine what is and isn't correct. French has the Académie Française, Spanish has the RAE, who has this to say on the matter:

https://www.rae.es/dpd/Estados%20Unidos</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511341068.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>To be the common usage someone had to start it.

And my alternative is not bad grammar. It’s LITERAL. Los Americanos del Estado Unidos. From the country called the los Estados Unidos de AMERICA. 

You might not agree and you might not like it. But it’s not bad grammar lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511415617.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Man, you don't even speak the language, what are you trying to argue here?

It's wrong. You can use whatever term you want in whatever language you want, but you are not above the RAE or the common literary Spanish in determining what's right or wrong in Spanish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511461450.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>I speak enough Spanish that you’re not gonna bullshit me. The RAE in that link is giving RECOMMENDATIONS. Which means they are foregoing what it’s actually literal to cater to sensitivities of others.

I’m telling you what it is in Spanish not based on feelings. You’re trying to tell me what it is based on feelings. It may be customary to use that because of cultural sensitivities BUT that doesn’t make it literally right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511520828.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>If you really do speak enough Spanish, surely, you'll understand this part:

&gt;Pero debe evitarse el empleo de americano para referirse exclusivamente a los habitantes de los Estados Unidos, uso abusivo que se explica por el hecho de que los estadounidenses utilizan a menudo el nombre abreviado América (en inglés, sin tilde) para referirse a su país. No debe olvidarse que América es el nombre de todo el continente y son americanos todos los que lo habitan.

There are no feelings. This is what the highest language authority for the Spanish language says about the matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511544116.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not your feelings dude. Read what you just sent me. The terms americanos should be avoided because it’s abusive to the other inhabitants of the continent (who feel they are americanos as well).

But yes thank you for proving that the RAE is giving recommendations to cater to the sensitivities of other people rather than providing unbiased linguistic information. This truly makes it clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511565022.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't say anything about feelings and "abusivo" doesn't have the same connotations as "abusive" in English, but you would know that if you actually spoke Spanish before trying to school someone on its usage.

The RAE is stating that its use is incorrect because "americano" refers to anybody from the Americas. That's the only thing that makes clear there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511611588.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Do you not know that abusivo used as harsh or insulting insinuates it’s affects peoples’ feelings. Lmao no they specifically say in there it’s a recommendation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511640124.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>See, if you actually spoke Spanish you would understand that that's not the meaning of abusive in that sentence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511651366.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Pero debe evitarse el empleo de americano para referirse exclusivamente a los habitantes de los Estados Unidos.

Translate that for me papa</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511717428.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>That PhD in Spanish you got fun watching Dora should be enough to translate it. Alternatively you can use the RAE dictionary, it exists for reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511726342.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao brother I just spoke to my Dominican friend who says, literally, I’m correct and she assumes you’re a liberal 😂</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511749998.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao brother I just spoke to my Dominican friend from DR who says, literally, I’m correct and she assumes you’re a liberal 😂

Pero, brother, when they say avoid using something because other latin Americans are offended because they feel excluded then that means they’re giving you a suggestion to not hurt someone’s feelings lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511865002.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao brother, sure your imaginary friend says you're correct. I thought you spoke enough Spanish to know it.

Truly peak reasoning here adding some unrelated politics as if that gives you the upper hand. Fits well with all the ignorant arguments you've been making.

I'm going to leave it here because I already entertained your bullshit too much.

PS: If you weren't this backwards you would have realised a while ago that I'm not even Latin American and I have no horse in this race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511900738.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Where does you being Latin American have anything to do with anything 😂😂. I told you why the RAE just recommended not to use the term American. Perhaps you need study more English. 

I’m not a native speaker so you’ll never take my word. I got confirmation from a native. So going to a source for a legit check is frowned upon LMAO. Dog I’m from the tri-state. I can meet a new Spanish person just by walking outside. 

P.s. she also assumes you go by LatinX 😂😂</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512562965.0" user="blurplesnow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I’m not a native speaker

That much is clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512614121.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao bro idc about anything you said</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512567210.0" user="blurplesnow" delta="False">
    <text>I bet they get into people's faces about LatinX, how white people shouldn't be making up words for native Spanish speakers, when we came up with those words in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516225340.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>So Spanish people, from Spain, are the governing body for Latin American people now. Brother 😂😂.

You really said I made the language you use so you’re going to use it how I want. Your issues are deeper than this topic lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511713546.0" user="headsmanjaeger" delta="False">
    <text>There are millions of Spanish-speaking Americans for whom "estadounidense" literally is correct</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511802696.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>It’s a created demonym by Spanish language speakers to refer to US Americans. Normal thought process is to simplify the complete term. In this case un Americano del Estados Unidos.

A person with no sensitivities to other parties would shorten that to Americano. Not estadounidense unless you needed a reason to create a different term. And the reason is because they feel they are Americanos as well, and they’re not wrong but let’s not act like that’s not the reason it was created</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512522808.0" user="blurplesnow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;un Americano del Estados Unidos.

that is not simplifying the term. Every single spanish speaker in America will know what "estadounisende" means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512622275.0" user="ASAP_Dom" delta="False">
    <text>Follow the thread mijo. Read my comment before this before jumping in</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511444532.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>There’s no continent called “America”. There are North America and South America. You can refer to people from each as North Americans and South Americans…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511482771.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Let me introduce you to this concept called "continental models": https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continent#Number</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511526048.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but OP was in Germany with a German professor where they use the 7-continent model. Further, by population the majority of people in the world use the 7 continent model since it’s also taught in china and India.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511547587.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>But this part of the thread is about Spanish... Not to mention the consideration of American in German is also different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511573192.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not to mention that the UN also designates 6 “geographic populations” including both North America and Latin America, so I’d call that international consensus</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511592788.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Which, even if it were true, would have nothing to do with what's right or with in a certain language...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511605243.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Which, since it is very much true, does actually mean something*

No one in a Latin American country is going to be confused if I refer to myself as americano in an American accent. Language is primarily about communication and arguably this is still communicating what is meant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511620870.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Who said anybody was going to be confused?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511636835.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>If no one’s confused I don’t see what the problem is</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511647601.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>Who said anything about problems? The guy was just explaining the logic behind the two terms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511660899.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>The logic being either confusion or offense…</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511696571.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>The logic being that because Americano refers to anybody from the Americas, it should be avoided when taking about US citizens. But that has nothing to do with confusion or offense, and it especially had nothing to do with what is right or common in English.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511756026.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Yet this initial argument took place in Germany where Amerikaner is most common, and was specifically about disrespect. I understand languages are different, but this thread is specifically commenting on the idea of Spanish speakers being offended by using the term american (an English term so the presumption is that English is being spoken). I don’t speak Spanish, but if I did I suppose I’d use the term that someone would understand best, however the Spanish for a person from the United States is also ambiguous because of Mexico, so in my opinion it’s still rather arbitrary</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511815390.0" user="Bigardo" delta="False">
    <text>But this thread is not about the "initial argument", it's about someone who explained why the difference made sense in Spanish.

You keep alluding to things that are off-topic and that I haven't talked about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511844837.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t say I see how it’s off topic. The comment referring to the difference in Spanish was replying to the initial argument, and so on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511004173.0" user="TheAlabamaJedi" delta="False">
    <text>But do any of the other countries have the word America in their name? I am drawing a blank on one. When we say American it's referring to our name and not the fact we are from north America.

Not all Americans are even from North America. Hawaiians are Americans for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511512540.0" user="WizeAdz" delta="False">
    <text>Guatemalans, Mexicans, Chileans, and Canadians are all Americans -- if you're speaking in Spanish.  They can all say yo soy un americano ("I am an American" in Spanish).

That's the context you need to work with.

Changing their language for your convenience is, uh, not gonna happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511561427.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>This is literally about people telling Americans to change our language for their convenience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512016912.0" user="calimeatwagon" delta="False">
    <text>Mexicans don't call themselves "Americans"... they call themselves Mexicans...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511118611.0" user="KneeNo6132" delta="False">
    <text>What?? In English "America" refers to the continents (América del norte y Sudamérica en Español) and The United States of America is a nation that happens to be on the continent of North America, which is the word-for-word translation of the spanish name.  

What other country has the name America in it in Spanish? you said that statement was not true in Spanish. 

&gt;It's a subtle distinction, but bilingual English / Spanish speakers can keep this straight without too much trouble.

I would sure hope so since it's literally the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511424256.0" user="someonenamedkyle" delta="False">
    <text>Kinda funny that in your example the only word that remained the same is… America. Quite literally proving yourself wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511023323.0" user="sonicboomslang" delta="False">
    <text>We're unitedstateseans</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511104044.0" user="seanflyon" delta="False">
    <text>That's a bit ambiguous.  How do people know you are talking about Americans and not citizens of another nation like the United States of Mexico?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512091459.0" user="igna92ts" delta="False">
    <text>Because nobody refers to Mexico as United States of Mexico</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511134084.0" user="Overthinks_Questions" delta="False">
    <text>How dare you erase the identity of people from the United States of Mexico (and historically, Brazil, Belgium, Colombia, Indonesia,  and Venezuela)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511150619.0" user="Cirieno" delta="False">
    <text>USAians</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511574192.0" user="darth_snuggs" delta="False">
    <text>Estadosunidosians</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511642388.0" user="redlegsfan21" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;there is no other country with the word america in it's name, this is simply the logical choice

My fun fact is that in Japanese, United States is translated as Amerika</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511658234.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>Reminds me of a cmv about soccer vs football I saw. Was weird to learn most English speaking countries in fact say soccer. And weirdly Japan does too

The things you learn</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514282577.0" user="acasta403" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, this is a weird one all around. Soccer just stands for association football. The British invented that term, and then turned around and made fun of Americans for actually using it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511749959.0" user="jtrom1010" delta="False">
    <text>This is my view. I am overwhelmingly called American when I meet Europeans while traveling and there's not exactly a good alternative.

I think this is a 10% of people type thing in any demographic and it's being presented as a European ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513059749.0" user="NopityNopeNopeNah" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, it’s a far more common opinion among Latin folks, whom you’re les likely to meet in Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513076993.0" user="jtrom1010" delta="False">
    <text>Agree, I was largely pointing at the implied generalization of Europeans from OP. At least I took it that way.

That said, I've personally heard Americano anytime it wasn't gringo in Spanish in all my LATAM trips. 

Not a local, small sample size, and speaking Spanish probably matters. But still.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514108720.0" user="488566N23522E" delta="False">
    <text>That's not even the issue people have, the problem lies in how exclusive the term "American" can be. White Americans can simply identify as "American," while others often feel the need, or were compelled to specify their ethnic background in referring to themselves. I've personally faced racism for asserting my American identity as someone from this continent. It's frustrating that, despite being on the same landmass, my claim to being American is questioned, even when we're on lands that now belong to the United States and I myself literally have strong native heritage tied to Aridoamerica and the Texas region. It just highlights a small glaring example of inequality in how we define and acknowledge American identity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
