<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43519844456.0" user="cyrusposting" delta="False">
    <text>If you are the big tent party that supports everything, why the hell should I vote for you? Parties get votes by standing for things and having clear goals and visions for the future. If I tell a candidate I have a concern about an issue, what I need to hear is "I have a plan for addressing that issue and here is that plan". I don't want to hear "you're valid and our party loves and accepts everyone". What does your candidate believe in and what do they plan to do? The perfectly ideologically impure candidate would never answer this question. They would tell the fascist that their ideas are welcome and they would say the same thing to the anarchist. Neither the fascist nor the anarchist would vote for them.

There is a degree to which a party's tent can be so big that there is no reason to vote for them, so by definition there is an amount of ideological purity that is *necessary* to win elections. Some degree of ideological purity is how you define what your party even *is*.

So how much is too much? Be honest with yourself, it depends entirely on which rhetorical stance benefits you. The "youre being too picky's" of today are the "we might as well just be republicans" of tomorrow.

And if two voters in the same party take different hardline stances that don't overlap, both can accuse the other of being too picky and both can complain about the other demanding "ideological purity". The fact is the electoral system failed them both in the exact same way by repeatedly nominating people like Joe Biden.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523224168.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I was talking more about individual ordinary people who push swing voters out of the tent by refusing to speak to them, but in terms of actual political candidates it can be good to take a clear stance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524305591.0" user="cyrusposting" delta="False">
    <text>Does that same mechanism not work in the other direction? Using the democratic party as an example, why is picking up swing voters more important than picking up voters who left the party after it shifted right? Maybe you can win over non-voters, or energize your base so they take an active role in your campaign beyond voting?

There are so many strategies for winning besides chasing centrists, who are frankly not as numerous as non voters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524414237.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Now that's an interesting point. So many Americans just plain don't vote. I understand not voting in local elections, but in the general?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43531274279.0" user="cyrusposting" delta="False">
    <text>If "did not vote" were a candidate, it would have won the 2016 election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43531658140.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Probably would have been a better president.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
