<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="120" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511789801.0" user="Manrocent" delta="False">
    <text>The conclusion is that the US founder fathers gave a terrible name to the country. It's an exercise of arrogance calling "united America" to a tiny portion of the whole continent. Even now the US isn't even the 1/3 of America. 

I understand that there is no option now, and I use "American" when speaking in English because there is no equivalent of "estadounidense", so I won't fight over the term as many Latinos do. But as someone who have friends everywhere, it's annoying to make the distinction between America and The Americas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512208929.0" user="DadsBigHonker" delta="False">
    <text>Tiny portion of the whole continent? It’s well over 1/3 of the continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512282244.0" user="Manrocent" delta="False">
    <text>The United States is like 3.5 million sq mi, while the continent is 16.43 million. It's massive, but not even the 1/4. 

Even so, at the beginning the US was the size of Colombia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512290526.0" user="DadsBigHonker" delta="False">
    <text>North America and South America are two different continents, sir.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512319524.0" user="Manrocent" delta="False">
    <text>Both are subdivisions, like Western and Eastern Europe.

It's even in the name, dude. The country is not called "United States of North America"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512334503.0" user="DadsBigHonker" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, so now North America and South America are one continent, and Western Europe and Eastern Europe are two continents. Ahh yes, the more I learn! My second grade teachers were wrong all these years!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512687187.0" user="Henrylord1111111111" delta="False">
    <text>They didn’t tho? When they named the country we were literally a bunch of states that were united and in America. Its not there fault that things change</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
