<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="307" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513689704.0" user="Foregonia" delta="False">
    <text>This is a bit of a language thing. In Spanish, there are alternative adjectives to describe someone from the US. I’m also from the US but lived in Spain when I was younger and I also heard this from Europeans and South Americans. I was told that it would be better to refer to myself at least as norteamericano with the understanding that I’m clumping myself with Canadians or “estadounidense” if I want to be more specific. With anything, your wrong but you’re not wrong. If you’re in Europe or South America, the culture and language favors other terminology and there are valid linguistic and cultural reasons. If you’re in the US, talking to other Umerricuns, then “American” is fine and proper. You’re wrong because you lack cultural sensitivity and awareness. Your very stubbornness to claim, in the face of multiple others telling you they also feel American, that you deserve to stake your claim on the name because it’s your god given right, further cements their view of you as an imperialist. Now.. I don’t think this is a hot bottom topic for everyone, but it’s definitely more common amongst Latin Americans. One more analogy to drive home the point- I once traveled to Morocco with a woman. Neither of us had ever been to a Muslim country before. When we showed up, we both, but especially my friend, immediately felt very out of place and potentially disrespectful, or at a minimum insensitive, and definitely obtuse. She was wearing shorts and a t-shirt. She really didn’t want to draw too much attention to herself or upset the people allowing us to visit their country. So we went to a shop and got some pants and a long sleeve shawl. We didn’t get a face covering and neither of us believed in these gender based clothing restrictions, but you have to balance your ego with your desire to live harmoniously with others. It’s give and take. In this case, what is the harm, when engaging with Latin Americans, and especially those who’ve voiced disfavor with your use of American, to ask what they’d prefer and them accommodate them in their request? How disruptive to your life is this accommodation really? How often will it come up where you need to use an alternative adjective?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
