<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510850736.0" user="homarjr" delta="False">
    <text>As a Canadian, I call them Americans. 

No one ever calls someone American with the intention of describing the continent. Call me American and I'll probably correct you immediately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512248831.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>But they are the ones kidnapping a term that belongs to all of us. You ARE American. From Canada to Argentina, we are all Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512298170.0" user="iamgr0o0o0t" delta="False">
    <text>We don’t think of ourselves as being Americans and I don’t think anyone is sad they took the word. We have our own national identities. What do you want Americans to be called?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512356458.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>US Americans. 

They are still American after all, they are just not the only ones. So not to get confused with any other 34 countries from the continent of America, they can be a bit more specific and say they are US Americans. 

Also, your national identity still places you in the continent of America. Being proud of your Canadian nationality is being proud of being American. Just like being proud of your Kenyan nationality makes you proud of being African.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512371146.0" user="The_Brain_FuckIer" delta="False">
    <text>There are 2 American continents, North America and South America. Conglomerating North and South America into one continent and leaving Asia and Europe separate is frankly dumb as fuck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512396026.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>That makes it even more confusing. That there is North America and South America yet one country gets the name American all to themselves?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512450934.0" user="iamgr0o0o0t" delta="False">
    <text>Would it still bother you even if people in the other American continent countries don’t want to call themselves American?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514917817.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't people want to be called American? Is it because they don't want to be mistaken by people from the United States?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515788140.0" user="iamgr0o0o0t" delta="False">
    <text>Kind of. We have our own national identities. We want to be called by the country we live in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515809678.0" user="Angelcakes101" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it matter why they don't want to be called American? Why would not be mistaken as being from the USA be a bad reason? 

Some people from Europe would rather be recognized by their country than being European. I don't think there's anything wrong with that. 


And in Asia a lot choose to identify themselves as East Asian, South Asian, Southeast Asian, etc. instead of just Asian because Asian is broad and people will assume you're talking about East Asian countries. Obviously some still like to self describe as Asian but I don't think it's wrong that people choose not to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518255117.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying it's a bad reason, on the opposite, I agree with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515969734.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>A much better question would be why would they want to be referred to as American? Ask anyone from any other continent of the world where they are from, and they will say the name of their country, not their continent. Likewise, it's generally considered reductionist and ignorant to label someone as European/African/Asian instead of naming their country. Of course, the categorizations of European/African/Asian still have meaning in a more abstract, regional context, but they don't really have much value or meaning when referring to an individual's personal background. Why would it be any different when referring to people of the Americas?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518311152.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly! It's arrogant calling a country a name that they are supposed to share with two whole continents. I'm trying to point out how ridiculous it sounds, because no other country does this. Nobody in their right mind would try to pass one country as a whole continent, it would take a very arrogant population to be ok with it and defend it. And when you go "how about you call yourself something else out of respect for every other country you share the term American with" is like you are asking them to put their skin inside out, like we are asking to kill their grandma's and all the puppies in the country.  

Asking US Americans for accountability? Outrageous!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518738902.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, no...that's not what I was arguing at all. But to address your argument: the "two whole continents" you refer to are called North America and South America, not America and America. That's the paradigm that's been accepted in English-speaking countries—North or South American when referring to the countinents, and American when referring the country. There is also another school of thought that rejects the separation of the Americas into two separate continents, and use terms such as "Americano" to refer to people from what they consider to be a single unified continent. **These are two different understandings borne of two different cultural contexts and neither is more valid or legitimate than the other.** So yes, it is in fact rather arrogant of you to try to browbeat someone from a different cultural context to change their entire understanding of geography and the established usage of their native language to match your own cultural context. Of course, totally valid to shit on Americans referring to themselves as "Americanos" in Spanish, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512359419.0" user="BritzlBen" delta="False">
    <text>They're American in the sense that people from France or Kazakhstan are Eurasian. Which is pretty much not at all because nobody uses a continental grouping region term as a descriptor for their place of origin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512384390.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly! Why do they get the special privilege of using the name of a whole continent just to describe themselves? 

I don't say I'm Caribbean, I say I'm Puerto Rican.  It will be really shitty of us if tomorrow we pretend there is no other country in the Caribbean and we start making  it a synonymous with our country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512404955.0" user="BritzlBen" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure if you noticed but the name of the country has America in it and is the main defining word of the name considering it's the only one with America in the name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512418419.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it means "this states are united in the continent of america" because it's a country in America. It's not America, is PART OF America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512461694.0" user="BritzlBen" delta="False">
    <text>So then the country just doesn't have a name and its citizens are not to be identified by a term?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514911371.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>That is not what I said at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512810001.0" user="ophmaster_reed" delta="False">
    <text>But America, and the English speaking world does not recognize a continent called "America". There's the continents of North America and South America. So this reasoning does not make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514923208.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>So neither does the name, should be United States of North America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514893291.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>Stop speaking English as if it was Spanish</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514899952.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>How many languages you speak?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514933835.0" user="Hedonistic_pleasure2" delta="False">
    <text>3, though I’m planning on taking French soon. Anyway, at some point you gotta realize what false cognates are and why you shouldn’t depend on cognates so much. I can’t go around saying “actually” thinking that it means the same as in my native language “atualmente”, meaning “currently”, and expect them to understand what I’m saying. 

In English, “America” means the USA, whereas “The Americas” refers to the continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515008073.0" user="CAHTA92" delta="False">
    <text>Actualmente me vale madres.  Because if it was just in the name, they could get a pass. But it's literally their brand to take whatever they want in their arrogance and dismiss anyone who dares call them on their shit. 

The fact that we have to make all these distinctions shows the way they named their country is not only wrong, but selfish. It should have been United States of North America then, but they didn't care about anyone else, and here we are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512965171.0" user="baconator_out" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. We'll annex you with the governance part once we wrap up some other foreign policy projects. We don't have unlimited money, after all. Your patience will be rewarded, we assure you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513044424.0" user="Tymptra" delta="False">
    <text>No we aren't, I'm North American and a Canadian. Pound sand (sorry).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513227502.0" user="Tiny-Gur-4356" delta="False">
    <text>Yup. 100%. Fellow Canadian and North American, but not American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512511599.0" user="ChineseVirus_69" delta="False">
    <text>you're a North American</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514501851.0" user="concretecannonball" delta="False">
    <text>I’m a Canadian living in Europe, always super offended and quick to correct when someone calls me an American lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514990826.0" user="1Commentator" delta="False">
    <text>Can you just call me a southerner and I’ll call you a northerner?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552982697.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
