<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510640419.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>American,
Canadian,
Mexican,
Honduran,
Costa Rican,
Equadorian..


By definition, “American” is someone who is a citizen or national of the United States of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511626459.0" user="clambroculese" delta="False">
    <text>The problem comes that it’s also in the name of two continents. Just like how often no matter what country in Europe you live in you’re called European. I agree US citizens are Americans, but I guess I can see where it comes from. I’ve only heard central and South Americans say this though. In my experience when a German says American they mean US citizen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511690229.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; In my experience when a German says American they mean US citizen.

Most people, when they hear "American" they think U.S.

Because people don't typically refer to their nationality or identity by their continent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511742296.0" user="clambroculese" delta="False">
    <text>Except when people say European……….</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511757377.0" user="Funtimes856" delta="False">
    <text>I've spend a lot of time in Europe, Asia, the Middle East, as well as in NYC.

When I meet a German, they say "I'm German."  
When I meet a Brit, they say "I'm British."  
.."I'm French."  
.."I'm Greek."  


... They don't say "I'm a European.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511770214.0" user="clambroculese" delta="False">
    <text>No, they don’t. But often they’re referred to by Americans in that way. It’s kind of the same thing calling anyone from the America’s American. I mean I call us citizens American, I’m just saying I can see where the thought comes from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513044736.0" user="thewizardsbaker11" delta="False">
    <text>Ecuadorian - they're not citizens of the equator. That's a whole other thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552977688.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
