<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="253" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513066720.0" user="NopityNopeNopeNah" delta="False">
    <text>Hey, so I’m a US citizen, and my SO is a Latina immigrant. From her country’s perspective, both continents are America. Since we all live in them, we’re all Americans. She is patriotic to her home country, but she also feels a connection to other American countries, and feels a pride there.

The USA, coincidentally, has held an economic and political stranglehold over much of South and Central America for over a century. They violently overthrew the government of my SO’s country, and instituted an authoritarian dictatorship. And this isn’t a distant past; her parents were alive during this dictatorship.

Are people from the US wrong for calling themselves Americans? I don’t believe so. It makes sense when you take into account the name of our country.

Are people from other American countries wrong for being upset about residents of USA calling themselves Americans? I don’t believe so. This can be taken (maybe deservedly so) as another attempt at hegemony over the continents.

I’m not saying you have to stop calling yourself American. But maybe listen to the people around you, and be sympathetic to what they say. There’s enough pain in the world already, we should try to act with kindness and understanding wherever we can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513520128.0" user="OscarGrey" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Are people from other American countries wrong for being upset about residents of USA calling themselves Americans? I don’t believe so

It's dumb in English because it's literally Latin America vs. the rest of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513707779.0" user="KLUME777" delta="False">
    <text>I think Latin Americans are wrong for being upset about it. It may be understandable due to historical reasons, but that doesn't make it right. They come off looking extra sensitive, hypocritical, and biased.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514609335.0" user="Arkrobo" delta="False">
    <text>The only issue is, what do you call us then? I'm from a Latin background and so is my wife and this is all news to me. You can't be upset and not provide an alternative, it's unreasonable. Saying I'm from the United States is not equivalent, and if that's the expectation, then they better be ready to give up "I'm German" for "I'm from Germany". Otherwise they're hypocrites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515552116.0" user="KLUME777" delta="False">
    <text>Are you replying to the wrong person? I think Americans ie. US citizens should be called Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515682956.0" user="Arkrobo" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, I failed to read your reply correctly and now I look like a dumbass. Sorry about that lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513925574.0" user="AssassinWench" delta="False">
    <text>I guess my confusion is, why does it matter what people from the US call themselves in English compared to what people from Spanish-majority countries call Americans in Spanish? 

Pulling from a completely different country, in Japan they say アメリカ人 (America + Person) and they don't associate/confuse that with people from Central or South America....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514418736.0" user="weedbeads" delta="False">
    <text>It could be seen as a respect thing. Don't lay claim to that which you don't own, and the USA doesn't own the entirety of the Americas</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514431742.0" user="AssassinWench" delta="False">
    <text>I guess when I say America I don't mean the Americas. Everyone I know is just shortening USA to just the A....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514446020.0" user="weedbeads" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that most people don't take it that way and that its a very "grammar Nazi" request.

I think its similar to using the wrong version of "to" or "there." People will understand what you mean, but it isn't technically correct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516637913.0" user="NopityNopeNopeNah" delta="False">
    <text>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_involvement_in_regime_change_in_Latin_America</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514575816.0" user="ARCFacility" delta="False">
    <text>There aren't really any other countries that are named after their continent, to my knowledge, but i guess a close example would be a country named similarly to its region, South Africa -- when a South African citizen proclaims themself a South African, they aren't refering to themselves as Southern African, they're specifically talking about South Africa because that's just the name of their country. To insist that they're claiming the entire region of Southern Africa would be pure pedantics

Granted, there's definitely a lot of history that, to my knowledge, isn't there with South Africa and Southern Africa, but my main point is, it's the name of the country -- we don't call ourselves Americans because of a superiority complex (though there are definitely plenty of us who unfortunately have one) but because it's just. The name of the country we live in</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
