<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="360" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43514302834.0" user="utgertz" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand how this is perceived to be an issue unique to the US.

Look at Korea for example. Both North -and South Koreans would happily refer to themselves as Korean, and while true of course, it is ambiguous in various different contexts;

While both are Korea, the cultural, economic and perhaps most notably political differences necessitate the distinguishing nomenclature. 

The same is true for the former West -and East Germany. Both countries citizens would have happily called themselves German, the umbrella term again would've been useless in any political context for example.

While true that the issue of identical common nomenclature for country and continent may be unique to the US case- naming ambiguity really is not. 

Of course, cardinal directions as a distinguishing feature make little sense when discussing the USA. "North American" as a term for the US population is true, but again useless when, for example, discussing the various cultures of North America.

Personally, I don't understand how the term "US-American" would do any harm or cause any misunderstandings in any given context.

Note: Since OP has encountered opposition to the use of the word "american" as a US descriptor in Germany, I want to add that, in Germany, "US-American" is coincidentally already a common way to refer to peoples from the USA.

Answering OP's question directly, depends on what one defines to be wrong. Objectively, the peoples from the USA are american but in differing contexts, for example global politically, referring to peoples as "Americans" is certainly ambiguous. And in my opinion, in a specific context and precise discourse, be it academically for example, unnecessary ambiguity would be wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
