<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="95" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511584147.0" user="tuss11agee" delta="False">
    <text>Latin Americans speak a Latin based language. (I suppose that could apply to Quebec which would be confusing given the geographic differences in climate and it’s affect on culture. However, the only other French speaking Latin American country is a pretty big anomaly in terms of their emancipation story). 

Native Americans were here prior to anyone naming it America.

And so, should English speaking Americans be called “Anglican American”? I guess. But almost all are, outside of Canada, in the US anyways. 

Canadians can call themselves Canadian. They are assumed to be English speakers, otherwise they call themselves “French-Canadian”.

Many Americans, when abroad, might actually say they are “from the states”. But there’s no way to turn the countries name into an adjective other than ”American”.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
