<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43510181507.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA

What do you mean by this? Official according to who?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510280297.0" user="catloaf_crunch" delta="False">
    <text>Presidential addresses and proclamations made to the citizens of the US start with:

"My fellow Americans..."

And:

"The American people"

The government uses the term in it's most official proclamations. Dunno how much more official it gets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510311137.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the USA's president officially decides these things. So that's pretty much level zero of officialness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510318392.0" user="catloaf_crunch" delta="False">
    <text>The elected leader of the country refers to the citizens of said country as "Americans".

That's literally as official as it gets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510352420.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>No it isn't, the office of President of the USA has no authority over the English language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510360952.0" user="catloaf_crunch" delta="False">
    <text>The government of a country has the authority to designate what its citizens are referred to as though???

You're kinda missing the forest for the trees here dude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510379293.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The government of a country has the authority to designate what its citizens are referred to as though???

Do they though, it's certainly not a principal that's been widely held throughout history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510951384.0" user="pleasedontharassme" delta="False">
    <text>If a tribe in central Africa referred to themselves as “Klatchian” but non-tribe members called them “Morporkians” are they Morporkians or Klatchians? I’d imagine the tribe has the day of what they should be referred to as</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510965798.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Given how languages work generally they'd be Morporkians in English (assuming non-tribe includes English speakers) and Klatchian in their own language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510970711.0" user="pleasedontharassme" delta="False">
    <text>But they both speak English</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510988348.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Different dialects now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511014775.0" user="pleasedontharassme" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, but the Klatchians aren’t wrong in referring to themselves as Klatchian then</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511028159.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, but both, neither or either one could be considered official. If there's no reasonable authority over it then neither would be official.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511906605.0" user="N3wPortReds" delta="False">
    <text>why are you arguing semantics over the officialness of the term american 

the first definition google states when search "definition american" is: 

```adjective
adjective: American
relating to or characteristic of the United States or its inhabitants.
"a leading American industrial company"
relating to or denoting the continents of America.
"the American continent south of the tropic of Cancer"
noun
noun: American; plural noun: Americans
1.
a native or citizen of the United States.
a native or inhabitant of any of the countries of North, South, or Central America.
2.
the English language as it is used in the United States; American English.```</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510964895.0" user="mrtrailborn" delta="False">
    <text>So what everyone else says they want to be reffered to as matters, but not people from the U.S. That's like rigidly referring to everyone from the continent of asia as asian, despite them asking you not to, lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510985292.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>What?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510527108.0" user="Power_of_Atturdy" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the English language has some centralized source of truth like French or Dutch? English is just monkeys hitting things and making neat noises that they cram together with other noises from other languages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510552507.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>In which case OP would be wrong to say something in English was the "official" term?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510695171.0" user="Power_of_Atturdy" delta="False">
    <text>No, not in the slightest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510708781.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>So, if I say "Statian" is the official term you believe that would be correct as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510723310.0" user="Power_of_Atturdy" delta="False">
    <text>Do you hold a position of power that can designate terminology for a group of citizens within a country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510750834.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I hold the same official power for doing so as the president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510898192.0" user="Power_of_Atturdy" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I wasn’t aware you had clearance to send official government communications. My apologies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510907123.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so sending government communications is now the requirement, that's a new one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510948956.0" user="Double_Abalone_2148" delta="False">
    <text>Let it go, the President isn’t going to start calling Americans USAians or whatever, that kind of word doesn’t even make in the English language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510952982.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not expecting him to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511059823.0" user="Power_of_Atturdy" delta="False">
    <text>You’re really not making a good argument here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511120412.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Glass houses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511131693.0" user="Power_of_Atturdy" delta="False">
    <text>Go on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511138074.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510791547.0" user="One-Organization970" delta="False">
    <text>Are there historical documents going back centuries with reams of examples of Americans being referred to as Statians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510822699.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>So you disagree with the other commenter that the country's leader decides the "official" term?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511380189.0" user="dnext" delta="False">
    <text>Common parlance.   Group usage defines what is acceptable.   You can use other terms but you'd be looked at askance and perhaps corrected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511420685.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so you disagree with both of the previous commenters.

3 different ideas about what is required for something to be official. Personally it makes me think maybe none of them are right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511950076.0" user="N3wPortReds" delta="False">
    <text>You are so fucking cringe bro holy shit this is wild that you're arguing this hard over the most commonly used term to describe people from the USA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513718614.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>No one's arguing whether it's common or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514656496.0" user="Stario98" delta="False">
    <text>Well you can call yourself your name and everyone else can call you a dumbass, both are right in your perspective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514767806.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>No, because a name is your official name when it's on your birth certificate or deed poll. So the name that's on that is your official name. You can refer to yourself with a different name and people can call you something different but that wouldn't change your official name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515246124.0" user="Stario98" delta="False">
    <text>You’re a moron, I hope you one day realize this too</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43515319371.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>You just forgot birth certificates were a thing didn't you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510295917.0" user="bullzeye1983" delta="False">
    <text>Basically that citizens of the US decided this is the official adjective, agreed on it, and expect the rest of the world to follow suit, including other people in other countries of American continents. Which surprises noone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510638751.0" user="eggs-benedryl" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;expect the rest of the world to follow suit

and they overwhelmingly have</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511058157.0" user="Gaoji-jiugui888" delta="False">
    <text>That’s how it’s referred to in English. Same in Australia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510958720.0" user="MelissaMiranti" delta="False">
    <text>Because we're the only ones with the word in the name of our country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511205642.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>If they're speaking English, yes. If they're speaking Spanish, then it's fine to have the differentiation between *Americano* and *Estadounidense*. What is actually very arrogant is to say, "It works this way in my language. Therefore, it must be the same way in yours."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511447360.0" user="Disdain690" delta="False">
    <text>What language do you think we're speaking here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511514281.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>We're speaking English. And in English, *American* generally refers to someone from the United States. What makes this whole conversation weird is how people are like "Well in my country, it means..." If you're country isn't an English speaking country, we're technically not even talking about the same word because we're not even talking about the same language.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511274401.0" user="Orion113" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, no one is demanding anyone else in the world call us Americans. You won't be thrown in jail or even criticized for calling us whatever the hell you want. But just as we can't force you to call us Americans, you can't force us to stop calling ourselves that.

&amp;#x200B;

I've always felt this is such a weird hill to die on, especially considering that I have never once heard someone from outside the US say to anyone "I'm an American", unless someone from the US says it first. Like they need to smack us down for using it.

If the term "American" has only one meaning, which applies to the entirety of two vastly different continents, it's such an awkwardly unspecific term as to be useless. So nobody actually uses it that way. Every other country in the Americas has it's own name, so we use that. We use Latin American to specify someone is from the part of the Americas where Romance-derived cultures dominate. We use North American to say they are from North America, and South American to say they are from South America. None of these are ambiguous terms in the US, and none of them are intended to demean or belittle anyone from any part of the Americas.

&amp;#x200B;

On the other hand, there is practically no context where the word "American" with nothing in front of it is particularly useful. If we really must, we can simply say "people of the Americas", or "from the Americas". 

And there is no other potential demonym for people from the US that doesn't sound exceedingly awkward in English. USians. Statians. United Statians. USAians. United Statsians. 

And furthermore, doesn't that create the same problem? Mexico is officially "The United Mexican States". By using USians to refer only to people from the USA, aren't you also excluding everyone from the USM, who are also from a group of United States?

&amp;#x200B;

The US has done and continues to do a lot of fucked up imperialist shit in the world, particularly to its neighbors, but I'm sorry, that simply was not and is not the motivation behind calling ourselves Americans. Why would we make the word people use all the time to describe "someone from the United States" harder to say than the word people basically never use to describe "someone from one of two continents that happen to share a name".

And it seems to me that focusing on that little linguistic foible only distracts from the actual imperialism my country engages it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511985581.0" user="PMMEUR_3RD_BEST_NUDE" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine that. A country coming up with its own demonym and genuinely expecting people to use it. The fucking temerity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512110985.0" user="Warm-Belt7060" delta="False">
    <text>So what you propose?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510334784.0" user="pyrated" delta="False">
    <text>Even the UN officially recognizes American Samoa as American Samoa.

It's unambiguous what they mean by American in this sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511197310.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>In what English dialect does the word *American* not refer to somebody or something from the United States?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511214436.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Not an answer to my question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511258089.0" user="InscrutableScruple" delta="False">
    <text>It actually is if you understand how the English language works. English doesn't have a central governing authority that decides what is correct or incorrect. Instead it's all based off of common usage. Meaning that the "official" meaning of word in English is what it commonly means to English speakers. In the English language an American is somebody who is from the United States.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511291459.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Meaning that the "official" meaning of word in English is what it commonly means to English speakers.

No, it isn't, because that isn't what the word official means. Before saying others don't understand English maybe you should be more certain yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511927765.0" user="N3wPortReds" delta="False">
    <text>First definition in google provides the word's most common usage and a chart of how commonly used it is throughout the years. Look up American and find out. You should be more certain of yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43511806970.0" user="thomash363" delta="False">
    <text>Gee, I dunno, The Department of State? One google search.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512310059.0" user="Crowdcontrolz" delta="False">
    <text>Which one? There’s quite a few Departments of State.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513137862.0" user="Ihcend" delta="False">
    <text>the us gov, the un, most other countries referring to the us in English, and almost every person referring to the us in English.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516296797.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>It's the standard usage for American English (see [here](https://archive.org/details/columbiaguidetos00wils_0/page/26/mode/2up?view=theater)).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43516551784.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>And you think the Columbia guide to English is what gives a word or phrase official status?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43517905377.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say official, I said standard. "Official" was a poor choice of phrasing on the part of the previous poster, which is why I opted for standard instead. However, my more precise choice of phrasing does not materially change the argument made by the previous poster, which is still at its core correct. In standard English usage, the word "America" refers to the country, not the continent—_that_ is the core argument here. If you actually had a proper counterargument, you wouldn't out here nitpicking over word choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518129933.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>None of that makes sense in the context of this thread, which was me challenging OP on the part of their claim that it was "official".

It's effectively you saying I'm right but here's a counter argument to something I didn't say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518203007.0" user="cantankerousgnat" delta="False">
    <text>Either you're not understanding what I'm arguing here, or you're deliberately misunderstanding it. Either way, I'm not going to continue to engage in dialogue with someone arguing in bad faith. Have a good one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43518226365.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>I never argued in bad faith, I'm open to the possibility of there being a good reason to consider it as an official term.

That's what this thread is about, whether something is standard or not is a different argument and establishing something as standard does not support the claim that it's official.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
