<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="208" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43512552444.0" user="Evil-Doctor-sinewave" delta="False">
    <text>Lord id hope not. American people as a rule are mutts. Sure we can pretend we are white or black or Mexican or Hindu, fact is if you've been here in the states for over 1 generation chances are really good your a mixture of everything and thank God for that. The less reasons we have to separate ourselves from one another the better off every one in this world will be. I think Americans have just 1 thing that seperates us as a nation and that is we are made up of everything. If you come from India you start with a definition of religion or philosophy as who you are because there are so many people and your all the same colors. Just as Asian people often do (my apologies as most Americans can't see the difference between Japanese, Chinese, Korean not or south) because you are of the same look. I myself can tell them apart because I see the difference and have known enough of the to do so. If you say you're from Russia people assume you're white but that's a different kind of white then what Americans mean when we say White. Why I'm not entirely sure but if ever there was a white that's on the more pure side of things I imagine Russians would be that. 

American people are unique in the sense that if we say we're American it means we're mutts. We come from everyone else in the world. There's no religion or region specifics to us sure we can tell the difference in dialect, slang words, and accent, just as Asian people can or the shieites and Muslim people but America itself is huge. Very huge. The same size as the 100 different countrys in south America or Africa or Europe so saying our nationality is in itself saying our culture, our history, our way of life despite what it started as. Because it started as everyone else's at some time . Everyone except the people who actually lived here first. Which I might add is down to a whooping 2.9% of our citizens. Which is a sad thing as when they are gone so is the culture in which they have. That culture itself is was the one that our American political system was built from. Which is the way of life for this planet if we people are ever going to survive both each other as a planet and as the an ecosystem. My native American ancestors respected all life and ways of being , they respected the place in which they called home. Earth. And that alone as a world has been forgotten. 

But to say we are Americans means we come from everyone and we have no 1 culture other then that which we created ourselves. Through the pain of slavery, and genocide, through civil war and the fight to be considered equal no matter the color or gender or sexuality. What makes Americans Americans is the constant fight to be Free to be ourselves no matter what it takes and Americans are so passionate about this freedom that we have taken it upon ourselves to ensure everyone else in the world experiences freedom as well. So when people say they are Americans that exactly what they are. What else would you call us. Our culture as Americans is so powerful because of this freedom we have changed the entire worlds culture as a whole in every way because people the world over know what is right. Freedom is right. It is what gives people space to correct them selves to imagine, to express their power in every way. From business, to find arts, education and learn in unique ways because we Force ourselves to be patient and understanding even if we hate each other. It's a melting pot all change and growth is painful at first but we make it work. It's a work in progress. As perfection usually is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
