<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="93" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511553906.0" user="namecantbeblank1" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody speaking English in the US uses “America” to refer to both continents collectively and nobody has for a long time. I think the same usage prevails in Canada. You’d say “the Americas” if that’s what you meant. I understand it might not be the same in all places and languages but that’s the dialect. What everybody in the place calls the place is America. Is it dumb? Maybe. Do I care? No. I’m not any kind of a patriot, but this is one of those criticisms that’s always struck me as pedantic and willfully obtuse. There are plenty of good ways to criticize and/or mock this country without pretending you can’t understand context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513071346.0" user="wad11656" delta="False">
    <text>I believe part of what contributes to this is that in Latin America, they teach that there are 6 continents, with North and South America being a single one. And they have a word ("Americano") to refer to any of those continent dwellers. It's purely a language/culture thing. Who cares. But everyone decides *their* way is the objectively *correct* way. No; we are all correct, in relation to our native culture and language</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513233157.0" user="DDub04" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, in Spanish they use the term “Estadounidense”, which basically means “United Stater”. English does not have an equivalent widely used word, so Estadounidense becomes American and Americano becomes North/South/Latin American.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
