<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="99" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511605397.0" user="RubricLivesMatter" delta="False">
    <text>Ive only met Argentinians who took issue with it...not a single other person in any other country in the Americas has ever cared.  It is not only a proper name because we are from America (specifically a state, within a country residing in North America) but most importantly because the name of said country is United States of America. 

Anyone from the Americas can call themselves American if they want others to be confused and if they have no pride in their own country. As for me, if you are born in the USA you are absolutely an American and then you can call yourself a state-ian. A.k.a. Ohian, new Jersian, etc. But that's less likely to mean anything to anyone other than a fellow American Anyway</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513318159.0" user="notapersonplacething" delta="False">
    <text>Ding, ding, ding.   


I've only ever heard this from Argentinians that have chip on their shoulder who think they are recently displaced europeans who happen to live in south america. There is a fair bit of anti-american, and for that matter, anti-semitic sentiment down there. "Yankee go home" but everyone is buying US dollars. Side note, it goes without saying that not all or most Argentinians are like that but there is enough of an anti-american zeitgeist down there that it is palpable.  


So....I guess if you are harming anyone you are harming Argentinians with a chip on their shoulder and if you want a suggestion for alternative I suppose we could go with turtle islanders which would make a really cool jersey if you asked me.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
