<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="62" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43511278471.0" user="zebrasmack" delta="False">
    <text>It's because it's the country's name. 

It's not like people from Canada are saying they're American. Some people say "the states" when talking about the nation, but you're not a statean, you're an american. you're not a united states of american, you're an american. 

Plus, you never hear anyone say "i'm from the dominion of Canada", they just say "i'm from Canada". We say "american". 

They're just misunderstanding and being pompous about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512830401.0" user="SHOW_ME_YOUR_KlTTlES" delta="False">
    <text>You give no reason other than, just because.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43512903319.0" user="zebrasmack" delta="False">
    <text>my first sentence is a solid reason, though? I mean, if you want to complain about the country's name, sure. but it's not like the people of the united states of america are known as americans without reason. It's following the same pattern nearly all other countries do. 

My point was there's no real alternatives, and "american" is the legal name chosen by the government. It's like...a whole stack of reasons? I'm not sure what points are unclear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513138160.0" user="fauxpolitik" delta="False">
    <text>Canada has not been a dominion since 1982, there is no long name for Canada. It’s just “Canada”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513177228.0" user="zebrasmack" delta="False">
    <text>That does explain the maps I have. I thought they had just gotten lazy. Thanks for the update, it's appreciated!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513307989.0" user="JackfruitFancy1373" delta="False">
    <text>Canadá is not a dominion but is still officially “the dominion of Canada” in name only.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513382078.0" user="fauxpolitik" delta="False">
    <text>I’m aware Canada has a very strange constitution but what document are you referring to when you say that this is the official name? As far as I know the act which turned Canada from a dominion to a fully independent country just refers to the country as “Canada” with no long name</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43513868477.0" user="Mysterious_Spell_302" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, would we call Canada "the Provinces"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43514413197.0" user="weedbeads" delta="False">
    <text>I think the suggested replacement is "US Citizen"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43552993455.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
