<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560940175.0" index="295" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16cpu33/cmv_there_is_nothing_wrong_with_a_citizen_of_the/">
    <title>cmv: There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as an “American”</title>
    <original_poster>thomash363</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is nothing wrong with a citizen of the United States of America referring to themselves as “American”.

When I was studying abroad in Germany my professor and many of my European classmates took issue with me referring to myself as an American, citing imperialism and disrespecting other people from the Americas. I fail to see how this is the case. American is the official adjective for a citizen of the USA, and consensus reinforces that fact. 

If someone were to change my view, they would have to show how using the term American harms other people from the Americas in a meaningful way, and also suggest an alternative, as there needs so be some adjective.

I look forward to discussing with you all, thanks!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43513498936.0" user="I_Seek_Understanding" delta="False">
    <text>***How does it harm others?*** The key issue (that seems to be overlooked by most commenters) is whether you are using terminology that implies that non U.S. Americans are not American.  


If your use of "I'm American" really means "I'm from one of the American continents", then no-one would have an issue. But **if you are implying** ***(consciously or unconsciously)*** **through the language you use, that non-U.S. Americans aren't American, then it's understandable that some non-U.S. Americans might take offence.**  


If you wouldn't want other people implying that you aren't American, then maybe others who are born in (non-USA) America, might feel the same way?  


*(Whether it's practical to change terminology now  that is so strongly embedded in people's consciousness and usage is a very important, but a separate question to whether the current usage  is appropriate and problematic.)*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
