<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="41" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43524225715.0" user="balcon" delta="False">
    <text>The illusion of choices exist, but not in a vacuum. Every decision point is the sum of factors leading to it. Those factors can be biological and out of your control. They can be circumstances that are imposed on you or thing that happen to you seemingly randomly. It does’t matter.

I am not a philosopher, so I don’t have the knowledge to make an argument using the jargon of logic and all that.

What has gotten me thinking about decisions and the illusion of free will, before coming across your post, is an elderly relative who contracted a UTI. All of the sudden, he began acting erratically and irrationally. Choices he was making were heavily influenced by this new biological factor - the UTI. The UTI was mixed in with all of the biological processes that happen in his body to keep him alive. 

The food we eat can affect what choices are before us. Spending the money to buy the food was a choice that arose from knowledge about nutrition (or lack thereof) and the means to acquire the money. The means to acquire the money and attitudes about money are affected by generational wealth.

Writing this out makes me realize that this is a difficult view to change because someone can come to the table with assumptions. These assumptions are cosmic truths in their mind. Dogma, if you will. People can take a single sentence from this post (quibbling with generational wealth, for instance) and use that to bolster a belief in the superiority of libertarian ideas of the will to power. 

But aren’t all of those things - dogma, etc. - part of the illusion of free will? Even the concept of “being right” is itself a construct of society. The value of fulfilling the requirements of being right contributes to more favorable conditions (for some people) for humans to endure as a species.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
