<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521714514.0" user="Holyfrickingcrap" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;it's illogical to not believe in free will

Being logical is logical. There is absolutely nothing logical about free will. Determining your beliefs on a feeling of correctness isn't logical. 

&gt;So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Sure

&gt;Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice

No, it still makes more sense to believe in things that make more sense. If your brain decides to 

&gt;if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.

Personally even if free will was true I would argue there's more value in believing in determinism. Free will is the default state, what you get when you take reality for granted. Determinism is what you get when you actually look at the laws of physics and use those laws to form an informed belief.

I can explain perfectly how determinism works whether that explanation is accurate or not, but no proponent of true free will can even come close to providing a logical explanation to the inner workings. 

Your math teacher asked you to show your work because there is no value in simply asking a calculator. There is no value in believing something because it feels good to be right. There is lots of value in believing something because it is the most logical explanation you can come up with, even if your wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521759001.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Did you believe in it because it was logical or because it was the only choice you had? I don’t think the laws of physics apply to human actions. Physics can give a deterministic explanation of non conscious objects (except quantum stuff but that is probabilistic not free will), but physics cannot explain consciousness. There is no reason for consciousness to exist in a deterministic universe. A brain that doesn’t produce consciousness and a brain that does will still have the same neurons fire, meaning all the same actions would occur, so why would consciousness exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522055215.0" user="Holyfrickingcrap" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Did you believe in it because it was logical or because it was the only choice you had?

Both, my brain can't believe in something it finds illogical. Much like I assume you can't make your self believe that jumping up in the air means you will float away. Believing you will fall back down is the only choice you have.

&gt;I don’t think the laws of physics apply to human actions.

That's an extremely major claim to make with no actual evidence.

&gt;but physics cannot explain consciousness.

On the contrary, while our limited knowledge of physics leaves us without a complete understanding of consciousness, physics still explains your "choices" extremely well. That's why all the top psychologists debate whether nature or nuture play a bigger role in who you turn out to be. Not whether nature, nurture, or the choices you make do. Every action you have ever taken can be explained pretty well by looking at previous events and brain chemistry. 

We may not know all about how it works, but it looks a hell of a lot like it works pretty similarly to how everything else in the universe works. 

&gt;A brain that doesn’t produce consciousness and a brain that does will still have the same neurons fire, meaning all the same actions would occur, so why would consciousness exist?

I'm not sure how you came to this conclusion. If all the same neurons are going off then either both entities are conscious or they aren't. Unless you believe that your consciousness comes from somewhere other then your brain. Which would be another major claim with no backing evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522078888.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>Consciousness is a label for the physical processes and patterns of neural activity that create our subjective experience.

There isn't a need to treat "consciousness" as a special characteristic or unique part of our being. It is just a word we use to describe what we think of as "self-awareness" and subjective thoughts. All of these can more easily be explained by physical responses to external stimuli.

The entity (us), our bodies... Respond to external stimuli, neither of which "we" control. Those external stimuli create physical changes in the entity. Those physical changes lead to potential changes in physical responses to stimuli. Even "thoughts" and memory are physical processes in the brain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522087682.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so why am I conscious? You can’t just say consciousness is physical, it’s Cleary not. Wtf is the feeling of colour, smell, rough outside our subjective experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522121367.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand what you mean. Communication has a clear evolutionary development. Words and language are part of that. We assign labels to things. Consciousness is just a label.

"Feelings" are physical responses to stimuli through the nervous system and its various processes. Color processing and recognition - can be entirely explained through physiological processes.

The same is true for your other examples. Memory can be explained and manipulated through purely physiological means. Association between "blue" and what you think of as blue can be manipulated purely physiologically. (Neuroscience has made tremendous strides in showing how memories physically form and can be even artificially created).

Consciousness isn't even a good label, as it doesn't have a clear definition at all and one I haven't seen you attempt to provide.

What are Experiences? Memories? The ability for specific neural patterns to fire in a specific way within the brain?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522160190.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine a world where there was no consciousness. Would anything be different? Neurons would still fire the same, all actions would still be the same. So consciousness, if an emergent property of material, is absolutely pointless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522186126.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>If (it is) consciousness, which you haven't attempted to define, is a result of those neurons... not having it would, by default, mean they don't fire the same way.

Do you really believe there are aspects of "consciousness" that can not be shown through physical tests of physiological parts of humans?

What are those parts? Thinking? Internal monolog? Memory and recall?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522470679.0" user="Wjyosn" delta="False">
    <text>Here you are making a huge assertion without evidence. There is absolutely no reason to believe that a world in which there was not consciousness would still have neurons at all let alone neurons firing the same way. This is a wild and baseless assumption that you were making solely for the point of being able to claim correctness based on knowledge that you made up. 

If neurons fire the same way, consciousness follows. Consciousness is derivative of our physical state. If there were no consciousness then it is a given that our physical state would be different. The world would not function the same way neurons would not fire the same way and nothing would be the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522224552.0" user="AceOfShades_" delta="False">
    <text>Because you have neurological activity going on. Sensations are from nerves sending signals to your brain and the brain processing it.

Even your ability to think about the fact that you are feeling things is brain activity, involving areas in the prefrontal cortex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522665136.0" user="ranni-" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I don’t think the laws of physics apply to human actions

uhhh, how do they not..?

&gt;so why would consciousness exist?

what's the "reason" it has to exist? is the whole crux of your argument that you believe in a metaphysical reality?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
