<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521772330.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>Name one thing you did without the involvement of another person? ill tell you right now you cant to me this would disprove the idea of freewill on the individual level you never have total control over everything therefore you never have free will and on another note a human baby wont even develop without the input of other humans therefore what you are is always an amalgamation of others before you therefore you never have full control over it therefore no free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521806440.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Free will just means the ability to make more than one choice. It doesn’t mean I have to be completely self sufficient and basically God.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521865246.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>i mean i guess we are looking at it different sure you have the choice to put the ketchup on your fries but my point is that the amount of free will you have is really limited other then simple things your choices are always influenced by other things that you had no control over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521880286.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, I think people don’t appreciate how free they are. Once I started remembering the gift of freedom everyday, I started taking life into my own hands and doing what I wanted to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521975671.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>there are enough choices that to the human mind simulates the idea of free will but in reality its a bunch of predetermined options that can be put together a certain amount of ways. Take music for example we like to think that its unlimited but in reality we can only hear certain frequencies and we also enjoy a finite spectrum of beats frequencies in an even more limited scope. All these things are predetermined and actually create a limited number of combinations that to the human mind seem infinite but are actually a limited scope of what is truly infinite. A project was even done to simulate all these combinations in a computer and patent them all so that nobody could lay claim to any of these combinations again its a massive number but it is in no way infinite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521985434.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Again, why do we need infinite choices?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522010129.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>because im saying in our limited scope we are being influenced by other factors every choice is influenced by something you dont just randomly decide to do it you decide it out of some necessity therefore that would not fit the definition of free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522029106.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t randomly decide, I simply decide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522048490.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>yes im saying that decision is not actually of your own volition it may seem that way but in reality its not its a trick. listen im not saying looking at the world as i am explaining it is better im just pointing out that reality is not the same as our perception.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522079594.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Well then I guess I’m determined to think I’m free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522131595.0" user="probono105" delta="False">
    <text>and as i said to our feeble minds we basically are</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
