<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43522502334.0" user="Wjyosn" delta="False">
    <text>Most of your arguments are essentially the same as arguments for creationism. Much like Pascal's wager you are effectively saying it would be nicer if I were right therefore it is more logical to believe I am right. But this has the same problem that Pascal's wager does, it ignores the infinite other possible outcomes. You're not choosing just whether to believe or not believe, you're choosing one belief from an infinite number of possible beliefs and choosing not to believe an infinite number in the process. It would be nice to believe we are all controlled by a benevolent creator. It would also be nice to believe we are all in a simulation for different reasons. Accepting one of these but not the other is illogical, but they are mutually exclusive therefore this logic chain does not produce a logical outcome.

Many of your arguments are effectively saying that there is an external existence beyond the physical universe that is capable of creating a causal chain of events. The only way this is possible is if there exists something outside of the physical universe that can influence it. Given that such an existence is tautologically unprovable, it is a useless conjecture. I can make any claim I want about unprovable sources of will and they all have the same merit as your perceived free will. "We are actually all one big extra dimensional soul that actually controls all bodies simultaneously and is not individualized" is exactly as accurate as your assertion, with exactly the same amount of evidence available, zero. There are an infinite number of concepts that we can make up and justify with reasons to believe that they are nice, but without any existing evidence there is no logical way to conclude they are correct.

The only logical conclusion is that free will does not exist, because all evidence available points in that direction. It is possible it is an incorrect conclusion, but that's true about all of science. We accept the models that most closely represent our observed reality until and unless we develop a model based on evidence that more accurately represents observed reality, and in this case that means deterministic lack of free will.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
