<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521628318.0" user="forgottenarrow" delta="False">
    <text>What is free will? And why do you believe that our decisions lack moral weight in a purely predetermined universe?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521671771.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>The ability for an agent to start a causal chain influenced but not controlled by previous factors.

Yes I believe decisions lack moral weight in a predetermined universe. I don’t get how you can blame someone for raping someone if they’re basically a machine who does what it was programmed to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521684089.0" user="forgottenarrow" delta="False">
    <text>One last set of questions. Do you believe in a higher power or any notion of an afterlife where we are judged based on our actions? If not, what is the basis of morality in your opinion? Why be a good person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521699281.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I am a deist so I believe in God. I hope there is an positive afterlife but I don’t have anything to back that up that’s just a hope thing. I believe it is rational to be good, being good is how humans have evolved to have the highest level of satisfaction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521755581.0" user="forgottenarrow" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that free will or not, we possess the illusion of free will. Even if free will doesn’t exist, we are not fully aware of all factors controlling our actions. We can only detect causal factors influencing our decisions, so we effectively have free will.

In this context, we can make decisions and the question of whether or not our decisions are controlled by other causal factors is immaterial. 

Lastly, you outlined a pretty good reason to act morally. We need to be good in order to operate as a social species, and as an individual acting with kindness is often rewarded in many subtle ways. This is a strong reason to act good whether or not we have free will.

So, it is perfectly valid to believe in determinism because even in a deterministic world we at least have the illusion of choice, and there is a strong rational reason to make the moral choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521789448.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I still don’t get it. If I believed in determinism and took it to its logical implications, I’d not have a choice to act morally. Id simply be a robot that is predestined to do what it is meant to do. I don’t get how people can believe in this and not feel some sense of nihilism. People say it still feels like you have free will, but the whole concept of self goes out the window without free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522042529.0" user="forgottenarrow" delta="False">
    <text>I’m getting tired and finding it impossible to get my thoughts out in a clear manner. I rewrote this comment almost a dozen times, but can’t quite get it right. I hope this makes sense to you.

I think the key point is the illusion of free will. If we don’t have free will, then whatever is controlling us maintains a type of consistency and subtlety that leaves us unable to detect the causes of our actions. It goes out of its way to make us feel free.

In my opinion this means I can live my life as if I had free will. And I can do it in either a deterministic or free universe. This also means I can believe what I believe and still believe that I am making choices that matter. They don’t matter because some God says so, but because they impact myself and the people around me. The consequences of my choices give them meaning.

In addition, I tend to believe more in determinism simply because I cannot fathom free will. You claim that free will is the ability to start a chain of events having been influenced by some causal factors but not controlled by them. This just sounds like a random algorithm to me. Why would there be more meaning in me randomly doing the right thing than me doing the right thing because the laws of physics, the chemistry of my brain and other factors all resulted in me making the “decision” to do the right thing? You’re just replacing some unobserved deterministic process with randomness, but I’m still a machine either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522075534.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t see it as random. I see it as just me deciding what to do. My decisions aren’t random but they’re decided by me. 

Illusion of free will just doesn’t cut it for me, I believed in determinism for a bit but it was just so depressing. Why did I want anything? Was I good because I chose to or because I am? I just couldn’t live like that. I tried just saying, pretend my life is a movie or just accept the illusion but there was a clear cognitive dissonance that plagued me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522229565.0" user="forgottenarrow" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t fathom that at all. What are you? You clearly respond to stimuli in a predictable manner. You have likes and dislikes, you have a personality and a personal moral code. But, if some mad scientist stuck a rod inside your brain in just the right way, your personality would change. Your likes, dislikes and the very way you interact with the world would change. How is that not like a machine? Would that still be you? Heck, even your gut microbiome can influence your emotions. If brain modification would make you a different person then aren’t you a different person than you were yesterday? 

Humans often behave irrationally, but we do so in a very predictable way. Especially when we are in large groups. This is exactly what I would expect if we were AI running on random algorithms. Randomness tends to gain structure in aggregate.

I guess the core of what I’m getting at is what is the “you” that operates on free will. What part of you makes those decisions that go beyond the countless factors influencing you? 

I fully reject the notion that the meaning of my life is dictated by anyone else. That holds true even if I am a puppet or (more likely) an AI running software with my brain and body as my hardware, all my actions determined by the laws of physics plus some randomness that operates external to myself. 

I’m not saying to pretend your life is like a movie. I think it’s more that I find deriving meaning from a world that will never be observable to be a pointless exercise.

Why do you want anything? Try introspecting and you’ll find plenty of reasons. Why are you a good person? Look back at your life and see how you were raised, what you experienced, what you feel now. There are millions of reasons beyond the actions of some creepy stalker of a God, and understanding those reasons will help you understand yourself in a way that brushing it all away never could.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521778804.0" user="forgottenarrow" delta="False">
    <text>Adding to my other comment, the illusion of choice is precisely what gives us moral weight in a determined universe. Those unobserved causal factors that control our actions are essentially our soul. So it makes perfect sense to hold a criminal responsible for their actions even in a determined universe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521730239.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>What is the determination between influenced and controlled?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521737361.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Influenced means you can account for it. I can account for me previous experience that a stove is hot so I wouldn’t like to touch it. Still that factor isn’t 100% controlling me to not touch the stove it is only an influence to my decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521771546.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>Why wouldn’t you like to touch it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521808376.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I chose not to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521983824.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>But why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521994728.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Because I chose to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522006771.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a tautology</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522025842.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe there can be something that is causeless? Or do you believe in infinite regress? Or both?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522036599.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Do you believe there can be something that is causeless?

Probably. Maybe to the other one as well. Feels like a non-sequiter though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522055767.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Then what’s wrong with an agents decision being caused by the agent with no further explanation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522110685.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>I ask you “why you wouldn’t like to touch it [a hot stove]” after you said “I can account for my previous experience that a stove is hot so I wouldn’t like to touch it.” Your response was “because I chose to”. Clearly your choice was based on something beyond the choice alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522118252.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>As I said, previous experience influenced it but  didn’t cause it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522225509.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>And now we’re back to qualifying. Where is the line between control and influence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522682825.0" user="ranni-" delta="False">
    <text>after a certain point - and that point is well before the existence of earth or humanity - there is nothing that is causeless, yes. i don't have to explain the beginning of all cosmology to know that all events we experience necessarily have precursors and consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523875473.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>If we some day have human-like robots, androids, with machine brains, it would still make sense to *punish* them for undesired actions and reward them for desired actions, to influence their decision algorithms. If we know that they have the goal to consume batteries, it would also make sense to *threaten* them with less batteries when they do something undesirable. If a robot accidentally hurts a human, they wouldn't need to be punished or retrained.

If humans are already biological machines, there would be no reason to stop punishing or threatening them.

I believe the desire to punish criminals is an evolutionary benefit. Populations that didn't punish egoistical behavior were less successful than those who did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523891089.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Yes it would still be pragmatic to punish evil for the sake of deterrence or security. But I’d have no reason to think a rapist has committed a moral fault, because he literally couldn’t have done otherwise. Also, punishing evil is determined as well. It’s hard to say it makes sense to do anything if it’s all determined, because how are you gonna change anything if you can’t make a choice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523942382.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>A rapist has to be separated from society, so he can't rape people anymore. It also helps to discourage other people who consider raping someone. Ideally rapists and all other people have to be educated about how harmful it is.

If a machine is broken, it makes sense to fix it. If it's determined to break, then it breaks and if it's determined to be fixed afterwards, then it's determined to be fixed again. It's not rational to fix humans because they are free but not machines, because they are unfree.

&gt; Also, punishing evil is determined as well. It’s hard to say it makes sense to do anything if it’s all determined, because how are you gonna change anything if you can’t make a choice?

Well yes! I replied to a similar concern somewhere else, with the athlete who trains very hard, because he thinks he is destined to win. Believing in determinism doesn't mean that you necessarily have to do any particular thing. I don't know if I have phrased that as well as I could.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
