<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521528970.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>You aren't arguing based. on truth, you are arguing based on some abstract concept of "the value of being right". 

The idea that our choices aren't the result of prior events and maybe random chance is just does not make any sense. What is "libertarian free will" if it is not the sum of the effects of a bunch of pre-determined factors? Because if it isn't, you are just describing random chance - how is that in anyway meaningful?

Like "You have free will - it is completely divorced from reality, your lived experiences and logical cause and effect" why is that in anyway meaningful. Even if the soul does it exist, if would have some sort of cause-and-effect, otherwise you are just describing randomness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521611186.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Not necessarily, it wouldn’t be random, and it wouldn’t be absolutely predetermined. Previous actions can come to influence a decision but an agent can still decide against it. An agent doesn’t select randomly. The cause of an action is simply that the agent decided it with the no further explanation since it is the originator of the causal chain. If there was a further explanation it wouldn’t be free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521743773.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>When you say "the agent can still decide against their own past actions" does the agent always do so in the same way (ie. a factor the agent can't control)? Or does it change over time? And when it changes over time is it explainable by what happens to the agent? (factors the agent can't control) or is it unexplainable by what happens to the agent (randomness)? 

I choose to hold open the door for someone carrying a heavy box -  Per you:  I am an agent who doesn't select randomly, and previous actions don't 100% dictate my actions. So why did I hold open the door? How did I come to that decision? am I intrinsically kind? Was I taught to do that? Both of these explanations are factors I do not have a control over. 

&gt;If there was a further explanation it wouldn’t be free will.

There are actually further explanations of why "agents" decide things, which is why "libertarian free will" doesn't make sense

You are basically saying "Human actions are not caused by nature or nurture, but a secret third thing, that is totally not randomness, but is also completely inexplicable, but is somehow a factor we have control over". It just simply doesn't make any sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521765653.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I’m saying that agents start a causal chain, the reason why the agent did something is just because the agent chose to do it. No further explanation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521947837.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>When you say “no further explanation” that’s you choosing to stop looking. There are actually explanations, you just don’t want there to be.

When an agent makes a choice - why did they chose that way? There are either reasons, or it is random. 

What you want is cause-less effect that isn’t random, but that just isn’t how reality works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521981439.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Why are the only options randomness or an infinite causal chain? Why can’t new causal chains arise? An agent isn’t a physical thing so it doesn’t need to follow physical cause and effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522046518.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>How does this new causal chain not fall under the category of “things outside of human control”? Do I choose the agent? Do I choose the choice? Or does it just happen to me? 
And why does the “agent” make that particular choice, why not another choice? If agents are making choices without a cause, that is randomness!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522076745.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>You are the agent</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522114546.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. And as an agent when I make choices?, do I always decide on the same type of thing , does it depend on the situation, or does it vary unpredictably?
For example, am I always kind, only kind to people when I’m in a good mood, or is it impossible to guess before hand whether I will be kind or not?
Why do I choose one option and not another ? You appear to say “just cause”, but really that means it is random.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522121607.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>You do what you choose</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522065174.0" user="zigfoyer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; An agent isn’t a physical thing so it doesn’t need to follow physical cause and effect.

Give an example of any measurable phenomena that has been demonstrated not to follow rules of cause and effect. Otherwise you're just arguing for a soul and giving it a different name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522099397.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Quantum shit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522124943.0" user="Jakyland" delta="False">
    <text>That is called randomness, and isn’t philosophically meaningful. “Oh why are you so generous/reckless etc etc?” “Oh, quantum shit”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522151650.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Didn’t say the agent chooses based on quantum shit. You just wanted an example of a causeless thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523454767.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct that not everything is determined.

The point is that Jakyland (and I) can't comprehend a third option besides determined and random.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523838585.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>The third option is called agent causation, if you search it up there’s some websites talking about it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524014098.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524980131.0" user="zigfoyer" delta="False">
    <text>Quantum shit isn't causeless. It's not yet fully understood, but they can build devices that manipulate the phenomena, therefore it's deterministic. 

It's clear throughout this thread that you're just proselytizing, that you're not capable or interested in any real conversation. But that's fine because that's what you were determined to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523488900.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>Even if you assume a soul, you have to ask how it works. Is it deterministic or random or something else?

FYI: René Descartes believed in the soul and he had a mail exchange with the princess of Bohemia on how the body can interact with the soul. [text](https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/elisabeth-bohemia/#MBInterMind) [video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kJIZzmUpfmk&amp;pp=ygURZGVzY2F0ZXMgcHJpbmNlc3M%3D)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522302706.0" user="AceOfShades_" delta="False">
    <text>If I’m watching a movie where the main character “just decided” to go on vacation, does the character have free will?

From their perspective, they decided to do something with no further explanation. No cause, just effect.

But from my perspective, the whole thing from start to finish is already on tape. The causes, decision, and outcome are all already present on tape, no matter how real they may feel to the character in any particular frame of animation. So it was all destined to happen exactly as it did, so do they have free will there?

That last bit is extremely analogous to real life time, by the way. But also in real life, “just decided” is determined by the way your life up to that point molded your brain. 

The will to do things randomly, or go against your beliefs on purpose, is even usually a response to emotions and thoughts, built from memories and learnings from the past.

Just because you don’t look for a cause, or struggle to find one, doesn’t mean there aren’t causes for actions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
