<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521548485.0" user="kev231998" delta="False">
    <text>Basically you're using the logic of pascal wager but for believing in free will? Either you're right or it doesn't matter.

The part that seems a bit weak to me is the link you draw between the capability to be right and being logical. Mostly because you say there's no value in being right if there's no free will but aren't clear on "value". 

No philosophical value because it's predetermined? If so why does that make it the less logical option?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521653612.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Believing in free will has its own value. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5209362/#:~:text=Free%20will%20is%20not%20only,large%20samples%20of%20Chinese%20adolescents.  

Free will is not only an abstract concept for philosophers; it also plays a vital role in laypersons’ daily life. In the present study, we found that a stronger belief in free will was associated with increased life satisfaction and PA in two independent large samples of Chinese adolescents.

Belief in free will has benefits but it may create cognitive dissonance just to believe in something for its pragmatic value. But when we get to the action of believing, we can either think of it as an action we can choose or something out of our control. If we think of it as free, we are either right and thus we were free to choose it, or we are wrong and in that case there was no other way to believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522053226.0" user="zigfoyer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Believing in free will has its own value.

This is a deterministic argument. Claiming that mind state leads to happiness is arguing that our thoughts and emotions are in fact driven by precursors. You're just also claiming that it's sometimes not true, and the cases where it's not true are at your discretion to decide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522073163.0" user="Captain_Clover" delta="False">
    <text>By identifying and analysing the contributing factors to own decisions, we are able to learn things about ourselves and correct for undesired behaviour caused by certain stimulus. If you've ever thought 'why did I do that?', you implicitly agree there are reasons that you do things. Someone who believes in 'libertarian free will' must view decision making as an abstract exercise where evidence and emotion is measured and weighed, whereas realists understand that our body and mind work together to make many decisions indecently of the conscious, and many of our true motivations are clouded from us by internal mists and misdirection. Analysing them and bringing them into the light through a framework of cause-effect thinking is the best way to correct your own mental biases; the biggest benefit in my opinion of seeing free will as it truly is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523289564.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I also find it useful to understand the motivations behind other people's actions. If someone steals a loaf of bread, we can punish them because stealing is illegal. But that doesn't really solve the problem, does it? Did they steal it because they have no food? Are a lot of people stealing food in a specific area? Maybe that's a good place to build a food bank or homeless shelter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523304820.0" user="Captain_Clover" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. I think it's the truth behind the question of good and evil and is the most just principle to base a system of justice around</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523317920.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and we see aspects of this in our justice system as well. Pre-meditated murder is worse than murdering someone because you got angry. Why? Because we understand that humans are animals who sometimes experience strong emotions that we have trouble controlling. When somebody kills another person not because of emotion but because they actually enjoy killing, that is a different pattern and we see that this person is likely to kill again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522371872.0" user="ThisIsDrLeoSpaceman" delta="False">
    <text>Your title is that it’s “illogical” not to believe in free will. The only argument you’ve been making so far is that it’s *not beneficial* not to believe in free will. Do you understand the difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523276734.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>China is an interesting place because the government has a huge amount of control over the population. People don't have significant freedom of speech, association, information, etc. Isn't there a system now where if your neighbors snitch on you enough, you can't leave the country? Didn't people get quarantined for months on end in some places?

I wonder if the results would be the same in a country where people have more freedom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524497799.0" user="BonelessB0nes" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but even if we grant that the belief increases life satisfaction, that doesn't relate to it's actual truth. You implied in your OP that the value jugement was associated with "being right" depending on the truth of the matter, one way or the other. 

This article shows a psychological benefit of the belief. We could probably broadly agree that this is valuable in some way, but it seems you are using 'value' differently here. Before, it was valuable to live in a universe that had freewill, while also correctly arriving at this conclusion. Now, it's simply valuable to believe something that's helpful regardless of if it is true. Sure, but so is believing the sugar pill is anxeity medication...you may psychologically benefit from your belief, but that doesn't get you any closer to believing a true thing.

This article says nothing about whether or not freewill is actually true. So, in the framework of your argument, which is it? Are we using 'value' to talk about things that are helpful, or are we using it to talk about some inherent value in coming to true beliefs. Because if it's just things that are helpful, sure I could grant that a belief in freewill may be helpful for lots of people; but it certainly doesn't follow from that that it is a true thing. The whole thing falls apart if it's only what's psychologically helpful to people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43539785119.0" user="kev231998" delta="False">
    <text>Belief in religion also improves life: https://www.forbes.com/sites/nicolefisher/2019/03/29/science-says-religion-is-good-for-your-health/?sh=6af12b613a12

Pretty obvious conclusion to come to because belief in something bigger than oneself (the power of free will and/or religion) gives the psyche comfort. 

You could probably find a similar correlation between strong beliefs in many things true or not. That doesn't really make it any more logical in my opinion. I would argue no value either especially since even the belief in things that are fundamentally untrue could lead to health benefits (placebo effect).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
