<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521688346.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>Is it better to believe what is true, or to believe what is almost certainty false for the slightest chance of being right due to a choice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521719522.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>It is better to have the ability to make the choice in the first place. What is better is pointless in determinism since there is only one path. It’s like driving down a one lane road and thinking if it would be better to change lanes, there is no other lane.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521874081.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>That is a cop out.

The fact that having a choice is better doesn’t tell us whether or not believing that we do is as well. 

It is a fallacy to say that it X is better, believing X is better than believing not X.

If “better” is pointless under determinism, let me ask you this: 

Let’s assume for a second that determinism is true. Under that assumption, I give you two options: 

1. I give you $1 million, no strings attached 

2. I throw you into a fire and you will burn to death. 

Does supposing that determinism is true cause to stop giving a shit which one it will be? Do your preferences magically evaporate? 

Clearly no. You want the $1 million, not to burn to death.

That proves that better, as a subjective concept, exists whether determinism is true or not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521896529.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>What’s your point? If determinism is true I’d do what aligns with my preferences which were caused by factors out of my control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521925951.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that the “better” factor doesn’t go away under determinism, so you cannot attribute “betterness” as a unique characteristic to believing true things by choice, but not by lack of choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521961154.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>How are things better? Better is a relative term when comparing two things. If there is, by definition, only one choice, there is no better choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522006756.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>Let’s assume determinism is true. 

I do not ultimately have a choice whether I believe in free will or not. However, which is preferable, a deterministic outcome in which I believe in determinism, or on in which I do not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522018140.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>If we assume determinism is true then neither is preferable, there’s no agent to chose what is preferable. Your just a machine running its code.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522029059.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>We just established that preferences don’t go away because determinism is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522050265.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>True, I guess you’d follow your preferences. I couldn’t say which one is preferable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522054843.0" user="libertysailor" delta="False">
    <text>By definition, what is preferable is that which one would rather be the case, no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522112902.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522062937.0" user="Any-Try-8293" delta="False">
    <text>...because you would rather take the money than burn in the fire.

There is only one choice because you are going to do that.

That's the whole point.

You choose it because its better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522102159.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>How would I choose it if it’s my only choice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523807538.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good question. How does a determinist distinguish between chosen actions and unchosen actions?

I'd call an action chosen if it has something to do with my goals. If I'm hungry and I eat an apple, that is both determined and a choice. If I'm not hungry and someone force-feeds me, that would not be a choice. If I'm asked to think of a random card for a magic trick, I'd say the card is actually determined by a subconscious part of my brain, but you can still make a meaningful distinction on whether my brain comes up with the number or whether I'm a secret accomplice of the magician and he has told me which card to say.

Maybe you could say that a choice is free from *certain* influences. Nothing is free from any influences, but depending on the context if might be implicitly clear which influences can be ignored. We also colloquially say buildings are stable, even though no building is absolutely stable. You can just infer from the context how stable the building actually is.

When a robber says they were forced to commit a crime, because they watched Scrooge McDuck as a kid and therefore wanted to be rich, that is not seen as a valid defense in court, because some causes of a crime are implicitly ignored for the purposes of establishing guilt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524903724.0" user="Any-Try-8293" delta="False">
    <text>You have two choices.

You are just always going to take the better one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523861166.0" user="randomguywithmemes" delta="False">
    <text>You already do</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
