<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="31" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43522886203.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>It would probably make sense for you to define free will. For me, free will is “the ability to have done otherwise”. So if you take a given choice say vanilla not chocolate and then rewind the universe infinite times resetting all conditions as they were, would I ever choose chocolate?

If the answer is yes then I have free will, even if the probability is tiny and if no then I don’t.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523099636.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>My definition is slightly different. I believe that free will is defined by an agent’s actions being caused through agent-causation, where it isn’t deterministic but also isn’t random. The explanation of why an agent did something is that he chose it full stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523173010.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Right so in other words an agent has some sort of ability to choose differently, even in identical starting conditions, right down to the last sub atomic particle, they can still somehow make a different choice. That seems like the same definition as I have, or maybe you can explain how it’s different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523177685.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>It’s basically the same, only thing that’s different is that I don’t think it’s random. It isn’t a dice roll of what you choose, it’s just your choice through agent-causation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523224396.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>That’s fair, but to be clear my definition didn’t presume randomness, just the ability for another choice to be made, which could be random or non random, so I think we agree :)

So the next question is, do you have some proposed mechanism which would allow the agent to choose? If all (currently) known matter and energy is reset to starting conditions then are you proposing some sort of naturalistic particle that resists this reset and enables agents a free choice? Or are you proposing some sort of non naturalistic mechanism akin to a soul?

The next question for me is how you’d test your hypothesis. Clearly we’re not able to reset the universe endlessly to see whether agents make different choices so do you have an experiment in mind that would test this?

I would argue that if you can neither propose a mechanism by which free will as defined could work nor an experiment to test it, then the logical thing would be to disbelieve in free will (different than believing it doesn’t exist).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523825369.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I think there’s is a soul or mind which enables the agent to make choices. Currently I have no way to test it, but neither does determinism, in the case of double unfalsifiability, I think it’s better to follow my intuition. Also I just simply think it’s logical to believe in free will, since if free will exists, I would’ve made the right choice, if it doesn’t, I would’ve made a choice that I have had to make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43525908246.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Well you’re making the additional assumption- you’re positing the existence of an as yet unproven soul and saying it’s capable of enabling free will. Determinism posits that there appears to be no mechanism to enable free will so any semblance of it is in fact an illusion. 

Why does going with your intuition make more sense in the absence of evidence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43528570137.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>My belief in the soul is because I think a material explanation of consciousness fails. Material determinists have to believe that consciousness is useless but also just happens for some reason. I like the philosophical zombie argument to demonstrate this, imagine a world exactly like this one but without consciousness. Nothing physical would change. Brains would fire the same neurons, and everyone’s actions would be the same. People would cry without ever feeling sad. So how do they explain this? They either deny the question and say that if the world was the same they would be conscious, which is missing the point; or they would say there doesn’t have to be a reason for consciousness, it just happens for some reason and doesn’t have any actual purpose. This wasn’t satisfying for me so I started departing from materialism.

The right choice is me being right about the question of free will vs determinism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43531188957.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, that’s all well and good, but you just spent a bunch of time explaining why you think the soul explains consciousness (personally I never understood that argument, it seems to be “well we don’t understand how material stuff can lead to consciousness, so I guess it’s magic”) but then you just assume that same soul allows for free will? Why does that follow from the first thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43532026833.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Because, as I said before, if there is no free will there is no point that we are conscious. If our actions can just be explained by previous physical causes, then why be conscious? Consciousness, imo, implies free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43532315823.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you assume that the universe owes you “a point”? 

Is there a point to biological carbon turning into crude oil? Is there a point to gravity acting as a force to draw matter together? Why would consciousness require a point? 

Maybe the point is to put us in the passenger seat of a wild ride with absolutely no agency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43533179786.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Live with that worldview if you wish, but if there’s two options which both aren’t proven, I’ll choose the one that uplifts me and enables me to be a better person more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43533536019.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Well neither is proven but yours makes the additional assumption, not to mention there is actual neurological, experimental data in favour of there not being free will, so really logically you shouldn’t believe either but maybe err on the side of no free will. 

I’d also add that practically speaking I live as if I do have free will, since if it’s not true it’s an extremely powerful illusion. Similar to how I could be a brain in a vat and I can’t prove it either way, but I live as if I’m not a brain in a vat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43539193431.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>Except, as I've commented previously, you assume that with ALL physical aspects equal, consciousness still exists independently and could even be absent.

There is no basis or logical reasoning for this belief. You can describe or identify any aspect of "consciousness" that can not be mapped through physiological tests or means to a satisfactory standard.

If your only hiccup is "why" consciousness developed, there isn't one. Evolution doesn't have a purpose other than momentary survival. That's how life came about and how life continues to change. It is what works at the time that continues to reproduce within the confines of the physical world. Evolution doesn't have a goal, a reason, or anything else that we wish to assign it. Evolution works and fails all the time when looked at from our perspective as "thinkers" (another activity that can be mapped within the brain).

"People would cry without ever feeling sad." Do you really believe 'sadness' is an entirely independent process from the physical world? That neuroscience is unable to explain that? That a field such as optogenetics won't likely show, beyond any reasonable doubt, how neural activity can explain these and many other neurological processes? Optogenetics has ever shown reactivation of memories, for example. Even with implications for targeting specific memories, the fields within neuroscience are more comprehensive than you might believe.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
