<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521800592.0" user="Brainsonastick" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with wager arguments for beliefs is that believing something for a reason other than being genuinely convinced is not easy if it’s even possible.

I have found the evidence points rather strongly towards determinism (possibly with some true randomness). I can’t just say “the fact point this way but I’m going to ignore that and believe the opposite.” That’s not belief. That’s lying about belief.

Flaws in Pascal’s wager aside, I can’t simply choose to believe in god either. I will still know I think it’s nonsense no matter how much I pretend otherwise in public.

The matter would different if you were talking playing a gameshow hosted by an omniscient being (ignoring that the existence of an omniscient being implies determinism) and they asked you if you had free will. Suppose, for whatever reason, you only value winning if you have free will. Then it makes sense to guess you have free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521833090.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>True, honestly this isn’t what convinced me of free will but helped me pragmatically believe in it because it does seem a bit stubborn compared to general scientific consensus. The main reason that made me inclined towards free will was the existence of consciousness. I liked the P zombie argument, if brains didn’t create consciousness, every neuron would fire just the same. Every person would do exactly the same action. Then what is the purpose of consciousness then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521923477.0" user="Brainsonastick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I liked the P zombie argument, if brains didn’t create consciousness, every neuron would fire just the same. Every person would do exactly the same action. 

That’s not true though. The neurons may start in an initial configuration but even p-zombies do react to stimulus and change accordingly. We wouldn’t all do the same actions, as we have different neurological states even without consciousness.

Of course, you do raise the issue of consciousness coming from the brain, a physical object which follows the laws of physics. Where would the free will come from if the consciousness comes from the laws of physics? Or do you disagree that the brain is a physical object subject to the laws of physics?

&gt; Then what is the purpose of consciousness then?

Why the assumption that there is a purpose to consciousness? I think the idea that we and everything about us has purpose is just our egos affecting our reasoning. We have no evidence that purpose exists. We WANT to have purpose but that’s not enough to make it real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521956033.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but all stimuli is controlled by physical processes. The same photons would hit the eyes. Same molecules hit the nose and the tongue. Same nerves would fire when touching something. Everything would be exactly the same without consciousness. There is no point of consciousness existing without free will.

If something as mystical as consciousness which we can’t even begin to comprehend why it exists just exists, I frankly think that’s just stupid. Why do I have awareness? “Idk bro you just do” I think there’s something special about my consciousness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521993611.0" user="Brainsonastick" delta="False">
    <text>You’re describing exactly what I was talking about: assuming purpose for the sake of our egos rather than any actual reasoning.

Your CMV is about logical belief but your belief isn’t coming from logic. That’s totally okay. But it does undermine your initial claim that it’s a matter of logic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522004215.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I guess so, I feel like either way we have to assume something. Wouldn’t it be logical to assume the pragmatic belief?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522055153.0" user="Brainsonastick" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that we have to assume something. It’s okay to acknowledge we don’t know.

That said, the general rule of reasoning is that if the options are “X exists” and “X doesn’t exist”, and there’s zero evidence of X existing, we assume it doesn’t exist. We need a reason to reject the null hypothesis. 

If we did it your way and assumed “X exists”, we run into problems like “Alex sets X to be ‘counting your toes every morning improves mental health’” and “Bob sets X to be ‘counting your toes every morning worsens mental health’”. If we assume the positive in the absence of evidence, then we assume counting your toes in the morning both improves and worsens your mental health, which is obviously not possible.

Again, it’s still totally fine to believe there is a purpose and there is free will. It’s just not a belief based on logic.

I still think society is much better off with everyone believing in free will… but logically, we have no evidence it exists and so we can’t reject the null hypothesis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522110746.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>True</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523174590.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve thought about this over the last couple of hours, and I think I disagree. If we just say we don’t know, to things we aren’t 100% sure of, then if we are consistent with this line of reasoning we can get into extreme skepticism. Why shouldn’t I believe in solipsism? Why should I believe in the material world? I feel like at some point you just gotta take the most pragmatic solution that seems intuitive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524883179.0" user="Brainsonastick" delta="False">
    <text>Hold up! This isn’t for “things we aren’t 100% sure of”. This is for things we have **absolutely no evidence of**. That’s not anywhere close to extreme skepticism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43528476962.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Well I have absolutely no evidence that other people have subjective experiences the way that I do, all I see are their bodies doing actions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
