<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521611814.0" user="derelict5432" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

This doesn't follow. If there is no free will and we are determined to think that, we were determined to be correct. How we got there has no bearing on the correctness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521663040.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>If we can’t make a choice on whether we are right or wrong the value of being right or wrong diminishes. It’s better to choose to be right than to be determined to be right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521689200.0" user="derelict5432" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you haven't really made the case for that. You seem to be taking for granted that a non-deterministic universe has more value to us than a deterministic one, which isn't obvious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521710994.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I think it’s intuitive that a universe where we are able to have control over our actions is better than a universe where we are essentially conscious robots. I can’t really make any formal logical argument of why it’s better as it has to do with subjective human satisfaction. If someone would rather live in a deterministic universe I guess that is their prerogative and I have no way to argue against that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522115931.0" user="Mammoth-Phone6630" delta="False">
    <text>It might be intuitive to you, but I don’t see it. 

To some, being able to say “there was nothing I could have done to change my life” is preferable to a life where “I caused all my problems”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522126738.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I think that’s a poor attitude. If more people believed they had the ability to change their lives for the better vs being stuck in their harsh situation, I’d think people would be happier. Determinism would lead to a defeatist mindset.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523609019.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>If someone doesn't belief in free will and they are defeatist, I think that's an error.

If someone is in a bad situation and thinks "Well, if I don't do anything about it, that would what's determined" that is just as true as "If I work hard to better my situation (or that of others), that would be what is determined".

It's illogical to think that free will condemns you to be passive, so even if you base your belief on the existence of free will, on whether you like to have an impact on the world, you wouldn't need to believe in free will.

If free will doesn't exist and I slap myself in the face, then, yes, that would be what is determined – but that doesn't mean that it actually *is* what is determined. If I don't slap myself in the face that is also what is determined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523868362.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>How can an error exist if there was no other option?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524002284.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>I heard that some dads teach their children some wrong words as a prank. I don't know what, maybe calling rhinos "unicorns". The child has no other option but to believe it and it's still an error.

Deterministic computer programs can also have errors/bugs. They don't correspond to a state that is deemed correct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521967866.0" user="KingJeff314" delta="False">
    <text>That’s an argument from consequence. You’re saying, “well it would be nice if such and such were the case, therefore it is the case”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521993066.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that if someone believes in free will, they’re either right, or were determined to be wrong. If the person was free to make a decision, then he’s right, if the person isn’t free, how could he have done otherwise?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522052907.0" user="batman12399" delta="False">
    <text>It does not logically follow from this that free will exists though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522072723.0" user="KingJeff314" delta="False">
    <text>He couldn’t have done otherwise up to that point, but he may be determined to do otherwise at some point in the future. It may be that some small asteroid exploded off a star a billion years ago strikes the earth next Tuesday, causing a power outage, causing him to read a book which describes a psychologically convincing argument for determinism. And so a sequence of events 1 billion years in the making created a determinist.

Or a similar set of circumstances might have made someone stumble on your CMV and become a free will libertarian. 

You can be deterministically correct or deterministically wrong, or be determined to transition from being wrong to being correct, or vice versa.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
