<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43522070898.0" user="Prescientpedestrian" delta="False">
    <text>Do you choose how you react to something or does your biochemical makeup do so? Like are there things that upset you and frustrate you but you wish they didn’t? Do you get jealous even if you wish you wouldn’t? Where do emotions come from? Do these emotions dictate how you navigate the decisions you make? I for one am always trying to be better but am often finding myself filled with emotions that I don’t choose when faced with a situation. These emotions are controlled by the chemical soup that is in my body which is a factor of many many externalities like my diet, my upbringing, the environment I grew up in and am currently living in.

There’s a reason why lead exposure as a child can be a risk factor for violence and aggression in adulthood, among other things. That doesn’t mean things are deterministic, there are an infinite number of possibilities all colliding around like the random jittering of particles. If you “make a decision” to do something it isn’t you making that decision, it’s all the internal and external factors surrounding your life and biology that are coming together to make that decision. On the extreme, as an example, people who suffer major head trauma become impulsive and can end up doing horrible things even if they were “good” people before. It can feel like free will but change a few chemicals in your body, or add external pressure from your peers and you will make different decisions in the same scenario than you would right now. Think of how trauma shapes peoples decision making. How you respond to any situation is shaped by so many things out of your control that it seems weird to imagine free will, to me anyway, even though the ego will say, “it WAS me who made that decision, I decided to do that.”</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
