<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521747823.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

This isn't really true, since if compatibilist (but not libertarian) free will exists, the decision to believe is _also_ within our control. So your argument doesn't really hold.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521770707.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not. You would’ve made the decision according to internal factors, which are entirely decided by your external factors. Compatibilism is the exact same as determinism but it defines free will to something it’s not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521838597.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't mean that the decision was out of my control. Quite the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521847430.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Then it’s just semantics at this point. You had only one possible choice, what’s the difference if it was internal or external?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521854368.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>Compatibilism does not assert that you have only one possible choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521859486.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Then determinism would be false thus compatibilism would be false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521878833.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>No, that's just not the case.  The position that there are multiple possible outcomes is not at all incompatible with determinism (determinism is not the same thing as necessitarianism), _and_ compatibilism does not require that determinism is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521901095.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Bro what. The definition of compatibilism is believing in determinism and free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521921102.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's not. It's the position they determinism and free will are not logically incompatible, and can both be true at once. A compatibilist need not actually believe in either one of these positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521934716.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>Again, why would you say you’re a compatibilist without believing in compatabilism, what are you exactly arguing here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521943855.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>A compatibilist believes that determinism and free will are compatible. A compatibilist need not believe in either determinism or free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521975313.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>You argued that if compatibilist free will exists, assuming determinism is true. You weren’t arguing based on what a person who believes in compatabilism believes. So if determinism and free will exists under the compatabilist definition, there would only be one choice. Otherwise if there are multiple choices, by definition it would be libertarian free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522001829.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>Well, no, as I already explained, determinism is completely consistent with multiple possible choices. Determinism isn't the same thing as necessitarianism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522010207.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>You said if compatibilistic free will exists, then there are multiple options. That is wrong by definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522038830.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not; determinism is not the position that there are not multiple possibilities. Determinism is the position that events are completely determined by previously existing causes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
