<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2562772438.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16dt3va/cmv_it_is_illogical_to_not_believe_in_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: It is illogical to not believe in Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>LAMARR__44</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people either believe in Hard Determinism or Compatibilism. I will argue that both are illogical.

Both argue that human actions are extensions of factors we do not have a choice over. Compatibilism seems to say we are still free but just redefines free will to the internal factors behind a decision, but the decision is still decided by a chain of events outside of our control.

My argument is a sort of wager argument. Either libertarian free will exists or it doesn’t. If it exists and we believe in it, we have made a free decision where we are right. If libertarian free will doesn’t exist, the decision to believe in libertarian free will was out of our control.

So either we have a choice and we can make the right choice, or we don’t have a choice and were determined to be wrong.

Thus it makes more sense to believe in libertarian free will since it’s potentially the only one where we have a chance to make a right choice, if determinism is true there is no choice, so there’s no value in being right.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43521772489.0" user="YossarianWWII" delta="False">
    <text>Classical free will is incoherent. It is inherently self-contradictory for a very simple reason.

To begin, all events are either random, nonrandom, or a product of random and nonrandom factors. This is true regardless of where you believe decision-making comes from because it is a logical statement, not one about material reality.

Under the classical free will model, nonrandom choices are not free. However, I think it's hardly controversial to say that random decisions would not be willful.

In any composite decision, any willfulness would stem from nonrandom factors and any "freedom" from those factors would be a manifestation of randomness. 

In other words, in a composite decision, the nonrandom factors constrain the possibilities and any variation within those possibilities is random. It's akin to rolling a die; the six-sided nature of the die constrains the possible outcomes, but the outcome itself is random.

This is true whether you believe in an immaterial soul or not. In both cases, people follow the patterns of their decision-making, and this is fairly obvious. Even with incomplete knowledge of a person we can say that a decision sounds "exactly like them" or "not at all like them." That's what a personality is.

What with classical free will being impossible, it's worth turning to other definitions that can be useful. I'm partial to that freedom simply being the freedom from undue outside influence, by which I really mean something like physical or chemical intervention, something that screws up the normal behavior of the brain. Alternatively, we could think of all decisions as acts free will but take extra care to consider the context in which they were made. It's easy to recognize the difference between a decision made with a gun to your head and one without. We can ask ourselves, "What's the value of judging this person's decision-making under extraordinary circumstances?"

TLDR: Classical free will is logically incoherent regardless of whether you believe in an immaterial soul or not. Because of this, any discussion of free will needs to settle on another definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43521802267.0" user="LAMARR__44" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think a choice means it’s either determined or random. I think a choice is simply an agent creating a causal chain for no other reason then he chose to. His choice is influenced but not controlled by previous factors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522253770.0" user="Huge_JackedMann" delta="False">
    <text>But how does he come to a decision absent those previous factors? We don't ever make choices in a vacuum or free of judgement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43522766479.0" user="ShrikeSummit" delta="False">
    <text>You’re begging the question. “I think a choice is simply an agent creating a causal chain for no reason other than he chose to” is just more words to say “I think the reason for a choice is that an agent made a choice” which is itself just more words to say “the reason for a choice is a choice.” Your view can’t be changed because it’s circular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523688614.0" user="JohannesWurst" delta="False">
    <text>If a view can't be changed, does it mean it's okay to have it?

For example I would say it's *correct* to say that there is a *possibility* that there is alien life on the moon, because it isn't disproven yet.

Is it similarly okay to say there could be a third option besides deterministic events and random, spontaneous events, because it isn't possible to disprove it? Is it just a agree-to-disagree thing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524596857.0" user="ShrikeSummit" delta="False">
    <text>It’s okay to have the view. Everyone has views they can’t or won’t change. It’s just not okay to post it in this sub because it defeats the purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43523572315.0" user="Logisk" delta="False">
    <text>How is that different from randomness though?

You say "for no other reason than he chose to". This means he would not be able to explain why he chose to, and he would not be able to predict his own actions in a future situation, so to himself it seems indistinguishable from randomness. For anyone else watching him, they would have even less of an explanation about it, so to them it would also be indistinguishable from randomness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43524616776.0" user="YossarianWWII" delta="False">
    <text>You misunderstand me. It being a choice isn't why it's either random or nonrandom. It being any sort of occurrence is what makes it random or nonrandom.

&gt;His choice is influenced but not controlled by previous factors.

Then what is the additional element? Where does the freedom in free will come from? You've left this as an open question, an unspoken assumption. My argument is that if it's not a nonrandom factor, it must be randomness. It's as simple as that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
