<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="256350592.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/48mhds/cmv_spotlight_was_a_marginal_movie_that_didnt/">
    <title>CMV: Spotlight was a marginal movie that didn't deserve all of the accolades that it received [Obvious spoilers]</title>
    <original_poster>layze23</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Am I the only one in the world that thought this movie was just ok? I mean, I really don't see the appeal. I guess the acting was good, but seriously, I didn't find it entertaining at all. My wife loved it. It's not like it was poorly written, had bad cinematography, or anything like that, I just found it... boring. I guess to me it was just a boring subject. "Yeah, priests molest little boys on a large scale. Is that it?" You could have written that on a post-it note and handed it to me and I think I would have had about the same reaction, but saved me 2 hours of my life. I don't know why I'm so bothered by this movie. I guess it's because I heard so many good things about it, I was expecting a lot more. I just felt like it was a newspaper article about an unentertaining subject that was made into a movie and won a ton of awards and accolades. 

   In contrast, I thought The Martian was excellent and I typically find space in general pretty uninteresting (I know, space should be really interesting, but that's a discussion for another day). I thought the Martian was a million times better than Spotlight. Like I said, I just don't understand the appeal of Spotlight. It wasn't even like there was a mystery to solve. I guess the only thing I can see as even slightly interesting is that nobody understood the magnitude of the problem and it was only through persistent journalism that it was even discovered. But, meh, so what?

   I'm not trying to undermine anyone's opinion that enjoyed the movie or even the movie itself. There are a lot of movies that I know are good that I just don't enjoy much and that's fine. I'm just baffled that I seem to be one of the rare few that feels this way about the movie and it bothers me more than it probably should that I can't understand what about it appeals to people.

   Counterpoint from a friend: "I sort of equate movies like spotlight to documentaries. Some of my favorite documentaries are ones that contain subjects I have no interest in or don't think I'd find enjoyable (ex: journalism, catholic church scandal) and it succeeds in making it fascinating. I liked how the story and scandal unfolded. I don't particularly have an interest in the journalistic process and definitely didn't think I'd want to watch anything involving the church scandal but I found it intriguing."

   My response: "I know what you're saying. The subject itself doesn't have be interesting in a vacuum to be the focal point of a good movie. I agree with that. But I guess even the plot development wasn't interesting to me. I mean, everything happened exactly as I anticipated it would. Maybe it would have been more interesting if there was an unanticipated event or if something happened behind the journalistic scenes that nobody knew about or would have expected. But we already know the story and it unfolded exactly how I would have expected it to play out. 

   For example, of course the church was trying to keep the skeletons in the closet. That's what I would expect that organization to do in that situation, and furthermore, we already knew that's what they did."

   Please, guys and gals, CMV.

* Sorry for the brevity of this explanation or any responses.  I'm typing with one hand due to an injury and cast on one hand. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28333177471.0" user="SOLUNAR" delta="False">
    <text>Its hard to change your mind on what makes a good movie or what you should find interesting.

Could you let me know some other movies you believe should have had this type of acclamation? And maybe tell me why? this would allow me to see what characteristics you use to define a good/great movie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333212902.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>As I mentioned in my post, I thought The Martian was an excellent movie personally. Moreover, I feel that it's a type of movie that could appeal to everyone. It had problem-solving, drama, humor, and many other qualities that I found lacking in Spotlight. I didn't see much problem-solving, suspense, or a large amount of humor in Spotlight. It was: here's something that could be a big story, let's investigate it. Investigation begins, finds out the details, reports that there's a problem. In my opinion, it was like an uninteresting documentary. That is part of my challenge, I know that isn't how most people probably feel and I'd like to know how or why they interpreted the movie differently than me. I guess the larger scope of the question might be what makes a movie interesting, but that's more philosophical. I'd like to stick to one particular movie to avoid getting into a deep discussion that probably can't be answered very well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
