<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="256350592.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/48mhds/cmv_spotlight_was_a_marginal_movie_that_didnt/">
    <title>CMV: Spotlight was a marginal movie that didn't deserve all of the accolades that it received [Obvious spoilers]</title>
    <original_poster>layze23</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Am I the only one in the world that thought this movie was just ok? I mean, I really don't see the appeal. I guess the acting was good, but seriously, I didn't find it entertaining at all. My wife loved it. It's not like it was poorly written, had bad cinematography, or anything like that, I just found it... boring. I guess to me it was just a boring subject. "Yeah, priests molest little boys on a large scale. Is that it?" You could have written that on a post-it note and handed it to me and I think I would have had about the same reaction, but saved me 2 hours of my life. I don't know why I'm so bothered by this movie. I guess it's because I heard so many good things about it, I was expecting a lot more. I just felt like it was a newspaper article about an unentertaining subject that was made into a movie and won a ton of awards and accolades. 

   In contrast, I thought The Martian was excellent and I typically find space in general pretty uninteresting (I know, space should be really interesting, but that's a discussion for another day). I thought the Martian was a million times better than Spotlight. Like I said, I just don't understand the appeal of Spotlight. It wasn't even like there was a mystery to solve. I guess the only thing I can see as even slightly interesting is that nobody understood the magnitude of the problem and it was only through persistent journalism that it was even discovered. But, meh, so what?

   I'm not trying to undermine anyone's opinion that enjoyed the movie or even the movie itself. There are a lot of movies that I know are good that I just don't enjoy much and that's fine. I'm just baffled that I seem to be one of the rare few that feels this way about the movie and it bothers me more than it probably should that I can't understand what about it appeals to people.

   Counterpoint from a friend: "I sort of equate movies like spotlight to documentaries. Some of my favorite documentaries are ones that contain subjects I have no interest in or don't think I'd find enjoyable (ex: journalism, catholic church scandal) and it succeeds in making it fascinating. I liked how the story and scandal unfolded. I don't particularly have an interest in the journalistic process and definitely didn't think I'd want to watch anything involving the church scandal but I found it intriguing."

   My response: "I know what you're saying. The subject itself doesn't have be interesting in a vacuum to be the focal point of a good movie. I agree with that. But I guess even the plot development wasn't interesting to me. I mean, everything happened exactly as I anticipated it would. Maybe it would have been more interesting if there was an unanticipated event or if something happened behind the journalistic scenes that nobody knew about or would have expected. But we already know the story and it unfolded exactly how I would have expected it to play out. 

   For example, of course the church was trying to keep the skeletons in the closet. That's what I would expect that organization to do in that situation, and furthermore, we already knew that's what they did."

   Please, guys and gals, CMV.

* Sorry for the brevity of this explanation or any responses.  I'm typing with one hand due to an injury and cast on one hand. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28333183306.0" user="fluke_skywalker" delta="False">
    <text>I think part of what you're missing here is the time period the movie is set in. To paraphrase what you said, "Priests molest little boys, what else is new?"

At the time this was happening, that wasn't considered common knowledge. Even those who knew didn't know that it was happening on such a wide scale, internationally over the course of decades. 

To me, what made this movie great was the lengths they went to to show how hard it was to convince anyone to even begin to look into this. It's a classic David vs Goliath story with the twist that even those on the side of David had helped with the coverup. I really bought into the characters, understanding what it would be like to be raised Catholic, live in a tight knit Catholic community, and try to expose the Catholic Church for condoning these atrocities. 

That may not change your view of the movie, but I hope it's helpful to look through the same lens that I saw the movie through.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333233425.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's fair to bring up the time period, but my counter point is that as viewers in the present day we do have the advantage of hindsight and we have that knowledge, even if at that point it wasn't common knowledge. I think a fair analogy would be if we could view Newton observing laws of motion. He is conducting experiments to support his hypothesis of his now famous laws. Is that interesting? I suppose to some it might be, especially to history or science buffs maybe? The results of these experiments are amazing in that they lead to imperative Laws of Motion. I just don't know if the process would be that interesting. What would be really interesting is if he used very unconventional methods or experiments that few people considered or knew about to make these eventual laws. To me, THAT, would be interesting. 

Your point about the lengths they went to in order to get the information is also valid, but again, it's exactly what I would expect. I'd be much more surprised if the information was NOT challenged by the Catholic church and they DIDN'T know about the extent of the problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333311651.0" user="Chronic_Apathy1" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic, a film decrying slavery or Jim Crow laws is boring because obviously we know today that racism is wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333562006.0" user="EffectiveExistence" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me that maybe this movie has come out too soon to really be profound to a lot of people. Most of us are old enough to remember the news stories about the abuse by the priests. I think at first people weren't sure if it was true, then gradually we started to accept it as more people came forward, so it never felt like a  "breaking news" story to us. Then eventually it was so prevalent and beaten into our heads that it became a joke. Remember [these Halloween costumes?](http://www.demeterclarc.com/wp-content/uploads/images/2010/09/PEDOPRIEST.jpg) Now we're just desensitized to the whole issue.

So the result this movie just feels like another newscast about old news that everyone knows about yet never really shocked most people. "Yeah yeah they molested kids we know." Well we forget that at one time it was not well-known, and this movie is about the people who brought the issue to light.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333672503.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is very true. I think you made a point for me that I couldn't or didn't articulate very well. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333806514.0" user="fluke_skywalker" delta="False">
    <text>Your analogy is fair, but the other component here is relevancy in the modern day. Not that I'm saying Newton's laws aren't relevant today, but to me it's very poignant that the current Pope apologized for the Church's actions just last month. So while it's true that this is an historical documentary, it's much more a current part of the public eye than the way Newton discovered his laws, which to me makes it much more interesting (and deserving of attention). 

As far as your second point, I don't mean to emphasize so much the lengths they went to as the tremendous individual bravery of each of these reporters. The story I found interesting, but it was this latter aspect that made this an Oscar worthy movie in my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28338131361.0" user="scattershot22" delta="False">
    <text>But molesting happens at a rate in our public school system that is much, much higher than religion. One researchers [estimates](http://www.cbsnews.com/news/has-media-ignored-sex-abuse-in-school/) it is 100X more frequent in public school than the catholic church.

Wouldn't a movie about how our teachers are raping our kids at school be more important?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28338172748.0" user="fluke_skywalker" delta="False">
    <text>I 100% agree that there's a problem in our educational system that's being largely ignored. A movie about that topic would hit even harder (and if done well, most likely also win an Oscar).

But I fail to see how pointing out that there's a bigger problem somewhere else diminishes this movie in any way. Furthermore, the movie could only be made because of the huge volume of background work done by the reporters to bring the story to light in the first place. 

If and when a similar investigation &amp;amp; report is conducted into sexual abuse in the educational system, I fully expect there to be an accompanying documentary and hope it's as well made and received as Spotlight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28347138563.0" user="scattershot22" delta="False">
    <text>The CBS link I provided indicated that rape in public schools happened 100 times more frequently than in the church. The bigger question, I'd think, is why were the reporters interested in such isolated incidence when there has been a much larger problem impacting people all over the country?

And here we are some 10 years after the catholic church expose and where is the comparable report and concern for what is happening in our public schools?

Reporters will often claim they can put biases aside when reporting. But usually, bias is simply that they find one story more interesting than another and thus they fail to report the more significant story and instead focus on the lesser story. Compare Bill Cosby and Bill Clinton, for example. 

It would have made much more sense to attack the problem of teachers having sex in our public schools (since it is a much larger problem) AND THEN after bringing that to light go back and do the same with the church.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
