<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="256350592.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/48mhds/cmv_spotlight_was_a_marginal_movie_that_didnt/">
    <title>CMV: Spotlight was a marginal movie that didn't deserve all of the accolades that it received [Obvious spoilers]</title>
    <original_poster>layze23</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Am I the only one in the world that thought this movie was just ok? I mean, I really don't see the appeal. I guess the acting was good, but seriously, I didn't find it entertaining at all. My wife loved it. It's not like it was poorly written, had bad cinematography, or anything like that, I just found it... boring. I guess to me it was just a boring subject. "Yeah, priests molest little boys on a large scale. Is that it?" You could have written that on a post-it note and handed it to me and I think I would have had about the same reaction, but saved me 2 hours of my life. I don't know why I'm so bothered by this movie. I guess it's because I heard so many good things about it, I was expecting a lot more. I just felt like it was a newspaper article about an unentertaining subject that was made into a movie and won a ton of awards and accolades. 

   In contrast, I thought The Martian was excellent and I typically find space in general pretty uninteresting (I know, space should be really interesting, but that's a discussion for another day). I thought the Martian was a million times better than Spotlight. Like I said, I just don't understand the appeal of Spotlight. It wasn't even like there was a mystery to solve. I guess the only thing I can see as even slightly interesting is that nobody understood the magnitude of the problem and it was only through persistent journalism that it was even discovered. But, meh, so what?

   I'm not trying to undermine anyone's opinion that enjoyed the movie or even the movie itself. There are a lot of movies that I know are good that I just don't enjoy much and that's fine. I'm just baffled that I seem to be one of the rare few that feels this way about the movie and it bothers me more than it probably should that I can't understand what about it appeals to people.

   Counterpoint from a friend: "I sort of equate movies like spotlight to documentaries. Some of my favorite documentaries are ones that contain subjects I have no interest in or don't think I'd find enjoyable (ex: journalism, catholic church scandal) and it succeeds in making it fascinating. I liked how the story and scandal unfolded. I don't particularly have an interest in the journalistic process and definitely didn't think I'd want to watch anything involving the church scandal but I found it intriguing."

   My response: "I know what you're saying. The subject itself doesn't have be interesting in a vacuum to be the focal point of a good movie. I agree with that. But I guess even the plot development wasn't interesting to me. I mean, everything happened exactly as I anticipated it would. Maybe it would have been more interesting if there was an unanticipated event or if something happened behind the journalistic scenes that nobody knew about or would have expected. But we already know the story and it unfolded exactly how I would have expected it to play out. 

   For example, of course the church was trying to keep the skeletons in the closet. That's what I would expect that organization to do in that situation, and furthermore, we already knew that's what they did."

   Please, guys and gals, CMV.

* Sorry for the brevity of this explanation or any responses.  I'm typing with one hand due to an injury and cast on one hand. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28333096294.0" user="James_McNulty" delta="False">
    <text>Can you clarfiy the view you're attempting to change?  Are you looking for arguments to help you understand why *others* found it as deserving of accolades (i.e. why it's critically acclaimed) or why *you* should personally like the movie more than you do?  Because your title suggests the former, but the body of your post was basically "I personally found it boring".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333158667.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good question. I guess I'm working on the assumption that any movie that's critically acclaimed as a great movie and by the consensus of everyone I've talked to should have enough appeal that any viewer can understand why the movie is so great, even if he doesn't personally agree that it's a great movie. I genuinely don't understand the seemingly huge appeal to the general audience and film critics. I feel like I, personally, am missing something great about the movie.  TLDR: Both?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333254652.0" user="James_McNulty" delta="False">
    <text>In that case, I'll separate my response into two parts.  The first will be its "film critic" merits and the second a more personal appeal.  

First, the movie is extremely well done.  As you have admitted, it has a well-written script, good cinematography, strong acting.  I also think it had really great pacing, which is not easy to do in a story spanning months with so many intricate moving pieces.  They were able to convey the meticulous investigative work it took, without resorting to a "smoking gun" or dumb luck plot device.

So why should you care?  What appeals to others about this movie that doesn't appeal to you?  The most glaring thing I see missing from your post is an analysis of how the scenes and interactions between characters frame the story.  This isn't an adventure movie where the point of it is This Thing Happens then That Thing Happens.  It's an exploration into the real world and how people relate to one another and the institutions of society.

I think the most important revelation of this movie wasn't that there was a massive conspiracy by a powerful organization.  This movie wasn't precisely about a Catholic Church coverup, although that was a main focus.  It was also about the complacency of society, unwillingness to look past personal bias, and what it means to do the right thing.  There had been plenty of ignored cries for help.  In some cases, the journalists had ignored the same warnings others had.  Michael Keaton's character especially is so ready to throw this in everyone's faces, and the revelation that the Boston Globe had had chance after chance to investigate this as failed was a major plot point.

One of the most interesting things was the range of reactions we saw from the various people who knew something was going on.  Everyone was reluctant to help the reporters, but for different reasons.  Garabedian was skeptical that the reporters would actually do anything, MacLeish had already tried to help and felt rebuffed.  Sullivan and the school board members seemed more concerned with protecting institutions.  Interestingly, the most straightforwardly helpful source was the molester priest who was interviewed in his front door.

The film also explored several moral dilemmas.  When Brian d'Arcy James' character has to decide whether warn the neighborhood that there's a child molester living around the corner.  They only briefly touched on it, but there talk about faith and its importance even to lapsed Catholics.  The decision to not publish until they could really nail the institution.  These are important things beyond the scope of the movie itself, which is often the mark of a great movie.  Not to pick on The Martian, but I didn't spend much time thinking anything other than "that was pleasant to watch" after.  And that's totally fine!  Entertainment for entertainment's sake is great.  But movies which can explore humanity and make you think more critically are also important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333380031.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First, the movie is extremely well done. As you have admitted, it has a well-written script, good cinematography, strong acting. I also think it had really great pacing, which is not easy to do in a story spanning months with so many intricate moving pieces. They were able to convey the meticulous investigative work it took, without resorting to a "smoking gun" or dumb luck plot device.

These are beyond my very novice interpretation of film critique. I basically look at a movie and generally can acknowledge some major points such as good acting, but beyond that the nuances of film making is lost on me. Even if I subliminally acknowledge all the points that you made, I can't really say definitively that I have a strong opinion on most of those points. I just know if the production "feels good" to me. In layman's terms, the production of the movie "felt good" to me, which I acknowledge and definitely made it better, but I don't think that made it more interesting to me personally. However, I could see how that would add value.

&amp;gt;This movie wasn't precisely about a Catholic Church coverup, although that was a main focus. It was also about the complacency of society, unwillingness to look past personal bias, and what it means to do the right thing. 

This is a very good point, and I had actually considered this, but my thought is that it's not much different than so many other things in the world. Maybe I've become numb to the complacency of human nature and I'v e already accepted it. As a regular Redditor, lurker or not, I feel like I've already seen and heard so much that while this scale of complacency should be appalling, I'm barely affected at all by the level shown in this movie. The unique part is the scale of complacency, but unfortunately I think the internet has numbed me to the effects of so many things, including this. 

&amp;gt;The film also explored several moral dilemmas...

This is probably the most compelling point that resonated with me. You gave great examples of moral dilemmas and internal conflicts. The part about Catholics choosing to support what's right or the institution that their faith is based on is an interesting dilemma. 

I don't know if I'm ready to award a delta yet, but you've made a strong case. Let me chew on this for a little bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333626467.0" user="misterpicklesthecat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; These are beyond my very novice interpretation of film critique. I basically look at a movie and generally can acknowledge some major points such as good acting, but beyond that the nuances of film making is lost on me


If you dont know anything about judging a film based on it's quality as one, why do you even HAVE an opinion about its 'best film' award? 

I don't know anything about landscaping, so I don't have a opinion about which tractor is better at doing a job. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333669883.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone is allowed to have an opinion, even if they aren't experts. You're allowed to have an opinion on tractors. People might not give much validity to your opinion, but that's a different topic. This is CMV, not 'Do you value my opinion'. I'm asking people what they thought made this an amazing film. Also... rude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28333913755.0" user="Minus-Celsius" delta="False">
    <text>If one a tractor was universally praised and lauded for being amazing by tractor critics, would you make a CMV "It's a marginal tractor that doesn't deserve the praise it's getting."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28334158976.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>If I spent 2 hours riding it I might </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28334150381.0" user="misterpicklesthecat" delta="False">
    <text>right. I didn't mean 'opinion'. I meant a viewpoint or stance. what i'm trying to say is. how can someone feel a certain way towards one thing or another if they don't have anywhere near enough information. sure they CAN. but they must realize it's not real since they don't know enough about it. its just a very meaningless thing. 


rude? to tell someone how I feel about what they are saying? it's rude of me to tell someone who ADMITS to not knowing ..basically ANYTHING about movies... that they shouldn't have a strong feeling or viewpoint about it... BECAUSE THEY DONT KNOW? 


that is not rude... you are just 12 years old. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28334179821.0" user="layze23" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, probably just more polite than you. Your viewpoint or whatever you want to call it is as valid to you or anyone else as you or they value it. If you don't put any stock into my opinion, that's fine. That's your prerogative. But my viewpoint is as a casual observer, not as a member of the Academy. I don't care if I don't have the credentials to rate movies as a professional film critic, that's not my point. I feel that your general demeanor is rude and that's my opinion too...  I'm an adult and I won't resort to demeaning. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28334194020.0" user="misterpicklesthecat" delta="False">
    <text>ok. demeaning aside your argument is still wrong. my temperament toward you has nothing to do with the argument. you said it yourself. you have a viewpoint of a casual observer. you said before about how you know what good acting is, everything else is indistinguishable. how can you have a viewpoint or take a stance on an argument that you dont know enough about. of course you can have an opinion as a casual observer. I have one of those as well. but that doesn't mean that you can even intelligibly or logically take a certain side or hold a viewpoint about what kind of awards or accolades the film deserve based on the ACADEMY judges. it just doesn't make any sense that you can take a stance on a view like that. it just doesn't. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
