<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2565162652.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16f8c64/cmv_there_is_no_living_being_whom_it_is_wrong_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no living being whom it is wrong to feel love for</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I wrote an earlier post about this with a somewhat confusing title. I believe that this is more clear.
    
To clarify further, this is not to say that anyone or anything is *owed* love. I do not believe that. I believe that love should always be freely given. I am also not talking about romantic love. 

My opinion is this: even if someone has done bad things in the past, or intends to do bad things in the future, it is not wrong for this person to be loved or to accept love.

For example, let's say a man has murdered eleven people in cold blood and is planning to murder a twelfth. Should this person have freedom? No, because he would use that freedom to commit murder. Should this person have power? No, because he would use that power to commit murder. Should this person have the trust of others? No, because he would use that trust to commit murder.

But if his mother still loves him, even though he is a serial killer, does that harm anyone? Not in and of itself. And he cannot use that love to commit murder. If she loves him, but does not trust him, her love for him does not put her or anyone else in danger.

To change my opinion, you would have to show me how love can be harmful in and of itself, and not only in combination with something else such as trust or power.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43536000239.0" user="Alesus2-0" delta="False">
    <text>The knowledge that he is loved may bring the killer comfort and reassurance that he doesn't deserve. That may even lead him to conclude that he is somehow virtuous and thus impair any reform he might undergo.

The love may also be deleterious to his mother. It will cause her distress, when he faces the deserved consequences of his actions. It may even be worse for her, since this anguish will be in conflict with her knowledge that he should face severe punishment. 

Worse, the love she feels could come to pervert her own moral judgement. Her desire to rationalise his the acts of her beloved son may cause her to decide that his immoral murders were justified. She might even apply that conclusion more broadly and commit murder herself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536307846.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>The knowledge that he is loved may also give the killer the inspiration to try to truly earn that love by redeeming himself.

And if a mother stops loving her child, this may bring her great distress in the form of guilt and self-judgment.

And I find it unlikely that a mother would start committing murders just because her son did so. If she does so, this is less likely a result of love and more likely a result of mental illness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536578399.0" user="Alesus2-0" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The knowledge that he is loved may also give the killer the inspiration to try to truly earn that love by redeeming himself.

&gt;And if a mother stops loving her child, this may bring her great distress in the form of guilt and self-judgment.

&gt;And I find it unlikely that a mother would start committing murders just because her son did so. If she does so, this is less likely a result of love and more likely a result of mental illness.

Maybe. So what? Your view, as written, is that it's never wrong to love someone, in and of itself. It doesn't matter that there are some situations in which loving someone is good. I doubt many people would dispute that. What matters is that there are never instances in which it is bad. If you concede that my examples are possible, isn't that evidence that loving someone can sometimes be bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43540162815.0" user="kisekibango" delta="False">
    <text>And hence why I really don't like people that claim absolutes in arguments... if you're starting an argument/discussion/debate off with hyperbole it's already off to a bad start 😂</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43541357723.0" user="Zyrus91" delta="False">
    <text>This Argument ist weak. While it is certainly possible, a Person May also conclude they are virtuos because Nobody loves them. Because everybody is brainwadhed, which is proven by the fact that they are the only bin brainwadhed, and also the only one that die whatever it is they did.

And yes, the mother May also pervert her own judgment. but so May the Anger she feels for giving birth to such a human. This can lead to one thinking they themselves are the evil in the world. At least, they ARE the source of that beeing.

Idk, this Point seems more Like "belief first, reasoning second" Type of Argument. All of what you Said May be possible, but If WE Go and speculate that mich, we have to be fair and speculate into the opposite Direktion aswell, which ultimately dismantles your Point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43541467491.0" user="Alesus2-0" delta="False">
    <text>As I said in a response elsewhere in the thread, I don't think this creates a problem for my argument. OP's claim isn't that it's sometimes good to love a bad person. The claim is that it is never bad to love someone, in itself. As long as my what I suggest is realistically possible, even if it is unlikely, it presents a problem for OP's absolutist position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43541625549.0" user="Zyrus91" delta="False">
    <text>True true. What i meant is that WE cant know how a Person reacts to love, not even the Person itself. So the Feeling of love can lead to Bad decisions, but the Feeling itself is never Bad, because you dont know the consequences of it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
