<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2565162652.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16f8c64/cmv_there_is_no_living_being_whom_it_is_wrong_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no living being whom it is wrong to feel love for</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I wrote an earlier post about this with a somewhat confusing title. I believe that this is more clear.
    
To clarify further, this is not to say that anyone or anything is *owed* love. I do not believe that. I believe that love should always be freely given. I am also not talking about romantic love. 

My opinion is this: even if someone has done bad things in the past, or intends to do bad things in the future, it is not wrong for this person to be loved or to accept love.

For example, let's say a man has murdered eleven people in cold blood and is planning to murder a twelfth. Should this person have freedom? No, because he would use that freedom to commit murder. Should this person have power? No, because he would use that power to commit murder. Should this person have the trust of others? No, because he would use that trust to commit murder.

But if his mother still loves him, even though he is a serial killer, does that harm anyone? Not in and of itself. And he cannot use that love to commit murder. If she loves him, but does not trust him, her love for him does not put her or anyone else in danger.

To change my opinion, you would have to show me how love can be harmful in and of itself, and not only in combination with something else such as trust or power.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43560429720.0" user="Old_Case5471" delta="False">
    <text>Love can be harmful. Example helicopter parents, love their kids so much that they shelter them and now they can't function in society. Point being love can be too much if it leads you to hurt the other person

Example 2:in the case of the criminal, mercy to the guilty is cruelty to the innocent. So if your love for this person seeks to stop or lower the penalties of their crime it is harmful.

So I would say, I agree it is not in principle wrongto love anyone, but so.etime the effects of live  are not always good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43560775899.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Helicopter parents: love plus fear equals a desire for control. Without fear, the love would be harmless. 

Love by itself would not cause someone to be overly forgiving. I can love someone and still think they should stay in prison forever.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
