<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2565162652.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16f8c64/cmv_there_is_no_living_being_whom_it_is_wrong_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no living being whom it is wrong to feel love for</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I wrote an earlier post about this with a somewhat confusing title. I believe that this is more clear.
    
To clarify further, this is not to say that anyone or anything is *owed* love. I do not believe that. I believe that love should always be freely given. I am also not talking about romantic love. 

My opinion is this: even if someone has done bad things in the past, or intends to do bad things in the future, it is not wrong for this person to be loved or to accept love.

For example, let's say a man has murdered eleven people in cold blood and is planning to murder a twelfth. Should this person have freedom? No, because he would use that freedom to commit murder. Should this person have power? No, because he would use that power to commit murder. Should this person have the trust of others? No, because he would use that trust to commit murder.

But if his mother still loves him, even though he is a serial killer, does that harm anyone? Not in and of itself. And he cannot use that love to commit murder. If she loves him, but does not trust him, her love for him does not put her or anyone else in danger.

To change my opinion, you would have to show me how love can be harmful in and of itself, and not only in combination with something else such as trust or power.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43535957700.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes something can only be wrong if it causes harm. What about things that we all have a moral duty not to do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536282924.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>In my worldview, something is only wrong if it causes harm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536335419.0" user="DeadCupcakes23" delta="False">
    <text>Are you sure about that? Would a doctor secretly raping a brain dead patient not be wrong, even if it causes no harm?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536394637.0" user="QuingRavel" delta="False">
    <text>So child molestation is okay for you if the child doesn't remember any of it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43537658186.0" user="RogueNarc" delta="False">
    <text>Was the child harmed at any point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43540576976.0" user="QuingRavel" delta="False">
    <text>If you read my post... If the child was molested of course it was harmed. The fuck</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
