<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2565162652.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16f8c64/cmv_there_is_no_living_being_whom_it_is_wrong_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no living being whom it is wrong to feel love for</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I wrote an earlier post about this with a somewhat confusing title. I believe that this is more clear.
    
To clarify further, this is not to say that anyone or anything is *owed* love. I do not believe that. I believe that love should always be freely given. I am also not talking about romantic love. 

My opinion is this: even if someone has done bad things in the past, or intends to do bad things in the future, it is not wrong for this person to be loved or to accept love.

For example, let's say a man has murdered eleven people in cold blood and is planning to murder a twelfth. Should this person have freedom? No, because he would use that freedom to commit murder. Should this person have power? No, because he would use that power to commit murder. Should this person have the trust of others? No, because he would use that trust to commit murder.

But if his mother still loves him, even though he is a serial killer, does that harm anyone? Not in and of itself. And he cannot use that love to commit murder. If she loves him, but does not trust him, her love for him does not put her or anyone else in danger.

To change my opinion, you would have to show me how love can be harmful in and of itself, and not only in combination with something else such as trust or power.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43535931039.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it's tautological, right? Because nobody would define love as something that could be harmful. Even if you were to find some case in which a gesture meant in love was harmful to somebody, most people would reject that as loving because definitionally love is not supposed to harm. So then, if you take a strictly consequentialist view of these things, it can never be wrong to love anybody because love is definitionally not harmful and harm is all we care about. So you're just saying it's not wrong to do things which aren't wrong by defnition</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43535948229.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I think some people would argue that it is wrong to love a 'bad' person. My point is that I disagree with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43535980100.0" user="OmniManDidNothngWrng" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;some people would argue that it is wrong to love a 'bad' person

Ok, but we aren't talking to those people we are talking to you. You don't need to bring anyone else into this conversation to make your point. You can explain why the earth is round without ever acknowledging flat earthers exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536212747.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Alright. Here is my belief: it is not inherently harmful to love any person, even if that person has done bad things or intends to do bad things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536103215.0" user="DuckDuckGoose006" delta="False">
    <text>The boys who loved Sandusky and were raped by him, because he abused the power he had from that love. That love isn’t harmful?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536214793.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>That power was harmful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43536429417.0" user="lilly_kilgore" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that without that love there would be no opportunity to abuse that power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43537794090.0" user="DuckDuckGoose006" delta="False">
    <text>Not for another delta, I just want to point out that the admiration before the abuse in these situations makes it difficult for victims to report it or reconcile it, they don’t want to get them in trouble. That manipulation of their love gives abusers the opportunity to continue and have more victims.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
