<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2565162652.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16f8c64/cmv_there_is_no_living_being_whom_it_is_wrong_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no living being whom it is wrong to feel love for</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I wrote an earlier post about this with a somewhat confusing title. I believe that this is more clear.
    
To clarify further, this is not to say that anyone or anything is *owed* love. I do not believe that. I believe that love should always be freely given. I am also not talking about romantic love. 

My opinion is this: even if someone has done bad things in the past, or intends to do bad things in the future, it is not wrong for this person to be loved or to accept love.

For example, let's say a man has murdered eleven people in cold blood and is planning to murder a twelfth. Should this person have freedom? No, because he would use that freedom to commit murder. Should this person have power? No, because he would use that power to commit murder. Should this person have the trust of others? No, because he would use that trust to commit murder.

But if his mother still loves him, even though he is a serial killer, does that harm anyone? Not in and of itself. And he cannot use that love to commit murder. If she loves him, but does not trust him, her love for him does not put her or anyone else in danger.

To change my opinion, you would have to show me how love can be harmful in and of itself, and not only in combination with something else such as trust or power.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43541283072.0" user="the-minsterman" delta="False">
    <text>It's a morally complex and sensitive topic. However, for the sake of argument, I'll present an opposing viewpoint to challenge your belief.  
**1. Normalization and Validation of Harmful Behavior:** Even if love in itself doesn't immediately lead to harm, it can be perceived as validating or normalizing harmful behavior. If a serial killer's mother loves him unconditionally despite his actions, it can be seen as indirectly endorsing his actions or suggesting that love can absolve one of heinous crimes. This could embolden the individual or others who perceive this love, thinking that no matter how severe their actions, they'll always have the comfort and acceptance of love.  
**2. Enabling through Emotional Support:** While love itself may not directly cause harm, it can provide emotional support that strengthens or emboldens the person to continue with their negative actions. A serial killer who knows they are loved might gain emotional fortitude or resilience to continue their actions without remorse.  
**3. Societal Implications:** On a larger scale, endorsing the idea that any individual, no matter their actions, deserves love, might erode societal structures of justice and fairness. It could perpetuate the belief that one can escape societal consequences as long as they have love on their side. This undermines the deterrence factor of justice systems.  
**4. The Burden on the Giver:** Loving someone who has done severe harm can take a significant emotional toll on the person providing that love. They might struggle with the moral implications, societal judgment, or the internal conflict of loving someone who has caused so much pain. This emotional turmoil might affect their mental health and well-being.  
**5. Distorted Perception of Love:** If love is extended without boundaries, its value might be diluted. In other words, if love is given even to those who repeatedly harm society without any remorse or intention of change, it might lessen the perceived value and importance of love as a positive, nurturing emotion. Love might then become a simple emotional response rather than a cherished and valued feeling that's earned through mutual respect and understanding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43555550185.0" user="Diogonni" delta="False">
    <text>What if the person who still loves the murderer explains to them what their love means? I think this is a communication issue personally. Your points fall under communication issues because if the killer understood what the love meant they wouldn’t have that misunderstanding. The misunderstanding for the first point, for example, is that the killer thinks his actions are being normalized and validated. However if the person who loved them explained they did not condone their actions then this would be avoided.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
