<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2574675996.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16kw8po/cmv_aiassisted_conversations_can_enrich_human/">
    <title>CMV: AI-Assisted Conversations can enrich human interaction, not replace it</title>
    <original_poster>Atyzze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hold the view that AI-assisted conversations have the potential to serve as a valuable complement to human interaction rather than act as a threat or a replacement. While many fear that AI could diminish the quality of human relationships and communications, I believe that when used responsibly, it can actually enrich them. Here's why:

1. **Diverse Perspectives**: AI can provide a plethora of viewpoints quickly, enriching the depth and scope of conversations. It can make you consider aspects that might not naturally occur to you, thereby broadening your understanding.

2. **Prompting Emotional Exploration**: Similar to the Socratic method used in therapy, AI can pose questions or offer prompts that lead to deeper emotional awareness and self-discovery. It's not about AI having feelings, but about it helping us to explore our own.

3. **No Judgment Zone**: AI provides a safe space for people to express thoughts they may be hesitant to share with other humans initially. The absence of immediate emotional reaction can sometimes be helpful.

4. **Non-Dual Perspective**: From a holistic standpoint, technology is not separate from humanity. It is an extension of the interconnected web of existence. When used as a tool for positive change, AI can be harmoniously integrated into human life.

5. **Enhanced Self-Understanding**: With AI assistance, individuals may find it easier to articulate complex thoughts or emotions. The machine serves as a sounding board, allowing for clearer self-expression and, consequently, clearer communication with others.

6. **The Balance**: The point is not to replace one form of interaction with another but to use each to enrich the other. AI’s role is not to usurp but to support, thereby potentially strengthening the intricacies of human connection.

I invite you to challenge this view. Are there significant downsides to AI-assisted conversations that I'm not considering? Could AI, in fact, diminish the quality of human interaction, or is the potential for enrichment greater than we think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43594111976.0" user="Zoombluecar" delta="False">
    <text>AI will become skewed to give you feedback that meets your preferences. This is already seen with Facebook and this app - Reddit. 

Your argument is flawed because companies are not developing AI to help humanity but to sell stuff. The stuff maybe ads on the app or to direct you to a profitable opportunity- data collection. Data is then sold to companies that can target your wants. 

Imagine AI as the best salesperson ever. AI will “know” you objectives and be able to overcome them smoother faster better than a person. AI will learn to overcome the objectives before you have a chance to disagree. The sales approach will be rationale and hit all your Yes Buy emotions, so if you don’t purchase you will have remorse… with the seed planted to have buy soon.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
