<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2574675996.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16kw8po/cmv_aiassisted_conversations_can_enrich_human/">
    <title>CMV: AI-Assisted Conversations can enrich human interaction, not replace it</title>
    <original_poster>Atyzze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hold the view that AI-assisted conversations have the potential to serve as a valuable complement to human interaction rather than act as a threat or a replacement. While many fear that AI could diminish the quality of human relationships and communications, I believe that when used responsibly, it can actually enrich them. Here's why:

1. **Diverse Perspectives**: AI can provide a plethora of viewpoints quickly, enriching the depth and scope of conversations. It can make you consider aspects that might not naturally occur to you, thereby broadening your understanding.

2. **Prompting Emotional Exploration**: Similar to the Socratic method used in therapy, AI can pose questions or offer prompts that lead to deeper emotional awareness and self-discovery. It's not about AI having feelings, but about it helping us to explore our own.

3. **No Judgment Zone**: AI provides a safe space for people to express thoughts they may be hesitant to share with other humans initially. The absence of immediate emotional reaction can sometimes be helpful.

4. **Non-Dual Perspective**: From a holistic standpoint, technology is not separate from humanity. It is an extension of the interconnected web of existence. When used as a tool for positive change, AI can be harmoniously integrated into human life.

5. **Enhanced Self-Understanding**: With AI assistance, individuals may find it easier to articulate complex thoughts or emotions. The machine serves as a sounding board, allowing for clearer self-expression and, consequently, clearer communication with others.

6. **The Balance**: The point is not to replace one form of interaction with another but to use each to enrich the other. AI’s role is not to usurp but to support, thereby potentially strengthening the intricacies of human connection.

I invite you to challenge this view. Are there significant downsides to AI-assisted conversations that I'm not considering? Could AI, in fact, diminish the quality of human interaction, or is the potential for enrichment greater than we think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43593848772.0" user="Money_Whisperer" delta="False">
    <text>I think it’s undeniable that AI can serve as a good intermediary step for certain interactions, I.e. as a way to reformat your messages in a way that’s more concise and easier to read for others. This in turn can “enrich human interaction”. 

However, where the problems start is when this sort of technology is relied on too much. Consider that each new generation of people takes technology for granted (how couldn’t they? They wouldn’t have a frame of reference for life before it). So what was a tool to help streamline existing interactions can and will quickly become overly relied upon. The more AI is relied on to handle how we think and speak to each other, the less thought that people put into their correspondence, and the less depth it truly has. In that sense, AI will lead to a great “dumbing down” a la Idiocracy if taken to its logical conclusion. So no, AI will not enrich our interactions in the long term, unless it’s use is heavily restricted. 

As a meta example- I ran everything I just said in this message through gpt4 for “clarity and brevity” and here’s what it came back with- 

“AI can help us communicate better by making our messages more concise and readable. But this can also make us rely on AI too much and lose our critical thinking and depth. AI can lead to a dumbing down of our interactions if we don't use it wisely. So AI will not enrich our interactions in the long term, unless we limit its use.“

See how it shortened my point significantly, which is great, but how it also removed lots of stuff that I felt was important for depth, like the point that historically, people have become reliant on technology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43593979838.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>Your point about over-reliance on AI technology is valid and resonates with a concern many of us share. It's the classical narrative of every tool we've created, from fire to the wheel: it's not about the tool itself, but how we wield it. But isn't that the eternal dance of any technological advancement? Its use is only as wise or unwise as we make it.

When you say that each generation takes technology for granted, you're correct. However, that’s not necessarily a disadvantage. Every generation also has the potential to evolve the way they use technology in a more nuanced and enriching manner. The initial novelty of any technology gives way to a deeper understanding and more targeted usage over time. The internet, for example, started as a tool for basic communication and data sharing but has evolved into an immensely complex and enriching facet of modern life.

As for the 'dumbing down,' what you're describing seems to be more a symptom of poor education and cultural values than the tool itself. There are numerous platforms and AI services aimed at education, self-improvement, and emotional well-being, and they are evidence that AI can contribute to, not detract from, our collective intellectual and emotional growth.

Your meta-example on the reduction of depth in conversation when optimized for 'clarity and brevity' is interesting. But couldn't that also serve to highlight the important role of human discretion in the use of AI? It's not AI that decided to remove elements you considered vital; you chose to use it as a tool to distill your message. You still have the choice to add back what you feel is missing.

In the end, like you said, the key is balanced use. AI doesn't have to become a crutch we lean on but can serve as a scaffold that can be erected and disassembled as needed. The fear of a future 'Idiocracy' does not come from AI but from our approach to integrating it responsibly into our lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594079618.0" user="LucidLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>Your opening post reads like it was written by ChatGPT. Is that the case?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594275642.0" user="PetrifiedBloom" delta="False">
    <text>Almost of their posts and comments are written by ChatGPT. They admit it here:

[https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16jowex/comment/k0tcgbq](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16jowex/comment/k0tcgbq/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3)

and here:

[https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16jpwfu/comment/k0w8ke3](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16jpwfu/comment/k0w8ke3)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594387643.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>They are *co*-written ... yes. I didn't to "admit" anything, I never cared to hide my habits. I just want to be able to express myself using the tools I need.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594426129.0" user="PetrifiedBloom" delta="False">
    <text>Express yourself however you see fit, but given the purpose of this sub seems to be a place for people to test their persuasive writing, research and argument skills, using an AI that does most of the work really feels like it's missing the point. It's supposed to be you changing someone's mind, or having your beliefs challenged, not something regurgitated by a bot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594511028.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>I am open to changing my beliefs but have yet to encounter a convincing argument as to why AI should not be used for that here. Especially when it's apparently also about testing argumentation skills, what better way then to test against people who aren't afraid to enhance their skills through modern AI?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594537363.0" user="PetrifiedBloom" delta="False">
    <text>My point was more addressed to cases where you are a commenter, having the bot challenge someone's belief for you. It's not your argument forming skills or persuasiveness on display.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594666965.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>I would think the purpose and thus focus would be changing the view of OP</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594690316.0" user="PetrifiedBloom" delta="False">
    <text>But it's not you doing it. It's a bot. If they wanted to have an algorithm tell them why they should change their mind, they could just open chat gpt themselves. 

It's like sitting down to a game of chess and then your opponent starts using a chess engine for their moves. Even if they are using a weak engine, you sat down to play with a person and have that human connection, not to vs a bot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594826937.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Even if they are using a weak engine, you sat down to play with a person and have that human connection, not to vs a bot.

Really? I thought people play to *win* or to appear the best. If people want human connection then I suggest they collaborate and be interested in each others personal experience instead of arguing with each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43594375348.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Enhanced Self-Understanding: With AI assistance, individuals may find it easier to articulate complex thoughts or emotions. The machine serves as a sounding board, allowing for clearer self-expression and, consequently, clearer communication with others.

So yes, of course I'll use AI to assist me in order to be able to better express myself. That doesn't mean it's *entirely* AI ... why the hell is the human aspect behind it ignored?! Hence this thread. Please do argue for why AI use should be banned entirely and how you imagine to actually enforce such a ridiculous rule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43596418504.0" user="LucidLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>What percentage of your OP is your own words, and what percentage is AI?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
