<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2574675996.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16kw8po/cmv_aiassisted_conversations_can_enrich_human/">
    <title>CMV: AI-Assisted Conversations can enrich human interaction, not replace it</title>
    <original_poster>Atyzze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hold the view that AI-assisted conversations have the potential to serve as a valuable complement to human interaction rather than act as a threat or a replacement. While many fear that AI could diminish the quality of human relationships and communications, I believe that when used responsibly, it can actually enrich them. Here's why:

1. **Diverse Perspectives**: AI can provide a plethora of viewpoints quickly, enriching the depth and scope of conversations. It can make you consider aspects that might not naturally occur to you, thereby broadening your understanding.

2. **Prompting Emotional Exploration**: Similar to the Socratic method used in therapy, AI can pose questions or offer prompts that lead to deeper emotional awareness and self-discovery. It's not about AI having feelings, but about it helping us to explore our own.

3. **No Judgment Zone**: AI provides a safe space for people to express thoughts they may be hesitant to share with other humans initially. The absence of immediate emotional reaction can sometimes be helpful.

4. **Non-Dual Perspective**: From a holistic standpoint, technology is not separate from humanity. It is an extension of the interconnected web of existence. When used as a tool for positive change, AI can be harmoniously integrated into human life.

5. **Enhanced Self-Understanding**: With AI assistance, individuals may find it easier to articulate complex thoughts or emotions. The machine serves as a sounding board, allowing for clearer self-expression and, consequently, clearer communication with others.

6. **The Balance**: The point is not to replace one form of interaction with another but to use each to enrich the other. AI’s role is not to usurp but to support, thereby potentially strengthening the intricacies of human connection.

I invite you to challenge this view. Are there significant downsides to AI-assisted conversations that I'm not considering? Could AI, in fact, diminish the quality of human interaction, or is the potential for enrichment greater than we think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43593687063.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Diverse Perspectives: AI can provide a plethora of viewpoints quickly, enriching the depth and scope of conversations. It can make you consider aspects that might not naturally occur to you, thereby broadening your understanding.

The AI, by being a large, massive system that is thought statistically, has a tendency to narrow it's POV, not broaden it.

This is kind of inherent in the way it works. The AI learns how to do stuff by seeing the things that happen often, and it knows not to do stuff by seeing the things that happen rarely or not at all.
As such the aspect it can show will always be limited, and because there are going to be very few AI's around, they'll often have the same gaps in their knowledge. 

The AI can create the impression of a broader perspective, while actually leaving severe gaps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43593826639.0" user="Atyzze" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The AI, by being a large, massive system that is thought statistically, has a tendency to narrow it's POV, not broaden it.

Nope, you can ask it to broaden your POV and it will. It is not *designed* to be narrow. It does however have a bias towards science of course. But it can perfectly explore spiritual topics without dismissing them due to its science knowledge.

&gt;The AI learns how to do stuff by seeing the things that happen often, and it knows not to do stuff by seeing the things that happen rarely or not at all. 

Same goes for humans.

&gt;As such the aspect it can show will always be limited

Same goes for humans, except that AI can transcend the knowledge and experience set limits of what is humanly possible. A human has about 100 years of experience worth of potential time to grow, read and accumulate knowledge and wisdom. AI has read nearly all books in all languages. No human will ever be able to match that.

&gt;and because there are going to be very few AI's around,

Huh? It's already nearly free available to anyone. There's no limit to the amount of AI's that can be around.

&gt;they'll often have the same gaps in their knowledge.

Same can be said about humans, and yet, again, machines can accumulate and process information way faster than any human.

&gt;AI models can express judgement (or at least imitate it), and they can certainly express severe misjudgement.

Of course they can when asked to, it's neutral, it'll do whatever you ask it to. End users will of course remain limited to the programmed in limitations such as not cooperating with how to make bombs and what not.

In my personal experience, I have never ever felt judged by AI.

Feel free to bring forth your own conversations and let me know where you felt judged, I am interested.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
