<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="257705290.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/">
    <title>CMV: I don't believe in punishment.</title>
    <original_poster>meur123</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't believe in punishment. I believe it's petty. I believe it does no good and only harm. As the old saying goes: "An eye for an eye makes the world blind." What does punishment actually achieve? If you kill somebody who killed somebody, it doesn't in any way bring them back. 

Look, I believe that we should have prisons, but not for punishment. The only reason to take away somebodies freedom is to prevent further harm to society. What has already been done is done. Prisons should focus instead on rehabilitation. If somebody is likely to cause harm to another, then it is necessary we take the means to prevent that. If they do not pose a danger, then it achieves nothing to take away their freedom.

**EDIT:** [I awarded a delta to someone that challenged the arguments of this final paragraph.](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/d0regc3)

&amp;gt;Before you mention deterrence, I agree that we should aim to cut the problem out before it happens. Where I don't agree is that fear is an effective motivator. A much better solution would be to eliminate the conditions that coerce people into turning to crime.

Talking about deterrence was really tangential to the argument that I was actually making, and I was wrong to say that it is not in any way an effective tool.

But CMV, does punishment achieve anything for the greater good?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28344199615.0" user="potato59" delta="False">
    <text>Many unfavorable behaviors are self-rewarding. Positive reinforcement wouldn't be enough to deter people from actions that might be intrinsically gratifying, or at least more gratifying at the moment than the values imposing against them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344210086.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Do these actions harm others? If so, then put them in prison or force them to pay compensation/restitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344763527.0" user="3xtheredcomet" delta="False">
    <text>These are punishments, are they not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344964325.0" user="kerfer" delta="False">
    <text>They are not. The purpose of putting people in prison to prevent them from harming others is not punishment. Forcing people to pay restitution is also not done so to punish people- it's to make the victim whole again</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
