<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="257705290.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/">
    <title>CMV: I don't believe in punishment.</title>
    <original_poster>meur123</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't believe in punishment. I believe it's petty. I believe it does no good and only harm. As the old saying goes: "An eye for an eye makes the world blind." What does punishment actually achieve? If you kill somebody who killed somebody, it doesn't in any way bring them back. 

Look, I believe that we should have prisons, but not for punishment. The only reason to take away somebodies freedom is to prevent further harm to society. What has already been done is done. Prisons should focus instead on rehabilitation. If somebody is likely to cause harm to another, then it is necessary we take the means to prevent that. If they do not pose a danger, then it achieves nothing to take away their freedom.

**EDIT:** [I awarded a delta to someone that challenged the arguments of this final paragraph.](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/d0regc3)

&amp;gt;Before you mention deterrence, I agree that we should aim to cut the problem out before it happens. Where I don't agree is that fear is an effective motivator. A much better solution would be to eliminate the conditions that coerce people into turning to crime.

Talking about deterrence was really tangential to the argument that I was actually making, and I was wrong to say that it is not in any way an effective tool.

But CMV, does punishment achieve anything for the greater good?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28344194355.0" user="ExploreMeDora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A much better solution would be to eliminate the conditions that coerce people into turning to crime.

Crime is a multi-causal phenomenon and it is inevitable. You are aiming for something that is near impossible.

Punishment is justified for several reasons:

1. Punishing law violators provides beneficial consequences. The public is protected from criminals.

2. Punishment is deserved. Criminals are blameworthy for violations of the law that they are either aware of or should be aware of. Similarly, citizens are aware of punishments that are attached to different crimes.

3. Punishment expresses public outrage. Wrongdoers provoke public sorrow and anger, especially for the victim or those who know the victim. There is an outcry for justice.

4. Punishment teaches a lesson. Those who are punished may be deterred from committing crime again so that they do not have to be punished. The cost of committing the crime outweighs the benefit of committing it.

5. Punishment helps maintain the government, the social structure, and society. Punishment is necessary for a functioning society. Laws and punishment provide structure and prohibit undesirable, harmful activities.

Furthermore, there are several goals of punishment:

1. Deterrence - both general and specific. Punishment can deter citizens from committing crimes and deter criminals from recommitting crimes. 

2. Incapacitation. This isolates offenders and protects society. It also prohibits criminals from being able to continue with their illegal mischief for a certain period of time.

3. Rehabilitation. This is meant to change the offenders’ attitudes, views, and actions in the future. The punishment is meant to be a lesson and the offender should learn why his/her actions were wrong and should never be repeated. The goal is to turn a criminal into a law-abiding citizen who respects the law when released.

4. Retribution/Just Deserts. The offender must pay for his/her actions in a manner proportionate to the crime that was committed. He/she pays in the form of confinement and stripped freedom/privileges. 

5. Restorative Justice. A program designed to reintroduce the offender back into the community.

6. Equity/Restitution. The offender must pay back the victim in some way as well as the justice system and society. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344325568.0" user="meur123" delta="False">
    <text>In hindsight, I was being too idealistic when I wrote that last paragraph. That would be the best situation, in most cases. Not one that is practical all of the time. &amp;amp;#8710; 

What I do believe, is that all of the goals of justice you listed have a place *except for retribution.* That was the main focus of my CMV, and it was silly of me to go on a tangent talking about what is and isn't an effective motivator for not committing crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344387987.0" user="ExploreMeDora" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you! I would just like to add that retribution in our criminal justice system does not quite reflect the eye for an eye model you described. If this were the case we would be raping rapists, etc. Punishments are meant to just outweigh the benefit of committing the crime. They must be proportionate to crimes so that we can understand their severity. For example, a small drug charge may carry a short sentence, where as a murder will carry a tremendous sentence.

Also, where you say, "Does punishment achieve anything for the greater good?" Essentially, the most obvious example of the greater good in this case is the safety of society. Therefore, this falls under incapacitation as a goal for punishment. Incapacitation accomplishes the greater good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345341345.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>If the government is seen as failing to enact any retribution, then victims or their families retain the perceived obligation to enact retribution.  This is extremely destabilizing for a society - one of the most basic responsibilities of a government is to eliminate the cycle of revenge by taking over everyone's retribution for them.  

Imagine if embezzlers were merely sentenced to new job training and not working with others' money.  You steal as much as you want as an accountant; the government lets you live in your old house and go to six months of forensic accounting classes, then you are being paid even more money to look for other embezzlers.  Might work out well in terms of preventing embezzlement.  But the people you stole from would feel that justice had not been served.  They would take legal or illegal action to get vengeance.  The government can limit this as much as practical, but it has to be seen as taking effective vengeance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28348514659.0" user="TheSkyPirate" delta="False">
    <text>So looking at your first list specifically because I feel that the second list is mostly just a restatement:

Point 1/4/5 (which sort of say the same thing) on your list, the utility of deterrence, is the only valid reason for punishment.  The instinct to inflict harm on those judged to "deserve" it, not for the sake of achieving some goal, but just because it is good to hurt "bad" people, can not be rigorously defended.  We want to make the best possible world for everyone, not just for an somewhat arbitrarily selected group of "good" people.  This comes into play with moral calculations about just and unjust laws: a law is unjust if more harm is inflicted on "criminals" and their families than is prevented by the reduction in the rate of that crime being committed.  

Your third point about public outrage/mob justice is a bit scary. Making laws just to satisfy the anger and bloodlust of the mob is a extremely dangerous.  That's why we have judges and a legal process:  if you're going to deliberately inflict harm on someone, you need to take that very seriously and have an objective party look at all of the available evidence and come to a fair decision.  The punishment needs to be fair and proportional to the crime committed, not proportional to how angry the mob is.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28348587697.0" user="ExploreMeDora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; not for the sake of achieving some goal

I outlined the goals. 

&amp;gt; not just for an somewhat arbitrarily selected group of "good" people.

It isn't arbitrarily selected. There are clear laws in our society and people who violate them are law-breakers.

&amp;gt; a law is unjust if more harm is inflicted on "criminals" and their families than is prevented by the reduction in the rate of that crime being committed.

Punishments are designed to just outweigh the benefit of committing the crime. They are meant to be proportionate. After all, swiftness, certain, and proportion are important factors in deterrence.

&amp;gt; The punishment needs to be fair and proportional to the crime committed, not proportional to how angry the mob is.

And it is. The point that it expresses public outrage is that it fulfills justice. Of course the punishment is not executed just to satisfy what the angry mob of people may want to do. It is carried out according to the system. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28348751059.0" user="TheSkyPirate" delta="False">
    <text>Yes your outlined the goals, specifying in point 1: 

&amp;gt;Punishing law violators provides beneficial consequences

This implies that points 2 and 3 are not directly related to some practical goal such as public security, but rather punishment specifically for the sake of the fundamental good of inflicting harm in certain cases (point 2), or for the purposes of emotional satisfaction (to satisfy public anger, point 3).  This is a biological or culturally ingrained human instinct, and does not in all cases correspond to a rational imperative to inflict punishment in order to deter future crime.  

And I agree with you that punishment should exceed the potential gain from a crime in order to create a rational motivation not to commit the crime.  However, there is some ceiling on what qualifies as a just punishment for a given crime.  The punishment must be proportional to the crime.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
