<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="257705290.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/">
    <title>CMV: I don't believe in punishment.</title>
    <original_poster>meur123</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't believe in punishment. I believe it's petty. I believe it does no good and only harm. As the old saying goes: "An eye for an eye makes the world blind." What does punishment actually achieve? If you kill somebody who killed somebody, it doesn't in any way bring them back. 

Look, I believe that we should have prisons, but not for punishment. The only reason to take away somebodies freedom is to prevent further harm to society. What has already been done is done. Prisons should focus instead on rehabilitation. If somebody is likely to cause harm to another, then it is necessary we take the means to prevent that. If they do not pose a danger, then it achieves nothing to take away their freedom.

**EDIT:** [I awarded a delta to someone that challenged the arguments of this final paragraph.](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/d0regc3)

&amp;gt;Before you mention deterrence, I agree that we should aim to cut the problem out before it happens. Where I don't agree is that fear is an effective motivator. A much better solution would be to eliminate the conditions that coerce people into turning to crime.

Talking about deterrence was really tangential to the argument that I was actually making, and I was wrong to say that it is not in any way an effective tool.

But CMV, does punishment achieve anything for the greater good?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28344194803.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>How would you ever teach children to follow the rules if there were no unpleasant consequences for breaking the rules?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344206271.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>I've never punished my child a day in his life, and his behaviour is perfectly fine. 

Making someone behave better doesn't require making them feel worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344248563.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>How old is your child?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344363510.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>9.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344966498.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>How do you deal with rule-breaking at home? And how are you planning to deal with rule-breaking when your child goes through adolescence? Or are you one of those parents who allows your child to do anything  and who leaves discipline to other people at school and in the community?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344997660.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>If he does something he shouldn't, I tell him not to, until he stops - and where appropriate, apologizes and/or agrees not to keep doing it. 

There's plenty of discipline in this house - I just don't need to use pain or fear or deprivation or misery in general in order to achieve it. 

If you don't start out with an adversarial relationship, you don't need to maintain one. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345025914.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>So how would you deal with it if he continued to break the same rule over and over again? I'm wondering if you use ''parental disapproval'' as your tool to keep him in line - it can work very well on emotionally sensitive children, but has little effect on the more reckless and impulsive and sociopathic type of children, so maybe you got lucky with having a child of the former type.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344218165.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Why wouldn't there be unpleasant consequences? There would be plenty. OP says:

&amp;gt; I believe that we should have prisons... The only reason to take away somebodies freedom is to prevent further harm to society.... If somebody is likely to cause harm to another, then it is necessary we take the means to prevent that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344250742.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>I'm asking how you would teach children to follow the rules - you can't put children in prison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344254609.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Hrmm. That's interesting.

That said, many children are raised just fine without "punishment".

You broke your toy... well, you don't get a new one. That's not "punishment" as much as it is economic reality. You beat up your cousins? Okay... you don't get to see them anymore (for their own protection).

There are plenty of natural consequences available, without having to resort to contrived "punishments".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344556569.0" user="insipid_comment" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You broke your toy... well, you don't get a new one. That's not "punishment" as much as it is economic reality. You beat up your cousins? Okay... you don't get to see them anymore (for their own protection).

&amp;gt;There are plenty of natural consequences available, without having to resort to contrived "punishments".

I'd say if the cousins start to avoid the belligerent child, it is a natural consequence. If an adult intervenes to refuse to let them see each other it is an imposed consequence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344960840.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>What are the negative consequences for the child when he jumps on the parents' bed with muddy shoes on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345012752.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>This is not an answer, it's a question even more difficult than the original CMV. Ask 10 parents and you get 10 different answers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345027093.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>It's an answer because it shows that punishment is sometimes necessary as the only way to teach a person how to keep to the rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345036016.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>Punishment of children is sometimes necessary? That's your opinion, and many others would agree with it. But it's not a consensus. It's not enough to be used at proof.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345038703.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>I think the only way it could be ''proved'' to you would be if you were in the position of responsibility for bringing up a child who is reckless and impulsive and a bit sociopathic, and who does not take any notice of polite requests to follow rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345047033.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>If I get children I'm gonna punish them when they get reckless because that's the only method I know. Don't argue with me. Argue with these guys: https://www.google.com/search?q=educating+children+without+punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28345051148.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>I only need to argue the point with OP - if OP agrees then my point has served its purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
