<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="257705290.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/">
    <title>CMV: I don't believe in punishment.</title>
    <original_poster>meur123</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't believe in punishment. I believe it's petty. I believe it does no good and only harm. As the old saying goes: "An eye for an eye makes the world blind." What does punishment actually achieve? If you kill somebody who killed somebody, it doesn't in any way bring them back. 

Look, I believe that we should have prisons, but not for punishment. The only reason to take away somebodies freedom is to prevent further harm to society. What has already been done is done. Prisons should focus instead on rehabilitation. If somebody is likely to cause harm to another, then it is necessary we take the means to prevent that. If they do not pose a danger, then it achieves nothing to take away their freedom.

**EDIT:** [I awarded a delta to someone that challenged the arguments of this final paragraph.](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/49fioa/cmv_i_dont_believe_in_punishment/d0regc3)

&amp;gt;Before you mention deterrence, I agree that we should aim to cut the problem out before it happens. Where I don't agree is that fear is an effective motivator. A much better solution would be to eliminate the conditions that coerce people into turning to crime.

Talking about deterrence was really tangential to the argument that I was actually making, and I was wrong to say that it is not in any way an effective tool.

But CMV, does punishment achieve anything for the greater good?
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28344188962.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>If nothing else, you appear to not be considering civil cases. You can't meaningfully do anything to a company that breaks a contract, for example, except by punishing it. There are enough cases where companies already do not honor contracts because it's expensive to make them do so in court- how much worse would this be if you couldn't even award punitive damages?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344192799.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>People that harm other people are removed from society. 

A company that breaks the law should have to pay back the taxes they stole, and if need be, they should be shut down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344196136.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>I edited my comment to be "contracts" while you were in the middle of responding, it seems. At any rate, shutting down a company that breaks laws is a punishment. It's like the death penalty for companies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344212062.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>What's wrong with that? If they are harming society, then they should be removed from society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344215738.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely nothing is wrong with it. (Well, alright, it's a little draconian.) But the point is it's a punishment by the standards OP has laid out- you're harming the individual(s) running the corporation, and not putting them in jail directly. So you need punishments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344222393.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain what you mean?

OP is okay with removing people from society that are a threat to society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344226182.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>Unless you want to put the corporation owner in jail, you didn't remove anyone from society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344230058.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Well that would depend on whether the company broke the law, or whether the employees of the company also broke the law too. One doesn't necessarily require the other.

However, I was simply talking about removing *the company* from society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344235158.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>That's fine, but companies are fictional entities. You don't actually do much directly for society by removing it if the person who started the company can simply start another one with similar tactics if it's successful. So either you say something like anyone who starts companies that tend not to fulfill contracts is put in jail, or you accept that a large portion of companies won't fulfill contracts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344239836.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>Companies are not fictional entities. That's silly. They are real. They have real employees. They produce real products or real services. And the take in and pay out in real money. How is that not "real"?

&amp;gt; You don't actually do anything for society by removing it- the person who started the company can simply start another one with similar tactics if it's successful.

A company can be 'bad' but still be full of 'good' people. The company is more than the sum of it's parts. No individual employee has to consciously/intentionally break the law for a company to have polices in place that lead to law-breaking.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344250619.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>Companies are not real in the sense that they exist solely in human heads and work because humans agree they work. This is what I mean by "fictional." 

At any rate, this is beside the point. The question is if removing a company consists of "punishment" in a meaningful sense. It presumably punishes the individuals who created the company and set bad policies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344256380.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>But those individuals aren't "punished" as a form of revenge. They simply deal with the fallout and natural consequences of their actions. I believe OP would be okay with this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344260934.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>The OP's CMV is not "revenge is wrong." They specifically mention punishment as deterrence as something they would object to- this would be a form of punishment meant to deter individuals from making corporations that have this behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344272033.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>It's not to be a deterrent. It doesn't have to be.

It's meant to be an action taken to protect society (and maybe involve restitution/compensation as well). Deterrence doesn't have to be involved *at all*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344280203.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>For the sake of argument, view it that way. It still constitutes a punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344284172.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>The OP is okay with taking action to protect society. He/she never said they had a problem with that.

&amp;gt; Look, I believe that we should have prisons... The only reason to take away somebodies freedom **is to prevent further harm to society**... If somebody is likely to cause harm to another, then it is necessary we take the means to prevent that. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344310206.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>They're specifically talking about actions to take away someone's freedom. Nobody's freedom is being taken away here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28344360283.0" user="meur123" delta="False">
    <text>Shutting down a company, and preventing those responsible from being self employed or in a managerial position for a period of time would certainly be taking away a freedom. This would be a reasonable action to take, since sending them to jail and isolating them from society would not make any sense since they have not proven themselves to be violent people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
