<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="258580368.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49y9w0/cmv_to_combat_rape_and_counteract_the_general/">
    <title>CMV: To combat rape and counteract the general physical advantage men have over women, girls should be taught self-defence at school, specifically anti-rape techniques.</title>
    <original_poster>Wonderslave</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____

During a self-defence class I attended, the instructor demonstrated several techniques for women to use when attacked by a rapist. He explained that the positions a male rapist would need to assume to rape a female victim are actually extremely vulnerable from a ground fighting perspective. Correctly applied Brazilian jui-jitsu would use the attacker's weight against him and provide an opportunity for the victim to attack (the eyes, usually) and then escape.

I'm not a martial arts expert but if this is all true, then girls should be taught to defend themselves from rape and assault, possibly in their early teens. It's not a panacea for sexual violence, I admit, but it will empower women physically and be an effective deterrent.  

Edit: Found a Youtube video with the kind of techniques I'm talking about: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6D8r-wH0dkk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28352810771.0" user="Yanginyangout" delta="False">
    <text>While I might agree with the inherent positive step of teaching all kids Self defense and deescalation of violence, I have 3 issues with this plan.

1) Effectiveness of female Self defense:  the overall effectiveness of anti rape Self defense tactics on the whole is highly questionable.   Effective statistically maybe, but on the whole would likely barely if at all make a dent in actual numbers of rapes.  This would begin the question of the utility of the practice.  Largely, the ineffective nature of the program would be driven by the simple overpowering nature of male strength and speed, the intensity of training required to be even minimally effective, the likelihood of familiarity of attackers that would put potential victims in positions where they are unable to employ defense tactics and.....

2)  Attenuation:  there is no reason to believe rapists wouldn't up their rape game and adapt to the self defense techniques, especially as they became well known engert masse.  Not only would this neutralize such training, but it could be actively used against them.

3) As others have mentioned,  the context of most rapes being from familiar figures often in dating situations would neutralize the ability to employ such techniques as the assailant would likely be in close before danger was realized.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
