<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="258580368.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49y9w0/cmv_to_combat_rape_and_counteract_the_general/">
    <title>CMV: To combat rape and counteract the general physical advantage men have over women, girls should be taught self-defence at school, specifically anti-rape techniques.</title>
    <original_poster>Wonderslave</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____

During a self-defence class I attended, the instructor demonstrated several techniques for women to use when attacked by a rapist. He explained that the positions a male rapist would need to assume to rape a female victim are actually extremely vulnerable from a ground fighting perspective. Correctly applied Brazilian jui-jitsu would use the attacker's weight against him and provide an opportunity for the victim to attack (the eyes, usually) and then escape.

I'm not a martial arts expert but if this is all true, then girls should be taught to defend themselves from rape and assault, possibly in their early teens. It's not a panacea for sexual violence, I admit, but it will empower women physically and be an effective deterrent.  

Edit: Found a Youtube video with the kind of techniques I'm talking about: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6D8r-wH0dkk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28351665751.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>I think a lot of women who are being attacked have an instinctive understanding that if they start to fight back, their attacker will use an even stronger amount of violence against them ... their number one priority is to survive the attack with as little damage as possible, even if that means taking a submissive position ... I'm not saying there is a right and wrong way to respond to an attack, and I do enjoy hearing stories of women who fought off their attacker, and it's fine to learn self defence, but I don't think women should be made to feel that they *must* fight back, and a little bit of self defence training can lead to a horrific counter-attack which leaves them worse off.

I think it's important to teach women to do what they feel is best in the moment, whether that is to fight or to submit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351680118.0" user="Wonderslave" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that women shouldn't be told to fight back. But nor should they be told not to. My CMV is about whether or not they should be taught these techniques, not whether or not they should do x or y if attacked. Give them the tools to even the field as much as possible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351709024.0" user="caffeine_lights" delta="False">
    <text>What would be the point of training somebody to do something that they shouldn't do? This IS central to your argument, not a handy fact you can brush aside.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351737452.0" user="Wonderslave" delta="False">
    <text>I said that they shouldn't be told what to do one way or the other. It's up to them. Individual actions are up to the individual. The point of training somebody is to empower them with options and a chance at fighting back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351733159.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>I'm certainly not against teaching women self defence techniques, as long as there is no suggestion in the lessons that this is what they must do, or that this is what is best to do - because sometimes it is far worse to attempt to use these techniques, and this must be emphasised to the students.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351746475.0" user="Wonderslave" delta="False">
    <text>I agree but only in theory, really. What's best will vary according to the individual. I'm reluctant to compare fighting back to prevent being raped but risking further harm and *not* fighting back, being raped, but preventing further harm. 

It's a heinous dilemma to find oneself in and I could never think to judge one way to be more right/smart than the other. 

I just think women should be empowered with better odds. Even if it only really works for the "stranger rape" cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351752784.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps what we need at this point in the discussion is a study to see if women with a *little* self defence training fare any better than women with no self defence training ... I don't automatically assume that a little self defence training will improve their odds, and can imagine it might lead to worse outcomes in some cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28352470117.0" user="PepperoniFire" delta="False">
    <text>Consider that even with some self-defense skill, the match is likely to be uneven.  Furthering the notion that self-defense will have a non-negligible impact when attacked provides a false sense of security that might result in more risk-taking behavior, resulting in a net loss of personal safety.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
