<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730332283.0" user="PMMEUR_3RD_BEST_NUDE" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence.

Ya, that's not true. Plenty of people do that. 

&gt;However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years.

Or you know, getting wealthier and wealthier by increasing your skill set, spending wisely, and investing prudently. 

&gt;Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors.

I think "the left's" issue is that it broadly introduces solutions, tries those solutions, blames conservatives when those solutions fail, and rarely analyzes why those solutions failed. 

&gt;It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself.

Are they? 

&gt;They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie.

Perhaps if "the left" was less willing to lie about their failed policies and was better at course correcting fewer people would be on the right. 

&gt; Although the left may lack immediate solutions

Or long-term solutions, much of the time. 

&gt; In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth.

"The left" hasn't been unwilling to lie, many on "the left" lie all the time. It hasn't caused people to flok to "the left." 

&gt;A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.

Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730344604.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Source?

Nazi Germany.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730591058.0" user="PMMEUR_3RD_BEST_NUDE" delta="False">
    <text>Germany was more prone to believing unfounded claims as compared to which other country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730961260.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>Why didn’t you respond to any of the other points in that comment? 

Why do you believe it is illegal for a poor person to make money and become rich? 

As you are advocating for lying and dishonesty do you practice them yourself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43731497977.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>I read them, I just wasn't convinced. I can go through each one and respond, "I'm not convinced", but that seems rude.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
