<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730099075.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>the left has solutions you just never heard of then  and they never been implement becuz the left never held anypower</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730299051.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t act as if you speak for the left, we don’t welcome homophobes like you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730538766.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>you literaly support the eua how can you say youre part of the left?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730574803.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>What does emergency use authorisation have to do with you condoning the murder of gay people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730596324.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>what are you trying to say?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730602088.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>You keep talking about the EUA (emergency use authorisation) and I don’t see how it’s relevant to you being a homophobe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730657149.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>i still dont get it?  
and no leftist suports the eua , so youre not one</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730689635.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>What does Emergency Use Authorisation have to do with anything? Whatever it is you mean, it’s probably still further left then Russia, which executes gay people, but you support that, don’t you?

I am further left than you because I actually care about the rights of gay people no matter what country they live in. You, who are willing to trade their lives to score political points, are just an evil human, and we on the left do not want anything to do with scum like you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730714441.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>i still dont get what you mean but that....  
and no i dont support russia , but you suport the eua witch no one on the left would do , so youre still a rightie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730728732.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>So do you or do you not condemn the abuse of lgbtq people by the Russian government?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730887070.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text> still dont get what you mean that...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730915586.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>Mate, you are the one who keeps bringing up the emergency use authorisation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730687574.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>What does Emergency Use Authorisation have to do with anything? Whatever it is you mean, it’s probably still further left then Russia, which executes gay people, but you support that, don’t you?

I am further left than you because I actually care about the rights of gay people no matter what country they live in. You, who are willing to trade their lives to score political points, are just an evil human, and we on the left do not want anything to do with scum like you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43732449597.0" user="seanflyon" delta="False">
    <text>That is a serious accusation that should be accompanied by some sort of evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43732469813.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>I had an argument with them largely centered on Russias actions as of late, and they refused to give a opinion on Russias treatment of lgbtq (especially in the Chechnya region) despite calling the US out for certain states having homophobic legislation. Any other statement I made would get a rebuttal except when I was asking their opinion on Russias treatment of lgbtq people, then it was silence. They also refused to take a stance on if an invasion is justified if it is in order to stop a genocide after saying “all war is immoral”. At one point they were giving excuses for nazi germany by saying it wouldn’t have happened if there hadn’t been economic issues and blaming the Holocaust (and all genocide) on capitalism as the root cause. Really crazy stuff tbh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43732505323.0" user="seanflyon" delta="False">
    <text>I just spent a few minutes looking through their comments and saw enough to say that I think you claims are plausible.  They are certainly creepy and pro-Russian.  I still think that you should not make that kind of accusation without including some form of evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730594485.0" user="keelanv10" delta="False">
    <text>No educated leftist supports Russia, but then again you are an idiot so what more can we realistically expect from you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730926510.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
