<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730332010.0" user="GadgetGamer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues...

Have you not heard of the various trials of universal basic income (UBI), would give everyone a guaranteed wage to cover basic living regardless of employment status?

Then there is the Left's efforts to raise the minimum wage to offset over a decade of stagnation.

Add to this their efforts to make education more affordable so that people who are motivated to raise their job prospects are not restricted by their ability to pay for it.

How about the infrastructure investments that the Biden administration has successfully used to create jobs.

Further living costs are reduced by the Left's aims for universal healthcare, as lack of access to healthcare results in poor health quality and an enormous burden on the family budget. Medical issues are a major cause of bankruptcies, and it disproportionately affects the already-disadvantaged people.

So there is no reason to lie. The Left simply has to point to their own policies.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
