<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730240200.0" user="merlinus12" delta="False">
    <text>If the only way to save democracy is to ‘fool the voters’ you haven’t saved democracy. You might save a party, a policy, a politician, but you’ve done so at the expense of democracy.

And frankly, if democracy is merely a system that picks the most persuasive liar, I’m not sure it’s worth saving anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730279451.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>Right now, it's the most persuasive liars VS the defenders of decorum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730310251.0" user="merlinus12" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, I’m not really sure that Republicans are that persuasive. Trump’s voters don’t really believe he is truthful. They just don’t care because he is on their team.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730329007.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Trump’s voters don’t really believe he is truthful. They just don’t care because he is on their team.

Exactly. If we knew how to lie better they'd be on our team and we wouldn't have a presidential candidate advocating for authoritarian fascism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730702520.0" user="merlinus12" delta="False">
    <text>On what basis do you draw that conclusion?

Trump is a *bad liar.* His followers aren’t loyal to him based on the *quality of his lies* but because they are *conservative lies* and they are *already conservative.*

Put another way, every democratic politician is already a better liar than Trump (almost by definition - ‘cause he’s terrible at it). That hasn’t helped them to steal any of his base, because his base don’t like him because he’s a liar, they like him because he tells them what they want to hear. The only way democrats can beat him at that game is by becoming conservative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730761265.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That hasn’t helped them to steal any of his base, because his base don’t like him because he’s a liar, they like him because he tells them what they want to hear.

The things they want to hear are lies. 

&gt;The only way democrats can beat him at that game is by becoming conservative.

I believe the left could just as easily come up with their own lies that their voters want to hear. Left-wing voters are often enthusiastic about a UBI. If a Democrat wanted to promise to make it happen they could. Obviously, their donors will never allow it to happen, but it's better than what they're doing now, which is not address wage issues at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730832103.0" user="merlinus12" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The things they want to hear are lies.

Yes. But not just *any* lies. Lies that promote their side and hurt the democrats. So again, unless you want the democrats to steal republican voters by becoming republicans, it won’t help you steal their base.

&gt; Obviously their donors would never allow that to happen…

AND that explains nicely why the republican strategy (tell the base whatever it wants to hear, even if it’s lies) won’t work on the left side of the aisle. The left is too divided - there isn’t one ‘base’ that all wants the same thing. The high end donors are socially liberal and economically moderate. The working class base is economically liberal and socially moderate. Any ‘Trump-esque lie’ (an exaggerated, unrealistic but liberal-base-satisfying promise) would gain points with one side only by pissing off the other.

Democratic politicians aren’t moderate by accident, but by design. That’s how they keep their coalition together. Stray from the popular middle and you alienate one demographic in the hopes of mollifying another.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
