<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730035589.0" user="unbotheredotter" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence.

What!? There are tons of government programs that redistribute wealth. The only argument is about whether to expand or cut these programs. To say they don't exist is just ignorant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730095335.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that while it's possible to earn enough wealth to not have to work, it's not likely for the vast majority. For whom it is unlikely, there's a risk that they'll believe anyone selling them hope in the form of false narrative. The left should also be willing to sell false narratives, if only to inspire hope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730160419.0" user="unbotheredotter" delta="False">
    <text>Financial independence and not having to work are two different things. You don't think anyone from a disadvantaged background has ever been able to afford to retire? That's obviously wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43735468754.0" user="Redditardus" delta="False">
    <text>Well well, what about UBI or social security? That seems feasible. Then wealth would not be the issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43735457674.0" user="Redditardus" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, exactly. There are plenty of them and they work. Conservatives just try to prevent and block their implementation because it threatens their sense of hierarchy and justice</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
