<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730029050.0" user="GogurtFiend" delta="False">
    <text>Moral grounds aside, lying to the public never ends well.

Within the context of US politics: look how it turned out for the Republicans.

The modern Republican Party has a base heavily influenced by (albeit not solely composed of) various flavors of religious fanatic or blatant bigot, none of whom will let the Republican party as a whole moderate its stance on anything. Such people have been fed lies for a good portion of their lives and that, combined with a lack of education and experience with people outside their comfort zone, has turned them into who they are now.

You want a communist-flavored version of MAGA instead of a facist-flavored version? Left-wing politicians and media lying to the public is how you get a communist-flavored version of MAGA thirty, forty years down the line. The right tried that starting roughly in the 1980s, and look where it got them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730152814.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You want a communist-flavored version of MAGA instead of a facist-flavored version?

To an extent, yes. 

&gt;The right tried that starting roughly in the 1980s, and look where it got them.

Let's say that fascism was in full effect as of tomorrow. They close the border, deport all illegal immigrants, and it doesn't make Americans any richer. Ok, deport the legal immigrants. Still not richer. Ok, deport all POC. Still not richer. Ok, kill all the non-Christians. Still not richer. 

This can go on forever. Anyone has the potential to be the next target. Sure, it'll never work, but most won't live long enough to run out of people to get rid of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730893867.0" user="GogurtFiend" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;To an extent, yes.

So you're fine with politically motivated shootings or attacks on the Capitol provided that they're left-wing in nature?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43731014656.0" user="SteadfastEnd" delta="False">
    <text>Then you're basically saying that American voters will only have 2 parties to choose from at the ballot box: a fascist, lying party or a communist, lying party.

It shouldn't be hard to see why that dystopia is........unappealing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
