<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730231832.0" user="throwawaydanc3rrr" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence.

This is false.  My dad was born poor, like not knowing where there next meal was going to come from poor, and quituated high school at 17 and rather than go into the coal mines went into the Marine Corps.  He got his GED, then went to school at night, then got a Master's degree.  When he passed away he had two modest houses and money saved for mom.

He stands as a counter example of your point.  

If you add more people to the labor pool then there is downward pressure on wages, this is not rocket science.  When you add million of low skilled labor into the labor market do you know who that impacts the most?  The current low skilled laborers.  

You might think that the right wanting to limit immigration to legal entrants as a bad idea but as an idea to raise wages, it is a solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730258022.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You might think that the right wanting to limit immigration to legal entrants as a bad idea but as an idea to raise wages, it is a solution.

If companies can outsource it's a moot point. It's not a feasible solution. A better solution, one that takes outsourcing into account, is socialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730316883.0" user="throwawaydanc3rrr" delta="False">
    <text>Your reply is nonsense.

What immigration does the right want to stop?  The illegal immigration.  Illegal aliens work off the books for cheaper than citizens.  

Here's a tip, those workers are not taking the jobs that can be outsourced.  It is not like the illegal aliens are physicians and engineers.  

Socialism is a fever dream based upon the idea of factories as the principle mechanism for employing the masses.  Factory work is skilled work, and the United States has among the highest level of skilled labor in the world.  Mexico has some and has every right to be proud of what it is has been doing to improve itself in that regard over the last 10-20 years.  But guess what?  Those factory workers are not leaving their jobs and the houses they bought to enter the country illegally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43734708041.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>And they do jobs nobody else wants to do.

Nobody wants to send twelve hours a day picking strawberries in hundred and ten degree heat waves, nobody wants to install shingles, nobody wants to frame houses.

If your house was built even somewhat recently anywhere near the border odds are half the people who built it are illegal immigrants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43735364192.0" user="throwawaydanc3rrr" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If your house was built even somewhat recently anywhere near the border odds are half the people who built it are illegal immigrants.

I am nowhere near the border and that was true for my roof.  At this point every state is a border state.

As for doing jobs that nobody else will do that is an incomplete statement.  They are doing jobs that nobody else is doing at the wages they are being paid.  Everyone likes throw out the idea of migrant farm workers because it is the worst example.  There are a huge number of low skilled jobs, housekeeping, custodial services, laborers, etc. and the presence of a nearly limitless supply of low skilled labor keeps those wages down.

If you would wave a magic want and make all of the illegal immigrants vanish, that roofing contractor will need to offer higher wages, and guess what my roof will cost more, because everyone's roof will cost more, because all of the roofing contractors had to raise all of their wages to attract and keep employees.  Same with housekeeping, and other low skilled jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43735531182.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>“Jobs nobody wants to do” implies at the current wage, people would do almost anything if you paid them enough.

Keeping those wages low is still beneficial for everyone else, paying twice as much or more for labor would make everything more expensive, without an increase in wages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43736783982.0" user="throwawaydanc3rrr" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Keeping those wages low is still beneficial for everyone else, paying twice as much or more for labor would make everything more expensive, without an increase in wages.

Wrong.  

If they had to pay people that replace/install roofs more, say from $20/hour to $40/hour, my new roof would cost more, this part is self evident.

But what does that do?  Everyone that was making less than that, a custodian at a factory making $15 an hour that is working nights might reasonably say, "whoa, $40/hour, and I get to work during the day and not second shift, so I see my kids more, yeah, it is hot work, but at that price I am willing to do it."  When he leaves the person hiring his replacement finds that many people are making the same sort of decision and he cannot find workers at $15/hour and guess what, he has to raise the wages he offers."  

You will get wage increases at the lowest end of the economic spectrum, where it will help the people that need it most.  

But there are knock on effects from that.  The plumber, that was making $28/hour is now looking that custodians are making $24/hour, and I have marketable skills, and from that comes pressure to increase his wage.  

The cost of strawberries will go up, and shortly there after John Deere will make a srawberry picker that attaches to one of their $300,000 tractors.  

All of these equilibrium points are not allowed to occur because the thumb is on the scale keeping non-skilled and low skilled labor cheap.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
