<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43731787387.0" user="-Razlin-" delta="False">
    <text>The usa is a republic not a democracy. Important difference. A democracy would be the bills they pass in congress would be voted on by the people. Instead we elect representatives to go to congress to vote on said bills. Why do you think more people is going to help the millions of super poor? Financial independence is associated with not having to work. If all of us don't work society will collapse. All the money in the world does nothing if there's nothing to buy. The more people that compete for a job the less the job has to pay to get it filler. If there is 1 job and 100 people applying it's going to be a low wage as demand is high there's 100 people that NEED a job. If there's 1 job and no one applied then they have to make the job more enticing so someone does it. Supply an demand also exists in the job market. Adding more people means housing will be more expensive. For renting and buying. The government should make it to where companies can not own houses. That would help. Limiting them to 5 apartment complexes and no single family homes. Limit citizens to 10 houses because no one needs more then 10. This would help bring down the costs of houses but again adding millions upon millions of people every single year means the people that were born here who's dead relatives built this country will have to compete for those houses that are for sale or for rent. Seriously think for a second. I saw you say that corporations will go overseas yeah they already do that congress could pass laws to stop it or get rid of all the regulations that stop poor citizens from starting business. Like less then 5 corporations own just about every single brand. For airlines to markers to tech to food they own it all. The government has the power to change this both sides are equally at fault for letting it happen. This is all by design. The left wont save you neither will the right its a ploy to stop you from taking action. Humans if they think someone else has it covered will do nothing. Free enterprise is how people would live comfortable lives. Being able to have sell something they made without the goverment telling them to jump thru expensive hoops. As marx would say if people owned the means of production(meaning the profit they could keep from making the items, if they choose to work for another person making items for them they can get a wage also called free enterprise)they would make profit for themselves. Not without work as i said a society where no one works isnt one its going to starve to death.  https://hannenabintuherland.com/asia/corporate-power-who-owns-the-world/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
