<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2597269403.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ychwb/cmv_democracy_can_be_saved_if_the_left_learns_to/">
    <title>CMV: Democracy can be saved if the left learns to LIE better than the right</title>
    <original_poster>Preaddly</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are numerous challenges for which effective solutions are yet to be found. Individuals who hold the belief that a world without solutions is not acceptable may find themselves disillusioned by the lack of offerings of the left. Similarly, the right does not provide viable solutions, although it is inclined to fabricate false remedies that instill hope. While the left may easily disprove these proposed solutions, it often fails to provide alternative avenues, resulting in a sense of despair. 

For example, there is presently no established legal framework to enable individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds to accumulate sufficient wealth to secure financial independence. The right suggests curbing immigration to create job opportunities for Americans, but this solution is not feasible. However, the only alternative is enduring an arduous existence of living paycheck to paycheck for a staggering sixty-two years. 

Choosing not to address this issue isn't doing the left any favors. It's now to the point where right-wing charlatans are now waging war on democracy itself. They never would've been able to gain as much power as they have if not for the willingness to lie. 

Although the left may lack immediate solutions, there exists a cohort of opportunists ready to exploit this vulnerability. In order to inspire hope, the left must also be willing to present alternate narratives, even if they deviate from the truth. A demoralized population will be more prone to believing unfounded claims made by just about anyone, including the idea that democracy is ineffectual.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43730014486.0" user="Dyeeguy" delta="False">
    <text>Ya never heard of programs that are for people of specific financial and racial backgrounds? 

I keep seeing posts the past few days of people who think we’re on the brink of civil war or somethin. Have you read some recent source to make you think so? I would stop reading that source 

Honestly this is all over the place, no clue what you’re saying at all lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730064285.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Honestly this is all over the place, no clue what you’re saying at all lol.

In short, the right offers fake solutions while the left only defends the status quo, which doesn't inspire hope the way fake solutions do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730086583.0" user="Dyeeguy" delta="False">
    <text>Right, I think that is a flawed premise. Most left leaning people would not agree they support fake solutions. So again, it is trying to solve a problem that only exists for you 

Why would fake solutions from one side be better than fake solutions from another? I don’t understand how that saves democracies 

Why do you want to support a party that you acknowledge doesn’t have solutions to issues anyways? 

All very confusing lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730185340.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why do you want to support a party that you acknowledge doesn’t have solutions to issues anyways? 

Because sometimes there really won't be a solution. But we don't want people to lose hope. Hopelessness leads to desperation, and that leaves them open to grifters, charlatans, fascists, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730256576.0" user="Dyeeguy" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it matter if that hope comes from one fake source vs another fake source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730265872.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>Some fake sources are advocating for authoritarian fascism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730274657.0" user="Dyeeguy" delta="False">
    <text>If it is a fake plan, it means that will not come to fruition. So it’s fine</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730313632.0" user="Preaddly" delta="False">
    <text>They'll still do it, it just won't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43730319949.0" user="Dyeeguy" delta="False">
    <text>So that is not really a fake plan it is a failed plan lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43731049888.0" user="rje946" delta="False">
    <text>Then they grift off it</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
