<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742936757.0" user="pathunwinder" delta="False">
    <text>We have limited selection of who you can pick and if the media told you, this list would be about Biden and you would be asking how could people vote for him.

I mean Trump is too old, he shouldn't be allowed to vote but Biden shouldn't be working, let alone President, you're a joke if you don't acknowledge that and yet it's barely acknowledged. So if you can't acknowledge the idea that people will vote someone in based on what little choice they have, don't ignore who is in power now, may as well be a corpse being puppeted with someone else's hand up their ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742943895.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't about Trump vs Biden though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743250254.0" user="b3polite" delta="False">
    <text>.........it's barely acknowledged?! What?

"BIDEN IS OLD" is the rights favorite thing to scream about besides hunters laptop/penis. The "barely acknowledged" part you're talking about is that Trump is only a couple years behind him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743281358.0" user="rockemsockemlostem" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the right acknowledges it, do YOU personally?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743578171.0" user="threemo" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah dog, most democrats never did and still don’t want Biden. Too old and too moderate. But he’s running and we’re certainly not fucking with Trump or any of the other nutjobs that are running.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744668405.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly do you expect that to look like? Democrats are very aware that Biden is old.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744256804.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Biden was too old according to repubs in 2020. Trump is 3 years younger. So the same should apply to Trump in 2024.

False dichotomy.

Trump _is_ power and wealth. Your solution to your own stated issue is empirically not Trump, but you believe it is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
