<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742685195.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I think there's a big piece you're missing here. Huge portions of the population are in echo chambers and have been for decades. For Republicans I'd call this the Fox umbrella although many elements are even more abominable than Fox editorial content. 

To people stuck under the Fox umbrella (often by choice) Trump is a trustworthy politician, perhaps the only trustworthy politician. They do not see what he does and says as lies even if those words and actions often contradict because they aren't shown that. Trump has been deified in such a way that they do not critically examine his statements and actions. They are benevolent because Trump does them and not the other way around. 

Trump's claims that he belongs to the categories you list are sufficient to demonstrate that he belongs to said categories regardless of the facts on the ground. People under the Fox umbrella are not shown the facts on the ground if they reflect poorly on Trump. If something does reflect poorly on Trump it was the DemoRAT's fault. 

So it's not necessarily that they're in an "in-group" or that they're purposely being evil to "own the libs" (although there are some conservatives this applies to for sure), it's a cult of personality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742857176.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I recognise what you are talking about. Yet a big part of being a cult is the sense of group belonging. 

I guess my question is, are there any actual ISSUES where they feel Trump represents them better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742894394.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;are there any actual ISSUES where they feel Trump represents them better?

All of them. Trump may as well be Jesus Jr. to a good portion of Republican voters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742961270.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Such as?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743045369.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I mean you list 7 solid ones in your OP. Trump supporters see him as the best proponent of those things regardless of whether he actually is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743541817.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK so you would argue his supporters see him as good on those issues? Is it really as simple as that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743550490.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely, why else would one of the most common criticisms of poor, working class Republican voters be that they're fundamentally voting against their stated interests?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743777241.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I see the logic. It's just hard to believe. The guy is so clownish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743360228.0" user="Far_Spot8247" delta="False">
    <text>These people have the internet. They don't want to know the truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747013405.0" user="Fieos" delta="False">
    <text>Do we deal in truth here on Reddit?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751295940.0" user="JohnD_s" delta="False">
    <text>No. Reddit is a bigger echo chamber than any news channel could be. Any opinion even hinting towards conservative values gets downvoted to oblivion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770256157.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>The conservative values mentioned in OP, or the conservative values conservatives actually have? (none)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43787388706.0" user="JohnD_s" delta="False">
    <text>People have reasons for their beliefs the same as you. To believe otherwise is a sign of immaturity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
