<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="51" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43745414689.0" user="corebuff" delta="False">
    <text>There's no man out there - family man or not - who hasn't made a off-color remark about women.  Boobs, etc.

He's not 'clownishly' ignorant of the Bible.  Just recently he said he couldn't go through the hardships he's facing without Christ.  More than we get out of the other hethens in the white house.

He's not 'clownishly' ignorant of the Bible.  Just recently he said he couldn't go through the hardships he's facing without Christ.  More than we get out of the other heathens in the white house.

Mexico provided military aid that equaled more than he was asking for the wall.

Beautiful healthcare?  I don't know what happened there - but I do know with the opposition he was facing it's amazing he got anything done.

It was rigged, lol.  If you've not figured that out by now you're nothing but a Dem troll.

Some conservatives have 'distanced' themselves.  I don't know one who has.  As for the 'ethnic vote' (as they call it) - he's got numbers 'biglier' than ever before.

He's going through hell for this country.  Don't you doubt it.

Anyone who turns their backs on him to be part of the 'in crowd'?  LMAO.  They get just what they deserve.  And that's more of the hell this country is going through right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745700713.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if this is a serious reply. But here goes. 

&gt;There's no man out there - family man or not - who hasn't made a off-color remark about women. 

There are plenty of men who don't talk about women the way Trump does. As you well know, it's not one remark. 

&gt;He's not 'clownishly' ignorant of the Bible.  Just recently he said he couldn't go through the hardships he's facing without Christ.

So what? What knowledge of the Bible does that require? Pretending to be a big Christian and then holding the Bible upside down and talking about "two Corinthians" is nothing but clownish. 

&gt;Mexico provided military aid that equaled more than he was asking for the wall.

Laughable. The Mexican government did not provide "military aid" to the US. Whatever contribution they have made on border security is dwarfed by the cost of this ridiculous wall.  

&gt;Beautiful healthcare? I don't know what happened there

Because we never saw his beautiful plan. Where's the plan? 

&gt;It was rigged, lol.

Tell that to the Trump-appointed judges who laughed his lawsuits out of court. 

&gt;Some conservatives have 'distanced' themselves. I don't know one who has.

You could start with the people who've worked for him. You know, the "best people" he was supposed to hire? Even John Kelly admits Trump described veterans as "suckers and losers".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746069514.0" user="corebuff" delta="False">
    <text>BS men don't talk like that.  You've never said, 'Nice tits' or something along those lines?  AND if you ever looked into it - that quote wasn't given out in totality.  He said something along the lines of 'when you're rich they let you - gtbyp'.  And he's right.  Women such up to rich men and do let them gtbyp all the time.  That makes the women hoes and the men, less than discerning for sure.  But 'gtbyp' wasn't his whole quote.

So?  Hard and fast Christians still say 'Revelations' - he gave Christ the credit - that's all that's important.  Or do you forget the thief on the cross?

You might want to look into just how much it cost for Mexico's military aid.  And, if it doesn't equal out?  The trade deal he made - that put the USA way ahead - did make sure they 'paid'.  

Again, health care - there's only so much he could do with the time he had and the opposition he faced.  Here's what he DID in that time.  

Signed an executive order to help minimize the financial burden felt by American households Signed legislation to improve the National Suicide Hotline.

  
Signed the most comprehensive childhood cancer legislation ever into law, which will advance childhood cancer research and improve treatments.

  
Signed Right-to-Try legislation, expanding health care options for terminally ill patients.

  
Enacted changes to the Medicare 340B program, saving seniors an estimated $320 million on drugs in 2018 alone.

  
FDA set a new record for generic drug approvals in 2017, saving consumers nearly $9 billion.

  
Released a blueprint to drive down drug prices for American patients, leading multiple major drug companies to announce they will freeze or reverse price increases.

  
Expanded short-term, limited-duration health plans.

  
Let more employers to form Association Health Plans, enabling more small businesses to join together and affordably provide health insurance to their employees.

  
Cut Obamacare’s burdensome individual mandate penalty.

  
Signed legislation repealing Obamacare’s Independent Payment Advisory Board, also known as the “death panels.”

  
USDA invested more than $1 billion in rural health care in 2017, improving access to health care for 2.5 million people in rural communities across 41 states

  
Proposed Title X rule to help ensure taxpayers do not fund the abortion industry in violation of the law.

  
Reinstated and expanded the Mexico City Policy to keep foreign aid from supporting the global abortion industry.

  
HHS formed a new division over protecting the rights of conscience and religious freedom.

  
Overturned Obama administration’s midnight regulation prohibiting states from defunding certain abortion facilities.

  
Signed executive order to help ensure that religious organizations are not forced to choose between violating their religious beliefs by complying with Obamacare’s contraceptive mandate or shutting their doors.

Given more time I'm sure he would have done MORE - he obviously wasn't going to quit there.

He was pretty busy creating the biggest tax cut in history - the lowest unemployment numbers - more manufacturers coming back to the USA and on and on.

Again - if you can't see how the election is rigged?  You're delusional.  It's been proven over and over, State after State.  Judges were nothing but puppets.

Many of the people who worked for him were losers.  He admitted he shouldn't have hired a number of them.  He gives people a lot of credit and most let him down.

Anyway - enough of this.  I'm not wasting my time on someone who refuses to see the facts and refuses the truth that the election was rigged.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746351015.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>The judges were TRUMP APPOINTEES IN SEVERAL CASES. I'm not sure what else would convince you. 

&gt;I'm not wasting my time on someone who refuses to

Your prolixity is your issue, not mine.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
