<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="102" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43752206697.0" user="Love-and-Fairness" delta="False">
    <text>Well, traditionally conservatives have been losers who get made fun of, particularly western tradition of the last 20-50 years, so him seeming to go against it is probably a good thing for conservatives because they needed new ways, specifically new ways that can bulwark against criticism.

 I can't say it wouldn't change with context because I didn't have a life experience in America, but I like Trumpism more than what I associate with the GOP typically. The problem I would have with voting for Trump is that all those other greasy GOP people would get power too. 

For me it'd be Trump &gt; Biden &gt; any Dem candidate &gt; any other GOP candidate.  I'd be a swing voter between progressivism and populist right-wing nationalism. I would've voted Obama and wanted Bernie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752416931.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You wanted Bernie and now you'd vote Trump? What?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752847827.0" user="Love-and-Fairness" delta="False">
    <text>🤯Yeah there are good forces on both sides, I labeled them. Trump despite his faults does aim to channel populist right-wing nationalism and does it well. When one of them is present in a purer form you choose that because both are positive developmental forces for your country</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754115758.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>The two of them are not remotely similar. Their policy positions and their personalities, and for that matter their conduct, are so far apart that I can't fathom how you would switch from one to the other. Make it make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
