<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="71" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43747798599.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>You watch too much cnn. Trump made America great. When he was in office. No inflation. Gas cheap. Low illegal immigration. Tell me something great biden did. Give people free stuff is all he did which is the democrat way. Common man. He is a joke.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750390256.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>The president has little to no control over inflation or gas prices. Gas is a commodity with a single world price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750821175.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>Which president says he want to end big oil. Which president ended most of the  fracking and oil drilling in the us. Having 4-8$ a gallon gasoline made inflation what it was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751438333.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment doesn't make sense, for the reason I've just given above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751506585.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know that we were making more oil than we were consuming thus exporting to other nations. Driving down the piece supply and demand. Cnn probably didn’t tell you that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751844633.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I knew that. Now tell me what the biggest supply shock was in recent years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751858180.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>When biden dug into the oil reserves because of high gas prices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751876229.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know what "supply shock" means?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751917342.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>You know Russia/Ukrainian make up less the. 10%of the worlds oil. Why did the prices go up so high then. Because we were producing much oil domestically. We were buying it from overseas. So biden created this whole mess in his first week in office by stopping oil production.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751963387.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>My guy there is ONE WORLD PRICE for commodities. And Biden stopped oil production? What?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751994713.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2021/01/27/biden-suspends-oil-and-gas-drilling-in-series-of.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752372760.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Ok great. Now what proportion of global production did this represent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752419302.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>Gas prices will go up when we stop drilling. Plain as day. The saudis will price gouge us to the bone because they know we need them. Like I said supply and demand. Not so great for the us economy seeing how 99% of all good are at some point trucked around using semi trucks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754050654.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>So you don't know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754139631.0" user="anakedman1" delta="False">
    <text>Why should it involve me?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754204153.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>We were talking about gas prices. Did you forget?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
