<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743641510.0" user="Realistic_Special_53" delta="False">
    <text>False dichomotomy, though I will get voted down for this, since most everyone, including me, hate Trump.  But that is not why these people are lining up behind Trump.  If you really want to know, talk to them. There reasons are not complicated.  Many of the poorer voters feel screwed by the economy and standard of living increases in the past decade, especially the last year.  And the identity politics are just too much nowadays.  Especially if you’re poor and being told you are part of the ruling class.  And the rich want tax breaks and less regulation for businesses.  They don’t care about the other stuff, because they see the Democratic alternative as worse.  Maybe you disagree, I know I do, but it is arrogant to think you know somebody else’s point of view without asking them.  I may disagree with them, but I get where they are coming from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743754840.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>The times I have tried that approach, what I get told is that they just don't believe the negative stories about him. I just don't think you can understand a cult from the inside, I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745931732.0" user="resumethrowaway222" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they believe the stories about him?  Here's a story about Ron Desantis banning books [https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/22/books/book-ban-florida.html](https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/22/books/book-ban-florida.html)

Turns out that's a lie.  No books were banned.  They were removed from an elementary school library.  And here's an excerpt from the "banned" books that shows it was absolutely the correct decision to remove them from an elementary school library:

&gt;"’I put some lube on and got him on his knees, and I began to slide into him from behind. I pulled out of him and kissed him while he masturbated. He asked me to turn over while he slipped a condom on himself. This was my a—and I was struggling to imagine someone inside me. He got on top and slowly inserted himself into me. It was the worst pain I think I have ever felt in my life. Eventually, I felt a mix of pleasure with the pain.’"

&gt; Kennedy then read from "Gender Queer": "’I got a new strap-on harness today. I can’t wait to put it on you. It will fit my favorite dildo perfectly. You will look so hot. I can’t wait to have your c--- in my mouth. I’m going to give you the b------ of your life, then I want you inside of me.’"

So the NYT blatantly lied about this issue.  Why would a conservative believe them in their accusations against Trump.  Journalistic standards have gone out the window, so why would they be trusted for anything?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744020562.0" user="Longjumping_Act_6054" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Especially if you’re poor and being told you are part of the ruling class.

This makes zero sense. Literally no one is saying this. I know you're referring "white priviledge" but that's not at all what it means and it shows how much of the propaganda you've swallowed to compare it as such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746931062.0" user="Dragolins" delta="False">
    <text>It really is amazing how often conservatives regurgitate talking points while not having the faintest idea what they are talking about. 

Yeah, the point of "white privilege" as a concept is definitely to say that poor white people are part of the ruling class just by being white. 

I mean this shit is so unfathomably removed from reality that it is honestly scary that a grown human being can believe it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744451082.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>So the solution to all those problems caused explicitly by Republicans is to... vote for more Republicans!? How does that make any sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757749100.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, high crimes rates are obviously caused by republicans, the party of "defund the police". Or did I have that twisted</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759258999.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>You're quite misinformed, yes. High crime rates are caused by poverty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764082390.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, but you can't logically or empirically causally link republican policy with poverty rates. It's pretty logically straightforward to show how efforts to defund police lead to higher crime rates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764321300.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Sure I can. Welfare reduces poverty. Reducing  welfare increases poverty. Increasing poverty increases crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764382616.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>The welfare state in america has only grown over the last century , why are crime rates in democrat run cities also getting worse?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764955985.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Crime rates fluctuate all the time but it's weird you're framing it like that given the areas with the highest crime rates are generally rural and poorer areas of cities. 

Also welfare in America sucks ass. Costs may have ballooned and we might pay for reasonable welfare but it's sort of difficult to make that work when one party is actively trying to dismantle it.

See pretty much any other first world country for working examples.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43765345341.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>Republicans haven't done much to try to dismantle welfare, it's too popular. And still, crime is way worse than it's ever been in america.

Maybe just being poor isn't the sole reason why inner city populations commit crimes against each other, and maybe just giving them money isn't the correct solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43765419739.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just going to use a recent example. Covid stimulus. Shit ton of grift because there was no oversight. Why was there no oversight? Because Republicans wouldn't pass the bill without removing that oversight. 

I'm not claiming poverty is the only factor, just a contributing one. I'm not saying giving money is the only form of welfare either but I am saying other first world countries with strong safety nets don't seem to have this problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770387133.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>So because you never tried searching for a causal link between Republican policy and poverty, it must be fake? Or is it because the truth would hurt your point? I mean for fucks sake, middle America has some piss poor fucking states. Im in Missouri right now and I see crumbling buildings and dilapidated factories all the time. You dont think the local government could help with that? Im sure the city would do more... If Republicans didnt also make it their policy to prevent municipalities from passing ordinances and playing with city funds and grants to enrich their buddies. Everything the GOP does causes poverty, my friend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43785548926.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>So why are inner cities that have been run by democrats for decades incredibly impoverished?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43790966650.0" user="pnwgrey" delta="False">
    <text>[You should do some research.](https://data.ers.usda.gov/reports.aspx?ID=17826#P1b1d731a299946608df3b9c9c0f89ff2_3_229iT3)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43846645227.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>I said cities, not states. Close though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43851292072.0" user="pnwgrey" delta="False">
    <text>You can click through for the cities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43856870079.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>Cool. I'm not gonna do that, thanks for the offer though. Everybody knows that liberal run cities and states are in shambles. California's homeless problem exists even though statistically it might be offset by the rich people who live there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43860511692.0" user="pnwgrey" delta="False">
    <text>The lowest income cities are all red ;)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43860644368.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>Completely baseless claim</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866771682.0" user="pnwgrey" delta="False">
    <text>I gave you the source</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43868770992.0" user="VinnyNicks12" delta="False">
    <text>And you studied it deeply I'm sure</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744635260.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>And this is the paradox of the conservative voter.

The people they're voting for are the direct cause of most of these issues and will exacerbate them further the more power they get.

So either conservatives are lying about their motivations or they're too stupid to understand cause and effect. Either way, liberals get painted with being "arrogant snobs" for pointing it out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745213803.0" user="lambo630" delta="False">
    <text>Identity politics is conservative? 

Retail crime in democrat run cities is caused by conservatives?

Conservatives want to raise taxes? 

Homelessness being a massive problem in democrat run cities is the fault of conservatives?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745920826.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Identity politics is conservative?

Yes, what is referred to as IDpol today has been the game plan for conservatives for far longer (cis-het white Christian men). 

&gt;Retail crime in democrat run cities is caused by conservatives?

Poverty is unalleviated specifically due to conservative policies, yes.

&gt;Homelessness being a massive problem in democrat run cities is the fault of conservatives?

Yes for the same reason but add in mental health and healthcare in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746125026.0" user="Jealousmustardgas" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, it’s the left saying shit like “you ain’t black if you vote trump”. Just cause your disdain for str8 yt men has caused a lot of them to go R doesn’t mean they’re the main drivers of identity politics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746170432.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not disdainful of straight, white men, I am one! Nor am I saying "the left" doesn't use IDpol now. 

I'm just saying that both predates what conservatives call IDpol and is itself IDpol. That doesn't mean conservatives are "the main driver" of it either, just that they're projecting as usual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746231310.0" user="Jealousmustardgas" delta="False">
    <text>A majority white culture had white male politicians? IDpol!!!!!! False equivalency, I don’t buy it at all. One party is still colorblind, and the other color-sensitive. The newest CA senator is a great example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746258885.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care if you buy it. It's a well documented fact. Republicans have historically *almost exclusively* voted for cis-het white Christian men. If it were just "mostly" then it wouldn't be IDpol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746364635.0" user="Jealousmustardgas" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, and it’s a well documented fact that democrats are the party of slaveholders and Jim Crow advocates. Destroying the patriarchy isn’t going to magically make everything better, but go ahead and keep on trying. Watch and you lose the minority vote to Rs</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746479426.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Yes dems were the party of slaveholders and jim crow up until the party switch when the Nixon campaign decided to go after the southern strategy. Also well documented. 

Who is "you" here? I'm not a Dem. I want actual leftist politicians not center right conservatives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746524183.0" user="Jealousmustardgas" delta="False">
    <text>Well-documented, just like we had the most secure election in US history in 2020. It’s bs historical revisionism that doesn’t pass the smell test. I swear that’s the left’s version of the right’s view of Reaganomics, just complete hogwash.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746596787.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>The southern strategy is historical revisionism? The only revisionist history is saying the GOP is still the party of Lincoln and the civil rights movement. If it were why do black people overwhelmingly vote against Republicans?

You know there are documents and interviews by Nixon campaign operatives talking about the southern strategy, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753139243.0" user="xXCisWhiteSniperXx" delta="False">
    <text>Actually,  the democrats are the party of states rights!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759825521.0" user="XNoob_SmokeX" delta="False">
    <text>Don't call yourself one. We don't claim you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759859098.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>What on earth are you talking about? Why do you believe you speak for anyone?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746677691.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Identity politics is conservative?

Conservatives threw a nationwide shitfit over a trans person on instragram getting some free beer. Yes. Identity politics is conservative.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Retail crime in democrat run cities is caused by conservatives?  


How many people would be ransacking Targets today if Conservatives didn't spend the last 40 years stagnating wages and dismantling the safety net.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Conservatives want to raise taxes?  


For corporations and millionaires, no. For everybody else, yes. Have you not been paying attention?

The Trump Tax Cuts lowered tax cuts for corporations for millionaires permanently, but raised taxes for some of the lower-middle class. And even those who did get lower taxes will have those cuts expire in 2025 where Republicans will use their extension as leverage to secure even more tax cuts for millionaires.

They pulled the same stunt with the Bush Tax Cuts. When those were set to expire, Obama proposed extending them for everybody but the wealthy. Republicans said "No, if the millionaires don't get a tax break, nobody does. We would rather taxes go up for everybody than see the rich pay more."

And keep in mind, they also keep trying to push a "flat tax," which is generally a tax increase for anybody making median wage or lower.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Homelessness being a massive problem in democrat run cities is the fault of conservatives?  


Again, see 40 years of stifling wages and dismantling social safety nets, but also add a reflexive opposition to social programs in general.

It's not even just that they're the cause of the problems, they actively oppose taking any steps to resolve problems. This is true for everything from climate change to COVID.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43758045793.0" user="jawshoeaw" delta="False">
    <text>They feel screwed but they live in rural areas or conservative shitholes and vote for rich people over and over. The identity politics are pushed by conservatives- everybody else wants to be left alone. 

What i get is that they have ignored reality for decades. And what powerful force could blind you to such a harsh reality ? Racism, misogyny, homophobia, religious hysteria that’s what. These are the same people fighting unionization, fighting against universal health care, fair taxation. All of which benefit the poor. I have no more sympathy for people who vote against their own self interest driven by hatred</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
