<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="154" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43858839077.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Family values and religion are not traditionally conservative positions. The Republicans adopted religious policy planks in order to court the evangelical Christians in the south, who had long voted Democrat. And it worked.

&gt;Honest dealing

He was up front and straightforward about all of that. How is that not honest dealing? He did a bunch of stuff that was legal and then told the truth about it. What exactly are we supposed to be upset about? That the government had those rules in the first place, even though Trump had nothing to do with writing them? Why would that make me mad about Trump?

&gt;Managerial competence:

Trump has demonstrated managerial competence as a businessman and as an entertainer for many years. The fact that you don't want to give him any credit on this just shows your bias, not our ignorance. But even then, the president really doesn't manage that much in our government. He's mostly a figurehead, with a couple exceptions. Foreign policy is definitely one of them, but Trump's foreign policy was actually excellent. He's the first president in a long time to talk to North Korea. He officially recognized Taiwan multiple times, through the Chinese on their back foot multiple times, and still managed to have normalized relationships with them. He moved the US Israeli embassy to Jerusalem, something that all the presidents before him had promised to do but never did. He's the first president in the modern era to not start a war in his first term. And that was with his five stars actively mutining against him. They straight up lied to him about having taken all the troops out of Syria.

&gt;Decorum

I don't actually give a shit about the quorum. I care about results, and from where I'm sitting Trump did pretty good on a conservative record. Way better than I was expecting when he was elected in 2016.

&gt;Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall?

Well, in any basic civics course they would teach you that Congress controls the money, and Congress was run by the Democrats, and Congress didn't want to give Trump any money to build a wall. He did what he could with DOD slush funds, but the experience with Biden has proved he was 100% correct. His immigration policy worked, and Biden's has been a complete and other disaster.

&gt;Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all.

First off, democracy is shit. It's not a thing that we've ever practiced in the United States. We do not have a democracy, and you don't want a democracy. It's a terrible form of government. We have a constitutional republic, which is not a democracy. I know they don't teach kids anything in school anymore other than what their favorite gender should be, but this is just absolutely the most basic of civics. Republics and democracy are mutually exclusive because the thing that defines them are antagonist. But even besides that, there was a lot of fishy shit that went on in 2020 and literally nobody seemed interested in investigating it. Three years on they're finally getting around to it, and low and behold, a lot of that shit was substantiated. 100% of a bunch of Wisconsin nursing homes voted for Biden, even though the residents had never voted before. Thousands of illegal votes and fraudulent voter registrations in Michigan, something that Bill Barr found out about before January 6th and ignored, hence why he was fired early. Despite all the promises of the governor, signature match verification audits have never occurred in Georgia, and the judge who's overseeing the court case has violated Georgia law multiple times in an attempt to delay that case for moving forward. Where there's smoke, there's probably a fire. If everyone is so confident that there's nothing to lose, then let everyone have access to the data, and they won't come up with anything. That's the only way to clear the air on the issue, and everyone refuses to allow it.

&gt;and wanting to own the stupid libs?

That's actually a very big motivation for conservative voters. And nobody has owned the libs more than Donald Trump. Those idiots set their own hair on fire to prove how much they hated Donald Trump. It was embarrassing, and it still is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43861076572.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Family values and religion are not traditionally conservative positions.

How far are we going back here? I suppose it depends what "traditional" means but they have been for decades at this point. 

&gt;He was up front and straightforward about all of that. How is that not honest dealing? 

We still haven't seen his tax records, because he lied about being "under audit" for years on end. 

&gt;Trump has demonstrated managerial competence as a businessman and as an entertainer for many years. The fact that you don't want to give him any credit on this just shows your bias

Very much a matter of opinion. But anyway, do we want an entertainer or someone with at least a minimal grasp of world affairs? Your list of achievements represents an extremely low bar. Simply meeting NK and coming away empty handed simply made him and the US look foolish. He failed to get Xi to put any pressure on NK. His trade war achieved nothing except disruption. Relations between Moscow and Beijing have never been better. And that's before we consider his domestic incompetence -- "hiring the best people" didn't work out so well, did it?

&gt;I don't actually give a shit about \[decorum\]

OK well that's clear enough. 

&gt;Well, in any basic civics course they would teach you that Congress controls the money, and Congress was run by the Democrats, and Congress didn't want to give Trump any money to build a wall. He did what he could with DOD slush funds

Doesn't address the question. Mexico was going to pay. 

&gt;First off, democracy is shit. It's not a thing that we've ever practiced in the United States. We do not have a democracy, and you don't want a democracy. It's a terrible form of government. We have a constitutional republic, which is not a democracy. I know they don't teach kids anything 

Nothing like being confidently incorrect. You are confusing form of sovereignty with form of government. 

&gt;Republics and democracy are mutually exclusive

Hilarious.

"A republic, based on the Latin phrase *res publica*, is a state in which political power rests with the public and their representatives—in contrast to a monarchy."

"Democracy is a system of government in which state power is vested in the people or the general population of a state."

&gt;\[general election conspiracy nonsense\]

Get back to me when you can get a court to agree with you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
