<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="146" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43781095729.0" user="sasukelover69" delta="False">
    <text>The people pulling the strings in conservative do believe in one thing whole heartedly, reducing taxes and regulations that impede big business. All the social issues surrounding Christian and family values are largely manufactured by think tanks to keep the fundamentalists in their rapidly shrinking voting block. 

With regards to the big business oriented policies that are actually at the heart of what they want to accomplish, they found during the decades since the 80s that instead of selling big-business oriented policies directly to voters it’s easier to erode voters confidence in government by dismantling its function and then pointing to its disfunction as evidence for why it should be further dismantled. 

Public schools, the USPS, social security, and Medicare are all institutions that conservatives have consistently rendered less effective and then those same conservatives have pointed to the ineffectiveness of these institutions as reasons that they should be replaced with private alternatives. 

The same thing applies to politics in a more general sense. Trump was an incredible candidate to run if your goal was to delegitimize democracy and government as a whole. 

Even before Trump McConnells entire platform for the latter half of obamas presidency was just to obstruct any attempt to do anything. 

The playbook is simple, they sabotage the government and then run on platform that the government is in effective. Merging politics and reality TV by electing an entertainment clown fits that playbook perfectly. 

The people who win at the end of the day are those that benefit most from an ineffective government: big businesses that want to skirt taxation and regulation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
