<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="109" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43753536710.0" user="godwink2" delta="False">
    <text>This is overly sensational and is ultimately incorrect. 

Conservatives wanting to stop the liberal agenda and wanting to have these values are not exclusive. Conservatives have these values. The prevailing narrative is that Biden/Dems policies are threatening those values and Trump is the one to stop them. 

Its all about how much two party system really sucks. A candidate probably exists that can deal with Dems and is actually a decent person but Trump has such grip on GOP that such a candidate is silenced.

Check out Vivek Ramaswarmy. I think he is a solid candidiate who I am likely to vote for. Will it matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754299176.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>So are you saying, you'll vote for an asshole as president as long as he aligns with you mostly on policy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755256025.0" user="godwink2" delta="False">
    <text>No? Is Vivek an asshole? Ive only watched a few interviews hes done so I don’t think so based on that but thats a small sample size for sure.

Im saying conservatives in general do that because they believe Trump is doing good work in making America better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755307690.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Just to be clear. Would you vote for Trump?

I mean Vivek is a gigantic liar but he's nowhere near the same category.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755406104.0" user="godwink2" delta="False">
    <text>If he gets the RNC nonination and Biden gets the DNC nomination most likely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755465204.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK and if I've understood you right, you dislike Trump as a person but you like his policy agenda?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
