<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="40" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43744401083.0" user="jacobsonjohn287" delta="False">
    <text>I think you need to watch the "grabem by the pussy" video again.

The full quote is: "when you arerich you can do whatever. People let you get away with anything. Women too. You could do anything and they don't care. You could grab them by the pussy or something."

This is a fact, and he was talking about the double standard. That rich get away with everything, and everyone else doesn't.

Trump is OUR rich guy. And the establishment hates him in unanimity. If you are a Socialist and proclaim to hate "multinational corporations", you should adore Trump. The biggest powers in the world arecl coming for him. Maybe they don't want to lose power, ever think of that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745034987.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>He wasn't decrying the double standard. He was celebrating it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43777721135.0" user="RazzmatazzThis2170" delta="False">
    <text>Bragging</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747415357.0" user="PartsWork" delta="False">
    <text>Immediately preceded by a LOT of him talking about himself. But then somehow we're to imagine that he begins talking about hypotheticals?  
"I moved on her actually. You know she was down on Palm Beach. **I moved on her, and I failed. I'll admit it. I did try and fuck her, she was married**."  
and  
"I moved on her very heavily in fact I took her out furniture shopping. She wanted to get some furniture. I said I'll show you where they have some nice furniture. **I moved on her like a bitch.** I couldn't get there and she was married. Then all-of-a-sudden I see her, she's now got the big phony tits and everything. She's totally changed her look."  

and  

"Yeah that's her with the gold. **I better use some Tic Tacs just in case I start kissing her. You know I'm automatically attracted to beautiful... I just start kissing them. It's like a magnet. Just kiss. I don't even wait. And when you're a star they let you do it. You can do anything."**</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
