<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742675791.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it depends on what counts as "beating the other tribe" but there's something missed here in that  Trump is politically useful for their ideals. They might prefer some deranged theocrat who knows how to dress himself, but no one in the GOP besides Trump seems to have any actual charisma so he's their best bet to get what they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742839369.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Could you give an example of what you mean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742893299.0" user="LiamTheHuman" delta="False">
    <text>I think what they mean is that maybe 70% of them think he is an idiot but still support him because they know the other 30% will back him. There is a willingness to choose the person who will win over someone who is better but will lose, because winning furthers their ideals(even if he doesn't embody them).  
I hate it, but it does seem like the kind of logic conservatives would use. It's very realistic and not very idealistic and I guess I wouldn't fault them for it if there weren't very obvious consequences to this type of behaviour.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742931023.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>While there are no doubt a lot of Trump cultists, a good amount of Republicans are likely supporting him for the sake of political expediency. Theres no real alternatives since the one they wanted, DeSantis, is some sort of lizard who is getting his ass kicked by a mouse. So they're left with Trump as their best shot at getting the policies and appointments they like enacted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742948594.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK so his support is because people want to enact what exactly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743007011.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>It depends on the people, but generally things like opposing abortion, friendliness with Russia, isolationism, white supremacy, anti-LGBT nonsense, opposing science, and so on. Or, for the rich assholes, the fact that all GOP economic policies are designed to funnel money into the hands of the wealthy at the expense of everyone else and the nation as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743563946.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK so there's a solid section of the population that really believes all of this stuff?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743574126.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>Like anti-abortion and white supremacy stuff? Yeah, there's a not-insignificant amount of them running around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743761537.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I just... is it really so many people who'd be willing to set everything else on fire for those issues?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743969454.0" user="NotMyBestMistake" delta="False">
    <text>Some of them, yeah. More of them don't view things as on fire. The venn diagram of people who are avid bigots and those who don't care about corruption or abuse is a lumpy circle. They don't care about abusing women, or about *actually* reading the Bible, or stealing money from the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744864042.0" user="SpezEatLead" delta="False">
    <text>what else, exactly, do you consider to be "set on fire" by trump?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744071058.0" user="PolOfThePot" delta="False">
    <text>They are dead set on having Italian food for dinner but the only place open is the Olive Garden. They’re going to take that option instead of a high quality Mexican place because they don’t want Mexican food at all and it makes no sense to constantly explain how Olive Garden makes shitty Italian food when they’re aren’t any better options for Italian food.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
