<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="46" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43745020839.0" user="asdf_qwerty27" delta="False">
    <text>The main issue I've seen among "normal" Republicans is that the alternative is not one they can tolerate. Imagine, how bad would a Democrat need to be to get you to vote for Trump? 

With only two choices precieved by many, they are stuck between a rock and a hard place.

I'm a libertarian who actually votes libertarian, so I can kind of sympathize with this perspective. I can't bring myself to stomach either of the two major parties, so I vote for the only option I can in hopes that we eventually build momentum among people who are tired of having to choose between two unacceptable parties. Unfortunately, these alternative parties are small and easily hijacked, astroterfed, or otherwise co-opted by mainstream political movements. People who can't think outside the binary can't comprehend not being Republican or Democrat, so they assume the other parties are just extreme or lite versions of the mainstream corporate backed parties. 

In short, it isn't only tribalism, it is the fact the Democrats alternative is so beyond unacceptable to some voters that they are forced to choose whatever is not them. 

Again, how bad would a Democrat need to be for you to break ranks and vote for Trump?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
