<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="80" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43748924995.0" user="No-Skirt-1430" delta="False">
    <text>It’s the classic “the enemy of my enemt is my friend” thing.

I think the public actors of all sorts are a bit wonky, so leaving all that aside for a moment:

Root conservatism is about preserving traditions.  The traditions may be / are implicitly solving a lot of problems that we don’t understand.  As much as it sucks that there are many problems today, it’s kind of remarkable that everything works as well as it does.

Root liberalism is about identifying the areas that demand change and advocating for continuous improvements.  They’re the main pushers of change, good-or-bad.  The valence is decided in the end by the outcome, not by the initial intent.

Any society that skews too extreme one way or another will collapse due to internal (lib) or external (con) forces, or so it seems.

The social media / wild propaganda era has got people pretty excited and pretty polarized.  There’s been some pretty weird stuff going on.

Even so, we -should- be figuring out how to navigate the impossible dance between the two overarching strategies, instead of killing each other.

Trump was an F-U candidate; clearly an indication of the ‘killing each other’ approach.

He has his share of kool-aid drinkers, don’t get me wrong.  Just realize there’s an alternate path for his supporters.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
