<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743355607.0" user="MajorPainmeme" delta="False">
    <text>They want MORE free speech.


Peace talks not F-16s in Ukraine.


Saying NO to judging by face colour.


Paper ballots.


Ending Nazi-like censorship. 


Fixing the economy.


No to trying to stop the weather from changing.

…..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743620095.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>IOW, culture wars, science denial, and helping out our strategic competitors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743665970.0" user="Km15u" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;They want MORE free speech.

America has had and continues to have the most liberal free speech laws in the world idk what you are upset about

&gt;Peace talks not F-16s in Ukraine.

Ukraine would love peace talks too, but they aren't the aggressor. The only one who can call for peace talks is Russia who continues to choose not to. You can't do peace talks if you're the one being attacked that's just called surrendering. 

&gt;Saying NO to judging by face colour.

No one on the left is judging by face color. For example Clarence Thomas happens to be black but every democrat i know agrees hes a piece of shit because of the content of his character

&gt;Paper ballots

Elections are already done on paper ballots 

[https://www.indiatoday.in/fyi/story/us-presidential-elections-paper-ballots-e-voting-350273-2016-11-04](https://www.indiatoday.in/fyi/story/us-presidential-elections-paper-ballots-e-voting-350273-2016-11-04)

&gt;Ending Nazi-like censorship.

Please give me an example of someone being sent to a concentration camp for something they said.

&gt;Fixing the economy.

Unemployment is below all historical levels, Inflation is down to 2.6% well within the range the Federal reserve shoots for, gdp is growing. what exactly is wrong with the economy. What indicator do you have a problem with?

&gt;No to trying to stop the weather from changing.

Climate is not weather. This would be like saying that Nasa trying to prevent a meteor from crushing Earth and wiping out life on the planet would be trying to "change the weather"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743953209.0" user="MajorPainmeme" delta="False">
    <text>Your anger shows regret</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755311393.0" user="MOUNCEYG1" delta="False">
    <text>Trump doesnt, this is the "media is the enemy of the people" president, so much for freedom of the press.

Sure, all of  Ukraines soverign territory back is a good deal to end the war yes?

I agree with that. That being said, Trump isnt gonna replace them with socioeconomic class based policy. 

Why? 

Doesn't exist in the US.

This is the guy who spent and spent and spent in a boom, while crying 4 years later about Biden not reducing the spending enough after recessions and during a war? 

Climate is not weather.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
