<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="78" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43748873309.0" user="ligasecatalyst" delta="False">
    <text>Let me start off by saying, fuck Trump. He’s a treasonous piece of shit. That being said, I think you’re missing two things.

The first is that the current conservative narrative, aside from evangelicals, isn’t really about family values or religion. It’s more about disdain for the “deep-state”, opposition to illegal immigration which they view as threatening the nature of the country, and an anti-progressive culture war. It’s a dumb and harmful narrative, but it’s still a narrative - something they truly believe in. 

The second point is a (comparably less dumb) willingness to ignore character flaws they deem irrelevant, or less relevant. Sure, Trump is an adulterer. So what? They’re supporting him for President, not marrying him. Same goes for religion. Yeah, maybe he wouldn’t be the guy they want their daughter to marry. That’s not the position he’s running for. And to be honest, pretty much every voter has to compromise and pick what’s more, and less, consequential to them. A lot of democrats voted for Hillary despite significant reservations about her. That doesn’t mean they don’t believe in anything. It means they chose between the lesser of two evils instead of staying home and letting the greater evil win.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
