<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="36" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43744151180.0" user="Agitated_Budgets" delta="False">
    <text>You failing to understand your political opposition is the main explanation.

The people voting for Trump and the people who were gung ho for a president Romney are not the same group of people. If it can be said anyone was really excited for Romney.

You are using a caricature of what a Republican is to argue a bunch of individuals that never fit that caricature are not living up to their supposed values. Many of which don't even apply to them.

But really it's just shaming tactics whenever people do this. They hope to weaken an enemy by guilting someone who supported them into doing something else. You could make the same arguments on principle about Biden and his pay for play operation.

None of this shakes you if you just go in assuming all politicians are horrible people and you're just picking the one least likely to mess up your holiday.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745019880.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Could you give some specifics? Which "don't apply", for example?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745097369.0" user="Agitated_Budgets" delta="False">
    <text>Well some of your caricatures are just doomed. Like the religion one. You act like them not memorizing the Bible means anything. Some do, far more don't, but most people aren't academics. 

So, some people will not be religious at all. Plenty of people like that also vote Republican.

Others will be religious but not as you imagine religious people are. Maybe it comes from a community teachings and gut feel kind of place rather than memorization. Not uncommon. They are doing what they feel compelled to do by that religious feeling they let guide them. It just isn't the explanation you want.

Others still will be religious as you imagine but have honed in on some principle you're ignoring that explains it. And if you're making a religious case for not running Trump you're forgetting that forgiveness and redemption is kind of a big plot point in certain parts of the Bible. Goes over pretty well. And he'll happily play the "reformed New York degenerate" role on TV. How true it is doesn't matter. What matters if it he's given the benefit of the doubt by them.

And others still will be religious, think he's a bad guy, but suppress that because in politics you only get to vote for bad guys. And so they determine he's less bad than the alternative. They only get to vote for bad options so they pick the least destructive in their view.

All ways your "they don't hold a principle here" falls apart. They just don't do what you want. That's all this is. A shaming tactic. Pearl clutching.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745758298.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You are trying to hand-wave away the incredible hyposcrisy on display by saying that it's simply that I personally don't like it. It is Trump who touted his extreme dedication to the faith, not me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745798956.0" user="Agitated_Budgets" delta="False">
    <text>No, you're trying to take things that can be logically consistent and paint them all as hypocrisy because you don't understand the people you're talking about, you don't understand people in general, or you have an argument posed in bad faith.

It's not hand waving when I say "Your argument is bad, this is why it's bad, here are a bunch of ways in which one of the examples you gave are built on your caricature not what people really are."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745835971.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree, for the reason I've already given above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745930173.0" user="Agitated_Budgets" delta="False">
    <text>Which is why you're wrong. "But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him." "Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values"

Look, answer this. Why do you think the GOP is your conception of conservative? Why do you think they even **are** conservative at the voter level?

You're making the mistake of thinking the GOP is "the crowd you have imagined" when they've been going through tumult and infighting because a populist wing full of new people is bashing heads with boomercons.

Your conception of the GOP sounds like what someone in the early 2000s would say the GOP was in the 1990s. You're like 30 years out of date.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746005594.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You are making my original point for me. If it's a radically disagreeing mish-mash of opposing views then why have they got behind Trump? Instead of theorising about what I imagine, give your own view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746130303.0" user="Agitated_Budgets" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not theorizing about what you imagine. I'm pointing out you're acting on your imagination instead of reality.

You're also being kind of silly about this. ANY mainstream political party will be a mish-mash of opposing views. Every party has factions. Many factions usually. As well as adjacent parties that sometimes dip voters and candidates in and out of their ranks depending on how things are going.

My whole point is you have this idea of **what a conservative is** that seems to be rooted in something other than what a conservative is. And then you hold them to that straw man. Or you just ignore one of the most common principles in politics. The one you can apply to nearly any ideology and resolve all hypocrisy instantly.

**All politicians are awful so I have to pick the one that will do the least harm or get me that one thing that will be good. I can't vote for a good person they aren't on the menu.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747522897.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, again you're just breezing past what I actually wrote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760776915.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
