<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="151" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43783782946.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>Very true.  And voting for a riddled old man with dementia proves the same for the other party.  Really. Is this the best we as a country can do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783939941.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>No it doesn't remotely prove the same. For starters, if you want to look at dementia, look at Trump. According to him, Biden is going to drag us into world war II.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43784286046.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>Hey.  I’m not saying one is better than the other.  They both suck.  I’m only asking, is this the best two options we the people have to offer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43784371331.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;They both suck

Enough with the "both sides". Biden hasn't called for his political opponents to be locked up and **killed**. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;And I wouldn’t say trump has dementia. 

Then why are you saying that Biden does, based on similar evidence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43785989047.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>Why would you vote any man or woman that obviously has no clue what day it is or where they are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43786361566.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You don't seem to have answered the question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43786460011.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>It’s obvious. If you can’t admit it I’m basically having a conversation with someone who can’t or won’t see reality. So there’s no point in carrying on.  Wake up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43792402950.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Who was it that said he beat Obama in 2016? Was that Trump or Biden? Who was it that said that Biden will drag us into world war II, a war that ended years ago? Was that Trump or Biden?

When Trump can put together a coherent sentence on stage or on "Troth Senchal", then maybe we can talk about the evidence of who has dementia. Not that either one of us is a psychiatrist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43794077775.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not defending Trump at all.  They are both obviously unfit.  My point from my first statement has been.  Is this the best we the people have to offer.  Both are unfit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43786469120.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>You really think that Biden is the best person the dems can offer to be president?  SMH.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43792394299.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have some issue with sticking to the topic? Why do you keep changing the subject?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43794139261.0" user="frontofthewagon" delta="False">
    <text>Haven’t changed topic once. My first comment was they are both unfit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43794374682.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>No one ever mentioned Biden being the best person that the Democrats could muster, apart from you. That wasn't part of my original CMV either.

You keep bringing up examples of Biden's gaps and ignoring examples of Trump's. 

You claim that you are not defending Trump, when you say that Biden has dementia but you don't agree that Trump has dementia.

Your posts are an absolute mess of self-contradiction and inability to stay on topic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
