<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="137" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43767951926.0" user="conservatore" delta="False">
    <text>Just a few questions will tell you the actual reason. Honestly none of that stuff you reference up there matters to most people. They want food on the table, cheap utilities, and affordable housing. They are also tired of war and being placed last in the priority list when it comes to international affairs. You can hate the way he went about foreign policy all you want, but it got results. The questions:

Was your life better in 2018?

Did your dollar go further?

Did we have any major foreign conflicts?

Many of you on this thread may not like it but all of those things were better for a lot of people when Trump was in office. I get very tired of hearing why it was actually Obama who made all that possible for the good years and why it is all Trump’s fault for why it’s bad now. I don’t believe any of that. The endless March to blame Trump for everything, go after him for stuff that no normal person or politician would be taken to court over, and the lying to our faces from Garland that the bureaucracy in the federal agencies don’t have a different set of rules for republicans than they do for democrats are just a few of the reasons Trump is back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43768826521.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;go after him for stuff that no normal person or politician would be taken to court over

I'm pretty sure I'd be taken to court for fraud, rape, or keeping nuclear secrets at my golf course. 

&gt; I get very tired of hearing why it was actually Obama who made all that possible

Whether you get tired or not is not the question. Democrats in general have been better  for the economy, and above all the public finances, by almost every metric that can be measured. Any idiot can introduce unfunded tax cuts. And what exactly is the US president supposed to do about cost-push inflation?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
