<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="107" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43753305413.0" user="octaviobonds" delta="False">
    <text>You have it completely wrong. People are dong with the established political class in Washington. They don't trust the professional politicians who are selling this country down the river. 

Trump already has a record, and a very good one. He brought the economy back, he ended unnecessary wars, and also the only president who has not started any new wars. He exposed the lying stinking media the uniparty Washington for what they were.  Closed our borders to a large degree. Axed the green agenda and Obamacare. Brought manufacturing jobs from overseas.

But after Trump left, it is established corrupt Washington politics as usual. Now we are back at wars we can't win. Our economy is in peril, our border is a complete mess. The corrupt green agenda is back on the table raping Americans. But more importantly the immorality that is pushed by Washington is the sole reason why Trump needs to come back, at least held off the barbarians at the gate from morally bankrupting America.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
