<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743043918.0" user="The_B_Wolf" delta="False">
    <text>It's not just blind tribalism. It really is about something. One side wants a more inclusive, multi-ethnic, egalitarian democracy. The other side wants to preserve white supremacy, misogyny and homophobia. When you hear a MAGA dummy use the word "woke" try substituting the word "inclusive." It's shocking how well it works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743804062.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>An incredibly depressing take</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743885128.0" user="The_B_Wolf" delta="False">
    <text>It's been brewing for the last forty, fifty years. Since the civil rights movement, desegregation, women's lib movement. In reaction to those events:

* The NRA went from being a gun safety/marksmanship group to a political group
* The Evangelicals turned against abortion
* Republicans turned against a government that had betrayed them and vowed to be against anything the government might do to materially benefit average Americans. 
* Regan declared government is the problem

Then we put a black family in the White House for eight years. Democrats looked sure to put a woman in next. And gay people can get married now!

Along comes Donald Jerome Trump. What's he got that the others haven't got? Open racism and misogyny. Finally a full-throated defense of Our Way Of Life. It's been his only appeal all along. It's why no scandal can bring him down. Is he still being mean to brown people and women? We're still with him! And now his followers have decided that if democracy means giving up the social order they're comfortable with, they'll do without democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744846413.0" user="SpezEatLead" delta="False">
    <text>it's also just incredibly wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747888465.0" user="The_B_Wolf" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I thank you for that cogent and thorough rebuttal. I certainly have some things to think about now.

Seriously, though. You want to debate it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747918542.0" user="SpezEatLead" delta="False">
    <text>i mean arguing a negative isnt really possible, especially when it comes to what someone believes, since it fundamentally lacks external evidence. 

but to refute the single argument you presented for your position, replacing one word with a different one changes the meaning. you can't just change someone's words as evidence of their beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748141316.0" user="The_B_Wolf" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have to argue a negative. You can tell me what you think are the reasons why we are where we are politically in America. I'm prepared to argue for my opinion. 

As far as word substitution, just try it as an experiment. "I'm against all this ~~woke~~ *inclusive* ideology!" "I'm against all this ~~wokeism~~ *inclusiveness* in the military." Is that not exactly what they mean when they are objecting to books that have gay people in them and a military that no longer distinguishes between gay and straight? Meanwhile, when you ask *them* what they mean, they can't seem to articulate it very well. Hmm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748986470.0" user="SpezEatLead" delta="False">
    <text>"I hate ~~fried oysters~~ jews" "~~fried oysters~~ make me sick!" "I don't want to go to a restaurant that serves ~~fried oysters~~ jews"

see how utterly absurd it is to replace words as a way to "prove" someone's beliefs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749128954.0" user="The_B_Wolf" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that substitution doesn't work, does it. You can put whatever you  want in the formula. But if it doesn't work, it doesn't work. But if it does, it does. make your case. So far.. not so much.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
