<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="157" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44613529644.0" user="ContestVast1984" delta="False">
    <text>Given the choice between Biden and Trump: who do you think will promote more traditional conservative values? It’s not complicated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44616607361.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Probably not the serial liar and adulterer, right? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44616659617.0" user="ContestVast1984" delta="False">
    <text>Personal attacks are not compelling logic. Stick to policy and outcomes, champ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44617562161.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>It was you who brought up conservative values, not me, champ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44617568854.0" user="ContestVast1984" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. And I want someone who will use policy to further those. Not someone who is omg such a nice guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44617587305.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Why would someone who doesn't embody or believe in those values at all, further them? The coping is absolutely unreal here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44617614641.0" user="ContestVast1984" delta="False">
    <text>Dude. He was president for 4 years. I already have receipts. If he wasn’t president Roe v. Wade wouldn’t been overturned. That’s one of many, many examples where his policy had an impact despite “not embodying values” which - lol - had always been a dumb way to choose candidates. Go go vote for someone who says the right words, because I guess that’s your level of depth. I’m done with arguing with your low IQ ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44621054344.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK so finally, on your 4th attempt, you actually put forward an achievement of Trump's. See, we got there in the end. 

But that's a **terrible** example. It had absolutely nothing to do with Trump that 3 justices were due to be replaced on his watch. Please tell me that isn't the best you've got.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44628620334.0" user="pro-frog" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
