<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742862849.0" user="toxicroach1" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine how scared and out of your depth you have to be to look at Donald Trump and think he's going to save you. It's some kind of religious phenomenon, more or less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742927146.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>That's my perspective, but his support is huge. It's not some tiny minority of the population. I just don't get it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749123219.0" user="Bandit400" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, you should do some research to understand it. I'm not saying you need to agree with it, but you should legitimately try to understand it. Try going to YouTube and watching the Timcast podcast. Lots of good left/right debate each night, and you'll understand the viewpoints better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750400153.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>That's just the problem. The more I see of Trumpists, the LESS I understand. This guy is not normal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751838672.0" user="Bandit400" delta="False">
    <text>So have you made any effort to actually hear what they have to say? I mean, roughly half of the voting public voted for him . If you think that's because half of the country is under some Trumpian cultish spell is ridiculous. Until you realize that people have legitimate grievances with the current system, you'll never understand it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751847798.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it ridiculous?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751883598.0" user="Bandit400" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's not true. Trump is a symptom, not a disease. He simply tapped into, and provided an outlet for existing concerns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743911811.0" user="Lb2815" delta="False">
    <text>Yea I am really afraid of low gas prices, low food prices, a contained southern border, low minority unemployment , but at least we do not get anymore mean tweets.   
and if you are not scared just listeNing to dementia joe try to answer an unscripted question. You are out of your depth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744263118.0" user="toxicroach1" delta="False">
    <text>uh huh 

gas prices. That's what you got? Lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755775251.0" user="-passionate-fruit-" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;low gas prices, low food prices

Gas prices are predominantly affected by forces outside the POTUS's control.  Food prices are strongly affected by inflation, which Trump contributed to when he signed off on the Covid relief cash giveaways that were financed by creating money out of thin air instead of undoing his tax cuts on the rich (the Democrat-controlled House had a hand in this, TBF).

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;a contained southern border

\#1 Show me illegal immigration numbers that illustrate what you're talking about.  #2 An unguarded wall is going to barely affect illegal immigration; what will is heavy legal penalties on those who employ them, but Republicans have had the opportunity to do write such legislation -- including Trump -- yet they didn't do it.  Efforts to privately finance a bigger border wall gained very little money.  The people you should be overwhelmingly blaming for not having better anti illegal immigration measures are other Republicans.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;low minority unemployment

??? National unemployment has reached the lowest since =checks notes= 1953, under Biden, so what are you talking about?  It's amazing how convincingly the Republican propaganda MSM can lie to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770501677.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>Its because in 2023, these Reddit comments ARE conservative MSM.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760591665.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
