<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="79" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43748882076.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>You can make all the lists you want, conservatives are largely satisfied (🙋🏿‍♂️) with how Trumps presidential term went... Some people thought it went great. That's all that matters, to many. Personally I'm of the belief that even tho i thought he was a good president, policy wise, he is so divisive, I think he and the other side will be at each other's throats so much, i dont know if it'll be worth it AGAIN. 

Plus... people bash the "culture wars" but voters eat that shit up. Conservatives will vote for almost any of their own thats against liberalisms we'reseeing these days. Its really that simple. And Trump is such a big personality, its no space for any of the others in the race, to breathe or spread their wings</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750381590.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You're making my point for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750532789.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>No im not. Its not about owning or one-upping the other side. Its about fundamentally disagreeing with the philosophy and overall viewpoint of the other side. And choosing the person seen as the best fit for stopping their vision of America from being a reality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751451896.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You just said that the list I made doesn't matter. So tell me what does matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751682750.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>Pushing conservative leaning values/culture via policy... Supreme Court Justice picks were probably his biggest win... Push back against hyper-progressive social issues. Lgbt ideology towards kids, abortion-happy policies, hyper-globalism, pro-guns (i actually dont like his gun record but he talks the talk, for whatever its worth, despite banning bumpstocks and saying "take gun first, due process later smh). And lower taxes. These are policy pushes conservatives vote for that he (except for guns) touted and actively worked towards. Liberal values are on the opposite spectrum and hence why conservatives dont care about your list. We care about pushing our values that we believe have a moral high ground just as liberals believe they have a moral high ground. Im sure success is some sort of balance somewhere in the middle, but im just speaking on why Trump gets the right wing nod... Values. And he also demands everyone's attention when he walks in every room. Kinda like when Obama came to some event President Biden had, and the reporters gave all their attention to Obama and mostly ignored Biden. Cause he doesnt have "it"...

Trump's personality is trash and he is not a likable human being at all. But if you cant admit he has an "it-factor" to him, youre not being honest with yourself. Which is why he has the power and influence he has. And also, consequently, why he goes through all the bs and controversy he constantly goes through. He cant separate the two, because he wouldnt be who he was if he only had one or the other characteristic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751870879.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK now we're getting somewhere. You're conservative, right? A lot of what you've listed there is just Trump saying the right stuff. What are your top 5 things he has actually delivered?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752165012.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>Conservative Supreme Court justices

The economy boomed whether it was from Obama policies taking effect or Trump bringing confidence to businesses and investors idk. But it happened under Trump

Black folks (the community i care about the most) had a lil fear and gettyup about us. Feeling like "racist Trump will fuck us" had us starting businesses and buying guns like never before. I loved that aspect

Gas prices were as low as theyd been since i was an adult. And actually stayed there seemingly.

I liked that he met with North Korea, even tho an official peace treaty didnt get done. I hate the narrative that we cant/shouldnt talk to enemies....  And i was concerned as hell, but after all the hype died down, i like that he pulled the trigger on Solemeini. Looks like he put the fear in Iran pretty bad. They even shot down one of their own planes just from being scared shitless, soon after

I have a love/hate viewpoint on his Syria policy. I hate that America always spends money and resources on Empire and acts as if we have a moral high ground. He said straight up we were in Syria "only for the oil"  He said, and i quote, "45 million dollars a month. Keep the oil."  That shit was cold as fuck to me. And at the same time it was a relief that a politician was being brutally honest about how the empire works... I think they fixed it up later, and someone in the DoD said it was for the Syrians fighting ISIS or something of the like. But the actual president didnt even try to pretty it up. I actually have respect for that type of honesty. I dont put him on any kinda pedestal or anything, Im sure he lies and did lie, plenty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752405288.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>The supreme court justices fell into his lap. It was pure luck, plus Republican cheating, that gave him three vacancies to fill. Why do you talk about it like it took some great feat of leadership?

Gas prices and economy had nothing to do with him, as you rightly say.

North Korea – again as you say, nothing got done.

I'm not sure what you're trying to say about Syria or black people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753661444.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>The Supreme Court was my least descriptive point. I didn't make it out to be a "great feat".Any republican could have done that but Hillary damn sure wouldn't have appointed conservative justices. Therefore its a Trump tribute... And i dont consider it cheating. It was fucked up to deny the Obama judge but it was political maneuver that WORKED.

Id say gas prices and economy did have to do with him. Truman dropped the bomb but he didnt even know anything about it until FDR died. But he gets credited for making that call, as he should. Obama gets credit for the bailouts but Bush already had it in motion. Such is life. Trump gets the credit for the economic boom just like he gets credit for the covid bust. I most certainly blame China and liberals and liberal state policies for starting and exacerbating the lockdowns, but all in all, Trump has to take that one on the chin.

North Korea, as i said, was a great step in the right direction. And he actually met with and talked to the guy. Which is something i have a great respect for, despite mainstream opinion to the contrary...

On Syria we took their oil for the profit, Trump announced it just like that, and didnt spin it as if we were "spreading freedom and democracy" which is par for the course in our foreign policy jargon... 
For black folks, we stepped up and created businesses more than I've seen in my lifetime and got heavy in the gun game. Which is as American as it gets. Thats a direct result of Trump being who he is... Whats confusing about me saying those two things?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754092125.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You listed the supreme court as one of his top achievements. We are playing games with words if you are now trying to say that anyone could have done it. It didn't take any particular skill on his part.

There is no serious economist who thinks that Trump had any significant effect on gas prices. Sorry but that's the fact.

North Korea. Nothing was achieved. I don't get in what sense there was a step in the right direction. You are buying into Trump's bullshit marketing unless you can name something solid that was actually achieved.

Syria. So what you are actually applauding here is the way he made the announcement? How is that an achievement? You have just basically saying that you like the way the guy talks.

And on black people setting up businesses and buying guns, you're going to have to show that that's true first of all, but more importantly, you're going to have to show that this was Trump's doing.

All of this seems to come down to, you like the guy's personality and/or the way he talks. Because you haven't named a single thing that he actually achieved through skill or merit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754577489.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>"What are YOUR top 5 things he has actually delivered"

Your question. My answers to it...

Nobody said anything about skill. HE delivered the justices. simple as that.

Domestic oil drilling lowers gas prices. Not saying thats the only factor. But in Trumps presidential term it was. And thats how he went about it.. When gas prices were high we blamed Bush when he was in office. When they were high AND low in Obamas terms, he had to take credit and blame for it. Same with Trump.

Willingness to meet enemies to prevent war. Especially nuclear war is a big deal to me. If you dont see it that way, then you just dont... I think some American prisoners got released and some old Korean War vet remains got released to families too. Positive stuff. Thats one of MY top things he delivered on, as you asked.

The Syria thing is transparency. We rarely get that out of foreign policy moves. And i mentioned before that he pulled the trigger on Solemeini and scared the shit outta Iran. Delivered on strong foreign policy.

[[Black economy improved under Trump](https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2020/11/01/donald-trump-african-american-black-economic-progress-vote-column/6081310002/)

[Black gun ownership increased under Trump](https://www.npr.org/2019/07/10/738493491/with-a-growing-membership-since-trump-black-gun-group-considers-getting-politica)
You can fairly say this is out of fear, but i dont care. Nobody else has/had that effect. And I'll take it 100x over.

I dont directly care for Trump at all. His personality or how he exaggerates every damn thing. What i do like is results and the byproduct of all that he encompasses. Even if fearing that he's racist (whether legit or not) fuels action. I LIKE THAT. Thats delivery enough for ME... whichbis what you asked</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754624315.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;HE delivered the justices. simple as that.

Something which anyone could have done. So on that logic, you should support anyone.  

&gt;Domestic oil drilling lowers gas prices. Not saying thats the only factor. But in Trumps presidential term it was.

Cite one serious analysis of commodity prices.

&gt;Willingness to meet enemies to prevent war. 

And get played? Like I said, point to what was achieved. You can't, because there's nothing there. 

&gt;Black gun ownership increased under Trump You can fairly say this is out of fear

Then why the hell is this positive for Trump? This makes absolutely no sense. 

&gt;Thats delivery enough for ME... whichbis what you asked

I appreciate you taking the time to respond. But having had multiple chances, you can't actually point to something solid that he achieved. He's either the beneficiary of good luck, or taking credit for other people's work, or (as in the case of North Korea), it's smoke and mirrors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756420064.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>You willfully ignoring the points i made within the list as if they need your stamp of approval to be acknowledged by me. You even ignoring my citations. So why should i cite anything else for you to label it as something that you don't think counts, AGAIN.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43758996223.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;as if they need your stamp of approval

You seem to be getting upset that I won't agree with you. When you can give an example of an actual achievement, rather than just liking the guy's style, then we can have a discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759059011.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>At no point have i been upset. I just pointed out that you have made it clear already citation doesnt matter to you. You'll act like it hasnt bren given unless you agree with it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761288289.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You talk about my stamp of approval as if that is somehow a bad thing. No, we are arguing the point so obviously we are trying to convince each other. And if you make what I consider to be bad arguments then I am going to point it out. In a way, that is what having an arguement IS. 

Anyway, the substance of what I am saying is, if you are giving Trump credit for things that would have happened anyway, with or without him, and also giving him credit for things where he achieve nothing, such as North Korea, then your bar is incredibly low.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761768886.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>Conservative justices wouldnt have happened under HRC. It wouldve been the very opposite outcome. I refuse to believe youre discrediting that in good faith.

 Still ignoring the citation of black economy, which after this many responses you are potentially responding in bad faith.

I mentioned some of the exchanges that happened because of the North Korea Summit, since the actual meeting was nothing to you. You ignored that too. 

You dont consider taking Iranian Solemeini out a foreign policy point that "counts", since you ignore that too. Or the oil in Syria that we stole/are stealing to this day. Obama went in first.  It was secured by Trump. You'd be right to say it wouldve happened with or without him. But thats not how credit works,  unfortunately for your positions on it.

I have no party pr personal loyalties so it doesnt bother me to give credit where credit is due, on either side of the political aisle. Seems like you operate differently tho</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761785084.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Accusations of bad faith break the subreddit rules. Stop it. 

If you think I have "ignored" those points then go back and read my previous replies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762189244.0" user="TChadCannon" delta="False">
    <text>Bruh if your feelings hurt by me insinuating your approach is in bad faith because you refuse to address specific citations as answers for your questions to me; use your moderator powers to stop me or go run tell them. If thats the bar for getting chastised or suspended or banned from this sub, i dont wanna be apart anyway. Thats the talk of people that dont have good cases for their points. l Angle and nitpick at a rule to threaten me with. Miss me with that cause this is a lightweight conversation dude.  Ive looked back at your replies 3x over and you do not address with specificity my black economics citation. Only the black gun one. You dont address the Solemeini call.  You havent acknowledged the N Korea exchange i mentioned. You only said he got played.... I listed MY top things Trump delivered. Sure, a couple are a byproduct of Trump rather than a product of him (positive black gun culture being at the top).... But if you wont even acknowledge the ones thats the easiest to admit were a policy or actionable decision, why further waste our time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762351720.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Then don't be a part of it. Who's forcing you?

"I listed MY top things"

You keep saying this as if it should make you immune from criticism. Again, if you don't like having to defend your view then don't be part of the sub.

And I am sorry but you are quite wrong about the things I supposedly did not address. Read more carefully next time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762400274.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/TChadCannon – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20TChadCannon&amp;message=TChadCannon%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/-/k3qmkza/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
