<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="158" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44680724724.0" user="Theodora_Angleterre" delta="False">
    <text>Well, they believe in a few things, but those values reflect just how bankrupt the philosophy has become. Trump is the latest figurehead in the very same party that chose the Southern Strategy &amp; made excuses to pardon Nixon.

Conservatives care about controlling others while being totally unaccountable themselves. They value their own freedom while fantasizing about their neighbors in chains. They rely on the state to do their fighting for them because in their hearts they are cowards. They value wealth because every dollar they have more than somebody else proves their superiority. They claim to value tradition &amp; the rules, yet time &amp; time again the rules must be applied with full vigor when it is their enemies while whenever they get caught cheating it is suddenly time to heal &amp; move on.

Trump embodies their ethos because he has relied on corruption, wealth, &amp; whiteness to avoid accountability his entire life. His freedom represents the ability of white men in this country to get away with anything, even treason. There is no engaging with modern conservatism, it is a stain on civilization. Their founding principle is the suppression of rights &amp; oppression of others. This nation has become rotten without an effective counter movement.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
