<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43744180176.0" user="FermierFrancais" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's the opposite in fact. This is a conservative talking point, but blame the media on this one. There's a 1000+ variables at play here. White privilege, white guilt, nativism, othering, and a million other thhings that Trump isn't directly responsible for. What Trump did do, as a brilliant con artist but shit president and person, was con the working class whites into thinking he was on their side. Think of this. Your dad put himself and his wife through college with a trade job, bought a house, raised you, all while going to church and following the "rules" whether they were laws or repressive folkways and mores. Now in the modern day, you can't afford a house, the local sports team was bought out and is a feeder team for a real team, the local factory closed and pit the whole town</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
