<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="93" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43751245943.0" user="Dismal_Humor_4071" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you! Number one, FINALLY. 
I disagree that they don’t believe in anything, however. I’m in the thick of Trumpland and the beliefs are real. They want Mayberry back, they want God back in schools and their grandchildren raised as they were. They want a closed border because all they’ve ever known is freedom, they have no idea what oppression looks like but they’ve been given a healthy dose of addiction and they hate it. They believe the Second Amendment is surpassed only by The Golden Rule and that Jesus is the only correct answer. They’re good people, strong people, the kind of people you want at the frontline when the shit hits the fan. Some of them are radical or just plain crazy, but the bulk of them don’t care if your colored, gay or Muslim, they’ll still stop in a snowstorm to help you change a flat.

And they were beguiled by a self-made businessman who promised them he could give that back to them, if only they’d vote for him.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
