<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="35" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43744111462.0" user="JustinRat" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your sentiment about Trump, but after 30+ years as a Democrat I have come to realize they are just the same. The whole damn country acts like it's the freaking Superbowl when we are talking about our actual lives. Both sides pander and say whatever they think people want to hear without actually answering any questions and saying anything of substance other than some soundbite. Partially this is exacerbated by media, news outlets, and social media "justice" played out in the court of public opinion where nobody is allowed to be human, nobody thinks about the other as people, and nobody is allowed to make mistakes, change their mind, or have an open dialogue without fear of retribution. Personally I would vote for a computer before I voted for either party.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
