<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="72" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43748323512.0" user="chicoisking" delta="False">
    <text>“the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.”

This is just politics in a nutshell. Democrats just appear a bit more sensible even though this attitude remains present in other ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43771594127.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>Because any Republican who has actual values gets labeled a RINO and has their career tanked. Lots of Dem voters hated and hate Biden as a Presidential candidate, and voted against him in the primaries, and those people are allowed to critique Biden and the establishment without their political existence being destroyed because, and I cannot stress this enough, Dems care about things other than Biden. Dems want problems solved. Trump does not solve real problems. Everyone talks about tarriffs, walls, grab their pussy etc etc. None of that shit matters or has raised Americas global stature in a single way. Speaking of global stature, if Trump didnt give off such weakness to the world, Russia probably wouldnt be in Ukraine right now, lol. And what do Republicans fucking do when a country is fighting a former Communist aggressor and trying to defend their own fucking democracy like actual patriots would? Republicans bitch and moan about the budget... Which theyve never even cared for while in power ONCE since I was alive. OP asks this question because anytime there is an opportunity to show us who Republicans are - on the budget, on patriotism, and defending ones country, on strength on the global stage... hell, even election security: they operate in complete bad faith, doing anything to get elected and then fucking right off and failing to govern AT ALL. OP is kindly asking, since Republicans are not just allowed to but are ENCOURAGED to act in bad faith and maliciously, what they even stand for. Based on the real actions of real-life Republicans writ large, they dont care about any real issue, and certainly dont care about real people. Unless youre going to try and convince me that building a wall was supposed to help the average American somehow like the bad faith actor Republicans always end up being.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
