<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="92" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43751193146.0" user="Candid-Maybe" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's more than belonging to a tribe and beating another tribe, although negative polarization is a huge part of it. What we're seeing in the US is embarrassing in it's extent but not unique in the world with the trending love for populist, illiberal demagogues. So I think the question that should be asked more often is, why are so many folks primed to buy the crap the populist is selling?

Very real, global concerns are affecting people but their complexity and unsolvable nature has exhausted them into believing that who wants to tear down the system, claiming that they're vox populi is better than the alternative we're used to. 

Increasing wealth disparity, loss of community, increasing social disconnectedness, pretty much any of the side effects of social media, SOME progressive overreach (trigger warnings, safe spaces, microaggressions, saying it's appropriation to write from another sex/race's perspective, the obsession with Identity, 1619 project). Somehow, because of the latter, everything including the former got blamed on "elites" AND the left, and I mean "elites" the same way Trump would - folks who understand and thrive in government/society as it works right now.

This along with opportunist grifting, the conservative media bubble and echo chambers has led to the beliefs that no matter how bad a conservative is, the liberal alternative must always be worse. The rampant anti intellectualism/anti-science/conspiracy theorism. The platform built entirely on grievance, bad faith and straw-men arguments, whataboutism and false equivalence. Life is just simpler and feels less chaotic when you can believe that conservatives are trying to save us from the liberal scourge than the more complex reality.

It's why I struggle so much personally with my family. 15 years ago I identified as conservative and generally with my parents. By the time Trump was elected, the only thing we could agree on was that we couldn't agree on a basic set of facts. We're here right now because one side is completely disconnected from reality and is impossible to debate in good faith. And I'm saying this as someone who equally hates far left tendencies. 

Just look at so many of the counterarguments posed in this thread. They're likely whataboutist or false equivalence. They're driven by mental gymnastics and feeling instead of fact, and when someone pointed out a fact, it's disregarded or deflected.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
