<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742954355.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>everyone of your bullet points could be said about Biden as well</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743096078.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>But of course we wouldn't bring it up because that's a completely different discussion that needs to be held on its own.

It's like you think it's a great point to change the subject. When in reality it's one of the weakest argumentation tactics.

Stick to the subject at hand and argue the merits or criticisms on their own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743162953.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>I was comparing the hypocrisy of the OPs statement</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743187723.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>To virtue signal?

What does that accomplish? Remember, you are in a subreddit that is for long discussion and exchanging ideas.

How is this contributing to the conversation?

This is not a place for Fox News style drive-bys. Please act accordingly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743215092.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>no to compare the hypocrisy.  I think I already said that.  Maybe the OP will understand they all renege on their promises and maybe it'll r/changemyview</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743240980.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>This is a red herring. A logical fallacy.

Whether you realize it or not all you've done is create a red herring to change the subject of the discussion.

If you're truly interested in changing someone's view you should learn what logical fallacies are and how to form a proper logical argument.

Because anyone with an education won't take you seriously when you use fallacies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743251920.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>I'll make my point how I please</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743267506.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, so you aren't serious about changing views. No worries.

When you use logical fallacies the only people's you can convince are they uneducated and emotional decision makers.

If you want to convince someone using sound logic, you can't use fallacies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743299995.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>No fallacies given</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743305298.0" user="mrGeaRbOx" delta="False">
    <text>Your post is a red herring.

It does not address the topics at hand.

Red herring is a fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743117455.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>No, they really couldn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743152558.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree obviously</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743172074.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>Cool.

Explain it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743219674.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>you first</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743230267.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>Predictable. Makes a statement and won't back it up. I should've known.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743258230.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>LOL  you made the first statement.  Will you back it up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743269064.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>So I replied to nothing?

Or are you just another shitty 12 year old troll like most of the Trump fans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743292885.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>A person knows they have won the argument when the other starts name calling.  Have a good day</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743299389.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>You thought this was an argument?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743309592.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>sorry I was out of breath from my victory lap.  discussion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743370845.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure getting out of your chair really wore you out, kid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743377303.0" user="whywhywhy4239" delta="False">
    <text>I am 60yo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743384170.0" user="230flathead" delta="False">
    <text>That's pretty sad, buddy. You'd think someone of your age would be able to defend your position. Must be all the lead poisoning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743439606.0" user="Doodenelfuego" delta="False">
    <text>I'll give it a go

Family values: He sniffs and gropes kids and its creepy, showered with his daughter  
  
Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible  
  
Managerial competence: ignorant of where he is at any given time  
  
Honest dealing: Hunter Biden and his dealings  
  
Promises kept: where's the money for student loans?  
  
Decorum: See family values  
  
Democracy: Believed by many to have rigged an election</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
