<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742979214.0" user="Sapphfire0" delta="False">
    <text>Wanting to "beat the other tribe" is something the democrats are better at. Dems are much better at demonizing the gop than the other way around. Also are you saying his policies aren't conservative? You mention competence, honestly, promises, and democracy but I can say the same about most other politicians. His policies include strong military, pro-life, free market, and others that have always been conservative views</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743532778.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You mention competence, honestly, promises, and democracy but I can say the same about most other politicians

I just don't think that's true. I've never seen another politician so consistent try to undermine an electino result, let alone a former president. I've never seen such an obvious crook either. And some of the promises were so outlandish that there was/is no way he could ever deliver. Peace in Ukraine in 24 hours? Please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744332891.0" user="Sapphfire0" delta="False">
    <text>Yes there are fair criticisms of trump, but you're saying his supporters don't believe in anything. He didn't just pull something out of the hat and tell his supporters "you agree with this now". The biggest issue he brought to the table was immigration, but both sides were largely in favor of border security 10 years ago. Many of his policies are largely in line with conservative views before him</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744908637.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK wait so now you're saying, his appeal is due to concerns about immigration? 

What are the other policies you're thinking of?

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;you're saying his supporters don't believe in anything

I'm saying they seem happy to flush many traditional conservative values down the toilet, so what do they REALLY care about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745589860.0" user="VoidsInvanity" delta="False">
    <text>Look at his quote about “transgenderism” and how he openly admits “none of you cared about this before I brought it up” and they cheer for that. 

Can you explain that at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744244510.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, when you say demonizing, I think of slander campaigns. This is GOPs bread and butter more so than dems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744350986.0" user="Sapphfire0" delta="False">
    <text>I think of both campaigns and media. Just look at opinion polls. Democrats view republicans much more negatively than the other way around. How many people vote for the democrats and how many vote against the GOP?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744377509.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>You are faulting opinions of candidates based on opinion polls to justify your argument?

Trump and base have earned their negative report with their behavior. J6 and support for is a huge problem.

You can flip this around and ask how many vote for GOP and against democrats? That's a huge problem either way. That's tribalism.

Opinion polls are pretty notoriously bs, too.

Republicans campaign on hateful policies l, actions, and narratives. Of course people hate them. Democrats are not out there yelling about how they are going to 'own the conservs'...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744445080.0" user="Sapphfire0" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't mention candidates? You prove my point exactly. You and so many others belive the GOP is full of all these horrible hateful people, and yet you think they are better at demonizing the dems? If you're going to ignore opinion polls, then show me something else</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744513701.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>The rhetoric of the current republican party is centered around hate and emotion.

Your arguments are incredibly lacking. What do you mean? Use your words.

People don't like to be persecuted. GOP campaigns on persecuting an out group while protecting an in group. Of course they are disliked. Why would anyone who loves a person of color, immigrant, woman, or member of LBGTQ support someone who wants to punish them?

Democrats aren't going after farmers, military, or rural citizens. Democrats aren't demonizing Trump excessively more than he demonized them.

Just look at the Hunter Biden stuff. Oh look how much his dad did for him? While completely ignoring Trumps kids being brought on to the administration.

What about people at polling places harassing voters to vote for Trump with intimidation tactics?

What about J6?

How about all of the insults Trump tweets/truths?

Your argument relies on a false dichotomy. The same reasons you are criticizing Democrats would be more applicable to Republicans themselves, and you don't even acknowledge that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744694331.0" user="Sapphfire0" delta="False">
    <text>I can't argue with you. You keep going off on tangents and not talking about your own original point at all. You are putting words in my month and accusing me of saying things I have never said. Next time open your mind a little</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744776833.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Typical deflection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746184455.0" user="Jealousmustardgas" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Democrats aren't demonizing Trump excessively more than he demonized them

LMFAO, y’all still believe he said Nazis were good people, 50+% of Dems think Russians hacked election machines to change votes in 2016, and they impeached him twice on the flimsiest reasons. But sure, they’re blameless and you’re the champions of the poor victims that are being targeted by GOP policies, okbuddy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746443075.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Where do you even get this sort of info. I don't believe 50% of democracy believe we were hacked. I believe you are misrepresenting their belief that Russia interfered via influence. This is not hacking or compromising, though.

You stated I believe Trump said Nazis are good people, but I have never indicated such. That said, Trump has plenty of public remarks that aren't much better than saying this directly.

Impeachments... flimsiest of reasons? How were they flimsy, and how do they compare to the current reasoning for impeachment Biden?

Double standards abound in your comment.

You claim GOP is _not_ targeting liberals, women, LBGTQ, immigrants, etc? They literally have polluted their public space with promises to enact the targeting of these groups.

You are gaslighting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746492975.0" user="Jealousmustardgas" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/opinion/whoever-convinced-most-democrats-that-putin-hacked-the-election-tallies-is-doing-putins-bidding

We have the honor of being one of the most propagandized to people in history, biden’s dirty af, while you impeached trump for asking about said corruption in Ukraine. I am not gaslighting, you’ve been gaslit by the media narrative since 2016</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746504746.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Washington examiner is a known propaganda outlet.  Soo... ummm... even if it wasn't, maybe don't cite opinion pieces with no credible sources as evidence? Especially one written by a pseudonym?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745579254.0" user="VoidsInvanity" delta="False">
    <text>If they aren’t hateful people why do they choose to elect peoples who’s entire platform is based on hate…?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744658252.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Just look at opinion polls. Democrats view republicans much more negatively than the other way around.

Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763718740.0" user="Additional-Grand9089" delta="False">
    <text>I bet you believed all 6 years of russia collusion and still bought that the laptop was disinfo.

Useful idiot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763780397.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>If you are unaware of Russian disinformation prior to 2016, and cannot piece together why the laptop story has serious holes and isn't even as egregious as what Trump is formally indicted for, than I don't think there is any possible common ground to debate with you.

What is your preference if given a choice, rich vs poor ... or democrat vs republican? And why does your choice serve you more than the alternative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763793844.0" user="Additional-Grand9089" delta="False">
    <text>I vote for individuals not collectives, useful idiot marxist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763874263.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763805388.0" user="Additional-Grand9089" delta="False">
    <text>“We’re getting additional insight into Russian activites from \[REDACTED\],” Brennan’s handwritten notes state. “Cite alleged approval by Hillary Clinton–on 26 July–of a proposal from one of her foreign policy advisers to villify \[sic\] Donald Trump by stirring up a scandal claiming interference by the Russian security services.” 

“Per FBI verbal request, CIA provides the below examples of information the CROSSFIRE HURRICANE fusion cell has gleaned to date,” the memo states. “An exchange \[REDACTED\] discussing US presidential candidate Hillary Clinton’s approval of a plan concerning US presidential candidate Donald Trump and Russian hackers hampering US elections as a means of distracting the public from her use of private e-mail server.”

&amp;#x200B;

https://thefederalist.com/2020/10/06/breaking-dni-declassifies-handwritten-notes-from-john-brennan-2016-cia-referral-on-clinton-campaigns-collusion-operation/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763836971.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Did you just quote the federalist? That's is a heavily biased source which often has poor credibility.

If this is the sort of stuff you consume, the result of you having these wild opinions, interacting with hostility, and not even answering any questions asked of you... is, well... expected.

English doesn't appear to be your native language either. So are you from some non-US country feigning to be a US citizen?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43786664326.0" user="HopefulWafer6195" delta="False">
    <text>Retard, the memos quoted in the article are declassified and publicly available. You can get them directly from the DNI if you actually cared about the truth of the matter.   


&gt;English doesn't appear to be your native language either. So are you from some non-US country feigning to be a US citizen?

Hussein, the FBI, the big guy, the CIA, and the whitehouse chief of staff knew in July of 2016 that the accusations that Candidate Donald John Trump was colluding (conspiring) with russians was a smear campaign by nasty woman and they knowingly used that false predicate and the intelligence agencies to spy on the leading opposition candidate for President, the President-Elect, and on the President (last FISA warrant was in February 2017) in coordination with the media and then tried to cover it up and you still believe that President Donald John Trump is compromised by the russians.

 I bet you believed the laptop was disinfo too. 

You are an easy mark, a gullible sucker, a useful idiot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43786684337.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/HopefulWafer6195 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20HopefulWafer6195&amp;message=HopefulWafer6195%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/-/k45g6fa/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763815479.0" user="Additional-Grand9089" delta="False">
    <text>They're laughing at you btw.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763877398.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763800049.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744632077.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Dems are much better at demonizing the gop than the other way around.

That's less a talent of democrats than a self-own by the GOP, to be honest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744717473.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>This is patently untrue.

Democrats successfully demonize Republicans for rolling back rights for minorities and dismantling social safety nets so that billionaires can privatize them for profit. That's about as hard as blaming the dog for the fur on the couch.

&amp;#x200B;

Republicans have successfully demonized Democrats for trying to make health care affordable and reducing the number of mid-winter LAND HURRCAINS in the Midwest. They're so good at demonization that they got rednecks to turn on Bud fucking Light.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746033535.0" user="resumethrowaway222" delta="False">
    <text>Specifically which rights to minorities did Republicans roll back?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746464112.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>The right to purchase services without worrying that they will be turned away over somebody's "religious belief."

The right to make their own healthcare decisions.

The right to be represented in government in district that appropriately reflects their community.

The right to vote with the same ease and convenience as people in sparsely populated conservative areas.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;

I'm sure there's more, but that's the top of my head.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746553844.0" user="resumethrowaway222" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have sources for these?  The only one of these that I know of a law that was changed is the second one, which I assume refers to abortions, but that isn't a minority rights issue anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746703986.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do you have sources for these?

You have google.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;The only one of these that I know of a law that was changed is the second one, which I assume refers to abortions, but that isn't a minority rights issue anyway.

You think that makes it BETTER?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770414006.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>Cons never have a real response, its just bad faith bs all the way down. The OP question should have been, "how do we convince cons to have discussions in good faith?" so we can get to the meat of the issue</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746129446.0" user="systemsfailed" delta="False">
    <text>First off,
What are you on. 

The entire LGBT people are "groomers" is one of the most horrific cases of demonizing I've ever seen. 

Conservatives constantly go on about "Marxists", and never once are they using the term right. Everything is communism, everything is Marxist. 

God, the entire abortion debate has boiled down to one side screaming "baby killers'

Are Democrats demonizing Republicans, really?
Or are they pushing vile ideology? Within my lifetime Republicans had a gay man arrested for the crime of being gay. And now Ken Paxton has openly stayed he's in favor of bringing back sodomy laws.  Is that demonization or is that accurately pointing out bronze age barbarism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749090277.0" user="Bandit400" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Conservatives constantly go on about "Marxists", and never once are they using the term right. Everything is communism, everything is Marxist. 

Left wingers constantly go on about "Fascists" and never once are they using the term right. Everything is Nazis, everything is Fascist. 

See how easy that is to do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749215711.0" user="systemsfailed" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao
Way to avoid basically every point I made. 

Republicans literally had their speaker claim he will "defeat socialism" when sworn in. 

The former president is literally daily calling prosecutors "Marxist communists"

But I'm sorry some people on the Internet called you a fascist. 

Also, considering the former president had Fuentes, you know an actual white nationalist, over for dinner. You kinda lost that argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749270047.0" user="Bandit400" delta="False">
    <text>The entire LGBT people are "groomers" is one of the most horrific cases of demonizing I've ever seen. 


Agree, some people take it too far, and paint with an overly broad brush. I'm not one of those. However, when you have sexually suggestive ( its not going to lick itself) drag shows with children present, you open the door to criticism. No adult should ever feel the need to dance sexually for a child. Full stop. 


Conservatives constantly go on about "Marxists", and never once are they using the term right. Everything is communism, everything is Marxist. 

God, the entire abortion debate has boiled down to one side screaming "baby killers'

Nope, I have plenty of reasons of why I disagree with abortion. None of them involves calling someone a baby killer or falling back on a religious argument. 

 Within my lifetime Republicans had a gay man arrested for the crime of being gay.

Who?


 And now Ken Paxton has openly stayed he's in favor of bringing back sodomy laws. Is that demonization or is that accurately pointing out bronze age barbarism?

I hadn't heard that. If true, he's wrong. That is not a Republican party platform. I do not agree with everything that everyone on the right says. Can I hold you to the craziest things said on the left?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
