<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="49" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43745394495.0" user="ZealousidealBother92" delta="False">
    <text>As a radical leftist, galaxies away from even being liberal let alone conservative, not sure if I agree. 

The hypocrisy listed is inherently irrelevant. The flip flopping is apart of the point. I'll break it down for you: 

-The right is divided between those who want to smash the poon but feel like the feminists aren't letting them and those who don't want to smash the poon because sex before marriage is basically cuckolding God. The best way to win over both sides is to brag about smashing poon while also pretending to care about family values/not cuckholding God. 

- Basically every Christian is clownish about the Bible. (Not every but the loudest and proudest) Theocracy requires hypocrisy in order to exist. Otherwise there would be conversion camps for people who wear cotton and have early Justin Bieber haircuts. Just kinda decreases your support by claiming those people are equally as bad as the queers. 

-Trump's so called "ignorance" is apart of the character, he as an actor is playing. In any behind closed doors conversion he speaks like a normal human being. The stupidity is to rile up the libs to foster their demonising while the cons see his stupidity as "being just like the commoners/not being a politician." Not that I care about liberals, but I feel like utilizing stupidity would help them too and I'm not sure why a boring NPC like Sleepy Joe never did that. 

- Majority of billionaire CEOs have been bankrupt during their rise. That's the point of capitalism in many ways. Boom and bust until you finish the crust. Liberals who use this argument, say this because they don't understand capitalism and think that's a gotcha point. 

-Ahh, broken promises. A thing no politican has ever done ever in history of everything. Gotcha 👌

-In their minds Joe Biden stole the election so this kind of thinking goes both ways. You really don't think liberals would cry about their stupid "democracy" had Trump won? 

In short, everything you mentioned as a hypocritical gotcha point, is irrelevant to criticising Trump. To win the red hat people over, you should maybe start with the fact that America was not at all great for an overwhelmingly majority of Americans and having a sweeping controversial solution is the only means of satisfying this pain that Hill Dog and Sleepy Joe deliberately ignore because they're too busy trying to cuck my man Bernie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745721235.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like much of this post is straying into "both sides" territory. I cannot agree with that, sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745748136.0" user="ZealousidealBother92" delta="False">
    <text>Ironic because I'm very far from being a centrist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745774483.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Not what I accused you of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745927512.0" user="ZealousidealBother92" delta="False">
    <text>True. However liberalism and conservatism are inseparable ideologies that require eachother to exist. 
We're self aware enough now to acknowledge western civilization isn't a good idea anymore. Yet conservatives have a better ways of expressing this by pretending to be anti establishment. Liberals on the other hand, might as well cosplay as the French monarchy in the late 1700s.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
