<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="99" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43751863032.0" user="canttouchdeez" delta="False">
    <text>Uhhh that’s dumb as fuck.

We care about how the country is ran and Trump did a great job with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751972338.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't the place for you to do OAN drivebys.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752058663.0" user="canttouchdeez" delta="False">
    <text>I know that most Reddit users live in a bubble but you should try to leave it sometime. You might actually learn something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752377210.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly not from you though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753554660.0" user="canttouchdeez" delta="False">
    <text>Coming from someone who thinks that all Republicans are terrible I don’t think that you have any room to talk.

You’re clearly not looking for a serious conversation from anyone. 

Pretty pathetic to be honest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754231644.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Stop projecting. If you can find where I said all Republicans are terrible, then we can discuss that. The first line of your first comment was "that's dumb as fuck" and you have the audacity to try and give me advice about how to engage with other people. Yeah, no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755325852.0" user="MOUNCEYG1" delta="False">
    <text>What did he get done apart from tax cuts and supreme court justices that were largely based on luck? for a 4 year presidency you'd hope for a little more big legislation than one big tax cut bill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761254664.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
