<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="57" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43745832842.0" user="Speedking2281" delta="False">
    <text>As a Gen X conservative, I can't imagine voting for a democrat.  If this was 1980, maybe.  If there was a "1970s democrat" ticket, then I might follow that.  But there isn't.  So I'm stuck choosing to vote for a person who I think is a bad person in a party I think is better, or a person I think is personally better in a party I think is worse.  It's an easy choice, and I'd dare say 95% of people would do the same thing (regardless of party).  

It's the reason I held my nose and voted for Trump for the last two elections.  We'll see if I have to do it again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748213581.0" user="minimusme" delta="False">
    <text>As a fellow gen x conservative who voted republican in every election my entire life how do you justify voting for the current party

Mtg is the most popular republican as measured by donations and she has spoken at two white supremisist events, flys the confederate flag and spits out antisemitism frequently.    

Tommy Tuberville says white nationalist are what he calls good Americans and is actively trying to get them let back into the military. 

Multiple Republican senators have said the reversal of roe v wade  sets the precedent that will allow them to overturn interracial marriage

The leaders of the proud boy’s and several nazi leaning groups  had cabinet members personal cell numbers

Desantis knowingly hired am actual nazi speech writer + the whole slavery is good thing along with nazi group’s actively supporting him publicly.   

Trump just threatened American Jews in the last week for being disloyal.  

We could also discuss the two conservative political conferences this year hosted by authoritarian leaders preaching ethnic and racial purity. 

I am all for small government and lower taxes but I can’t support that.   I would rather we went full Venezuela than become what the current Republican Party wants.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
