<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="90" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43750786933.0" user="liveviliveforever" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, the same could be said of progressives rallying behind Clinton or Biden. 

Also, idk if you knew this but the reason Trump got elected in the first place is because a lot of people wanted literally anyone besides Clinton. Now those same people want literally anyone besides Biden, because the man has legitimately  lost his mind and doesn't know where he is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751189547.0" user="catmanbeliever" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't know Biden, who actually has wins for the American people who aren't rich,  is the same as Trump. 

Anyone with eyes can see this is a disingenuous POV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751558598.0" user="liveviliveforever" delta="False">
    <text>Biden has no idea what's going on nor does he have any plans for the American people no matter their wealth.

Anyone with eyes can see this and it is disingenuous you claim anything else. Seriously, you would have to be both blind and stupid to think Biden has any idea of what's going on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759783860.0" user="catmanbeliever" delta="False">
    <text>"Anyone with eyes", lol. 

I guess he hasn't done anything for you and I'm sorry. Go vote for Trump or something.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
