<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="73" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43748431587.0" user="TotallyNotFucko5" delta="False">
    <text>I have long contended that republicans are very black and white in their reasoning. Point A is true because validation A is true...period. And while point A might be true, they often times will refuse to acknowledge any nuance associated with it or the fact that Point B could also be true. Point A satisfies their argument so case is closed.

But you can, quite literally, use the keystone argument they rest their case on to argue against another one of their positions keystone arguments. 

They want small government but want the ability to control crime absolutely and also want nothing less than a military that can draw a name from a hat and literally be on its door step with a gang of armadas within the hour. They also want a government that snoops and intervenes in every countries bullshit down to the smallest nail so that their own government can ensure the best trade deals for their life styles.

They are prolife until the kid is born. Then its on its own. Its not the unborn childs fault the parent is unfit to be a parent but once its born and cant afford to eat lunch at school, its "fuck that kid, its the parents fault its in this situation." They of course just pretend the mountain of children in these situations should just be taken by the  (small and limited) government and raised to be doctors or whatever they think arises from most foster relationships.

They want lower taxes because taxes are stealing and lead to socialism but they love the police and the military which in my opinion are socialism. Its not my fault your gran or your wide and three kids are pussies who can't defend themselves in the face of danger and its not my responsibility to help pay for their protection and...and...a society of laws...

which they hate when they are applied to themselves with the same extra-judicial effect the police have become known for. Further worth mentioning that a society of laws requires taxes to pay for the arm that enforces said law and it also requires a basic ground work we all agree on so things can be reasoned against themselves. The people hate that system because it occasionally ensnares their shit heel nephews named Kyle which are for some reason different than other peoples shit heel nephews named Tyrone or Hector. 

\*\*\*

I wonder if republicans play games like SimCity or Travian or Age of Empires or Tropico and let their civilizations just run themselves at their own leisure or if they play the games as intended and maximize the output and enjoyment of their civilizations.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
