<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="85" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43749983841.0" user="Geezersteez" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree.

I honestly think that we are all being let down terribly by our political system, in particular the parties themselves.

By succeeding in only focusing on a limited number of polarizing issues they have effectively scuttled any chance at reasonableness and compromise.

This has led us to the point where each side has something in their program that is completely unacceptable to the other side.

For instance, previously I would look at the character of the individual candidate and judge them based on that (plus their platform obviously, but for ac while (couple decades ago) everyone was kind of maintaining the status quo, so it really came down to things like character and other minor program points.
Then things changed.

Nowadays my vote gets cast based on two issues, period. Nothing else matters.

Are you attacking the 2nd amendment?
You don’t get my vote.

As of this year, moving forward, I’ve added another issue: immigration.

If you intend to swamp us with millions upon millions of immigrants you will not get my vote.
If you’re ambiguous on the subject, you will not get my vote.

Period.

Now, people tell me I’m a pretty intelligent fella. Historically most people would consider me liberal.
I’m very aware that only the Sith deal in absolutes, and that nearly every problem facing us is extremely complex, and cannot easily be solved. It will require nuance, understanding, and discernment.
Yet I find myself in the position that I will probably be forced to vote for someone who doesn’t measure up to my standards, and who is unlikely to solve the problem to my satisfaction, but at least he won’t actively work against me. At least he’ll do SOMEthing, even if it’s not the BEST solution.

I despise Donald Trump, but he checks the above boxes for me.
I like some of what I’ve heard from the Indian guy, Rawamsai, so far.

Sadly, even were there an acceptable alternative to Trump that checked those two boxes... just two boxes! I’m not asking for much, am I?!...the second problem is that I wouldn’t be able to vote for them in this election anyway for fear of splitting the vote and handing the election to an even worse candidate than Trump. That would be Biden.

So, as you see, it’s not so much tribalism, more that we’re held hostage by these two political parties, who refuse to be reasonable.

The Democrats could say...hey we’re actually going to actively stop illegal immigrants and protect and uphold the 2nd amendment instead of actively trying to ban firearms.

And the Republicans could say, hey, we’re going to cut out all this trying to make abortions illegal stuff.

But, no. They both prefer to pursue radical agendas which contain unacceptable provisions to someone or another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750418559.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>We probably all have disagreements with both parties. But this is not a "both sides" issue. One side is trying to undermine democracy, the other isn't. One side talks about imprisoning and **killing** its opponents, the other doesn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753482377.0" user="Geezersteez" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. That’s a whole lot of hyperbole.

The truth is both parties are doing things to threaten our democracy, such as fooling with abortions (Republicans) and our ability to protect ourselves by carrying firearms (democrats). 

At least with firearms we’ll be able to protect ourselves from a truly unhinged or undemocratic government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754100171.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>It's what the guy actually said. What are you disagreeing with exactly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754354803.0" user="Geezersteez" delta="False">
    <text>Who advocated killing one’s political opponents?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754454566.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Buddy, come on. Trump told Beck the other week that he would have "no choice" but to lock up his opponents. This is just one in a long line of calls for violence and retribution. He gave his endorsement to the idea of extrajudicial executions of Antifa. He even called for the chairman of the joint chiefs of staff to be executed. And you look at that and say, "hey, both sides have faults"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754764413.0" user="Geezersteez" delta="False">
    <text>Have you considered that you assume too much?

I don’t follow Trump, he’s not my candidate, and I don’t know why you expect me to know every little thing he says.

A good search did not bring up any quotes of him advocating murder of his political opponents.

I did find some snippets of him being goaded (by Beck), into suggesting Hillary Clinton should be arrested because she’s a criminal.

Please support your allegations, otherwise you’re spreading misinformation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755012939.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>No, you're not following the thread. You went into a "both sides" justification, so I said Trump threatened violence, you said it was hyperbole. But it's not, because he did. That's how we got here. 

So I'm really not sure where this stuff about assumptions has come from. 

The comment about Milley was literally in the last week. You can find it if you look. The interview with Beck was in August and he wasn't talking about Hillary (exclusively). Again, it's all out there if you care to look so don't talk about "misinformation".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
