<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="144" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43778429078.0" user="Stunning-Feed-9145" delta="False">
    <text>If you made a post in the same vein but about liberals, it would look very similar. 

Biden is continuing to build the wall, apparently. It was racist to do so not long ago.

They have given billions of dollars in cash to Iran, who supported the Israel Terri attacks today, and their senators chant death to America. Oops!


Currently, it is the official opinion of the White House that 5 year olds can and should take hormones and get gender affirming surgery, if true child feels they are the wrong gender.

Almost all liberals feel it is totally appropriate, and if one of the parents does not want to transition their child, they should then lose their child. In reality, anyone who tried to transition a child is a groomer who deserves life in prison. 

Liberals also believe that borders shouldn’t exist, and that we should never deport somebody regardless of whether or not they have any ID. They refuse to acknowledge that supporting illegal migrants is also supporting the drug cartels that make money off of every illegal who passes into America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43778873799.0" user="tugboat8" delta="False">
    <text>Not arguing but do you have any proof of the hormones for 5 year old? Want to read up on that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43780525363.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Don't bother. That post is absolutely nutty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43780539953.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Some sources would be nice. But whatever, agree or disagree on policy, Trump has called for political opponents to be imprisoned and *killed*. Let that sink in before you reach for the reply button.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781585878.0" user="Stunning-Feed-9145" delta="False">
    <text>Aren’t Trumps opponents trying to put him in jail though?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783524395.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Has Biden called for Trump to be put in jail? Has Obama? Who are you talking about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43784633848.0" user="Stunning-Feed-9145" delta="False">
    <text>Yep.

Also, both Biden and Obama think that if a biological male verbally claims to be a female, all of society must treat them as one, despite having a penis and a mustache.

It’s very stupid! Haha!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43784758803.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>But they haven't though. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Also, both Biden and Obama think that if a biological male verbally claims to be a female, all of society must treat them as one, despite having a penis and a mustache.

This isn't true either. 

Posting statements that aren't true isn't a very good argument.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
