<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743034956.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that they are being tribal. It's that they agree with Donald Trump. You should read this book called Democracy in Chains by Nancy Maclean. It charts the rise of this right-wing movement in the United States which started with the neoliberal Mont Pellerin society. These were economists and philosophers who wanted a very libertarian sort of government with little to not regulations and taxation on businesses. 

And what people kind of usually leave out is that the fiscal conservative movement has always been tied to white supremacy, sexism, and anti-democratic measures, and paradoxically tons of investment in policing, prisons, and military. And while the neoliberals (like Charles Koch) have been secular, they have a marriage of convenience with the radical Christian right who form a very strong political bloc. And now straight up fascists have also joined this movement.

Trump did not really do anything new. He repeated some of the same things Reagan did. Buchanan ran in the 90s with a similar or exactly the same slogan and he didn't find much success at the time. Because unlike Reagan, Buchanan was too open and honest about his message. 

The capitalist class on either side (liberal and conservative) did not like Trump because he was erratic, he played to populism, he made all sorts of promises which went against their interests (health insurance for all, canceling TPP).

However, eventually the right-wing fell in line with Trump because he could win. This was not the 90s anymore. Since Fox News, the Republican base had been further radicalized. There was a growing populism since the financial crisis which Trump tapped into really well.

And they got what they wanted out of Trump. Trump's major piece of legislation was the tax cuts. He gutted the CDC, the NLRB, even the fucking Postal Service. He almost succeeded in cutting Obamacare. He nominated tons of right-wing judges, most of whom go through the Koch pipeline. Because Trump himself is so erratic and careless, his own agenda takes a backseat to that of the party establishment. The wall didn't happen, the tax cuts did. Anti-voting rights bills and anti-medicaid bills flooded the red states. The Neoliberal project marches on. The only mitigating factor to this was Covid which forced the government to invest in operation warpspeed and spend a lot in direct stimulus (because capitalism cannot function without this stuff as any crisis lays bare). 

So yeah, rhetoric about Christian values and all that aside, they all share a lot of ideology with Trump. They have the same political goals. Trump is an paradoxically an effective but also catastrophic vehicle for this movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743554921.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so at the core it's about tax cuts and deregulation, and his supporters agree so hard with that, that everything else is just ignored. Would that be a fair summary?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743647569.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's not just tax cuts and deregulation. It's complicated because it's tied also, as capitalism in the West has been, to racism, sexism, and this anti-democratic streak. It's important we don't discount those because they've always gone hand-in-hand with tax cuts and deregulation. In fact, they have to. 

And I don't know if the supporters agree. I think it's fair to say a bunch of people are duped. They watch Fox News which straight up lies to them. They think it's news, but it's naked propaganda. On Facebook, right wing websites make up a huge amount of traffic. Again, people are falling for this fake news.

It's not as if everyone agrees on the same reality and some decide on one solution and some decide on another. It's that the reality itself is up for debate, because there is so much misinformation within the capitalist media.

And it is also important, again, to tie this back to racism. Many people fall for the fake news because it plays to the racist beliefs prevalent in the US. They will vote against their interests even if they disagree because of racism. It's a been a long Republican strategy to use racism to cut welfare for everyone. White people want to protect their social security benefits and medicare, millions rely on medicaid. But they also vote Republican. This is not all of the Trump voters but in general I think this is true.

So I know you're trying to sum it up in a sentence but all the intricate connections here are key.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743732539.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's complicated because it's tied also, as capitalism in the West has been, to racism, sexism, and this anti-democratic streak. It's important we don't discount those because they've always gone hand-in-hand with tax cuts and deregulation. In fact, they have to.

Would you mind expanding on this a bit? They HAVE to? What makes you say that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743995396.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>One, capitalism in this country has its roots in slavery. And this colors everything about our society even today. Part of it is the idea that there is a difference in intelligence and capability between the races. And not just between the races, but among people in general, where the productive, intelligent few deserve the right to rule over everyone else. That wealth inequality is the result of the inequality in IQ. In modern times, this notion is expressed in the writings of Ayn Rand and Charles Murray's "The Bell Curve." We see this being used by economists and right-wing politicians as a way to justify cutting welfare, defunding public schools, cutting voting rights, etc. 

This strain of neoliberal capitalism relies on this myth. It relies on this myth of the great genius capitalists and also on the difference between the races. People have to believe this stuff for it to be a politically viable project. It's not a coincidence that the same people who talk about free markets and deregulation are also the ones who blame Black fathers or Black culture for their poverty. 

Two, the other part of this racism has to do with imperialism. The AFL (organization of labor unions) in the 50s supported the US bombing of Guatemala and the overthrow of their democratic government. Instead of showing solidarity with the exploited Guatemalan workers, the American workers took the side of United Fruit corporation. The AFL also allowed segregated unions and purged progressives and leftists who tried to change that. It is in capitalism's favor that the workers are divided in this way, by race, by nationality. And again, the political project of neoliberalism relied on these sentiments to be successful. 

And in terms of sexism -- capitalism is what cemented our division of labor between the sexes. Capitalism itself is built on the unpaid reproductive labor (the labor that keeps society going) that women provide, on top of in many cases working as wage workers. The more that capitalism can squeeze out of workers for free, the better. The more it can subjugate foreign workers or women workers, and pay them less, the better. So again, the neoliberal movement and right wing Christian movements were natural allies. There is no neoliberal movement that uplifts the rights of women, it wouldn't happen. 

Here I would like to make an important distinction. Capitalism itself, while relying on these ideas, also freed women and slaves to an extent. And a progressive capitalism also allows for social movements to develop that stand up for the rights of these exploited minorities. However, we are talking about the right-wing of capitalism. Specifically the neoliberal movement characterized by unfettered free markets.

Democracy is similarly a hindrance. You do not want people banding together and demanding the government pass worker safety regulations, or recognize unions, or pass consumer or environmental protections. This is where the idea, again going back to Revolutionary times, of the majority as a tyrannical force comes in. James Madison explicitly talked about how our government needed to protect the wealth of the few from the masses. John C Calhoun, a southern senator, went even further. He hated how the constitution gave people any democratic rights. The masses were tyrannical. Democracy itself was tyrannical. And we see the modern right-wing movement harken back to this. We see this in particular in the right-wing's opposition to unions. The unions are painted as the bullies. They push around the Democrats and force them to do their bidding. It's not the big banks and corporations that have outsized political influence, it is the unions and the grassroots political orgs.

For a bunch of Southern states to become Right to Work states, there had to be this belief against unions, against democracy. And it all ties together with the aforementioned racism and sexism. Today you have conservatives like Matt Walsh saying women shouldn't vote. Or there should be some sort of IQ test to vote. 

Their agenda is deeply tied to the cultural right wing. Neoliberalism not only comes from that but also relies on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744888900.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for posting a detailed reply. I was reflecting that much of your analysis is Marxian and then I saw your username. Was I right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747082683.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, this comment is mostly plagiarizing different history books I've read.   
In addtion to Democracy in Chains, I would recommend reading Caliban and the Witch by Silvia Federici. The Counterrevolution of 1776 by Gerald Horne. A Brief History of Neoliberalism by David Harvey. A Peoples History of the United States by Howard Zinn.  The Shock Doctrine by Naomi Klein. Democracy May Not Exist...by Astra Taylor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745082969.0" user="Political_What_Do" delta="False">
    <text>Counterpoint, Trump himself has no actual goals. He's just saying whatever he thinks it benefits him to say in any given moment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746947875.0" user="marxianthings" delta="False">
    <text>It's clear what side his rhetoric appeals to, though. I agree his goal (like many politicians) is to simply succeed in his own personal ambition. However he does have an ideological lean to his actions, his policies, the people he surrounds himself with.

Maybe you could say it's not that the Republicans' and Trump's goals align, but Trump is a useful vessel for their goals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759833820.0" user="XNoob_SmokeX" delta="False">
    <text>The only thing i share with Trump are his enemies. The rich and elite.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
