<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743037669.0" user="FlyHog421" delta="False">
    <text>The Republicans tried nominating the religious, competent, honest, polite, nice guy in 2012. His name was Mitt Romney. But he was portrayed by his opponents and the media as a racist, sexist, tax cheating authoritarian monster.

Trump may actually be a racist, sexist, tax cheating authoritarian monster but there’s only so many times you can cry wolf before people just stop listening. 

I mean if the Republicans nominated this hypothetical stand-up, family values, religious nice guy, would you consider voting for him? Or would you just call him a racist theocrat? At some point you stop wasting time trying to court people that aren’t going to vote for you anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743385779.0" user="Doodenelfuego" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;At some point you stop wasting time trying to court people that aren’t going to vote for you anyway

Mitt Romney tried that with the 47% comment. It didn't work out for him. Hillary Clinton tried it with her "basket of deplorables" comment. It didn't work out for her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743754844.0" user="Km15u" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;But he was portrayed by his opponents and the media as a racist, sexist, tax cheating authoritarian monster.  


He was all those things. He is less racist than most republicans but he still is a racist or at the very least used racism to try to get elected. Not sure if this journal is available for free but this is a great article on the topic by the APA 

https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2014-29457-005 

But ultimately that wasn't why Romney lost. He primarily lost because his industry where he made his money is also responsible for hollowing out the middle class and destroying middle america. Companies like Bain capital took over firms and then hollowed them out and scrapped them for parts. Its one of the main reasons why manufacturing has decreased significantly in the US since Reagan. Thousands of people lost their jobs because of companies like Bain and the Obama admin cut some really strong ads about it. Romney lost because he was a weak candidate not because he was "too nice and polite"

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;I mean if the Republicans nominated this hypothetical stand-up, family values, religious nice guy, would you consider voting for him?

No because none of those things are important to me in fact they make me want to vote for that person less. But that doesn't make me a hypocrite because I never claimed to care about any of those things. Republicans do claim to care about all those things, thats what makes them hypocrites when they elect someone who is the antithesis of all those things. They impeached a president because he got a blowjob. Clinton at least didn't embezzle funds to pay off pornstars.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
