<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743090888.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>Have you read UCAL professor Agre's paper "[What is Conservatism and What Is Wrong with it?"](https://pages.gseis.ucla.edu/faculty/agre/conservatism.html)

In it the professor summarizes with: 

"Q: What is conservatism? 

A: Conservatism is the domination of society by an aristocracy.

Q: What is wrong with conservatism? 

A: Conservatism is incompatible with democracy, prosperity, and civilization in general. It is a destructive system of inequality and prejudice that is founded on deception and has no place in the modern world."

He adds: 

"Nowadays, though, most of the people who call themselves "conservatives" have little notion of what conservatism even is. They have been deceived by one of the great public relations campaigns of human history. Only by analyzing this deception will it become possible to revive democracy in the United States."

Professor Agre paints a clear picture that the goal of conservatism  -- going back thousands of years -- is to protect the aristocracy. 

"The tactics of conservatism vary widely by place and time. But the most central feature of conservatism is deference: a psychologically internalized attitude on the part of the common people that the aristocracy are better people than they are. Modern-day liberals often theorize that conservatives use "social issues" as a way to mask economic objectives, but this is almost backward: the true goal of conservatism is to establish an aristocracy, which is a social and psychological condition of inequality. Economic inequality and regressive taxation, while certainly welcomed by the aristocracy, are best understood as a means to their actual goal, which is simply to be aristocrats."

"Although one of the goals of every aristocracy is to make its preferred social order seem permanent and timeless, **in reality conservatism must be reinvented in every generation.** This is true for many reasons, including internal conflicts among the aristocrats; institutional shifts due to climate, markets, or warfare; and ideological gains and losses in the perpetual struggle against democracy. In some societies the aristocracy is rigid, closed, and stratified, while in others it is more of an aspiration among various fluid and factionalized groups. The situation in the United States right now is toward the latter end of the spectrum. A main goal in life of all aristocrats, however, is to pass on their positions of privilege to their children, and many of the aspiring aristocrats of the United States are appointing their children to positions in government and in the archipelago of think tanks that promote conservative theories."

OP, as you noted. Conservatism is about in-groups and out-groups. It's the only thing they believe in. 

Thus, Conservatism's goal has not changed -- it's still about supporting the aristocracy. 

However, the look of conservatism always changes every generation. 

So what we are seeing with MAGA conservatism is simply the aristocrats pivoting their base.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743572406.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>So, the broad-based support must be because people are just deluded?

And thanks for that reference -- I will read it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744946675.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So, the broad-based support must be because people are just deluded?

Yes. 

&gt;And thanks for that reference -- I will read it.

It is a jaw dropping read. 

The professor who wrote it vanished without a trace. 

The Police put up notices for him. Eventually he walked into a Police station, verified his identity, said he was just fine and didn't want to be found. Then he disappeared again. It was all over the news in LA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745362269.0" user="omgFWTbear" delta="False">
    <text>According to Google he was also a tech professor and had some rather sour predictions about the future of tech. What a wild dive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745582508.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>What's your opinion on climate change? Why do so many people deny its existence? 

The American populace has been subjected to the largest misinformation campaign in history to gaslight them into doubting climate change. Oil companies knew about it in the 70s and have spent the past forty years and billions of dollars to discredit, attack, and suppress it. Media campaigns work.

In the same vein, the GOP media apparatus was constructed after Nixon to make sure that no Republican president ever suffered consequences again. Sinclair group, owned by Murdoch, parent-company of Fox, is the most obvious manifestation of that, and that's what they do day in and day out- reputation launder and misinform.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745991143.0" user="sisk91" delta="False">
    <text>Not op but your second paragraph nails it. The Oil companies created one of the best propoganda campaigns I can think of and it was so successful that people actively deny what they see and not only ignore what the experts say but will gladly discredit them.

One other point as to how it worked so easily, it worked on two fronts:

1. The politicians. Give them enough money and they'll adapt whatever you want to their platform. With climate change, it resulted in politicians pushing anti-green (for lack of a better word) policies. Vilifying your opponents for pushing green polciies. And finally telling people who are lower middle class or in poverty that that green policies are going to destroy America, your way of life and steal your money (that strategy also works on middle class and up but if you can get the south and people are aren't well-off to be for you then you'll have an easier time winning elections)

2. The regular people. I covered it in my first point but to expand, if you can convince people who aren't doing well financially that education is bad (yes education, because if the populace aren't smart enough to do proper research as well as thinking the highly educated are going after them such as the geniuses at NASA then they won't be able to verify if climate change is real as well as see through the common tactics used by anti-green politicans), that green policies are designed to take all their money with high taxes to fund programs to combat climate change, and that these programs will take jobs away (such as coal mining jobs), then you will have a populace that will continue to vote for crooked politicians and indirectly enrich oil CEO's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756755816.0" user="justjoshdoingstuff" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, YOU might believe people deny it for one reason, and I (someone who denies it) may do so for a different reason. 

I know you have no reason to trust me, but if you’re up for a challenge, post why YOU believe I deny man made climate change. 

Also, I do not deny “the climate changes.” It has for billions of years. I think that is another problem in this discussion… But let’s start with what I asked. 

You have no reason to trust me, but if you go back and look through all of my posts, you will see a) that I am more truthful with my beliefs than I probably should be and b) that I don’t edit my answers later. I will give you my truthful explanation of denial. I will honestly tell you whether you got it right or not. We can even get a neutral third party to play along if you think I’ll change my answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761608555.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>how the fuck would I know why you have convinced yourself to ignore the evidence of your own eyes? 

Like I'm happy to discuss this with you but I'm not playing "guess what number I'm thinking of"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762286166.0" user="justjoshdoingstuff" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that you’re dismissing my rejection of “climate change” with “oil companies and their propaganda!!” You’ve already made up your mind that my rejection is unfounded. At least, that’s what is coming across. 

You also seem to be lumping my rejection in as misinformed by Fox. 

My rejection is based on a lot of information, including that science is ever evolving, and will always cherry pick information to suit their belief, when in reality their belief is supposed to be informed by their information. 

We can discuss the “coming ice age!!!” of the 1970s. We can discuss information campaigns targeted at western societies like “cow farts” vs the miles of burning car tires in Iran (or Mexico). We can discuss how the west is light years ahead of most nations in relation to literally any pollution regs, but are somehow attacked. 

We can discuss that we are actually warming from an ice age, if you don’t cherry pick data… And how we are still several degrees cooler than the average temp during mammalian existence on earth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43765290309.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;  
My point was that you’re dismissing my rejection of “climate change” with “oil companies and their propaganda!!” You’ve already made up your mind that my rejection is unfounded. At least, that’s what is coming across.  
  
You also seem to be lumping my rejection in as misinformed by Fox.

I am and I have. I mean, I'm open to new data, and I'm sure there will be some. I just gravely doubt your ability to provide something I haven't heard. 

&amp;#x200B;

If you go and look at the breadth of scientific literature on the topic of climate change, the vast, *vast* majority of it conclusively agrees there is climate change and it is anthropogenic. Like, &gt; 10,000:1 if you want to try and scrape up peer-reviewed papers indicative of climate change vs not indicative. While there's *lots of disagreement*, it's usually over minutiae; the fine details. How fucked are we. What's the largest mechanism. How soon are we fucked. Was that extinction due to climate change or just pollution. 

&amp;#x200B;

You, in fact, seem to be the one cherrypicking here. :( It *is* constantly evolving, and all it's showing us is a higher and higher resolution image of a furnace that seems to be getting closer. 

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;We can discuss the “coming ice age!!!” of the 1970s. We can discuss information campaigns targeted at western societies like “cow farts” vs the miles of burning car tires in Iran (or Mexico). We can discuss how the west is light years ahead of most nations in relation to literally any pollution regs, but are somehow attacked.

This is conflating a lot of stuff, some of which are good points- not against climate change, admittedly- but it would just take like three pages to address even in brief. I'm going to say the west consumes a disproportionate amount of resources per capita, and generates a disproportionate amount of waste per capita, that complaining that Greta Thurnburg is trying to call our leadership to account over this instead of China's is the height of disingenuous argument. 

*"Wow you're asking the nation that claims it can conceivably be moved by popular support for a movement and also claims it is accountable to its voters?  And not the nation that you speak zero languages of and will kill you for trying to interfere in politics? I guess you're just a poser, smh."*

&amp;#x200B;

But maybe that was too much reading between the lines on my part, apologies if that's the case, I've just had this conversation too many times before so I'm trying to skip past some of it. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;*We can discuss that we are actually warming from an ice age, if you don’t cherry pick data… And how we are still several degrees cooler than the average temp during mammalian existence on earth.*

[Mammals have been around for about 240 million years.](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/77/Geologic_Clock_with_events_and_periods.svg) Humans have been around for *about* 2 million years. You understand, I'm sure, that 'average temperature during mammalian existence on earth' would be weighted 120:1 *away* from human interests? Why the hell would the average temperature during the late Cretaceous period matter to human existence on earth now? I'm not a tyrannosaurus, but note: even a tyrannosaurus rex is closer to literally the present day than the start of the period you're citing. 

That's really so *totally irrelevant* as to be an antifact; a disingenuous framing. Technically true information that's being used to *prevent*, rather than *enable* an accurate picture; Useless factoids being used to muddy the waters and *hobble* identification and solution to issues.  

Imagine if you went to your landlord complaining that it was literally 0\*F and the heating in your apartment was broken and he really needed to get that fixed and he went "whoa whoa whoa, it's *way above* the universal average of 2.7 kelvin, and you want it to be *hotter still?*". It's that level of dishonest.

&amp;#x200B;

[Here's that ice age of yours, at the top.](https://xkcd.com/1732/) Why don't you scroll down, maybe count the inflection points, and see if you can find something people might be concerned by?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43769255569.0" user="WallSome8837" delta="False">
    <text>While there may be climate change for various reasons, the "solutions" from the left are primarily money grabs and political power grabs that useful idiots champion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770161486.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>What various reasons do you think there may be?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770815855.0" user="WallSome8837" delta="False">
    <text>That climate changes over time to start. 

But honestly I don't care enough to argue this. Even if it is man made we can't willingly gimp ourselves when our competition doesn't so it doesn't even matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43772468716.0" user="info-junkie" delta="False">
    <text>I guess you never heard of the game theory and the prisoner's dilemn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43772534521.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>Ah yes. 

Well we can't not launch nukes, what if our competition launches nukes and we don't? The only solution is to launch nukes *now*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858925999.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why do so many people deny its existence?

Because while they're not as highly educated, they're not stupid. And they can smell bullshit when you try to feed it to them. NASA has been lying about this repeatedly, and they refuse to come clean, and so there is a lot of evidence of Tomfoolery going around. Not to mention when you look at the actual direct from the UN IPCC reports, they're talking about very minor and manageable effects, not the end of the world that AOC and other dumb twunts constantly screech about. A 6% reduction in global GDP 80 years from now is sufficient to starve billions of people to death and give the global governance unheard of authoritarian powers? No. Absolutely not. A very mild and absolutely within historically normal ranges of warming from a particularly cold point is not anything to lose your mind over. It's something to be mildly concerned about and keep your eye on. That's why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43860449075.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;NASA has been lying about this repeatedly, and they refuse to come clean, and so there is a lot of evidence of Tomfoolery going around.

So I'm sure you have plenty of it you can cite for that. 

Why has this summer been the hottest on record with summer temperatures recorded in the southern hemisphere?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866000155.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>You are aware that winter temperatures are what is driving the entirety of the global temperature rise over the past 150 years, right? I bet you're not, but that is a fact. There is no such thing as global temperature. In the northern hemisphere it's summer and in the southern hemisphere it's winter, or vice versa. To say that the world's temperature is 60° is fucking nonsense. Very few places in the world are 60° at any time of the year. So they take the northern temperature and they take the southern temperature and they average them together. If you raise the lowest temperatures and don't move the highest temperatures the average still goes up. This is not hard to comprehend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43868637703.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>Hypothetically, let's pretend everything you said is entirely, 100%, unqualifiedly true. 

Does that not still constitute global warming?

And because I'm sure you don't see how this would matter, let me explain it a little.

Okay, imagine a circle made out of months of the year. At the top you have the july-august, and the related kind of temperatures. Around here that's 110-115, maybe 120 if we're unlucky.

At the bottom you have the mid-winter months and temperatures. Around here that's when it gets cold, rains, *soooometimes* it even snows. 

In between, you have the changing of the seasons. 

Maybe it snows, I don't know, twenty days a year normally. Refill the icepack on the mountains, give us good skiing, refill the alpine reservoirs for the summer. 

&amp;#x200B;

Now raise the temperature in the winter by a couple degrees. 

Now instead of 20 days of snowfall you're getting 18. And rain is warmer than snow. When it rains on those 2 days it used to snow, that rain is *melting* snowpack. 

Mountains that are year-round in snow- because they were getting emptied and refilled at similar rates- are now getting *drier* year over year.  It's a simple equation; equilibrium is when input=output. Even if summer temperatures don't change a smidge- (and that's pretty silly to think, after the hottest summer on record) -with only winter temperatures changing you're knocking that equation out of balance. Input &lt; output means snowcover is decreasing year over year. Snowpack begins to diminish. Rivers stop running because there's no more snow to melt in late July. Reservoirs drain. 

&amp;#x200B;

Even assuming every word out of your mouth was god's honest truth, it's still a problem and saying you're a "climate skeptic" or whatever is like being "gravity skeptic" or a "round earth skeptic".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43873456956.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Okay, imagine a circle made out of months of the year. At the top you have the july-august, and the related kind of temperatures. Around here that's 110-115, maybe 120 if we're unlucky.

Off the bat, you're not doing well. Globally the hottest month if the year is January. If you don't know basic facts, I'm not sure I want to listen to your explanations. 

&gt;Now raise the temperature in the winter by a couple degrees.

Lol, no. You don't live in the areas driving the change. At no point in the year do they reach 110 degrees. You're freaking out over things that aren't going to happen. 

&gt;Mountains that are year-round in snow- because they were getting emptied and refilled at similar rates- are now getting drier year over year.

No. Warmer air holds more moisture than colder air. It can actually get too cold to snow, another fact I imagine you did not know. There will be some areas right on the cusp that will get less snow but they will also get more rain. Even the IPCC agrees that rainfall will be heavier and more frequent. There's some concern about WHERE it will fall, but a warmer world is a wetter world, not a drier one. 

&gt;Rivers stop running because there's no more snow to melt in late July. Reservoirs drain

And the small handful of places where this happens can easily adjust with technology and infrastructure. A far cry from "ZOMG THE WORLD IS ENDING". 

&gt;Does that not still constitute global warming?

Yes, the world has gotten slightly warmer since 1850. The only problem is that we're still well within historical norms. There have been THREE periods that were warmer than currently in the last 12000 years (aka since the start of recorded human history) and none of those were the fault of humans. It's almost certain that we are having an impact this time, but it is not apparent that it's harmful let alone catastrophic. You want the end of civilization? Try another ice age. We're overdue for one too. 

&gt;it's still a problem and saying you're a "climate skeptic" 

Lol. I'm more of a "black box computer model that tells you to give me more money" skeptic. The climate is changing, like it always has. There's no evidence that we need to be panicking at this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43873837767.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>Seems like a bunch of not very coherent stuff that doesn't really respond to anything.  I know you're arguing that warm air holds more moisture than cold air but you're not so stupid as to actually believe that addresses what I was talking about. Look at the Sahara. Warmest air around, surprisingly little snow. Rain does not create snowpack. Neither does heat. Glaciers are in full retreat, arctic ice is melting, and sea levels are looking to rise *this year*\- maybe we can put a pin in this and come back in a year to see if "sea level rise" has caused a bunch of problems a year from now. 

&amp;#x200B;

Even if it's changing totally independent from us, even if it's changed before, shouldn't we be concerned if those changes are going to make life worse? Or do you get  a check-engine  light on your dashboard and go "Well, lights have come on before, there's less lights now than there have been at times before, it's fine." 

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;

But hey, maybe you're a visual learner. [Why don't you try to find me those three periods with warmer temperatures?](https://xkcd.com/1732/) Scroll all the way to the bottom, see if you can find an inflection point or two that seems like a reason to be concerned. 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Lol. I'm more of a "black box computer model that tells you to give me more money" skeptic. The climate is changing, like it always has. There's no evidence that we need to be panicking at this point.

I have to admire the "I choose not to understand it, therefore it's not concerning." tactic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43874670342.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Look at the Sahara. Warmest air around, surprisingly little snow.

I can't decide if you're being facetious or if you actually think this is a good argument. 

&gt;I have to admire the "I choose not to understand it, therefore it's not concerning." tactic.

Not only do I demonstrafully understand more than you on this topic, so do a lot of other people who you would agree also know more than you. How about President Obama's deputy secretary of energy? He wrote a book on climate change. I suggest you go read it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43874697790.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Scroll all the way to the bottom, see if you can find an inflection point or two that seems like a reason to be concerned.

Just because someone drew a picture of something on the internet doesn't mean that it's representing reality. They did not include the medieval warm period, which is proven to be a global phenomenon at this point. But if you really want to prove to yourself that that chart is absolute bullshit, where is the younger dryas cooling? A mild dip of half a degree? Total horseshit. There's no possible way that he could have misrepresented the data that way accidentally. That is an intentional lie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43875434124.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>It's literally right there on the chart fam. Try finding 11000 BCE and reading real slowly.

&amp;#x200B;

But hey, I guess that's another point for my "choosing not to understand" summary isn't it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43876711142.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Here's what it [actually looked liked].(https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/63/Evolution_of_temperature_in_the_Post-Glacial_period_according_to_Greenland_ice_cores_%28Younger_Dryas%29.jpg/1280px-Evolution_of_temperature_in_the_Post-Glacial_period_according_to_Greenland_ice_cores_%28Younger_Dryas%29.jpg) 

You were lied to and you believed it. You never thought to question that someone on your team might not be honest. And that's why you are where you are. Keep insulting other people who know more than you, kid. That will take you far in life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43886504910.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>You know that says "Just Greenland" on the side there? Do you think that might be relevant vis-a-vis global temperature trends? Particularly when you were arguing that "global warming is only happening in the southern hemisphere so it doesn't matter" earlier?

&amp;#x200B;

It doesn't really matter though; we're not arguing on anything important. Like it's downstream of the actual ridiculous shit you believe.

&amp;#x200B;

The sequence of events is 

1. papers in 1800s hypothesize about anthropogenic coal-usage-based climate change in the future
2. oil companies find out about climate change in the 70s
3. oil companies pour billions of dollars over the next fifty years into disputing and discrediting it every step
4. the overwhelming scientific consensus (since maybe the 80s at worst?) has been "wow this is happening and it looks like it's gonna be a shitkicker"
   1. there's disagreement on the specifics (what the primary mechanism is, how much) and the timeline (how fast it's going to get awful) and impacts (just how hard is it going to suck) which is often inflated into "scientists don't agree" or "there isn't a consensus". See step #3.
   2. There is no real disagreement on the broad strokes. Anthropogenic. Driven by fossil fuels. It's going to get real bad.

And you said you didn't disagree on 2, you said you didn't disagree on the fact that climate *is changing*, but for some reason you don't think keeping the climate *basically in line* with what our society is built around the climate being is good. 

It doesn't even matter if it's anthropogenic or not; the issue is that we're in a house, and people are going "hey do you hear that? Do you smell smoke? Is it me or is it getting kind of warm in here? Did someone leave the oven on?" and you're going 

"Well it's been hot before. It gets hot in the summer. When I turn on the stove in the kitchen it gets hotter than this. I don't see why we should be worried about that smoke or the fact that the firealarms are going of. After all sometimes they go off when there's no fire- remember when they were tested?" 

&amp;#x200B;

You're doing this by, essentially, feeding on the scraps of step #3. They were just as happy to create people who deny that climate can change, as to create people who think climate change is natural and the fears are overblow, as they are to create people who think the climate is changing and that's good actually. It doesn't really matter to them. But the evidence you can point to is still a misinterpretation of a subset of the *vast minority*\- we're talking ten thousand to one- of the prevailing scientific opinion. Go find some papers concluding that climate change is "natural" and current trends are unremarkable. You might find one, but you can find *one* paper that suggests vaccines cause autism too. Which- wouldn't you know- is brought up and pushed by people with financial and political agendas totally unrelated to the science. 

&amp;#x200B;

And then, of course, this grand conspiracy- you know, 95%+ of all climate scientists in the world- are all on board with "yeah you have to give us- no, actually, unrelated companies and industries money to maybe prevent the house from burning down, or from burning down as quickly". Scientists, a famously easily cowed, docile, and willing to toe the conspiracy line demographic. 

&amp;#x200B;

The set of prerequisites for your viewpoint are so absurd that no amount of data can talk you out of it, but that's what happens when data doesn't talk you into it.

&amp;#x200B;

99% of the species that have lived on this planet are now extinct. [How many of them do you think died to climate-change?](https://www.yahoo.com/news/billions-crabs-went-missing-around-180012346.html) If you skim through extinct civilizations, a surprising number of them boil down to "local climate changed and they had no way of coping, they ceased to exist". 

&amp;#x200B;

Supposing, just for a moment, people successfully spend a trillion dollars on preventing climate change. We migrate to sustainable, non-oil based power. There's a little less coal exhaust in the air, there's a little less gasoline exhaust in your lungs, and the rising temperatures you've agreed exist- anthropogenic or not! - are limited to just a degree or two. We're no longer dependent on shitty autocratic dictators who wield outsized influence and are insanely wealthy simply because they control a bunch of dinosaur juice.

  
Where's the harm? What else do you think that was going to be spent on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43896647690.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>I am aware that is just Greenland. However, It was a global phenomenon and there is no credible argument against that at this point. I'm not going to spend extra time looking on the internet when that photo is perfectly serviceable. And it also comes from a source that you are not likely to complain about.

&gt;The set of prerequisites for your viewpoint are so absurd that no amount of data can talk you out of it, but that's what happens when data doesn't talk you into it.

Yeah exactly the opposite. My viewpoint is based on the actual data, which you are ignorant of. You clearly have not read through the relevant literature on this topic. You are taking what mainstream media tells you at face value, and they are known liars.

&gt;If you skim through extinct civilizations, a surprising number of them boil down to "local climate changed and they had no way of coping, they ceased to exist".

Except I'm talking about extinction events where 99% of all species on earth went extinct at the same time. There have been five, possibly six, such events in the history of our planet, and none of them had anything to do with humans. That's my point. I don't understand how your point is even remotely relevant. I don't disagree with it.


Scientists, a famously easily cowed, docile, and willing to toe the conspiracy line demographic.

3 years ago, you might have had a point. But now we've seen behind the veil and we know that they are in fact cowards and that they are willing to lie in order to save their jobs. Thanks covid!

&gt;- you know, 95%+ of all climate scientists in the world- are all on board

I will reiterate that consensus is fucking irrelevant to whether or not something is true. Additionally, the supposed 97% agreement is about the statement " humans have influenced climate change" and nothing else. If you question those same people about the magnitude and the effects of that influence, there is no more consensus. Some of them are very hawkish, some of them are very dovish. Some of them view it as a positive, because they believe that without human influence we may have been headed back to an ice age. We are in fact overdue for one. So again, your ignorance of reality is not an actual argument against what I am saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43901069405.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I will reiterate that consensus is fucking irrelevant to whether or not something is true.

You're still going to need some justification for why you choose to believe one tiny minority of opinion instead of the majority. And the majority overwhelmingly believes it's primarily anthropogenic in nature, and happening. Sure, that doesn't make it true- but if you're going to say they're all wrong, you're going to need a tremendous amount of evidence.

Incidentally, you seem to be trying to sneakily water it down at every step. [It's 99% agreement, and that agreement is that it is primarily caused by humans.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_consensus_on_climate_change) Already, we have exciting and serious impacts of it, from the eight hottest summers in the past century being the past eight years (weird, how they group up like that) and two consecutive years of Alaskan crab fishing being canceled because climate change caused a billion crabs to go missing. 

&amp;#x200B;

Boy, sure hope they have lots of alternative employment up there.  Golly, I wonder how much money they're losing from the impacts of climate change on their economy. Gee, you think that maybe prevention could be cheaper than cure? 

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;

It's just so bizarrely petty and pointless. "I believe the climate is changing, I believe it's anthropogenic, I believe it's changing for the worse, but I don't think we should do anything about it and the people trying to do something about it must be a scam. It won't be a problem, actually." 

lol. lmao.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745585450.0" user="Psyduckisnotaduck" delta="False">
    <text>'Someday I could be one of them' is also a strong driving force. Which is usually but not always delusional. Sometimes people like that DO succeed. Not often, though. 

but it's not always delusion. Some people genuinely believe in hierarchy, subservience to power, etc. it's ironic how many of the Gadsden flag people become Please Tread On Me types when it comes to leaders they like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747455392.0" user="ShafordoDrForgone" delta="False">
    <text>Religion

People can't think for themselves. Their best reasoning amounts to Symbol X = Symbol Y. And often Symbol Y is "good" or "bad"

When you can't reason for yourself, you have to rely on the people in power to reason for you. Worked for thousands of years. Pre Christianity, Greece had indoor plumbing. During Christianity, people drank from the same river they disposed of plague victim bodies in. Post French Revolution, life expectancy doubled</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757161425.0" user="AdItchy4438" delta="False">
    <text>Dark Ages indeed! Do you think we are seeing the beginning of Dark Ages Part Deux?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757505180.0" user="ShafordoDrForgone" delta="False">
    <text>Ohio just disbanded their department of education...

Some people are trying as hard as they can</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762824217.0" user="Frnklfrwsr" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;broad-based support

This is a relative term. There are certain communities where this way of thinking has broad support. And there are other communities where it has almost none. 

Religious and rural communities often times have different types of people than non-religious and urban communities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745654779.0" user="CosmicLovepats" delta="False">
    <text>My first instinct to this thread was to respond that conservatism was basically a belief that the enlightenment was a mistake, but didn't know if I felt like exerting the effort to elaborate on that today. Thank you for this excellent source.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745660875.0" user="upstateduck" delta="False">
    <text>another good read is "Class" by Paul Fussel

He examines class in the US's supposedly classless society

The idea that has stuck with me is that because folks believe the US is classless [it isn't just doesn't have rigidly defined  class strata] they do a lot of stressful grasping in the hope that they can actually change their position in the strata.

"Conservative" power brokers use this to advance their aims [oligarchy]. Also on point is the Johnson quote "give him someone to look down on and he will empty his pockets for you" [referring to racism but  applicable here too</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754528007.0" user="creepyswaps" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;they do a lot of stressful grasping in the hope that they can actually change their position in the strata

I don't think most conservatives are trying to move up the "hierarchy".  They believe it is the natural order of the world (there's always a bigger fish), and they're content with that as long as there are classes lower than them, or people they think are below them aren't trying to cheat their way to the top.

[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=agzNANfNlTs](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=agzNANfNlTs) \- There's always a bigger fish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858941692.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>That would be a right wing ideology. Right wing and conservative are not synonyms. Despite how they are treated in mainstream media, what you have described is right wing and has very little to do with conservatism other than the overlap of people who hold both ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858881668.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>You know Johnson was a Democrat right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43860130397.0" user="upstateduck" delta="False">
    <text>you might read my post again? but ,yes, Johnson as a Progressive [though probably not personally]  is  a continuation of the discussion of "aristocracy" and it's need for the working classes to have someone to look down on so they accept that there is a group to look up on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745800153.0" user="Daniel_The_Thinker" delta="False">
    <text>What is the point of such a paper other than to show off how progressive you are to other progressives? No one past center left is going to read it and interpret it as anything other than left wing propaganda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745858584.0" user="liefred" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think it’s meant to convince people who are conservative to no longer be conservative, it’s meant to analyze conservatism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746463974.0" user="Dragolins" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What is the point of such a paper 

Oh, I don't know, perhaps to accurately analyze the question "what is conservatism and what is wrong with it?"

Seriously. Conservatism has always been about defense of (traditional) hierarchies, or whatever lets the powerful keep their unjust power. From the aristocrats of the French revolution, to the confederacy fighting to preserve slavery, to the modern day conservatives who white knight for billionaires and have open contempt for the homeless. It's always been about keeping humanity artificially stratified into arbitrarily defined classes of people where some are inherently better than others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749427506.0" user="nmj95123" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Seriously. Conservatism has always been about defense of (traditional) hierarchies, or whatever lets the powerful keep their unjust power

That isn't conservatism. That's government, period, which is why normal people have almost [no impact on policy](https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/perspectives-on-politics/article/testing-theories-of-american-politics-elites-interest-groups-and-average-citizens/62327F513959D0A304D4893B382B992B).

&gt; Multivariate analysis indicates that economic elites and organized groups representing business interests have substantial independent impacts on U.S. government policy, **while average citizens and mass-based interest groups have little or no independent influence**.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750277679.0" user="mikeewhat" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you say that conservatism is not about maintaining existing hierarchies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750849459.0" user="Dragolins" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That isn't conservatism. That's government, period, which is why normal people have almost no impact on policy.

Normal people do not have impact on policy because essentially every government that has ever existed has been structured in a way that is far too authoritarian in nature. It's quite obvious, really. 

The founders of the United States were pretty explicit in their desire to keep the power out of the hands of the average person. They literally only allowed white men who owned land to vote. 

The United States government, even today, is highly undemocratic. 

The government needs to be organized in a way that is more democratic and is designed to serve the interests of the people instead of the interests of the powerful. 

When the average person is highly intelligent and educated from a robust and well designed education system, and the government is structured in an efficient, adaptable, highly democratic manor that incorporates the [lessons that we've learned about how power should operate](https://brianpklaas.com/corruptible) and you'll see an unthinkable amount of societal problems dry up like a well in a drought. 

Conservative policies are about keeping the government serving the interests of the powerful, whether that be through deregulation, tax-cuts, anti-labor union legislation like "right to work" laws, constantly attacking and undermining public education, and doing everything in their power to keep unfettered capitalism as the dominant status quo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757224638.0" user="AdItchy4438" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. And seems to me that in the post WW2 era, especially from the late 50s to the late 70s, average Americans started to get more education and question authority and structures, and to use a 21st century word, get more woke. Just as fast was the backlash from the Monied Interests and Gatekeepers of Power. We had anti-war and pro-civil rights movements, but then we had Reagan and tax cuts for the wealthy and a young Donald Trump. We had harmonious and thoughtprovoking and disco dance music, but then we had records smashed and hard rock &amp; heavy metal take over. We got Medicare &amp; Medicaid and the EPA and the Clean Air act, but then we had deregulation of things like plane travel and communications and defunding of care for mentally ill folks who became homeless. We saw both parents having to work while minimum wages remained low, and blame placed on single income parents who needed keeping their kids out of poverty</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754670637.0" user="UCLYayy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That isn't conservatism. That's government, period, which is why normal people have almost no impact on policy

That is a symptom of a government failing to be representative and money influencing politics. Would you say Germany's people have no influence on policy? Because I would say they absolutely do. "American politics" is not "government".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746592600.0" user="xXCisWhiteSniperXx" delta="False">
    <text>In my experience as a lefty, most people don't actually understand that the promotion of a hierarchy and an ingroup and out-group is the actual goal of conservatism. I think recognizing this can make ones own political advocacy and arguments a lot more effective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747041984.0" user="Daniel_The_Thinker" delta="False">
    <text>Thats honestly too vague a description.

You could call communists conservatives, because they collectively ousted the Cossaks and the church and promoted a new, party based heirarchy, even if the end goal is the abolition of hierarchy. 

In fact a lot of conservatives view the left wing in the same light, "coastal elites" and such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747702577.0" user="Darsint" delta="False">
    <text>You’re actually closer than you think.

The “stated” end goal of those communists that gained power was the abolition of hierarchy.
And yet, they retained that power afterwards and never put any effort towards infrastructure that would reduce their power.

Likewise, “coastal elites”, by their very nature, are very interested in maintaining their superior position, just using other ways and methods. If a coastal elite is actually pushing for more egalitarian or fair situations, even if it hurts their position short term, they’re not really “elites” anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750283655.0" user="mikeewhat" delta="False">
    <text>What’s your point here? Which point are they close to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750406852.0" user="Darsint" delta="False">
    <text>Two things:

That the words people say aren't nearly as important as the actions they take.

That if your actions promote the elevation of a small group of people at the expense of everyone else, especially if they are already powerful or wealthy, then you are conservative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750436116.0" user="mikeewhat" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for elaborating</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754730163.0" user="UCLYayy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The “stated” end goal of those communists that gained power was the abolition of hierarchy. And yet, they retained that power afterwards and never put any effort towards infrastructure that would reduce their power.

Which would make them: Not communists at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756161934.0" user="Darsint" delta="False">
    <text>EXACTLY!! This is why we need to pay more attention to what they do than what they say. Pushing for actual egalitarian solutions, especially if they lose power by doing so, is the hallmark of a genuine communist. And quite a few other ideologies too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43769273038.0" user="WallSome8837" delta="False">
    <text>But then someone who doesn't believe it and sees an easy avenue to power will take it. Every single time. I sure as fuck would</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757247940.0" user="AdItchy4438" delta="False">
    <text>Which is an example of how the world has never had real pure Communism or socialism or libertarianism. Things don't work in vivo the way they do in a book or in a professor's call or in a political leader's speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858979924.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Boy those communists sure did hate hierarchy. So much that they made a new hierarchy with themselves at the top! That's how much they cared about the workers of the world, that they were willing to take that one on the chin for the team.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858975957.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>He's wrong. He's describing personality traits of people who support conservative positions and arguments. It comes from evolutionary psychology, and the fact that the two biggest risks to your clan or tribes survival were outsiders, who might try to murder you straight up or could have new and deadly diseases, and internal group dissension. People who are more focused on the first threat tend to be conservative. People who are focused on the second threat tend to be more progressive. The problem is that the brakes came off the progressive movement and they've all been insane since Marx.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748524586.0" user="Pale_Pineapple_365" delta="False">
    <text>Conservatives want to protect the existing hierarchy, which is mostly based on family background (and race). It’s a romantic notion that pretends the elite are benevolent.  But who wants to be at the mercy of the out-of-touch elites?  

Liberals have a hierarchy too, but it’s based on a so-called meritocracy.  Which sounds good on paper, but encourages unkindness towards those who are unlucky enough to be below average in skills, connections, and genetics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760701423.0" user="socraticquestions" delta="False">
    <text>Group identity politics pushed by the left do not have hierarchies, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747251660.0" user="FullPercentage" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t imagine a conservative seeing that analysis as anything more than a straw man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747331824.0" user="Daniel_The_Thinker" delta="False">
    <text>True, but I'm honestly more concerned about a moderate thinking "these leftists are crazy"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759749159.0" user="XNoob_SmokeX" delta="False">
    <text>Too late for that good buddy, that cat ran out the door when you guys decides to displace American citizens infavor of illegal migrants while also deceiminalized shoplifting.

You look like insane people to the average American.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759979795.0" user="Daniel_The_Thinker" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're too confident in thinking you represent the average american.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759992623.0" user="XNoob_SmokeX" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confident in data

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4qoD6El8k2c</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761147154.0" user="Daniel_The_Thinker" delta="False">
    <text>A 4% difference among blue collars?

Not really a slam dunk</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858960687.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>They are crazy. They've been crazy for 150 years. They were inspired by a misanthropic crazy man who made up a bunch of bullshit and pretended it was economics and then pivoted to one of the most insane, anti-human screeds about politics ever. It's an incredibly insidious ideology, and it will be very difficult to defeat, but if we do not defeat it, it will be the end of mankind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749648148.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>But it's a positive portrayal. Hierarchy is order, lack of hierarchy can be seen as anarchy, chaos, things that conservatives truly fear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754743352.0" user="UCLYayy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Hierarchy is order

What? Are you suggesting egalitarian societies don't have order?

&gt;lack of hierarchy can be seen as anarchy, chaos, things that conservatives truly fear.

"can be seen as" is doing a lot of heavy lifting in that sentence. Lots of things can be seen lots of ways, that doesn't mean that reflects reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762799975.0" user="AloysiusC" delta="False">
    <text>People organize into hierarchies anyway no matter how "egalitarian" you think you've made them. The question is only by what metric.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747819435.0" user="Otherwise-Sky1292" delta="False">
    <text>You should read it, it's enormously compelling. Conservatives will dismiss it but it thoroughly explains what conservatism actually is and why it's such a toxic, potent force</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858983566.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Conservatives will dismiss it because it's horseshit, and only a leftard could believe it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43861428911.0" user="Otherwise-Sky1292" delta="False">
    <text>Did you read it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748402809.0" user="inscrutablemike" delta="False">
    <text>That's because that is all it is. The basic premises are left-wing premises, and the left-wing conclusions are baked into the left-wing assumptions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748561637.0" user="TraitorMacbeth" delta="False">
    <text>What if.... there were more ideologies than that? More than.... a single left to right scale? It's the easiest way to categorize, sure, but people could be 'anti left wing' and not be conservative too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748751993.0" user="Daniel_The_Thinker" delta="False">
    <text>There are of course,  but most beliefs are surprisingly comorbid

Like I'm sure there are eco vegans who are also pro military/foreign intervention but they're rare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746762802.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>The actual nobility and old ruling families tend to support center-left parties and policies though, especially in the US recently. I agree with your characterization but it's misleading to latch that to the American two-party system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747705695.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about parties. It's about conservative ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748382896.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>Just because a movement claims the mantle of conservatism doesn't mean it's a conservative movement. I don't believe MAGAs fit the definition. They neither hold power nor have any aristocratic aims, it's simply the angst of a dispossessed group that is rapidly losing the ability to influence the national current. They're not particularly revolutionary or radical either for that matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749633240.0" user="hedonihilistic" delta="False">
    <text>You don't seem to have much reading comprehension or critical thinking skills. Nowhere does anyone say that the conservative masses aspire to be aristocrats. Instead, it is clearly being argued that the conservative masses are defined by deference and a blind belief in the aristocratic authority of some ruling class. That perfectly describes Trump's cult. None of these people are dispossessed of anything. They don't have any values except for imagined grievances regarding guns and immigration.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751939271.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;conservative masses are defined by deference and a blind belief in the aristocratic authority of some ruling class. That perfectly describes Trump's cult.

It actually doesn't, most of them believe more in what they believe to be "autonomy" and what they perceive as the "freedom" from forced propaganda. It's not Trump's side that wants to preserve an entrenched elite that has all the legitimacy and recognition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754335411.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's not Trump's side that wants to preserve an entrenched elite that has all the legitimacy and recognition.

It is exactly Trump's side. It's Elon's side. It's Putin's side. It's the side of the wealthy elite. 

Trump was born into extreme wealth. Y'all seem to forget that. 

MAGA Poors literally defended Trump's tax cuts which transferred trillions of dollars from the middle to the wealthy elite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754362538.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>Trump and Elon are lower tier billionaires with little real power compared to older more politically entrenched families, some would call them "old money". Now Trump's tax cuts do serve the elites regardless but that's less reflective of the ideology involved than his staffers being packed with pro-System elites from the inside. Many of whom switched allegiances pretty rapidly after serving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754528277.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Elon are lower tier billionaires 

Elon is the richest man in the world. What's he got, 200 Billion?

Elon controls Twitter. Elon has the ability to disable Ukraine's war effort.

Trump is connected to tyrants all over the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755085351.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>Trump can't even connect to a half decent lawyer. He's isolated. Elon has power over the Ukrainian war effort because of a unique infrastructure project he presided over with a lot of state help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770271969.0" user="BrothaMan831" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like msnbc propaganda to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770316651.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754653650.0" user="Syzygy_Stardust" delta="False">
    <text>You are currently not worth taking seriously if you think *literal billionaires* are not the wealthy elite. You've bent your brain too far, people can't see the shape anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755073718.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>Power isn't just about how much your real estate or stock portfolio is appraised at (neither Trump nor Elon are particularly liquid). It's about networks, influence, lineage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858872211.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;MAGA Poors literally defended Trump's tax cuts which transferred trillions of dollars from the middle class to the wealthy elite.

There were no transfers from the middle class to the wealthy in those tax cuts. You think you're entitled to that money that already belongs to the wealthy. But you're not. So you're mad that you're not getting something you thought was yours but never was. That's not a transfer. That's allowing people to keep more of the shit that is theirs. But you're so baked into a progressive mindset that you can't, even for a second, step outside of it and consider the world from a different view. Letting people keep more of the shit that's already there's is what we want. The fact that rich people get to keep more money because they're more rich than everyone else is an unimportant side effect. To you it's a big deal, because that means less money for your stupid nanny state projects, but we don't like those, and we're happy to see that money stay in the hands of the people who earned it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43859908658.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;There were no transfers from the middle class to the wealthy in those tax cuts. 

Clearly you have no idea what you are talking about. 

You can't even wrap your head around how a wealth transfer works. Not at all surprising, BeefcakeWellington. LOL.

&gt;You think you're entitled to that money that already belongs to the wealthy. But you're not. 

Again, you simply don't understand. 

The issue is not what I or anyone is entitled too. 

The issue is making the middle class pay for unfunded tax cuts!!! 

What always happens is this: The GOP swears the tax cuts will be good for the economy. The reality is the tax cuts raise the deficit so that future generations will have to pay it off by  A) paying more in taxes and B) getting less services from the government (less social security for example).

It's like going out to eat at a fancy restaurant and the rich asshole at your table orders $20,000 bottles of wine which he himself drinks. Then he gets up chips in only $80 for his share and leaves, sticking everyone else with the tab. Now the other people have to pay $1,500 each for the soup &amp; salad and water they had. That's how the transfer works. 

&gt;So you're mad that you're not getting something you thought was yours but never was. 

Nope. 

&gt;That's not a transfer. 

You should google unfunded tax cuts and "trickle down theory" which was originally called "horse and sparrow" because the wealthy elite tricked people into thinking feeding the horse (the rich) benefits everyone else because the bird gets to eat the seeds out of the horse's shit. 

Bragging about having the middle class eat the rich's shit is why they changed the name to "trickle down". 

&gt;That's allowing people to keep more of the shit that is theirs. 

At the expense of everyone else. Because the government doesn't collect enough tax revenue to pay its bills so it goes deeper into debt and then Uncle Sam is forced to raise the middle class tax rate and cut social services people rely on like Social Security. 

Trump's 2017 tax cuts were permeant for corporations but they had baked in middle class tax increases -- to higher than they were before the cuts -- starting in 2027 IIRC.

&gt;But you're so baked into a progressive mindset that you can't, even for a second, step outside of it and consider the world from a different view.

Dude, you don't even understand how the transfer works. 

I had to explain it to you using a fucking restaurant as an example. And I imagine I'll have to dumb it down yet again.

&gt; Letting people keep more of the shit that's already there's is what we want. 

The government can't just not pay its bills. Uncle Sam has financial obligations it must meet and if there is not enough tax revenue Uncle Sam will take out more loans which the middle class will have to pay back at a future date.

&gt;The fact that rich people get to keep more money because they're more rich than everyone else is an unimportant side effect. 

Taxes were a lot higher in the 1950s, wasn't that supposed to be when America was great?

CEOs didn't make nearly as much as they did back then either. 

&gt;To you it's a big deal, because that means less money for your stupid nanny state projects, but we don't like those, and we're happy to see that money stay in the hands of the people who earned it.

You're happy to be on the hook for a billionaire's debt?

Sounds about right.

I say make the rich pay their fair share. 

I bet you refuse to believe the rich own politicians who enact favorable tax laws for the wealthy elite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866031085.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;unfunded tax cuts

This is your problem right here. There is no such thing as an unfunded tax cut. Allowing people to keep more of their own property cannot be defined as unfunded. What you have are unfunded spending priorities. And when your tax revenue goes down, you should do the responsible thing and spend less. And while Republicans certainly are not great on this, they're not the utter garbage that the Democrat party has been. The Democrats like to pretend that they're the only ones balancing the budget when the only reason the budget was out of balance in the first place is because of their entitlement programs and social spending. 

&gt;I say make the rich pay their fair share.

And what is that? What is the fair share of the rich? And how are you defining fair such that a flat tax on all dollars earned isn't the fairest solution? Again, you say this is a transfer because it's actually you that doesn't understand transfers. When you steal my shit and give it to other people and then I managed to convince the government to not do that anymore, that is not a transfer from you to me. That is a lessening of the ongoing transfer of me to you. There's still a wealth from me to you, it's just not as big as it used to be. And you have a problem with that because you feel like you're entitled to my shit, and I disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866219864.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;This is your problem right here. There is no such thing as an unfunded tax cut.

The GOP said the tax cuts would be so good for the economy that actual tax revenue wouldn't fall because the money the wealthy elite saved would be dumped right back into the economy. It was a lie. 

&gt; Allowing people to keep more of their own property cannot be defined as unfunded. 

The Government is on the hook for spending X-amount of money every year. They know the amount. You can't avoid spending money on INTEREST owed every year.  The Bills MUST get paid. And it wouldn't be a problem if there is enough tax revenue.

What the GOP repeatedly does is lie and say it won't be an issue. Then it becomes a huge issue -- there is not enough tax revenue to pay the bills -- and so Congress is forced to raise the debt level. 

HAPPENS ALL THE TIME WITH GOP PRESIDENTS. That's how a normal person can tells Cons are full of shit.

&gt;What you have are unfunded spending priorities. 

The spending WAS funded. Everything was OK. 

THEN ole Donny Moscow cut taxes for his wealthy friends and suddenly there is not enough money to pay for the things we MUST pay for like social security. 

&gt;And when your tax revenue goes down, you should do the responsible thing and spend less. 

No shit, Sherlock.

Why not figure that shit out before cutting taxes? Because it would make the   Poors who support Cons look and feel stupid for voting against their own self-interest.

&gt;And while Republicans certainly are not great on this, they're not the utter garbage that the Democrat party has been. The Democrats like to pretend that they're the only ones balancing the budget when the only reason the budget was out of balance in the first place is because of their entitlement programs and social spending.

Clinton balanced the budget. Bush II fucked it up and left a disaster for Obama who cleaned up the economy, then old Trump derailed it. 

Rinse and repeat.

&gt;And what is that? What is the fair share of the rich? And how are you defining fair such that a flat tax on all dollars earned isn't the fairest solution? 

Elon Musk is worth over 200 billion dollars. He just asked the government to spend 100 million building 8 charging stations for electric vehicles. 

&gt;Again, you say this is a transfer because it's actually you that doesn't understand transfers. 

Oh really? You're correct? And all the professionals are wrong?

You clearly share Trump's narcissism. 

&gt;When you steal my shit 

LOL. "Steal"

Good lord. You sound like a sovereign citizen.

&gt;and give it to other people 

That's how Governments are funded.

&gt;and then I managed to convince the government to not do that anymore, that is not a transfer from you to me. 

You are literally defending the wealthy elite in response to a comment that was originaly about a paper detailing how middle class Cons are  programmed to serve the wealthy elite. Of course you refuse to read the paper. LOL. The professor also talks about keeping people like you willfully ignorant and uneducated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43776113883.0" user="UnComfortingSounds" delta="False">
    <text>Trump is literally an East Coast elite from an ivy league institution who boasts about his net worth in the billions, whose success in politics is  shuttering unions and cutting taxes for the wealthiest individuals. 

Just because his base are morons doesn’t mean that he isn’t exactly standing by these same principles ascribed above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43767467485.0" user="sirremingtoniii" delta="False">
    <text>as someone just scrolling through this thread, just saying, your first sentence is super off putting and makes me not want to agree with whatever comes after it. whether or not it’s true of the person you’re replying to, this accusation never seems to accomplish much besides inflaming tempers</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43769072372.0" user="Nuwisha55" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Nowhere does anyone say that the conservative masses aspire to be aristocrats. 

I must have missed that "temporarily embarrassed millionaire" thing pointed out over a hundred years ago, about America specifically.

I've spoken to conservatives and grew up in Texas. A) One conversation was about how Appalachia had "proud" poor, as opposed to the lousy, "undeserving" poor walking around California. Even when you're the so-called "deserving" poor you don't get bailed out.  
B) The UAW strike was bitched about ruining things for the shareholders. The shareholders in conservatism mean you, even when it's not you. CEOs are never to blame for moving jobs to China or Mexico, but workers can be blamed. These people don't own shit, but they'll act like they do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782765826.0" user="MildlyAttractiv3" delta="False">
    <text>"You don't seem to have much reading comprehension or critical thinking skills" is grammatically incorrect. Proofread your post before attacking someone else's English skills. This is also stated in the anti delta page.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782895094.0" user="hedonihilistic" delta="False">
    <text>oh wow, thanks. You're running behind, checking the language/grammar for 4 day old posts. Better pick up your pace, don't want to fall back too far behind with your pathetic existence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783348303.0" user="MildlyAttractiv3" delta="False">
    <text>Check the anti delta page of the wiki. You are doing the exact things it tells you not to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754913737.0" user="-passionate-fruit-" delta="False">
    <text>What's being argued is not that MAGAs are broadly trying to be aristocratic or are personally power-hungry, but that they support certain politicians who are.  

The part of them that's becoming dispossessed are the white supremacist faction (due to demographic changes).  You could argue that's most of them, but at least a significant minority of MAGA supporters aren't.

They are revolutionary and radical, considering:

* They don't care about the morality of their politicians.
* They were okay with trying to bypass our democratic institutions to install Trump as dictator.
* They're embracing misinformation and constant lying to advance their causes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756007720.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;but that they support certain politicians who are

Yes

&gt;The part of them that's becoming dispossessed are the white supremacist faction (due to demographic changes)

No it's all working class whites, especially rural ones, regardless of their views on white supremacy. And the entire post 2016 GOP base is made of this group, since suburban affluent whites have completely abandoned ship. After 2028 or so they will have no real direct influence on national elections. Wealthier and connected whites will remain in the ruling class. 

&gt;They are revolutionary and radical, considering

None of those traits are characteristics of revolutionary or radical actors</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755825069.0" user="Muninwing" delta="False">
    <text>The MAGA movement is a tool for conservative aims. They just don’t realize it. 

The people in the movement are not the aristocracy that would benefit. In fact, quite the contrary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755860618.0" user="TAMILIANPSYCHO" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed actually, just a conduit to pass policies to strengthen the System long run, especially post 2028 when there won't be a meaningful opposition anymore. They didn't get jack shit that they wanted, even guns Trump was worse than the recent democrats lol. The only reason Americans haven't had mass gun confiscation is that the feds got scared shitless by Timothy McVeigh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43769111819.0" user="starion832000" delta="False">
    <text>Turkeys voting for Thanksgiving</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43778849062.0" user="Odd_Local8434" delta="False">
    <text>It is a tool for conservative aims, but it's a fascist movement. If it wins it will unilaterally start altering the rules to what it sees fit, and will cull the poor and rich alike who stand in its way. What it wants will also continuously change, creating more enemies and out groups on a constant basis. It already is out grouping former in groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43778877386.0" user="Muninwing" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not just Fascism. It’s conservatism in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43779326734.0" user="Odd_Local8434" delta="False">
    <text>Conservatives ally with each other to create the society they want. The out groups they target and go after are basically always the same. Sexual and gender deviants, those of other faiths, atheists, immigrants, poor people, those with darker skin. They also can have neutral groups, those that could be in the out group but currently aren't, Muslims in America before 9/11 for example..

If you're in the in group with conservatives you'll stay there unless you leave it. Fascists will wake up one day, and declare you the enemy for things that were completely acceptable yesterday.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858858852.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, we're all just so stupid that we can't figure out what's best for ourselves. I know that you guys treat pretty much everyone like that, and for some inexplicable reason it does work with certain racial groups, but that's not us. Please point to a single example of something that Donald Trump did for the American aristocracy. You can't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43859382813.0" user="Muninwing" delta="False">
    <text>Tax cuts. Regulation cuts. Gutting EPA regs. 

Should I continue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43767147406.0" user="DropAnchor4Columbus" delta="False">
    <text>Their movements ability to influence the current seems to be rippling out rather than dying, though, doesn't it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762799043.0" user="Frnklfrwsr" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct, and that’s why many people consider the center-left politicians to be conservatives. They also want to protect the aristocracy, but they are more risk-averse about pissing off the “regular folk”. So they’re willing to accept more left-leaning policy and be the “good guys”. They will support rights for LGBT people, women and people of color, and maybe slightly more progressive taxation. As long as they can maintain the aristocracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43771400956.0" user="Big_Zookeepergame_87" delta="False">
    <text>Source</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43773241228.0" user="Still_Difference5461" delta="False">
    <text>You only know what they do publicly, and people are under no obligation to publicize their wealth either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750026179.0" user="Dark_Ansem" delta="False">
    <text>That link is now my favourite read ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43750396729.0" user="Certified_JLB" delta="False">
    <text>So the conservative base in states like WV chose to abandon the Democratic Party and embrace trump because they wanted to be aristocrats?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754381052.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;"Nowadays, though, most of the people who call themselves "conservatives" have little notion of what conservatism even is. They have been deceived by one of the great public relations campaigns of human history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755273093.0" user="Certified_JLB" delta="False">
    <text>True.  While their jobs were being shipped overseas they were being told the global economy was going to produce more wealth.  Guess who not for?  Remember the line then was we can train you for computer jobs.  Both parties have abandoned the middle class.  It’s about jobs jobs jobs. Nowadays all the rest is noise.  And this article is nothing but pure bullshit that further helps to divide Americans by claiming the high ground.  Lol aristocracy, what a load of pure shit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755821454.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;While their jobs were being shipped overseas they were being told the global economy was going to produce more wealth.

Free Trade WAS (past tense) a tenant of conservatism. The wealthy elite got free trade and they immediately shipped manufacturing jobs overseas (because with free trade they don't have to pay a tariff to import the goods). 

Trump ended free trade. Cons went along with it. 

This is perfectly inline with what the professor said about how conservatism changes every generation.   

You should read the professor's paper. 

HISTORY OF CONS CHANGING:

Cons support segregation. A generation later Cons are okay with de-segregation.

Cons support free trade. A generation later they are okay with trade wars. 

Cons oppose gay marriage. A generation later they are okay with gay marriage.

Cons oppose legalizing marijuana. Cons still oppose legalizing marijuana, but not for long.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755936090.0" user="Certified_JLB" delta="False">
    <text>Hold on first who gives a shit whose idea it was, the problem is it was perpetuated by both side for what, over 30 years now?  although if I’m not mistaken NAFTA was Clinton.  I read the paper and it’s speaks of a class of Americans who are tone deaf.  They shut off the voice of fully 50% of voting Americans with the waive of a hand.  Aristocracy I’m laughing so hard I can’t breathe.  Yeah Americans who have no hope of owning a home and wait tables for a wage you wouldn’t accept, that describes them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760584476.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Hold on first who gives a shit whose idea it was, the problem is it was perpetuated by both side for what, over 30 years now?  

This CMV is about Conservative ideology changing. 

So it is 100% relevant. 

&gt;although if I’m not mistaken NAFTA was Clinton. 

Clinton was President (the first Democratic president in 12 years) who signed the bill into law. 

NAFTA was supported by more Republicans than Dems in both the Senate and House. 

&gt; I read the paper and it’s speaks of a class of Americans who are tone deaf.  They shut off the voice of fully 50% of voting Americans with the waive of a hand.  

Ok

&gt;Aristocracy I’m laughing so hard I can’t breathe.  Yeah Americans who have no hope of owning a home and wait tables for a wage you wouldn’t accept, that describes them.  Meanwhile let’s fight over bathrooms

Wow. You get it but you don't get it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752201692.0" user="FiveEnmore" delta="False">
    <text>This is correct.

 The problem was, is and will be,"how to explain this to the average person"? 

When education is under attack.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753152771.0" user="Arndt3002" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes that conservativism is some unified, homogeneous, or coherent ideology. This argument is as asinine as saying liberals don't believe in anything because they originally supported free market capitalism, but current liberals needed to reinvent the notion of freedom to justify modern liberalism. It's confusing the fluidity of terms for inconsistency of the ideas themselves.

It's not as though people are conservatives because they want to be conservative and then mold their ideas and values around the concept of being opposed to new ideas. They first hold certain ideas, which they hold to when confronted with a view that opposes theirs. Similarly, people are liberal, not because they just want change, but because they hold certain beliefs which necessitate change. That is, people are liberal because they believe in liberal policy, not because they like the label. This is similar to conservatives. This sort of argument forces an absolute binary that is extremely disingenuous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754509274.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;This assumes that conservativism is some unified, homogeneous, or coherent ideology.

Generally, it is. 

And I'll stick with the UCLA Professor's paper over your reddit comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760566284.0" user="PirateDaveZOMG" delta="False">
    <text>Your given reasoning here is a logical fallacy known as 'appeal to authority'.  It's not that you, or the 'UCLA Professor' are necessarily wrong, but rather that your reasoning is fallacious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762244058.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>You've made 2 comments. You are clearly very bothered by the fact that Cons serve the wealthy elite (aristocrats). 

If it bothers you so much why don't you attack the Professor's paper?

You can't. You won't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43777456262.0" user="PirateDaveZOMG" delta="False">
    <text>And this is an ad hominem fallacy.  Perhaps you see, at this point, that your lack of self-awareness leads me, and likely others in your life, to have no respect for your perspective whatsoever - perhaps you don't.

I assure you it is the former, and you can and should improve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43779306315.0" user="You_Dont_Party" delta="False">
    <text>Hahaha it’s not an ad hominem to point out that you’re unable to address the actual arguments being made.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781224199.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; fallacy.

Cringe</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43784948998.0" user="Acrobatic-Poet-1913" delta="False">
    <text>This discussion reminds me of the scene in Good Will Hunting.  You should have ended. “Now, How do you like them apples”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43777572302.0" user="Bootsandanecktie" delta="False">
    <text>It's not worth debating. Implying that the modern American "conservative" movement is devoid of liberal ideology is incredibly ignorant and demonstrates a near complete lack of understanding towards modern political thought and discourse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781229689.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Implying that the modern American "conservative" movement is devoid of liberal ideology is incredibly ignorant and demonstrates a near complete lack of understanding towards modern political thought and discourse.

Who implied that? Where? Quote it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782723018.0" user="MildlyAttractiv3" delta="False">
    <text>From the anti delta page:

\&gt; Inform them of their inherent cognitive limitations  
"You are incapable of responding to these points."  
"You have proven that you cannot grasp this concept." (Bonus points for using "proven")  
Bring the actor-observer bias into full force and interpret a lack of response, or an unsatisfactory response, as evidence of a core dysfunction.  
You will encounter a problem not just with your opponent, however, but with any other spectator who--like your opponent--has a different model of how the discussion is progressing and what is being argued. You'll reveal your own inner bias on what's important to the argument, which may not be flattering in the eyes of others. It's common on CMV for people to have different ideas of what matters and what's irrelevant or tangental.  
It's better to take the fight to where they are, not stand on an empty battlefield and pretend you won.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782724141.0" user="MildlyAttractiv3" delta="False">
    <text>From the anti delta page:

\&gt; Inform them of their inherent cognitive limitations  
"You are incapable of responding to these points."  
"You have proven that you cannot grasp this concept." (Bonus points for using "proven")  
Bring the actor-observer bias into full force and interpret a lack of response, or an unsatisfactory response, as evidence of a core dysfunction.  
You will encounter a problem not just with your opponent, however, but with any other spectator who--like your opponent--has a different model of how the discussion is progressing and what is being argued. You'll reveal your own inner bias on what's important to the argument, which may not be flattering in the eyes of others. It's common on CMV for people to have different ideas of what matters and what's irrelevant or tangental.  
It's better to take the fight to where they are, not stand on an empty battlefield and pretend you won.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782813396.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782833443.0" user="MildlyAttractiv3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm bad with tech. I couldn't figure out how to quote something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858849220.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>And why would that be? The man is a professor at a disgustingly progressive university. Everything points to the fact he is an utter moron, even before you read his tripe of an article.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43859788680.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And why would that be? 

Well for one, BeefcakeWellington has -63 karma.

Second, I actually read the Professor's paper.

&gt;The man is a professor at a disgustingly progressive university.

No he is not. He disappeared a long time ago. The paper was written over 20 years ago, fyi.

&gt; Everything points to the fact he is an utter moron, even before you read his tripe of an article.

You should read it, Einstein.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866034750.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Are you trying to claim that 20 years ago UCLA wasn't a garbage cesspool of progressive thought? Because it was. Has been for at least 40 years, probably more like 60.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866248981.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>Convincing Poor Cons that college is "bad" is key to the Cons keeping y'all willfully ignorant. You fucking celebrate it while literally defending the wealthy elite. 

Un-fucking-real.

Read the paper. Educate yourself. Pretend the paper won't make you gay or trans or whatever it is you have been programmed to fear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753339293.0" user="LogicalLetterhead272" delta="False">
    <text>It's abundantly clear that you've put no effort in trying to understand conservatism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754477327.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>You should read the piece. 

I grew up conservative. Voted for Bush. I understand conservatism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755291002.0" user="EazyPeazyLemonSqueaz" delta="False">
    <text>This would be a great place to show the effort you've put in and correct them on what conservatism means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757969021.0" user="littleferrhis" delta="False">
    <text>I highly disagree with this. It really reaks of a superiority complex, like normal conservatives are just low IQ idiots who can’t tell they are being duped when there are reasons to be a conservative beyond supporting the rich.

 The root of conservatism is about supporting the status quo or bringing things back into a period before a status quo was changed. There can be a multitude of reasons for this. 

From just genuinely disliking change because it leads to instability to not agreeing with the changes. 

The former is pretty universal being your typical, “we like our way of life, everyone knows their place and it functions really well why change it?” When the truth is that it only really functions well for you type deal. 

The latter is honestly more interesting and tends to be where I have a lot more sympathy. There’s many reasons that people may dislike the growing push for socialism(such as the past revolving around socialist nations, because unless you think the hatred/fear of the Soviet Union, China, or North Korea was just a bunch of wealthy capitalist manipulation, and not actually legitimately terrible states, there’s a lot of baggage that comes with the term). There’s many reasons why people may not like the push for intersectionality(from thinking its overly judgmental on people’s actions, to being far too confusing and contradictory to really function). Economically lassies faire capitalism tends to be synonymous with booms in the economy(until it doesn’t obviously). I should say I don’t agree with these, but I feel like there’s as much unfair judgement thrown at the right as there is being dished out to left. 

Its more complicated than, “a bunch of rich people are manipulating a bunch of dumb troglodytes and those dumb troglodytes have votes.” It’s just so fucking insecure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760648311.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I highly disagree with this. It really reaks of a superiority complex, like normal conservatives are just low IQ idiots who can’t tell they are being duped when there are reasons to be a conservative beyond supporting the rich, 

That's basically it. The wealthy elite (aristocrats) use Culture War bullshit to get Poors to support wealth transfers (via tax cuts) by way of conservatism. 

Middle and lower class Cons vote against their own self-interests. Surely you've heard that before. 

&gt;unlike the high IQ left that totally doesn’t fall into the same traps and get duped by politicians.

I think you are confusing Conservatives on the Left who masquerade as progressives. 

&gt;The root of conservatism is about supporting the status quo or bringing things back into a period before a status quo was changed. 

And the status quo was aristocracy. Wealthy elitist families that controlled everything: Kennedys; Rockfellers, etc.

&gt;There can be a multitude of reasons for this. From just genuinely disliking change because it leads to instability to not agreeing with the changes.  
&gt;  
&gt;The former is pretty universal being your typical, “we like our way of life, everyone knows their place and it functions really well why change it?” When the truth is that it only really functions well for you type deal.  
&gt;  
&gt;The latter is honestly more interesting and tends to be where I have a lot more sympathy. 

You're ignoring how Cons change every generation. 

&gt;There’s many reasons that people may dislike the growing push for socialism(such as the past revolving around socialist nations, because unless you think the hatred/fear of the Soviet Union, China, or North Korea was just a bunch of wealthy capitalist manipulation, and not actually legitimately terrible states, there’s a lot of baggage that comes with the term). There’s many reasons why people may not like the push for intersectionality(from thinking its overly judgmental on people’s actions, to being far too confusing and contradictory to really function). Economically lassies faire capitalism tends to be synonymous with booms in the economy(until it doesn’t obviously). I should say I don’t agree with these, but I feel like there’s as much unfair judgement thrown at the right as there is being dished out to left.

Ok. 

&gt;Its more complicated than, “a bunch of rich people are manipulating a bunch of dumb troglodytes and those dumb troglodytes have votes.” 

No it is not. It's always been the HAVES manipulating the HAVE-NOTS. 

&gt;It would be easy for me to say the same thing about the left, 

Do it. 

&gt;but the truth is both sides are being duped, 

Both sides have Cons. Obama was not a progressive. Neither was Clinton or Biden. 

The issue is about CONS. 

&gt;and we just attach our ideologies to politicians who won’t follow through on any of them and instead go with whatever the rich people say.

You've explained nothing. But you got narcissism to think you no better than a UCLA professor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43767139691.0" user="DropAnchor4Columbus" delta="False">
    <text>Someone who says things like 'its only the secret right wingers on the left who get duped' has no right to speak about narcissism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43768573464.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; 'its only the secret right wingers on the left who get duped' 

Who said that?

Are you trying to imply I said that?

Are you trying to imply the UCLA professor said that?

&gt;has no right to speak about narcissism.

LOL.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43768772646.0" user="DropAnchor4Columbus" delta="False">
    <text>You get to laugh when that ISN'T still part of what you wrote above. lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43769153339.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>Huh?

Why don't you quote it and stop beating around the bushes with nonsense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858903086.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The wealthy elite (aristocrats) use Culture War bullshit to get Poors to support wealth transfers (via tax cuts) by way of conservatism.

How exactly does not stealing money from people amount to a wealth transfer? Like taking tax dollars from rich people and giving them to middle class people is definitely a wealth transfer, but stopping doing that is not. That's allowing people to keep their own shit. So how in the world do you figure that that is an actual wealth transfer? Just because you say something enough times doesn't make it true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43862463133.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;How exactly does not stealing money from people amount to a wealth transfer? 

Let's say 100 million people are responsible for paying America's bills.

To do this the Government taxes everyone. 

Then one day, the wealthy elite get their puppet into office. The puppet, who is subservient to the wealthy elite, single handedly changes the tax rate so that the rich get huge, permeant tax cuts and the Poors get short term, small tax cuts. 

The Poors are programmed via right wing propaganda to believe "their" tax cut is equal to the wealthy elite's massive savings. The Poors are also programmed to believe the tax cuts will pay for themselves by spurring the economy. 

Then reality sets in: The tax cuts drastically increase the federal deficit, adding TRILLIONS of dollars to the debt. 

The 100 million people now have 10 trillion extra dollars worth of debt to pay off. So a few years later the Government is forced to raise taxes to pay off the debt and the Government is forced to cut social security, medicare, medicaid, etc.

Thus, the Poors end up paying for the 10 TRILLION the wealthy elite "saved" (as you would say) via the 2017 Tax Cuts. Call it what you want but it is a transfer of wealthy via unfunded debt. 

&gt;Like taking tax dollars from rich people and giving them to middle class people is definitely a wealth transfer, but stopping doing that is not. 

Yeah, I wouldn't disagree with that per se. But a functioning civil society in a first class country needs to tax higher incomes more than the Poors. 

Whether that should be the case or not is irrelevant because America is $33 TRILLION. That debt needs to be paid off. And it is going to be the middle class that pays most of it off. 

FWIW, America's total debt was under 6 trillion when Clinton was President in 1999.

&gt;That's allowing people to keep their own shit. 

The bill is due. Someone MUST pay it off. Why do you want the middle class to pay off the wealthy elite's fair share?

&gt;So how in the world do you figure that that is an actual wealth transfer? Just because you say something enough times doesn't make it true.

Here's what the professionals have to say:

"The consequence of a tax cut on the wealthy is basically a transfer of wealth from average households to wealthy households, and if it is to generate higher growth this transfer must sustainably increase demand in the form of higher consumption or higher investment.

If taxes on the wealthy are cut with no change in fiscal expenditures, the net result is that the wealthy pay a smaller share of total expenditures, so—with the tax cut—wealth is effectively transferred from average households to wealthy ones."

[https://carnegieendowment.org/chinafinancialmarkets/71359#:\~:text=If%20taxes%20on%20the%20wealthy,average%20households%20to%20wealthy%20ones](https://carnegieendowment.org/chinafinancialmarkets/71359#:~:text=If%20taxes%20on%20the%20wealthy,average%20households%20to%20wealthy%20ones).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43865946425.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Let's say 100 million people are responsible for paying America's bills.

No, let's not say that. You're assuming the premise.

&gt;Then reality sets in: The tax cuts drastically increase the federal deficit, adding TRILLIONS of dollars to the debt.

Positively untrue. Congress increases the federal deficit, and no one else. There are refusal to be responsible and to only spend money that they actually have is the problem, not how much money they bring in from rich people, who pay way more in taxes than you could ever earn in your entire life. Again, you are assuming the premise that their money belongs to you, but it doesn't. It's their money and then the government steals it.

&gt;"The consequence of a tax cut on the wealthy is basically a transfer of wealth from average households to wealthy households, 

Nope. Wrong. Not getting as much of a transfer as you were previously getting doesn't count as a transfer in the opposite direction. It is simply less of a transfer from rich to poor then previous. That's a pretty big distinction. It's also one that dumbass liberals make all the time when it comes to things like white privilege. You only feel like you're experiencing racism because you have less white privilege now than you did previously but you still haven't experienced racism. Same concept, except in this case it's correct.

&gt;the net result is that the wealthy pay a smaller share of total expenditures,

There is always the option to simply lower your total expenditures. But you're presuming that Congress won't do that. You're absolving Congress of all agency because you like the current wealth transfers from the rich to the poor. But you still haven't explained how the government has the right to take that money from them in the first place. How is that even remotely fair? More than half of the US population doesn't even pay federal taxes, and you have Elon musk paying more in a single year than 10,000 people will earn in their entire lifetimes. That seems far more than fair to me, except you want more. And you cannot explain why you deserve it or how it could possibly be classified as a transfer. Stop absolving Congress of their shitty behavior!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866122386.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>ME:

&gt;The tax cuts drastically increase the federal deficit, adding TRILLIONS of dollars to the debt.

YOU:

&gt;Positively untrue. Congress increases the federal deficit, and no one else. 

You are arguing semantics. The deficit needed to be increased because the GOP lied when they said the tax cuts would pay for themselves. 

I'm not gonna bother reading the rest of your garbage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866137496.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>It's not semantics. It's an incredibly important distinction. You do seem to struggle with abstract reasoning though so let me spell it out for you in more concrete terms:

Let's assume for simplicity of maths sake, that you pay $10,000 a year in taxes and I pay a million. Then Trump comes along and changes the tax code now you pay $10,000 a year in taxes and I pay $500,000. I got a nice big old tax cut. You pay the exact same amount of taxes. So how could it possibly be considered a wealth transfer from you to me when we didn't take anything additional from you? You pay the same amount of taxes. I pay less taxes. It's a wealth transfer from the government to me, paid with my own dollars that they stole from me previously. It has nothing to do with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43871122752.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Let's assume for simplicity of maths sake, that you pay $10,000 a year in taxes and I pay a million. Then Trump comes along and changes the tax code now you pay $10,000 a year in taxes and I pay $500,000. I got a nice big old tax cut. You pay the exact same amount of taxes. So how could it possibly be considered a wealth transfer from you to me when we didn't take anything additional from you? 

Jesus Christ you are stubborn. You truly think you're right and all the professionals are wrong? 

Your narcissism is off the charts. Right wing propaganda seems to have programmed you really good.

Your problem is you can't see past TODAY. 

You don't understand DEBT that is owed in the FUTURE.

&gt;You pay the same amount of taxes. 

TODAY, yes. Poors pay the same amount.

TODAY, the Wealthy Elite pays a LOT LESS.

Which results in the DEBT increasing.

So instead of there being 20 TRILLION in debt there is no 30 TRILLION in debt because the US had to take out loans to cover the lost revenue from the tax cuts. 

Your position is "Well don't spend as much" which is ignorant of how the system works. Most of the money we owe is INTEREST and obligations which cannot be avoided. 

&gt;I pay less taxes. 

TODAY you less, but in 2028 you will pay MORE in taxes while the wealthy elite pay the same rate as the 2017 tax cuts.

So a few years from now you'll PAY more than you did in 2017 while the wealthy elite pay LESS.

You pay MORE **so** the Wealthy elite can pay LESS. In other words, you are financing the rich's paying less. You make up the difference.

It's like overpaying for food at a restaurant because the rich asshole is underpaying for what he got. You're paying for the assholes lobster and wine. The rich asshole chips in a fair amount of money for someone who ordered soup &amp; salad. 

You don't have the ability to understand that.

TRUMP: "I love the uneducated."

The GOP keeps people dumb so they will support voting against their own self-interests (and wealth transfers).

&gt;It's a wealth transfer from the government to me, paid with my own dollars that they stole from me previously.

Pay real close attention.

&gt; It has nothing to do with you.

It has EVERYTHING to do with me because the MIDDLE CLASS will in the future be forced to pay more to cover the debt that was created by cutting your taxes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43873332758.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You truly think you're right and all the professionals are wrong?

Yes. You can't redefine words to fit your narrative. Also, of only progressive academics say it, its not all the experts. Ask a conservative *economist* and you'll get a very different answer. You simply can't conceive of someone starting with a different set of assumptions than you, and that's why this makes no sense to you. But you're wrong. The money that is taken in taxes *belongs to the people the government took it from*. If the government stops demanding as much, letting those people keep it *** cannot possibly be considered a transfer of wealth because they end up with the same amount of money that they had before it began.*** A transferred wealth needs to take something from one person and give it to the other give it to the necessarily has to have more when you are done with the transfer. This is basic definitions.

&gt;Your position is "Well don't spend as much" which is ignorant of how the system works.

I'm fully aware that it's unlikely. But you don't get to redefine words so that you come off as the good guy. You're not the good guy in this situation.

&gt;So a few years from now you'll PAY more than you did in 2017 while the wealthy elite pay LESS.

Not at all. I will actually be paying less taxes. So nice of you to assume that I have the same problems as you.

&gt;So instead of there being 20 TRILLION in debt there is now 30 TRILLION in debt because the US had to take out loans to cover the lost revenue from the tax cuts.

An utter and absolute misunderstanding of how government finances work. An utter and absolute absolution of the responsibility of Congress to maintain fiscal responsibility. Congress doesn't get to do whatever the fuck they want and then tax people to pay for that stuff. That's actual tyranny. There is nothing fundamentally different between that and the system of monarchy that we rebelled against.

&gt;It has EVERYTHING to do with me because the MIDDLE CLASS will in the future be forced to pay more to cover the debt that was created by cutting the Wealthy elites' taxes.

More than they had been paying, yes. Not more than rich people, neither an absolute terms nor percentage terms. You're mad because you're having to carry your fair share and you don't like it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43896670570.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You don't understand DEBT that is owed in the FUTURE.

You don't think that I am aware of how debt works? Really? Also, debt isn't owed until you receive the up front payment. Nobody is forcing Congress to spend money that they don't have. Nobody is forcing the Treasury to issue bonds to support that spending. These are choices by the government. These choices negate your assertion of a wealth transfer. Beyond the fact that literally no wealth is flowing from poor people to rich people, only less money is flowing from rich people to poor people, the choice to spend beyond the tax revenues is the responsibility of Congress and no one else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43896804678.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You don't think that I am aware of how debt works? Really? 

No I do not. From your username to your comments and your general inability to understand what a wealth transfer. All those things tell me you have no god damn clue how debt works.

&gt;Also, debt isn't owed until you receive the up front payment. 

Holy shit. Add that sentence to reasons I know you don't understand how debt works.

&gt;Nobody is forcing Congress to spend money that they don't have. 

It's too late. We're already 30 trillion in the whole. Y'all think it is about future spending it is about interest payments that is owed. You can't line dance around that, Cleetus.

&gt;Nobody is forcing the Treasury to issue bonds to support that spending. 

You simply can't comprehend what defaulting on bills owed means. 

&gt;These are choices by the government. These choices negate your assertion of a wealth transfer.

LOL. 

&gt; Beyond the fact that literally no wealth is flowing from poor people to rich people, 

The Poots are now on the hook for more debt that was created by Tax Cuts for the wealthy elite. 

You literally defend the wealthy elite. 

Everything in the paper by the Professor detailing how gullible Cons serve the wealthy elite is on perfect display by you in this thread.

&gt;only less money is flowing from rich people to poor people, the choice to spend beyond the tax revenues is the responsibility of Congress and no one else.

Tell me where you think and I will meet you there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43897412421.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Add that sentence to the reasons I know you don't understand how debt works.

Is that a fact? You think that you can owe a debt before you receive the thing that you owe the debt for? Please explain to me how that works.

&gt;The Poors are now on the hook for more debt that was created by Tax Cuts for the wealthy elite.

Well then they should be mad at Congress for spending money that they don't have. You are literally trying to defend theft and forcible reallocation of other people's money to you because you're poor. I'm sorry you have that problem, but it's not my problem. Everything you said in this long thread is just being salty over the fact your poor and I'm not. Cry me a river.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43968188995.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>[https://finance.yahoo.com/news/great-wealth-transfer-isn-t-100000946.html](https://finance.yahoo.com/news/great-wealth-transfer-isn-t-100000946.html)

"The ‘great wealth transfer’ isn’t $72 trillion but $129 trillion, BofA says—and the government gave most of it to baby boomers"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44680789177.0" user="Theodora_Angleterre" delta="False">
    <text>It's always darkly humorous to see the dupes go on a rant about how they weren't duped, it was the dang commies &amp; queers that ruined america durnnabbit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43769776625.0" user="Tokubai" delta="False">
    <text>If I were a crazy person willing to spend money on this website, I would give this comment an award for being a rare instance of measured sanity on Reddit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858887934.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It really reaks of a superiority complex, like normal conservatives are just low IQ idiots who can’t tell they are being duped when there are reasons to be a conservative beyond supporting the rich, unlike the high IQ left that totally doesn’t fall into the same traps and get duped by politicians.

It's called Murc's Law, and even though Democrats love to pretend that Republicans are the ones guilty of it, they just can't help themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759534559.0" user="Potatoenailgun" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of the aristocrats pivoting their base...

How about that about face on 'believe all women's once Biden got accused of sexual harassment?

Or what about Biden waiving environmental laws to get Trump's law built?

Dems thought it was a matter of human rights to let all migrants claim asylum even if they crossed the border illegally instead of claiming asylum at a port of entry.  Never mind that Obama required migrants from Cuba to be at a port of entry to claim asylum, even though navigating the sea to a port of entry on a makeshift raft is a lot harder then walking up to one.

Dems used to be the champions of freedom of speech, but now the DNC finds it useful to deplatform deplorables, and Dems pivoted right on queue.

If you ever find yourself thinking, "my party isn't like all the other parties" your clowning yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762137420.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Speaking of the aristocrats pivoting their base...  
&gt;  
&gt;How about that about face on 'believe all women's once Biden got accused of sexual assault?

Huh?

&gt;Or what about Biden waiving environmental laws to get Trump's wall built?

Haven't you heard, Biden is a conservative. You should read about the shit he did in the 90s. 

&gt;Dems thought it was a matter of human rights to let all migrants claim asylum even if they crossed the border illegally instead of claiming asylum at a port of entry.  Never mind that Obama required migrants from Cuba to be at a port of entry to claim asylum, even though navigating the sea to a port of entry on a makeshift raft is a lot harder then walking up to one.

Totally irrelevant. 

&gt;Dems used to be the champions of freedom of speech, but now the DNC finds it useful to deplatform deplorables, and Dems pivoted right on queue.

You clearly don't understand freedom of speech. It is a restriction on the government, not private enterprise. 

You regurgitating right wing talking points is entirely irrelevant. 

&gt;If you ever find yourself thinking, "my party isn't like all the other parties" your clowning yourself.

Again, it is NOT about parties. The issue at hand is the conservative ideology. 

There are lots of conservative Dems. See Clinton, Obama, Biden, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783100761.0" user="SheenyCurse01" delta="False">
    <text>One party thinks the constitution and Bill of rights were fundamental to a free nation, guaranteeing the basic human rights for all citizens

The other thinks it's an old document and that socialism isn't evil</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43785403131.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;One party thinks the constitution and Bill of rights were fundamental to a free nation, guaranteeing the basic human rights for all citizens

1) Pay attention. The issue is "ideology", not "political party."

2) You sound programmed. Conservatives vehemently oppose the right for Americans to possess a plant (cannabis/marijuana) our founding fathers cultivated. In fact, over 99% of Conservatives recently voted to keep marijuana a Schedule 1 substance, meaning they don't recognize the plant's medicinal use. That is Cons bending over for Big Pharma. 

3) Cons support civil asset forfeiture, which is a grave violation of the right to property and due process. 

4) Cons ban books.

5) Cons ban clothing.

6) Cons want laws dictating how parents can raise their own children.

7) Cons want Christianity in public schools. Hows that for separation of chucch and state?

8) Cons oppose gays having the right to have gay sex. 

9) Most cons oppose the right to inter-racial marriage.

10) Most cons oppose gays having the right to gay marriage. 

The last 3 things I listed is known by virtue of the laws that did and did not pass protecting marriage rights. I think only 16 cons voted to legalize interracial and gay marriage. That means the vast majority of Cons oppose those rights. 

&gt;The other thinks it's an old document and that socialism isn't evil

Is Social Security evil?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858908427.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>There's definitely a small fraction of the GOP trying to turn it into a populist party. The establishment is fighting tooth and nail, but we'll see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759727688.0" user="XNoob_SmokeX" delta="False">
    <text>Progressives control most western governments, corporate America, Hollywood, Legacy Media, The music industry, the catholic church, and Wallstreet. 

Conservatives make up more than 50 percent of the working class. 

You ARE the aristocracy. And we WILL defeat you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762187886.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Progressives control most western governments, 

America is a conservative country. Just like Ireland, England, etc etc. 

&gt;corporate America, 

Corporate America is driven by greed and capitalism, that's why corporate America is Republican. 

If they say shit you take to be "woke" it's so they can make more money. 

&gt;Legacy Media, 

Fox News is conservative. 

&gt;the catholic church, 

You think the Catholic Church is progressive? 

I don't believe anyone is so ignorant to believe that. 

&gt;and Wallstreet.

LOL.

Hahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahahah

&gt;Conservatives make up more than 50 percent of the working class.

No shit. They vote against their own self-interests. 

The Wealthy Elite use propaganda and culture was shit to manipulate the HAVE NOTS into supporting the HAVES. 

Poor Cons were happy Trump's tax cuts transferred trillions from the middle class to the top 1%. Why were they happy? Because they were deceived!!!

&gt;You ARE the aristocracy. And we WILL defeat you.

LOL. 

You've literally been brainwashed to believe supporting the wealthy elite with defeat the wealthy elite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43987413667.0" user="EnQuest" delta="False">
    <text>that dude is dangerously close to /selfawarewolves material</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760555361.0" user="PirateDaveZOMG" delta="False">
    <text>Easily the most egregious, short-sighted, circle-jerking violation of Rule 1 I've seen in a long time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762228020.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.

My comment: That is not true. Cons DO believe in something, protecting the aristocracy. Here's why you are confused: Because Conservative ideology changes every generation. Here's something you should read. 

It's funny how triggered and hurt Cons get when they finally begin to see how the GOP serves the wealthy elite/aristocrats.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762667057.0" user="Highside2023" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like a very balanced and objective take, how can I not agree?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763660064.0" user="GopherChomper64" delta="False">
    <text>This is beautiful and it's a perfect explanation for what conservatism is and explains perfectly the absolutely insane levels of cognitive dissonance displayed by the people who vote for conservatism who are not actually of the aristocrat class. 

"They psychologically internalized belief that the aristocracy is better than they are." Perfect explanation for why all these people can just believe absolute nonsense about Trump and straight up disown things that we know to be true about him. They think because he is rich even though he was born into it, he lied as well as colluded with the Russian mafia to maintain it, and conned his way to maintaining his wealth, which these inbred poor fucks have psychologically internalized as making him better than them because their values are shallow and they base a person's worth on their financial worth, not on their intrinsic value as a human being, and most certainly not as their hypocritical religion /Jesus would value, which is the goodness of the human being in question.

Seriously look at prosperity gospel, rooms full of conservatives believing a guy preaching about how being wealthy is his reward for following a faith that despises wealth for its own sake and is there for a measure of how holy they are. 

Just absolutely perfect to say it's an internalized inferiority complex that drives all these idiots into voting for and admiring people and policies that are against their own best interests...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43767809181.0" user="henrycatalina" delta="False">
    <text>Are Facebook and Google and other wealthy aristocracy also captured or have captured progressives?  Just like the Koch brothers, I'm told support conservatives. The republican party was formerly captured by aristocracy, which tends to be the middle of the road. The democrats were likewise captured by liberal aristocracy. Both parties now have populist heavily influencing agendas.

Liberal formerly referred to a bias toward freedom and individual rights. I'd argue that we in the USA don't have any true to the definition liberal parties. We have two parties with fringe elements setting agendas. 

MAGA in itself is a trend in both parties. They just call it different things. In fact, follow the money and the current administration funds made in America. 

Every person I know has flaws. Some people have worse flaws than others. Trump had a very flawed history. That is his biggest flaw. Next is his often poor selection of some advisors that are clearly incompetent. Some policies seemed to work, and others failed. Just like his predisesor  Obama, Trump creates divisions by playing to the fringe. Biden is even worse. All three are incapable of building goodwill. Clinton, Reagan, the Bushes, Kennedy, and Carter all were reasonable politicians despite personal flaws. I left out Ford (appointment) and Nixon, but at least Nixon resigned in shame and owned his flaws. 

That professors' diatribe about conservatives is disingenuous and fails to recognize the range of reasons people are in either party. All presidents are in the aristocracy. The only ones I'd say weren't are  Harry Truman and Jimmy Carter.  Their flaws were somewhat benign. Truman didn't understand business and was demostrably terrible at it. However, he was honest, and not in politics for self agrandment. Carter didn't understand that empathy is a small part of leadership. People need to see a future and not commiserate on misery. He had some quite positive business policies started that Reagan claimed credit for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43768689745.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Are Facebook and Google and other wealthy aristocracy 

Huh?

Aristocracy is made of wealthy elite people. Not corporations. 

&gt;also captured or have captured progressives?  

?

&gt;Just like the Koch brothers, I'm told support conservatives. 

The Koch brothers (one is dead by the way) spent hundreds of millions on Republicans and conservative issues. 

"As of 2014 the millions of dollars both brothers donated to candidates went to Republicans, not Libertarians..."

"They actively fund and support organizations that contribute significantly to Republican candidates, promote climate change denial, and in particular that lobby against efforts to expand government's role in health care and climate change mitigation. Unlike less patient, shrewd, or deep-pocketed activists, they spent time and money on less visible projects "like influencing policy at the state legislative level". By 2010, they had donated more than $100 million to dozens of conservative advocacy organizations. From 2009 to 2016, the network of conservative/right-wing donors they organized pledged to spend $889 million..."

&gt;The republican party was formerly captured by aristocracy, which tends to be the middle of the road. The democrats were likewise captured by liberal aristocracy. Both parties now have populist heavily influencing agendas.

The issue is not political parties. The CMV is about the conservative ideology, which switches parties when necessary. 

&gt;Liberal formerly referred to a bias toward freedom and individual rights. I'd argue that we in the USA don't have any true to the definition liberal parties. We have two parties with fringe elements setting agendas.  
&gt;  
&gt;MAGA in itself is a trend in both parties. They just call it different things. In fact, follow the money and the current administration funds made in America.

?

&gt;Every person I know has flaws. Some people have worse flaws than others. 

Note to self: Buckle up. 

&gt;Trump had a very flawed history. That is his biggest flaw. Next is his often poor selection of some advisors that are clearly incompetent. Some policies seemed to work, and others failed. Just like his predisesor  Obama, Trump creates divisions by playing to the fringe. Biden is even worse. 

Oy vey.

&gt;All three are incapable of building goodwill. 

LOL.

&gt;Clinton, Reagan, the Bushes, Kennedy, and Carter all were reasonable politicians despite personal flaws. I left out Ford (appointment) and Nixon, but at least Nixon resigned in shame and owned his flaws.

What does any of this have to do with the CMV about conservative ideology?

It's just you --and other cons -- going to the mat to defend conservatism with essentially "Whataboutism" and "both sides are the same."

&gt;That professors' diatribe 

It's a paper examining the history of conservatism. You don't like it so you consider it mean and call it a diatribe. Because you are triggered. 

&gt;about conservatives is disingenuous and fails to recognize the range of reasons people are in either party. 

AGAIN, it is NOT about party. It is about ideology. 

&gt;All presidents are in the aristocracy. 

Obama was not a member of the aristocracy before becoming President. You can argue he is now a member of the aristocracy.

However, being an aristocrat does not make one conservative. 

You should read the linked paper. 

Conservatism is the tool aristocrats use to protect the aristocracy (social hierarchy). 

&gt;The only ones I'd say weren't are  Harry Truman and Jimmy Carter.  

Irrelevant. You are now just defending Cons by "both sides are the same."

Again, it's not the people. It's the conservative ideology -- the tool -- used to safeguard the pre-existing aristocracy. 

&gt;Their flaws were somewhat benign. Truman didn't understand business and was demostrably terrible at it. However, he was honest, and not in politics for self agrandment. Carter didn't understand that empathy is a small part of leadership. People need to see a future and not commiserate on misery. He had some quite positive business policies started that Reagan claimed credit for.

Irrelevant. 

You clearly don't understand the issue at hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43773102325.0" user="henrycatalina" delta="False">
    <text>I should have said it is not labels but leadership and policy that make the difference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43776555305.0" user="DalinarsDingleberry" delta="False">
    <text>When the first thing that author does is create a strawman argument, nothing else he says can be taken seriously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43776793529.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>What is the straw man argument?

Why don't you prove you are not triggered, programmed servant of the wealthy elite, and copy and paste it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43776829373.0" user="DalinarsDingleberry" delta="False">
    <text>His first question and answer are the strawman. And then he goes on with a further strawman for his second question and answer. 

And now you’ve created a third strawman with this comment. This is exactly what the left does. Create false statements to argue against to the mentally stunted can agree to hate “those evil conservatives”, meanwhile ignoring how their own idea are antithetical to actual democracy and freedom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43776892055.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;"Q: What is conservatism?  
&gt;  
&gt;A: Conservatism is the domination of society by an aristocracy.  
&gt;  
&gt;Q: What is wrong with conservatism?  
&gt;  
&gt;A: Conservatism is incompatible with democracy, prosperity, and civilization in general. It is a destructive system of inequality and prejudice that is founded on deception and has no place in the modern world."

How is that a straw man?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43776954717.0" user="DalinarsDingleberry" delta="False">
    <text>Conservatism is most definitely not the domination of society by an aristocracy (that’s leftism) nor is it incompatible with democrats (again that is leftism).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43777183358.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>You are just a butt hurt, triggered Dingleberry. 

You clearly haven't read the paper. 

Y'all love transferring middle class money to the wealthy elite via tax cuts so much you literally defend it. You've been programmed to believe the wealthy elite (people like Elon Musk) are better than everyone else. You support the aristocrats by voting conservative. 

Read the paper!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43777220256.0" user="DalinarsDingleberry" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t need to read the paper when the entire premise it is based on is false. It says a lot about you if you think calling out BS makes one triggered.  Nowhere did I say I think the wealthy are better than anyone else. I also pointed out that leftists are the ones worthy of the labels generated by your author, and you ignored that. It’s sad you are so consumed with hate and vitriol pumped into your brain that you can’t see what’s been done to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781204964.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like you are proud to be ignorant. 

The professor explains in detail that conservatism changes every generation (Cons once opposed segregation, now they accept it for e.g.) and that the Con ideology seeks to protect the wealthy elite (i.e. aristocracy) and that destroying language and education is one of their means. 

Sadly, Con ideology has been so effective that lots of Poors think higher education is bad. 

I understand you not having the courage and mental wherewithal to read the paper that absolutely paints you as a tool of the wealthy elite. Don't forget to defend permeant tax cuts for the rich! Oh and cutting benefits for the needy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782213594.0" user="DalinarsDingleberry" delta="False">
    <text> Conservatives do not favor segregation. It’s leftists doing that. Look at who the big banks and corporations donate to. Democrat politicians. Everything you just said is the opposite of reality. I knew what the paper is going to say based on the two questions and answers you listed. So it looks like *you* are the one who is ignorant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43782785330.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Conservatives do not favor segregation.

Not any more but they did. Cons fought de-segregation. 

You're not paying attention. 

Cons change every generation. The only thing that doesn't change is that they work for the aristocracy. 

&gt; It’s leftists doing that.

WTF are you talking about?

I'm talking about literal racial segregation. [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racial\_segregation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racial_segregation)

In America whites and blacks were not allowed to use the same drinking fountains, etc. 

It took a huge civil rights movement to de-segregate. Conservatives fought against it.

A generation later and Cons are okay with whites and blacks co-mingling. 

&gt; Look at who the big banks and corporations donate to. Democrat politicians. 

What does that have to do with anything?

A person would have to be extremely ignorant to not understand the wealthy elite favor Conservative laws and policies. 

&gt;Everything you just said is the opposite of reality. 

You don't even know what segregation is. You are extremely confused. 

Follow the money. 

Which ideology -- the progressive one which wants higher worker pay and higher taxes on the wealthy elite OR the conservative ideology which wants billionaires to pay less taxes, etc -- favors the wealthy elite?

You'd be lying if you said the ideology which wants to chop the wealthy elite down is somehow the party the wealthy elite favors. 

Again, Cons use propaganda to get Poors to support the aristocracy by voting conservative. 

&gt;I knew what the paper is going to say based on the two questions and answers you listed. So it looks like you are the one who is ignorant.

You are clueless. 

Keep supporting the wealthy elite, kid. Maybe another billionaire born into elite wealth can get your family members to send them their hard earned money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783506793.0" user="DalinarsDingleberry" delta="False">
    <text>You are [wrong](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/aug/28/republicans-party-of-civil-rights) on the segregation issue. And you don’t have a clue about which corporate elites are buying which politicians. It’s stunning how confidently incorrect you are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43785446124.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;"Once you control for region, it turns out that Democrats were actually more likely to support the 1964 Civil Rights Act"

That above is the first fucking line in your linked article. 

Besides, the issue is IDEOLOGY not "party."

Christ, Dingleberry. Quit living up to your name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43779972587.0" user="vinceglartho" delta="False">
    <text>He clearly was a Democrat that believes he’s a liberal and he’s just plain wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781240508.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43858845141.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Conservatism is the domination of society by an aristocracy

That is his opinion, and it is objectively wrong. Any other thoughts you care to share with the class?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43859771151.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;That is his opinion, and it is objectively wrong. 

Prove it.

&gt;Any other thoughts you care to share with the class?

You should read what the professor wrote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866042479.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>I did. His conclusions are baked into his assumptions. There's no other outcome possible if you make the assumptions that he makes. And those assumptions are provably wrong. So his conclusion is wrong. It's also radically ahistorical, because in the last 200 years, there's been a lot of death because of political ideology, and not the conservative one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43866257351.0" user="uSeeSizeThatChicken" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I did. His conclusions are baked into his assumptions. There's no other outcome possible if you make the assumptions that he makes. And those assumptions are provably wrong. So his conclusion is wrong. It's also radically ahistorical, because in the last 200 years, there's been a lot of death because of political ideology, and not the conservative one.

You can't prove a single thing you just wrote. Not one thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
