<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743708201.0" user="Xanatos" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that republicans want to vote for Trump in particular.   They just want to vote for the republican candidate.   

Democrats behave the same way -- Biden is definitely not the best democrat for the job, but democrats will all vote for him anyway.

American politics is pure tribalism, on both sides.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743721644.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>So you're agreeing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743779141.0" user="Xanatos" delta="False">
    <text>Technically, yes, but I'm also pointing out that it's not just conservatives who do this, not by a long shot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743784194.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Ah OK</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744237451.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Ummm. Yup.

I will say though, any democratic candidate will experience the same republican base opposition.

However, an alternate republican candidate may actually grab votes from independents and democrats by simply dropping to emotional rage and campaigning on policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755482162.0" user="MarkNutt25" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, that explains the Republicans who "hold their noses and vote for Trump" in the general election. And there are certainly many of them. 

But look at the way the current primary election is going for them! *Anyone* on the candidate list would be a better poster-child for these supposed conservative values than Trump, yet he's winning the race by a landslide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755625154.0" user="-passionate-fruit-" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's not that republicans want to vote for Trump in particular.

Gambling oddsmakers have Trump as the heavy favorite to win the GOP primary, so Republican Americans wanting Trump in particular is exactly the case.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Democrats behave the same way -- Biden is definitely not the best democrat for the job, but democrats will all vote for him anyway.

[This is so not true](https://www.axios.com/2023/09/07/poll-biden-2024-second-term-democrat-voters-cnn) that you probably have to go back a long ways in history to find a poll suggesting that most Democrat voters didn't want an incumbent Democrat POTUS eligible for reelection to step down.  Though to be fair, you're correct in the instance he wins the primary (which is a virtual certainty considering the lack of elite Democrats even trying to primary him), but that's different.  

Circling back to MAGA support for Trump:  there's no equal on the left who's as morally bankrupt as Trump while getting anywhere near the support he does... and I don't think there's any politician in post Civil War American history who has.  There's no one on the left who's tried to usurp USA's basic institutions of democracy, using massive misinformation campaigns, to install or keep themselves in power, and still kept the good majority of their voter base supporting them.

Toxic tribalism is definitely an issue on the left, I agree with that sentiment, but Donald Trump's seeming hold on the right is very unique in American politics.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
