<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743387191.0" user="Far_Statement_2808" delta="False">
    <text>As a lifelong MA Republican (fiscal conservative, social libertarian) I have to laugh at the “conservatives” who fawn over Trump.  He is about as far as you can get from conservative values.  He loves debt.  He has no moral compass.  He pretends to love the military—and then almost every General comes out against him.

Trump is the epitome of a NY Republican.

It is maddening to see what he has done to this country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744271243.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Yep. And as someone who disagrees extremely with Trump, Biden isn't a very liberal candidate.

Trump is far far worse. But his existence is limiting our options on the left.

The best solution for all of us is to see a different repub candidate, so the left can stop playing it safe just to avoid a tyrant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755678808.0" user="-passionate-fruit-" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The best solution for all of us is to see a different repub candidate, so the left can stop playing it safe just to avoid a tyrant.

So I don't think a different candidate winning the GOP primary would affect Biden from winning the DNC primary, but it's a shame that there's no serious push by Democrat elites to replace Biden, considering polls show most Democrats would welcome it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756252968.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed, but I am not surprised. Giving up the incumbent advantage vs picking a more appealing candidate. Retaining the incumbent advantage is playing it safe. If democrats lost with an alternate candidate vs Trump, this would be the number one criticism. Alternately, if Biden loses vs Trump the number one criticism would be going with Biden again...

Ultimately, both parties are appealing to their bases fears and not their bases opinions on policy. Which is how we ended up here.

Vote in your primaries, and do so based on policy - not on emotions and ideologies. That's how we will see candidates with better approaches to policy from our representatives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756904084.0" user="-passionate-fruit-" delta="False">
    <text>I've studied election results predictors myself, and agree that incumbency is a historically-proven edge.  Two things on that.  One, a non-incumbent Democrat who manages to win the general will have the incumbency edge in 2028, on top of presumably being better skilled than Biden.

Secondly, a wildcard in all of this is the economy.  I've done a lot of research into economy direction predictors, and strongly suspect that we're in the midst of a slow-burn recession right now that's going to see unemployment tank a bit before it gets better (this generally would occur regardless of who was POTUS, due to a collection of factors).  

Normally, said imminent recession would spell doom for Democrats; one article wrote that an incumbent POTUS who experienced a recession in the second half of their term has never won reelection.  But... Democrats have been doing pretty well in recent special elections, whose vote margins compared to regional partisan lean is usually a good predictor of the next general election cycle (e.g. Dems ran between even to a few points behind their special election margins each of the last few cycles).  It's clear that reasons Dems overperformed last cycle, and the Trump legal prosecutions, are still affecting how people are voting.

I think what'll happen is if the recession goes deep, comparable to the GR, and assuming Trump's the GOP nominee, Republicans will probably win the general in another close one.  If the recession has definitely wrapped up and we're in a clear bull run during the last few months of the campaign cycle, Dems should pull it out.... if against Trump.  I think any other Republican candidate would win the general under either second half recession circumstance, but shh, don't tell them 🤫😊</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757073805.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with everything you said, but this next election has all sorts of moving variables we can't account for in predictions.

Will Trump's legal woes help or hurt him? Will the republican base feel like 2020 was apathetic on their end (similar to dems in 2016) and step up? Will dems become apathetic in 2024, or will they vote more, as well? Will the effects DeJoy has had on USPS play a role? How have the electoral maps changed? Does the dem party choose to swap in a wild card candidate near the election to throw off oppo campaigns/research. Do either of the old guys randomly kick the bucket? How well will each party be funded? Will Trumps name be removed from any ballots? Will Hunter/Joe legal challenges be brought by Republicans? How will each side play the inevitable shutdown, and how will that impact voting? Are any policies surrounding voting going to change on any level?

I can probably think of more... it really is just a wildcard election. And the stakes are way too high for gambling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770426967.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>Just wait until you see what hes done to your party, when all you can recruit are young Andrew Tate fans who want to get ahead and make money quickly.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
