<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="97" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43751781001.0" user="Salty_Map_9085" delta="False">
    <text>Many conservatives voted for Trump for the same reasons that leftists are told to vote for liberals. They significantly disagree with individual positions of the politician, but believe that having a person of their party in power, no matter who it is, will help them achieve their ideological goals. Just look at Trumps actually presidency, tons of wins for conservatives even if they didn’t like that he’s a divorcee or whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751885512.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>What are the key wins?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751893378.0" user="Salty_Map_9085" delta="False">
    <text>Supreme Court justices culminating in the overturn of Roe v Wade, tax cuts</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754285726.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Any Republican president would have had the chance to appoint three supreme court justices. I don't see why this makes Trump in particular look good.

I take your point about the tax cuts though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754728057.0" user="Salty_Map_9085" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t make Trump look good. It does demonstrate that republicans have a motivation for supporting Trump while still maintaining their value system. They simply believe that he is the most likely Republican candidate to win, and therefore the best way for them to achieve their political goals. Think of them like Bernie supporters who have come around to backing Biden.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755055366.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>But why Trump IN PARTICULAR is the question. There are other candidates who would also have appointed conservative judges. So I don't think it demonstrates what you're saying, at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756094786.0" user="Salty_Map_9085" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think it’s Trump in particular. I think that a lot of conservatives were like this for McCain, Bush, Reagan, etc. Trump is just the current figurehead of the party so they stand behind him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43758998330.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK but he's way out in front of the other candidates. Why?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
