<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743330953.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>*The way that leftists have got in line behind Biden shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.*

Family values: He's a known nepotist. Using his political connections to help out his son.  
Managerial competence: Cannot speak a complete sentence.  
Honest dealing: Used his status as Vice President to put pressure on businesses outside of America. Huge corpo buddy.  
Promises kept: Can he even remember his promises anymore?  
Decorum: I hate to beat a dead horse but again, getting lost mid thought.  
Democracy: "If you don't vote for me, you ain't black."  

Huh, it's almost like extremists are super tribal or something. I wonder which causes which. Is it their naturally tribal nature that causes them to be extremists, or is it their extremism that causes their tribal behavior? Or perhaps a third variable causing both. Either way, it has nothing to do with left/right political affiliation. 

Inb4 downvoted by extremists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743598626.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Family values: He's a known nepotist. Using his political connections to help out his son.

So why does the evidence keep getting lost? 

&gt;Managerial competence: Cannot speak a complete sentence.

And Trump is articulate? Please. Find me one screed on "Troth Senchal" without a litany of spelling and grammar mistakes. 

&gt;Honest dealing: Used his status as Vice President to put pressure on businesses outside of America. Huge corpo buddy.

Which ones?

&gt;Promises kept: Can he even remember his promises anymore?

Can Trump remember that we already won WWII? That he beat Hillary, not Obama?

&gt;Decorum: I hate to beat a dead horse but again, getting lost mid thought.

OK. We've done this one.

&gt;Democracy: "If you don't vote for me, you ain't black."

vs "If you don't vote for me, then you actually did and it's rigged." GTFO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743888449.0" user="PaxNova" delta="False">
    <text>They responded to your statement line-by-line like somebody would that just hated the left. His point was that a statement like that would be seen as laughable by somebody who supported Biden, and by the transitive property, your statement comes across as somebody that just hates the right. 

They were not trying to make a cogent statement about Biden. They were making a statement about how this line of thinking is already extremist, painting half the country as hatemongers (which makes it more justifiable to remove them from positions of power by any means necessary).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744022594.0" user="DrinkBlueGoo" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, when did the original post call anyone hatemongers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744071517.0" user="ScrumtrulescentOsman" delta="False">
    <text>Just another self admission.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744098347.0" user="PaxNova" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I used it as shorthand, as that's the stereotype the left has of the right: hateful, bigoted, backwards fascists. Conversely, the stereotype the right has of the left is: elites, ivory tower, disconnected socialists. 

When it comes to Trump, I generally agree with everything the left says about him. But I also know they've said the same about everyone else on the right, so I believe it based on my own evidence gathering, not trust in anything they'd say. Partly, this is because the silent majority stays silent, so it's just the more extreme element that bothers speaking up and calling itself the left in media.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744075656.0" user="ScrumtrulescentOsman" delta="False">
    <text>No one is painting half the country. Conservatives make up closer to 30%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744144564.0" user="PaxNova" delta="False">
    <text>Now add on people who don't declare themselves conservative, but vote for conservatives. If you're splitting it by solely conservatives, liberals are also in that ballpark, with the remaining third being independents. 

It's not accurate, but pragmatic, that when people are talking rhetoric they often conflate conservatives with Republicans. In the end, voting conservative matters more than being conservative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744504298.0" user="Clickclacktheblueguy" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t believe people didn’t catch what he was doing. Honestly I expected better from this sub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744646562.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone caught what he was doing. It was just an incredibly poor attempt at it, so it was easy to pick apart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745982044.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>No one even attempted to pick apart what I said because none of the negative replies even understood what I was saying. All I got was "Well, Trump is worse!" which is completely beside the point. The point is that Democrats are exactly the same as Republicans as both sides are tribalistic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746244683.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, yes, you're so centrist that you always have to go to bat for the right.

Yawn.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747232597.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744540566.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>The point they're making is obvious, it just doesn't work because they have to stretch so hard to make their whataboutism comparison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745950439.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>There was no whataboutism. That's something you do to support your side. My side isn't found in this conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746248195.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>Yawn</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747230721.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43751750245.0" user="disc_addict" delta="False">
    <text>🤡</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759998552.0" user="URthekindacrazyilike" delta="False">
    <text>Whataboutism is a very tribalistic term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760564857.0" user="oldtimo" delta="False">
    <text>Because only Republicans have to rely on it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760599196.0" user="URthekindacrazyilike" delta="False">
    <text>I see people from both sides use it in real life tbh. However, I’d say 99% of the time i see it on Reddit it used by left leaning people as a “gotcha” type comment. When i see right leaning people use it on Reddit it seems to be done to make fun of their counterparts. I also know it was left leaning people who popularized it when John Oliver famously did a whole segment on it in 2016.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760606127.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760606229.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/oldtimo – your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. Comments that are only jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744935013.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>If you're arguing that their post was intended as parody, then maybe you're right, but if so then it completely fails, because the two sides are not remotely comparable. The "both sides" trope has aged extremely badly in the era of Trump.  It's not extremist to think that Trump is a clown, and a dangerous one at that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744333315.0" user="sleezysneez" delta="False">
    <text>Fell right into the trap huh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745046190.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>No, see my other reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43752997377.0" user="InTheEndEntropyWins" delta="False">
    <text>You know what, the Republicans have exactly the same kind of half baked rebuttals to your original post.  

The point is you and these Republicans are almost exactly the same, you've just on different sides.

Once you understand yourself, you'll understand these idiot Republicans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754107032.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I am sorry but this is more "both sides" nonsense. Other people have tried that same approach numerous times on this post and it always falls apart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754270015.0" user="InTheEndEntropyWins" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I am sorry but this is more "both sides" nonsense.

You are missing the whole point. 

But I wouldn't expect a 70 IQ redneck, trump voting anti vaxer to understand. 

But like I said 

&gt;Once you understand yourself, you'll understand these idiot Republicans.

So maybe it was too much to expect you to understand basic logic and reasoning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43754351788.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>No, YOU are missing that your analogy breaks down because the two sides are not comparable. You might well disagree but you don't have the monopoly on "basic logic and reasoning", unfortunately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43756857863.0" user="HunterMaria" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that you think that both sides are not comparable is because you are an extremist on one side, if nobody else will give you this reality check, then I’m doing it now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43758990073.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's because one side IS extreme and the other isn't. Simply *asserting* the contrary isn't giving anyone a "reality check". The argument has to be better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759413062.0" user="HunterMaria" delta="False">
    <text>It’s pretty clear and obvious dude. I saw some of your other comments down the line from here and you are fucked in the head from too much Reddit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761261270.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>If it's so clear and obvious, what's preventing you from making it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43764922070.0" user="HunterMaria" delta="False">
    <text>I did make it, go touch grass, take your blinders off and reread what you wrote. Ask your parents or read what you wrote and ask them if that sounds like something a healthy normal human would write. The reactions of horror should be telling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43767396477.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, you made it so well that you're comment got removed for breaking the sub rules. Perhaps you should be taking your own blinders off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43761336403.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/HunterMaria – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20HunterMaria&amp;message=HunterMaria%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/-/k3p837q/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760624072.0" user="LucidLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>u/InTheEndEntropyWins – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20InTheEndEntropyWins&amp;message=InTheEndEntropyWins%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/-/k3m5utb/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755051300.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;"both sides" nonsense

It is both sides though. And that's being *really* generous to Democrats, because Biden is far worse a Democrat than Trump is a Republican. Democrats are able to do *far* better than Biden. There are *actually good* Democratic candidates.

Trump is actually above average for a Republican. Far further left than many of the Republicans running for president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755808628.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It is both sides though. 

Only one side is making is more difficult to vote. Onle one side is undermining the legitimacy of the democratic process. Only one side is calling for their opponents to be locked up and **killed**.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762682995.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>Only one side is trying to get illegals to vote. Only one said is refusing to go to presidential debates.

&gt;Only one side is calling for their opponents to be locked up and killed.

Definitely both sides here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763859287.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK, well then find me where Biden or indeed any senior Dem has said this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783315308.0" user="JakeWasAlreadyTaken" delta="False">
    <text>[Here’s all your evidence.](https://media.marcopolousa.org/pdf/Report.pdf#page200) Have a look through this document and tell me in good faith that his family isn’t a complete disgrace</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783528804.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>That report, and its author, are a joke.

If Ziegler has such great evidence, let's see him present it in court. Or Congress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43888919004.0" user="JakeWasAlreadyTaken" delta="False">
    <text>Can you say the same about this? Eventually, you gotta realize your guy isn’t the shining pony you think he is.

https://oversight.house.gov/release/comer-releases-evidence-of-direct-payment-to-joe-biden/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43890253259.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Dude this is truly pathetic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743986253.0" user="Cyberpunk2077isTrash" delta="False">
    <text>Love how you got an idea for a comeback but couldn't actually execute it so instead you just kept saying he was old.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744001188.0" user="ratbastid" delta="False">
    <text>You may or my not believe this, but I'm telling you: your experience of Biden's speaking ability is filtered through partisan media. Have you ever actually watched him give an entire speech? Or just clips that make him look bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744917696.0" user="ICallFireStaff" delta="False">
    <text>*Watches Lebron James worsts plays compilation* “oh wow this dude sucks at basketball”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781510868.0" user="Obi-Brawn-Kenobi" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, Biden is to speaking as LeBron is to playing basketball LMAO

Not a fan of either, but anyone has to admit Lebron is good at basketball</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746059702.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>It may be a bit of an exaggeration, but also, there shouldn't be DOZENS of examples of him being unable to speak. Isn't it the left complaining of old white guys in Washington DC? And they voted for the oldest, whitest one...

It's still an excellent example of how absolutely awful he is as a Democrat. It's funny because as a kid even, I would have pointed out his corporate ass as a Republican. Now I understand how much they both love corporations. But to me, corporations and Republicans have always gone hand-in-hand. So it's not hypocritical of Republicans to vote for a corpo. I'm probably being too hard on the Dems and they've always been just as trashy. I should stop holding them to a higher standard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744220002.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Family values: He's a known nepotist. Using his political connections to help out his son.

Worse with Trump and kids. They literally were brought on to his admin. This is an incredible double standard.

&gt;Managerial competence: Cannot speak a complete sentence.

Also worse with Trump. Double standard.

&gt;Honest dealing: Used his status as Vice President to put pressure on businesses outside of America. Huge corpo buddy.

Also worse with Trump, double standard.

&gt;Promises kept: Can he even remember his promises anymore?

Student loans? Certainly more kept than Trump... walls, etc.

&gt;Decorum: I hate to beat a dead horse but again, getting lost mid thought.

Getting lost in thought is not decorum, Trump gets lost more, and has wayyy worse decorum...

&gt;Democracy: "If you don't vote for me, you ain't black." 

Very different than intimidate people at polls, stop mail in voting, J6, etc.

This demonstrates OPs point. There is no consistent moral foundation to be found here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745923533.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Worse with Trump and kids. They literally were brought on to his admin. This is an incredible double standard.

No it's not. Nepotism is explicitly against Leftist values. That makes support for Joe hypocritical.

&gt;Also worse with Trump.

Trump talks just fine. As fine as anyone. He's a fine talker.

&gt;Also worse with Trump. Also Trump. Trump Trump Trump. 

Really doesn't matter. My point has nothing at all to do with Trump nor conservatives. OP already made that point. My points is that extremists on both sides do what OP described.

&gt;There is no consistent moral foundation to be found here.

That is exactly what I was saying. Extremists have zero moral foundation. It's not just the conservative extremists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745961465.0" user="bunkSauce" delta="False">
    <text>💀</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763274013.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43781696572.0" user="cokronk" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; "Look, having nuclear — my uncle was a great professor and scientist and engineer, Dr. John Trump at MIT; good genes, very good genes, OK, very smart, the Wharton School of Finance, very good, very smart — you know, if you’re a conservative Republican, if I were a liberal, if, like, OK, if I ran as a liberal Democrat, they would say I'm one of the smartest people anywhere in the world — it’s true! — but when you're a conservative Republican they try — oh, do they do a number — that’s why I always start off: Went to Wharton, was a good student, went there, went there, did this, built a fortune — you know I have to give my like credentials all the time, because we’re a little disadvantaged — but you look at the nuclear deal, the thing that really bothers me — it would have been so easy, and it’s not as important as these lives are — nuclear is so powerful; my uncle explained that to me many, many years ago, the power and that was 35 years ago; he would explain the power of what's going to happen and he was right, who would have thought? — but when you look at what's going on with the four prisoners — now it used to be three, now it’s four — but when it was three and even now, I would have said it's all in the messenger; fellas, and it is fellas because, you know, they don't, they haven’t figured that the women are smarter right now than the men, so, you know, it’s gonna take them about another 150 years — but the Persians are great negotiators, the Iranians are great negotiators, so, and they, they just killed, they just killed us, this is horrible."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43759976276.0" user="URthekindacrazyilike" delta="False">
    <text>You had to bring up walls, lmao.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43744574561.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Family values: He's a known nepotist. Using his political connections to help out his son.

How is that NOT supporting his family?

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Managerial competence: Cannot speak a complete sentence.

He's probably a terrible tango dancer. Neither of which has anything to do with his management ability.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Honest dealing: Used his status as Vice President to put pressure on businesses outside of America. Huge corpo buddy.

Furthering American interests overseas is literally part of the job.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Promises kept: Can he even remember his promises anymore?

Can you?

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Decorum: I hate to beat a dead horse but again, getting lost mid thought.

And?

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Democracy: "If you don't vote for me, you ain't black."

Encouraging people to vote is anti-democracy now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745564774.0" user="leafs456" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; How is that NOT supporting his family?

So should Trump be applauded for advancing Ivanka and Trump Jr.'s career by appointing them to government positions during his presidency?

Supporting family, eh?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43746499902.0" user="TeekTheReddit" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody said it should be applauded.

Dude was complaining about Biden's apparent lack of family values, which in that context, nepotism is neutral at worst.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745091693.0" user="Haytaytay" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Family values: He's a known nepotist. Using his political connections to help out his son.

Trump filled the White House with his severely under-qualified family. Infinitely worse.  


&gt;Honest dealing: Used his status as Vice President to put pressure on businesses outside of America. Huge corpo buddy.

He's the most pro-union, pro-worker president of our time. Literally the first sitting president in history to join strikers on the picket line.   


&gt;Managerial competence: Cannot speak a complete sentence.  
&gt;  
&gt;Promises kept: Can he even remember his promises anymore?  
Decorum: I hate to beat a dead horse but again, getting lost mid thought.

Couldn't think of any actual examples so you just keep saying "he's old" repeatedly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43755245509.0" user="MOUNCEYG1" delta="False">
    <text>On managerial competence, his speaking ability isnt relevant to this. Do you know what does? his phenomenal legislative record during this administration.

Honest dealing: There is no evidence of this

Democracy: Yes the classic mispeak you've been harping on about suddenly isnt a misspeak when its convenient. Also if thats what he meant that isn't even on democracy, its racist. 

Biden is not extremist lol. The left extremists of the world complain that hes not even a lefty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762740553.0" user="felidaekamiguru" delta="False">
    <text>He used to have competence in dealing with others. He's old now.

&gt;There is no evidence of this

Yeah OK. If you're this willingly ignorant, I've got nothing to say.

&gt;Also if thats what he meant that isn't even on democracy, its racist.

It's trying to pressure people into voting a certain way. It's a stretch, but I don't need 100% alignment to make a point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762782118.0" user="MOUNCEYG1" delta="False">
    <text>But his current administration right now has been extremely impressive legislatively not just in the past.

There’s evidence hunter Biden used his status as VP without Joes knowledge.

Isn’t that the whole job of a politician in democracy lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43803099905.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43757190641.0" user="Halorym" delta="False">
    <text>Downvoted by those that read the subreddit's name.  You're spewing supporting arguments to OP's premise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43758010235.0" user="jawshoeaw" delta="False">
    <text>What was the alternative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770937260.0" user="TearsoftheCum" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;inb4 downvoted by extremist

All you need to know about someone who is unwilling to have a conversation and change their own view.

Someone who is deep in the kool-aid and only here to antagonize not rationalize.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43783294630.0" user="JakeWasAlreadyTaken" delta="False">
    <text>Best reply in this thread</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
