<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="103" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43752613400.0" user="JimMarch" delta="False">
    <text>There's two issues that Trump "won" on even though he's disgusting in both.

Let's start with guns. For decades Trump bribed members of the New York Police Department for access to NYC-specific handgun carry permits at a time when they were extremely rare.  Most of those years the numbers were measured in hundreds except for judges, district attorneys and a few others.  This seriously pissed off a lot of gun nuts like me and still does, and I think it shows his general corruption.

However, the US Supreme Court justices that he picked finally solved this problem in 2022 in the case of New York State Rifle and Pistol Association v Bruen.  That decision caused a whole lot of gun folk to decide that he's still a better choice than Biden.

The abortion decision that same year did exactly the same thing for the radical Evangelical Christian community in the US.  Yet again, his US Supreme Court picks changed the entire game.

Without those two decisions he'd have no chance whatsoever in a 2024 matchup with Biden.  None.  But with them?  Yeah.  He actually does.

Especially since Biden is being dragged down by his son into a miasma of weird overseas corruption, hookers, blow and all kinds of weird shit.  "10% for the big guy" is being used by voters predisposed to vote right to ignore Trump's obvious corruption by saying "they're both sketchy".

**Personally, I think Trump is one hell of a lot more corrupt than Biden.**</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
