<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743074115.0" user="contrarian1970" delta="False">
    <text>Bushes and Clintons showing up on the ballot over and over again is how Trump got elected in 2016.  Americans are so terrified of establishment uniparty candidates being forced down their throats by the media that they will vote for ANY flawed candidate who breaks this authoritarian cycle.  There was a sense that John McCain and and Mitt Romney were COMPLETELY controlled by the establishment uniparty.  There is also a desperation for ANY candidate who supports the second amendment and border security.  Most of the people in both parties give them lip service but are more than happy to forget both the moment they win another election.  America is in greater danger than ever of becoming like a 1930's Germany or a 1950's Stalin regime with no balance of power at all.  The mainstream media has become the enemy of the people.  Trump is simply the ONLY alternative to the uniparty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743457999.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain how? In what way is he doing something different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43762845069.0" user="AloysiusC" delta="False">
    <text>You can tell by how the establishment is desperately trying to destroy him at all cost. They don't care what principles they have to abandon so long as they can stick it to Trump. It really is a witch hunt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745838489.0" user="AmongTheElect" delta="False">
    <text>I was curious in this anti-Republican post just how far I'd have to scroll down to see a top-level comment which wasn't also anti-Republican.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747372687.0" user="Minister_for_Magic" delta="False">
    <text>really? Because these same people were campaigning for a new Trump royal family.

These claims never hold up to deeper scrutiny</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43747654661.0" user="TrishPanda18" delta="False">
    <text>I agree on it potentially falling into a 30s Germany situation but the broader left has been dead in the US for decades, there is absolutely 0 chance of a marxist-leninist vanguard party seizing control of the state apparatus</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43753231117.0" user="Arndt3002" delta="False">
    <text>I think their appeal to 1930s or 1950s isn't in terms of Leninism of Fascism, but rather the fear of authoritarianism more broadly, particularly by the influence of corporate bureaucrats and the perceived government overreach of gun control.

Also, with COVID, my guess is that some people saw it as something imposed by the government, which makes it seems like they would have control to singlehandedly force a comparable shutdown for political dissent.

And part of it is just that government overreach and corporate interests are a really easy target to latch onto. It's like how "alternative medicine" nonsense can easily be sold by just leading with the idea that "Big Pharma doesn't want you to know about this." As long as you tie your craziness as being opposed to a widely agreed upon nebulous evil and, such government overreach controlled by special interests, then people will eat that right up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749474019.0" user="Unable-Finance-2099" delta="False">
    <text>What the fuck are you talking about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43760886611.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**.  

Comments should be on-topic, serious, and contain enough content to move the discussion forward. Jokes, contradictions without explanation, links without context, off-topic comments, and "written upvotes" will be removed. Read [the wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5) for more information.  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%205%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763232427.0" user="flag_ua" delta="False">
    <text>This just in: Supporter of man who gave family members very lucrative cabinet positions complains about nepotism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763266224.0" user="contrarian1970" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you are talking about a single elected official allowing a single relative to work as an aide of some sort.  I am talking about a vast machine of corporate donors who use the mainstream media and big tech to prop up the candidate they have the most control of before the election and ignore the candidate they have the least control of.  The Clintons and Bushes became giant machines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43763326469.0" user="flag_ua" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, I’m not and you’re putting words in my mouth. Ivanka Trump and Jared Kushner were senior members of the administration. The same Jared Kushner that secured a 2 billion dollar investment from the Saudis after leaving office. That is the real “corruption” that conservatives love to ignore.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
