<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="110" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43753559110.0" user="SLUnatic85" delta="False">
    <text>Without getting into the weeds, you are blatantly ignoring the "*gets things done that he promises the people*" bullet point, which for many rests well above morality or even general personal behavior when voting for a president... for many people in ALL parties. It's not just about "*beating the other tribe*" but creating action and momentum toward change that benefits the people (*people being you*). 

Trump also very much promotes "*beating the other tribe*", I am not saying you are wrong there. That's just not the bullet point you forgot.   


I am not saying that Trump is a prime example of someone who gets great things done. Not at all. But to those voters you ar pointing at, he is specifically picking issues that get them riled up or emotionally involved, and then doing what he says he would do (*appearing as if standing up for his base*), even if by bending morality (*reality?*) quite a bit:

* Roe. v. Wade
* the Wall (ie. spotlight on immigration)
* removing EPA regulations put on industry
* storming the capital
* getting new SC justices on board
* making sure people don't need to ever wear masks or pay any mind decent medical advice
* making people who previously didn't understand politics and global relations (*and still don't*) feel good about themselves

Even if I don't like any of those kept promises, you can't tell me he doesn't get shit done for his base.  Or at least appears as if he is working hard to push his agenda through literally any resistance.   


In your OP, you are just saying that Trump is overall pretty shady (*and he really is*), in like 8 different ways.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
