<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="43" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43744464138.0" user="SingleMaltMouthwash" delta="False">
    <text>They do have beliefs:

\~ They believe that they are victims and that all their failures are the fault of someone else. Usually someone darker and/or of another faith. They believe that all their dreams will come true if they can just expel or kill enough of these people. 

\~ They believe the government should do nothing and help no one. They will believe it right up until their toilet stops flushing and their welfare check stops arriving at which point they will blame someone darker for ruining the plumbing and the mail. 

\~ They believe Jesus wants them to curb-stomp people who annoy them. They believe the bible is a manifesto on the superiority of white people and the evils of government. 

\~ They believe that anything benefiting them is good and anything benefitting anyone else is bad. Why should women get maternity leave and not men? Why should women get free pelvic exams and not men? Why should women be able to refuse sexual advances if it means saying no to them? They are invariably shocked to find that their interpretation of the Second Amendment allows black people to carry firearms too.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
