<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="56" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43745803094.0" user="TheLazyScarecrow" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who strongly dislikes ***both*** political parties, and think they are ***both*** tearing our country apart, with little interest for the true good of the American People, (whatever that even is at this point) I do think it worth noting somewhere in this chain that you can just flip the message, and it carries the same truth of tribalism:  


CMV: the way that liberals have got in line behind Biden shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.

&amp;#x200B;

I am by no means a Trump guy, and have never voted for him, but from what I've observed with my limited smoothbrain eyes, is that half the country jumped behind an incompetent geriatric racist because they felt the other option was an incompetent racist asshole. **The sad truth is that most people vote for who their parents told them to growing up, and do very little critical thinking on the matter**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745851214.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>I just don't think that "both sides" is a very good analysis here. One leader has talked about imprisoning and **killing** his opponents and critics. The other hasn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770478801.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>bOtH sIdEs is not an analysis at all - OP is being nice to you. Put your actual comparisons on the table so we can critique you properly like a real man</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43933934094.0" user="TheLazyScarecrow" delta="False">
    <text>Lol i’ll be honest lil dude - I thought about doing it respectfully in response to OP’s response, but figured he and I both would be happier if we didn’t do that. I hope your day is going well, and stays that way. Neither side keeps their promises, both sides are dangerous. 

I appreciate your highly intellectual response, though. It really was a positive add to the thread lmao</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
