<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43743724376.0" user="ragepuppy" delta="False">
    <text>It could be that they don't really value the principles that you listed and are just paying lip service, that's a possibility alright. Could also be that they prioritise some principles more than others under certain conditions.

For example, conservatives may reject the last few decades of GOP faux-libertarians and obstructionists in Congress who are committed to only "reducing spending", or other inscrutable goals, and fundamentally believe that their job is to be British Tories who prevent government from working and complain about how government doesn't work.

Democrats and the left leverage political power when they have electoral success. I know more than a few conservatives who look at that and then are so fed up with their McConnell type of representation that they're willing to put aside concerns about Trump's obvious deficiencies in integrity, honesty, decorum, and respect for (his) family so that he can smash all the norms, bureaucratic give and take, and legacy of doing politics in the US.

It makes sense, if you think about it. The libertarian strain isnt totally gone. They tend to believe that creation and support of a family is a duty that *one* has to fulfill themselves. A given conservative wants their politicians to either remove obstacles create and maintain the conditions needed *for them and their community* to raise families in, not necessarily to legislate that obligation onto everyone elses plate (though theres plenty of exceptions.) They could just see Trump as a shitty person who will, otherwise, further their interests in the long run.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43770467515.0" user="Greedy_Emu9352" delta="False">
    <text>Hyperindividualists decrying others needing material help for aquiring, maintaining, and feeding a household is the main threat to traditional families continuing to exist. We used to have communities and wide family networks. Now we are treated like cattle, to be milked for cash and left to our own devices without a paddle otherwise. Its a fact of survival that young workers will go childfree and join a childfree household of workers just to save up a little cash so that one day, they can achieve that elusive American dream. 

Always cracks me up when a con mentions the death of the traditional family lol</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
