<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="261258033.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4bjnzl/cmv_south_florida_is_an_area_that_is_as_socially/">
    <title>CMV: South Florida is an area that is as socially diverse and isolated at the same time</title>
    <original_poster>B0pp0</original_poster>
    <original_post>Earlier today, I was watching history unfold with the exhibition between the Tampa Bay Rays and the Cuban National Team in Havana with US President Obama in attendance. While seeing much of the pagantry unfold this morning while working out, I saw the [dissenting view of Miami-based ESPN pundit Dan LeBatard, himself the child of a mother who escaped the early years of the current regime]
(http://espn.go.com/mlb/story/_/id/15032737/historic-game-cuba-ignores-pain-many-people-endured) and while I respect and to a point disagree with his opinion on this matter I realized something else.

South Florida is one of the most diverse areas of the US if not the world while serving as a gateway to the Caribbean. As a part of the US itself, it seems a bit cut off from the rest of the US. The area has a very large transplant population, both foreign and domestic, which coupled with Florida having boomed only in the last 75 or so years means that entrenched local culture doesn't exist. Also, many transplants see Miami as a way station to make money, ride out some storm, or both and see it as not home even generations after their family arrived. Those that do settle fall victim to geography since being  at the end of a peninsula with favorable weather year round doesn't afford itself to transplants on a domestic level. The jokes a friend who grew up in Broward County would make about South Floridians rarely making it north were frequent.

On the political tangent it can be seen in the long, long process to the Cuban Thaw as exiles out of the Miami area, guided by a favorable political situation in a swing state, seemed to have little awareness of the views of the nation north of West Palm Beach or so with even the North Jersey exile bloc being a bit more amenable. On a lighter note, it can be seen in the struggles of Miami area sports teams which are often seen as "having no fans" due to poor attendance at home and few fans traveling as well as the "we only support winners" culture there. I know weather and traffic play a role and ownerships often have been weak, but there seems to be something about fandom there people don't get.

I might be rambling and I know other areas fit into this criteria, but I can't be alone in thinking that as a part of the US South Florida is an oddball, yes?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28379226465.0" user="islamabob2" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, I've been living in South Florida for almost 20 years (Boca Raton) and can attest to a lot of what you're saying, but not everything. Tbh, you are kind of rambling so if I'm not directly answering your question I hope you'll understand. 

South Florida is definitely a unique part of the country. Though Florida is a southern state, you would *never* consider it as such looking at SF, especially the Miami Metropolitan Area. The vast majority of people living here are either from other parts of the country (born in the mid west myself) or world. The ones who were born here are sure to have immediate family who weren't. Most the the Americans here are either from NY/New England and the immigrants are from South/Central Americas and the Caribbean. Boca itself is, as a friend of mine aptly put it, "where people move to when they've made it in life". It's where Mr. and Mrs. Goldfarb go when they have finally saved up enough money so they can sell their house in Long Island and move to sunny Florida, where it never snows! It certainly means something totally different when I say that I'm from the South vs. someone from Mobile saying it.

It's certainly diverse, but isolated?

&amp;gt; the Cuban Thaw as exiles out of the Miami area, guided by a favorable political situation in a swing state, seemed to have little awareness of the views of the nation north of West Palm Beach...

Well, that depends on how you think the rest of the nations sees the Cuban Thaw. Are you saying that rest of the Nation sees this as a good thing while people in WPB downward hate it, mostly due to the Cuban exiles? I'd like to say that the nation is still pretty split on it, Cuban exiles withstanding, it's just that their opinion takes precedence, and rightfully so in some ways. IMO I love the idea of the thaw, but I feel that a lot of people would hate it based on the fact alone that Obama is spearheading the effort. I can't really speak for sports as I don't follow them myself.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
