<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2615080682.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/178y962/cmv_taylor_swift_is_the_best_artist_of_the_21st/">
    <title>CMV: Taylor Swift is the best artist of the 21st century and is on track to become the best artist of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>DesperateForYourDick</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.

Taylor Swift is a cultural phenomenon. Yes, her music is stereotypical “basic white girl music” (which is a problematic belief that many hold that I won’t get into here), but way too many people deny that she’s an all-time great just to be controversial, quirky, different, etc.

[Here is a quick list of her awards](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_awards_and_nominations_received_by_Taylor_Swift)

In addition to those, she has been on top of Billboard Artist 100 for **81 weeks**. She is the only artist to take up **every single spot** on the Billboard Hot 100 at the same time. She has multiple songs (Love Story, You Belong With Me, Shake it Off, We Are Never Getting Back Together) that have stood the test of time for a decade and will likely be classics at least on the level of songs like Hey Jude, or even We Will Rock You.

Furthermore, the Eras Tour is arguably already the most famous concert tour ever. Going by current numbers it will absolutely demolish the record for highest grossing concert tour, which was set by Elton John’s Farewell Yellow Brick Road. And it’ll do so with just 1/3 the number of concerts.

Just look at the NFL. Their Twitter account changed their profile picture, bio, and banner just because Taylor Swift showed up to a Chiefs game. To have that level of influence over the most popular sports league in the United States is insane.

Yes, I’m a big fan of her work. But even objectively speaking, I don’t see how anyone can deny that, when she does retire, she will be one of the greatest artists to ever live, just in terms of objective popularity.

And just to directly address the claims made in my title—I for one cannot name any artist with more name recognition in the 20th century. “Taylor Swift” is, at this point, used as the default name-drop for “stereotypically popular singer”. And her current level of popularity/fame is on par with any great artist (say, for example, the Beatles or Michael Jackson) at their peak, which is why I think she has a shot at becoming #1 all time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43842774416.0" user="Captain231705" delta="False">
    <text>It comes across as somewhat simplistic to call the race for the entire century less than a quarter in. Barring some catastrophe, the world’s population will continue growing for most of it, and you’ll be hard-pressed to find many people who *still* like Taylor’s songs 20 years down the line.

As far as name recognition goes, I’d say the Beatles come pretty close, and have her beat on staying power (almost by definition since they were a thing before she was born). Ditto for Michael Jackson, Beyoncé, Madonna, Queen, Elvis… and that’s just 20th-century artists. 

Go back further and you’ll see dozens of classical composers who are still remembered and performed hundreds of years after their death, with their names being synonymous with success and musical immortality. The only reason they don’t have as many accolades as Taylor Swift is because those awards didn’t exist at the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842789386.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It comes across as somewhat simplistic to call the race for the entire century less than a quarter in. 

I should clarify that I mean she’s the most popular, *so far*.

And yes, there are many artists who are arguably more popular than her, but I would argue that it’s because 1) they’ve stood the test of time, making people more aware of their lasting legacy, whereas she hasn’t had the opportunity to, and 2) her career is far from over, hence why I said she’s “on track” to becoming the most popular artist of all time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842805388.0" user="Captain231705" delta="False">
    <text>In order for her to become the best of all time by your metric, she’ll have to both outshine and outlast those artists you mentioned in point one. Which… seems unlikely. She very well could end up the most dominant artist of the decade, possibly even the century, but because of the already existing stuff competition, “best of all time” may be out of reach. We just don’t know, and won’t know, for a pretty long time to come.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842826854.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I agree on that. And I’m not saying that we will. All I’m saying is that she’s the most popular and famous artist, so far, of the 21st century and I think that, based on how she’s doing, she’ll have a case for most popular all time by the time she’s done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843129186.0" user="Captain231705" delta="False">
    <text>There’s also an important caveat to be had here: she’s the most popular artist so far *among white American women*. Most any other demographic you can find artists more popular than her.

As for absolute numbers:

[Statista says](https://www.statista.com/statistics/271174/top-selling-artists-in-the-united-states/) the Beatles take the crown.

[Wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_best-selling_music_artists) has her at #12 all-time by confirmed unit sales

[Ranker says](https://www.ranker.com/list/most-popular-musical-artists-of-the-21st-century/gookin) Beyoncé outranks her for the 21st century.

[Chartmasters](https://chartmasters.org/most-successful-artists-by-decade/) has her outranked by BTS for the 2020s and by Adele and Justin Bieber for the 2010s, the only times she’s on the chart.

Have I changed your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843487883.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP but

* the "chartmasters" proves she's the most popular artists of 21th century since unlike Adele, Bieber or BTS, she's in the ranking in 00's, 10's and 20's 

* "Ranker" is just an online survey with a few thousands vote

* Wikipedia chart shows she's the only artist who began career in the 00's to reach the 200 millions album milestone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845411605.0" user="Captain231705" delta="False">
    <text>Gonna nitpick your comment a little bit:

- The chartmasters ranking listing Taylor for three decades doesn’t prove she’s the most popular, only that she’s got the most staying power. That’s important, but it’s not the silver bullet you seem to think it is.
- Ranker was included in my comment for variety’s sake, and random sampling surveys are a valid form of data, even if not the most scientifically weighty.
- Wikipedia’s distinction is also important, but, as you’re already arguing that staying power is what’s important in point 1 (chartmasters), you don’t get to both-sides the argument here. If anything, her being the only one to start in 2000s and reach 200m should be a *detriment* by your logic, since there’s other artists who started earlier and had more records sold.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43846746401.0" user="Galious" delta="False">
    <text>My bad I didn't read that in the comment you answered to, OP tried to argue that she was on the road for being best of all time and thought we were only talking of the 21th century.

Because yes I think that Taylor Swift is the most successful of the 21th century but obviously not of all time (though it's hard to really compare different eras)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843936200.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; there are many artists who are arguably more popular than her

Then she's not the "best" (according to your definition)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
