<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2615080682.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/178y962/cmv_taylor_swift_is_the_best_artist_of_the_21st/">
    <title>CMV: Taylor Swift is the best artist of the 21st century and is on track to become the best artist of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>DesperateForYourDick</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.

Taylor Swift is a cultural phenomenon. Yes, her music is stereotypical “basic white girl music” (which is a problematic belief that many hold that I won’t get into here), but way too many people deny that she’s an all-time great just to be controversial, quirky, different, etc.

[Here is a quick list of her awards](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_awards_and_nominations_received_by_Taylor_Swift)

In addition to those, she has been on top of Billboard Artist 100 for **81 weeks**. She is the only artist to take up **every single spot** on the Billboard Hot 100 at the same time. She has multiple songs (Love Story, You Belong With Me, Shake it Off, We Are Never Getting Back Together) that have stood the test of time for a decade and will likely be classics at least on the level of songs like Hey Jude, or even We Will Rock You.

Furthermore, the Eras Tour is arguably already the most famous concert tour ever. Going by current numbers it will absolutely demolish the record for highest grossing concert tour, which was set by Elton John’s Farewell Yellow Brick Road. And it’ll do so with just 1/3 the number of concerts.

Just look at the NFL. Their Twitter account changed their profile picture, bio, and banner just because Taylor Swift showed up to a Chiefs game. To have that level of influence over the most popular sports league in the United States is insane.

Yes, I’m a big fan of her work. But even objectively speaking, I don’t see how anyone can deny that, when she does retire, she will be one of the greatest artists to ever live, just in terms of objective popularity.

And just to directly address the claims made in my title—I for one cannot name any artist with more name recognition in the 20th century. “Taylor Swift” is, at this point, used as the default name-drop for “stereotypically popular singer”. And her current level of popularity/fame is on par with any great artist (say, for example, the Beatles or Michael Jackson) at their peak, which is why I think she has a shot at becoming #1 all time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43845403407.0" user="PicardTangoAlpha" delta="False">
    <text>*I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.*

In that case you have completely negated your own argument and the use of the word "best".

You could have said "most successful" or "biggest selling" or any number of statistical superlatives, but instead you have wandered into the subjective and even argued against yourself, while continuing to argue in favour of your post.  

Others are pointing this out as well and you are ignoring them by not awarding Deltas.  

Are you being an edgelord by choosing the most musically vapid and empty headed artist you could possibly think of in order to gain clicks?   I mean you could find another monosyllabic, three-note, two-chord wonderkind stuck in permanent adolescence if you try really hard, but I don't think you would find one to beat her.

Don't you think there is anything odd about a thirty year old woman continuing to court and cater to an audience of twelve year olds?  Doesn't this strike you as a little odd, repetitive, embarrassing, while all the while she tries to pass herself off as a said twelve year old in dress, behaviour, vocabulary and facial expression?

Maybe she just can't help it?

Other childhood stars move on, grow up, get a life, break out, act out, maybe even swear, drink, get risqué, evolve, rebel, and eventually resolve into functional adulthood.  Miley Cyrus, Shirley Temple, Daniel Radcliffe, Fred Savage, Levar Burton, Elizabeth Taylor, Ricky Nelson, Curt Russel, Brooke Shields, Jodie Foster.....some had or have issues but *being adults* wasn't one of their hangups.  

Taylor Swift seems uniquely frozen in prepubescent identity syndrome.  

Or maybe it's a cynical and rather annoying marketing ploy.

Are you prepared to reconsider her elevation to sainthood in light of this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43846218379.0" user="Itchy_Egg9279" delta="False">
    <text>"Hey kids! Spelling is fun!" - T. Swift lyrics.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
