<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2615080682.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/178y962/cmv_taylor_swift_is_the_best_artist_of_the_21st/">
    <title>CMV: Taylor Swift is the best artist of the 21st century and is on track to become the best artist of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>DesperateForYourDick</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.

Taylor Swift is a cultural phenomenon. Yes, her music is stereotypical “basic white girl music” (which is a problematic belief that many hold that I won’t get into here), but way too many people deny that she’s an all-time great just to be controversial, quirky, different, etc.

[Here is a quick list of her awards](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_awards_and_nominations_received_by_Taylor_Swift)

In addition to those, she has been on top of Billboard Artist 100 for **81 weeks**. She is the only artist to take up **every single spot** on the Billboard Hot 100 at the same time. She has multiple songs (Love Story, You Belong With Me, Shake it Off, We Are Never Getting Back Together) that have stood the test of time for a decade and will likely be classics at least on the level of songs like Hey Jude, or even We Will Rock You.

Furthermore, the Eras Tour is arguably already the most famous concert tour ever. Going by current numbers it will absolutely demolish the record for highest grossing concert tour, which was set by Elton John’s Farewell Yellow Brick Road. And it’ll do so with just 1/3 the number of concerts.

Just look at the NFL. Their Twitter account changed their profile picture, bio, and banner just because Taylor Swift showed up to a Chiefs game. To have that level of influence over the most popular sports league in the United States is insane.

Yes, I’m a big fan of her work. But even objectively speaking, I don’t see how anyone can deny that, when she does retire, she will be one of the greatest artists to ever live, just in terms of objective popularity.

And just to directly address the claims made in my title—I for one cannot name any artist with more name recognition in the 20th century. “Taylor Swift” is, at this point, used as the default name-drop for “stereotypically popular singer”. And her current level of popularity/fame is on par with any great artist (say, for example, the Beatles or Michael Jackson) at their peak, which is why I think she has a shot at becoming #1 all time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43842835333.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>Your opening remark says you are not concerned with the quality of her art. Rather, you are concerned with fame and popularity.

Given the label artist relates to art and celebrity to the characteristics you are focused on, I would say that you are actually arguing for her being the biggest celebrity and not the best artist.

Imagine I said Dr. Whoever is the greatest doctor because of their celebrity status. I could even acknowledge that the quality of the care they provide to patients is irrelevant in making this claim. It would clear I was judging celebrity rather than their skills as a doctor so the label of best doctor is obviously incorrect.

That all said, I'm not going to waste my time arguing who is or isn't the best celebrity as I don't give a shit about that. I'm just pointing out that you aren't talking about artistry so it is incorrect to pretend you are by arguing for her as the best artist. 

You might as well say she is the best door knob operator, seat sitter, eye haver, etc since achievement in those areas is just as irrelevant as her artistry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842845478.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; you are actually arguing for her being the biggest celebrity and not the best artist.

You are completely correct. That is what I am arguing, what I intended to argue, and what I (attempted to) present my argument as.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842886826.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>Then she isn't necessarily the best artist as your view stated. You don't actually care if she is the best artist as your view stated. You were wrong in your view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842892695.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.

As stated in the first paragraph of my post, I only used the word “best” to mean “most popular” because putting the full definition I intended to use exceeded the word count for titles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842911912.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>How did you miss that I didn't take issue with the word best? I clearly took issue with the word artist.

You aren't arguing for her ranking as an artist. The first thing you say is that you don't care about the quality of her art - the thing which actually determines the label of best artist.

You are arguing for celebrity. Not artist. Celebrity.

Not best artist.

Best celebrity.

Get it yet? Or do I need to repeat it more?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843000311.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>If I had used the term “best celebrity”, that would include non-artist celebrities, which is not my intention.

I would think that the most popular celebrity is Lionel Messi. But the most popular artist is Taylor Swift.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843026611.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I would think that the most popular celebrity is Lionel Messi. But the most popular artist is Taylor Swift.

But again, you didn't say most popular artist. You said best artist.

And again, none of your criteria have anything to do with artistry. It only has to do with celebrity.

So you are still not arguing she is the best artist as artistry plays no role in your evaluation.

And you aren't arguing for best celebrity as you are now limiting it to celebrities who happen to be artists of any quality.

Are you arguing for "most popular celebrity who happens to be an artist but doesn't need to be the best artist since popularity doesn't concern itself with quality"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843931518.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>The *first* sentences from the OP: "Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844528378.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>How could you have read all that I wrote and mistakenly think I am focused on the word best rather than the word artist? Especially when I already addressed that very same confusion with OP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43847234109.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>I came in because you continued down this path *after* addressing it with OP, even though it's the first line of the post.

&gt; But again, you didn't say most popular artist. You said best artist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844464694.0" user="jawanda" delta="False">
    <text>You're arguing in bad faith and bringing the entire quality of this sub down . Op acknowledged in their opening paragraph that their title wasn't accurate to their actual argument. You're arguing semantics ad nauseam but there's no one to argue against since everyone has understood your point since op made it in their opening paragraph.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844589254.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Blatant bad faith delta hunting. No attempt to actually engage, just trying to get a technicality win when none is actually available.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844619824.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, white knight. I'm trying to help OP express their view more clearly by choosing the words that best express what they are getting at. As I wrote, they could have said best eye haver and immediately dismissed having eyes to instead just celebrity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844802303.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/BrokkenArrow – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal%20BrokkenArrow&amp;message=BrokkenArrow%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/178y962/-/k53xpl2/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843645154.0" user="RogueNarc" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You aren't arguing for her ranking as an artist. The first thing you say is that you don't care about the quality of her art - the thing which actually determines the label of best artist.

That might be true in a vacuum but OP clearly indicated the criteria by which they were evaluating artists. Best has been given a stipulative definition which is perfectly fine for discussion. You can either engage with the discussion or ignore the conversation, what you can't do is propose another in place of what has already been procided</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844578531.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care about Taylor Swift but you're just arguing pure semantics. And unneseccarily rudely so. 

OP clearly means recording artist, which is a widely used term for someone who produces music for a living. Nothing here is contradictory, you're just being sparky for the sake of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844604750.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm trying to help OP make their view more accurate by choosing the more appropriate words. As I clearly explained from the start, they are fully focused on celebrity. And they agreed with their first comment. They are focused on celebrity. Thus they should be saying most popular celebrity who also happens to be a singer, or some such thing, given artistry is tosses aside from the beginning of the OP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844618894.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>"Artist" in this context is someone who makes music for a living. It's not just a vocation, its a simple *job title*.

OP's use of it was fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844627014.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>I know. But they then tossed all of that aside to judge purely based on celebrity. I explained that from the start.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845062676.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>He didn't toss it aside, he explained, quite precisely, exactly what he meant by "best" for the purposes of his argument, setting a framework for the discussion. 

*You've* tossed aside what you knew he clearly meant by it, pursuing instead some technicality in hopes for a delta. 

Frankly I don't care about Taylor Swift or this discussion, my gripe is with blatant delta chasers on this sub who pick out some minor semantic issue rather than actually argue the subject at hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845116110.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>Just to be clear, your whole response is built upon rejecting my correction of your assumption and returning to your assumption? Because if you are just going to tilt at the windmill that is your strawman, you can have that conversation in your head. Because that is where that strawman lives.

I'm here to help OP express their view more clearly. If you refuse to accept that, I can't help you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844787431.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>u/2r1t – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%202r1t&amp;message=2r1t%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/178y962/-/k52xrc8/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843918551.0" user="B33p-p33P-M3m3-kR33p" delta="False">
    <text>You are using the wrong word then. 

Everything you listed comes with being “successful”. You are arguing that she is the most successful artist currently, which I don’t disagree with. Saying she is the “best” however, implies that the quality of her art, is the “best”, which it isn’t. Quality of art isn’t dictated by how many people listen to it, how many album sales it has, or how many sold out shows she plays. You will find thousands of artists that put much more passion into their art, and don’t come off as soulless. She is literally rereleasing her music by re-recording it and putting it out as a new album. That kind of thing comes off as a money grab from fans that will buy whatever she puts out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844245317.0" user="Zeabos" delta="False">
    <text>So your actual CMV should read:

“I think Taylor Swift is the most popular celebrity of all time.”

This is, obviously incorrect. As there currently are more famous people on the planet. Including: Lionel Messi , Donald Trump, and Christian’s Ronaldo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843544235.0" user="Finklesfudge" delta="False">
    <text>There is no such thing as a 'best' anything in subjective media like art and music.

The only thing that has any semblence of meaning is popularity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844539444.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>Which I find irrelevant when the first fatal flaw in the OP is the mislabeling of celebrity as artist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844769344.0" user="Finklesfudge" delta="False">
    <text>Are you under the impression that a musical artist is not an artist...?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844783505.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>No. I have read the OP where they clearly dismiss any consideration of their art to focus on celebrity. Which I why I wrote what I wrote saying as much and suggesting that best way to express their view is to use celebrity rather than artist since that is actually what they are talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844815391.0" user="Finklesfudge" delta="False">
    <text>I dont see anywhere where they have said this, if you could point it out since you say it's "clearly" written</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844843891.0" user="2r1t" delta="False">
    <text>The first two sentences. The first says the focus is celebrity. The second says the quality of the music isn't the focus. And the rest of the OP focuses on fame and popularity - which is celebrity, not artistry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43852078421.0" user="Finklesfudge" delta="False">
    <text>That seems like it's not clear at all, it seems like he's just saying what I said basically.

He's telling you what "Best" means, and that it doesn't mean "objective" anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43851253671.0" user="asktheages1979" delta="False">
    <text>"The only thing that has any semblence of meaning is popularity."

Why? Choosing to value popularity as a metric is just as arbitrary or subjective as choosing to value e.g. formal complexity or rhythmic intricacy or anything else. It only "has meaning" if you decide it does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43852072424.0" user="Finklesfudge" delta="False">
    <text>There's plenty of reason to choose popularity over anything subjective.

Best = most useful to most people or most valuable to most people or most beautiful to most people or most wanted by most people.

It's obviously the most meaningful metric.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43853726152.0" user="asktheages1979" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't think that's obvious at all - and it's still entirely about subjective preferences, just on a collective level: if one person's subjective preference doesn't have much meaning, it doesn't necessarily obviously follow that a large number of people's subjective preferences do have meaning just because they happen to agree. There's also no universally agreed-on metric for measuring popularity - you could just as easily conceivably come up with objective metrics for e.g. number of time changes in an artist's catalogue or number of chromatic harmonies if you wanted.

Plenty of very intelligent musicians have not sought after mass popularity and have had other priorities. There's no obvious, objective reason why they are wrong. Plenty of very intelligent music scholars, critics and historians have prioritized things other than popularity when evaluating music. It is absolutely a choice to decide that popularity is the most meaningful metric, and actually a fairly radical and controversial one: I've studied music on an academic level and that is hardly a consensus view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43854096506.0" user="Finklesfudge" delta="False">
    <text>You are sort of jst getting entirely too in the weeds.

There are plenty of agreed upon metrics for popularity.  One of the biggest is that the more people that will pay you for your art, the more popular it is.

It's not even slightly as complicated as you are trying to make it out to be.

You call it "popularity" most people call it "success" and there's an obvious reason for that.  

It probably is controversial, because all kinds of people think they know some other way to say "these are the best artists" and they all suck at it, and most people who don't try to subscribe to some weird stuff like that just look at who actually succeeds and says "there ya go, the best ones" and nobody can actually argue against it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43854931542.0" user="asktheages1979" delta="False">
    <text>I did argue against it. The question of metrics was a secondary point. To try to expand:

Music is a form of creativity and communication. The purpose of creativity and communication does not need to be to appeal to the largest number of people and I don't see where you have made a strong case why it should be. It makes sense that governments should be elected democratically since their decisions have an impact on everyone's lives but that's not necessarily the case for someone playing a guitar. 

Many musicians, quite possibly the majority, even at the professional level, are not aiming for mass popularity so "success" could mean something quite different for them - it doesn't necessarily make sense to judge someone as succeeding or failing at something they weren't trying to do in the first place. It's actually pretty uncommon that I hear a musician say their main goal is to be the most popular artist in the world - many would instead talk about what they're trying to express, the formal ideas they had in terms of what they're trying to create, having fun playing with other people, the joy of playing in front of an audience (not necessarily a huge audience, which not everyone is comfortable with, but just an audience that appreciates what they do), be able to make enough to not have to work a day job and play the music they love (and \_not\_ have the pressure of always trying to reach the widest audience), influence people to take action on an issue, ...

You dismiss "subjective" evaluations of music but what is popularity other than just a summing up of people's subjective evaluations? People like Taylor Swift's music for subjective reasons - it just happens that more people happen to agree when it comes to their subjective preference for Taylor Swift than for Victory Over the Sun but their reasons are no less subjective. So if individual subjective evaluations are not meaningful, it needs to be explained why they become meaningful when they are added together.

That's not even getting into the questions of privilege and access - there may well be artists out there who many people \_would\_ love as much as Swift but who for various reasons don't have access to the same channels of distribution - so is their music less good? If it DID get discovered and mass-distributed in five years and become just as popular, would that mean the music suddenly became better, even though the music itself didn't change at all?

And, lastly, with regards to metrics of popularity, no, they're not crystal clear. There are no bodies that keep consistent track of sales on an international basis - they all work on the national level and use different methodologies. And the way people consume music changes over time. It's not an exact science to decide how many streams are equivalent to an LP sale from 1975 and how to compare those to concert attendance or sheet music sales in 1857. If we choose to use revenue as our metric, that privileges artists who appeal to audiences that can pay more. An artist might be very widely loved among populations that are less able to pay for their art. Etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44367560091.0" user="Johnny_theBeat_518" delta="False">
    <text>Then perhaps, the title of this post should be "best celebrity of the 21st century", not artist. I will be more agree on that.

I will ambivalently considering Beyonce as "the best artist" even though i'm still not sure about it, we'll see until the end of 21st century when i get old ig.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844857017.0" user="RevRagnarok" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Imagine I said Dr. Whoever is the greatest doctor because of their celebrity status. 

The thought of Dr. Oz or Dr. Phil actually needing to treat somebody [sends shivers down my spine](https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/dirty-painful-death-president-james-garfield). 

(The link addresses the theory of an incompetent Surgeon General.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845035775.0" user="rewt127" delta="False">
    <text>Supposedly Oz was actually a pretty good surgeon, but got the option of surgeon money, or TV money, and realized he could make a fuuuuuuuuuuck load more but selling out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845066677.0" user="RevRagnarok" delta="False">
    <text>You can be really good at one thing and [still be a moron](https://theweek.com/articles/578765/how-ben-carson-both-incredibly-smart-spectacularly-stupid).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845478181.0" user="abstracted_plateau" delta="False">
    <text>The best surgeons are sociopaths</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
