<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2615080682.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/178y962/cmv_taylor_swift_is_the_best_artist_of_the_21st/">
    <title>CMV: Taylor Swift is the best artist of the 21st century and is on track to become the best artist of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>DesperateForYourDick</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.

Taylor Swift is a cultural phenomenon. Yes, her music is stereotypical “basic white girl music” (which is a problematic belief that many hold that I won’t get into here), but way too many people deny that she’s an all-time great just to be controversial, quirky, different, etc.

[Here is a quick list of her awards](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_awards_and_nominations_received_by_Taylor_Swift)

In addition to those, she has been on top of Billboard Artist 100 for **81 weeks**. She is the only artist to take up **every single spot** on the Billboard Hot 100 at the same time. She has multiple songs (Love Story, You Belong With Me, Shake it Off, We Are Never Getting Back Together) that have stood the test of time for a decade and will likely be classics at least on the level of songs like Hey Jude, or even We Will Rock You.

Furthermore, the Eras Tour is arguably already the most famous concert tour ever. Going by current numbers it will absolutely demolish the record for highest grossing concert tour, which was set by Elton John’s Farewell Yellow Brick Road. And it’ll do so with just 1/3 the number of concerts.

Just look at the NFL. Their Twitter account changed their profile picture, bio, and banner just because Taylor Swift showed up to a Chiefs game. To have that level of influence over the most popular sports league in the United States is insane.

Yes, I’m a big fan of her work. But even objectively speaking, I don’t see how anyone can deny that, when she does retire, she will be one of the greatest artists to ever live, just in terms of objective popularity.

And just to directly address the claims made in my title—I for one cannot name any artist with more name recognition in the 20th century. “Taylor Swift” is, at this point, used as the default name-drop for “stereotypically popular singer”. And her current level of popularity/fame is on par with any great artist (say, for example, the Beatles or Michael Jackson) at their peak, which is why I think she has a shot at becoming #1 all time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43842798609.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>First off, I'd argue that title is intentionally misleading if you exclusively mean 'most successful'. 

In any event, if you're going by objective measurements, Dr. Dre made more money than Taylor Swift in the 2010s, and there were many years in which she was not the most successful musician, including last year. Yes, she's popular, she's rich, she's successful, she's famous, but she's not the most famous artist of all time.

Also, personally, I think that the Reputation era alone disqualifies her from any sort of GOAT status. Shake It Off is bad too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842813624.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Shake It Off is bad

That’s a completely subjective argument though

&gt; In any event, if you're going by objective measurements, Dr. Dre made more money than Taylor Swift in the 2010s

There are many objective measurements, and it’s not possible to say which specific objective measurement makes an artist the “best”. Of course she doesn’t lead in *every single* category. And I would argue Dr. Dre doesn’t make most of his money from music.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842820869.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>By any objective measurement, Taylor Swift is not the most successful musician of the 21st century. She is not the richest, or the one who makes the most money. She even occasionally loses the 'most successful female celebrity' category to people like Ariana Grande.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842836407.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; By any objective measurement, Taylor Swift is not the most successful musician of the 21st century. 

&gt; She is not the richest, or the one who makes the most money. 

Those two categories are by far not the only two objective measurements, so I don’t see how you can say she’s not the most popular by “any” objective measurement.

“Most time spent at #1 on Billboard Artist 100” is an objective measurement, and she is #1 in that, for example. And a pretty good one at that.

I don’t see how your statement “by **any** objective measurement, Taylor Swift is not the most successful musician of the 21st century” is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842847045.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Are you here to nitpick my wording, or are you going to actually address my point? 

Monetarily, Taylor Swift is not the most successful artist of the 21st century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43842851719.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Monetarily

I agree, but I feel that I should point out that that is not the primary concern of my post.

The primary concern of my argument is fame and popularity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843011393.0" user="earthianfromearthtwo" delta="False">
    <text>You made the claim that she’s the best artist because ________. This comment replied and gave you a dimension in which she is not. That’s a valid argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43843024936.0" user="DesperateForYourDick" delta="False">
    <text>The first paragraph of my post (if you read it) makes it clear that my post is **only** concerned about her fame and popularity as an artist.

It’s a legitimate argument to say that money is a part of “fame and popularity”, I just disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43844267857.0" user="thoschei" delta="False">
    <text>Your claim cannot be fully supported by a single metric or two alone. Success and popularity depend on a multitude of factors. 

And every time someone highlights a metric where Taylor may not be the most successful or popular, you say that you don't measure success by that particular metric. This approach seems arbitrary, and no one but you knows which metrics you consider valid or not.

You mention that money doesn't play a role in determining popularity. Why is that? Taylor Swift's wealth is a direct result of people consuming her music, attending her concerts, and purchasing her merchandise. Money undeniably plays a significant role in gauging success. (Not the only one, we both agree, but it does play a role.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845382728.0" user="earthianfromearthtwo" delta="False">
    <text>There’s no way to prove or disprove your argument. okay so she is the most popular by some arbitrary metrics. so what? that’s like coming here and saying “Whales are the largest mammals on the planet and they will continue to be in a hundred years. Do you disagree?” There’s no way to argue that with the info you’ve given and the metrics you either accept or reject</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43845429077.0" user="PicardTangoAlpha" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I agree, 

Yet here you are continuing to dig deeper and not awarding deltas.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
