<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2615080682.0" index="31" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/178y962/cmv_taylor_swift_is_the_best_artist_of_the_21st/">
    <title>CMV: Taylor Swift is the best artist of the 21st century and is on track to become the best artist of all time.</title>
    <original_poster>DesperateForYourDick</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note that here, “best” means most popular, most successful, most famous, etc. I am in no way saying that her music is the objective best music to listen to or anything like that.

Taylor Swift is a cultural phenomenon. Yes, her music is stereotypical “basic white girl music” (which is a problematic belief that many hold that I won’t get into here), but way too many people deny that she’s an all-time great just to be controversial, quirky, different, etc.

[Here is a quick list of her awards](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_awards_and_nominations_received_by_Taylor_Swift)

In addition to those, she has been on top of Billboard Artist 100 for **81 weeks**. She is the only artist to take up **every single spot** on the Billboard Hot 100 at the same time. She has multiple songs (Love Story, You Belong With Me, Shake it Off, We Are Never Getting Back Together) that have stood the test of time for a decade and will likely be classics at least on the level of songs like Hey Jude, or even We Will Rock You.

Furthermore, the Eras Tour is arguably already the most famous concert tour ever. Going by current numbers it will absolutely demolish the record for highest grossing concert tour, which was set by Elton John’s Farewell Yellow Brick Road. And it’ll do so with just 1/3 the number of concerts.

Just look at the NFL. Their Twitter account changed their profile picture, bio, and banner just because Taylor Swift showed up to a Chiefs game. To have that level of influence over the most popular sports league in the United States is insane.

Yes, I’m a big fan of her work. But even objectively speaking, I don’t see how anyone can deny that, when she does retire, she will be one of the greatest artists to ever live, just in terms of objective popularity.

And just to directly address the claims made in my title—I for one cannot name any artist with more name recognition in the 20th century. “Taylor Swift” is, at this point, used as the default name-drop for “stereotypically popular singer”. And her current level of popularity/fame is on par with any great artist (say, for example, the Beatles or Michael Jackson) at their peak, which is why I think she has a shot at becoming #1 all time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43845980955.0" user="Itchy_Egg9279" delta="False">
    <text>Just because you can't name an artist more popular doesn't make your point valid. 

Taylor isn't even in the top 20 top selling artists when looking at units sold. The eras tour has sold 2.4 million tickets, this is less than half of what the top 10 tours have sold. The #1 spot being  8.8m ticket sales, being held by Ed sheeran. 

Popularity is a really hard metric to measure but with these numbers not only is she not the best. She isn't even really close yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43848033919.0" user="Awayfromwork44" delta="False">
    <text>She has the most weeks of #1 on billboard artists chart and it’s not close. Shes on her way to most streamed artist of all time despite not being on streaming until 2017, and she’s not a top selling artist by unit because of how music has changed since 2008. She has consistently been the only artist selling &gt;1 mil in debut weeks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43848236197.0" user="Itchy_Egg9279" delta="False">
    <text>So with this were measuring greatest success of all time from a period of less than 20 years. The games completely changed so how could we possibly hold older artists up and compare them subjectively. 

If it's solely popularity what metrics are we using and are we taking into account total population at the time of release? Every metric I've looked at shows she isn't the most popular. Without a doubt she is popular, but we are talking about the very best. And I don't see her beating Ed Sheeran or others by any measurable unit aside from maybe billboard hits.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
