<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2631950179.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17iztr7/cmv_most_relationship_failurefrustration_can_be/">
    <title>CMV: Most relationship failure/frustration can be summarized as treating others like crap and get treated like crap back</title>
    <original_poster>itsdoctorlee</original_poster>
    <original_post>It is almost comical how people have been blaming men, women, dating apps, school, God, horoscope + a million more over-analyzed factors as their barrier to finding a satisfying partner and relationship. (but never realizing what they bring to the table themselves)

Two common scenarios pre-relationship:

Women often talk to multiple guys to "increase" their chance of finding the prince charming. Little did they know that it shows on the quality and enthusiasm in how they converse, their behavior and demeanor (And they are somehow oblivious to how obvious that is to a guy with just minimal intelligence). And then they get mad when some guys they are actually interested in don't treat them seriously anymore due to their diluted effort. That is, girls often give guys the impression that they are replaceable entertainment providers.

Guys, on the other hand, set priority in getting girls onto their bed (that is, treating women as sexual tool. I don't think it needs further elaboration). This easily ruins otherwise what could have been a good relationship, and then they are somehow surprised and frustrated that they don't get any relationship satisfaction, appreciation and support in return. (they have been brainwashed that sex is too important, but in fact, the most substantial missing element in mens' life is genuine care and support).

The same happen with existing partners and relationships. Just change it with "having other priorities" in life and it shows a consistent lack of interest and concern about their partners (doesn't matter what you truly want and value, it only matters what you do and show outwardly). Watch your actions and what you are bringing to the table, that's the only thing you need to care about if you want a satisfying relationship.

Edit1: Some commenters rightly pointed out that it is unclear what relationship failure/frustration means. I want to clarify that I mean bad breakups or failed attempt to relationships that results in resentment, as implied by the fact that people feel the need to the point to blame/complain other entities/reasons for their apparent failures.

Edit2: About some commenters trying to give me another reason which they claim as more "ultimate" e.g., I am sampling an immature population from my own experience, or those are "teens" who just have some growing-up to do, they have mental problems, etc. In fact, they validate my point as I am giving "proximal mechanism" that causes relationship failure/frustration. They are by no means mutually exclusive. My post is exactly trying to shed some lights for those "immature" people that some commenters claim I-don't-know-how invalidate my point.

Edit3: To address the comments "sometimes the bad behavior is one-sided and the other party just put up with it". It is a valid point, I very much agree that it would lead to relationship failures and resentments at some point. However, based on mathematical intuition, I would be inclined to think that the "bads" are most often reciprocated at some point later to the "self-unaware" perpetuator, or sometimes even off-target (and then that off-target person grow resentful and retaliate), in order for this vicious cycle of relationship resentment to grow bigger and bigger and more and more people are complaining about it (there are tons of stats that indicate single/loneliness/divorce/relationship dissatisfaction is at an all-time high).

Edit4: The "it is something good, this is what it should be" argument. At no points I am implying if the relationship failures/frustration are either "good or bad". I am just here to describe the most likely cause. Not sure what those commenters are trying to achieve.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43955026059.0" user="Affectionate-Sand838" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most relationship failure/frustration can be summarized as treating others like crap and get treated like crap back

Well, this really doesn't account for incompatibility. Some people just don't fit well together, neither their lifestyles, nor their plans in life (kids/no kids, living in the city/rural, etc.). More often than not you cannot overcome these differences because there is no solution to this other than one person giving up what they prefer.

And another point, "treating others like crap" is usually really not the core issue that people have. They often have growing up to do, or they might have self-esteem issues that need to be dealth with, or they could have trauma, emotional problems, mental illness, etc. All of these things are the ACTUAL issue, not the "treating like crap". Treating somebody badly is more often than not a symptom of some bigger problem, not the problem in itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43955086069.0" user="itsdoctorlee" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, incompatibility is a thing, but if one constantly finds/attracts incompatible people, then I would say your outward behavior and action is again messed up. Meaning one didn't really prioritize their outward action in getting a relationship with their desired group of people.  
As I said, one can always delve into a million factors "underneath". But if a person is truly living (not living like a robot) and is confident in their free will, then it is obvious that they would need to prioritize treating that "person" like a human being over other inconsequential thing in the world (in a substantial way, quality &gt; quantity, it doesnt mean bombarding their partner with text all day), if they truly want a loving and respectful relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43955141840.0" user="Affectionate-Sand838" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Yes, incompatibility is a thing, but if one constantly finds/attracts incompatible people, then I would say your outward behavior and action is again messed up.

You make the assumption that everybody is 100% upfront with what they want, or is even in a position to know what they'll want in a couple years. Yet especially for anyone under 30 they have no clue where they'll want to go in life. They figure that out WHILE living their life, not before it.

So I disagree on that point. No, it's not always people's fault for being in relationships that don't work out. You gotta live to know yourself, it's not just a given.

&gt;they would need to prioritize treating that "person" like a human being over other inconsequential thing in the world

Inconsequential to who, exactly? We all stay individuals, doesn't matter if we're in relationships or not. And people just have their own ideas of how they want to live. That will never go away. To you it seems inconsequential because it doesn't serve the peace of the relationship, but in reality it just shows that two people don't fit together if they can't find common ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43955296635.0" user="itsdoctorlee" delta="False">
    <text>Far too often, people not knowing what they want and then go all in and then pull out their effort abruptly when they realize they are not incompatible. It very likely means that they treat others as replaceable object and hence cause relationship outrage and frustration. One could have done it in a way that show respect, honest communication (upfront that they don't know what want and is just experimenting) and walk out gently in a way (or avoid starting a relationship with incompatible goals to begin with) that does not cause relationship outrage and frustration. (Gentle, friendly breakup does not equate relationship failure and frustration, which is what my post is about) 

You ignored that I am writing in concern of people who actually want to build and grow a satisfying relationship. It doesn't apply to those who treat relationship secondarily from the get-go.

To me, it is a no-brainer that you need to prioritise treating a human being with respect as well as treat their effort with respect (you would be surprised how many people fail to do that), once you realize they are a breathing living human being like you do, it is as obvious as prioritizing saving a child over your expensive iphone falling into the river. 

Your partner/potential partner who you want to build a relationship with can feel the difference when you treat them with respect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43955381537.0" user="Affectionate-Sand838" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Gentle, friendly breakup does not equate relationship failure and frustration, which is what my post is about

I feel like you should've mentioned this huge caveat in your CMV in the first line in bold letters. It is most certainly not obvious that "relationship failure" only means "bad breakups" and not "gentle breakups". And I'm still not exactly sure what that means to be honest. Do you want to say that only toxic breakups are destabilizing and hurtful to the other partner, as opposed to "friendly" breakups" that don't hurt the other person?

At which point, again, I'm questioning the validity of this argument. Breakups are inherently difficult. They always leave people with some hurt feelings because we have to admit that things don't just work out simply because we want them to. There is pretty much always the reality of (I'll say it again) incompatibility (and other issues that I mentioned in my very first comment) that both partners will have to face when they break up, even in the most healthy break ups. 

&gt;It very likely means that they treat others as replaceable object and hence cause relationship outrage and frustration.

I don't think you ever really consider the possibility that friction/break ups/ambivalence/issues between two people aren't inherently due to one person "doing something really bad" . If two people get together then 2 completely different realities come together. 2 people who have their OWN needs, their OWN wants, their OWN views, thei OWN history. That inherently causes friction, no matter who the 2 people are. You try to dumb it down to "if you break up it's because one person was really bad and selfish and didn't care about the other" but that is not the reality of relationships. You gotta be compatible to a pretty high degree to for things to work. They will never be perfect. And it's all about finding somebody who is compatible enough for/with you.

&gt;You ignored that I am writing in concern of people who actually want to build and grow a satisfying relationship. It doesn't apply to those who treat relationship secondarily from the get-go.

The issue that I see in your CMV is that you have a double messaging going on. 

On one hand you say that people should care more about the PERSON that they're with (which sounds right enough, yes, we should see our partner as a real human being, not an object. I agree.) but then you completely throw that idea out of the window when you say that the solution to this problem is that people need to "watch their actions" and "stop treating your partner like an object". 

I mean, if it was that easy people would just do that, right? You wanna solve a complicated issue (= issue of interpersonal relationships that have so much ground for friction) with a shallow solution (=just stop doing it). And that double messaging is all throughout your comments, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43956501105.0" user="Ill-Description3096" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Gentle, friendly breakup does not equate relationship failure and frustration, which is what my post is about

Just want to reiterate like the other commenter that you need to edit your post  to reflect this. I have had amicable break-ups that still caused me frustration. We really liked each other and got along great, but we weren't compatible for one reason or another in a long-term romantic sense. In some cases where we wanted to live was not compatible. In others it was if/how many kids we wanted. If you are going to have a massive carve-out you should state it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43962279983.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>Of the dozens of relationships I've had only two ended on bad terms that would fit your description. Most ended because we just had different goals, incompatible needs, or our lives just took us in different directions.

Real life isn't nearly so dramatic as TV/internet/movies make it out to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43963872222.0" user="itsdoctorlee" delta="False">
    <text>Check my edit1. Do you hold grudges and resentment that you need to complain about for those relationships you ended on mutual good terms?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43964056628.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, I'd say the edit changes the scope of the conversation to something I don't have much personal experience with</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43974067361.0" user="nikkilouwiki" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Yes, incompatibility is a thing, but if one constantly finds/attracts incompatible people, then I would say their outward behavior and action is again messed up.

This doesn't make sense. You shouldn't be compatible with a large number of people. You're unique and have specific attributes that wont click with most people.

That's just how humans work. Sometimes you'll be too loud for one person, you'll not shower enough for another person, your views wont align with someone else.

And they shouldn't. Most people aren't dating to find multiple compatible partners and not being compatible with most people isn't a fault.

It's just how dating works.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
