<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019047521.0" user="VeloftD" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;transmisogynoir 

What exactly is that supposed to mean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019124149.0" user="Kakamile" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Misogynoir is a term referring to misogyny directed towards black women where race and gender both play a role.

&gt; Transmisogyny, otherwise known as trans-misogyny and transphobic misogyny, is the intersection of transphobia and misogyny as experienced by trans women and transfeminine people.

Sounds like an attempt at a package deal that OP forgot to define</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019435605.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao get educated - next you are gonna tell me you don’t know what the cisheteropatriarchy is</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019447003.0" user="VeloftD" delta="False">
    <text>That didn't answer my question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019876637.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
