<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44018999978.0" user="AlwaysTheNoob" delta="False">
    <text>What would change your view on this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019010799.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>I would like evidence that the average person does not subscribe to these HATEFUL ideologies, and actively is against persisting in a transmisogynoir society that such we live in today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019030680.0" user="iStayGreek" delta="False">
    <text>Most people barely know what a trans person is nor do they care, outside of what they see on TV, and quite frankly they shouldn’t care. .1% of the populace isn’t worth being upset about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019038554.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>this just isnt about trans people - you clearly dont know what transmisogynoir is and means so please dont participate in this discussion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019109703.0" user="le_fez" delta="False">
    <text>You specifically mention people being transphobic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019151363.0" user="NoAside5523" delta="False">
    <text>Bluntly OP, *most* people don't know what transmisogynoir means. It's the kind of vocabulary you acquire only by hanging out in very specific internet or academic circles. Most people aren't going to be actively persisting against it because they don't know what it means.

Most people care about holding a decent job, spending time with their families, and having a basically health and happy life, maybe with one or two pet causes or hobbies. They might agree in a general sense that people should be treated with kindness and dignity, but they're not wading into the details.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019317289.0" user="TopScoot" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve never even heard the term “transmysognoir”…sounds like the latest in a long line of hot new sociological terms that few understand or care about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019370886.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>The problem seems to be how you are presenting yourself and your ideas. You are coming off as very arrogant and holier than thou. You are using some very specific terms that are not normal parlance are are likely limited to very specific niche academic fields and thinking yourself better to any that are not familiar. That is leaving out that it should be expected that the one using a particular term should define it when introducing it to the conversation. Not doing that and in fact using that as a gate keeping tactic does not show you to be acting in good faith. Your behavior and language is the reason it is not well taken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019393067.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>I am not gatekeeping anything? Anyone is free to educate themselves on these terms - I ENCOURAGE it. People just decided to show up and be transphobic in the thread and it has unfortunately derailed. I let my inner monster out and once I’m let loose I have a hard time containing it… I barely want to contain it though cause I am correct and everyone else is wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019445830.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>You are gathering when you said: “this just isnt about trans people - you clearly dont know what transmisogynoir is and means so please dont participate in this discussion”. 

So are you lying about it just one comment later? 

Why don’t you define the word if you are going to use it? Can you? Do you know what it means? You haven’t presented any evidence of such in this thread. 

If you can not control yourself you should seek some mental health treatment. Agency, the ability to choose is one of the most important things that makes us persons. 

Where does your sense of hubris come from? Why is it you believe yourself to be better than everyone else, that only you are right and everyone else is wrong? Are you that special? Why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019082143.0" user="AlwaysTheNoob" delta="False">
    <text>[https://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/news/4210692-most-in-new-poll-say-restricting-access-to-gender-affirming-care-should-not-be-focus-for-politicians/](https://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/news/4210692-most-in-new-poll-say-restricting-access-to-gender-affirming-care-should-not-be-focus-for-politicians/)

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;In a survey of more than 20,000 American adults, 72 percent said politicians do not know enough about gender-affirming health care to make accurate policies. Just 17 percent of Americans, and 29 percent of Republicans, said restricting access to gender-affirming care should be a focus of politicians on either side of the aisle.

Seems like most people want the trans community to be left alone by legislators and be free to do what they wish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019114486.0" user="xoiinx" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;In a survey of more than 20,000 American adults,

The city of Los Angeles alone has close to 4 million people. America's population is 330 million people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019169302.0" user="NoAside5523" delta="False">
    <text>That's how statistical sampling works though -- you don't have to survey every single person, just a reasonably large cross section of them. As long as you've sampled reasonably (which to be fair, is often not the case, but that's not what you're objecting to), 20,000 is a perfectly reasonable sample size for that kind of statistic.

When we say the average American man is 5'9", it's not because we've measured all adult men in the country either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019306917.0" user="RottedHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Someone doesn’t know how sampling works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019523215.0" user="thesweeterpeter" delta="False">
    <text>Your first survey of a sample group?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
