<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019181862.0" user="bill___brasky" delta="False">
    <text>Still? Did anyone convincingly make the argument America ever wasn’t?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019679345.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/bill___brasky – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20bill___brasky&amp;message=bill___brasky%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zvu3q/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
