<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019185451.0" user="katzvus" delta="False">
    <text>Trans women, cis women, trans men, and black people all face discrimination in various forms. 

But I’ll just say I don’t think it’s often helpful to the cause of equality to use words that few people understand. It’s alienating to ordinary people. When it’s possible to convey ideas using normal language, I think that’s preferable to academic buzz words. You want to persuade people, not confuse them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019197350.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>More debate bro tactics - please address my points and not the presentation of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019238556.0" user="katzvus" delta="False">
    <text>If your point is just that discrimination and inequalities exist, then I’m not going to disagree with you. Is that your whole point?

You seem really hostile though. I don’t think I’m being a “debate bro.” And as much as I dislike Elon Musk, I think it’s creepy to call anybody “ROACHES,” since that term has a long history of being used to dehumanize and justify violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019288680.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>trust me, I know language that dehumanizes and justifies language - I hear it every day from the SCUM OF THE EARTH in America and abroad (Sweden). I know which terms are appropriate ! Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019315567.0" user="Not_again_1" delta="False">
    <text>You’re Swedish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019321782.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>No that’s just an example of where some of the scum of the earth live</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019329506.0" user="Not_again_1" delta="False">
    <text>
So basically every country on earth</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019385342.0" user="Not_again_1" delta="False">
    <text>Sweden is most likely the most progressive country in Europe lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019507624.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you dehumanizing people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019326194.0" user="katzvus" delta="False">
    <text>Ok well, carry on then. If you want to use words no one understands, while also using dehumanizing language against people you don’t like, alright. I just don’t think it’s an effective way to persuade anyone of anything. But you do you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019408818.0" user="codan84" delta="False">
    <text>Scum of the earth is pretty dehumanizing language. Why is it okay for you to dehumanize others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019890880.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
