<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019062368.0" user="Superbooper24" delta="False">
    <text>How exactly are women getting less of a say? Also, the thoughts of Elon Musk is very different from the thoughts of American society. I think the average American isn’t logging on Twitter to see what Elon Musk is thinking. And ig white people do run our institutions, however so do many black people and Asian people and Hispanic people. I feel like there are better places to get examples of this yet your examples are 1. Have no evidence 2. Have no basis in it being considered American society 3. And don’t prove anything racist is happening because white people run institutions when you don’t provide a number of how many white people or provide which institutions. Like 2 vague non evidence based points and an Elon Musk tweet</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019192258.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>You are supposed to change MY view, not use debate bro tactics to get in a mastubatory win in a debate. Attack my points not the presentation of them BUB</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019634314.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Cahania – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Cahania&amp;message=Cahania%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zw24i/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
