<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019000006.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>Well, sorry to burst your bubble, but most women are extremely offended. That men are trying to become women after oppressing us for millions of years. Anybody who doesn’t hold of you is guaranteed under 25 and has a very jaded outlook on reality. Here’s a great example. In no way shape or form, should a man ever being a woman’s bathroom. As somebody who’s gone through a violence sexual assault, it makes me extremely uncomfortable to see a man in the washroom even if he’s wearing a skirt. That doesn’t mean I covered colonial values. It means I am biologically a female, and I am mentally undisturbed. I would also like to add that thinking this whole trans movement and everything that accompanied it is OK makes you a part of a fringe minority was unacceptable views, your rampaging of rainbows will come to an end sooner than you think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019075674.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>So you want a trans man, who is male passing, and for all intents and purposes looks like a man, to be in the bathroom with you because they happen to have female plumbing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019116434.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>You’re reaching, and I’m not engaging. If you’re that obtuse I sincerely hope you don’t have any reproductive plumbing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019340845.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not reaching, and it’s not obtuse.

If you want people to go into the bathroom that matches their plumbing, that would mean you want trans men that are passing as men, to still go into the women’s room.

And with regards to your comment about being against men transitioning into women because men have been oppressing women for millions of years, pretty sure the people transitioning in 2023, aren’t the ones who have been oppressing you for “millions of years”.

Pretty sure in 2023 we don’t punish people for the “sins of their fathers”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019366590.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not even going to read beyond obtuse, how obtuse of me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019658253.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Odd_Pattern_4196 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Odd_Pattern_4196&amp;message=Odd_Pattern_4196%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zzsn2/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019656680.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Odd_Pattern_4196 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Odd_Pattern_4196&amp;message=Odd_Pattern_4196%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zufma/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019110184.0" user="TimelessJo" delta="False">
    <text>I am truly sorry about your experience, but I'm going to be honest with you, I and a lot of trans woman don't often get called out on for using the bathroom of our gender because a lot of us just don't really look like men, at least from a glance. 

But I've known several gay cis women who have had authorities called on them for being in the women's bathroom and this has been a cited issue, so the question is: Is it just for those cis women who present to some as men to be asked to not use the restroom when their appearance makes other cis women genuinely uncomfortable? 

In addition what about trans men? There have been issues of trans men complying to use the restroom demands only to get their asses kicked when they became "men entering women's spaces." Also, wouldn't you be uncomfortable seeing someone who looks like a bearded bodybuilder entering the women's room. Which also brings us to the big fallacy of the bathroom panic--if cis male sexual predators can pretend to be trans women to assault people in the bathroom, in a world where assigned sex defines what bathroom you use, why couldn't those same predatory men just lie and say they're trans men?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019128963.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>Please don’t call me cis. I am a woman. That’s it. There is a woman, and there is men parading as women. There is a difference, a scientific one, and I can’t bring myself to argue with anyone harbouring psychological delusions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019358368.0" user="RottedHuman" delta="False">
    <text>You’re a cis woman. Get over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019664691.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/RottedHuman – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20RottedHuman&amp;message=RottedHuman%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zzmao/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019470906.0" user="TimelessJo" delta="False">
    <text>Got you, here is my post in which I edited my language so you can respond to my arguments instead of insulting my mental health: 

I am truly sorry about your experience, but I'm going to be honest with you, I and a lot of men who have a mental defect in our heads that causes us extreme unhappiness unless we are able to reintegrate ourselves into society as women don't often get called out for using the bathroom of our self-identified gender because a lot of us just don't really look like men, at least from a glance.  
But I've known several gay women who have had authorities called on them for being in the women's bathroom and this has been a cited issue, so the question is: Is it just for those women who present to some as men to be asked to not use the restroom when their appearance makes other cis women genuinely uncomfortable?  
In addition what about women with a mental defect in their heads that causes them extreme unhappiness unless they are able to reintegrate into society as men?  There have been issues of such women complying to use the restroom demands only to get their asses kicked when they became "men entering women's spaces." Also, wouldn't you be uncomfortable seeing someone who looks like a bearded bodybuilder entering the women's room. If some women look like men, can't men just enter women's spaces pretending to be *those* women?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019662434.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Odd_Pattern_4196 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Odd_Pattern_4196&amp;message=Odd_Pattern_4196%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zupab/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019763401.0" user="MorningNo2197" delta="False">
    <text>We don't call you lot out because we don't want some angry man raging in our faces about his supposed right to be there. You've already disrespected our boundaries and ignored our lack of consent by even being there, so it's actually crossing into dangerous territory to challenge you men for invading our spaces.

You might think this is "transphobic" or whatever, but it's not. I really don't care about some dude crossdressing in his own house or a private club or whatever. It's you other ones who try to take everything that's there for women that I have an issue with. I absolutely despise your type and I'm so glad there's a growing backlash against what you're doing to us.

You should know that you are widely hated for a reason, and that it's your own fault because of your own behavior. Just leave women and girls alone and do your thing elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019888805.0" user="TimelessJo" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you're creating a fiction to disregard the points here. Like... what about the trans man who got his ass kicked for using the women's bathroom or cis women who present as masculine getting shit? Obviously people do get called out for not being feminine enough for going to the women's bathroom. 

I'm not calling you transphobic, I think I'm pretty generously discussing things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44020110642.0" user="MorningNo2197" delta="False">
    <text>If a woman with a beard wants to use the women's restroom, or any women's space, then that's fine of course. It's men like you that are the problem. Your lack of respect for women and our boundaries just shows that you're like any other abusive man. Worse actually because you do this while parodying us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019148088.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>I’ll also add to the people who feel the need to try and change my view or assert theirs, according to what “you” all portray to society rational people’s opinions don’t matter and we are phobes and whatever else for having them, so why engage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019338250.0" user="gauss253" delta="False">
    <text>Brave of you you to speak out on Reddit of all places. Respect tbh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019352367.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>I know it’s pretty rare to see somebody using Reddit that isn’t far left but contrary to popular belief we can read we are educated, and we do have rational opinions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019394284.0" user="gauss253" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t agree with everything you stated, but the majority of it, yes.

Reddit should less exclusionary — ironically what the ultra left yaps about. 

Often any centrist views get censored. Or even left leaning centrist. 

Oh you don’t want a fat guy with a huge cock undressing in your locker room? You’re obviously a neo nazi</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019413648.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>Yep, and a phobe and a bigot and whatever other defamatory insult people want to sling at a normal chick, who’s okay with the plumbing and identity she’s got. I hate hate hate these psychos. It’s so gross.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019443562.0" user="gauss253" delta="False">
    <text>They aren’t worth your hate. Take solace that there are others who think like you. There is a silent majority of sane centrists who are too busy leading normal lives and raising our kids / working in our careers to farm up 400k karma by going full time keyboard warrior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019461968.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, good point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019780987.0" user="MorningNo2197" delta="False">
    <text>I'm with you. I despise these men. The only ones I have any time for are the ones that cross-dress in private and don't harm anyone, who don't try to worm their way into our spaces. The rest can fuck right off. Thank you for speaking up against their abusive bullshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019937107.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>I sincerely hope this wave is squashed before it gets any more out of hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44020400313.0" user="gauss253" delta="False">
    <text>LOL looks like the mods nuked your comments. 

Because you’re basically Hitler.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44020780017.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>Oh for sure, something awful indeed… mein comments were offside af.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019363781.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>How do you picture the rainbow rampage ending? Do you have a plan to facilitate this ending? I'm extremely curious. 

How many times have you personally seen a "man" in a washroom you were using? You do realize panicking in public bathrooms is the opposite of mentally undisturbed and something you should really seek therapy for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019375070.0" user="Odd_Pattern_4196" delta="False">
    <text>Well here come the delusional. And imma dip.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019616268.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>So zero times has this impacted you in any way, but you're still big, big mad about it. Got it. :-)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019667651.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Odd_Pattern_4196 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Odd_Pattern_4196&amp;message=Odd_Pattern_4196%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zzz6m/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019368985.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>How do you picture the rainbow rampage ending? Do you have a plan to facilitate this ending? I'm extremely curious. 

How many times have you personally seen a "man" in a washroom you were using? You do realize panicking in public bathrooms is the opposite of mentally undisturbed and something you should really seek therapy for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019673040.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/TheOutspokenYam – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20TheOutspokenYam&amp;message=TheOutspokenYam%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zzuhl/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019654669.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Odd_Pattern_4196 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Odd_Pattern_4196&amp;message=Odd_Pattern_4196%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zrxs6/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
