<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019272585.0" user="Difficult-Meal6966" delta="False">
    <text>You packaging this all together makes it a hard point to defend on your part and also a hard point to challenge if you state that we should bring all the proof without you providing appropriate backing or even a well laid foundation for your claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019312806.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>I made an assertion, and I just have a bunch of people ranting and raving about transgender bathrooms and mad that I actually use educated terminology. If people actually wanted to bring evidence regarding stats and cool hard numbers maybe we can chat!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019344947.0" user="CPTherptyderp" delta="False">
    <text>You can do that too. You haven't really laid any concrete thesis of a position for us to challenge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019367781.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>It’s change MY view not change YOUR view. The onus is on YOU bub</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019434986.0" user="katzvus" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the point of this sub is that you present some view that you’re open to changing.

But no one can change your view when they’re not even quite sure what your view is. So it is actually on you to articulate your position in a coherent way in the first place. Otherwise the sub would just be “respond to my confusing rant.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019392716.0" user="4gotOldU-name" delta="False">
    <text>Your "educated terminology"?  That word, that was created by a web site in 2014?  The word, that such a ....   Never mind.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
