<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019433545.0" user="ChickerNuggy" delta="False">
    <text>The systems that built America weren't built for trans black women and its very obvious, but that doesn't mean everyone who is (unwillingly) part of the system a racist misogynist transphobe. That term is just a collective of several nuanced and individual identities known for being oppressed smushed together for a perfect victim. There are women working incredibly hard to have a say, and aspiring POC institutions. Elon Musk might be an influencer but he's definitely not a thought leader. There are 330,000,000 million people in the US and there is more nuance than squeezing into however many intricate labels you want to make. "The oppressed people are oppressed" isn't a hot take and throwing a tantrum where you call of all society every term you can think of just looks childish and discredits the movements they stand for. Society at large isn't just the straight white men, and there is a massive difference between raising a voice or elevating it. To reduce society to just the actions of straight white men is the opposite of what you're effectively trying to preach.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
