<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019445029.0" user="Lou-Saydus" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t understand why you would want your mind changed. There is nothing incorrect here, might makes right. To real question is why do you think these people should change to accommodate? What gives you the idea that people have to care about your opinion or treat you fairly? That’s just not how the world works and it’s childish to get angry at that fact. It’s much better to understand that fact and play the scenario to your favor depending on what’s happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019457300.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>I want my mind to be changed because I want positivity in the world - right now the world is a dark dark place. Darker than you’d even know! And I am hoping I can gain HOPE and not feel downtrodden in this cisheteropatriarchy we live in</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019468438.0" user="Superbooper24" delta="False">
    <text>What as a woman can you do that a man cannot?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019559130.0" user="chemguy216" delta="False">
    <text>This post was NOT the way to go for that. Yes, it’s CMV, but as you’ve now learned, you discussed a topic that can longer be posted about in the sub. And I can guarantee you that based on the vast majority of your responses, if the trans topic thing wasn’t a rule, you were well on your way to get hit with a Rule B violation.

No matter how justified your defensive responses were or weren’t, you can’t be as combative and condescending as you’ve been on this post. The mods are very much “if someone posts unhelpful or aggressive comments, report them for violating CMV rules, and don’t respond with the same kind of energy.” Combative responses, especially on the scale at which you delivered them, help build a case that you’re soapboxing or don’t seem to be willing to change your view.

I feel for your state of mind, but this sub really isn’t great if your goal is to have someone change your mind as a means to feel better about the world. Part of that requires a more conversational sort of approach to make you feel heard and acknowledged, and that’s something that isn’t necessarily a priority for users in this sub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019626170.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Lou-Saydus – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20Lou-Saydus&amp;message=Lou-Saydus%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k801h5x/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
