<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019201567.0" user="amortized-poultry" delta="False">
    <text>Respectfully, the fact that you're this black-and-white about a term that is nowhere near the mainstream zeitgeist means you're a little too trigger happy with your rage ranting. Most people care about making themselves, their lives, and the lives of their families better now and in the future. This coincides with issues of racism or sexism or etc inasmuch as a person has witnessed or been as victim of that specific thing. However, most people are not every victim category at once and, frankly, not every victim category should be given the same weight. People care about what they care about and do their best to be decent people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019441101.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>No one knows what the word “zeitgeist” means lol - please read the definition and try again</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019488332.0" user="Asiriomi" delta="False">
    <text>As a random, non-college educated, highschool dropout person who knows what the word zeitgeist means, I can say anecdotally that there's probably more people who know what that word means than you claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019615828.0" user="amortized-poultry" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is I'm not claiming that everyone who doesn't know the word "zeitgeist" is essentially every form of bigot. You on the other hand appear to be essentially making this claim about "transmisogynoir".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
