<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2641475741.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/cmv_american_society_is_still_transmisogynoir_and/">
    <title>cmv: American society is still transmisogynoir - and anyone who claims otherwise is still sympathetic to old colonial racist transphobic values.</title>
    <original_poster>Cahania</original_poster>
    <original_post>Today we live in a society which maintains that women get less of a say, white people run our institutions, and thought leaders like elon musk are deeming calling a cis person cis is a SLUR. normalising relations with these ROACHES is fundamentally racist, transphobic, anti feminist. A true transmisogynoir 4 course MEAL. if you asked the average person, they wouldnt be aware of these concepts - theyd be living along a normal life cause they DONT CARE. American society is transmisogynoir and the fact that people don't even know the terms like this is evidence enough that people don't care.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44019015301.0" user="DJ_Ponko_Yo_Yo_Yo" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;/neoliberal user

Move along, folks, nothing good can come of engaging with this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019032164.0" user="Cahania" delta="False">
    <text>lmao how bricked can you be only commenting in r/news and r/worldnews - get off r/all and please use reddit like a human and not a bot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019645480.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/Cahania – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20Cahania&amp;message=Cahania%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zsmlg/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019319407.0" user="ge93" delta="False">
    <text>But… but dude… it’s a centre-left sub…and we just talk about dune and why our wives left and r/badeconomics plz bro pls</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44019643415.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/DJ_Ponko_Yo_Yo_Yo – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal%20DJ_Ponko_Yo_Yo_Yo&amp;message=DJ_Ponko_Yo_Yo_Yo%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17onzq5/-/k7zs9l1/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
