<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2660036271.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17zpt4f/cmv_rape_victims_have_a_harder_time_processing/">
    <title>CMV: Rape Victims Have a Harder Time Processing Their Rape Because Society Expects Them To Have the Expected Feeling of Being Raped.</title>
    <original_poster>DayOk2</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the main reason why rape victims have a harder time processing their rape is because society expects them to feel like how a rape victim is supposed to view. For example, society expects rape victims to have a particular reaction to being raped like they should cry, be numb, be scared, or be embarrassed, which makes it harder for rape victims to process their rape because they will feel like they are an exception to rape victims.

My conclusion is that rape victims would have an easier time processing their rape if society explicitly tells them to feel whatever they want to feel like. Change my view about why society does not necessarily make it harder for rape victims to process their rape.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44160641799.0" user="Softnessness" delta="False">
    <text>Mmmh, survivor here. The fallout was just what it is. Tried denial. Hide a lot of my feelings about it still. Was completely disconnected and dissociative for years after. Feel that the extremity of what I experienced cuts me off from other humans. It's just so beyond most people's understanding. I feel invalided in my innermost pain of people are casual about rape, downplay it etc. Even though I TRY to to the same. It is really complex imho.


Hoooooowever, I will grant you this. I'm scared of being OK and moving past it and, I don't know, allowing myself to be happy, because it will inevitably lead to people not believing how HARD I worked and how strong I was to do that. I'm scared, that if I move on people will think: it wasn't as big of a deal, or if didn't happen, or that rape is not that big of a deal. 

Part of me wants to throw my life away just to make my pain seen and heard. It's hard to find a way to honour what I survived. And not have it minimised because I healed. 

I find women finding joy, happiness, drive eventually after rape is definitely inhibited by the myths and legends around it, but not in the way you think, it doesn't exacerbate the trauma, but victim blaming, bad faith, invalidation that happens after makes it hard to move on. 


And I think that for a lot of us survivors, well not all of us make it to being survivors. There are humans that didn't survive. It is for them we hold rape in the space it is. Because it can absolutely end a life psychologically. Not everyone is strong enough to survive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
