<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2660036271.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17zpt4f/cmv_rape_victims_have_a_harder_time_processing/">
    <title>CMV: Rape Victims Have a Harder Time Processing Their Rape Because Society Expects Them To Have the Expected Feeling of Being Raped.</title>
    <original_poster>DayOk2</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the main reason why rape victims have a harder time processing their rape is because society expects them to feel like how a rape victim is supposed to view. For example, society expects rape victims to have a particular reaction to being raped like they should cry, be numb, be scared, or be embarrassed, which makes it harder for rape victims to process their rape because they will feel like they are an exception to rape victims.

My conclusion is that rape victims would have an easier time processing their rape if society explicitly tells them to feel whatever they want to feel like. Change my view about why society does not necessarily make it harder for rape victims to process their rape.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44145436078.0" user="team-tree-syndicate" delta="False">
    <text>I can kind of understand your view and I feel many people are misunderstanding what it is, so tell me if I have this right.

Many people would expect a rape victim to react a certain way, but that isn't the case for a lot of SA cases. Such reactions can include fear, depression, a total indifference, or even pleasure. My first gf was raped and her reaction was the latter one and it fucked her up mentally for a long time. It took lots of support and therapy for her find peace with it. She blamed herself and had severe low self esteem for a while, but eventually recovered. 

I don't disagree with your CMV but I'm confused on why you want to change your mind? Are you looking for someone to convince you that if a SA victim doesn't react stereotypically then it isn't SA?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
