<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2660036271.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17zpt4f/cmv_rape_victims_have_a_harder_time_processing/">
    <title>CMV: Rape Victims Have a Harder Time Processing Their Rape Because Society Expects Them To Have the Expected Feeling of Being Raped.</title>
    <original_poster>DayOk2</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the main reason why rape victims have a harder time processing their rape is because society expects them to feel like how a rape victim is supposed to view. For example, society expects rape victims to have a particular reaction to being raped like they should cry, be numb, be scared, or be embarrassed, which makes it harder for rape victims to process their rape because they will feel like they are an exception to rape victims.

My conclusion is that rape victims would have an easier time processing their rape if society explicitly tells them to feel whatever they want to feel like. Change my view about why society does not necessarily make it harder for rape victims to process their rape.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44143425600.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Could you give some examples of who is telling rape victims to feel a certain way? I can honestly say I've never seen that before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44144324945.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>There was a post in here two days ago: You're not really a rape victim if you willingly go back to the rapist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44144392807.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>Is that literally what was argued or was it phrased as "i don't believe you are a rape victim if you willingly go back"? Because that makes a big difference.

If you claim someone raped you and then go to their party and have a great time taking tons of photos with them and thanking them for raising money for your slimy husbands political campaign, then I don't Believe you were actually raped, Mrs Newsom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44144624910.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>Do you understand that you are an example of the thing you just said you've never seen happen? Victims don't need to acceptably perform their trauma for you in order to have "actually" been raped.

But no, it was a jealous boyfriend who didn't think his girlfriend's ex had begged hard enough to get taken back after he came inside of her without her knowledge or permission. Even the guy who wrote it admitted it was assault. 

But you can read it for yourself. I'm not interested in relitigating it with you.

https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/17y46z3/cmv_youre_not_a_rape_victim_if_you_willingly_go/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44145440207.0" user="BeefcakeWellington" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do you understand that you are an example of the thing you just said you've never seen happen?

No I'm not. We don't have an agreed upon set of facts here, for which I'm arguing a different interpretation. We have competing sets of facts and I view one of them as being more likely than the other. That's not the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
