<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="266369687.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4el85z/cmv_voting_for_trump_if_sanders_loses_nomination/">
    <title>CMV: Voting for Trump if Sanders loses Nomination</title>
    <original_poster>Dorozhand</original_poster>
    <original_post>Doing damage to the system and the bourgeois state by helping bring into power a candidate whose regime would be disastrous would be an effective strategy not only for the short term goal of getting a leftist into office four years from now and perhaps permanently disrupting and damaging the Republican Party, but also for the long term goal of revolutionary agitation among the working class to the end of building socialism.

It is plain that a Trump presidency would be a disaster. Not only does fiscal management of a capitalist enterprise not translate to fiscal management of a state, but Trump's record of fiscal management in the market is atrocious. Furthermore, his evident racism and covert white nationalism (evidenced by his nativist rhetoric in regards to Mexico and non-white immigration) would agitate a growing sector of the US against him and his government. Thirdly, his pro-bourgeois mentality and methods would cause further neglect and degradation of US public services and infrastructure and in all likelihood erosion of US power.

His presidency, therefore, if it occurred, would result in revolutionary agitation. The working classes whom he regards in contempt and the minorities whom he regards with vile malice would be primed towards the support of leftist candidates in the next election, which would in all likelihood be a democratic and left-democratic landslide and greatly damaging and disruptive to the reactionary-republicans' capabilities of fielding another effective opposition force for some time, possibly to the point of heralding a Seventh Party System. A solid south republican bloc ineffectively opposing a left-democratic New-Dealist state in the successful Sanders model. This stage on the road to socialism, of economic stimulus through public works and infrastructure, worker's rights, protectionism and a return to manufacturing, as well as the beginnings of both the vanguard party and directional centralism is vital in building the structures necessary to travel further on this path, like nationalization of vital industries, guaranteed employment, workplace collectivization, alleviating pressure on small proprietors, and agricultural mobilization.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28421407387.0" user="mattholomew" delta="False">
    <text>We do have a precedent for a disastrous presidency not resulting in revolution: George W Bush.  Not only did a revolution not occur, but he got reelected. And when voters finally tired of his administration they voted in Obama, a centrist democrat.  Your assertions fail to account for the still very strong influence of single issue voters on the right who care very much about religion and abortion.  Also, Sanders himself has claimed that there would be a revolution of young people sweeping the nation to vote him in and while he is doing suprisingly well, that revolution has failed to materialize among ethnic minorities and center-right voters.  Finally, an attempt to nationalize major corporations would just result in them shutting down their US operations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28421468074.0" user="Dorozhand" delta="False">
    <text>Trump is not the same as Bush, and Bush's presidency pales in comparison to the disaster that Trump's would be. Bush was actually a fairly intelligent man and had the benefit of being a "War President" (viewed as such at the time at any rate), and he handled the resultant newest phase of the Great Game about as well as his father had (and frankly better than Reagan). Though he handled economic and social policy very poorly, he did so very intelligently, with an almost fascist finesse manipulating public outrage to effectively pass Nuremburg Laws. 

Trump's radical racism, delusion, and complete lack of skill are the makings of the kind of disaster that ruins parties. Think Herbert Hoover and James Buchanan levels of incompetence combined with Mussolini-esque nativism and a pseudo-libertarianism which in his position translates to support for a fascist bourgeois state with a lack of subtlety that Bush could only pity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28421495134.0" user="mattholomew" delta="False">
    <text>Trump has also proven to be very effective at capitalizing on public sentiment.  If Bush could gain popularity from being a 'War President' why couldn't Trump?  And while I intensely dislike Trump it is just plain wrong to say that he has a 'complete' lack of skill. After all he has brought the Republican party to its knees and has gathered quite an impressive backing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
