<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="266369687.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4el85z/cmv_voting_for_trump_if_sanders_loses_nomination/">
    <title>CMV: Voting for Trump if Sanders loses Nomination</title>
    <original_poster>Dorozhand</original_poster>
    <original_post>Doing damage to the system and the bourgeois state by helping bring into power a candidate whose regime would be disastrous would be an effective strategy not only for the short term goal of getting a leftist into office four years from now and perhaps permanently disrupting and damaging the Republican Party, but also for the long term goal of revolutionary agitation among the working class to the end of building socialism.

It is plain that a Trump presidency would be a disaster. Not only does fiscal management of a capitalist enterprise not translate to fiscal management of a state, but Trump's record of fiscal management in the market is atrocious. Furthermore, his evident racism and covert white nationalism (evidenced by his nativist rhetoric in regards to Mexico and non-white immigration) would agitate a growing sector of the US against him and his government. Thirdly, his pro-bourgeois mentality and methods would cause further neglect and degradation of US public services and infrastructure and in all likelihood erosion of US power.

His presidency, therefore, if it occurred, would result in revolutionary agitation. The working classes whom he regards in contempt and the minorities whom he regards with vile malice would be primed towards the support of leftist candidates in the next election, which would in all likelihood be a democratic and left-democratic landslide and greatly damaging and disruptive to the reactionary-republicans' capabilities of fielding another effective opposition force for some time, possibly to the point of heralding a Seventh Party System. A solid south republican bloc ineffectively opposing a left-democratic New-Dealist state in the successful Sanders model. This stage on the road to socialism, of economic stimulus through public works and infrastructure, worker's rights, protectionism and a return to manufacturing, as well as the beginnings of both the vanguard party and directional centralism is vital in building the structures necessary to travel further on this path, like nationalization of vital industries, guaranteed employment, workplace collectivization, alleviating pressure on small proprietors, and agricultural mobilization.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28421366961.0" user="mostlymutualmastur" delta="False">
    <text>Presumably if you are a leftist then you and Hillary Clinton have a lot more beliefs in common than you and Donald Trump. When they were both in the senate they voted the same way 93% of the time. 

Obviously there are big differences in between the two, but not so many as to deter you from voting for Hillary if you were originally going to vote for Bernie. 

The "blow up" the system approach you are considering is dangerous. There are flaws in the system, but one of the thing that more fringe candidates like Sanders does is bring them to the forefront, so they matter in the future. Sanders has awoken a passion for politics in people and that is huge!

However, achieving the goals that Sanders and his followers want to achieve will be all the harder if the Supreme Court is stacked against them. If Trump wins then he will likely get to choose two to three judges in their 50s and 60s, setting up the court to be a bastion of conservatism and the old system you are railing against for another 30 years. 

If you believe in Donald Trump, vote for Donald Trump, but if you believe in the progressive agenda, vote for Hillary, she may not be as progressive as Bernie, but she will not undo the social progress of the past decade, and she can set up the future for progressives like Sanders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28421436897.0" user="Dorozhand" delta="False">
    <text>Clinton voted consistently against LGBT rights and African-Americans were subject to increased oppression under her husband's various crime legislation which she whole-heartedly supported. Her views only changed when homophobia and racism began to come under fire. Her current campaign is based entirely off of her husband's political dynasty and her efforts to appeal to minority voters have been condescending at best.

Sanders is the very first step towards what the country needs and a step towards the road to socialism. New Deal public works and infrastructure support, anti-privatization measures, workers' rights, a firm and decisive stance on racial, LGBT and economic equality and a movement away from the centre-right authoritarian consensus. 

The options for the democratic primary are a step backwards or two steps forward. Either the road to socialism must be taken or the system must be broken if it can't be worked through. Bringing disaster on the US in the form of Trump would cause a massive anti-conservative backlash in the long run and would agitate the working class to throw off conservative shackles and begin an American path to socialism. In terms of political strategy, Trump would do all the work for us, and would likely permanently cripple the GOP's reactionary power to the benefit of the new left-democratic movement towards a firm and decisive party for the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28424978490.0" user="maxpenny42" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Clinton voted consistently against LGBT rights

This just isn't true. She hasn't been the most vocal or militant supporter of LGBT rights but she hardly voted against them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28435131930.0" user="zero3_book" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Clinton voted consistently against LGBT rights and African-Americans were subject to increased oppression under her husband's various crime legislation which she whole-heartedly supported.


-http://www.retroreport.org/video/the-superpredator-scare/


-http://fair.org/media_criticism/superscapegoating/

 While I certainly think they should answer for their decisions, Bill Clinton was doing what he was elected to do- represent the American people.  They believed what a lot of people believed at the time, the problem was that all of them were wrong.

To single out Hillary instead of Bill (the actual president at the time) seems a bit of a stretch.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
