<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2666021095.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/183a31j/cmv_francis_fukuyamas_end_of_history_has_been/">
    <title>CMV: Francis Fukuyama's "End of History" has been proven wrong</title>
    <original_poster>Real_Carl_Ramirez</original_poster>
    <original_post>This post is partially inspired by this news story: [Bin Laden's Letter to US Stuns Young Americans: 'He Was Right'](https://www.newsweek.com/bin-laden-letter-us-stuns-young-americans-he-was-right-1844234)

Francis Fukuyama is an American political scientist who wrote of the "End of History". This concept posits that with fascism and communism defeated, humanity will now gravitate towards a gradual universal adoption of capitalist liberal democracy. Fukuyama also claimed that the "End of History" will reduce conflicts between nations as the people concern themselves less with ideology and national identity, as increasing economic prosperity becomes the main concern and smooths over other concerns. Thanks to recent history, I think that such a concept is now laughable:

* Regarding the news story about young Americans agreeing with Bin Laden, this goes to show that even within capitalist liberal democracies, this model is being undermined inconvenient truths, which are further spread by social media and influencers.
   * There is a lot of dirt to be dug up about capitalist liberal democracies (e.g. regime change operations, war crimes, atrocities against indigenous peoples). With the advent of the internet, these inconvenient truths are easier to find and therefore further weaken our nations through distrust, while more authoritarian countries can keep their dirt under wraps.
   * I'm not against truth and freedom of information, I'm just pointing out that the model that Fukuyama believed would triumph is actually quite fragile and easy to undermine.
* [Democratic backsliding](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democratic_backsliding) is occurring in many countries across the world, vastly overshadowing any progress in democratisation:
   * See [this report from 2020](https://web.archive.org/web/20210914030243/https://www.v-dem.net/media/filer_public/74/8c/748c68ad-f224-4cd7-87f9-8794add5c60f/dr_2021_updated.pdf) or [this report from 2022](https://web.archive.org/web/20230314164628/https://bti-project.org/en/reports/global-dashboard?&amp;cb=00000).
   * There seems to be a perverse incentive to democratic backsliding, as increasing autocracy appears to be advantageous to leaders who intend to govern like a Paradox Interactive grand strategy game (i.e. to make their country even more powerful on the world stage).
   * Additionally, [multiple countries are experiencing a double whammy of democratic backsliding and political polarisation](https://carnegieendowment.org/2022/01/18/what-happens-when-democracies-become-perniciously-polarized-pub-86190), [which is also growing around the world](https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2022/11/16/most-across-19-countries-see-strong-partisan-conflicts-in-their-society-especially-in-south-korea-and-the-u-s/).
* Living standards in capitalist liberal democracies are decreasing, which sows doubt on the promises of capitalism and liberal democracy:
   * See "[Living standards tumbling in Australia despite booming national wealth](https://independentaustralia.net/politics/politics-display/living-standards-tumbling-in-australia-despite-booming-national-wealth,15747)" and "[Britons ‘need to accept’ they’re poorer, says Bank of England economist](https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/apr/25/britons-need-to-accept-theyre-poorer-says-bank-of-england-economist)".
   * Even if you blame external factors for these problems, such as the COVID-19 pandemic or the Russian invasion of Ukraine, these events prove to us the resilience of authoritarian systems in the PRC and Russia in contrast to liberal democracies, as declining living standards don't destabilise them as much.
   * The large-scale international resurgence of the far-right is [partially fed by legitimate concerns of economic insecurity](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/may/31/across-europe-the-far-right-is-rising-that-it-seems-normal-is-all-the-more-terrifying).

To conclude, while I believe that Fukuyama's concepts have been debunked by recent history, I can also understand why Fukuyama made such claims in the 1990s. Back then, he wouldn't have been able to foresee the problems that we're facing now.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44182815938.0" user="Yogghee" delta="False">
    <text>Not "proven" wrong. Regardless of your political or ideological affiliation the MASSIVE apparatus of progressive recidivism and social manipulation in *universally* recognized and it's entrenchment and reach cannot be overstated. If somehow humanity could harness the new tools of communication and use them for things like communication and democracy What would "come to be" and what is actually allowed to manifest by the powers that be would be dramatic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
