<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2666021095.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/183a31j/cmv_francis_fukuyamas_end_of_history_has_been/">
    <title>CMV: Francis Fukuyama's "End of History" has been proven wrong</title>
    <original_poster>Real_Carl_Ramirez</original_poster>
    <original_post>This post is partially inspired by this news story: [Bin Laden's Letter to US Stuns Young Americans: 'He Was Right'](https://www.newsweek.com/bin-laden-letter-us-stuns-young-americans-he-was-right-1844234)

Francis Fukuyama is an American political scientist who wrote of the "End of History". This concept posits that with fascism and communism defeated, humanity will now gravitate towards a gradual universal adoption of capitalist liberal democracy. Fukuyama also claimed that the "End of History" will reduce conflicts between nations as the people concern themselves less with ideology and national identity, as increasing economic prosperity becomes the main concern and smooths over other concerns. Thanks to recent history, I think that such a concept is now laughable:

* Regarding the news story about young Americans agreeing with Bin Laden, this goes to show that even within capitalist liberal democracies, this model is being undermined inconvenient truths, which are further spread by social media and influencers.
   * There is a lot of dirt to be dug up about capitalist liberal democracies (e.g. regime change operations, war crimes, atrocities against indigenous peoples). With the advent of the internet, these inconvenient truths are easier to find and therefore further weaken our nations through distrust, while more authoritarian countries can keep their dirt under wraps.
   * I'm not against truth and freedom of information, I'm just pointing out that the model that Fukuyama believed would triumph is actually quite fragile and easy to undermine.
* [Democratic backsliding](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democratic_backsliding) is occurring in many countries across the world, vastly overshadowing any progress in democratisation:
   * See [this report from 2020](https://web.archive.org/web/20210914030243/https://www.v-dem.net/media/filer_public/74/8c/748c68ad-f224-4cd7-87f9-8794add5c60f/dr_2021_updated.pdf) or [this report from 2022](https://web.archive.org/web/20230314164628/https://bti-project.org/en/reports/global-dashboard?&amp;cb=00000).
   * There seems to be a perverse incentive to democratic backsliding, as increasing autocracy appears to be advantageous to leaders who intend to govern like a Paradox Interactive grand strategy game (i.e. to make their country even more powerful on the world stage).
   * Additionally, [multiple countries are experiencing a double whammy of democratic backsliding and political polarisation](https://carnegieendowment.org/2022/01/18/what-happens-when-democracies-become-perniciously-polarized-pub-86190), [which is also growing around the world](https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2022/11/16/most-across-19-countries-see-strong-partisan-conflicts-in-their-society-especially-in-south-korea-and-the-u-s/).
* Living standards in capitalist liberal democracies are decreasing, which sows doubt on the promises of capitalism and liberal democracy:
   * See "[Living standards tumbling in Australia despite booming national wealth](https://independentaustralia.net/politics/politics-display/living-standards-tumbling-in-australia-despite-booming-national-wealth,15747)" and "[Britons ‘need to accept’ they’re poorer, says Bank of England economist](https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/apr/25/britons-need-to-accept-theyre-poorer-says-bank-of-england-economist)".
   * Even if you blame external factors for these problems, such as the COVID-19 pandemic or the Russian invasion of Ukraine, these events prove to us the resilience of authoritarian systems in the PRC and Russia in contrast to liberal democracies, as declining living standards don't destabilise them as much.
   * The large-scale international resurgence of the far-right is [partially fed by legitimate concerns of economic insecurity](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/may/31/across-europe-the-far-right-is-rising-that-it-seems-normal-is-all-the-more-terrifying).

To conclude, while I believe that Fukuyama's concepts have been debunked by recent history, I can also understand why Fukuyama made such claims in the 1990s. Back then, he wouldn't have been able to foresee the problems that we're facing now.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44182712387.0" user="Effective_Opposite12" delta="False">
    <text>In my personal opinion Fukuyama is a total hack so take this with a grain of salt. 


First of all, there is no wave of people suddenly liking Bin Laden, this is completely made up. You can check for yourself by searching for the alleged Bin Laden praising videos. 

Secondly I don’t agree with the Premise of „Liberal Capitalism is universal and dominating, so it must be a kind of natural convergence point“. This ignores the decades of Propaganda and Suppression many governments and powerful people employed to make it so because it directly benefits them and also ignores so many countries where this was far from the norm until colonialism happened to them. Many countries experienced significant regression in social norms after they adopted the neoliberal MO, for example many countries in Africa, where progressive social norms like the acceptance of LGBTQ people was already normalized (something we struggle with hard today) and only ceased to exist after meddling by the Catholic Church. Most of the historical writings by European settlers concerning this takeover are deliberately written to make it seem the African people were already like this „naturally“ when in reality it was brutally enforced. 

Fukuyama makes the same mistake many „pop historians“ with controversial takes make: assuming most of these developments aren’t in some way directed and controlled but naturally emerging. In a time where we already know about stuff like Cointelpro this argument simply falls flat for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185461662.0" user="daddicus_thiccman" delta="False">
    <text>Fukuyama wasn’t a “pop historian”, you have the same critiques of those who literally judged a book by its cover and did not read it. 

Fascism and communism didn’t fail because capitalism “undermined them” (which would also prove Fukuyama’s point) but rather because they did not provide for the needs or desires of their populations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185883501.0" user="EvergrYn" delta="False">
    <text>America literally waged war against communism for decades (you could even say its been going on for a century now)

How can you just spout bullshit like this is beyond me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44187687116.0" user="daddicus_thiccman" delta="False">
    <text>What war? 

Communism also sought out the downfall of the U.S. Only one of them failed and in the case of communism it was not due to US interference (unless you count the effect of comparative standards of living)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44187726452.0" user="EvergrYn" delta="False">
    <text>The cold war?

And america sought out the fall of every even slightly left leaning leader of south american country (also asian, european.. basically every country in the world).

It's easy to win when you can exploit the rest of the world by imperialism. Doesn't speak to how good capitalism is for humans, only how good it it for amassing money and power</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44187763537.0" user="daddicus_thiccman" delta="False">
    <text>And the USSR had the explicit goal of world revolution. 

Imperialism is a funny charge to level against he IS given that it ended European imperialism and was opposed to the Russian empire of the USSR. 

I would recommend actually reading Fukuyama’s book though given that his argument is independent of Cold War tensions. The West won because it was freer and richer than communist states based off of its ideological system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44187778696.0" user="EvergrYn" delta="False">
    <text>The west won because it was richer. I agree with that

Now if you only would think about why it was so much richer you might end up with an epiphany</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44188735010.0" user="daddicus_thiccman" delta="False">
    <text>Because capitalism is a superior economic system? Communist states were just as imperialistic if that is going to be your argument, they were still far poorer. The USSR was an empire until the day it collapsed. 

You can even compare split countries to see the difference economic systems made, such as East and West Germany or North Korea and South Korea. 

What is your argument here? Western countries were only wealthier than the Soviet Union because every dime they made over was pillaged from the global south?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44189393001.0" user="EvergrYn" delta="False">
    <text>Because it exploited (and still exploits, of course) it's own citizens, and even more the people in countries it economically and militarily bullies to such a high extent that of course it's more productive. For the people at the top, that is.

The USSR was not an empire and no serious and sane capitalist thinks that. I won't pretend like every decision the Soviets and the Chinese did during the last century was good. Because plenty weren't, but still plenty were. And even if they did everything right, it might not have been enough still. Because a competitor who's aim is to better the lives of their people is going to have a nightmare of a time dealing with a competitor who has no problem from extracting everything from their people (and even more from those occupied imperial provinces) just to throw it at the first guy in the hopes of maintaining their own power and wealth.

I know it can be a meme, but every time we discuss politics and historical events we need to see what material conditions led to them, maintained them and changed them.

Cuba had a communist revolution changing the country from a fascist state very friendly with the USA full of plantation barons and those slaveowners then fled mainly to florida and became a big part of the conservative anticommunist votes there. The USA proceeded to try assassinating Castro dozens of times, militarily and economically bullied Cuba. Invaded it. Embargoed it (for decades now any ship that docks a Cuban port can't trade with the USA for a year and has to pay $100.000.000 in "damages" if they used "ports illegally seized by the Cuban government in the '60s"). Opened a blacksite prison for torturing anybody they want because they just label them an enemy combatant and a terrorist and not a normal citizen. You might now figure out why Cuba hasn't made it big on the international stage economically. Even still, it manages to have an amazing doctor system (which is also of course non stop sabotaged by the USA).

North Korea completely bombed to rubble by the USA. So bloodthirsty were the americans that even after dropping more bombs on it then were dropped in the entire WWII (sans the nuclear bombs) some US generals even wanted to top it off with a nuke. Then they installed a fascist government in South Korea (fascism is the best friend of capitalism it seems), embargoed North Korea and all the time floats its battleships, jet carriers and submarines along it's cost just to bully haunt them as much as possible.The isolation of North Korea might not have been it's best decision, but it is very much understandable because the actions of the west. You can constantly read online how ridiculous and evil things are in N. korea, especially from the S. Korean government and "totally unbought and homest defectors". Then you read how the same defectors say exactly opposite and contradictory things some time later.

Vietnam was similarity firebombed to hell because they dared to communism. And they managed to survive somehow. Now they see that a compromise with the west is needed because otherwise they will be massacred again.

Yugoslavia had it's own flavour of communism. Their curse was they were in between. Had to be as as neutral as possible as to survive. Im from the Balkan. Im not saying that it was all the west's fault for destroying Yugoslavia. But ethnic tensions is also a good friend of capitalism. It's dissolution was a great boon for the west, damn the lives of people who ended up worse in exchange.

US backed fascists in Indonesia massacred a million (1.000.000!!) people. Presumed communists and communist sympathizers.... 

The isolatiom of East Germany towards the west was Stalin's attempt to guard it from capitalism and fascism. He was plenty paranoid, that's a fact. But can you blame him. Look at how many assassination attempts Castro survived. It was a try. Of course it couldn't have lasted om the border with the west. The USA embraced thousands of Nazis, and turned Germany into it's right hand of imperialism and world policing. That's so much better.

And yes, western capitalist countries only won the cold war because of the exploitation of the global south, and it's own citizens of course. No cost to high in fighting the red menace!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44195086278.0" user="daddicus_thiccman" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Because it exploited (and still exploits, of course) it's own citizens 

How so? How do the liberal democracies as described by Fukuyama exploit their citizens? His entire argument for the success of liberal democracy in practice is that it provides its citizens freedoms that affirm their life and value as individuals, and economic prosperity that they desire as human beings. It isn't exploitative, and any basic measure of wealth between MLM's and liberal democracies will show you that the exploitation lies with collectivist states, not with capitalism. 

Also what does this have to do with disproving Fukuyama's argument? 

&gt;even more the people in countries it economically and militarily bullies to such a high extent that of course it's more productive.

What states do Western nations exploit and bully, and how did this make them so much richer than communist states? I know it's a joke but Marxists seem to have little to no understanding of what actually makes economic growth. None of the West's wars have ever made them any richer since the US ended colonialist imperialist after the Second World War. You think the American invasion of Iraq increased the wealth of the US? 

As for "economically and militarily bully", you sound like one of those whiny Serbian nationalists who are angry NATO kept them from genociding all of their neighbors. States literally exist to bully each other, it's just that liberal democracy makes peace with other liberal democracies and creates free trade that enriches all states involved, making it a richer and more stable system. Fukuyama's argument is that humans have not created a better system than liberal democracy and recent history has  been generous to this thesis, just look at the US alliance system, the largest peacetime set in human history, for evidence of the benefits of liberal cooperation. 

&gt;he USA proceeded to try assassinating Castro dozens of times, militarily and economically bullied Cuba. Invaded it. Embargoed it 

Shouldn't have hosted Soviet nukes. How does this make Fukuyama's thesis any less true? Cuba has gotten poorer and poorer over time during the embargo, it obviously isn't the true root cause of their issues. 

&gt;You might now figure out why Cuba hasn't made it big on the international stage economically. Even still, it manages to have an amazing doctor system (which is also of course non stop sabotaged by the USA).

It is literally the fault of having a non-market economy, it has steadily gone down even as the embargo conditions have not. The doctor argument is also hilarious given that the Cuban government uses them as slave labor for foreign currency. 

If they wanted the embargo done today, Castro could hold and lose free and fair elections. 

&gt;North Korea completely bombed to rubble by the USA.

Shouldn't have invaded the South. It is literally "fuck around and find out". 

History vindicated US actions given that they spared half the peninsula from being run into the ground by a absolute monarchy. 

&gt;Then they installed a fascist government in South Korea

Not fascist, but yes authoritarian. Unfortunate state of events but it is a good sign that decades of US engagement turned them into a thriving liberal democracy. The fact that Rhee could enrich the economy but still lose power to a democratic movement is a major piece of evidence Fukuyama uses in his argument for liberalism. 

&gt;Vietnam was similarity firebombed to hell because they dared to communism. 

Communist movements said they would see global revolution. Obviously the US took this personally, it's not that hard to understand. Yes in fact the world's oldest democracy will have a problem with the spread of oppressive regimes. I'm not justifying the Vietnam War, it's just that the motivation is obvious and straightforward. 

Vietnam now likes the US more than Americans do and has a population where 96% support capitalism. Fukuyama was right. 

&gt;Yugoslavia had it's own flavour of communism. Their curse was they were in between. Had to be as as neutral as possible as to survive. Im from the Balkan. Im not saying that it was all the west's fault for destroying Yugoslavia. But ethnic tensions is also a good friend of capitalism. I

Yeah, and that flavor was Tito playing everyone off each other to keep the peace under an authoritarian government. The fact that his death destroyed the state is maybe a sign it wasn't meant to be. 

The West didn't destroy Yugoslavia, failing to address ethnic tensions when they had the chance did that. The West didn't mind control the Serbs into being vengeful power monopolizers. 

&gt;t's dissolution was a great boon for the west, damn the lives of people who ended up worse in exchange.

Lmao how? Having a genocide on their border didn't help Europe. A united Yugoslavia would be better than the fractured Balkans of today for everyone.

&gt;US backed fascists in Indonesia massacred a million (1.000.000!!) people. Presumed communists and communist sympathizers....

Yeah Suharto was bad. Fukuyama agrees with this. Your point? 

&gt;The isolatiom of East Germany towards the west was Stalin's attempt to guard it from capitalism and fascism.

East Germany rose up against Soviet rule and called for reunification with the West in 1953 (ironically it was started by a workers strike). They were put down mercilessly. Capitalism is what made West Germany so much more desirable, the Soviets had to oppress the people to keep them from adopting it. It is the perfect example of Fukuyama's argument. 

&gt;The USA embraced thousands of Nazis, and turned Germany into it's right hand of imperialism and world policing. That's so much better.

LMAO I love this argument because it comes from uneducated Maoists who do not understand the period. The US was the strictest of the occupying powers on de-nazification. Their entire West German government was meant to create a stable liberal democracy that never fell back into fascism and they succeeded. The Soviets actually reinforced the anti-semitism and and fascist impulses of East Germany with their authoritarian rule (Stasi, wall, etc.) such as by framing the Holocaust as a action taken against communists alone, which is why anti-semitism, holocaust denialism, and far-right ideology is so much more widespread in the East when compared to the West. It is statistical fact that communism was more beneficial to fascist impulses in Germany than liberal democracy. 

&gt;And yes, western capitalist countries only won the cold war because of the exploitation of the global south

Evidence? Who got exploited? Please cite it. Because the West won the Cold War when the USSR collapsed its economy. Brezhnev couping Kruschev was the origin of the West's win in the Cold War, not "exploitation".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185885636.0" user="Effective_Opposite12" delta="False">
    <text>Fascism and communism failed for vastly different reasons, fascism is built on the same limitless growth ideology as modern capitalism, it’s just far less restrained and creates a cult like environment, constantly propagating „us vs. them“ to justify the subjugation of the „lesser“ and in the case of communism yes, it was literally undermined, wtf do you think the Marshall plan and the Cold War was about? The fact that it couldn’t provide for its citizens was a result, not an inherent quality. Do you also think trade blockades and foreign coup attempts happen after the citizens are devastated or do they directly cause it? You are equating a hostile attack with „natural“ progress, exactly what proponents of neoliberal thought use to justify the atrocities that are necessary to uphold western dominance today.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
