<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2666021095.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/183a31j/cmv_francis_fukuyamas_end_of_history_has_been/">
    <title>CMV: Francis Fukuyama's "End of History" has been proven wrong</title>
    <original_poster>Real_Carl_Ramirez</original_poster>
    <original_post>This post is partially inspired by this news story: [Bin Laden's Letter to US Stuns Young Americans: 'He Was Right'](https://www.newsweek.com/bin-laden-letter-us-stuns-young-americans-he-was-right-1844234)

Francis Fukuyama is an American political scientist who wrote of the "End of History". This concept posits that with fascism and communism defeated, humanity will now gravitate towards a gradual universal adoption of capitalist liberal democracy. Fukuyama also claimed that the "End of History" will reduce conflicts between nations as the people concern themselves less with ideology and national identity, as increasing economic prosperity becomes the main concern and smooths over other concerns. Thanks to recent history, I think that such a concept is now laughable:

* Regarding the news story about young Americans agreeing with Bin Laden, this goes to show that even within capitalist liberal democracies, this model is being undermined inconvenient truths, which are further spread by social media and influencers.
   * There is a lot of dirt to be dug up about capitalist liberal democracies (e.g. regime change operations, war crimes, atrocities against indigenous peoples). With the advent of the internet, these inconvenient truths are easier to find and therefore further weaken our nations through distrust, while more authoritarian countries can keep their dirt under wraps.
   * I'm not against truth and freedom of information, I'm just pointing out that the model that Fukuyama believed would triumph is actually quite fragile and easy to undermine.
* [Democratic backsliding](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democratic_backsliding) is occurring in many countries across the world, vastly overshadowing any progress in democratisation:
   * See [this report from 2020](https://web.archive.org/web/20210914030243/https://www.v-dem.net/media/filer_public/74/8c/748c68ad-f224-4cd7-87f9-8794add5c60f/dr_2021_updated.pdf) or [this report from 2022](https://web.archive.org/web/20230314164628/https://bti-project.org/en/reports/global-dashboard?&amp;cb=00000).
   * There seems to be a perverse incentive to democratic backsliding, as increasing autocracy appears to be advantageous to leaders who intend to govern like a Paradox Interactive grand strategy game (i.e. to make their country even more powerful on the world stage).
   * Additionally, [multiple countries are experiencing a double whammy of democratic backsliding and political polarisation](https://carnegieendowment.org/2022/01/18/what-happens-when-democracies-become-perniciously-polarized-pub-86190), [which is also growing around the world](https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2022/11/16/most-across-19-countries-see-strong-partisan-conflicts-in-their-society-especially-in-south-korea-and-the-u-s/).
* Living standards in capitalist liberal democracies are decreasing, which sows doubt on the promises of capitalism and liberal democracy:
   * See "[Living standards tumbling in Australia despite booming national wealth](https://independentaustralia.net/politics/politics-display/living-standards-tumbling-in-australia-despite-booming-national-wealth,15747)" and "[Britons ‘need to accept’ they’re poorer, says Bank of England economist](https://www.theguardian.com/business/2023/apr/25/britons-need-to-accept-theyre-poorer-says-bank-of-england-economist)".
   * Even if you blame external factors for these problems, such as the COVID-19 pandemic or the Russian invasion of Ukraine, these events prove to us the resilience of authoritarian systems in the PRC and Russia in contrast to liberal democracies, as declining living standards don't destabilise them as much.
   * The large-scale international resurgence of the far-right is [partially fed by legitimate concerns of economic insecurity](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/may/31/across-europe-the-far-right-is-rising-that-it-seems-normal-is-all-the-more-terrifying).

To conclude, while I believe that Fukuyama's concepts have been debunked by recent history, I can also understand why Fukuyama made such claims in the 1990s. Back then, he wouldn't have been able to foresee the problems that we're facing now.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44179916526.0" user="-Dendritic-" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have time to fully address your CMV right now (I will later) but have you read any of Fukuyama's more recent books since he wrote the end of history? The Origins of Political Order and Political Order and Political Decay are both great books imo, and a little more current</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44179976790.0" user="Real_Carl_Ramirez" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't read *Political Order and Political Decay* yet, but judging by the synopsis on Wikipedia, it appears to agree with the points I outlined, while also contradicting the End of History, as it shows that even strong democracies like the USA can decay, and that this decay can hit Europe too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44180858923.0" user="vertaranrix" delta="False">
    <text>His point wasn’t that it’s impossible for other political and economic systems to exist or for democratic capitalism to revert. His point was that there isn’t going to be a new, better system. We’ve reached the apex. Of course things will sometimes go backward, but in the sense of broad human progression towards the best system: we’re done. We got there. Now we just have to keep it. 

Btw: I don’t particularly agree with him on that point over the long term. I suspect that technology will enable systems that don’t make any sense right now. But I don’t think your argument undermines Fukuyama’s.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44181018639.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>I think the idea that people willfully construct systems is just misguided. Swedish economic system is very different from American, and that one from Russian, and that one from Chinese. They are all vaguely market economies with very different outcomes. Capitalism really is a meaningless word if it fits all of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44181027418.0" user="vertaranrix" delta="False">
    <text>I can see your argument, but (1) I think it deprives humans of agency, and I choose not to believe it because that’s a path of despair, and (2) nothing that I said requires that people willfully construct those systems. Natural selection of the systems works just fine for Fukuyama’s argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185702018.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>But what defines a system? Is Britain and Sweden and Greece following the same system by that definition? They are extremely different countries and have little to do with each other. But they would be labeled as capitalist. So what does capitalist mean then, if most countries, regardless of differences in organization, ideas and outcomes are still labeled the same?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185853640.0" user="vertaranrix" delta="False">
    <text>The capitalism category is defined by private ownership (and the things owned are “capital”). If you own something, then you can set the terms by which that thing is used. Those terms often end up being payment of some sort. If there is private ownership in the economic system, then it is a form of capitalism. Of course there are subsets (as with any category), and some of those subsets can provide divergent outcomes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185878645.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>And when in history did we live outside of those terms before 19th century? By your definition, Roman Empire is capitalistic, as is current-day Estonia. So they are both using the same systems?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185921155.0" user="vertaranrix" delta="False">
    <text>Estonia is absolutely capitalist. 

An example: land was owned by the monarch and/or feudal lords in feudal systems. That land wasn’t transferred via sale but rather bequeathment by the monarch or by acquisition via combat.  Control of that land didn’t look much like the current system of ownership. 

Another example: many native Americans used a very different concept of “ownership”. More like everything was public commons. 

We could keep going. I won’t argue that there weren’t any capitalistic systems historically—there were a lot. They just weren’t the only systems; not by a long shot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44189440785.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>But by your definition so is Roman Empire, would you say that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44189485107.0" user="vertaranrix" delta="False">
    <text>Some parts certainly were. Lots of the Roman economy behaved in an essentially capitalist way, and I’ve read before that some consider Rome to be one of the first capitalist societies. 

That said, I think I’d argue that the extent of power that the government held made it more like modern China.  Generally modern China’s economic system is considered a modified form of capitalism—“state capitalism” or some such.  This is because much of the private property is private with a very significant and relevant footnote: it is private as long as the govt allows it to remain private.  

(Note: this is one of the reasons that democracy pairs well with capitalism, as democracy is the mechanism to defend seizure of property by the state.)

Out of curiosity, why is it important to you whether the Roman Empire was considered capitalistic?  I provided several other examples, and the Roman Empire was maybe 20% of the human population at the time.  (Remember: your argument was that effectively all economic systems are capitalism, which makes the category meaningless.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44189810527.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Out of curiosity, why is it important to you whether the Roman Empire was considered capitalistic?

Because if you can call Roman Empire capitalistic, then the term is utterly meaningless. It can be applied to anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44191414640.0" user="vertaranrix" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, I just gave several other examples that weren’t.  There are obviously several from the modern era. And yet you’ve decided that Rome is somehow the only example that matters?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44181272898.0" user="comfortablesexuality" delta="False">
    <text>Is capitalism meaningless or do you not know what it means?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44183914956.0" user="FellFellCooke" delta="False">
    <text>Is this kind of snide insult hiding as rhetoric really appropriate for a subreddit about good-faith conversation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185678273.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I think as a term it is meaningless since it only serves to describe pretty much everything and, as a result, nothing at all. The same would go for feudalism I would argue, as do most current historians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44186069760.0" user="comfortablesexuality" delta="False">
    <text>That's because we live under capitalism everywhere. Of course it doesn't differentiate. That doesn't change the fact that they are all capitalist economies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44182439077.0" user="gender_is_a_spook" delta="False">
    <text>Whether you agree with our politics or not, I actually think the socialist perspective would be helpful here.

We spend quite a lot of time analyzing and defining different capitalisms. After all, we want to explain exactly what we think is wrong with them. You can have capitalism cover all these countries and still give it a *very* specific meaning.

**Capitalism is primarily defined as an economic system with a capitalist class and wage labor.**

Capitalists (the actual class position) are people who are able to own companies where other people work, and to control how the profits generated by the workers are spent. The workers only get a small portion of the value they've produced, paid back in the form of wages. They are not elected by the companies (though in large companies they're now elected by an oligarchy of large shareholders.)

There are many different flavors of capitalism, but they all retain the sovereignty of a capitalist class and a wage system.

The Nordic countries are social democracies, where the government has stepped in to regulate many of the worst excesses of capital and labour unions are generally well supported. But they retain the presence of capitalists and the wage labor system. Therefore are still capitalist.

China has shown itself unafraid to enforce state policy on companies when it deems it necessary, but it also regularly suppresses independent labor organizing. China's only legal union, the AFCTU, does not offer many opportunities for workers to pick their own representatives, but stacks the hierarchy with department heads and managers, who are much more likely to side with the employers in any labor dispute. They fully retain the existence of private companies and the wage system. They are obviously capitalist, too, just much more "state capitalist."

There are obviously important and meaningful differences WITHIN the umbrella of capitalism. I would much prefer working in Norway rather than toiling away at a 996 job in China.

But when talking in terms of systems, we can apply capitalism to all these different societies and it's still logically consistent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185687911.0" user="5thKeetle" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The Nordic countries are social democracies, where the government has stepped in to regulate many of the worst excesses of capital and labour unions are generally well supported

But you are incorrect on this one. The government stays out of salary negotiations, for example, at the wish of both the unions and the companies. So what does that mean?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44185707683.0" user="gender_is_a_spook" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I understand your point. Could you elaborate?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
