<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="54" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44200002220.0" user="Level-Condition9031" delta="False">
    <text>I agree… if you’re talking about a long term relationship. A lot of those high net worth men come with baggage and problems of their own

Mega millionaires, athletes, community figures, etc have affairs constantly. They can party a shit ton, do a lot of drugs and/or are away from their partners for long stretches of times. They are surrounded by several other high value women that can make the partner feel insecure that can cause a lot of stress on a relationship

We all want money, power, fame, beauty, etc. We don’t all want the headache, baggage, and responsibilities that it comes with. I think many people (subconsciously) realize this and adjust their expectations accordingly</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
