<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="42" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199678278.0" user="ChaotiCrayon" delta="False">
    <text>I have not much to add, but trying to change your view: Don't you think, this  percepted choosiness is something, that is mostly prevalent in the context of Teenagers/young adults? This is the generation, that really embraces the Online-Dating-Apps, and i think these really enforce this percieved choosiness. Additionally: The social hierarchy is much more present in the more closed social environments like school or maybe the social group, you study in. Therefore, this chossiness may take place more often in these environments - in contrast to your anecdotical experience (that i share), which doesn't really have any ... hermetic social groups, in which "upper tiers" of partners exist.  


So, tldr: This choosiness exists, but mostly in the (closed) social groups of young adults. Since these are the ones, that dominate the content online, the perception can take place, that this choosiness is more or less unviersal.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
