<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44198915168.0" user="RespondHuge8378" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it need to be questioned? If they are choosey, that's their choice and they have every right to make their own decisions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198998434.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>Much easier to focus on women and try to make them think they have some kind of behavior that they need to change. If women are being particularly picky (which is a claim I would challenge along with OP), it is generally good for women and not to great for men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199077225.0" user="libertyman77" delta="False">
    <text>Bad for women too if social expectations makes them feel like they have to have a man who is 6'5, makes 250k a year, looks like a Greek god, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199104801.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>That’s an enormous “if”. Your characterization is more or less the claim I often see for the ways in which women are “picky” and yet it doesn’t really hold up to scrutiny if you just look around at the couples you see or know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199247156.0" user="libertyman77" delta="False">
    <text>The couples we see and know often haven't been affected by it. The people that are single now are the ones that have (and with young people that rate has risen hugely the past 20 years). I am just saying women are hurt by such standards at a similar degree as men are hurt by such standards (look at the retarded Andrew Tate crowd). 

The internet is causing this, but also of course exaggerating how much of a problem it really is. I do however think teen boys and girls growing up to Tiktoks of people saying you should never date a woman who weighs above 120lbs or a man who makes less than 200k a year is problematic for their individual lives and maybe even detrimental for society as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199370530.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>You’re coming to this argument with the assumption that those previous standards you listed are common enough to be hurting people looking for relationships but I don’t see any indication of that being the case.

To be honest, unless you can show me legitimate data that young women are expecting men who are 6’5, make 250k, and have sculpted bodies in any significant numbers, there’s not much for me to talk about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199485880.0" user="taralundrigan" delta="False">
    <text>Go outside. Take a look around. This is a chronically online take.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199047509.0" user="BadgerSame6600" delta="False">
    <text>Well yeah, I agree with you! 

It isn't up to women to fulfil men's sexual needs. Or, vice versa.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199158182.0" user="johnnyblaze6398" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah women should never be held accountable for anything right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199192882.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>Held accountable for what exactly? What behavior in this instance would a woman need to apologize or make amends for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199251432.0" user="johnnyblaze6398" delta="False">
    <text>For expecting Prince Charming but not being all that themselves</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199256525.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn’t answer a single question I asked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199490053.0" user="taralundrigan" delta="False">
    <text>Projection much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44201386175.0" user="johnnyblaze6398" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah right like men are allowed to have any kind of standards at all without being berated</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199355446.0" user="l_t_10" delta="False">
    <text>Have you seen all those lists women make of unacceptable first dates to go on?

Literally filming themselves refusing to get out of the guys car when they see where he took them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199387464.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>Have I seen what sounds like internet ragebait for attention?

Not much because that stuff is stupid and not grounded in reality. And this comment doesn’t really have anything to do with my questions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199441267.0" user="l_t_10" delta="False">
    <text>Its really not, its put up on personal accounts real names real faces.
Same with the videos

Its obviously grounded in the women who do its reality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199466190.0" user="LilSliceRevolution" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not grounded in overall reality and people are fully capable of posting fake ragebait under their own names.

All the existence of videos like that tells me is that there are trashy people in the world, a fact I already knew. You should not take trash people post to TikTok for attention as representative of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199748324.0" user="HeisenbergCares" delta="False">
    <text>The women who "hate" fuckboys, oftentimes find themselves repeatedly going after fuckboys, and then lamenting that they cannot find any "good" men. Frequently in life, if there is an undesirable outcome, the person who is the common denominator is the cause of the problem.

Women should absolutely be picky in choosing a partner (choosing wrong can ruin one's life). The problem is many people are designed to be reluctant to admit they made a bad decision, so you get women who are not quick to recalibrate their expectations (expecting a guy whose attributes are superior to her), and they end up getting burned by guys who have options (a guy who is an 8 is likely to have more options than a guy who is a 5). The sexual marketplace, much like the stock market, is very complex. A lot of people have no idea of how deceptively tricky it is. Average women are thirsty in the middle of the ocean; average men are thirsty in the middle of the desert.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
