<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="52" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199789721.0" user="DifferentNinja7221" delta="False">
    <text>I think what you're ignoring is that relationships and sex are are both very high-stakes for women but low-stakes for men.

If a woman sleeps with a man and gets pregnant, and the man she slept with is "low tier" (poor personality traits or unemployed) then she knows may be in trouble.

Obviously birth control takes a lot of this out of the equation but at the same time sex can be painful for women if they aren't genuinely attracted to the person they're with, men can be more easygoing with this. So this is another reason why it is low stakes for men.

And finally, I think you might be selling your male friends and acquaintances short. I don't think that finding a well kempt man with stable employment is as common as you might think, specially not as you get older. Women also say that sex for them is often more about the emotional connection than just physical attraction so your opinion might be formulated by your own narrow view of how a man's value is perceived.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
