<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199328987.0" user="ICuriosityCatI" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, most women are not going for the upper tier of men. They probably fantasize about them- as men fantasize about women models or celebrities- but when push comes to shove that's not who they (most women) decide to be in a relationship with. . 

But they keyword is most, because there are plenty of women who bring very little to the table and are looking for men who bring a lot to the table. Some women seem to interpret the old saying "guys chase, girls choose" as "I can have any man I desire and I deserve that." 

That is to say women are not a monolith and when men run into *those* women they naturally get the impression that women are going for the upper tier of men. 

Also, I would say when dating men and women are generally looking for someone who is special to them, which could be considered the upper tier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199789303.0" user="shrimp_sticks" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah honestly "upper tier" means something different for everyone. So yeah, you'd be looking for someone who's to your standards, which could be anything, and that would be who's "upper tier" in your eyes. Doesn't mean that person is at highest demand objectively or across the board.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
