<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199371222.0" user="GorchestopherH" delta="False">
    <text>They are on dating apps. We have statistics on this. It's basically entirely proven on dating apps.

Women decline *more* than 80% of men, while men decline *less* than 50% of women.  
This is the average woman, and the average man on dating apps, so yes, this information is only definitive for people using dating apps (which is about 2/3rds men).

As the percentages of male/female interactions that are due to dating apps increases, this will be increasingly true.

It's also a natural phenomena that women prefer men that other women prefer.

Taking a step back to antiquity, and deep history. If other women have selected a specific man, that means he's been validated as a good choice. If a man is powerful, good at acquiring resources, in control of good land, stronger than his rivals, then he's a good person to have offspring with. It means your children will have good land, have plenty to eat, and will have higher status than the offspring of a lesser man.

Men on the other hand are wired differently. 

A man doesn't want to expend resources raising another man's children, he wants those resources for his own offspring. He isn't amassing his power and resources to just give to another man (or the offspring of another man). As such, he doesn't want to share a woman with another man.

So, it's a bit of genetics (for millennia women have preferred the best men, even if that man is shared), and a bit of technology (men are more common in dating apps, therefore there's more competition for the women).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
