<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199038188.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>Lets break it down. What do men have to bring to the table to be good enough for the average woman? Above average looks, above average salary, above average confidence, absolutely no trauma or mental health issues. What does the average woman have to bring to be good enough for the average man? Sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199338306.0" user="Cayowin" delta="False">
    <text>What does a man have to bring? 

Intelligence, humor, respect and personality. You will stand out of a crowd like a beacon. 

And a highly under discussed quality of -   Potential.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199355640.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>While these qualities are great, if someone is lacking in looks or money, they won’t be a woman’s first choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199480496.0" user="taralundrigan" delta="False">
    <text>Wrong. Have you ever spoken to a woman irl?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199498715.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>I have, Ive dated, hooked up with, and been in relationships with multiple women. Ive also struggled financially for most of my life. When you’re average looking and broke, women will either choose the more successful/better looking guy, or cheat on you/leave you for the more successful/better looking guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199626601.0" user="XelaNiba" delta="False">
    <text>So, all a woman has to bring is sex? How dehumanizing. I guess some women want to be seen as more than a life-support system for a vagina. Maybe they're holding out for men who think they have more to offer than their sexual organs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199637405.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>Men value women as people, women value men as protectors and providers. If they fail to meet that requirement, then they’re no longer valued.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199876733.0" user="jasmine-blossom" delta="False">
    <text>How is only caring about being able to stick your dick in someone equivalent to valuing them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199908130.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>When Im sleeping with someone, I usually care about them and value them as a person. But as a man, Im no longer valued as a person if I can’t protect or provide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200000270.0" user="jasmine-blossom" delta="False">
    <text>This isn’t just about you tho. 

Plenty of men, like op, are capable of fucking women they don’t respect or even actively hate. 

And my partner neither protects nor provides, and many men do not contribute equally to the household, as demonstrated by data on household contributions divided by sex. so your statements are not accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200010800.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>Just because your partner doesn’t protect or provide doesn’t mean other women don’t have that expectation. Most women will put up with a bum if he’s hot enough, it’s average men who are only valued for their money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200024967.0" user="jasmine-blossom" delta="False">
    <text>You are literally just spewing opinions, not facts. Women want to be with someone who will contribute equally to their shared life together, and unfortunately, according to the data on relationship responsibilities, most women are experiencing men FAILING to meet them halfway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200037856.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>You say this, yet ignore that most men are expected to be the breadwinner and pay for the majority of the bills/expenses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200466638.0" user="jasmine-blossom" delta="False">
    <text>Not only has this rapidly changed over the past 50 years, because of women stepping up and having actual opportunities to further their earning potential, studies still show that women lose more free time than men even in households where both work.

“Among married couples in the United States, women’s financial contributions have grown steadily over the last half century. While men remain the main breadwinner in a majority of opposite-sex marriages, the *share of women who earn as much as or significantly more than their husband has roughly tripled over the past 50 years.*

In 29% of marriages today, both spouses earn about the same amount of money. Just over half (55%) of marriages today have a husband who is the primary or sole breadwinner and 16% have a breadwinner wife.

*Even as financial contributions have become more equal in marriages, the way couples divide their time between paid work and home life remains unbalanced.* **Women pick up a heavier load when it comes to household chores and caregiving responsibilities, while men spend more time on work and leisure.**

*This is true in egalitarian marriages – where both spouses earn roughly the same amount of money – and in marriages where the wife is the primary earner*. **The only marriage type where husbands devote more time to caregiving than their wives is one in which the wife is the sole breadwinner. In those marriages, wives and husbands spend roughly the same amount of time per week on household chores.”**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199815092.0" user="HeisenbergCares" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize that men and women look for different things in each other, right? Right?

Men who have financial security do not need financial security from a woman. Men who are physically strong, aren't looking for a woman to protect them.

Most straight men want to get laid. I'm sorry, it's the truth. Men give attention and love in relationships to get sex. Women give sex to get love and attention. It is amazing to me that people are oblivious to this.

Yeah...  there is alsp happiness, shared experiences, all that. Most of us just want to get laid. Even when in love, we want to get laid. This doesn't mean that we also don't care about the women in our lives, but if we aren't getting sex, what is the woman doing to make herself irreplaceable? Don't believe me? Do a poll to see how many men want to have a platonic wife or gf. Men need women and women need men. The reason why is different. Not better, not worse. Just different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200454461.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to blow your mind with this. Women like to fuck, too. A lot. We just don't necessarily want to fuck someone who'd stick his dick in a corpse with some Crisco and consider it an equal experience to fucking us. And since it's not 1802, we don't need you to financially support us or protect us either. I guess you'd better work on your own irreplaceability. :-)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199646303.0" user="HeisenbergCares" delta="False">
    <text>Your calculus is a little bit off, but still relatively accurate. For men, the more a guy is lacking in certain factors, the more imperative it is that he makes up for that in other areas. Basically, if you're ugly, you better have a lot charisma and not be broke. You can swap the attributes, but the important part is making sure the guy in question is working to max out the attributes that are within his control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199661360.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. And in our current era of dating, average guys are seen as ugly unless they make more money than the average woman. Meanwhile a hot guy can be broke and women will stay with them for years, even if he cheats on them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199722005.0" user="Wooden-Ad-3382" delta="False">
    <text>no i think men have lots of expectations as well, in fact i think one of the biggest ones that's being overlooked here is age.  men prefer younger women.  my suspicion is this dating gap is entirely due to older men marrying younger women</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199797620.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>While most men prefer younger women, most are not opposed to dating women in their own age range.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199817146.0" user="Wooden-Ad-3382" delta="False">
    <text>probably as they age they get more and more picky about it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199832206.0" user="nhlstintrovert" delta="False">
    <text>I think along with younger women also being more attractive, they’re also less likely to have baggage or trauma that will interfere with dating them. Ive noticed this myself when dating a woman older than me vs a younger one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
