<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199298170.0" user="NW_Ecophilosopher" delta="False">
    <text>The basis of your opinion is self-confessed anecdotal experience. I know very few conservatives so clearly 90% of the country must be democrats. That’s the fundamental error you’re committing. The world will always be an unknowable mystery to you with that attitude and you’ll dismiss things that are almost certainly going to be huge problems.

So what does the data say then? Well there’s the (in)famous dating app data about 10% of men getting 60% of all replies from women. You can’t impress someone with intelligence, compassion, or repartee if they literally won’t even grace you with acknowledgment. For 18-29 year olds, half use dating apps which is admittedly lower than I would think, but that number is ten percentage points higher than the next age group and is expected to rise.

Certainly your view is on shaky ground at best, but what about real life? Well it is hard to parse, but consider the following: 1/3 of women 25-34 are single whereas 2/3 of men in that age group are single. That trend doesn’t invert until ages 50-64, and it doesn’t truly become anywhere close to as bad until 65+ (which “coincidentally” marks a large change in male/female ratio as men die off much earlier and as such is likely responsible for the bulk of that shift). So how the hell is that kind of situation possible? For 100 single women, there are 200 single men. I’d venture that since the singleness trend doesn’t revert until much older, a significant amount of women are “dating” the same guys. We’ve progressed so much, we’ve looped back around to the ultra-progressive arrangement of harems.

Now, there is no credible reason to believe that on the whole, the distribution of attractiveness for men and women is anything but a normal curve. At least, not in the physical sense (hilarious distribution of wealth aside). Yet, while men rating a random group of women will recreate a normal distribution, women rating a random group of men will create a power law or Pareto distribution. Quite literally, women have unrealistic beauty standards by definition.

All of this taken together tells a very different story from your anecdotal experience. But in the race between what one person experiences and what an impartial data set suggests about what is readily becoming apparent as a problem, it’s better to rely on the data. You can still dismiss men as losers if you like, just recognize you are untethered from reality and feeding into your biases.

Ultimately this is a brewing catastrophic problem that will have an impact on your life or on the life of your son/daughter/cousin/friend/etc. Nothing good can come out of literally tens of millions of young men feeling hopeless and angry. I don’t know what the solution is, but I do know the answer isn’t something vile and dehumanizing as found in some dark corners of the internet or to just do nothing. 

There has been a paradigm shift in dating that will have consequences in the near future. You can blame men, but at that point you might as well blame minorities for being disenfranchised because you’re missing the same point. Your experience is a singular point clouded by personal judgement, societal expectations, and an inborn need to “other” out groups. The objective data is where the truth can actually be found.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
