<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199509372.0" user="gilgamesh_99" delta="False">
    <text>You are 35 not 24 come see the new generation mentality. It’s an unfair game where you really see it in real life. Am Arab and When I was 18 I came to Uk due to father business and I was unattractive and not the in the best space mentality due to UK insane amount of racism. 

Women were very scared of me and they didn’t even wanna look or even have small talk with me. They were very guarded as if I will rob them or something. 

At 21 I made the decision to go gym and start taking really good care of how I look. I still dress the same and am the same dude. Now at 24 the amount of options I have is insane due to the fact I only focused on studies and graduated engineering and business masters. 

Now suddenly women even if they are in relationships they still talk and message me as “friends” and even the amount of options I have is insane. 

Makes you really see the world differently and makes you think that new “friends” are simply an option in the case they break up with their boyfriend. 

The rhetoric is true. However it’s very easy to become a “upper tier” man as men nowadays don’t read, don’t take care of themselves and don’t even have nice degrees or work. 

Your generation is much different than the new generation. Everything now is different they want someone they can post and flex on social media. They don’t mind cheaters as long as he fits the their fanatasy</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
