<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199469884.0" user="NoSoundNoFury" delta="False">
    <text>I think it has a lot to do with the behavior and choices of specific age brackets at a younger age.

An 18-year-old woman realistically has an age bracket of eligible men roughly ranging from 17 to 25. An 18-year-old man realistically has an age bracket of eligible women somewhere between 16 and 20, i.e. a much smaller one.  

That is because most women prefer a man of the same age or slightly older (and vice versa), but the behavioral differences between younger people are too big and sometimes even legally problematic. 

This clearly leads to frustration. If you are an 18-year-old man who has a crush on a peer 18-year-old woman, you have to compete with much older men who have already accomplished much more, have had more time to mature, have more money and experiences, etc. Vice versa, the 18-year-old woman has to compete with younger girls who are usually much more immature - which is a downhill battle, not an uphill one. 

Later, the age brackets are roughly the same, but I think the first experience many men have when growing up continues to shape their views. 

I'd also expect that most people who adhere to the cliché of women having too many options are probably rather younger and less experienced than older and experienced.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
