<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199382165.0" user="Naive-Principle3262" delta="False">
    <text>Well it's because people who are online saying this stuff are young men who are just entering the age to date or are having trouble finding success. 

It's much easier to blame someone else than it is to work on yourself. This isn't exclusive to young men either. Women do this too. 

The thing about these discussions is that they're nuanced. Some women are going for the "upper tier" of men. Some women are too choosy. 

The younger you are, the more shallow your dating life is. Teens and college aged kids find the dumbest shit to like about someone or dislike. They have no idea what they want or like and they're facing more pressure to conform to their peers. As you get older, dating starts to be less about looks or superficial stuff. 

So while I disagree with the analysis and reaction of young men or frustrated men, I understand it. There are women who fit the mold of what they complain about. But I find that this type of view is not a 180 degree turn. 

It's best to understand the dynamics of it all better. You're 35, you see people around your age with partners because they're in their 30s and figured themselves out enough to date. Whereas when you're 19 or 24, you may be insecure, not understanding yourself, and have a selection bias in terms of what you want to see. 

All people are picky in dating. I don't think anyone wants to date someone who feels like a step down. I'd say most people want to date the "upper tier" of what they're attracted to. It's just not the same for everyone. I just have never met someone whose long term dating approach is "I don't want someone who is a catch."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
