<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44198800200.0" user="hapidaron" delta="False">
    <text>I've never heard anybody reasonable claim that women are going for the "upper tier". Percentage of people who have been married at least once is well above 50% IIRC, And obviously, 50+% of people can't be "upper tier".

Attractiveness is a complex thing, and physical appearance is just one dimension.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199346663.0" user="Popularopionstates" delta="False">
    <text>Relationship wise, no.  Casual sex wise, yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199552386.0" user="UnlikelyClothes5761" delta="False">
    <text>Not for lack of trying though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199778835.0" user="ImmodestPolitician" delta="False">
    <text>If you filter your dating options for College or greater degree(36%) and not overweight, that limits the dating pool to 20% of men.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
