<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199066244.0" user="LexicalMountain" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy.

Agreed. Because the framing is judgemental. Which is not necessary or helpful when analysing innocuous things that don't have significant moral implications. "Women are too choosy" is judgemental with paternalistic undertones. "Women are _more_ choosy (than men)" however, is pretty much the research consensus.

There have been tonnes of studies, pretty much all showing the same thing. Of those that I remember, there was one where college students were asked point blank if they'd sleep with an attractive stranger of the opposite sex that night. The male students responded with yes about 60% of the time. The female students, 0%. Now, of course, one could make the argument, that there might have been some that were open to it but for societal, reputational, safety or other concerns, wouldn't say yes immediately, but that's not a rebuttal, it's an explanation. The truth of the matter is that for the majority of the young men, just seeing the model was enough to agree, whereas, for the women, it wasn't. More hoops needed to be jumped through.

Another interesting one was just showing male and female judges scores of pictures of members the opposite sex, asking for a 1-10 rating for each. The men judging women averaged their judgement at around 5. The women, on average, judged the men closer to 2. So, in this study, at least, men see women as more attractive than women see men. Which of course means that if a man and a woman have the exact same bar of attraction (both will only date someone who's a 6 or above in their eyes, let's say), the man will see there to be far more women that meet his standard than the woman will see men.

The same discrepancy is borne out in dating site statistics, but to the extreme, showing far less engagement in one direction than the other. Though the extent of the asymmetry should be taken with a grain of salt as the nature of dating sites does not perfectly reflect the nature of normal interactions. I saw [this](https://youtu.be/x3lypVnJ0HM?si=c5zJBXDm8ZAN7imO) interesting video talking about dating sites, using simulations, if you wanna watch it.

Anyway, yeah, I'd steer clear of statements of condemnation like "women are too choosy" or "they only go for the higher tier of men" but we shouldn't throw the baby out with the bath water. The baby being the genuine researched validity of the claim that women are _more_ choosy than men. Or men are _less_ choosy than women. The two statements are functionally identical but sometimes the female centric framing can tell about someone's leaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199435084.0" user="Stiblex" delta="False">
    <text>Great answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199446599.0" user="Yamochao" delta="False">
    <text>This one goes into the math a bit, it’s fairly clear for online dating:

https://medium.com/@worstonlinedater/tinder-experiments-ii-guys-unless-you-are-really-hot-you-are-probably-better-off-not-wasting-your-2ddf370a6e9a

However, the same can’t be said for meeting women in the world, I think it’s more of an artifact of gender imbalances in swiping apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199476014.0" user="LexicalMountain" delta="False">
    <text>That's what's interested me about most of the replies. The idea and much of the research supporting it, was done before internet dating existed. The earliest I can recall was done in the 1970s. So, as I mentioned above, the nature of dating apps causes something of a feedback loop that exacerbates the asymmetry, there has to be an asymmetry in the first place _to_ exacerbate. And this was postulated for decades prior to online dating existing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199660751.0" user="rogthnor" delta="False">
    <text>That survey has a pretty severe bias towards assuming attraction is (or should be) the major determinant of whether you sleep with someone.

I imagine if they question had been "would you sleep with someone rich" or "would you sleep with a person who made you laugh" or something other metric you would have seen vastly different results. Saying "men are less choosy because they are more likely to sleep with an attractive person all other factors being the same" isn't a logically complete statement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199685216.0" user="ImmodestPolitician" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; That survey has a pretty severe bias towards assuming attraction is (or should be) the major determinant of whether you sleep with someone.

Do you sleep with people you aren't attracted too?

I think most people need to find something attractive, even if it's not just looks, about a person before they are willing to sleep with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199728908.0" user="jasmine-blossom" delta="False">
    <text>There are lots of reasons to find someone attractive though. If I was shown a photo of my bf with no other info, I’d have said I’m not really attracted to him. There’s only one man I have ever dated who falls under “conventionally attractive according to patriarchy,” and I still needed to get to know him too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199839450.0" user="rogthnor" delta="False">
    <text>This. Attraction is only one metric.

This would be like if I asked men and women "would you eat this food" while showing a picture of a roast beef sandwich and assumed men were less picky because they are more likely to eat it. Maybe women just don't like roast beef</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199980039.0" user="jasmine-blossom" delta="False">
    <text>Yea maybe she’s vegan or maybe she prefers her meat more rare or more well done or maybe she cares about what condiments are on the sandwich or what bread is being used. 

I don’t get how men are like “women are shallow” but like dude, there are people of both sexes that are shallow. I’m not whining over men seeking skinny blondes with fake boobs just because it’s easier for those women to get laid and find men willing to be in relationships with them. Why would I be upset over those men? They aren’t looking for what I’m offering, so I can either go find someone who’s looking for what I’m offering, or I can change what I’m offering. I can’t stop those men from being attracted to those women and it’s silly of me to try or even care about that. 

 
Most of us aren’t that shallow and recognize other traits that attract us to someone beyond their fitting into a stereotype of beauty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200008123.0" user="LexicalMountain" delta="False">
    <text>I cannot understate the amount of research done in this field, though. If you think that doesn't suffice, there's so much more (and google scholar is a godsend), all pointing towards the same conclusion, a conclusion which ties into fairly sound evolutionary ethology and hypotheses based on anisogamy. Also, worth noting that physical appearance is obvious. Pretty much every other trait like wealth or humour has to be displayed, which is a bar that the person in question may not be able or willing to clear.

Plus other research into frequency and intensity of companionship aligns with what I've said. Surveys asking "what's the most you would sacrifice for a shot with the girl/guy of your dreams?" and "what's the most you would pay for a kiss with the person you find most attractive in the world?" (thus controlling for any differences in _why_ they're attracted to them) tend to get much higher sacrifices from men, and surveys asking how often people want to look for a partner skew the same way, same for surveys asking how much worse being single is compared to being in a relationship. All of it aligns with the fairly standard, simple conclusions that one can draw from evolutionary ethology, considering the gap in physical investment in procreating between the sexes and the inherently one sided risk of parental uncertainty, which is nearly always paternal. Maybe I'm biased from having to read all this shit and then write about it but to me it's as obvious as anything can be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200057150.0" user="pretenditscherrylube" delta="False">
    <text>Those surveys also don’t take into account the rates of female orgasm in one-time encounters (abysmally low). I’m a slutty woman and I would say no because there’s no guarantee just looking at a guy that the sex will be good. Let alone that he will be a respectful, ethical sex partner. All these types of studies show is that straight men tend to be lazy sexual partners in hookups at best and predators at worst.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200099593.0" user="LexicalMountain" delta="False">
    <text>This ties in to what I said earlier, this isn't a rebuttal, it's an explanation. It's not a statement that disputes that women are choosier, it's a statement that explains _why_ women are choosier. And, while of course, expected performance will be a factor, safety tends to be the larger one, especially with strangers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199707894.0" user="ThemesOfMurderBears" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The truth of the matter is that for the majority of the young men, just seeing the model was enough to agree, whereas, for the women, it wasn't.

I am not sure that this particular example is all that helpful. This is strictly "would you sleep with a stranger tonight", and doesn't necessarily tell us anything about whether or not women are more picky in their choices when it comes to *relationships.* It seems like the mitigating factor is the "tonight" part, so this feels like a question about "sex on a first date." That would tell me that men are more willing than women to jump right into bed, which I suspect most would agree with intuitively (it certainly lines up with my anecdotal experience).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200056764.0" user="LexicalMountain" delta="False">
    <text>They were shown the person, not a picture. The model was instructed to remain silent and neutral. Sorry, I was writing as if I'd already outlined the study in the "procedure" segment of the essay since that's how, well, I did it the first time, all those years ago. Regardless, I acknowledge that the study has gaps, as all social studies do, but it's just a drop in the bucket. There are tonnes of other studies asking about hypothetical people, referring to kissing, sleeping with, dating and marrying. It's an asymmetry that saturates much of human behaviour.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
