<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199429851.0" user="blueeyed94" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously, what's the "upper tier" anyway? If it comes to physical attractiveness: Everyone has their own taste. Oh, the times my girl friends and I debated over "how cute he is" and I was rolling my eyes... The only thing most women agree to is that Flynn Rider is most likely the most attractive disney male lead. At least I have never heard someone say something different 😂
There are so many things that make a person attractive for us, good looks is only a small one. I fell in love with my now husband when we were awkward, late teenagers with no money of our own and pimples everywhere. That was ten years ago, and I wouldn't change him for anything in this world. Like I know that he wouldn't throw my depressed ass on the street because he couldn't handle my only recently diagnosed ADHD anymore. Would others consider him an "upper tier" man? Probably not. But for me, he surely is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
