<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="56" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44225636061.0" user="pseudonymmed" delta="False">
    <text>No, women aren’t all going for some “upper tier” of men. Women might be more choosy about a wider range of factors when it comes to relationships, but they’re not all going for the same 10 or 20 percentage of men. People like to take one piece if data out of context to make claims and ignore all the other data. They can take a random sampling of tik tok ragebait as some kind if “proof” for something when you could easily find “proof” for the opposite if you look.
The same study that showed women rated men’s looks more harshly also showed that women message average looking men the most while men message the hottest women disproportionally. 

https://techcrunch.com/2009/11/18/okcupid-inbox-attractive/amp/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
