<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="37" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199561293.0" user="FlyChigga" delta="False">
    <text>It mostly affects gen z, not people in their 30s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199664835.0" user="BadgerSame6600" delta="False">
    <text>people in their 30s are single too y'know haha. I have been single for 3 years not. Not had a date since Feb this year. I don't blame women for this. I quite literally do everything alone, I am either running , mountain hiking and being with my dog, if not that I am at work. Work in a tiny office (people wise), don't drink, don't smoke anything, so there ya go, it would be a miracle for me to meet someone. I did look on Tinder but I live in a small town, so I reached the 'end' pretty fast.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199685985.0" user="FlyChigga" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t only affect gen z but it affects gen z more if that makes sense. This generation was raised on social media which is extremely elitist and naturally affects people’s mindset.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
