<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44198809690.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>This highly depends on context. 

It's unquestionably what happens in online dating.

There is data that shows that about 10% of men on online websites get 60% of all replies by Women:

https://qz.com/1051462/these-statistics-show-why-its-so-hard-to-be-an-average-man-on-dating-apps

It's much more more difficult to translates this to real world of long term relationships, but it is not simply data we can ignore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198962417.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is where the entire myth originally stems from, because dating apps are such a poor tool for both men and women. Not only are there far more men in general which explains the pickiness, but also for women capabilities like charisma, confidence, intelligence etc. are far more important to build up attraction, so men are naturally handicapped on dating apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198998738.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is that couples meeting online is now 40% of all couples and [rising](https://cdn.statcdn.com/Infographic/images/normal/20822.jpeg)

So again, it's not something we can ignore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199252751.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>Online doesn't mean dating apps though, you can meet someone through gaming or being in the same selfhelp or hobby group. That experience is not equal to dating apps, because there you do connect with various people, get to know them and then if you happen to like someone you meet up - they are not pre-swiped by looks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199420444.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>

I bet vast vast majority of online meetings were via dating apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199509707.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>"I bet" is no evidence, I would say the opposite. You were also not talking online meetings but relationships, please understand your own studies before you post them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199828307.0" user="ThemesOfMurderBears" delta="False">
    <text>The page itself has some info on this:

&gt;With the help of dating apps like Tinder and eHarmony, but also through social networking sites like Facebook, daters reconnected with old friends and acquaintances (8 percent of couples who met online), were introduced to someone (11 percent) or – in the majority of cases – met someone completely new on their own (81 percent).

It does not tell us what percentage comes from dating apps versus social networking sites, but clearly they consider both to be part of what they designate as "online."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199262905.0" user="Pseudoboss11" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder how many of those were with dating apps vs social media or other places?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199705427.0" user="rollingForInitiative" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.statista.com/chart/20822/way-of-meeting-partner-heterosexual-us-couples/

It doesn’t really break down the different places “online”, but it seems to include everything online. Being introduced to a partner through an online friend, reconnecting with someone over Facebook, all manner of social media, etc.

So it’s not all dating apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44203033261.0" user="LaMadreDelCantante" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me the best solution for that is for men who aren't having luck with online dating apps to focus more on meeting people in real life. The ratios are better for you and you get a chance to make a real impression beyond a few pictures and a profile. Plus, if you are a man having no luck on online dating apps, that's really the only thing you have the power to change other than improving your profile, which might help but the odds are still pretty badly against you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199108379.0" user="Poly_and_RA" delta="False">
    <text>Yepp. I'm convinced that's the entire explanation. 

What would **ANYONE** do if they signed up for a dating-app and then in the first day they get 20+ matches? 

They'd become a whole lot more selective about which profiles they like, and who they send messages to and/or respond to, that's what. There's no alternative! It's not as if anyone \*can\* engage with hundreds of matches per week!

What would **ANYONE** do if they sign up for a dating-app, and then in the first week of using it they get 0-2 matches, none of which respond when you send them a message?

They'd become a whole lot **less** selective about which profiles they like, and who they respond to -- of course. No harm in giving people a chance if there's only the tiniest trickle of attention anyway. 

So yes, hard agree. It's not that women are inherently more picky; it's just a \*response\* and a perfectly rational at that, to a reality where most women on dating-sites are FLOODED with attention, and most men are STARVING for attention.

(\*why\* that happens on all dating-sites is another question entirely!)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199337887.0" user="LittleFloppyFella" delta="False">
    <text>They why is not a different question at all, it’s entirely baked into the same premise. As a man who has been successful in dating both people I meet in real life and in online dating, most guys really do just seem to be fucked.

I would hear girls constantly talk about how shitty so many other guys are, when candidly it seems they all just think they deserve the top of the top. They are then floored when I was not interested in pursuing things further because they just assume guys will be super clingy. It’s tiring, but edating and meeting people irl tend to work the same way in my experience, most girls over value themselves and most guys destroy their self esteem because these girls will hold out for dudes that will never actually settle down with them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199397800.0" user="Poly_and_RA" delta="False">
    <text>It is absolutely a different question. Because while OLD is extremely dominated by men with most sites having something like 3 to 5 men signed up for every 1 woman signed up, and a even **MORE** uneven distribution among active users (Tinder has, as an example, about 10 men for every 1 woman among their active users) -- dating **in general** isn't like that.

Instead, a fairly high fraction of both women and men want romantic and sexual relationships to be part of their lives, and since most people are both straight and monogamous, it follows that in the world in general, most women want a partner; and so they end up dating most men.

But OLD is different. There's a huge imbalance, and most women are flooded while most men get incredibly close to zero attention at all.

I'm polyamorous myself, and have observed the same thing in my own life. I feel fairly popular and well-liked in most social settings where women have a chance to get to know me. I'm someone with 4 current lovers (two girlfriends and two fwbs) -- who nevertheless, if I was judging by OLD, would have to conclude that nobody wants me. (which is clearly wrong in the larger picture)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199987061.0" user="LittleFloppyFella" delta="False">
    <text>I believe dating in general absolutely is like that. I have many friends who will not have interest from a girl in the same time span I may have met and spoken to many. There are a lot of guys who are not dating, because they literally just can’t get interest. Girls go after the top percent, has been my experience both online and offline.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44202413810.0" user="Poly_and_RA" delta="False">
    <text>Very early stages in dating is a bit like that. It becomes LESS like that the more long-term a relationship is and the better you know each other.

Being physically hot is ENORMOUSLY helpful if your goal is to get laid today, with some stranger.

It matters not-that-much if your goal is for your 3-month relationship to be just as happy and healthy a decade down the road.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44202602928.0" user="LittleFloppyFella" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah no kidding, this entire discussion is about guys getting screened before they can attempt to show what virtues they have other than physical appearance and surface level details regarding your life. The whole conversation is about the early stages, which most guys cannot get past.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199784421.0" user="wycreater1l11" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with this. The same phenomenon exist in places like club-like environments but to a lesser extreme. I agree with this but a weird dismissive undertone can be read into it. Sadly, for a lot of us younger folks the extremification of the phenomenon seems/is simply all too real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44202963963.0" user="Poly_and_RA" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that bad. Sure it **IS** that bad in online dating, and places like the club-scene. So yes, many men will just have to come to terms with the fact that going to a typical space for pickups, be it Tinder or the local nightclub, and find a lover -- just won't happen. At all. Ever. 

And that's a bit sad, if that's something you'd like to experience.

But it shouldn't be overstated. The vast **MAJORITY** of dating, including hookups, happen not between strangers, but instead among people from the same social circles that know each other for quite a while before their first date or first shared night.

And frankly, isn't it usually BETTER and a BIGGER compliment if some woman who knows you well is into you? I'd **certainly** choose that! (but sure, once in a while it'd be nice if strangers would also find me hot, but as you say, that rarely happen for most straight men)

Myself I have a dating-life that's beyond anything I would've dared dream as a young man. I'm poly and currently have 2 girlfriends and 2 fwbs, which is downright \*astounding\* -- but you're right; **ZERO** of those women started out by being strangers into me, they all got to know me first and then liked me **after** that, not before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199464238.0" user="Parking-Ad-5211" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;dating apps are such a poor tool for both men and women.

I don't agree with that. I avoided dating sites (the predecessor to dating apps) and then dating apps in favor of meeting women IRL for years. I was very social and had many hobbies yet never got as much as a date. Frustrated I gave Coffee Meets Bagel a try. I had nothing but good experiences from it and within a year I met my now wife.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199540269.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>If you look at the overall success rate of dating apps it turns out to be a poor tool, ofc there are some people who will make good experiences as well, it there weren't I wouldn't rate it "poor" but "horrible". Personally I uninstalled the only dating app I ever had after a day, because the experience was uncomfortably overwhelming and it felt completely pointless to swipe someone solely based on looks and a 3 sentence self description. I met all of my partners through friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199704603.0" user="Parking-Ad-5211" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I met all of my partners through friends.

Not everyone has that luxury though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200394293.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>Of course not. But if you have trouble finding any friends then it's also likely you have trouble finding a partner. Nevertheless there's a billion other ways as well, online Dating just generally has very low success rates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199769270.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>There are several other links in the comments here where similar patterns were observed in dating as far back as the 70s, and where women routinely rated men as less attractive on average than men rated women. It might be exaggerated by online dating, but I don't think it's fair to say it's a myth that started with dating apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200278956.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, as I've explained, if you are comparing only pictures then men are naturally handicapped, because to women allot of other factors are more important than they are to men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200303560.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>And how does that account for the phenomenon pre-dating apps?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200401909.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>It accounts to exactly what you wrote if I'm guessing the study correctly that you're referring to, cause there they only showed the contestant pictures.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200495649.0" user="WakeoftheStorm" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, possibly. I'll be honest I skimmed it for the findings not the methodology</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200659984.0" user="PolarDracarys" delta="False">
    <text>Methodology is the key factor you should look for before you quote any study, so often it completely changes your view on the outcome. There's usually multiple pages in studies explaining why the results are limited in significance due to methodology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199077856.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>I saw these statistics and the accompanying article on OKCupid which compared “average males” and “average females” with pictures. The “average” males:

- had uninteresting haircuts that might as well have rolled straight out of bed with no way to really tell
- did not have groomed eyebrows
- clearly did not do any skincare or makeup

Essentially, it was unclear what at all they did to improve the quality of their head except shaving their facial hair which was the only thing shown in that picture.

The “average” females:

- All clearly had haircuts that required some care in the morning
- All had groomed eyebrows
- All clearly did some kind of skincare, or simply naturally had far better looking skin than average
- Probably also all removed facial hair in some capacity

This was on a platform where essentially looks are everything to be selected. It seems like the classical story of demanding even outcome rather than even opportunity to me. Females who put the same effort into their appearance as the “average” male on those websites wouldn't be faring well either I'd say, potentially even worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199107158.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>I higlh doubt that the difference between top 10% and bottom 90% is groomed eyebrows.

Almost no male does that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199161098.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and what you do now is pic out the weakest argument from a summation that is meant to provide several contributing factors, and act like that is the only thing I said.

Obviously haircut and quality of skin are more important, but groomed eyebrows doesn't hurt either and that almost no male, except of course those working in showbusiness whose look are their selling point who do suddenly find the time for all those things I listed, would serve as an explanation for the issues they claim to be having.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199176383.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>I want to see if top 10% of males have interesting haircuts or superior skin care.

Again. I don't think that this is what separates top and bottom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199234525.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I want to see if top 10% of males have interesting haircuts or superior skin care.

Some of them will, some of them won't. Obviously a very good looking face can offset a lack of grooming, just as proper grooming can offset a lack of a very good looking face.

&gt; Again. I don't think that this is what separates top and bottom.

Then why does every male showman clearly do it in every public appearance?

[It clearly makes a considerable differencel](https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Tqukz_yJ76fskY2r_nQ18mSuNco6CDZqvHVr-zd3Z8D1YeQnoH0jLHC0bDTm8Nt-tWT3VqU_S-Lu_47YorwwMMX5OQB4jMkSXA=w780-nu-rj-l80-e365), which picture do you think will score better?

&gt; But groomed eyebrows was such a weird thing to mention

It's simply something that immediately stands out and it's definitely something that contributes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199415680.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>I suspect the two profiles will score about the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199711183.0" user="BadgerSame6600" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, these guys are both attractive. I don't get this comparison</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44202984177.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>Your expectations betray you are clueless to be honest.

One indeed looks somewhat “average” though probably better. The other looks at what it is: a professional model of pristine skin quality one will rarely found outside of such a professional world</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44203287421.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>Yet, I don't think that would make a difference for matches</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44203326965.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>There's a reason people in boybands all look like the right, not like the left.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199825387.0" user="EmotionalEnding" delta="False">
    <text>One guy is whiter than the other and with your context of it being about who is more attractive that looks pretty bad for you ngl

They're both about the same attractiveness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44202966607.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>Both are the same person...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199263824.0" user="Workacct1999" delta="False">
    <text>And don't forget about all those dudes wearing make up!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199488191.0" user="AdequateTaco" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, agreed. The “average male” who complains about not being able to get any attention is typically a slob who doesn’t put any effort into his appearance or making his profile look decent. When I was online dating, probably 75% of the male profiles were awful- first photo is a bathroom selfie with a dirty mirror, or one where they clearly cropped out another woman (presumably their ex). And their bio is some weird joke or it’s blank. You can’t even put on a clean shirt, go outside, and spend 5 minutes taking a decently lit selfie and filling out your profile?

Yet when I had ANY photos up with me not wearing makeup and dressed like I was on my way to a club (because I was hiking, camping, kayaking, etc and wanted to show my interests) I’d get men matching with me just to tell me that I looked like shit. God forbid you’re a woman who never wears makeup and tries online dating!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44204716668.0" user="Theevildothatido" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the quality of the pictures is another issue I did not address.

They are often not trained in the noble and deceptive art of the selfie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199077924.0" user="ScarySuit" delta="False">
    <text>It's worth noting that the bottom 50% for women from that link only get 7.8% of replies. Dating is tough for women too, but the focus is always on how hard it is on men for some reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199114206.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>That's true, but it does not really affect my point, just expands on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199694033.0" user="BadgerSame6600" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, this is a good point. Why do we settle for this shitty corporate meddling in our love lives? OND has changed things massively and not for the better it seems (except the lucky ones like the commentator above).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199786410.0" user="Fudelan" delta="False">
    <text>That's still 50% more than men</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199934202.0" user="ScarySuit" delta="False">
    <text>Percent is misleading since both are small values. I'm not saying there isn't a difference, but the difference is less important than the fact that they are both small values compared to what you would expect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200059110.0" user="Fudelan" delta="False">
    <text>That's fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199311353.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>As a woman who used dating apps, Most men on those apps just send pictures of their dicks and start demanding sex within five seconds. Their shitty behavior is the reason why they get rejected. Less than 30% of women use dating apps. And of those profiles, there are bots and scammers. 

Needless to say all the men who take awful photos with literal shit floating in the toilet bowl of their bathroom selfies and dead fish pictures.

It's extremely disingenuous to talk about women's "lack of interest" on dating apps while completely ignoring the behavior of men on dating apps, which have ultimately run women off of most of the platforms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199397182.0" user="J9AC9K" delta="False">
    <text>Not that you're wrong, but it's worth noting that you can't get a dick pic unless you match with a man, and as noted the top 10% of men are getting nearly all the matches. Because of this, they get to be the choosy assholes; they send dick pics because they aren't interested in you.

But the bottom 90% of men aren't sending dick pics because they aren't getting matches. So telling them to just stop sending dick pics isn't helpful advice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199416311.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>As a woman. No, Most men do this. Even the one's that complain they never get any matches. The men who say they get little to no attention from women behave the worst. 

They're all engaging in this behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199500349.0" user="plushpaper" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds fishy. How do you know that the ones who complain they aren’t getting any matches do this? Did they tell you they don’t get many matches when you matched with them or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199546355.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>They talk about how poor their experience has been on the apps in the conversation. So yes, they inform me of their online dating experience. 

Then they proceed to be sexually inappropriate, then throw a self pity tantrum or an aggressive tantrum when called out on their behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199553574.0" user="rustcohle02" delta="False">
    <text>She doesn’t. She’s just generalizing all men. I know plenty of men and none of them have sent dick picks to women as far as I know. I don’t even know the point of doing it so idk what this chick is talking about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199589916.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>They've done some studies on it. The estimate is like 22%, ±5%,  of men have sent at least one unsolicited dick pic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199648562.0" user="Commander_Uhltes" delta="False">
    <text>Well, 80% of women getting at least one over their entire dating history, and about 20% of men doing it at least once in their life, are pretty far removed from "all men are actively engaging in this behaviour". So yeah, ApatheticMill is still being sexist and and generalising against men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199700167.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>It probably wasn't meant to be taken literally, and was being said out of frustration. I think a lot of people talk like this.

I understand the frustration though with feeling targeted for something you've never done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199875422.0" user="ThemesOfMurderBears" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I know plenty of men and none of them have sent dick picks to women as far as I know. 

I suspect most wouldn't admit to doing this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44203261649.0" user="LaMadreDelCantante" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they tell you if they did?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199547880.0" user="nikdahl" delta="False">
    <text>This is such a toxic bigoted opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199561191.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>My lived experience is toxic and bigoted? lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199569333.0" user="nikdahl" delta="False">
    <text>Your insistence that this is most men is what toxic. 

Your prejudice against all men is what’s toxic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199589263.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so you're going to invalidate my experiences and not "All men" me to death. I'm not interested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199743468.0" user="OfTheAtom" delta="False">
    <text>Your thoughts are invalid because they are stupid. Same rules as the rest of us you just put yours up more often for consideration</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44208440089.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/OfTheAtom – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20OfTheAtom&amp;message=OfTheAtom%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/-/kazdwbw/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44208441022.0" user="AbolishDisney" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199908882.0" user="ThemesOfMurderBears" delta="False">
    <text>I took her comment as "most men I've interacted with on dating sites" -- not "all men in general," or even "most men in general."

I don't know her, but I suspect she would not agree with the statement "most men send unsolicited dick pics."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44208438822.0" user="AbolishDisney" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44208442735.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/nikdahl – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20nikdahl&amp;message=nikdahl%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/-/kaza5yt/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199572837.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>What do you define as most men? Do you think more than half of all men have sent a dick pic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199608928.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>The overly sexual and highly inappropriate sexual behavior immediately is a common theme. The lack of impulse control regarding any sexual idea that pops into their heads has been my frequent experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199689979.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>That's really not an answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199743184.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>Yes it is, redditors just have a habit of hyper focusing on one point and ignoring every other aspect of a conversation. Talking about this is irrelevant anyways, as men will just "nuh uhh" my comment thread to death as if they have experience with dating their own sex. 

It's amusing because gay and bisexual men don't disagree with me and have the same exact experience with dating men. Heterosexual men are the only demographic that attempts to tell me that my lived experiences never happened and don't happen on a regular basis with various men from various backgrounds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199824852.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's part of human nature to be frustrated when you are lumped into a group of people doing the wrong thing and are innocent.

That being said, I don't doubt your lived experience though, both with getting unsolicited pics or getting the "not all men" comments.

That still doesn't mean you've answered my question though, which is fine. I know the actual numbers, and while most men is a vast overstatement, it's still way higher than I would have ever guessed. It's actually kind of terrifying how high is it, so I don't blame you for being a bit vitriolic about the topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199874554.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>No, I think men have a tendency to to view themselves collectively. I never said  "ALL" men, but that is often what these conversations get reduced to. Where men derail the conversation in an attempt to make the topic become a worship session for specific individual men who compost and volunteer to help senior citizens. 

It's a control thing. They don't see themselves as separate from one another, which is why they can never separate themselves individually from any negative act that people describe. They take all the praise for other men's accomplishments and good deeds as a collective, then pretend that no man has ever engaged in any of the negative behaviors and that it's just a "few". 

It's exhausting and boring. I did answer your question. I'm not being vitriolic, I've simply explained my experience on dating apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199962094.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>You can try to spin it whatever way you want, but you didn't answer the question. I asked what you define as most. I didn't ask you about your experience. The only way to answer my question is with a percentage. Anything else is just dodging the question.

&gt;  I'm not being vitriolic

That may not be your intention, but that is how your comments are largely going to being perceived.

It's like if I went and told a group of women they are statistically worse drivers because they cause more accidents, I'm going to come off as a misogynistic asshole. It doesn't matter if that's objectively true and that I'm just trying to share facts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200015469.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not spinning anything. I don't have any interested on specifically discussing dick pictures alone. The redundancy in the conversation isn't what I have an interest in. You're deliberately ignoring the bad behavior that I'm referring to on purpose. It's not just the dick pictures, it's the inappropriate sexually explicit behavior that happens immediately that is the problem. 

No, I'm just a woman that you're attempting to whip in line. You're reading text. You're emoting onto it because that's how you feel when you're reading what I write. 

If you said "Every time I drive a woman that is on her phone or putting on makeup while driving crashes into me." I'm not going to call you a liar and say "NOT ALL WOMEN."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200037244.0" user="Merakel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; No, I'm just a woman that you're attempting to whip in line.

And I'm the one emoting onto you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199424811.0" user="southpolefiesta" delta="False">
    <text>To send a dick pick you would have to match. Which most men don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199464968.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>Women aren't on the apps anymore because men kept sending dick pics and behaving terribly on the apps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199664491.0" user="Commander_Uhltes" delta="False">
    <text>That's just demonstrably false. There are still plenty of women on them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199701325.0" user="ImmodestPolitician" delta="False">
    <text>If you are reported for sending dick pics on a dating app you will be banned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199754685.0" user="ApatheticMill" delta="False">
    <text>It's sexually explicit behavior in itself. One guy sends a dick picture, the next guy asks to get his dick sucked, the next guy asks or says something else sexually inappropriate immediately. It's a never ending sea of the same behavior. It's easier to simply delete the app than report every profile that's doing the same exact thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199318437.0" user="Popularopionstates" delta="False">
    <text>The only real world statistic to show who women go for is to look at the number of sexual partners people have.  On average, men a women have the same number.  But, if you look at a more individual basis, you'll see that most women have had more sexual partners than most men.  The reason behind this is a smaller % of men will have a very high number, pulling the whole male average up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199355762.0" user="wibblywobbly420" delta="False">
    <text>I would be interested in seeing these statistics you are quoting because it has not been my experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199403071.0" user="CommunicationFun7973" delta="False">
    <text>It literally goes both ways, it's not "individual basis women have more", it's the exact same story on both sides. Some women have had a fuck load of partners, some men have had a fuck load of partners. The stats show men generally have a higher body count per individual, actually. Most men have had more sexual partners than most women, as per the CDC. The majority of women have had 1-9 partners, the majority of men have had over 5-15.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199587416.0" user="pseudonymmed" delta="False">
    <text>Where is that stat from? Studies in the US and UK show men have a slightly higher number than women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44223949826.0" user="Popularopionstates" delta="False">
    <text>Are you talking mode or mean average?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199352436.0" user="AspiringTomato" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone misunderstands this statistic. 

There are much less women on dating platforms to begin with. 

In reality, the 10 women on the platform are replying to 10 men, but the other 50 men don't get a message. 

No one's disproportionately stealing your attention, there are just a lot more men on dating sites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199443319.0" user="c1pe" delta="False">
    <text>There are fewer women, but that doesn't explain the matching gap near fully. Overall population is one of five or six factors, and not the biggest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199477144.0" user="AspiringTomato" delta="False">
    <text>Overall population is the largest factor, numerous studies have shown this already. 

Another significant decisive factor is the recommendation system most apps use - more popular accounts get shown first, giving an advantage to accounts that are already popular. 

Another factor is the lack of effort men put toward creating a good profile. Societally, men make fun of each other for behaviours that are deemed "unmasculine", and being vain, (aka. Spending a lot of time on looks and taking nice pictures) has been looked down upon. 

Enough with the "top 10%" nonsense stereotype. Stop blaming women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199864865.0" user="c1pe" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't blame anyone for anything - even if women were only swiping on the top 10%, that wouldn't be their fault, it would be the fault of the algorithm for showing them people they are unlikely to match with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199554159.0" user="rpujoe" delta="False">
    <text>That's not how it works. There's nearly 2-3:1 more men than women on the apps, but regardless of the numbers only the same 5% of men get the overwhelming majority of matches. That's the Porche Polygyny Professor Scott Galloway has been talking about in recent years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199579269.0" user="AspiringTomato" delta="False">
    <text>It's natural for people to be drawn to people they find the most attractive, and its definitely one of the many facets of the platform. 

However, blaming this one factor and elevating it to be the most important one is a self-defeating view used by many men to justify their own shortcomings. 

This applies to both genders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44225569069.0" user="pseudonymmed" delta="False">
    <text>And most of the men are messaging to hottest women. It goes both ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44225976573.0" user="rpujoe" delta="False">
    <text>The dating apps say you're wrong. Men message women in an equitable bell curve distribution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44228300213.0" user="pseudonymmed" delta="False">
    <text>
https://medium.com/refinery29/average-looking-men-get-more-messages-on-dating-apps-7d4aff590f85

https://techcrunch.com/2009/11/18/okcupid-inbox-attractive/amp/

https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/15/style/dating-apps-online-men-women-age.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199394959.0" user="taralundrigan" delta="False">
    <text>It's definitely data we can ignore, especially with absolutely no nuance. Men's dating profiles often have minimal information about them, usually with bad pictures and when I was using these apps, the type of engagement I got from men was low effort. 'hey' is a horrible way to start a conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199800416.0" user="s1lentchaos" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair on the hey they might want to make sure you are there before starting a conversation, opening with some grand philosophical question is incredibly awkward, small talk first then big talk.

As for dick pics most apps don't let users share images you may need to spend more time vetting them on the in app messenger before going to snap chat or whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199520792.0" user="pseudonymmed" delta="False">
    <text>But stats also show a similar effect of men towards women, they disproportionally contact the youngest hottest women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199582089.0" user="One-Organization970" delta="False">
    <text>My fiance and I (women) helped a friend of mine rewrite his profile on dating sites. He immediately went from nothing to getting dates, and now has a girlfriend. I've seen it occur repeatedly with other men I know as well. A lot of dudes don't know how to market themselves to women - I.E. don't give off the vibe that their prospective date's skinned corpse will be found in a roadside ditch somewhere - and it's a matter of bad profiles rather than bad men.

Which is really just reinforcing your point that this isn't easily applicable to real world relationships. Swiping is an efficiency puzzle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199601667.0" user="CleanEnd5983" delta="False">
    <text>There's also research that shows that many online chats don't end up in a meetup.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
