<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199303525.0" user="Wend-E-Baconator" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances, the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

That "or" seems problematic. Being stronger in one category but weaker in all others hardly proves the arguments you intend to make. 

&gt;Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy.

This is one of the most well-researched and stable findings in social science. Yes, women prefer to date men who are peers or who offer some sort of advantage. It's so stable [it's got its own Wikipedia page](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mating_preferences#:~:text=In%20sum%2C%20men%20appear%20to,social%20status%2C%20and%20financial%20stability.). The key is that these things (particularly social and financial) are more seriously influenced by age than anything else. At the statistical level, this bears out on women's statistical preference to date slightly older, more established men. It gets more complicated in old age, but when talking about the dating market the discussion is usually centered around child rearing age. 

&gt;My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them.

In some cases, this is very true. It's certainly the viewpoint pushed by feminist outlets, which have been well-established in media for nearly 70 years and which have gained new life from their capitalization of short-form media. But it doesn't explain the massive statistical disparity we can observe in the population. More young men than women are single, and that gap is [wider than ever before](https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/2020/08/20/a-profile-of-single-americans/). The market imbalances are older women and younger men. This imbalance has more to do with older men having more money and a more established social circle than younger men, and pulling a limited supply of young women upwards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199443769.0" user="Wooden-Ad-3382" delta="False">
    <text>how would we ever have any real idea why there's an imbalance in young men vs young women in relationships, it could be any number of things</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199455761.0" user="Wend-E-Baconator" delta="False">
    <text>Because when you ask the same questions over the course of centuries, you get the same answers. Those answers spill over into the non-romantic as well. Those answers are also supported by biological incentives of the environment of primary adaptation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199748089.0" user="Wooden-Ad-3382" delta="False">
    <text>what if its just younger women marrying older men</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199752121.0" user="Wend-E-Baconator" delta="False">
    <text>What mechanism of action would create that statistical change?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199789549.0" user="Wooden-Ad-3382" delta="False">
    <text>if im understanding what that means correctly, its men preferring to date younger women, and women preferring to date men who are of high status/income</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199794226.0" user="Wend-E-Baconator" delta="False">
    <text>That is the statistical trend observed for centuries, yes. Although "high" isn't nearly so important as "stable"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199500514.0" user="SageHamichi" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It's so stable   
&gt;  
&gt;it's got its own Wikipedia page  
&gt;  
&gt;.

like wikipedia is this very prestiged science mag or something ahah got a chuckle out of me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199539255.0" user="Wend-E-Baconator" delta="False">
    <text>Wikipedia generally only gives pages to things that are super mundane (although the details aren't always)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
