<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44198736332.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them.

Or far more likely they are just too damn picky themselves.

And it's not exactly an easy thing to fix either. You don't choose who you are sexually attracted to. I can't take a look at some smelly homeless person say "I shall henceforth be attracted to you" and magically poof they suddenly look like Jessica Alba. It's actually a fairly difficult problem to deal with, that nobody appears to want to tackle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198827741.0" user="NaturalCarob5611" delta="False">
    <text>Attraction based solely on physical features can be hard to change, but in my experience that's only the surface level part of attraction, and even if physical attraction is there, personality will dominate attraction once you get to know them. One of the big problems with dating apps is that they put pretty much the whole emphasis on physical attraction.

That's not to say your smelly homeless person will poof into Jessica Alba once you get to know her personality, but if people were out meeting in person instead of filtering people on physical attractiveness through an app that gives them nothing else to go on, they might find someone who has qualities they like a bit below the surface.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198842421.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Yes that's kind of what I meant by "not exactly an easy thing to address".

What these guys need is loads of social interaction. But they have very little incentive to do engage in it outside of looking for a girlfriend. And they are told at every corner "you shouldn't go socialize just to find a gf". So they take that advice and DONT socialize at all. It's a catch 22. 

But yes I agree. The more you socialize. The wider the range of who you find attractive becomes. For many different reasons. Humans prioritize dating the best looking partner. But they also prioritize reproduction more. Which means if the human brain see's that you can't get the best looking partners it scales down what you find attractive. Hence why most couples are within the range of each other. But that mechanism doesn't happen if you sit at home playing Call of Duty or League of Legends all day. While masturbating to 9s and 10s on pornhub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199830253.0" user="Cali_Longhorn" delta="False">
    <text>Well the whole point of "you shouldn't socialize just to find a gf" is just that. Socialize to have fun doing whatever you enjoy with other people.  And in the process of having fun, you probably come off as likeable.  You make friends, you get invited to parties and events where people of the opposite sex are.  And your "fun and likeable" self is more appealing to members of the opposite sex who want to do things they enjoy with someone else.

Basically it's not a 1 step process to getting a bf/gf.  But more a 2-3 step.  It's like when I discovered when I was going out to "meet someone" it rarely was fruitful.  If I was out with my friends having a good time without much thought of meeting someone.  It was then I'd easily find myself talking to a cute girl and getting a number somewhat effortlessly.  I was having a good time and others wanted to be a part of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199864917.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and it ends up with guys just sitting in their house all the time. Cause they don't actually enjoy any social events. If they did you wouldn't be having this conversation with them in the first place.

I understand the logic. But it doesn't work with your target audience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199906240.0" user="Cali_Longhorn" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose.  But I'd argue that there is something more fundamentally wrong with a target audience who "never wants to get out of the house".  Not "getting out" contributes of lots of issues.  Poorer health as kids don't go out a "play" with others the way they used to.  Poorer face to face communication generally that would apply to the workplace.  Issues with dating is just another symptom of the bigger problem.  People need to "get out of the house" for many reasons aside from dating.  

It's why I'm big on making sure my kids actually have "facetime" with people for their long term social growth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199944324.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>It's simple human nature. Humans have never been this comfortable at home.

You stay at home you have food and grocery delivery, video games, social media, netflix, youtube, porn etc.

Try doing that in 1920. You'll get very bored listening to that janky radio. 

There's nothing wrong with them. They just enjoy things like video games more than socializing with a bunch of randos.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200143704.0" user="Cali_Longhorn" delta="False">
    <text>Well I'd argue that it's a problem though.  Yes there are lots more "fun" things at home than there were back in the day.  When I was a kid I had much more access to things like "lower tech" video game systems like NES and such, that my parents did not.  But still my parents would make sure I got out of the house.  I played sports and such.  My son plays PS5 games, but he's more excited to get out to his martial arts classes and cub scout campouts.  I sure HOPE it stays that way for his own good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44200173750.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>Let's say 40% of guys just prefer to stay at home. 

In 1920 almost all of them will have no choice but to socialize. Unless they are significantly mentally impaired they will be bored to tears sitting at home.

In 2023 a large chunk of them do just that. Just stay at home. 

These are different personality types that don't really enjoy socializing all that much. You can only force yourself to stomach it so much. 

The reason "go out looking for a girlfriend" tends to work despite sounding counter intuitive to you. Is because they are perfectly capable of socializing. They just need incentive to. And looking for women is a MAJOR MAJOR MAJOR incentive for a young man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44201433021.0" user="Cali_Longhorn" delta="False">
    <text>But the point you were making in earlier posts made it sound like "go out looking for a girlfriend" does NOT work well.  Now you are saying it "tends to work despite sounding counter intuitive to you".  So which one are you saying?

I THINK what you were saying is essentially...

1. Because so many guys don't socialize now, they only go out with the express purpose of finding a girlfriend.  
2. But this often doesn't go well because they are not very good at being social since they lack practice at it.

That's what I thought you were saying earlier (which I agree with).  But now you are saying point 2 DOES work well?

You use 1920 as an example.  You don't have to go nearly that far back.  As a child of the 80s-90s.  Sure you had video games.  But we had the most fun playing Tecmo Bowl if you had friends actually COME OVER to play 2 player with you.  We'd have 4 of us taking turn challenging each other.  You weren't playing against faceless people over the internet yet.   And yes we'd actually try to play some real football outside emulating what we just played afterward and not just the video game version of it.  

But I think where I stand is I'd like to as best I can encourage people around me (especially my kids) to get out and socialize more with real people as it's ultimately better for you.  Where you are more saying "Guys now don't want to socialize, so we have to accept that reality and adjust accordingly".

Sure I enjoyed playing online shooters in my single days, but I had way more fun playing in a coed kickball league and meeting up at the bar afterwards and making friends (and yes stumbled into a couple of dates through it).   Playing sand volleyball at "volleybars".  And it also helped me lose weight and overall be healthier (and more physically attractive/confident) aside from being tons of fun.

I don't deny that the current generation may do these things less.  I just think we should try to do what we can to change these habits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44201469348.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>No I was saying "Don't go socializing to find a girlfriend" is bad advice. Sorry if I didn't make it clear. 

&gt;Where you are more saying "Guys now don't want to socialize, so we have to accept that reality and adjust accordingly".

A certain portion of them. That's why I said something like 40% of them. Which means that 60% of them you hardly have to encourage to socialize, they already want to. But the other 40% they need incentive to do it, otherwise they will not.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
