<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44198852068.0" user="llijilliil" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy.

Generally anyone who can't find a partner is setting the bar a little high.

The points about women going for the very "best" men generally refers to stats from the likes of tinder.  There in general women get to be very picky as most men will hook up with most women but the reverse isn't true.

Why settle for a 6/10 hook up if you can be confident that almost all 9/10 or 10/10 guys will happily hook up with you?  Meanwhile all those guys that are 6/10 or less get absolutely no where and the 7-8/10s have a rough time too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198927984.0" user="ZappSmithBrannigan" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Generally anyone who can't find a partner is setting the bar a little high.

My bar right now is "alive" and "wants to spend time with me". 4 years and nadda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198980528.0" user="llijilliil" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure there's some middle aged, overweight, grumpy women without a job or friends that would accept you as long as you are very kind and patient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199542060.0" user="UnlikelyClothes5761" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't seem to be case even then for majority of men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199644887.0" user="llijilliil" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't make much sense.

Are you sure there are no "standards" at all that you are insiting on that are ruling out some women that would otherwise consider a relationship with you.

Its OK to decide that certain compromises make things not worth it, e.g. kids, income, appearence, age etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199678062.0" user="UnlikelyClothes5761" delta="False">
    <text>Not referring to me but the countless experiments online where men will flood the inboxes of any women regardless of what she looked like: old, obese, 10 kids, disfigured,  etc.

Personally I have also dropped most standards I have to get laid at times because it was tired of masturbating. This is what leads to this dynamic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199798409.0" user="llijilliil" delta="False">
    <text>The issue here is "looking to get laid" with relatively little effort or investment.  

The women looking for a fast hook up are going to be able to choose the most attractive guys and there's nothing that can be done about that.  

If however we are talking about longer term relationships, well those guys can only manage to properly date one person at a time.  That's going to take effort though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199833366.0" user="UnlikelyClothes5761" delta="False">
    <text>Sure things get more even but we're talking why there is a difference between the genders and this explains it. Also the initial stages of dating and hookup are the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199619315.0" user="HeisenbergCares" delta="False">
    <text>I think you raised some very salient points.

Part of the built-in issue with the current dating culture of the west is women who are the 6/10 you cited, will oftentimes be able to get sexual access to a guy who is a 9/10, but not a relationship. Then, after that happens a few times , maybe she "downgrades" to a guy who is a 6/10, but is now jaded that she cannot get the man she thinks she is worth because that tier of man is not willing to take her seriously.

There also seems to be an inversion that happens (on an aggregate level), in the late 20s to early 30s, where men's dating options start to increase, and women's dating options slow down. There is a technical name for this, but I'm drawing a blank.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199698033.0" user="llijilliil" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, you've hit the nail on the head.

For women, their prime is earlier (say 18-25) and they get flooded with offers of sex from any man they like.  They get used to that "standard" of man and complain that they "fear commitment" or are "fuck boys" or whatever while completely failing to recognise that their "shagging league" is very different to their "marraige league".  

For many the biological clock starts ticking and their appeal to partners starts dwindling and holding out hope for some amazing guy leads to increasing bitterness.

For men, the issue is typically that most can't get many or any dates around "their level" as a result of the above when they are young.  Then when they start earning money and hit their prime (around 30) they aren't pressured to settle down yet and they are looking for some fun with the new women in their mid 20s etc.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
