<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44198817043.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not going to argue your main point, because I refuse to add fuel to incel psychosis. Instead I refute the idea that your view is purely anecdotal.

The concept itself has been debunked over and over as having been based on swiping habits from online dating sites. The same surveys showed men also bombarding the "top tier" of women with messages. Aside from that, the math simply doesn't work out. 

62% of Americans ages 25 to 54 lived with a partner or were married, according to a 2021 Pew Research Center study of 2019 U.S. Census Bureau data. This included 53% who were married and 9% who were cohabitating.

This does not include people who are dating but not living together. If women are only choosing the "upper tier", it's a wide fucking tier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44198949097.0" user="JackC747" delta="False">
    <text>While I don't disagree that this just statistically isn't true, your evidence only supports that for relationships. Anecdotally, I've seen this in my female friends when it came to casual sex and hookups. On apps, women are bombarded with attention from many men. It seems like it's only natural then for them to choose from that group only the most attractive men to go forward with for dating and sex</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199334133.0" user="Popularopionstates" delta="False">
    <text>There is definitely a tier system for men when it comes to who women choose to have casual sex with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199353733.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, and because women are not a monolith, they're each going to be attracted to different things. It IS only natural to go after the people who are most attractive to you. Only in an incel mindset does that get twisted into "women who won't give me a chance are soulless whores."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199459540.0" user="taralundrigan" delta="False">
    <text>Ya, but these comments conveniently ignore what people find attractive. Men who make the claim that women only go for 'top tier' men, picture that billions of women are searching for their Jason Mamoa or Chris Pine. 

When the reality is a lot of women don't find men like that attractive. Some want a Tom Hiddleston or Jeremy Allan White.

 'Attractiveness' is extremely subjective, and in my experience existing in the world, there aren't really a lot of ugly people out there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199125680.0" user="johnnyblaze6398" delta="False">
    <text>62% feels really low to me and it's sad because for most of that other 38% I doubt it is completely by choice. People want love it's just not in the cards the way it used to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199277841.0" user="Cayowin" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;People want love it's just not in the cards the way it used to be.

When did it used to be? 

You mean when there were arranged marriages? When woman felt obligated to finish high school and get married? When the only choice in life for women was secretary work, teaching or nursing but having a husband was mandatory.  

When lesbians and gays got married to hide who they were? When woman stayed in abusive relationships because divorce didn't exist? When the church and society only saw her as her husbands property? 

Please also note the 62% in that stat only include married or co-habiting. Does not include those in relationships one would place as "long distance" or "short term" or non-traditional. 

There are 28 million people in long distance relationships in USA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199376170.0" user="l_t_10" delta="False">
    <text>When we werent headed to the same dating/relationship scene as Japan one could perhaps guess</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44201372346.0" user="johnnyblaze6398" delta="False">
    <text>Why you gotta make it like that? I'm not straight and it's tough for women too obviously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44217246253.0" user="Cayowin" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm asking is when is this mythological time when dating was easy? 

I feel like you may be either looking back with rose colored glasses or i'm missing something</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44199282319.0" user="TheOutspokenYam" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't mean the whole 38% don't have love, simply that they aren't cohabitating. Instead of sad, I think it's a positive thing. Women no longer have to stay in abusive relationships, or settle for a man in order to survive. Men don't have to be the breadwinner for some mythical family if they choose not to. The way it used to be wasn't a fairytale for anyone involved.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
