<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2668984841.0" index="35" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1851lvt/cmv_women_are_not_going_for_the_upper_tier_of_men/">
    <title>CMV: women are not going for the 'upper tier' of men</title>
    <original_poster>BadgerSame6600</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see this rhetoric over and over and over online, and hear it IRL sometimes.  It drives me crazy tbh. I am a man out in the world, living life, 35 years of it now. I have friends who are all over the spectrum of physical attractiveness. Some are single, most aren't. Their gfs/wifes are also across the spectrum. In most couples I know, friends and acquaintances,  the woman is better looking, earns more, or has more social skills ect. 

Now I know this is my experience, so it is anecdotal, but at the same time I just don't buy this whole women are too choosy. My opinion is that the dudes who say this are refusing to address their flaws and accept them. If these men believe this and they go out into the world feeling hard done by, fighting a losing battle, then it becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy. Most people can smell that level of victimhood a mile of. 

OK, open to have this challenge, so- change my view, Redditors! </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44199537023.0" user="rpujoe" delta="False">
    <text>You need to rethink what "upper tier" means. It's just a catch-all for the men up near the top of the competence, dominance, and socioeconomic hierarchies. 

It's not just rhetoric, it's backed by hard data, in part from the dating apps as well as the general social survey and similar. 

Example #1: 20% of women are in fact sharing a man. That's right out of the GSS. This is why Facebook groups such as "Are we dating the same guy?" are popping up all around the country.

Exampe #2: The men with the top 5% amount of sexual partners, that amount is roughly equal to the entire bottom 50% of men's sexual partners combined. The average male sexual partner count is 7. When you exclude those at the very top and very bottom, the mean is 3. Of those men in that top 5%, they are having well into triple digit body counts (I forget the exact figure). For those at the absolute top (I can't remember if it was 0.1% or 0.01%) the partner count figure was in the thousands. That would be your Drakes, Machine Gun Kellys, Leo DiCaprios, professional athletes, etc.

TL;DR - This isn't people's opinions or them speaking rhetorically, but rather data driven social science.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
