<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44229443557.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

...are we told that?

My impression is that both parties are effectively resigned to the outcomes of their primaries that make Biden/Trump a near certainty.  The parties themselves and public opinion polls seem to loathe both and election projections seem to suggest that whoever wins would assume leadership of a country that generally hated them from day one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229570830.0" user="PostPostMinimalist" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most people seem to agree that they want other candidates, but the structure of the primaries traps us

Not the "structure," the result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229585713.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>I said what I meant.

Primaries could be structured differently and produce a different, more desirable result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229675325.0" user="ackermann" delta="False">
    <text>Ranked choice voting, or something?  Where you don’t have to vote against the candidate you hate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229787607.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>I know this probably won't be popular but...*symbolic* primaries would be best, I think.

Primaries that don't inherently mean anything because the parties pick their candidates while taking any votes of constituents under advisement only and while reserving the right to put forward any candidate they please.

Political parties are supposed to be organized around ideas and goals, primaries as currently structured turn them into bizarre and incoherent alliances between demographic cohorts.  Right now parties are almost powerless as institutions; they can't write coherent platforms because they have a weak hand in choosing candidates and their positions.  They preside over massive primaries where all their viable candidates murder each other in public while the parties watch in embarrassed horror.  You can't identify what Republicans or Democrats generally believe because nobody is gatekeeping who is allowed to represent either party - they both contain internal contradictions that make no sense.

We'd be better off letting parties put forward candidates on their own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229990633.0" user="BraxbroWasTaken" delta="False">
    <text>Nah. Then you'd effectively have a full oligarchy because the entire voting process would become effectively symbolic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230096059.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>Like it isn't now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231538908.0" user="BraxbroWasTaken" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, at least there's *some* say in *some* of the process. More democratic than "Organizations have decided that these are your two options on the ballot this year".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230112252.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Nah.  "The *real* democracy is in the primaries" is obvious bunk.

Letting parties pick their candidates would force parties to cater to broad voter tastes to win elections and not just the base micro-coalition that currently decides primaries.  "The base" in each party would be disempowered, and failure of the two major parties to cater to majorities would create real fertile ground for third parties.  While they might never be viable, they would help adjust major parties when they become sufficiently unpopular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230166573.0" user="TheLizardKing89" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Primaries that don't inherently mean anything because the parties pick their candidates while taking any votes of constituents under advisement only and while reserving the right to put forward any candidate they please.

This was basically how primaries functioned before the 1970s and people hated it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230175136.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>I know.  They were wrong.  Shit got worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229960638.0" user="sockgorilla" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t have to do that in the primaries. Everyone votes for who they want in the primary, then just vote part line no matter who won, because it’s better than the other party’s choice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230091319.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>Approval voting would suit a primary better than ranked choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230158638.0" user="TheLizardKing89" delta="False">
    <text>More desirable to who?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230166082.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>The general electorate and sane people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230205338.0" user="TheLizardKing89" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly is more desirable to them that isn’t desirable to primary voters?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230228961.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Candidates with broad appeal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229685001.0" user="mule_roany_mare" delta="False">
    <text>That result is almost always the rational strategy for a first past the post ballot.

The consequences of winner takes all forces people to get behind the most viable candidate, not their preferred or the best. 

When getting 49% of electors means you get **nothing** dumb strategies become wise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229818691.0" user="thorleywinston" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's very much the structure which determines the result.  I can't speak for what the Democrats do but on the Republican side they changed their primary rules at their 2012 convention so that (a) delegates were "bound" to vote for the winner of presidential primary (instead of having the ability to change their vote at the national convention) and (b) the winner of a plurality (I think it might be as low as 40 percent) got awarded a majority of their state's delegates (who were "bound" to vote for the candidate who got a plurality).  

What that means is that a candidate like Trump who has a core of 30+ percent who are "ride or die" for him just needs to peel off enough to get to a plurality (which isn't that hard when the anti-Trump candidates keep splitting the vote) and gain an early lead such that by the time the weaker candidates have finally dropped out, he's too far ahead in the number of "bound" delegates for anyone to realistically catch up to him.  That's how he was able to get the nomination in 2016 - by the time the rest of the field had been whittled down to him, Cruz and Rubio it was too late.

We're seeing a repeat of that here where even though if a majority of Republicans want someone other than Trump, the non-Trump field is so fractured that unless they whittle it down to a much smaller number and soon, Trump's "ride or die" base while a minority could be enough to get him to the numbers where he can get a majority of "bound" delegates with a plurality of primary votes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229675846.0" user="PoissonGreen" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, we are. https://thehill.com/opinion/campaign/4331362-biden-or-bust-democrats-are-stuck-with-joe/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229710504.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>That article was hard to read lol lots of shit opinions there</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229737309.0" user="PoissonGreen" delta="False">
    <text>I only got through enough to be sure it was promoting the idea OP is talking about lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229808720.0" user="Candyman44" delta="False">
    <text>So what has changed in the last 5 elections?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229818666.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>That feels like a leading question.

Do you have a point you want to make?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230976281.0" user="abacuz4" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Most people seem to agree that they want other candidates, but the structure of the primaries traps us. 

Is this really that surprising? Most right-leaning voters don't like [Democratic Candidate] and most left-leaning voters don't like [Republican Candidate]. I would tend to think it would be completely normal that most voters would dislike one of the candidates enough to say that they wish the matchup were different.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
