<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="129" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44233779431.0" user="Synensys" delta="False">
    <text>Lets imagine a world in which the DNC didn't want to run Biden, but Biden did want to run. 

Well you don't need to imagine. You see this exact scenario playing out in the Republican Party in fact. I'm sure the RNC absolutely would LOVE if Trump had decided to hang it up. They ARE having a real primary with real candidates. Major money people and politicians are getting behind some of those candidates. And none of them have a shot at beating Trump because being an incumbent (or in his case former incumbent) is such a huge benefit to running that  despite him being a massively flawed candidate, their primary will likely be over before February.   


But Biden would be even harder to beat because he's actually the incumbent. Biden is still quite popular with Democrats. He's got 72% approval among Democrats. Thats not great, but any primary opponent has to convince most of those people who approve of Biden not only that Biden is doing a bad job, but do so in a way that doesn't shit on the Democratic Party too much. And as we are seeing in the Republican Primary even then, if you have many candidates they just split the anti-incumbent vote. And if a candidate drops out, a good chunk of their supporters would just go back to voting Biden.  


Its not that the DNC backs Biden. Its that the voters back Biden to a big enough extent that challenging him would be a waste of time. Anyone with a real political future is just going to wait until 2028 and then either chllenge Harris or if Biden loses, run in a wide open field.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
