<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44229652411.0" user="Pixel-of-Strife" delta="False">
    <text>To paraphrase Chomsky, propaganda is to a democracy what violence is to a tyrannical dictatorship. It's the mechanism of control. Anyone can run for president. But if the corporate state media doesn't ordain them, no one will notice or care. This is how the system worked for decades. But the internet came along and changed things. They tried to destroy Trump but didn't understand the Streisand Effect. They wanted Jeb Bush. Both sides. Same thing with Bernie. But Bernie bent the knee and didn't complain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249455753.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Same thing with Bernie. But Bernie bent the knee and didn't complain.

And I'm not sure if you're meaning that as a good or bad thing as some people seem to think him not, like, reacting to losing the nomination with a violent socialist coup involving guillotines or something thus proving everyone's worst fears about his ideology right proves he's somehow a "controlled opposition shill" (and those same people love to bring up the fact that he has three houses as if that makes him a hypocrite even though every congressman has to have two, one in DC and one in the state they're representing, and yeah the third is a vacation home but it's a family-inherited property and not some kind of mansion and it looks like a normal house iirc people just got mad because he called it a cabin on social media or something and it didn't look like something they could build out of Lincoln Logs)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
