<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44229465563.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>You think that the dems should give up a proven winner with incumbent advantage? That's an absurd call. 

Fundamentally most people do not care nearly as much about age as you do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229532074.0" user="Emperor-Dman" delta="False">
    <text>It's like 70%+ incumbents win reelection, part of why it was so interesting to see a record number of Americans (and a nearly record proportion of Americans) turn out to vote Trump out of office in 2020</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230094956.0" user="BraxbroWasTaken" delta="False">
    <text>Somewhere around 77.77%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231522517.0" user="Light_Error" delta="False">
    <text>I do wonder if Trump would have lost if Covid had not happened when it did. It showed his faults in a worse case scenario in a way people predicted would happen if he was truly tested. I think he did slightly better than I expected on the logistics end, but stuff like his conspiratorial nature fucked him over and reminded people how he was fucking up by doing stuff like promoting questionable or understudied cures.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44236530193.0" user="Ancient_Response_317" delta="False">
    <text>I think a lot of america was already over Trump but covid just made it tenfold.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229662540.0" user="SteadfastEnd" delta="False">
    <text>If it were any other Democratic president (say, this is Clinton in 1996 or Obama in 2012,) then of course  the Democrats should run that incumbent as the default. But Biden is different. Not only is he by far the oldest Democratic president ever, but significantly more Democratic rank-and-file voters themselves are dissatisfied with him being the 2024 nominee than they were with Clinton or Obama.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230001786.0" user="Sspifffyman" delta="False">
    <text>Problem is agreeing on another option. Most people may not prefer Biden or Trump, but that doesn't mean they would agree on another candidate. Look at the 2020 Dem primaries. Bernie, Warren, Pete, all excited segments of the Dem base, but not enough other people wanted those candidates. Biden was the one that most people could agree on. And then between Biden and Trump, Biden won more voters over. 

When you already have one person who has won before, it's a huge risk to try to switch to someone different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230085700.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Bernie, Warren, Pete, all excited segments of the Dem base, but not enough other people wanted those candidates.

As if the power structures within the party didn't have their boot on the scale...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230267888.0" user="Radix2309" delta="False">
    <text>How did they put their boot on the scale?

Biden was crushing Bernie in the primaries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231285612.0" user="Hannig4n" delta="False">
    <text>No one had their boot on any scale, those other candidates just weren’t as popular as your online echo chamber would have you believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230569262.0" user="Thai-Reidj" delta="False">
    <text>Well first of all...no..Biden has an 80% approval rating them Democrats which is literally the same as Clinton and Obama at this point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231401750.0" user="agray20938" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Democratic rank-and-file voters themselves are dissatisfied with him being the 2024 nominee than they were with Clinton or Obama.

Satisfaction is only part of the equation though. The more appropriate metric is "are they willing to, and will they show up to the polls to, vote for this person"? Being satisfied or preferring a certain candidate is part of it, but it's absolutely not a perfect correlation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44260615639.0" user="Frnklfrwsr" delta="False">
    <text>Same as in 2020, Trump will drive millions of people to the polls to vote against him. When he has at least one felony conviction in hand and more about to drop, he’s going to lose a lot of enthusiasm from independent voters that feel that’s just a little too much for them. 

People have grievances with Biden, sure. But next year is shaping up to be the worst year of Trump’s life to date, and I just don’t see any path for him to win over any voters he didn’t already have in 2020, and there’s millions he will absolutely lose that just won’t show up, or will vote 3rd party, or could even vote for Biden. 

Next year will be defined by Trump being put on the stand over and over again and being humiliated over and over again. His money will all be locked away due to the result of the current civil fraud trial. He won’t even be able to go to nearly as many rallies due to all the court dates he will have to make. 

At that point, people will look at Biden and realize that at least he doesn’t piss them off. He may be old, he may not be their favorite, but he hasn’t driven the country into the ground, inflation has cooled off a bit, interest rates have started to come down slightly, and he seems to have mostly competent people around him. 

I think Biden will hold onto all his voters from 2020 and probably add a little more. I think Trump will lose millions off his vote total from 2020. 

The down ticket effects in congressional races next year will likely be large. You could see a blue wave in both the senate and house next year due to so many GOP voters staying home because they can’t bring themselves to vote for Trump after he’s been convicted and sentenced.

So yeah, the GOP of course is making a very dumb choice going with Trump as their candidate. But it’s what their voters want, and he’s almost certainly going to be locked in as their candidate by the time he gets his first conviction. Of course they should go for anyone else, but they won’t. 

And as long as the GOP is locked into Trump, it makes zero sense for the Democrats to take any unnecessary risk. Biden is the quiet devil-you-know that while many voters may not love, very few have actually changed their mind about in a significant way. He’s boring. He’s quiet. He’s uncontroversial. He doesn’t make spicy headlines and insert himself into people’s lives. He quietly does the work of government and people who want to live their lives can do so without stressing too much about what Biden is or isn’t doing. 

Don’t forget that once Trump has ONE conviction, he no longer has the presumption of innocence. You will see ads everywhere calling him a convicted felon. News media won’t have to pull any punches and risk slander/libel liability. If he’s convicted of fraud, they can correctly call him a fraud. If he’s convicted of sedition, they can correctly call him a seditionist. 

Also, those trials are going to be plastered across the TV almost everywhere. People that are usually stuck in echo chambers won’t be able to avoid it. And those trials are going to be in courtrooms where the judge controls the room, not Trump. He doesn’t get to spout lies unchallenged. He doesn’t get to make accusations without evidence. 

To his supporters, he will look weak and neutered, killing their motivation to turn out for him. 

To people on the fence, they will finally be faced with facts about his wrongdoings that they’ve avoided up to now. 

To people who already hate him, it will motivate them even more strongly to vote against him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230077528.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>Incumbent advantage doesn't work if the people really really don't like your decisions.

Just see Trump's defeat for reference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230098211.0" user="Zeabos" delta="False">
    <text>It still matters. Trump got *more* votes in 2020 than he did in 2016. Biden just got even more.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
