<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44229512645.0" user="ThatSpencerGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Trump and Biden are very different cases, and should be treated separately. I'll let others talk about Trump, but big picture Trump is the likely Republican candidate because he's [wildly popular among Republican voters](https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/favorability/donald-trump/r/). 

As for Biden, there are many fewer than 10,000 people who would be a viable Democratic party candidate for president. Your criteria are too generous. Being a smart, charismatic doctor doesn't make you a viable candidate. Running for President is hard, and it's not like running for City Council. A person needs political experience or connections, ideally some name recognition, and lots and lots (and lots and lots and lots) of money or the ability to raise it. 

That said, there are *more than zero* other viable Democrat candidates for President. So the question still stands. Why Joe? And I don't think there's an obvious answer, but the truth is that an alternative candidate will have to be a *real* person, with all their real baggage and targets for the opposition, and it's not clear who the best alternative would be. Gavin Newsom? Pete Buttigieg? Kamala Harris? Elizabeth Warren? Amy Klobuchar? Any of these folks **might** be an improvement on Joe, but it's not an open-and-shut case. There's no **clear** better alternative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229541331.0" user="Novel_Patience9735" delta="False">
    <text>Michelle Obama ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229553650.0" user="ThatSpencerGuy" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Michelle Obama ?

Sure, maybe! She'd be a brutal target for Republican opposition and media, and by all accounts she hated politics and has no interest. 

Again, it's not like we all know Biden will beat Trump. It's just... if there's an obviously better option, I can't see it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229826638.0" user="Candyman44" delta="False">
    <text>Big Mike is definitely Biden replacement. Why do you think they are having the DNC convention in Chicago?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229627944.0" user="I_am_the_Jukebox" delta="False">
    <text>She hates politics and would never run.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229744121.0" user="thecftbl" delta="False">
    <text>No. More. Dynasties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229906128.0" user="WerhmatsWormhat" delta="False">
    <text>What qualifications does she have? She’s never held public office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229981115.0" user="Novel_Patience9735" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I agree, but she’s someone that gets mentioned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230199082.0" user="Nate2322" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty sure she’s said publicly there’s no chance she’s gonna take the job even if it got to her without her running</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229593324.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why Joe? And I don't think there's an obvious answer

I dunno that it's that non-obvious. He's an incumbent whose party has performed well since his election. I think that this stands on its own as an explanation of why Biden is a good pick. I would like it if someone more progressive had a plausible shot, but I'm highly skeptical. Honestly, incumbency alone is probably a sufficient argument, but I could imagine someone losing like a billion seats and folks realizing that we have to bail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229719817.0" user="Aggravating-Forever2" delta="False">
    <text>\&gt; Why Joe? And I don't think there's an obvious answer, 

Obvious answer: he already beat Trump once, so they know he's viable. They hope he's too bland to have alienated most of the people who voted for him (at least not enough that they'd go to the extent of voting *against* him). 

Beyond that, none of the people on your list of other candidates scream "Yeah, this guy/gal should absolutely be our next president!" either.  They might be just fine as pres... but I'd have no reason to believe any of them would be particularly better than any other, nor necessarily better than Biden necessarily. 

So, if your options are to run an unknown, with more variability/risk, or run the incumbent, with a known level of mediocrity, but more predictable chances... why take the risk? 

tl;dr - Democrats are basically still running on the platform of "We're not *Trump*", not "here's an inspiring leader to rally behind".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230197163.0" user="TheLizardKing89" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Why Joe? And I don't think there's an obvious answer

Seems like the answer is pretty obvious to me;  Biden is an incumbent who’s already beaten the likely GOP candidate. Also, any of the other potential candidates don’t want to risk alienating members of the party with a primary challenge. They’ll keep their powder dry and run in 2028.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230236061.0" user="Nate2322" delta="False">
    <text>Biden is the incumbent, his party preformed historically well in the midterms, he’s been a senator and vice president and now president so he’s the most qualified, he’s beaten trump before, he got the most votes for a single candidate in one election, and looking at his policy’s he’s not actually that bad. Idk why democrats wouldn’t run with him if he wants to run again.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
