<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="53" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44230087373.0" user="kung-fu_hippy" delta="False">
    <text>First, the view you want changed is a false understanding of the premise. The notion that democrats or republicans must run Biden or Trump respectively isn’t because they’re the best possible candidates. So the existence of thousands of better candidates doesn’t matter. 

On the Republican side, Trump’s command of the crazier half of the Republican voters and his absolutely batshit ego means that the GOP has to run him because if they don’t he will turn on them. Trump may not win, but anyone else they run will absolutely lose. Trump will see to that himself. And if he does so, he will splinter their party and they may see a repeat of what happened to the Whigs (although for much worse reasons). So they have to run Trump in the same way that you have to give a man in an alley armed with a gun your wallet.

As for Biden. First I’d question that there are thousands of people better qualified to be president than him. He’s a former VP, and a senator for 40 years or so before that. Unless we’re going to assume that a qualified president doesn’t need political experience, there aren’t thousands of people even remotely as qualified as him. They might be better, but how would we know that? Campaign promises? There is a reason resumes list your previous jobs. 

Second for Biden, while there may be better (and younger) choices, it’s a question, not a certainty, that they would pull in as many voters as he will. Perhaps, perhaps not. But for the same reason the GOP can’t turn on Trump  (if for completely different outlooks), the DNC can’t risk losing to Trump. If all it took to beat Trump was running a better candidate than him, he wouldn’t have been elected to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
