<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="108" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44232061386.0" user="RareCanOfBeans" delta="False">
    <text>Trump and Biden both have experience being the president. That’s something you’re not going to get being a random mayor. 

MAGA Republicans aren’t going to accept any of the old establishment republicans so anyone who worked for bush is gone. Bye bye Condoleezza Rice and John Bolton

Nikki Haley has experience but she’s basically an outcast after publicly hating on Trump only to double back and kiss his ass after he won.

Romney probably won’t win, or even try. 

Mike Pompeo is popular but who’s gonna vote for him over Trump? Plus he’s a CIA guy, not exactly a popular thing to be if you want to seem trustworthy. 

Graham won’t run against Trump, which

As for Biden, what more can you ask? 

Experience practicing law, experienced in the senate, experience as vice president to one of the nation’s greatest presidents of all time, and is currently leading the nation as our President. 

His experience with bipartisan legislation  allowed him to get massive bills on infrastructure, manufacturing, and inflation reduction through Congress. As well as major tax reforms(including the child tax credit) and a 1.9 trillion dollar economic stimulus. It’s a big reason why we’re s

He has been praised by many Arab nations for negotiating pauses and a truce that lead to the release of 100 hostages in Gaza, last year he announced the AUKUS pact and rejoined the Paris Agreement and the WHO. This year during his meeting with Xi, the president got China to commit to more open communication(particularly with regards to their military and AI) and to curb fentanyl production, He also managed to skillfully address Taiwan in a diplomatic way that did not rise tensions. 


He’s passed reforms for the USPS, Gun Control,  and Veteran Healthcare all while having faster GDP recovery at the end of the pandemic than any other G7 nation. Creating 13 million jobs and seeing a 5.9% increase in GDP (the highest the country has seen in 37 years) marking the first time in 2 decades where the US economy is actually outpacing China.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
