<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44229473027.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument for suitability rests entirely on capability.

But capability is not in question here. An election is first and foremost a popularity contest. And in a popularity contest, an ex-president has a huge name recognition advantage.

Any outsider candidate, by definition, lacks this name recognition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229591341.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>[Except Biden polls unfavorably against 'A Generic Democrat.'](https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/first-read/biden-trump-both-underperform-generic-opponents-poll-finds-rcna126098)

The fact of the matter is the DNC would like Biden as he will continue to enable their legalized bribery and insider trading versus a progressive candidate that they might have to lose face by transparently conspiring against in a primary.

Take your pick between which genocidal, bourgeois, racist, old homophobic white man you want, I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229642834.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Take your pick between which genocidal, bourgeois, racist, old homophobic white man you want, I guess.

I mean, don't mistake me for a Biden stan, but are you suggesting that he's as bad as Trump is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229673505.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>I imagine a lot of Palestinian children consider him significantly worse.

Either way it's the same corporate sectors paying for the campaign of either candidate. I find it really weird how Liberals tend to alternate between 'The President will destroy the entire nation with his power' and 'The president has no power to do any of the things he said he would' depending on which side is in office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229748709.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I imagine a lot of Palestinian children without parents, and mothers without children consider him significantly worse

I'm sympathetic to their dislike of Biden, but are you saying you believe Trump would be tougher on Israel and more pro-Palestine?

&gt;Either way it's the same corporate sectors paying for the campaign of either candidate. I find it really weird how Liberals tend to alternate between 'The President will destroy the entire nation with his power' and 'The president has no power to do any of the things he said he would' depending on which side is in office.

The president absolutely has the theoretical power to destroy the entire nation regardless of who is in office (more difficult to actually do in practice).  There are also things that the president is powerless to do just due to the basis for and nature of presidential power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229797190.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I'm sympathetic to their dislike of Biden, but are you saying you believe Trump would be tougher on Israel and more pro-Palestine?

No, but full support for a literal genocide should be a fucking dealbreaker. Full stop. It's disgusting that centrist Liberals have so little regard for the life of others that it's not. The fact only 20% of his base supports his decision should equate to active, vocal dissent and the other 80% agreeing to not  vote for him. The fact that you are willing to be bullied into voting through ultimatums is what is continuing to get you right wing scum like Biden.

&gt;The president absolutely has the theoretical power to destroy the entire nation regardless of who is in office (more difficult to actually do in practice). There are also things that the president is powerless to do just due to the basis for and nature of presidential power.

Yet meaningful change only seems to occur when the right is in power due to Democrats wanting to 'play by the rules' or 'work with republicans' or whatever else appeals to affluent white voters who have the privilege to not have to worry about policy. Such as with the Senate Parliamentarian debacle. It's an advisory position. Biden let himself get stonewalled. Bush went against the Parliamentarian's will, fired him and got a new one.

Democrats literally just serve as controlled opposition that stops progress to the left while Republicans make progress to the right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229929945.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The fact only 20% of his base supports his decision should equate to active, vocal dissent and the other 80% agreeing to not  vote for him. The fact that you are willing to be bullied into voting through ultimatums is what is continuing to get you right wing scum like Biden.

Blame the math of our FPTP voting system.  It's not bullying, it's that our voting system necessitates a harm reduction strategy rather than a vote for the candidate we actually want.  You already agreed that Trump would be worse, and like it or not until election reform happens a protest vote against Biden effectively gives support to Trump.  I don't like it either, but that's what we have now.

&gt;No, but full support for a literal genocide should be a fucking dealbreaker.

I agree, but we literally do not have a choice but to vote Democrat if we don't want Trump because of the way the math of the system works.  I do not want Joe Biden to be the president again, but I would prefer him to Trump and that's where we are at.

&gt;Yet meaningful change only seems to occur when the right is in power due to Democrats wanting to 'play by the rules' or 'work with republicans' or whatever else appeals to affluent white voters who have the privilege to not have to worry about policy. Such as with the Senate Parliamentarian debacle. It's an advisory position. Biden let himself get stonewalled. Bush went against the Parliamentarian's will, fired him and got a new one.

Preaching to the choir.  Doesn't change the mathematics of our voting system.

&gt;Democrats literally just serve as controlled opposition that stops progress to the left while Republicans make progress to the right.

The term "controlled opposition" implies a level of deliberate conspiracy I don't think is applicable here, but the sentiment I agree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230026859.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I agree, but we literally do not have a choice but to vote Democrat if we don't want Trump because of the way the math of the system works. I do not want Joe Biden to be the president again, but I would prefer him to Trump and that's where we are at.

So then how do you exert power over candidates of either party? If you are unwilling to withhold your vote under any circumstances, then you literally have no power within a democratic system. If Democrats would at some point just muster up the courage to eat 4 years of whatever the 'existential threat of the week' is, then, in theory, the party would have to pivot to meet the wants of their base... Of course the democrats would use that as an excuse to continue pivoting right and court the centrists who never vote for them anyway.

They're a corrupt, dead party that will never change. Any notion of 'pushing them left' is entirely naive.

&gt;The term "controlled opposition" implies a level of deliberate conspiracy I don't think is applicable here, but the sentiment I agree with.

Well you agree both parties are funded by more or less the same corporate sectors. Those corporate sectors are giving you two options. Right wing, and further right wing. It's the illusion of choice that keeps people from openly opposing the country's oligarchic government. It's not really a conspiracy theory, just the endgame of capitalism. It's smart for corporations to use money to ingratiate themselves to political parties and candidates and win favors. If they can do that to both sides, then it is, in fact, controlled opposition. You can bribe a politician for a hundred thousand in speaking fees for a tax break that saves your corporation a few million. You are being denied the opportunity to support candidates who represent your interests because through financial control of media and political parties alike, candidates that represent the people will generally not  reach higher levels of government.

It's not like there's some illuminati controlling it all. It's just good business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230331085.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So then how do you exert power over candidates of either party? If you are unwilling to withhold your vote under any circumstances, then you literally have no power within a democratic system.

Only at the presidential level, there are more races at different levels that influence the direction of the party, and direct action measures that can be taken.  There are more ways to influence the system than just voting for president every 4 years and peacing out.

&gt;They're a corrupt, dead party that will never change. Any notion of 'pushing them left' is entirely naive.

I agree that the Democrats suck, but the idea that there has been zero change at all is false.  There is a reason that labor has been able to make significant strides under the Biden administration, and a large part of it is rulings from the NLRB and the Secretary of Labor who he appointed. It's far from the comprehensive reform needed, but there are some signs of progress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230673447.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And direct action measures that can be taken.

At last  something we agree on.

However, I invite you again to examine Wilding v. DNC Services Corp. We will not be getting anyone with a position of power within the DNC that represents the interests of the working class.

&gt;I agree that the Democrats suck, but the idea that there has been zero change at all is false.

Token change to appease voters that does not enact material change are the same as no change. Again, incremental change means people dying, and in the case of climate change dying en masse. Liberals seem distinctly incapable of understanding the actual human cost of their contentment with political inaction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230837690.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think of myself as a liberal nor am I content with political inaction.  I just don't think a protest vote helps anybody given the system we have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44242778462.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>Are you actually aware of the steps that Biden has taken to support labor and unions? Or are you just guessing that it's "token change"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249431978.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, he was great when he supported those rail workers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229956870.0" user="EarsLookWeird" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; equate to active, vocal dissent and the other 80% agreeing to not vote for him

So back to the question posed to you - do you think Trump is better on this issue? You're suggesting that America elect Trump by suggesting that America not vote for Biden. Unless you want to have a sophomoric discussion about the game theory of the 2 party system and the benefits of keeping/abandoning it, I must assume this is a pragmatic conversation.

Pragmatically either Trump or Biden will be the next US President. So what is your suggestion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230037005.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly not.

However if you are never willing to withhold your vote, then do you actually have any power in a democracy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230131007.0" user="EarsLookWeird" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you have the power to vote for who you prefer. Withholding your vote is literally forfeiting what power you do have - you seem to want people to forfeit their power in an effort to reclaim it which, well, not what I'd suggest</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230162401.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>So let me get this straight. Democrats run someone you don't like because they claim he will get more votes. Then you vote for him unquestioningly.

Then the next one is further right and you still vote for him.

Then the next one is further right and you still vote for him.

It sounds like you have no actual power in this system. The way to actually exercise your power (in the idealized version of democracy and not the oligarchy we have) is to show that, "No, that candidate will not get more votes because he does not represent my interests." Ideally, then the party makes concessions to you and runs someone more favorable instead or offers policy goals favorable to you. If you are not willing to withhold your vote you never get those concessions and you are in fact not living in a democracy at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232643078.0" user="EarsLookWeird" delta="False">
    <text>Sophomoric it is, then

I hashed this out years ago in classrooms, have fun with it though it's an interesting thought exercise. Just remember to vote in November</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232767797.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Amazing how a Rick and Morty fan like you with your vast intellect can't understand that the only leverage a voter has disappears if they choose to vote for the party selected candidate each time, no matter how right wing.

I am voting in November, for the PSL.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44236610138.0" user="xXCisWhiteSniperXx" delta="False">
    <text>Do you feel like the democrats are trying to win over PSL voters?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44238866452.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>No, in fact the Democrats have made a concerted effort to cast off the progressive wing of their party, but it hangs on since running PSL or Green means no chance of election... because Democrats are entirely unwilling to organize to move to a new party, since that requires more conviction than online slacktivism and meaningless electronic petitions.

Again, going back to the point that a voter who is always going to vote for a party has no power over that party.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44233903573.0" user="Giblette101" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're sorta misrepresenting both the system and its history. 

First, the last three Democratic Presidential candidates have been going leftward, not rightward. They're not left-wing, by any means, but they're to the left of their predecessors. This is, in large part, because left-wing candidates manage to command good amount of votes in primaries and other elections, not because people don't go out to vote (not going out to vote doesn't send any signal, it's just pouting). 

Second, presidential candidates are elected by Democratic Party Members. The Democratic Party is a pretty broad coalition that covers centre-right to farther left, so whatever candidate manages to win is likely to be a pretty moderate left-leaning centrist such as Biden. On the balance, few people are going to be super passionate about Biden because he's a compromise candidate, leaning towards the largest faction in the democratic tent (sorta left-leaning liberals). 

Then you also need to compare that candidate with it's obvious alternative, Trump. Giving Trump the win is not going to further any of your interests, neither short term or long term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44242814253.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>You do know that Biden is to the left of Obama, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249437667.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Wow. To the left of Obama. He must be practically a Communist, then.

Both are centrists at best, and that's by American standards. By worldwide standards both are squarely right wing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44255432223.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>He is literally to the left of Obama. You can believe that or not but it won't change that fact. I'm happy to back it up with evidence if you really don't know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44255897719.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>And Obama was also very right wing by global standards. Both are war criminals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44259260911.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>You claimed that Democrat presidents are moving to the right. That's not true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44260246399.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Actually I did not claim that. I used the example of presidents being further right to illustrate the powerlessness that voting unquestionably creates. I would instead argue that more accurately democrats stop leftward progress in any meaningful capacity, as they are a party of corrupt, corporate puppets.

That said, both Obama and Biden are far right of say, FDR.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44265070068.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>Except Biden has literally supported letters l leftward progress. What policies are actually important to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44265585898.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;How about just not keeping ethnic internment camps?

Internment camps on the border say hey.

He has approved more drilling permits than the Trump administration.

He has wholeheartedly approved of a literal genocide, monetarily supported it, and is aiming to offer Israel unfettered access to US arms stockpiles.

He enacted numerous anti-union measures to thwart the rail workers strike... no doubt contributing to the spate of train disasters.

He doesn't support even slightly left-leaning policy that is favored by the vast majority of his party, such as ceasefire in Gaza or universal healthcare.

He has continued the unlawful and unconscionable blockade of Cuba.

He has continued to antagonize China.

He has done nothing to dismantle the billionaire class that is exploiting the proletariat and literally destroying the planet.

A few pieces of token legislation approved by the corporations holding his strings are not satisfactory and they are not sufficient to stave off one of the biggest disasters our species has faced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44272617385.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>Most of that is literally hyperbole. The temporary detention centers are not internment camps, and the Biden admin has absolutely instituted rule changes to decrease time spent and family separation. He's still not a Libertarian so you're still going to have border detention. Just like any other president would. 

&gt;He has approved more drilling permits than the Trump administration.

And the infrastructure bill that he helped create did more for environmental policy and green energy than any other bill in recent memory. 

&gt;He has wholeheartedly approved of a literal genocide, monetarily supported it, and is aiming to offer Israel unfettered access to US arms stockpiles.

That's hyperbolic. Israel is not committing genocide. Their reaction to the attack on October 7th certainly has deserved condemnation, but it's not literal genocide. If you disagree I'm going to need some excellent sourcing of that and not simply "academic who studies this says it probably is". 

&gt;He enacted numerous anti-union measures to thwart the rail workers strike... no doubt contributing to the spate of train disasters.

As any president would. Also, after which he continued to work on their behalf and got them sick days even after most people stopped paying attention. I can find statements from several union heads saying that he's the most pro-union president in our lifetimes, as well as several tangible policies and appointments that are excellent for unions. I'll take the word off the actual unions over some random redditor. 

&gt;He doesn't support even slightly left-leaning policy that is favored by the vast majority of his party, such as ceasefire in Gaza or universal healthcare.

Universal healthcare doesn't stand a chance in hell of passing so supporting it literally means less than nothing. 

&gt;He has continued the unlawful and unconscionable blockade of Cuba.

He has taken steps to ease restrictions including  increasing consular services, but also I fail to see how an embargo is unconscionable. It's stupid, yes. But other than that restricting trade between nations is less a moral issue and more just bad policy. 

&gt;He has continued to antagonize China.

China who is literally enacting coercive population control methods, forced labor, arbitrary detention in internment camps, torture, physical and sexual abuse, mass surveillance, family separation, and repression of cultural and religious expression? That China? Jesus. Who cares? 

&gt;He has done nothing to dismantle the billionaire class that is exploiting the proletariat and literally destroying the planet.

Except, you know, being the most pro-union president in our lifetimes...

&gt;A few pieces of token legislation approved by the corporations holding his strings are not satisfactory and they are not sufficient to stave off one of the biggest disasters our species has faced.

I'll take "you don't actually pay attention to policy and vote mainly on vibes" for 10,000 Alex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44273265763.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>I'll take you're very bad with definitions and apologizing for a piece of human refuse. But that's common for liberals.

&gt;The temporary detention centers are not internment camps

They're not a camp where you intern someone, perhaps someone of a specific ethnicity? I think they actually are that. You just don't like to call them that because it's inconvenient for your naive worldview were America can do no wrong.

&gt;And the infrastructure bill that he helped create did more for environmental policy and green energy than any other bill in recent memory.

And he approved more drilling permits than Trump. Clearly, one of those things is optics and the other one he's not proudly announcing. I wonder why? Maybe because a 'too-little-too-late' bill is nothing close to sufficient to addressing the climate crisis. Meanwhile, under the table he's still fellating oil companies.

&gt;That's hyperbolic. Israel is not committing genocide. 

According to the UN definition, yes. Yes they are. And many countries are calling for them to be tried for it. Genocide denial and the people who participate in it are disgusting.

&gt;As any president would.

As any president that could be elected in our plutocratic oligarchy, yes, I do agree with you. However any president who actually represented their constituents would not.

&gt;but also I fail to see how an embargo is unconscionable. It's stupid, yes. But other than that restricting trade between nations it's less a moral issue and more just bad policy.

Because embargos, by America's own admission are enforced SPECIFICALLY FOR THE PURPOSE of causing the suffering of the people in a country until they engage in action against their government, causing instability. Cuba has languished for decades and lost billions upon billions of dollars that could have been used to improve the lives of their people. Moreover the embargo was only enacted in the first place as a punishment for the Cuban people choosing Socialism over exploitation by the imperialist United States.

&gt;China who is literally enacting coercive population control methods, forced labor, arbitrary detention in internment camps, torture, physical and sexual abuse, mass surveillance, family separation, and repression of cultural and religious expression? That China? Jesus. Who cares?

And yet their people are happier and better cared for than those in the United States. Would you care to back up any of those claims without sourcing Falun Gong, Radio Free Asia or Adrien Zenz?

Further are you implying the United States doesn't have arbitrary detention or forced labor? I invite you to look at the ENTIRE FUCKING PRISON SYSTEM.

&gt;Except, you know, being the most pro-union president in our lifetimes...

Because they paid some union heads to put their tongue up his ass? Cool. I guess we know who the class traitors are now, so that's nice.

&gt;I'll take "you don't actually pay attention to policy and vote mainly on vibes" for 10,000 Alex.

Better educated than you since all you have is parroting pathetic liberal propaganda about a neverending string of feckless corporate puppets who are responsible for your exploitation and suffering at the hands of a parasitic class of sociopaths.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44274917054.0" user="vankorgan" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And yet their people are happier and better cared for than those in the United States. Would you care to back up any of those claims without sourcing Falun Gong, Radio Free Asia or Adrien Zenz?

This. This is the point where I decided you're not worth the argument. The wholesale denial or forgiveness of China's many human rights abuses simply because of your political leanings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44279057725.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Which ones in particular? Because I'm happy to debunk the vast majority of them for the propaganda they are. You'd probably do well to read 'Manufacturing Consent' by Chomsky.

China is far from perfect, however the United States wants to cast them as a almost comically evil mustache-twirling villain so that politically uneducated people like you will consent to another cold war. It was virtually the same thing with the Soviet Union.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230390921.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>When Trump levels the Gaza Strip to develop resorts and starts a War with Iran, you’re going to be disappointed.

Do you not get that he formally recognized Jerusalem as the capital of Israel?

He moved the US Embassy there after every President since Clinton deferred the move.

Trump will do the genocide part himself.

Refusing to vote will not stop Trump from becoming president.

I don’t believe the people who push this argument actually care about Palestinians, because no one who does would ever allow Trump to become president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230647681.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>And that's different than having it leveled and depopulated to build infrastructure for the new trade corridor, how?

The end result is the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232105080.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>Is that what Biden is doing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230938670.0" user="abacuz4" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;When Trump levels the Gaza Strip to develop resorts and starts a War with Iran, you’re going to be disappointed.  

Maybe they won't be. Maybe we should listen when they are telling us who they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232108974.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>You’re not wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229645912.0" user="Bodoblock" delta="False">
    <text>I don't find the matchups against "Generic X" all that convincing, simply because Generic X does not have any substantial baggage. It doesn't trigger any of the emotional triggers that an actual name and a face would.

In an election, each voter makes an assessment of who to pick based on the trade-offs each candidate presents. A generic option doesn't actually force anyone to do this calculus in their head.

It's like the partner that says I'm open to eat anything and then when actually confronted with choices they strike down every option presented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229882338.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Could also be that Biden is near as makes no difference a republican and, as of recently complicit in war crimes such as ethnic cleansing at best, and genocide at (a much more substantiated) worst.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230090099.0" user="Minister_for_Magic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;n is near as makes no difference a republican

If you actually believe this after seeing 4 years of Trump, I have no idea what planet you are living on</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230124009.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Is the working class any better off? Nope.

Was there meaningful action taken for climate change? Nope. Token bullshit doesn't count. It should have been declared an emergency.

Less money spent on wars/defense? Hard nope. Plus a genocide.

Did we get significant healthcare reform? Nope.

Student debt forgiveness? Nope.

Immigration reform? Nope.

I mean good on him for hating gay people slightly less, I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230246281.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Was there meaningful action taken for climate change?

The Inflation Reduction Act was the largest piece of climate change legislation in US history. 

&gt; Student debt forgiveness? 

Biden forgave $10,000 per borrower, but was stopped by the Supreme Court.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230585166.0" user="ObviousSea9223" delta="False">
    <text>People just have not been paying attention the last 2 years. Or 6. Or...oh no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230683388.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Have you? How much material change has been made?

A token payment to student loan borrowers and some corporate subsidies constitute enough change for crises that are literally threatening civilization? Okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230710730.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>What wouldn't be token if $10,000 is a token payment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230737420.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>How about the hundreds of billions he's sent off to support genocide in Gaza and neo-nazi militias in Ukraine?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230752139.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>The loan forgiveness program *was* hundreds of billions of dollars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230771361.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Around as much as he's spent on two wars. So in other words he could have doubled the program.

Additionally according to experts he could have solved homelessness and hunger in the country with that money, but those issues are less important to his affluent voters.

And, just for the record, proposing policy you know will fail doesn't count for shit. It's optics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230813593.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Dude I'm hard into leftist stuff and generally would like to see massively increased investment in these things but you are losing your mind if you think that 400b can fully solve homelessness and hunger in the US. What "experts" are you referring to here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230883791.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And yes, Trump can destroy democracy while Biden struggles to enact his policies because Trump would have a friendly court and that shit matters.

And how did that happen? Because Democrats constantly nominate center-right SCJ's. Then they don't do anything to convince standing ones to resign while they have office and could stack the court. Oh, and they haven't expanded the court either. It's just like Obama running on codifying Roe V. Wade, then just deciding not to so the party could keep holding it over the people's heads..

&gt;What "experts" are you referring to here? Usually you want to refer to specific people and research

According to HUD, it's actually strikingly inexpensive at 20 billion, however, I think more realistic estimates put the total at 97 billion (8.1 billion/yr over 12 years.) Of course if homelessness and destitution were to end then Biden's corporate donors couldn't as easily make use of exploitive labor practices.

Hunger is cheaper at 25 billion, but again, without the ultimatum of destitution, corporations lose money since they can no longer pay their employees starvation wages. 40 billion per year solves hunger worldwide, incidentally.

I invite you to look up either figure yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44233525843.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; And how did that happen? Because Democrats constantly nominate center-right SCJ's. 

We could exhume and clone Marx three times and replace Kagan, Sotomayor, and Brown-Jackson with them and it'd still be a 6-3 court. 

&gt; According to HUD, it's actually strikingly inexpensive at 20 billion

Surely you've got a link to a report here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230803711.0" user="ObviousSea9223" delta="False">
    <text>With that margin, against this obstructive an opposition, with this SCOTUS, and the current set of varied problems during a global crisis after his predecessor nuked most of the flex we had, economically?

Yes, lol. It's been quite a lot. Literally just the infrastructure bill is a huge deal. Even if I didn't understand anything about the U.S. political process or current context whatsoever, he's still done a crap ton of stuff, just objectively, by the standards of U.S. Presidents in general. In particular, he's done a huge amount of deferred maintenance. It all looks pretty conservative, but he's been objectively effective in the role.

Given the electorate we have, I expected far less. This helps us move a bit. You're not going the accelerationist route with this, are you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230836964.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. I mean that's nothing but ignorant apologia and simping for a tyrant who would as soon step on your face, or anyone else's from your class as look at you...

But no, I'm not accelerationist. I just have enough fucking scruples to put my foot down and not vote for a person who is directly supporting a genocide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231464908.0" user="ObviousSea9223" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, now you're talking about elections. Look, I have plenty of criticisms of Biden. Most are predicated on criticisms of the left coalition and voters as a whole. AND he's objectively accomplished a lot of good, which I'm pretty sure is what we were actually talking about. AND if you prefer Trump, you don't actually care about the genocide, much less things like improved domestic policy. Yes, yes, you're familiar. But I think there's a more fundamental point here. There's plenty to be mad about and plenty to demand better on. The U.S. role in Israel-Palestine is a disaster and a stain on basically us as a people. Biden in his own role, but not independent of us. See, the dynamic there can't be validly ignored. It might seem convenient to pretend that the reason for it is just who Biden is. What Biden is is a reflection of this half of the country. Practically clockwork. The median of the half is somewhere around "hey, maybe we should try not to kill so many civilians, if possible, if you don't mind."  The median of the other half is like "better to just flatten the whole area." That's us. We're not going to tolerate a candidate that's head and shoulders morally better than us as a people. Not once they act like it. And that has huge implications for the manner in which we need to proceed if we care about these things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230709614.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>And it's literally not even close to enough. Instead we'll continue to blame the Global South who we have exploited to the point where they cannot afford to transition to renewable or nuclear energy. Probably China too, even though they are making FAR larger strides towards green energy.

Lol. 10,000 dollars. Then he failed. Okay. Amazing.

So Biden can't repay the victims of predatory loan sharks, but Trump can dissolve democracy forever. It's weird how Liberals think the president is simultaneously omnipotent and unable to do anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230966259.0" user="Possible-Ad-2891" delta="False">
    <text>It is much easier to break things than to build them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232507813.0" user="the-awesomer" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah really really ignorant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232870596.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>I think the ignorant one here is you if you're content with half-measures and corporate kowtowing when it comes to climate change. I know it's easier to stick your head in the sand, but the inaction of corporate stooges like Biden will be disastrous within your lifetime.

Also, do you know how much the average student loan debt is? He offered to pay off around a quarter. Then failed, and I'm not even sure he ever thought he'd succeed, which may be why he championed the cause at all.

Good optics for idiots who believe there's any difference between the corporate mouthpieces in blue ties and the ones in red ties, though. I mean it's nice that the blue ones hate gay people a little less, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232505194.0" user="the-awesomer" delta="False">
    <text>You are coming off as crazy ignorant, but that probably doesn't bother you...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232850870.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>And you're coming off as a liberal with Trump Derangement Syndrome.

He wasn't even as bad as many other republicans in living memory. Reagan, for instance, was exponentially more disastrous for the country.

If you want to complain about the rise of the far right, [your party is also to blame](https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/09/12/democrats-interfere-republican-primaries/). Want to moan about Roe V. Wade? Well Obama ran on codifying it and passed 20-something bills that weren't that or the ACA while he had a supermajority. The democrats thought it would be useful to hold over the heads of idiots like you (and at the time myself) so they had to keep voting blue. The only ignorant person is your average young Democrat voter who thinks that against all historical precedent THIS TIME you'll be able to push the right winger they nominate in a farcical primary further left.

And when it comes time for the next election? It's funny how they always have to try to court the centrists who never vote for them, but when it comes to the left wing of their party they act like they can just be ignored.

It's almost like the same corporate sectors bribe both parties with speaking fees, campaign contributions and other legalized forms of corruption so it's always a corporate candidate that wins.

Either way, electoralism in general has failed. Bourgeois democracy has failed and people being simps for the DNC are just valuing stability over justice and it's getting people killed.... But naturally they don't care, because it's no one they know. Just statistics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232896460.0" user="the-awesomer" delta="False">
    <text>Ignorant probably the least of your problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230586360.0" user="sqrtsqr" delta="False">
    <text>I don't. But I voted for the Democratic party specifically because the Republican party (not Trump, **all of them**) is a criminal organization that must be stopped.

We voted for Biden. And we won.

And what did Biden do? Appoint a Republican to head the DOJ. 

There is literally nothing he can say to earn my vote at this point. I would rather embrace Accelerationism and give the country to Trump than watch the Democrats run interference for them any longer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229648748.0" user="VoraciousVorthos" delta="False">
    <text>But the thing is you will never vote for a “generic democrat.” There will always be a name there, and that name will not have the advantage of “generic democrat” where prospective voters can project their own preferred policies into them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229656311.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I vote PSL generally, but were I the sort of person who would still vote for Democrats, I would probably favor *any candidate that doesn't support genocide.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229775367.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>So you'd never vote for a socialist? Good to know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229810768.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>What's this supposed to mean? Are you ignorant and implying socialists support genocide?

I mean really voting for a socialist is generally DOA. You can look to Chile to see what happened with an electorialist/reformist transition to Socialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229873108.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>Socialism is genocidal. Full stop. Unless you are going to deny the crimes of the USSR, PRC, Khmer Rouge, and others.

Allende was a Soviet stooge and deserved to be ousted by Pinochet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229909522.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Then you're extremely uneducated and propagandized. Full stop.

The Khmer Rouge, for instance was funded by the United States. Of those we can focus on the USSR, though since of them it's the one I'm most versed in the history of, though. Would you like to focus on an example of genocide?

&gt;Allende was a Soviet stooge and deserved to be ousted by Pinochet.

Ah yes, that warm and fuzzy guy who... let me check my notes... gained power in a military coup instead of a democratic election and dropped his political opponents from helicopters or had them raped by dogs. Is that the guy you're rooting for here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230100926.0" user="Minister_for_Magic" delta="False">
    <text>*Claims socialism is genocidal and then proceeds to name several* ***communist****, totalitarian regimes.*

this is a big brain strategy, cotton.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230325137.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>So which Socialist regime is working out right now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231714648.0" user="BiDo_Boss" delta="False">
    <text>By US standards? All of them are socialist.

Give me a list of what regimes you consider to be "working out", and I'll show you why the vast majority of them are more socialist than the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232120841.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t have a real world example of a successful Socialist regime?

More “socialist” is not socialism.

It’s capitalism with public services and some publicly held businesses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249743492.0" user="BiDo_Boss" delta="False">
    <text>Your first problem is thinking capitalism and socialism is a binary, the world doesn't work like that. You'll just draw an arbirary line to call every regime you like "capitalist but" lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249963429.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>I have never said it was a binary.  Socialism has a definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44255027035.0" user="BiDo_Boss" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I have never said it was a binary.

But also 

&gt; It’s capitalism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44255126722.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to have decided that any country that is not the US is socialist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44272708775.0" user="BiDo_Boss" delta="False">
    <text>Don't put words in my mouth or forget the original argument.

You responded in support of an comment saying 

&gt; Socialism is genocidal. Full stop. Unless you are going to deny the crimes of the USSR, PRC, Khmer Rouge, and others.

saying that socialist countries aren't working out. Are you even arguing in good faith? You really think socialism means USSR and PRC level oppression authoritarianism?

If you say yes, name whatever countries you think are "working out" and provide a good life for its citizens right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232257891.0" user="mana-addict4652" delta="False">
    <text>What drivel, I'm curious if you claim the same of religious people based on their religion.

Or if you say the same about every death caused by a capitalist country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230092966.0" user="Minister_for_Magic" delta="False">
    <text>100% spot on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229670473.0" user="golden_boy" delta="False">
    <text>This is an extremely bad take. Biden is an incrementalist but has implemented a wide range of meaningful shifts in federal policy. He recently made a rule change requiring replacement of lead pipes where previous policy to keep them effectively wrote off systematic albeit stochastic lead poisoning of communities without the resources to lobby their utilities to mitigate corrosion.

He also instructed the FTC to end its decades-long policy of permitting monopolistic practices where efficiency gains could be demonstrated.

He also instructed disaster mitigation programs to change their benefit - cost formulation for protection projects to increase their consideration for poor communties, where previously their structure implicitly prioritized wealthier areas with more expensive assets.

Just a few examples - I'm sure if you Google it you can find more. IRA was also a pretty big deal for green infrastructure.

Iirc he may have also instructed the fed to consider disaggregated welfare metrics in monetary policy rather than top level indicators which implicitly prioritize the rich, but I'm not sure about this last one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229739176.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Incrementalism means treating the symptoms and not the condition causing them. The truth is that reformism will not solve the problems with capitalism and bourgeois democracy because capital will always insinuate itself into every branch of power.

We can talk about how 'green' he is, but the fact is that he has not done enough, or as much as he could have. In fact he approved more drilling than Trump.

We can talk about how pro-working-class he is, except he's proven staunchly anti-union.

Oh, and there's also the genocide.

The fact is that his policy doesn't represent the wishes of his voters, which is the function of bourgeois democracy. You get representatives that only represent capital. Which is how you can have issues like M4A or Gaza ceasefire that have 75-80% support and corporate scum like Biden don't stand for. That's no accident.

Also, I'm not sure if you've been paying attention to climate scientists? But incremental change isn't enough change fast enough to avert serious catastrophe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229776569.0" user="golden_boy" delta="False">
    <text>Are you referring to the situation in Gaza as genocide or is there something else you're talking about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229846920.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>The actively transpiring genocide that fits the UN definition to a T, particularly when combined with the legal precedent from Srebrenica, yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229847645.0" user="Getlucky12341" delta="False">
    <text>They're probably talking about the Palestine genocide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229909108.0" user="EarsLookWeird" delta="False">
    <text>"The situation in Gaza" does sound alot better than "genocide" so we will award you half marks for a valiant effort</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230313918.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>The propagandists are really starting to bury the lede.  I guess starting out with the genocide claims hasn’t been working as well as they’d hoped.

They’ve resorted to claiming Biden isn’t acting enough like he’s king.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231557361.0" user="golden_boy" delta="False">
    <text>I mean personally I view Likkud's long term approach towards Palestine as genocidal but to conflate that with the latest conflict (and what exactly is a government to do when its people are kidnapped following a mass murder?) and lay it at Biden's feet it plainly disingenuous.

At a certain point these tankied are just accelerationists cheering on the spectre of fascism because they're similarly more interested in owning the libs than in the hard work of governance in a pluralistic society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232112307.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>Very eloquently put.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44237353156.0" user="abacuz4" delta="False">
    <text>They are also egged on by influencers who literally do better financially when fascism is more popular. 

Cui bono and all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229687301.0" user="ReflectiveJellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>This isn’t true in practice though because no one knows if a random, unheard of candidate is actually “a generic candidate.” 

There’s a difference between comparing an incumbent president against an ideal and comparing that incumbent against some guy running for office that you’ve never heard of. 

Seriously, hundreds of people run for president every presidential election and no one knows about them. An incumbent president has a four year track record, years of news stories about them, etc. and in practice, people go with the devil they know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230919183.0" user="dankdougie" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is, I’m not gonna vote for a devil i know when his history in office has been filled with policy i can not support. I vote democrat for every slot on the ballot, except president lately. Obama was the last democratic presidential candidate I supported. 

It has nothing to do with being progressive, or him following my ideology 100%. And everything to do with his record in office and the fact I’m not voting for a member of a generation that makes up less than 7 percent of the population and expecting him to make the right calls for the generations that are actually gonna be around much longer than him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230934102.0" user="ReflectiveJellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough dankdougie, I’m not really saying people should vote for incumbents, just that this is the longstanding, prevailing trend in American politics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231312455.0" user="dankdougie" delta="False">
    <text>You ain’t wrong. Just those of us who never wanted him there to begin with, aren’t suddenly gonna change our minds. Especially when he continues to push for things that I disliked about him before taking office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229702893.0" user="notkenneth" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; There is no name recognition.

Underperforming a generic candidate doesn't mean there is no name recognition. 

Whether he'd get the same sort of incumbent advantage is a separate question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229804993.0" user="WerhmatsWormhat" delta="False">
    <text>Generic candidates basically always outperform actual ones because they don’t have baggage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229809467.0" user="Deadmau007" delta="False">
    <text>Dean Phillips, a prototypical "generic democrat", is running in the primary and he's not doing well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229832425.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Could it be because money is what wins primaries and because, according to 'Wilding v. DNC Services Corp':  
"The DNC is a corporation and under no legal obligation to follow its own charter with regards to neutrality in primary elections"

The fact that a ruling like that doesn't outrage liberals to the point of abandoning a party is frankly ridiculous. It's legal precedent reinforcing Biden's credo that, 'nothing will fundamentally change.'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229895564.0" user="GabuEx" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;money is what wins primaries

[Bernie Sanders raised and spent more money than Hillary Clinton in 2016](https://www.npr.org/2016/04/29/476047822/sanders-campaign-has-spent-50-percent-more-than-clinton-in-2016).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229935909.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Could it be because money is what wins primaries (along with the support of media monopolies) and because, according to 'Wilding v. DNC Services Corp':

Let's read that again closely. I didn't say funding. I said money. We can look at  statistics and see the amount of positive vs. negative stories on major news outlets regarding both candidates, as obviously large corporations stood to lose something in a Sanders presidency.

Further, Wilding v. DNC Services Corp was about the 2016 primary, where evidence for favoritism and shady election practices was so strong the DNC's only defense was to say they weren't legally obligated to follow their own charter rather than to constest the evidence.

I'm no fan of Sanders. He's center left at best and a lapdog of the party, but he was absolutely robbed in that primary, beyond a shadow of a doubt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229914168.0" user="Deadmau007" delta="False">
    <text>Bernie Sanders wasn't supported by the DNC but he was personally popular enough to come within striking distance of the nomination. Trump managed to win the 2016 primary despite the getting no institutional support from the GOP.

In contrast Dean Phillips is polling in single digits. Lack of party support is not the issue here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229946941.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you should read a little further about that case I mentioned. He would never have been nominated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230157143.0" user="Particular-Court-619" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone polls unfavorably against 'A generic XYZ.'  Because a generic XYZ is an ideal candidate in your mind, not someone who's human with flaws, real and imagined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230161271.0" user="Particular-Court-619" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Take your pick between which genocidal, bourgeois, racist, old homophobic white man you want, I guess.

This is absolute nonsense. Biden came out in support of gay marriage before any other major national politician.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230173849.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>In the United States.

Because social issues like that are meaningless to his campaign donors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230182323.0" user="Particular-Court-619" delta="False">
    <text>You can change the goalposts and such, but you literally just said something absolutely false and nonsensical.  Just own up to it lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230203931.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>I mean he voted for 'Don't Ask, Don't Tell.' He claimed gay people were 'A security risk' and shouldn't be given clearance. He voted for the Defense of Marriage Act.

The goalposts haven't moved. It's just that your criteria for 'not being homophobic' are dumb. People don't necessarily set policy because it's what they believe. They set it because it's a popularity game.

You must be the kind of person who thinks Disney cares about LGBTQ people because they represent them in movies... even though they give millions to right wing PACs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232430522.0" user="Hartastic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I mean he voted for 'Don't Ask, Don't Tell.'

I'm not sure how old you are, but at the time, DADT was considered *insanely* liberal.  A majority of Americans believed, in total seriousness, that if a war were to break out after it was put in place, America would be defenseless because the entirety of the armed forces would be too busy blowing each other to fight.

This all seems stupid now but 30 years ago most people thought it was true.  Clinton burned a ton of political capital to get it in.

Often meaningful progress ages poorly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232811243.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>That same year Cuba would allow for openly gay, bisexual and transgender soldiers to serve in their armed forces, and Latin American culture broadly was much more homophobic than the United States at the time.

DADT was ridiculous even in 1993. Biden fucked up.

What about the other things? Did he also mean well when he voted for DOMA?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44234184227.0" user="Hartastic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; That same year Cuba would allow for openly gay, bisexual and transgender soldiers to serve in their armed forces, and Latin American culture broadly was much more homophobic than the United States at the time.

Despite your claim that definitely would not have flown in the US at the time.  It was still legal to murder gay people in the US in those days -- as long as you claimed, without evidence, that they hit on you first there was zero chance of finding a jury that would convict.

Your opinion is wildly ahistorical and I'm not having this discussion further with someone who can't have been old enough to pay attention to politics three decades ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44238842877.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>And there were people who opposed that. I'm not a huge fan of Bernie these days, but he opposed both bills. You make it sound like literally signing off on evil is just something you have to do. You actually don't.

Just like when people were voting for slave owners when John Brown was alive. There's no such thing as an ahistorical opinion here. There is right and there is wrong. When people do things that are wrong and never apologize for them or make a concerted effort to change, they are bad people. Joe Biden is a bad person. See the current genocide he's signed off on for further evidence.

I mean the conversation is a loss anyway since I'm talking to a pathetic sycophant who will bend over backwards to defend a lapdog for the parasitic  bourgeois who would just as soon step on your face as look at you. Blue MAGA is just as pathetic as the red version of the cult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249433647.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>And which third-party outsider with conveniently your views should we vote for or are you one of those people advocating "guillotine 'em all and let god sort out how to run our society"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249449186.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>Naw, I'm a communist, not an anarchist. Though, 'guillotine them all' sounds pretty appealing.

I mean, probably vote for a party that actually represents the proletariat and has a track record of doing so? As opposed to either flavor of the uniparty that has a track record of repeatedly screwing over the working class?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44295977207.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>And which party would that be? As I hate how, whatever their politics, a lot of people who don't take the side of either major party seem to just push voting third party with no further specifics as if there was this one alternative party called The Third Party that had perfect policies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44296108629.0" user="SaltiestRaccoon" delta="False">
    <text>I prefer the Party for Socialism and Liberation.

I'm a Marxist, so I don't think reformism is something that will work, as the plutocratic oligarchy we live in has too many checks and balances against that, but of the options, PSL's positions are the ones I agree with most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231400917.0" user="ScannerBrightly" delta="False">
    <text>So you would vote for Kamala?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229633924.0" user="SteadfastEnd" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely agree. That being said, prior to 2008, Obama was still somewhat unknown, despite his ascendancy in 2004. Hillary was still considered the default shoo-in (D) candidate as late as spring 2008.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229749302.0" user="ERJAK123" delta="False">
    <text>Ds and Rs aren't whose vote matters. Party members have chosen already.

Undecided voters are whose vote counts and, as Family Guy said in the early 2000s, they're some of the dumbest people alive. You need simple concepts, catchy slogans, recognizable names, and pretty colors to convince them to vote for your guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229836456.0" user="sockgorilla" delta="False">
    <text>Terry Crews, but in character as President comancho 2024</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230433530.0" user="ObviousSea9223" delta="False">
    <text>Throw in Dwayne Johnson as VP, but in character as Kevin Hart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249416046.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>I presume Johnson has never played Kevin Hart per se so you're trying to just make a cringe-funny incongruous combination</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249926157.0" user="ObviousSea9223" delta="False">
    <text>He does the voice only. Haven't seen him pull off the look yet. And yes, the idea was to pick a character that was a foil for Camacho as opposed to like a Maui.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44295964961.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Character makes it sound like you want to watch the election as a movie or some other way that you can get all the cringe-comedy without any policies from whichever one you disagree with negatively affecting you if they win</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44296370847.0" user="ObviousSea9223" delta="False">
    <text>.......

This was a joke in the context of jokes. I'm very serious about actual politics, which most people don't take a tenth as seriously as they should. It's life and death for all but the most privileged. And more of even them than realize it. 

Shoot, I thought you were messing around before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249426160.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't it be election fraud to run as someone you're not (yeah I know, the whole cliche of politicians 180-ing on their campaign promises but that's their ideas not their literal identity) especially if the person they claim to be doesn't technically exist

No matter how cringe-memable the combination (looking at you ObviousSea9223 wanting Dwayne Johnson to play a real person he's never played who looks barely anything like him apart from same gender) wouldn't it look a bit rich for any party to run someone under false pretenses (even if that wouldn't be fraud) given George Santos's house ouster</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229941162.0" user="sir_aken" delta="False">
    <text>This is a good point. If you’re educated on politics, you probably have a good idea of who you’re going to vote for and what party you align with. Hell, if you’re educated at all past high school, there’s a good chance you’ll never vote Republican.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230283481.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>Party platforms change.  Pre-Contract with America and even pre-Tea Party, reasonable people were still able to vote Republican with a straight face.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230299291.0" user="sir_aken" delta="False">
    <text>This is true, but I think the social upheaval of the 60s radically changed that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232101909.0" user="Savingskitty" delta="False">
    <text>The 60’s was another polarizing time, but I wasn’t alive then.  I’m talking about pre Newt Gingrich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230231986.0" user="Radix2309" delta="False">
    <text>Well you do care about turnout. The party faithful can fail to show up at the polls as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44233790418.0" user="SlipperyTurtle25" delta="False">
    <text>9/11</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44233845120.0" user="Aegi" delta="False">
    <text>That's bullshit, undecided voters might often be dumb, but if you live in a state that's obviously red or blue the electoral college means that your vote doesn't matter and therefore you should stay undecided to see which third party candidate you're going to vote for to try to get them nationally above 5% so that they can be entitled to funding from The presidential election commission...

Plus, in some states, a party's candidate getting over five, 10, or 15% of the vote can then put them at the top of the ballot in a randomized order with the other two parties.

The fact that they didn't even differentiate in that family Guy joke between the electoral college votes for president, and other votes like senators, etc also showed that the people who found that joke true to be dumber than the people being made fun of in the joke in my view.

For example, it's still a while away but I don't know who I would vote for next year living in New York State because it's pointless to vote for either the Democratic or Republican candidate, so when it comes to voting for president next year I would still be undecided because I don't live in a swing state.

I also don't know who I would vote for for our next county coroner because I need to see who ends up running and what their record is like. Same thing goes for my vote for some more local offices since the party people are affiliated with in local politics is generally more an issue of practicality than necessarily what their views or character is like and we've had elections where none of the candidates for town supervisor or something are running on a major party line and they're all running on minor party lines.

People who simplify voting like that joke in Family Guy did instead of talking about strategic registering and strategic voting are also idiots in my view when it comes to the issue of elections.

People also forget that voting, but turning in a blank ballot is so much more effective and actually speaks to being dissatisfied with the choices instead of just not voting at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44234425277.0" user="Philo_T_Farnsworth" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; People also forget that voting, but turning in a blank ballot is so much more effective 

Yes, I agree. The best way to express your dissatisfaction through voting is by...  not voting.

That'll teach 'em.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229760015.0" user="dollabillkirill" delta="False">
    <text>That’s the problem. Every race is so close that they can’t win with just 90 or 95%. They need them all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44229934443.0" user="jakesboy2" delta="False">
    <text>People vote for who to nominate. If your theory is true then one of those random people would beat trump/biden in the primaries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230060159.0" user="I_Am_Coopa" delta="False">
    <text>You're forgetting a very important part of how parties select candidates: primary elections. The very idea of some John Doe being the nominee is born out every election cycle. People registered to a party vote to elect delegates who support their presidential candidate of choice as the nominee.

Imagine if a party nominated someone who only got 10% of votes in the primaries when there was an otherwise clear winner, that would be an *extremely* tough sell that would anger a good chunk of the base you need to vote for unknown John Doe. 

It's also important to remember that beyond capability, voters also want *experience* from a candidate. Even the dumbest voter recognizes that being president is not an entry level position any shmuck off the street can handle. That's why candidates tend to be older with long careers in politics, business, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44232537800.0" user="WhiteWolf3117" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, it’s sort of a misunderstanding to ask why the parties don’t “just choose”, because outside of incumbency (indirectly anyway), they’ve already chosen. 

It’s obviously more nuanced than that, but the general concept applies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230069731.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>I mean we could nominate the VP as president. It's not like there isn't any precedent, either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44231952618.0" user="Randomousity" delta="False">
    <text>Except she isn't who the majority of Democratic voters want. They want Biden. What good would it do to please, say, 20% of Democratic voters by nominating Harris instead of Biden if it would displease a different 60% of Democratic voters?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44233205306.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>It's not democratic *voters*, it's democratic members.

Democratic voters gonna vote Democrat anyway. What you need is to appeal to the middle ground who normally doesn't give a fuck and often doesn't vote.

That demographic wanted to vote out Trump because he was just awful. Are they going to take off work or even get off the couch to vote in Biden the bankroller of bombings? No. And then we'll get four more years of Trump.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44237191582.0" user="Randomousity" delta="False">
    <text>Do you even read your own comments?

&gt; That demographic wanted to vote out Trump because he was just awful. Are they going to take off work or even get off the couch to vote in Biden the bankroller of bombings? No. And then we'll get four more years of Trump.

So, it's your position that the people "who normally [don't] give a fuck and often [don't] vote" but who were motivated to elect Biden to "vote out Trump because he was just awful," will now see a rematch between Biden and Trump and magically be ok with Trump winning this time around? Do these people no longer think Trump is awful? What's your evidence that they no longer think Trump is horrible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44237214581.0" user="almisami" delta="False">
    <text>People don't vote to prevent future things, they vote based on current inconveniences.

It's not rational, but it's a proven trend. They don't see abstaining from voting as handing the victory to Trump, even though it functionally is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44260476971.0" user="Frnklfrwsr" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah the purpose of an election first and foremost is not to pick the best, most qualified, smartest, and most capable candidate. It’s nice if that candidate does win, but that’s not the purpose it serves. 

The first purpose is to be a popularity contest, as you said. That’s not a criticism, it’s just a fact. And it’s actually an important role for it to play. 

Elections are the compromise we made as a society to replace violent revolutions when we want political change. That’s the purpose they serve. If the winner of the election is the actual best candidate, great! But the most important thing is that they have legitimacy and a violent overthrow of the government is avoided.

The country can survive a bad President for a term. The voters make mistakes sometimes, and the consequences can be bad but generally the democracy survives. 

It’s when the legitimacy of the institutions themselves are questioned and the validity of the elections is doubted that we start to get into trouble. 

If the President sucks but everyone accepts that he is who the voters picked, we can live with that. 

But if a critical mass of people do NOT accept that the winner has a legitimate claim to the office, that’s when we get in a lot of trouble.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
