<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="63" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44230199284.0" user="New_Name_Guy" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not gonna change your mind. I agree. 

Generally speaking, I like Biden, but I know he could easily lose. I'm also starting to hate the Democratic part, not as much as I hate the GOP, but they're getting there. 

The only thing I can think to do this year is just vote third party. That will send the message to the big parties that we don't like what they're selling and that they work for us. 

NOT voting is not an option because they'll just ignore us, so we have to put our votes into people who will challenge their control over the political process in America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230477623.0" user="xoLiLyPaDxo" delta="False">
    <text>Here is the reality in the US: If you vote third party the right will win, and yes, they have every intention of doing terrible things when they do. It's no secret. They have their plan online for all to see, and it's horrible. It's not possible for a 3rd party to win in the US, all it does is hand it over to GOP guaranteed.

If the left tries to replace center, or center right candidates, the right will win. If the left tries to make the party more progressive and actually get things done, the right will win. This is the present conundrum.

The only possible way to change this at present is when the Republicans are 100% guaranteed to not win anything at all for an extended time period, and democrats gain a consistent supermajority ( they don't even have the house at present so keep dreaming) . Only then can they push the party left and replace "right wing" democrat seats with progressives so that they can actually pass legislation that will actually improve the quality of life for Americans.

That's not happening ATM, so unless people figure out how to make it happen, we are screwed and getting more screwed by the day with every single seat in Congress that is lost to Republicans in our lifetimes. Every state legislature, state government and the white house election, things just become more and more broken as the country gets pulled backasswards further to the right.

We don't have to say " this is what Republicans really think" , all we have to do is look at what they really do.

For example, at first opportunity, Republicans cemented corporate power over the people so they could elect their own corporate officials directly by corporations via Citizens United. You remember that ruling that gave corporations personhood and took the power away from the people? Yea, that was 100% GOP. Only the democrats are trying to get it overturned, and the GOP are doing everything in their power to prevent it. All you have to do is scroll down click tab Trump administration and you will see who is really filling the swamp with corporate power. It's not possible to stop corporations from directly electing their own candidates at will unless citizens united is overturned. Corporations will push their candidates through regardless as they have too much power and money to compete with.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizens_United_(organization)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230563647.0" user="New_Name_Guy" delta="False">
    <text>Fair points. I vote in Massachusetts, so I voting third party will not change things very much. The Dems will will my state and get all of its electoral college votes. 

But I disagree that voting third party will automatically mean a win for the GOP. It may be true with West and Stein, but not RFK. Right now RFK is taking more votes from Trump than he is Biden. 

But I think if we can be strategic, we can get a reasonable Republican as Biden's opponent, then we can be assured that it won't be that bad should the GOP wins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44230839328.0" user="xoLiLyPaDxo" delta="False">
    <text>There is no way it's not going to be bad if GOP win at all regardless of who their candidate is due to the overall makeup and platform if the party itself. 

Regardless of which GOP wins it, the supreme Court makeup is already lopsided  and the federal courts stacked. It will cement a lifetime of interpreting laws in conservatives favor to block any  future legislation meant to improve the quality of life for Americans, not just a four year presidential term. The sheer overwhelming amount of damage that was already done due to Trump's election alone will actually take  lifetimes to begin to adjust at this point when you look at exactly how many federal judges McConnell and Trump seated last time. Adding another round of that regardless of what GOP it is at this point is putting the nails in the coffin for any hope for the future of improving programs for the people.

Bidens chances are actually better if Trump runs, the people are worse off if Biden loses. 

There is no such thing as a "reasonable" Republican at this point, the GOP platform is 100% the problem. Look who they elected to be speaker of the house. Trump isn't the actual problem here, he's just one of the symptoms. Any GOP being elected just makes the problems go from horrible to hopeless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249468040.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>Reminds me of this crazy idea worthy of r/crazyideas I had a while back to get the right on board with taking down corporate personhood, argue that unless they give up either corporate personhood or abortion bans the combination of those two existing means everyone with a failed business or business idea they gave up on or w/e (including perhaps their "dear leader" Trump) is guilty of murder for aborting the corporate person</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
