<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="122" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44233013701.0" user="Crab_Shark" delta="False">
    <text>Given the resources, timing, and support needed for a successful campaign - it really is too late for alternate candidates to be viable. Trump and Biden already started running campaigns and are the top picks, of their respective parties full stop. 

At this point, more candidates don’t matter. 
If someone was sufficiently viable to take Biden’s spot - they’re not trying because he chose to run. Winning now happens on razor thin margins due to the mountain of bad election policies/hacks, and voter ambivalence/suppression. 

If a 3rd party manages to miraculously get big enough to offer a more viable platform than Biden, they would most likely not have a more viable campaign and would only serve as a spoiler candidate for Democrats. 

Even candidates like DeSantis who were being pegged as the next big horse in the Republican race several months ago, formally threw his hat in the ring - too late. He lags Trump significantly in polls and GOP donors are already pulling support for him. For a while, he was supposed to be the guys to replace Trump.

Campaigns need more than votes. They need money, media, massive scale support from institutions, a savvy team, and a compelling candidate and platform. They have to hit scale against people who dominate the news. 

I think a lot of people who want a younger, more progressive Democratic candidate, or a younger Republican candidate with less baggage simply should vote for the least bad candidate until a movement gets a candidate that more aligns to their ideals within spitting distance of the presidency. 

Anything else is feeding their opposition - and no, the candidate closer to your side is not part of the opposition. Revolutionary change is not going to lead to better faster results than incremental. Nothing will lead to better results faster than everyone deciding to actually vote.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
