<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2673789025.0" index="151" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/187wktd/cmv_the_notion_that_the_democrats_or_republicans/">
    <title>CMV: The notion that the Democrats or Republicans "must" run Biden or Trump "because there are no other viable candidates" is ridiculous. There are thousands of people who would make better presidential candidates for 2024 than Biden or Trump.</title>
    <original_poster>SteadfastEnd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every argument for Biden or Trump to run in 2024 boils down to some version of "status quo" or "inertia." We're told that the Ds and Rs have no choice but to run these super-old candidates because there's nobody else who could be suitable.

&amp;#x200B;

In a nation of 332,000,000 people, there are well over 100 million who are over the age of 35, American-born, and have resided in the United States for 14 years or more - in other words, are constitutionally eligible to run for president.

Out of those 100 million, surely at least half have a basic education, are mature, sensible, decent people, and have demonstrated solid character - and also be significantly younger than Trump or Biden.

Out of those 50 million, surely at least ten million would qualify as *highly* educated - the metrics of which can be tricky to figure out (is it a master's degree? or something else?) - but they would be significantly above average.

Out of those 10 million, surely at least one million would be quite exceptional - people who have substantially high IQ, have advanced quite far in life and a career - such as being a doctor, or having worked in public governmental service for decades, etc.

And out of those million, surely at least 10,000 would have the political know-how, the charisma, the political interest, maybe have spent significant time abroad in foreign countries or speak multiple languages, to be a suitable president.

In fact, even in Congress, state legislatures or governorships alone, there must be dozens of good, qualified, educated, experienced politicians who would be much younger than Trump or Biden, and who would make suitable presidential candidates. 

So, CMV on this one. I don't buy for one moment the notion that, in a nation of 332 million people, America somehow has no choice but to run Biden vs. Trump in 2024 because "we've got no one else who'd be a good candidate."  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44236571792.0" user="Winter_Ad6784" delta="False">
    <text>In polling against Biden, despite what almost everyone would assume, Trump outperforms the other republicans running. The only "person" beating Biden more than Trump in polling is *Generic Republican* which of course is because *Generic Republican* has less baggage attached than any real republican candidate. So Trump looks like the best bet to Republicans.  


There's two problems with your statistical analysis that there must be a better option among the 300 million Americans. First, you overestimate how good the average person is. That person you went to highschool with that seems like they would make a good candidate would not look the same under the media spotlight (and the president is under the brightest spotlight), because Trump and Biden were those people in highschool and they don't look good now that they are under the spotlight. The second problem is that you don't consider whether those people who would make good presidents would *want* to be president because being smart, and mentally sound, and choosing to be the most famous person on earth don't go well together.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
