<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246040520.0" user="Green__lightning" delta="False">
    <text>So what are the costs of it? How many great things have been stopped by liability in some way? It's often said that if the automobile was invented today, they'd not be allowed or sold to the general public because of liability and increased safety concerns. Conversely, if we were as gung-ho as a hundred years ago, we'd likely have flying cars by now. More generally, great things step on people's toes, and the liability dominated, risk adverse culture gets in the way about that. The best counter example of this is the Internet, which came about because it's just information and harmless, and thus people could take risks with it. While it's still more like that than most industries, progress clearly slowed when everything became ran by a few major companies held responsible by advertisers, something that also seems to be greatly detrimental to the quality of the internet, and any semblance of free speech on it. 

Secondly, lets take global warming as a second example. As someone with a car, I'm slightly liable for all the bad things caused by climate change, despite doing nothing unreasonable. This liability is also shared with every automobile owner who ever existed, not evenly mind you, and you can quickly see how this leads to impractical things. I posit that there should be limitations to liability around things where liability is very thinly spread, like pollution, and also where it's indirect or unreasonably high. In effect, people have a right to endanger or inconvenience the rest of the world to some small degree, and this is necessary, lest every iota of the negative effects of someone's existence be tallied and the people of the future be expected to justify their life against these costs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246069626.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not sure that our views are mutually exclusive 

I am contending that the conception, maintenance, and administration of a system that allows everyone a chance to present their case is an overall positive thing for humanity and a strong example of something we’ve done right

You are saying that there should be limits on liability as not to impede overall progress within our civilization. I agree with you as does the civil justice system since there are limits on liability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246160788.0" user="Green__lightning" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, and that the system as it currently exists may be stifling innovation, and that these costs of it are somewhat hard to see, but very much real. The interesting question is what exactly has it made us miss out on, and how do the benefits of such a hypothetical compare to the actual benefits of our justice system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
