<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44245892367.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>Something for you to think about with Americans-

The vast majority of Americans are not First Nation/native. So there isn’t a cultural identity that unifies everyone to the extend that you would have in Scotland or in most other countries, for that matter. Instead, our predecessors brought their own cultural identities with them and continued to practice them here. And communities of people with the same cultural background formed. So when an American says “I’m Scottish” or any other nationality, they aren’t claiming to literally be from that country. They are identifying their cultural nexus to a country because those are the traditions that were passed on to them. Between Americans, that is how we understand how and why our cultural background is different from our peers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44248812222.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>But the problem arises when they then use that to justify or explain their actions in a way that negatively represents the culture that they're claiming to be from:

"I'm Scottish, so I drink a lot of whisky" - Scottish people may take a bit oc umbridge to that.

"I'm Irish so i hate the English" - both English people and Irish people would have a problem with this. People who are both English and Irish would have an even bigger one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251357519.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>That speaks more to the person being an asshole in general. In general terms, that’s not how an American uses it. You don’t stop doing something that is commonly done because of a few fools who spoil things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251848423.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;In general terms, that’s not how an American uses it.

It permiates through your media, though, and you see it on reddit a lot.

If people weren't doing it often, it wouldn't be an issue. When you challenge it, you just get attacked and downvoted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252134741.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>Because those people are just being assholes trying to excuse bad behavior. Stereotyping, both positive and negative, is a global behavior and not exclusive to Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252241097.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>No one said Stereotyping was an exclusively American behaviour.

However, when it is even in your sitcoms, lets not pretend that it's not widely occurring phenomenon and not some small sample of bad actors</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252274016.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>And I can cite examples of stereotypes of Americans in British shows and in British novels. Lady Violet certainly had lots of quips about Americans. It just doesn’t bother us because we don’t take it personally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252747907.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>We're specifically talking about **problomatic stereotypes**, not some period drama stereotyping about the 18th century, no one in their right mind gives a hoot about that.

How many times, honestly, have you seen "We're Irish", "I'm Irish" or whatever, being used to justify bad behaviour?

There's posts on reddit using "irish" as derrisive:

Irish Exit: [https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/10yc8sr/aita\_for\_doing\_an\_irish\_exit\_at\_a\_restaurant\_so\_i/](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/10yc8sr/aita_for_doing_an_irish_exit_at_a_restaurant_so_i/)

If they knew anything about Irish people, is that they take FOREVER to say goodbye. Not only is it mildly offensive, it's actually incorrect.

Irish car bombs, Irish Temper. [https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/hg9fkf/aita\_for\_telling\_an\_irishamerican\_to\_stay\_in\_her/](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/hg9fkf/aita_for_telling_an_irishamerican_to_stay_in_her/) 

Irish Twins [https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/17h6mrq/aita\_for\_refusing\_to\_resign\_a\_lease\_weeks\_before/](https://www.reddit.com/r/AmItheAsshole/comments/17h6mrq/aita_for_refusing_to_resign_a_lease_weeks_before/) 

You get the idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44253446188.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>And I can give you just as many posts about “fat, stupid, ugly Americans.” Name calling doesn’t bother us as much as it seems to bother you. But that’s not what this whole post is about. The OP wrote about claiming ancestry. I gave an answer. Yet again, it’s an issue that some people seem to take personally because they have no frame of reference for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44253707089.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>You're missing the point.

No one calls being rude an "american" whatever, here. If you're rude with your goodbyes, it's not "an American goodbye". Calling people names is one aspect of sterotyping, it is not the entire thing.

*Using someones identity* is entirely different. Do you seriously not understand the difference here?

I think you're just being willfully ignorant of it now, frankly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44254269709.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>And it seems like you don’t understand that every nation , every culture has something that people of other nationalities use as a pejorative. Island time because people of a certain ethnicity “are always late.” Indian burn. Tiger mom. You sound like someone who thinks that there are only certain groups of people that get pejoratives attached to their culture and that can’t be further from the truth. No one is special in that regard because everyone gets it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44257073296.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>The fact best three examples you can think of are:

1. "Island time", which isn't specific to one nation and isn't a thing outside the USA

2. "Indian burn", which has nothing to do with the nation on India, 

3. "Tiger mom", which has nothing to do with a country and isn't a thing outside the USA 

Is *very* telling. Thanks, i guess, for proving my point. Amercia has a problem with using a certain group of nouns as a pejorative. 

Just because you're using everyone's nationality or something as an Insult doesn't make it OK. 

Rule of thumb for you, if you wouldn't replace that word with "black" for risk of being racist, then you probably shouldn't say it in its original form.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258255312.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>Please show me one place where I said that these pejoratives were acceptable under any circumstance. 

“Indian burn” is not about India. 

It’s funny that the same people who get upset about terms like “Irish exit” are the same ones who also tell Irish Americans that they aren’t really Irish. Because over here, those Irish Americans are the ones who do speak out against those terms. Thus why the whole premise of this entire thread is nonsense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258273378.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Please show me one place where I said that these pejoratives were acceptable under any circumstance.

I think you need to read my comment again. I didn't say you said they were acceptable.

This is the point you're missing:

&gt;Amercia has a problem with using a certain group of nouns as a pejorative.  
  
Just because you're using everyone's nationality or something as an Insult doesn't make it OK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258305146.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>You’re literally saying that we are condoning the use of nationalities as pejoratives. We’re not. As I said from the beginning, those are assholes being assholes. Because I am measuring that against the premise of this thread, which is that OP does not agree with Americans who have ancestry outside of America calling themselves fill-in-nationality-of-choice. What you have an issue with is another issue entirely. Now, if you want to have a post that discusses how the examples I gave are not the same as Irish exit or Irish car bomb, I’m more than happy to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258635561.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You’re literally saying that we are condoning the use of nationalities as pejoratives.

Where? Exactly where have I said that?

I said you have a problem with it, not that you personally condone it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258710154.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>“Just because you’re using everyone’s nationality as an insult doesn’t make it ok” is very easily interpreted as someone condoning it. If you mean to say you Americans collectively, and permitting, it is perhaps better phrased as “Americans permit a lot of casual pejoratives against certain nationalities in their culture.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258746135.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>Y'know I apologise. I actually do take it back, condone is the right word.

condone, verb

* accept (behaviour that is considered morally wrong or offensive).

I think that's a reasonable description. It is, generally, accepted in American culture that you use (to borrow your phrase) casual pejoratives against certain nationalities in your culture.

I'm by no means claiming it's something that Brits or Europeans can claim moral superiority on. I'm sure we have our own that I'm blind to, but I think that's a reasonable observation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44259118246.0" user="Trouvette" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you, I appreciate that. 

Now, speaking to your point. I think the whole American melting pot thing is the major driver for casual pejoratives. To give an example from my own life: my grandmother was born in Ireland. My other set of grandparents were born in Puerto Rico. Growing up, they always sniped at each other. But my parents never shut it down unless what either side said was especially egregious. Because we don’t have that unified cultural identity the way you do in Europe, we thus don’t have a strong national consensus on what is ok, or what is toeing the line versus stuff that is an absolute no-go, which there is a consensus on. So I think among Americans, there is an unspoken tolerance of casual use that has developed over time. Otherwise, we would be in a perpetual cycle of outrage on our own behalf, and then turn around and use a casual pejorative against another group, who would then in turn be upset. It doesn’t make it right, but in absence of a national consensus, it’s the next best alternative.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
