<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246294871.0" user="daveshistory-ca" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is a bit like the situation Winston Churchill supposedly said (probably apocryphally) about liberal democracy -- that it's the worst system imaginable, except for all the others.

I will concede that it is hard to imagine an alternative to the civil justice system that would practically allow people to redress their many harms and injustices they suffer.

However, the system as it exists does not seem nearly so rosy as the picture you paint of it. In practice there is something deeply disturbing about the bedrock of how we relate to each other socially and economically ultimately being rooted in an institution that follows legal precedents so detailed and arcane that few of the people who need the system to work for them could possibly understand them, and which are only understood by a niche profession so costly that equally few people can afford to hire the specialists they require to effectively advance their interests within that system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246321278.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>That is a fantastic quote. I agree with it.

I do not think that the system is perfect - I do think that having a system at all is a great thing. I do not think that anyone in this comment section (or anyone in the world, really) can think up an alternative that is superior to the thoroughness of the current system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
