<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44245629967.0" user="ejunker" delta="False">
    <text>I feel that you didn’t give enough evidence to explain how it is problematic. Are you expecting Americans to feel sorry for your country for its problems? Why does it matter what Americans think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245738926.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Good point, sorry the post felt too long as is. The best example I can think of is the way Irish Americans engaged with the troubles. Now please do not get me wrong, not every American in support of Ireland were in support of the IRA. 

However there was a phenomenon at the time where Americans were donating thousands to the IRA, often glorifying the conflict. Will some of those people been recently immigrated Irish, that were genuinely affected by the conflict, yes. However there was a noticeable commodifaction of the issue in some American communities.

Look this is a very touchy complicated subject so I won't be able to explain it properly. But my example is essentially, there are consequences by aligning yourself with another nationality and speaking on their behalf with regards to their issues. 

Stiff little fingers (an Irish punk band during the troubles) say it better than me in their song "each dollar a bullet".

Also, to your point about why care about what Americans think. Well. Great question. You guys are fucking powerful. Very powerful. Sometimes I don't think Americans know to what extent your culture bleeds into ours. Its frustrating when a country so big, so powerful, co-opts part of our identity and ignores the ugly parts. Its not each Americans individual fault. But its frustrating. We're so small, I just wish we could represent our selves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245886048.0" user="ejunker" delta="False">
    <text>So, you think that if Americans just learned the "truth" about the troubles that they would have acted differently? I feel that is the same with any political issue. Each side thinks they are right and if the other side just saw the facts, they would change their mind.

I'm reminded of the "No true Scotsman" logical fallacy which seems like you may be using and stating things like if the Americans actually were true Irish then they would not have supported the IRA.

I can understand how it may be frustrating. I don't mean to sound elitest, but I would guess the average American rarely thinks about Ireland and Scotland anyway, and when they do it is in a positive manner. We love St. Patrick's Day and the most education we have about the troubles is from watching Derry Girls on Netflix.

In summary, I understand your frustration, but I don't think it is as big of a problem as you think it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245955508.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Oh god you have massively misunderstood what I've meant. I don't think it was on purpose, clearly just cultural crossed wires, which is fair enough. But no this isn't what I meant.

First, I don't think there is ever one truth. And with regards to the troubles, there's never going to be one right answer. What I meant is, the IRA was commodified by certain communities in America, often with a limited understanding of the very long, very complex and very tragic history that lead to the troubles. Please listen to that song I mentioned above, its a banger and very relevant.

Also I know you mean well and I know your trying to be polite. But you've exemplified my point really well. Our culture has been reduced and minimised to pop culture references and stripped of its context. It may not be a big deal to you, but have you seen how Americans act when they feel their nation has been misrepresented. My culture matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246085244.0" user="ejunker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What I meant is, the IRA was commodified by certain communities in America, often with a limited understanding of the very long, very complex and very tragic history that lead to the troubles.

So, if I understand you correctly, your main concern is that Americans are making judgements and decisions without having a deep understanding of the history. That is undoubtedly true, but are you more concerned by the method by which they make their judgements or their actual judgements? For example, if you think they make the "right" decision does it matter or not if they came to that conclusion by having a true understanding?

And like it not I think most people's knowledge about a country's culture comes from pop culture. Hey, at least Derry Girls exposed many Americans to the troubles otherwise many would not even know about it. I would assume most European's knowledge of America is from pop culture. I don't think that is necessarily bad as long as they know it is a stereotype.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246173174.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Aye I think we're getting closer to understanding each other. 

To answer your question, its neither. For me it's the context that bothers me. It's not about cherry picking what parts i like or don't like depending on if I think they've picked the "right" decision. It's dangerous to get into that habit of only listening to the people who agree with you and ignoring those that don't, so it's not about that for me.

I genuinely belive the average American does not see the sheer influence and weight that America holds across the globe. American culture has seeped into every country across the globe and shaped and changed the cultural landscapes of many nations. Its a uniquely American phenomenon. And I think with being the most powerful nation in the world leads to an obvious power imbalance. Americans just don't need to learn about other nations the way we need to learn about yours. 

Aye, America is in a lot of pop culture references. Yous make great entertainment. But your politics, your election, your cultural climate: we know about it. We watch your elections. We listen to what you say on Ukraine Russia Palestine wtc. 

Your country is unique in this way. You get to be more ignorant to the rest of the world. We don't have that choice in terms of America. 

I get the point your making about stereotypes. But thats the thing, they don't affect the people that have them. Just the people it's about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246296280.0" user="ejunker" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Americans just don't need to learn about other nations the way we need to learn about yours.

But do you really learn about our nation in the deep understanding way you expect us to understand your culture or is it just a surface level understanding? I recently learned that British students do not learn about the American Revolution in history class. It makes sense that Americans learn about it since it is our history, but I can understand why it is not taught to British students.

If I want to be a good American, what expectations do you have of me? Are you expecting me to spend time learning about the history of all the other countries? While that sounds interesting, nobody has time to do that. I would suggest that perhaps pop culture is the best tool for a country like Ireland to educate Americans about their culture and history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246338230.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>We actually get taught about your political system at school. We learn all about the checks and balances.

I don't really have any expectations beyond, be open to seeing the world through a different lense. Different communities across the globe are going to have different interpretations of the way you engage with our culture. 

Nobody can get it right all the time. God knows I've pissed off a lot of Americans tonight. But just be open. And be open to the idea that your american news isnt giving you a global picture. I wouldn't say learn the words history. Literally impossible. But maybe every now and then check in on the news around the world and see if you hear anything you might not have before. 

I can tell your already trying, by having a polite conversation with a stranger who disagrees with you. Your already more open minded than most people online.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246313545.0" user="AngryBandanaDee" delta="False">
    <text>So do you not have any political opinions outside of Scotland? Are you against European support for Ukraine? As it stands the vast majority of Europeans don't have any recent ancestors from Ukraine or Russia. So how could you possibly have a full understanding of the long and complex history between them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246399159.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of my local community is made up of Eastern Europeans. This war is affecting people I know and love. 

Regardless, its a strawman fallacy. Stating that I find some American interpretations of my culture reductive and dated, does not equate to having an opinion on a war in Europe. But I'll indulge.

The Ukrainian Russia war is reshaping global politics. Since the cold War European and altantic relationships have relied on Mutually Assured Distruction (MAD). This war is rapidly changing the way the international stage understands and operates within MAD. As the UK is a NATO member, and as Putin becomes more unstable and threatened by Nato, the likelihood of a nato vs Russia war becomes more and more normalised by the day. 

The UK and the USA house nukes in Scotland. Just up the road from me actually. If this war goes tits up, I could quite easily become a victim of nuclear war fair. My home is literally up the road from one of Russias main nato nuclear targets.

I by no means understand the thousand year history between Russia ans Ukraine. I don't need to. I just need to know what I can do to keep my Eastern European neighbours assured of our support. 

Literally not the same at all as saying Americans can be a bit rude to other cultures with the way some of you ( not all ) reduce us to stereotypes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246530448.0" user="AngryBandanaDee" delta="False">
    <text>You were just saying the reason it was problematic was because American got involved in supporting the Irish in the troubles. The people who did so would tell you a variation of what you just did. Oh their community is made up of Irish and it is affecting people they know and love and how this conflict is reshaping global politics in important ways for XYZ reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246567286.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that's not what I've said. At all. I've said that there is, within celtic communities, an understanding that Americans have influenced the troubles through their own ignorance. I have also, already said that this isn't to say ALL Americans or even ALL Irish Americans. But when you couple cultural ignorance with the massive cultural influence America has, you end up with people uneducated and unaffected in a conflict, massively influencing a delicate and tumultuous conflict.

Enough with the straw man fallacies. If you can't engage with what I'm actually saying and not what you assume I mean from words that I haven't written then I'm going to disengage. This isn't a conversation or a debate, it's you picking a side to argue from and refuse to engage with the facts of what I'm saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44248866208.0" user="Enderules3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm also not sure I'm completely grasping the difference between the troubles and the Ukraine-Russia Conflict. Are you saying that the key difference is that you are more educated on the issue and therefore able to make a more informed decision?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252220753.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245753484.0" user="On_The_Blindside" delta="False">
    <text>I think they're expecting Americans to stop playing up to negative stereotypes of their claimed heritage.

"I'm Irish so I drink a lot". For example.

Or worse, that god forsaken drink the "Irish car bomb". Ask for one of them in Belfast and expect some firm pushback, shall we say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246022035.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Aye this is exactly it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
