<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44249582248.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>Kurdistan doesn't exist as a country today.  Do Kurds exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249608569.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Of course Kurds exist. But I wouldn't go asking me for that validation, I have no connection to the Kurdish community and therefore don't feel qualified to determine the validity of anyone's Kurdish identity. Also I don't really see how this comment is relevant to anything I've said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249645865.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>There are multiple Scottish communities, with different membership rules.  Some have membership merely by residency/citizenship, while others are membership by blood.  Why is the Scottish community in Dallas any less Scottish than the Scottish community in Glasgow?  Why do you feel like you (living in Scotland) have any ability to say what the rules are for American Scottish communities?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44250663124.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>I'm definitely not saying I am less or more Scottish than communities i havent met. I don't think I've made that clear enough, which is on me. My point is when people use their heritage to entitle them to make sweeping statements about Scottish culture and endorse stereotypes that harm native Scottish people in the long run.

I think there is a difference between taking part in and contributing to a culture, for example in Dallas or in Glasgow, and equating your heritage to an entitlement to make a false representation of Scottish culture. 

I'm really not a fan of a national identity through blood type of thinking. I have friends from across Europe, or from England that have settled in Scotland that I would say are Scottish. They love that this is their home, they contribute to the culture and community and they feel an ideological alignment to our countries ideals. By blood are they Scottish? No. Are they Scottish? aye.

Glasgow has a big refugee community and there is a movement around how co-opting a Glaswegian identity can help people settle in their new community. I think this website  [refuweegee ](https://www.refuweegee.co.uk/) is a perfect example of how non native nationals can develop a Scottish identity.

For me this has never been about who qualifies as actually Scottish. Just who is qualified to make generalised statements about a culture and how Americans can tetter on the edge of disrespectful because a misinterpreted idea that they are apart of that culture, and not an Americanised version of that community. Again not every American does this. But it'd be great if every American could be aware of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44250792460.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;My point is when people use their heritage to entitle them to make sweeping statements about Scottish culture and endorse stereotypes that harm native Scottish people in the long run.

But here you are saying they can't make statements about Scottish culture when they are talking about *their own* Scottish culture.  

&gt; Just who is qualified to make generalised statements about a culture and how Americans can tetter on the edge of disrespectful because a misinterpreted idea that they are apart of that culture, and not an Americanised version of that community

But they are a part of Scottish culture.  They just aren't a part of your specific branch of Scottish culture.  I guess I just don't understand why you are privileging your version over the Dallas version and considering yours more real with words like "native".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44250938333.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think I am entitled to spread and engage in damaging stereotypes and stigmas of American culture? 

Why is my lived experience of my own countries culture not allowed to be viewed as its own thing. Why does it have to equate to an Americanised version. 

American Scottish culture is valid. Is a real thing. Its a unique experience. I can't really comment on it, its not my own.

I'm not saying mine is more real. I'm saying its a specific thing. Being a variation of Scottish does not entitle you to make disparaging comments on my culture. 

What American Scottish people experience as their culture just does not entitle them to make sweeping statements or perpetrate stereotypes of my country. Can you give me a reason why this isn't true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251043527.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do you think I am entitled to spread and engage in damaging stereotypes and stigmas of American culture?

Yes.  Everyone is entitled to do this due to our cultural hegemony.  If you don't live on North Sentinel Island you have adopted some American culture and anyone in a free country like the UK is surrounded more by American culture than local culture.  To forbid you to stereotype Americans would be grossly unfair. 

&gt;Why is my lived experience of my own countries culture not allowed to be viewed as its own thing. Why does it have to equate to an Americanised version.

It *is* allowed to be its own thing (even though of course it's been heavily Americanized.)  It's just that you seem to be just saying "Scottish" to mean only the Scotland-Scottish version and reserving hyphenation only for US versions.  The Dallas version is just as entitled to be called plainly "Scottish" as yours, unhyphenated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251126521.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>You want me to call myself Scotland Scottish? God how unbelievably entitled are you? More American determinism I guess. Your Americanism does not entitle you to make these statements. Being American Scottish and being Scottish are two different things. It's literally just a fact. That's why I think there is importance to separate them. Let each community represent itself. It's literally just showing basic respect to cultures that aren't your own. I wish it wasn't this hard to ask for something so common.

Also Scottish culture hasn't been Americanised. That's just not true. This literally proves my entire point. The American arrogance of making just plain false statements about a culture you clearly do not understand. Ideologically Scotland is in many ways in opposition to American ideals. We are a western culture, so their are similarities. But we not Americanised. 

"Surrounded by more American culture than local culture" fuckin hell. What a complete load of pish. 

Also your making arguments that spreading stigma and stereotypes are okay? I think we are just two people with opposing values and perspectives. I acknowledge your opinion but I vehemently disagree with it. Mostly on the basis that it seems founded in sheer arrogance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251273883.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You want me to call myself Scotland Scottish? 

See!!!  That's how Scottish people who happen to have been born in the US feel when people like you say they're "Scottish-Americans".  Being Scotland-Scottish and American-Scottish are two different things.  Yes, agreed, just a fact.  Separation is fine.  But why does *yours* get to be "just Scottish" and the other not get to be?  If you want to separate them, separate them equally!

&gt;Also Scottish culture hasn't been Americanised. That's just not true.

Ok, well don't do this on Reddit, but some time when you are calm or at a party with some friends, go ahead and name a hundred movies, just whatever movies you've heard of and spring to mind.  Maybe make it a game like you have to have the first letter start with the last one's last letter, whatever.  Just see how many of those hundred movies you've heard of were made in the US and how many were made in Scotland.  You can do the same with TV shows, bands, whatever.  I'm definitely not asking you to do it right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251321246.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Culture goes way beyond what you watch on TV. 

Culture is a shared history or cuisine. It's traditions or identity. It's a community experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251515304.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>I'd be careful of that one, it's the argument racists make to say certain immigrant ethnicities don't truly belong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251723556.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>That's why I put in, community experience. As in something that is specific or unique to a certain area. I was just trying to make clear to you that your idea that because we watch American films sometimes it doesn't mean our culture is Americanised.

Please see my prior comments where I clearly state that those within a community do not have to be from there. Ie the Glasgow refugee community [refuweegee ](https://www.refuweegee.co.uk/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251796884.0" user="LentilDrink" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I saw, that's why I pointed out the need to be careful of those arguments when they delegitimize something you care about.  The only approach that actually welcomes people of all ethnicities to the country is to dissociate ethnicity from citizenship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251813247.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>I'll agree with u there</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
