<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246259423.0" user="deep_sea2" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is not with the principles of the civil justice system, but rather the application of it. Like all elements of law, it suffers from access to justice issues and from the clogged up judicial system.

Access to justice is probably worse in civil action than in criminal action. In criminal action, the Crown/state has the ability to do whatever it needs to do without issue. It can afford several years of pre-trial along with months trial. So, there is no access to justice with regards to the complainant. For the defendant, they may have to pay for a lawyer, which is of course not good for them. However, the accused has constitutional protections. Public defenders, financial aid, and other methods allow those of lower income to get lawyer if they cannot afford one. If you are paying for you own lawyer, the constitution also prevents the legal process from extending too long. Since there is a time limit on criminal proceedings, there is a time limit on how long you will have to pay your lawyer.

In civil cases, it is not nearly as good. The plaintiff is not state funded. If you want to take action against someone, you have to do it yourself, either with self-rep or with a lawyer. As the defendant, there is no system to help you pay for a lawyer. You either have to self-rep or pay for a lawyer. Civil trials are often much more complex than criminal ones. In criminal trials, it is often a more simple case of proving if the accused did the act. Did the accused shoot the victim? Yes, then they are guilty of murder. There is some complexity, but not really. There might only be a few witnesses, a few exhibits, and that's all. The discovery is a often a single police investigation file, which if often organized and easy to go through. Some civil cases can be massive. First, the law can be more complicated. Negligence is a common tort action, and the law is negligence is not simple or intuitive. In some cases, the evidence is also extensive. There could be thousands of documents in discovery that you have to go over. That is a lot of billable hours. In short, many civil claims by their nature will require more time and more expertise, and this means more money. If either party is low on money, then they will suffer a serious disadvantage. Many cases are won or loss simply because one party runs out of money first. 

I remember this one case where a self-rep plaintiff was suing the government because a housing inspector condemned a building they owned. The government asked that the court issue a cost-bond on the plaintiff, and the court did so. They had to put up $10,000 to court just in case they lose the case and the defendant wanted costs. Unfortunately, for the plaintiffs, they could not put up that money in time. I don't remember if they got an extension or won their appeal to eliminate  that bond, but they could have lost a very winnable case simply because they could not afford that $10,000. Something like that would not happen in a criminal trial.

In short, civil trials are far more of a "pay to win" system than criminal trials. This makes it more likely that rich litigants will get richer, and poor ones will get poorer. Of course, not all civil cases are like that, especially not in small claim court where lawyers are not common. However, this is a problem for higher stakes civil cases. In higher state criminal cases, the more legal protection the state must provide the accused. In higher state civil cases, the richer party has the significant advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246354982.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, criminal proceedings are much much much much more complicated than you’ve implied here. It is not nearly as simple as “did he shoot the guy? Yes? He’s guilty of murder.” Proving a crime has requirements or elements - every requirement or element of every crime can be interpreted and argued in many many ways.

The burden of proof needed to win a civil trial is the balance of probabilities. What probably happened. Which side’s version has a higher likelihood of being true? That does not change from the small claims level upward.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246453926.0" user="deep_sea2" delta="False">
    <text>How do these points you bring up support your argument?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
