<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246294820.0" user="eggynack" delta="False">
    <text>You act like this system is relatively unlimited, responsive to the needs of the public, but it's really not. Just consider one of the prime examples of this, the Exxon Valdez oil spill. The oil spill did tons of damage, and was caused by outright flouting of safety rules. The original punitive damages awarded in the case were 5 billion dollars. The actual frigging supreme court forced the damages down to like 500 million, partially in the explicit name of making damages predictable, and clearly in the aim of making them low.

Notably, this system, where a company commits horrendous malfeasance and then gets punished by it in civil court, is effectively a replacement for a serious system of oversight. No one was forcing Exxon to abide by the laws and regulations that would have prevented this outcome. There were no audits, no government issued fines to my knowledge (and certainly they weren't substantial enough to stop them), no incentive to do anything but what they did. Just this system you love, suing someone in civil court.

All this to say, I think that one main function of the civil court structure, as it currently exists, is to limit our ability to deal with corporate malfeasance. This system tells us that there is a remedy for companies doing serious harm to this world and its people, that we can have our day in court, but, in practice, attempts to actually hold companies accountable are destroyed by the system itself. I would suggest we'd be better off if we just had a well enforced regulatory structure in which doing deeply unsafe and damaging nonsense is fined by the state, and that we thus prevent the horrible outcomes of that nonsense from occurring.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
