<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44245963466.0" user="Any-Pea712" delta="False">
    <text>Why repost?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245986053.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>My post was too long for the other subs rules</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
