<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44254599650.0" user="Mashaka" delta="False">
    <text>Your post has been removed for breaking Rule E: 

&gt; **Only post if you are willing to have a conversation with those who reply to you, and are available to start doing so within 3 hours of posting**. If you haven't replied within this time, your post will be removed. [See the wiki for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_e).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%20E%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
