<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44252190191.0" user="gregbrahe" delta="False">
    <text>How far of a separation do you need? I identify wry my Scottish heritage because my mom's parents age extended family immigrated to the States less than a decade before my mom was born. Her eldest sister was born there as was another sister who died as an infant and is buried there.

My Great-grandmother had an incredibly thick brogue, making her difficult even for Scots to understand sometimes, and my grandmother and her sisters brought a ton of Scottish traditions and customs to our family.

I didn't visit Scotland until after my Great-grandmother and grandmother had passed away, and I haven't yet been to Glasgow or Ayr, where they lived.

I have family that all lives in Scotland who I am in contact with regularly.

I also have English and Danish ancestry, but that is further separated from me by time. The English was my grandpa, but we didn't really have any interaction with his extended family. I do still have family in England and in fact I even have a nephew who lives there.

So, where should the live be drawn?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252358084.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>It's really not for me to say. It seems like your Scottish heritage is important to you, like a connection to loved ones past and far away? That's a valuable thing. I don't really feel entitled to say whether you are or aren't Scottish. Is your American identity important to you? Do you value your American culture? Would Scottish American feel like a fair description of who you are? 

My point is you have no right to make generalised statements about my culture, just because a distint relative in your lineage hails from here. My point is not to say who is or isn't entitled to their identity.

Just that ours are intrinsically different, and we should respect our differences while embracing our commonalities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252426450.0" user="gregbrahe" delta="False">
    <text>Distant relative isn't a very good description of the woman who consistently babysat me and was a huge part of my life until she died when I was 18.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252458379.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not demeaning your relative. I was trying to make a distinction between a family member you actually know and someone who died generations ago. Because clearly there is a difference</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252466290.0" user="gregbrahe" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the clarification</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252474405.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Do you want to engage with anything I've said above?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252612169.0" user="gregbrahe" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that most of what you wrote is controversial in most circumstances, but there is an important exception to this in the tendency of large Metropolitan areas in the states to have entire sectors or Burroughs that are HEAVILY dominated by immigrants from a particular area where the culture from their homeland is still very much practiced. I don't know if you have traveled to places like New York or San Francisco and seen their China Town or K Town areas, but even in places like Houston Texas there is a Chinatown area where even the street signs are in a Chinese dialect.

This is part of what the 'tossed salad' description of the US refers to. The nation is young and does not really have a singular "culture" of its own to speak of, though there may be some threads that are cookbook to most. I'm in the Midwest where we tend to be friendly to strangers, make eye contact and small talk with random people at the grocery store, and be wierdly passive aggressive about confrontation, but few of us see this as an *identity*. A large portion of our population alive today knew the ancestors who immigrated here and have heard the stories of that journey growing up. A large number of traditions from a variety of potatoes kind of mix together here, so you might see a polka dance with Bratwurst at an even that also has Italian cannolis and tamales.

Almost none of my friends growing up shared the same mix of cultural heritage. As a result, that heritage is something that helps us correct to our family while also sharing something unique about ourselves to our friends.

Do people get carried away? You bet. I've known b people who have strongly identified with some culture that they only *believed* to be part of their ancestry only to learn that the story got mixed up somewhere along the way and it was really just that their line of ancestors made friends with and were assimilated into a local group of immigrants and adopted aspects of their culture as a result.

I would argue that most people who do take things too far do so in earnest, and that it is not a super common thing (or at least it wasn't until being a associate media influencer started becoming the goal of so many young people looking to find some unique niche to fill) for people to knowingly exploit something like this through stereotype and appropriation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
