<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44245513135.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>Curious if you say the same thing applies to Korean Americans? Mexican Americans? Or African Americans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245597953.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Personally (as someone who has never been to the US, lol) I would say no. I mean more specifically the "old world" type countries.

With respect to Korean immigration to America, its much more recent than say Irish or Scottish. Plus I'd say that from what Ive seen online (basic af, I know) and from my experience of Asian communities in my own country, they tend to be more insular and self sufficient. Whereas for example, Italian Americans have relied on American culture just as much as Italian culture within their communities.

With regards to Mexican Americans, I think purely due to the geographical fact that yous are neighbours, there is more of a continous exchange of culture. Also I could be wrong but is Mexican Immigrants not the biggest immigrant community in the US? I think in this context its more of a mutual exchange. Mexico and the US have a unique international relationship, I don't think this compares to Scotland or Italy in the same way.

Also "African American" has a LOT more context and history to it as an identity than I'd say of any the ones I've mentioned. It's also a racial identity which makes it more personal to each person and not specific to one particular African nation. But I do think this identity is fundamentally more complex than any European/ American identity could be.

So to end my ramble, I guess I mean a more European context. Since the original immigrants were hailing from this part of the world, and thus more disconnected to the current experience of what it means to be from that part of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245620096.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so you’re saying you need to change your view so it specially and ONLY apply to Americans of European descent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245635899.0" user="4amLasers" delta="False">
    <text>Also, does this only apply to people who are past the third generation? If someone's parents immigrated from one of the countries you mention, or their grandparents, is that different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245661587.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Mmm not quite. I'm just saying I have no business being offended on behalf of other cultures. As a European, I feel that we have a unique experience of this phenomenon, purely due to how long ago so much of our people left for America. 

Sorry if I'm not explaining it well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245698387.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Sorry if I'm not explaining it well.

You certainly are not. You make no distinction for the exceptions I pointed out, valid ones imo, and admit that your logic does not apply to all Americans.

By your own admission, your view as expressed is wrong.

I am willing to listen to you explain why your view is not wrong, and has not changed, so please expand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245741795.0" user="atxarchitect91" delta="False">
    <text>Dude wtf. You’re a hypocrite and a bigot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245776774.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry can you explain how I'm a bigot? Was it not European WASPs that are credited with the late 1700s and early 1800s with creating the melting pot by mass immigration?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251182634.0" user="atxarchitect91" delta="False">
    <text>What’s wrong with people claiming heritage when they are European descended. Do you honestly believe people lose their entire culture on a boat ride. And you’re a bigot and hypocritical because you only apply it to white Americans and obviously don’t to any other race. You just hate Americans irrationally because you’re a bigot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251236784.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying you lose your heritage after you get off the boat. Literally nothing I've said anywhere supports that. 

I'm not being a bigot. I'm just making the point that I can't apply this to other cultures because other cultures are not my own. I refuse to make judgements or sweeping statements on behalf of other cultures. I'm European, I'm comfortable commenting on that, and that's as far as I'm willing to take it. Context my dude, Context is key.

I'm also not saying that Americans aren't entitled to an American Scottish identity. They obviously are.

My point has been and still is:

Because your ancestors came from my country, it does not entitle you to perpetrate and encourage disparaging perceptions of my culture. It does not entitle you to further dated stigmas.  Eg, you don't get to make jokes about Scots being drunks because in some form you view yourself as a variation of Scottish. If you want to say, for whatever reason, American Scottish people are drunks, well that's not my place to say. 

Now you know what my point is, what part do you agree/ disagree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44265273073.0" user="atxarchitect91" delta="False">
    <text>Look when an American says they are Scottish it means like 50% of their family that recently immigrated 100 years ago still prides themselves in it. They do not actually mean they are Scottish. Scottish culture has obviously progress past the small land owning farmers that paid for the voyage over the Atlantic. It was mostly second sons and merchant classes plus refugees from the scots-Irish population during the famine. 

Nobody actually means they are Scottish beyond insanely lonely folks who just want to feel they belong somewhere.

We are all mutts of different cultures across east to west Europe and more. Don’t be too harsh on them. They only want to feel they belong somewhere as we don’t have a ancestral heritage.

Some Americans get overly excited with their heritage. Let them have their fun. They are harmless and it means a lot to them. Correct them with kindness and they will be excited to learn about the modern culture and the differences.

That’s all I really mean</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44265569171.0" user="atxarchitect91" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with we are my Scottish. 1/8 my family were scots who settled in Ireland and moved to the US. I don’t claim Scottish heritage but I’m also a mutt of serval different cultures and look nothing like any of them. 

I’m still proud of my Scottish ancestors and respect their stories and culture. But I’m such a mix I can’t claim any culture besides American. At best I’m 50% German Lutheran New Yorkers but they gave up their identity after the wars outside of Lutheran and I honestly never really knew any of them. But I carry it in my name and I feel pride in all the cultures and family that have been in my family. 

The Americans who claim to be actually Irish or Scottish are weird and not normal. They have issues at home</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245810841.0" user="RedditExplorer89" delta="False">
    <text>u/atxarchitect91 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal%20atxarchitect91&amp;message=atxarchitect91%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20\[their%20comment\]\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/-/kbqrsv7/\)%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245773187.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>You’re not. Because based off what I’ve read from you. You’re saying it’s not okay if it’s Scottish being claimed but otherwise you don’t care because it’s not your culture and it’s even somewhat okay with other countries. Either it’s a problem across the board or it’s not a problem. Which in all honest it’s not a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245808686.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>No I'm just trying to acknowledge that there are historically, different waves of immigration to America. 

Europeans leaving on old ships in the 1800s have a different experience and context than say, Mexican Immigrants, who have a much closer, in both time and geography, relationship to America now.

I'm a massive believer that context is important. I'm not saying it is or isn't the same for other cultures, I'm just saying that I don't feel particularly comfortable deciding for them. I'd be a hypocrit for saying that I don't like Americans speaking on my behalf and then speak on behalf of other cultures.

I'm just trying to acknowledge that the situation will vary regarding the context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245960184.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not like Latin or Asian immigrants to America is a new thing. Not even close. Look at the history of the west coast and immigration and there’s a lot of Asians. It’s not like there was only Europeans coming, then only Asians and then only Latin. Sure you can point to large waves from a certain place at a specific time but those windows of time are usually less than a decade. Other than those specific times, such as the potato famine in Ireland, it’s been people of all colors and creeds coming here. Which even during those times it’s not like immigration from other countries stopped, at the time all those Irish people were coming here, droves of Chinese people immigrated to the west coast.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245980360.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Aye I agree with you. I'm just saying I have no cultural connection to these other communities. So I have no right to comment on if people in other parts of the world might feel the same as me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246025038.0" user="colt707" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I understand that but where I think the disconnect here is, you can’t even speak for your entire culture. I’m sure there’s Scottish people that don’t care and I’m sure there’s some that even enjoy or appreciate it. Now in this situation which of the 3 Scots is the true Scotsman? Because I’d say all of them. You can be annoyed by it same as the next person can enjoy it and then both of you go about your day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246052014.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it's not that serious. I'm not walking around shouting fuck America. Its just a phenomenon that you come across online, especially on such a massively American social media. 

And no I don't speak for my entire culture. We are a fickle people.

But I don't think anyone ever has that right, to speak for a whole nation. That's why I posted. I wanted views that weren't my own. 

I just think its weird that so many Americans can think its our job to be fine with being annoyed by the way yous discuss our culture. When I think its fair to say a lot of Americans wouldn't be fine with other nationalities talking about your culture in a way yous may find disrespectful. American determinism no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245970401.0" user="gogonzo" delta="False">
    <text>You have no idea what you are talking about https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tejanos</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246011157.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Honey, I don't think you know what I'm talking about. I'm talking about my culture. A lot of my people left, either due poverty, famine or Highland clearances, for America. It was these massive waves of celtic and European setlers that created a specific immigrant communities across the states. I am not going to comment or pass judgement on other countries histories or expiernces of mass migration. Its not my right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44257866029.0" user="ChipmunkNamMoi" delta="False">
    <text>Mexican Americans started immigrating to America centuries ago. Japanese and Chinese Americans have immigrated far longer than Italian Americans. So then why is it ok for Chinese Americans who lived in America since 1880 to still say they are Chinese, but not Italian Americans who have lived in America since 1920?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44258010629.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Because I'm not Asian, I'm European. I'm not going to comment on behalf of a community I have no part in. 

Also that's true. There are immigrant communities that are just as old as some of the old European ones, but Mexican immigration has been a much more continuous exchange, compared to the massive waves from Europe centuries ago that eventually teetered off to a steady flow like it has today. 

I was just trying to show a balanced view of why I feel other communities may think differently. I just don't feel right making assumptions for a community I'm not a part of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44262729127.0" user="ChipmunkNamMoi" delta="False">
    <text>You're Scottish, you don't represent all of Europe. Scottish immigrants had a significantly different experience as Irish, Italian, or Polish immigrants. 

Many of the latter immigrants still live in ethnic enclaves in city neighborhoods. I grew up in a neighborhood like that as a Millennial. I have an "ethnic" name. When I was born, a relative told my mom that she once had the same name as me, but had to change it because of the prejudice against our ethnicity. That's someone from my lifetime, not too long ago. So the histories of different European American ethnic groups is a lot more complicated, and frankly I don't know why you get to speak of it when you don't have knowledge of it. I don't see how its any different than Mexican Americans or Chinese Americans. We all have different complicated histories in America that our unique to our ethnicity and immigration history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246112941.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, since you’re not expanding, probably because you can’t, imma make one point which proves your entire premise wrong.

&gt;but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. 

For an American to become an Italian citizen, all you need to do is prove your great grandparents were Italian citizens and that they did not renounce citizenship. 

The official policy of the state, Italian Citizenship by Decent, is that you are an Italian citizen if you had Italian great grandparents. You don’t need to travel there, live there or speak the language. You are welcome there and get every benefit of Italian citizenship. Doesn’t matter if you’re raised in a 1st, 2nd, or 3rd generation household. You can be adopted. You can be raised without a shred of heritage or connection to Italy and still the official position of the entire state is that you are a part of their culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246195865.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting, weird that a country that struggles so much with fascism has such an open citizenship policy. The more you know eh? 

Also I have expanded. In several other comments. Please don't be so rude, I've genuinely tried to be open minded. I just think that Americans can be a bit short sighted towards other cultures depending on how they carry themselves sometimes. I'm sure you can agree that I'm not exactly making that up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246231365.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re being willfully ignorant or intentionally obtuse.

You said Americans are X. I proved that wrong, so you walked that back and said it’s actually only European Americans. I proved that wrong too and you’re still being obstinate.

It’s not being rude when you’re having a discussion with someone and they keep moving the goalposts and pretending that they’re still right. It’s called frustration and I have every right to be feeling that. You have a right to feel the way you do, and I have never questioned that right.

A little self awareness may be necessary atm. Pot kettle black and all that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246881209.0" user="wanderinggoat" delta="False">
    <text>or maybe they dont think you proved them wrong.
Instead of trying to insult somebody maybe try to understand them and ask them to clarify in a friendly manner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246911562.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>I’m sorry where was I rude</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44247260419.0" user="wanderinggoat" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I think you’re being willfully ignorant or intentionally obtuse.

Rather than trying to understand what they mean or why you accuse them of something, how is that going to help a discussion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44247407828.0" user="DeltaBlues82" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that was true. I certainly could have said worse.

She’s just mad I beat her on a technicality and doesn’t want to admit it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44275946645.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>No I stopped engaging because your rude. Also, no,  one country in Europe having lax citizenship rules does not mean that Amricans get to act entitled to spreadin misinformation about a culture they've never experienced. 

Can u give me one reason as to why italian immigration laws have anything to do with what ive said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252210132.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245602521.0" user="lilgergi" delta="False">
    <text>Probably yes. If they match the same criterion, why wouldn't they?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245746137.0" user="Lazzen" delta="False">
    <text>Mexican-Americans are similar thing, for example many take being Mexican as an "ethnic/race/DNA" thing and try to retroactively add US understanding of themselves towards Mexico itself</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
