<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246045218.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes.

It's pretty obvious this is a bad thing.  What you're actually saying is that you have the power to force your mother to defend herself in front of a judge because you have access to a website and were feeling squirrelly.  You can steal her time and resources because...jackassery.

&gt;Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

And for you, that's great - because you're paid to know those things.  For everyone else...well, they have to pay someone like you.  Not because you're especially talented or intelligent or skilled (no offense, not saying you're not those things), but because you occupy a niche no one else has any reason to occupy.  Lawyers have long been likened to parasites for that reason.

&gt;This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a right, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”.

We've had this, to one degree or another, since we were living in tribes where warlords or elders would hear disputes and render judgment based on whatever passed for wisdom.  The civil justice system isn't new in that respect.

We can say that it's more professionalized than it's ever been, perhaps more dedicated to consistency than it's been in the past and is more egalitarian than it's been for most of our history...but it's just a basic function of the state.  It has substantial downsides and costs, and it leaves a lot to be desired.  It's no more or less a triumph of humanity than tax collection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246108082.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It's pretty obvious this is a bad thing.  What you're actually saying is that you have the power to force your mother to defend herself in front of a judge because you have access to a website and were feeling squirrelly.  You can steal her time and resources because...jackassery.

It’s not a bad thing. It’s a good thing. If I truly believe that I have been wronged and the way that I have been wronged should be compensable, I have an avenue to try to get justice. There is also a massive procedural gap between filing a lawsuit and appearing in front of a judge - let alone for a trial. If my claim had no merit, was frivolous, did not disclose a reasonable cause of action, or no evidence, it would have been weeded out by the system before the idea of even having a trial

&gt; And for you, that's great - because you're paid to know those things.  For everyone else...well, they have to pay someone like you.  Not because you're especially talented or intelligent or skilled (no offense, not saying you're not those things), but because you occupy a niche no one else has any reason to occupy.  Lawyers have long been likened to parasites for that reason.

I have no idea how the last sentence of your paragraph here relates to any of the previous sentences lol. I don’t know how possessing niche knowledge makes you a parasite. A parasite implies something that only takes (to the detriment of the host) and provides no value. Lawyers have the potential to provide incredible value to the people who pay them.

&gt; We've had this, to one degree or another, since we were living in tribes where warlords or elders would hear disputes and render judgment based on whatever passed for wisdom.  The civil justice system isn't new in that respect.

I did not say that the civil justice was new. I said that it is a triumph of humanity which I still believe that it is. The fact that it has been around, in some form or another, across all of human history is a good thing. Today, it is as consistent, thorough, and equitable as it has ever been</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246197589.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; It’s not a bad thing. It’s a good thing. 

No it isn't.  You very literally gave an example of your ability to waste your mother's time and resources (not to mention public employees and resources) for reasons that are demonstrable horseshit.  That's obviously a bad thing.  You may think it's a worthwhile tradeoff given what's gained, but it's definitely a bad thing.

&gt;If I truly believe that I have been wronged and the way that I have been wronged should be compensable, I have an avenue to try to get justice.

Which you also have if you *don't* truly believe but want to pretend you do, or if you do truly believe but are batshit.

&gt;I have no idea how the last sentence of your paragraph here relates to any of the previous sentences lol.

...really?  You're a lawyer and you've never heard this?  Okay, I'll spell it out.

The idea is that lawyers - especially lawyers specializing in civil litigation - promote questionably necessary legal resolutions to various problems that may or may not exist.  They then charge exorbitant fees to do something that's very often not that complicated simply because the average person has neither the time nor the energy to know the intricacies of the law.

Hence the "bloodsucking lawyer" trope.

&gt;I said that it is a triumph of humanity which I still believe that it is.

My point is that it's not "triumphant."  It's like...the most basic function of a state.  The alternative is just straight-up murdering each other over basic disputes, so it's one of the first and simplest things any government does.

And our system lets you sue your mom because you have an internet connection, which is not great.  It can very easily be used frivolously or dishonestly, and it's increasingly displacing informal conflict resolution as it expands, which is a bad thing.

I'm not saying it's bad.  It's just...meh.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246261616.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; No it isn't.  You very literally gave an example of your ability to waste your mother's time and resources (not to mention public employees and resources) for reasons that are demonstrable horseshit.  That's obviously a bad thing.  You may think it's a worthwhile tradeoff given what's gained, but it's definitely a bad thing.

I think we’re missing each other here. Obviously that specific example is one of a frivolous, baseless, and meritless lawsuit. Because the lawsuit is all of those things, it will be quickly thrown out - long before too many resources are wasted. The party who was unfairly affected by what is deemed to be a frivolous lawsuit will, in all likelihood, be made whole and compensated.

What I am saying is that a system that allows anyone a guaranteed a chance to plead my case and show evidence is, ultimately, a good thing. The claims that are proven to be frivolous are dealt with accordingly and are ultimately outweighed by the overall utility and fairness of the system.

&gt; Which you also have if you don't truly believe but want to pretend you do, or if you do truly believe but are batshit.

If you lie or bring a crazy/frivolous claim - you will likely be held accountable.

&gt; ...really?  You're a lawyer and you've never heard this?  Okay, I'll spell it out.

Of course I’ve heard of lawyer jokes. Obviously I know about the negative stereotypes surrounding lawyers. I just didn’t see how what you said about niche knowledge in any way related to why lawyers were called parasites. 

Also, for what it’s worth, any profession with specified knowledge - who uses that knowledge to provide a service that people are willing to pay for - have the potential to abuse that esoteric knowledge. 

&gt; My point is that it's not "triumphant."  It's like...the most basic function of a state.  The alternative is just straight-up murdering each other over basic disputes, so it's one of the first and simplest things any government does.

It being a function of the state (keeping everyone from murdering each other over feuds) has no bearing on whether it is a good system that is an overlap positive thing that we have done. 

I also think it’s a triumph because the mechanisms of the procedures themselves, the burden of proof/evidence, what is and isn’t allowed, and the discretion given to judges to “bend” the black letter of the law in the interest of fairness on a case by case basis make the system *incredibly* thorough and fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246312840.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Obviously that specific example is one of a frivolous, baseless, and meritless lawsuit. Because the lawsuit is all of those things, it will be quickly thrown out - long before too many resources are wasted.

Are we really going to pretend that no frivolous lawsuits not only make it to trial or adjudication, but are rewarding for the plaintiff?  Or that it's not a fairly common occurrence for parties to lawsuits to pay a settlement because it's cheaper than paying to win?

&gt;The party who was unfairly affected by what is deemed to be a frivolous lawsuit will, in all likelihood, be made whole and compensated.

I think the "in all likelihood" there is wishful thinking at best.

Do you think it's a coincidence that you have a rose-tinted view of the institution that provides your living?

&gt;I just didn’t see how what you said about niche knowledge in any way related to why lawyers were called parasites.

I suppose it's that there's lawyers on both sides enabling a process that otherwise wouldn't exist.

&gt;It being a function of the state (keeping everyone from murdering each other over feuds) has no bearing on whether it is a good system that is an overlap positive thing that we have done.

It being the most basic function of the state that it does *okay* is an argument that it's not a triumph.  It is *better than us murdering each other over minor disputes.*  That's not a ringing endorsement.

What would change your view?  Why did you post this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246422457.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Are we really going to pretend that no frivolous lawsuits not only make it to trial or adjudication, but are rewarding for the plaintiff?  Or that it's not a fairly common occurrence for parties to lawsuits to pay a settlement because it's cheaper than paying to win?

Firstly, “frivolous” is subjective. What is and isn’t “frivolous” is to be determined by a judge who has seen all of the evidence and heard all of the arguments. They are in the best position to determine what is and isn’t frivolous. So to answer your question: while I am positive that judges over time have made decisions that you or I might deem questionable, the system generally functions in a way where something that’s actually as crazy as what I described above would never ever make it to a trial.

&gt; I think the "in all likelihood" there is wishful thinking at best.

I don’t think it’s wishful thinking at best. I litigate for a living. I have literally never litigated a suit where one party did not have to pay some amount of the other party’s costs. Never once. Not even at the small claims level.

&gt; Do you think it's a coincidence that you have a rose-tinted view of the institution that provides your living?

I don’t think I have a rose-tinted view - I think I have a well-educated view and a deep understanding of how the system works. My opinion, which stems from a deep understanding of the systems, is that (in its current state) it is more fair than anything else that anyone has ever conceived.  

&gt; I suppose it's that there's lawyers on both sides enabling a process that otherwise wouldn't exist.

I don’t really follow where.

&gt; It being the most basic function of the state that it does okay is an argument that it's not a triumph.  It is better than us murdering each other over minor disputes.  That's not a ringing endorsement.

It wasn’t my argument - it was your argument. The system’s secondary effect of keeping us from being barbarians, which I acknowledge is a tool of the state, is not what I think is triumphant. Giving people a platform to prove their claims is the triumph.

&gt; What would change your view?  Why did you post this?

I already acknowledged a great point made below in other comment. I made the post for discussions and exchanges of ideas like the one we’re having now - which I happen to think was a good discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
