<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246789964.0" user="somehugefrigginguy" delta="False">
    <text>A civil justice system is a triumph of humanity, however from the posts you've made here, it sounds like you are really promoting the American civil justice system. The American system does have some merits, but is flawed on many levels.

The real problem is that the American civil justice system is entirely based on money, not actual justice. 

Take for example slapp suits. These aren't at all about justice, but are actually a form of injustice supported by our legal system allowing those with more resources to harass and financially decimate those who are less fortunate.

This is an area where most European law is Superior to American law. In the European system, the losing Party is required to pay the legal fees of the winning party. This cuts down on frivolous suits.

Another example of this is that civil suits are really only valid if you could show monetary damages. There are numerous cases where citizens have their rights infringed, but are unable to show true monetary damages, and therefore have no legal recourse.

One of the biggest injustices in the American civil system is federal rule of civil procedure number 68 part D. This rule is almost universally invoked in police misconduct cases forcing victims into a financial settlement while allowing corrupt government officials to avoid any admission of wrongdoing. It allows corrupt government officials to essentially erase the wrongdoings through a misuse of taxpayer funds. So not only is the individual plaintiff harmed, but the remaining citizens are also wronged by misuse of their tax money.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
