<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44245707355.0" user="LysenkoistReefer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America.

Ya, it can often feel like Europeans can be willfully obtuse by refusing to understand that when an American say they’re Scottish, or Irish, or German they’re not claiming citizenship they’re denoting their ancestry. 

&gt; I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it.

Nobody’s saying you have to like it. But if you’re going to willfully misinterpret them you’re gonna keep having a bad time. 

&gt; I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

I can speak to this a little more since I’m at least partly ~~Irish~~ of Irish descent. There are some unique factors that lead to the difference of opinion between the Irish and ~~the proud and exiled sons of Erin~~ Americans of Irish descent. Firstly, there are 34,000,000 Americans with some Irish ancestry, even more if you include Scotch-Irish, whereas the population of Ireland is only 5,000,000. In order to preserve a national identity that isn’t dictated entirely by Americans of Irish descent a level of gatekeeping is necessary for the Irish. But that gatekeeping isn’t reflected in America, where most Americans of Irish descent live, so we see basically problem calling ourselves Irish since most people understand that’s a comment on our ancestry not on our citizenship status. Secondly, and this is often overlooked, most Irish immigration to America occurred before Irish Independence. Irish Americans were heavily involved in the various Independence movements, but since they didn’t have to deal with the consequences of failed risings and sectarian conflict first had their collective view on Independence was necessarily as tempered as the Irish in Ireland. For example, the anti-treaty side of the civil war probably has far more admirers in the US than in Ireland. This difference in opinion tends to lead Irish people to view Americans of Irish descent as flippant or casual about the struggle for independence. 

&gt; However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland. 

Again, nobody’s saying you have to like it. But you should at least try to understand that it’s not coming from a bad place but rather from a genuine interest in that person’s ancestry. You might identify that person as in an out group to you, but they genuinely indenture you both, however distantly, as in the same in group. 

&gt; To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation.

No, the means of production is not owned exclusively by the workers in Scotland. What you likely mean to say is that Scots value social democratic policy and a strong social safety net more than Americans. 

&gt; What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh.

But if you can accept differences of opinion on what it means to Scottish between cities why can’t you accept differences of opinion of what it means to be Scottish between Scotland and the US? 

&gt; I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level.

You don’t say. 

&gt; I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Like I said, you don’t have to like it. But again you should try to understand where it’s coming from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44245909703.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like I spent quite a fair bit of my post trying to show a balanced view, and that I made a lot of points supporting and respecting immigrant identity within America. 

I think this comment is a perfect example of American determinism. The notion that when someone who is American says they are Irish, Scottish etc, that the onus is on the other culture to understand how America works, how your society understands nuanced identities and your cadence of speech.

We should just -get- that yous say one thing but you mean the other. Why? Why should I? Why can't you just say what you mean and then we can both make equal effort to understand each others perspectives. Why is it so often on the other side to first understand the American perspective? Ironic that you think we are willfully obtuse but you expect me to see this through an American lense.

I think American determinism is essentially what my main issue is. 

Also the difference between Scottish identity varying within Scotland or across America, is LIVED EXPIERENCE. Lived experience should trump ancestral love when it comes to issues relating to identity.

I love America, but sometimes you lot can be a bit tone def and self obsessed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246281883.0" user="LysenkoistReefer" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I think this comment is a perfect example of American determinism. The notion that when someone who is American says they are Irish, Scottish etc, that the onus is on the other culture to understand how America works, how your society understands nuanced identities and your cadence of speech.

I think this is a good example of the disconnect between the American perspective and the European, or really any community trying to interact with its diaspora community. Because I feel like I made clear three separate times that nobody was asking you to just accept the statement, but let you know how Americans typically mean what they’re saying when they say that they’re Irish, or Scottish, or German. It seems, a forgive me if I’m misreading you, that you’re taking what I said as some sort of order rather than some friendly advice. 

&gt; We should just -get- that yous say one thing but you mean the other. Why?

Like I said you don’t have to. You can take it in any way you like. But I’m giving you the typical American perspective. 

&gt; Why can't you just say what you mean and then we can both make equal effort to understand each others perspectives.

I’ve gone to a little bit of effort to distinguish Irish people and Americans of Irish descent in my comment because I wanted to make sure I was clear in the distinction, but I wouldn’t do that in the course of a normal conversation. There are some situations where specificity is called for, but in everyday conversation that specificity isn’t necessarily going to appear. 

&gt; Why is it so often on the other side to first understand the American perspective?

Because nobody’s making a post saying CMV: Europeans are willfully obtuse when it comes to discussions of ancestry. But if someone did make that CMV I think it would be acceptable and probably helpful even for you to give the European perspective. If you want to understand where other people are coming from it’s important to understand their perspective. Now you obviously don’t have to, but that’s not exactly going to help with communication or shared understanding. 

&gt; I think American determinism is essentially what my main issue is.

Ya, I think if Americans and Europeans a little more empathy and desire for understanding of each other’s perspectives this wouldn’t really be a problem. 

&gt; Also the difference between Scottish identity varying within Scotland or across America, is LIVED EXPIERENCE. Lived experience should trump ancestral love when it comes to issues relating to identity.

Nobody is saying that someone who’s granddad was from Glasgow is more Scottish or even as Scottish as someone who was born and raised in Glasgow, but that doesn’t mean that the former doesn’t identify their lives experience as even a little bit Scottish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44249123603.0" user="could_not_care_more" delta="False">
    <text>(I'm not OP, just meddling lol)

&gt;It seems, a forgive me if I’m misreading you, that you’re taking what I said as some sort of order rather than some friendly advice. 

I mean... you did start your comment with calling OP, and most Europeans, "willfully obtuse". That's not really a good way to set a friendly tone for the rest of your comment to be read in.

You also continually spoke as if the issue was OP not understanding that Americans speak of their ancestry not their nationality, even though you quoted this from the original post:

&gt;"However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland."

Which is where OP condenses the actual issue found throughout their post: that in their experience Americans use their ancestry as a way to perpetuate outdated or harmful or hurtful stereotypes of the actual people living in that country today, and spreading misinformation or painting the country or it's people poorly. Such as being primitive or making a light of actual issues or stereotypes they have faced or are still facing today.

For example: an Irish-American can joke about, say... being Irish and therefore drinking a lot, because the "Irish" is such a small part of their national identity that the stereotypes about the Irish people doesn't impact them negatively; They are American above all. Meanwhile an Irish-Irish has a completely Irish national identity, and the stereotype about Irish always binge-drinking is harmful and hurtful to them, because such stereotypes becomes all they are in the eyes of the world. And to other Americans that Irish-American seems as a reliable source on the people of Ireland (while also not being counted as one of "them"), regardless of if they have any personal connection to the country or not - so the old stereotypes of the Irish inhabitants gets validated when people with Irish ancestry regurgitate them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251565023.0" user="crazyashley1" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;We should just -get- that yous say one thing but you mean the other. Why? Why should I?

Because it's blatantly obvious and you're the one taking offense?  Accents and customs are hard to supplant, even after living for decades in a place.  Someone with an American accent, clothing, ans speach pattern saying they're X nationality is almost without fail either of X nationality descent, or came to the country so young they may as well have been born in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251753982.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Slippery slope putting all the responsibility on the person who is offended to stop and change their behaviour without taking any time to reflect on your own contribution to the situation. 

All I'm asking for is a little bit of respect from Americans that misuse their ancestral identity to make disparaging comments against my community. Where is the issue there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251252142.0" user="Jip_Jaap_Stam" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;No, the means of production is not owned exclusively by the workers in Scotland. What you likely mean to say is that Scots value social democratic policy and a strong social safety net more than Americans. 

You've misunderstood them. They don't say "Scotland is a very socialist nation"; they say "we are a very socialist nation". They're talking about Scottish people (hence the "we"), not the  state of Scotland. The word "nation" can be used as a collective noun to refer to the individual people as well as the institutions of said country. And Scottish people *are* more inclined to socialist worldviews than most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44251874635.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Aye this is spot on. Also a wee FYI, we are in the process of nationalising more of our services. We have the most nationalised health service across the UK, we have free Higher education, we just nationalised our railways, we have nationalised engery and water. So in some ways, we are a very socialist state as well. In context to the US ans UK of course</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252328900.0" user="Jip_Jaap_Stam" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it sounds like there's a lot of positive progress on your side of the border.

You're a few steps to the left of England, and a million miles from the US, where the 2 main parties occupy an extremely narrow section of the political spectrum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44252497906.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>Aye but our nations politicians are just as shaddy and just as self serving. Never the will of the people and always the will of the rulling elite. I guess that's something we all have in common 🤷</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44254352343.0" user="Jip_Jaap_Stam" delta="False">
    <text>Yep. Imagine, though, if we just all decided we'd had enough and chucked them out of office. They'd shit themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
