<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676388845.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189gaul/cmv_the_civil_justice_system_is_underappreciated/">
    <title>CMV: The civil justice system is under-appreciated as a triumph of humanity</title>
    <original_poster>JamoWilliams</original_poster>
    <original_post>For context: I am a lawyer. I often get asked “can you sue someone for X”, “can you sue someone for Y”, “am I at risk of being sued if I do Z”?

Yes. The answer is always yes. You can sue anyone for anything at any time. I can walk into my office, hop make an account on my jurisdictions e-filing system, and sue my mom for emotional damages because she told me that she didn’t like the pants that I wore to her birthday party within 20 minutes. Whether I will be successful in my claim or not depends entirely on the evidence of the case, how that evidence is presented and contextualized by the parties, and the prevailing jurisdictional case law authority on how certain aspects of the claim, the evidence, or the prospective requested remedy should be decided upon or viewed by the Judge.

This is a reality that I feel is often lost on people who do not understand what the civil justice system actually represents: an ability, a *right*, for people to voice their complaints to a higher authority and say “I was wronged. Here is how I was wronged. Here is my evidence. Here is who I was wronged by and here is the remedy that I would like from the court”. The system is meant to be, and designed to be, just. That’s why it’s called justice.

In my view, the vast majority of people who say “the justice system is broken”, especially when meaning to refer to the civil justice system, do not at all understand the justice system, its procedures, or what it aims to do. Despite criticisms that one may have of the system, the fact that it permits anyone to have a chance to plead their case and show evidence is a triumph.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44246420103.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>This sort of system is a necessary prerequisite for any form of society, and has existed in some way for as long as people have lived together in groups. Society is predicated on people following some set of rules and being compelled to do so by some governing body.

If you felt someone wronged you, you could always go to the lord / tribal council / priest nearest you and plead you case. How easy it would be to technically do, to what extent the decision makers would follow the laws, and to what extent the laws themselves would've been considered 'just' today might vary, but the general framework is the same.

If anything I think the fact that despite our incredible technological and societal advancements in the past couple of centuries our justice systems still have to rely on the subjective judgment of elite individuals and are only really accessible to those who have enough money and time or training should be considered a shortcoming of our societies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246476585.0" user="JamoWilliams" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that civil dispute resolution systems have evolved massively over time and continue to evolve

I’m not sure that I would call a judge considering a case “the subjective judgment of an elite individual” - it the decision of a person (who has sworn an oath to mitigate or minimize any biases) reaches after seeing all of the evidence and hearing the arguments of both parties. I do not see an alternative to that. AI, for instance, cannot do that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
