<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="267886791.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4fhqrr/cmv_actively_encouraging_everyone_to_vote_is/">
    <title>CMV: Actively encouraging everyone to vote is overall harmful to a democratic society.</title>
    <original_poster>The_Law_of_Pizza</original_poster>
    <original_post>I would like to start off by clarifying that I do not support voter suppression, poll taxes, poll tests, or restrictions on voting rights in any form. I even disapprove of removing felons' rights to vote.

That said, I reject those things not because I believe broadening the voter pool benefits society, but because such restrictions are far too dangerous to allow people to meddle with. The temptation by those in power to restrict the rights of voters who disagree with them is too much for people to resist, so as a necessary evil we must prohibit such meddling in any way.

More to the point, though, I believe that actively encouraging *everyone* to vote is the other side of that same coin - it is rounding up reactionary, low information voters to vote for your position on an issue. It warps democracy from being about a collective process to discuss and decide policy, into a competition to see who can bus the most warm bodies to the polls.

Voting is a right, but it is also a responsibility. Voting without being informed is an abuse of that responsibility, and encouraging uninformed voters to go to the polls is aiding in that abuse for your own political benefit.

A democratic society functions best when the voters are rational and informed. They (ideally) learn what they can about any issue, make a subjective decision based on their internal values, and then vote for a candidate or proposal that they believe will best accomplish that. 

While obviously not always true, the people who make a point to go out and vote on their own tend to be the ones who actually care enough to put the time and effort into the process as described in my previous paragraph. They're the closest we get in reality, anyway.

Deliberately rounding up non-voters and pushing them towards the polls dredges up the opposite - low information, reactionary voters whose only knowledge on the issues likely comes from the partisan individuals who gave them the voter registration sheet. They seldom take the time to seek out the other side and hear their version of the story.

So, while these people have every right to vote, they're abusing that right and partisan organizations designed to "get out the vote" are complicit in that. They're harming the overall system for their own gain.

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28434383320.0" user="ThePillowEffect" delta="False">
    <text>Same argument came up a couple weeks ago, so I'll bring my response from there over here:

The purpose of a democracy is to create a government by and for the people. That's all there is to it. Democracy cares not for the well-being or advancement of society, or taking steps to preserve itself; simply that everyone in that society participates in the decisions it makes. It doesn't care who has the most information; who spends time studying relevant issues and who does not.  From the OED, a democracy is (some parts bolded for emphasis) "a system of government in which **all the people of a state** or polity ... **are involved** in making decisions about its affairs, **typically by voting** to elect representatives to a parliament or similar assembly".

By excluding or dis-encouraging people from voting (a core tenet of democracy/the primary means by which the people participate in their government) you're reducing the chance democracy functions best. To eliminate people from the democractic process is to weaken democracy. You can argue that your view would be conducive in making a society that functions better, advances faster, and is more likely to survive threats made against it; but not that a "Democratic society functions best" under this view, as it would function just the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
