<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="267886791.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4fhqrr/cmv_actively_encouraging_everyone_to_vote_is/">
    <title>CMV: Actively encouraging everyone to vote is overall harmful to a democratic society.</title>
    <original_poster>The_Law_of_Pizza</original_poster>
    <original_post>I would like to start off by clarifying that I do not support voter suppression, poll taxes, poll tests, or restrictions on voting rights in any form. I even disapprove of removing felons' rights to vote.

That said, I reject those things not because I believe broadening the voter pool benefits society, but because such restrictions are far too dangerous to allow people to meddle with. The temptation by those in power to restrict the rights of voters who disagree with them is too much for people to resist, so as a necessary evil we must prohibit such meddling in any way.

More to the point, though, I believe that actively encouraging *everyone* to vote is the other side of that same coin - it is rounding up reactionary, low information voters to vote for your position on an issue. It warps democracy from being about a collective process to discuss and decide policy, into a competition to see who can bus the most warm bodies to the polls.

Voting is a right, but it is also a responsibility. Voting without being informed is an abuse of that responsibility, and encouraging uninformed voters to go to the polls is aiding in that abuse for your own political benefit.

A democratic society functions best when the voters are rational and informed. They (ideally) learn what they can about any issue, make a subjective decision based on their internal values, and then vote for a candidate or proposal that they believe will best accomplish that. 

While obviously not always true, the people who make a point to go out and vote on their own tend to be the ones who actually care enough to put the time and effort into the process as described in my previous paragraph. They're the closest we get in reality, anyway.

Deliberately rounding up non-voters and pushing them towards the polls dredges up the opposite - low information, reactionary voters whose only knowledge on the issues likely comes from the partisan individuals who gave them the voter registration sheet. They seldom take the time to seek out the other side and hear their version of the story.

So, while these people have every right to vote, they're abusing that right and partisan organizations designed to "get out the vote" are complicit in that. They're harming the overall system for their own gain.

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28434423473.0" user="More_like_regreddit" delta="False">
    <text>I'm Australian, so I'm going to go all in and say I'm very proud of the fact we have compulsory voter attendance on election day.

I think a government can't be truly legitimate unless it wins an election that the overwhelming majority of the population actively participated in.

&amp;gt;It warps democracy from being about a collective process to discuss and decide policy, into a competition to see who can bus the most warm bodies to the polls.

I agree, I think this is a large problem. Elections should be about winning the consensus of public opinion, not motivating your supporters to get out and vote. If everyone is forced to attend, you eliminate voter apathy as problem.

&amp;gt;Voting is a right, but it is also a responsibility.

Couldn't agree more. I would go further though, and say it's everyone's responsibility.

&amp;gt; Voting without being informed is an abuse of that responsibility

This statement, while potentially true, I think isn't important. At the end of the day every person's voice should be counted equally. From the politicians themselves, down to the most lowly uninformed voter.

All of this said though I'm sure I won't find much agreement here, but I thought I'd give my two cents anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28434449653.0" user="The_Law_of_Pizza" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think a government can't be truly legitimate unless it wins an election that the overwhelming majority of the population actively participated in.

I almost awarded a delta for this, but after further consideration, I think my response is:

A large bulk of people, possibly even a slim majority, have no real interest in and pay no attention to politics. They know next to nothing about what they're voting for.

These people may have "participated" physically, by checking a box, but they did not truly *actively* participate in the process. They did not genuinely make a decision based on their own values. 

If we take your statement at face value, is the Australian government actually legitimate under your definition, if so many people just tick a box almost at random?

I'd argue that there really isn't much of a difference between the US and Australian systems, besides that the Australian one has a lot more "statistically noise" from compelled voters.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28434476941.0" user="More_like_regreddit" delta="False">
    <text>I think the largest difference is that special interest groups are far less powerful in Australia, because motivating large numbers of people to get out and vote isn't a tool at their disposal. Australian politics therefore becomes much more about what the silent majority think, rather than who has the loudest voice.

I also think, from my own experience anyway, that people are generally more engaged in politics here, if only because they feel they need to have an opinion come election time.

&amp;gt;if so many people just tick a box almost at random?

I don't think this really happens as much as you would think. Keep in mind that it isn't actually compulsory to vote here, just to submit a ballot. It's perfectly legal to submit a blank (or defaced) ballot paper if that's what you want to do. Submitting a blank vote has actually become a means of protest in itself, as those votes are still counted and reported.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28434728158.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a little confused by your position. 

Why are you proud of forcing people to vote? Why does participation legitimize a government?

Is this participation legitimate if it's compulsory? Isn't that a perversion of the ideals of democracy? 

How does forcing everyone to attend eliminate voter apathy? If a country increases import taxes - leading to people importing less - does this prove that people don't want as many foreign products anymore? Are really few homosexuals in countries where homosexuality is illegal? 

Do you see what I'm getting at here? You're not eliminating voter apathy. You're masking it. You're pretending that it doesn't exist by compelling people to vote. 

If you agree that encouraging as many people as possible to vote is a large problem in terms of "rounding up reactionary, low information voters to vote" and in turn warping democracy into a competition to see who can bus the most warm bodies to the polls, why are you proud of your country mandating this phenomenon? 

Why should everyone's voice be counted equally? It's absurd to think that every view, opinion and stance is equal, is it not? 

I see your sentiment being mirrored greatly in Norway, and I'm so puzzled by it. I've never had anyone really explain their reasoning to me beyond platitudes and implying their reverence for democracy, so I hope that you can offer some clarity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28436093194.0" user="More_like_regreddit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You're not eliminating voter apathy. You're masking it. You're pretending that it doesn't exist by compelling people to vote.

This isn't what happens though. Mandating attendance of elections just makes it part of life. It becomes a part of the culture that at election time, everyone makes time to get their name marked off.

It becomes like eating. You don't eat everyday because you think 'my biology is forcing me to eat today' you eat because it's just what you do.. Some people enjoy it more than others, sure, but everyone does it out of habit without fuss. People very rarely take the attitude 'shit I have to vote/eat today or I'll get a fine/die.'

The evidence of this is the fact that in most Australian states attendance at local council elections is not compulsory, but the voter turnout is still in the region of 95%. People do it out of habit, not out of necessity. So no, it isn't just masking apathy. It actually eliminates it.

&amp;gt;If you agree that encouraging as many people as possible to vote is a large problem in terms of "rounding up reactionary, low information voters to vote" and in turn warping democracy into a competition to see who can bus the most warm bodies to the polls, why are you proud of your country mandating this phenomenon?

This is only a problem insofar as it is a contest in getting people to the polls. If everyone has to attend the polls, the contest is moot. The election will be won by the group/person who has the most support among **all** eligible voters, not the group/person who manages to get the most supporters to attend the polls.

&amp;gt;Why should everyone's voice be counted equally? It's absurd to think that every view, opinion and stance is equal, is it not?

No. In a democracy every view, opinion and stance is only worth the number of people who support it. Every person gets one vote. Their voices should be equal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28437038458.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This isn't what happens though. Mandating attendance of elections just makes it part of life. It becomes a part of the culture that at election time, everyone makes time to get their name marked off.
It becomes like eating. You don't eat everyday because you think 'my biology is forcing me to eat today' you eat because it's just what you do.. Some people enjoy it more than others, sure, but everyone does it out of habit without fuss. People very rarely take the attitude 'shit I have to vote/eat today or I'll get a fine/die.'
The evidence of this is the fact that in most Australian states attendance at local council elections is not compulsory, but the voter turnout is still in the region of 95%. People do it out of habit, not out of necessity. So no, it isn't just masking apathy. It actually eliminates it.

Sure. Following other laws is just a part of life too. I don't much alcohol since I'm poor and the state has made it incredibly expensive. That doesn't mean that I wouldn't enjoy relaxing with a drink more often without those taxes. 

Look at it this way: If your government made everyone free to vote, or not to vote - would the numbers stay the same? 

And people do eat because their biology forces them too. I know, because I'm one of those people who hates getting interrupted by hunger. 

Another important point to consider is also not just that the voters show up, but how informed they are. Rational ignorance, and  rational irrationality becomes relevant to this point.

 I'll do my best to describe what rational ignorance is, though it may be obvious from the name. The rationality of not getting informed stems from the low value of a vote, versus the high cost of getting informed. The value of a vote also doesn't change if you don't get informed.

The cost of ignorance is obviously vast nationally, but the cost is spread over every single individual. It's a negative externality. The individual does not bear the cost, society does. It's a case where individual rationality does not equal collective rationality, a market failure.

There is a similar concept; rational irrationality that follows the same lines. Being irrational costs nothing (to the individual). Holding false beliefs costs nothing. The cost of ridding yourself of false beliefs however can be great. Especially if you've held these views for a long time. Especially if they have become part of your identity. Especially if your friends and family share these views. I would wager that this concept is very relevant in this sub in general too.

These incentive problems are inherent to democracy. A vote will never be worth much. Humans also don't operate on collective rationality. Saying "We would all be better off if we stopped fighting" is not going to affect global conflict. We all know this. That doesn't change the fact that the incentives for this or that group do not align with non-conflict.

&amp;gt;This is only a problem insofar as it is a contest in getting people to the polls. If everyone has to attend the polls, the contest is moot. The election will be won by the group/person who has the most support among all eligible voters, not the group/person who manages to get the most supporters to attend the polls.

If a voter needed the government to mandate that they show up, or put another way, if they wouldn't have shown up without the government prodding them to do so, do they really support the candidate? More importantly though, the problem outlined there is mainly the fact that you're ushering low information voters to the poll.

&amp;gt;No. In a democracy every view, opinion and stance is only worth the number of people who support it. Every person gets one vote. Their voices should be equal.

You're not responding to what I said. You're just reiterating your beliefs. Why should everyone's voice be counted equally? It's absurd to think that every view, opinion and stance is equal, is it not?

Do you think a position is only worth the people who support it? 

I've done some googling, and found some statistics on public opinion in Australia on racism. I knew that you had a bit of a checkered history. If we assumed that most people in Australia were prejudiced against indigenous, - as statistics seem to indicate both Aboriginal and Australians seems agree with - would you then support, defend oe think that prejudicial opinions, views and stances are worth more than egalitarian stances? 

Doesn't the fact that your people think that these prejudices are real already prove that they are prejudiced, and as such, according to your worldview, these prejudices are necessarily more legitimate than contrary stances? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
