<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="270163330.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4gujcy/cmv_closed_elections_are_not_undemocratic/">
    <title>CMV: Closed elections are not undemocratic.</title>
    <original_poster>spydormunkay</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Closed elections are not undemocratic.**

I argue that Sanders and his supporters are using selective argumentation to prove that Clinton is only winning the Democratic primaries due to closed elections. I argue that Clinton’s ability to win closed primaries is not because of the lack of independent voters, but because of her more diverse base of supporters in terms demographics in the states that held closed primaries.

This discussion pertains to the current 2016 U.S. Democratic primaries. Recently, Bernie Sanders and his supporters have been increasingly critical of the current Democratic primary system, particularly closed elections. Though, the Democratic primaries run various types of elections throughout the primary season besides closed elections.

Before we get into the discussion, here are some information on U.S. primary elections for those who don’t know:

*What are closed elections?*

* **Closed elections** are elections where only people registered as members of a certain party can vote in that primary. Independents and registered members of other parties like the Republican Party are not allowed to vote. This is in direct contrast to open elections.

* This is in contrast to **open elections** where everyone is allowed to vote, regardless of party affiliation or lack thereof.

There are other types of elections such as semi-closed elections and semi-open elections:

* **Semi-closed elections** allow party members and unaffiliated voters to vote, leaving out people from other parties.

* **Semi-open elections** are pretty much open elections except that unlike open elections where voters are given a ballot and on the ballot they choose which party to vote for, in semi-open elections, voters must declare party they wish to vote for and are then given a party-specific ballot. For all intents and purposes, semi-open elections are essentially open elections.


Furthermore, elections are either primaries or caucuses. These types of elections do not pertain to who can participate in the election, but rather how elections are conducted. Primaries are essentially normal elections while caucuses are town hall meetings where delegates who support the same candidate group up and whichever candidate has the most support wins.

Closed elections have been a staple of both Democratic and Republican primaries for years. Once upon a time, all party elections were closed. In fact, back then, nominees were not chosen by the people in an election, but instead they were chosen in a single National convention by party leaders only. Things have changed. Parties now host elections open to normal people. This is due to the fact that the old system was simply undemocratic and it sometimes led to unelectable people being chosen as the nominees. Elections open to normal people is an easy way to determine if a candidate is electable or not. However, state parties are given the choice on whether to run a closed, open, semi-closed, and semi-open election. Closed elections have been a part of the primary process for years and have not really been a huge issue until this election. And it wasn’t until the New York Democratic primary where the issue really became controversial.

*What is the purpose of closed elections?*

* The purpose of closed elections is to keep outsiders out. The reason for this is the belief that only true supporters of a party know who would best represent them.

* There is also a fear of saboteurs or “raiders” from other parties that might purposely vote for weaker candidates to make the election easier for their preferred candidate from other parties. Though this occurrence is rare, it has happened before recently. In 2008, Rush Limbaugh pushed Republican voters to vote for Hillary Clinton over Barack Obama because Barack Obama was seen as the stronger candidate. In 2012, Democratic voters in Michigan voted in the Republican primary for Rick Santorum in an effort to prevent the nomination of Mitt Romney, who was seen as the stronger candidate.

*Why have closed elections become so controversial?*

* **Bernie Sanders** is a major candidate for the Democratic Presidential nomination, he is currently second place in pledged delegates. He tends to be more popular among independents than current Democratic frontrunner Hillary Clinton. Because independents are locked out of closed elections, supposedly a large part of his potential voters are locked out, leading many to believe that closed elections are undemocratic.
* Because closed elections only allow party members to vote, closed elections tend to favor party favorites. The current party favorite is **Hillary Clinton**, who tends to be more popular among Democratic Party members. As a result, she stands most to gain by having closed elections.

There are several problems with this argument:

The most obvious being that Clinton has won 10/13 open primaries so far (11/14 if you count semi-open primaries). The most common counter to this point is that most of those primaries were in the Deep South, which are usually conservative and don’t vote Democrat anyway. There are several problems with this counterpoint is that:

* First off, such a dismissal unfairly diminishes the results of the battleground states that held open primaries. Only two battleground states held an open primary and that was Ohio (semi-open) and Virginia, both of which were won by Hillary Clinton. If we consider independents as undecided voters or voters in the middle who can swing elections as they usually do, naturally, they would be more influential and more numerous in the swing states. If there were places that the supposed independent voting bloc that Sanders always touts about could have swung elections his way it was those two states. They didn’t.

* Secondly, the idea that the South is conservative and therefore categorically against Sanders is a fundamental misunderstanding of the Southern electorate, a mistake that has led to the rise of Trump in the South and has led to Sanders tremendous losses there. **The South may be socially conservative, but they are not fiscally conservative.**

* Why do you think Trump won a large part of the Deep South? Was it because Southerners are just racist and hate immigrants? No, it’s his economic policies that attracted Southerners. Early on, he called for taxes to decrease on the poor and taxes to increase on the wealthy (though this is a lie or truth, depending on who you ask). He called for keeping Medicare and Social Security at a time when Republicans were calling for them to be cut. He called for a replacement of Obamacare with something similar to Canada’s healthcare system. These are leftist economic views that Sanders touts. Southerners are predominantly working class whites and blacks who stand most to gain from Sanders policies.

* Perhaps it was because he’s socially liberal? Then what is Clinton? A gun-loving racist? They’re basically the same in terms of socially liberal values. His failure to reach them stems from his inability to connect with those voters personally, which Clinton achieves by appealing to the blacks.

* If anything, Clinton’s ability to win in the Deep South is a testament to her diverse electorate and, thus, her superior electability compared to Sanders. This attitude that Sanders and his supporters are taking in dismissing the South as “distorting reality” is a defeatist attitude that haunts Sanders even in the Northeastern states that Sanders likes to tout about. Why do you think minorities in the Northeastern states, especially blacks, vote overwhelmingly in favor of Clinton? Are they socially and fiscally conservative? Or are they just more attracted to Clinton than Sanders on a personal level?


The second most obvious hole in Sanders’ argument is that Sanders has won 6/9 closed caucuses so far (6/7 if you only count states). If it really were the case that Clinton has a much bigger advantage in closed elections than in open elections, wouldn’t closed caucuses basically be the ultimate advantage for Clinton? If we consider the argument that closed primaries limiting the potential amount of voters are an advantage for Clinton, surely a closed caucus, which drastically results in a low amount of voters, would give an even bigger advantage to Clinton? This is not the case. Strangely enough, in some of the most fiscally conservative states Sanders has swept closed caucuses. The only closed caucuses Clinton has won was in Nevada, a swing state, and the American Samoa and the Northern Marianas. It’s obvious to see why a place like deeply liberal Maine would vote for Sanders. Though it’s amazing to see that deeply fiscally conservative places like Wyoming, Alaska, Nebraska, and Kansas would vote for Sanders. Aren’t they fiscally conservative strongholds, directly opposite to Sanders views? If we examine Sanders and his supporters’ argument that conservatism, more specifically fiscal conservatism, is his biggest weakness which led to his blowouts in the South, then why doesn’t this argument apply to actually fiscally conservative places like these states? One counterpoint would be that because elections are closed only real hardline liberals would be registered Democrats in such fiscally conservative states. But why can such hardline liberals only sprout in these places and not places like New York? Surely there are hardline liberals registered as Democrats in those states? The real reason why such states voted heavily in favor of Sanders is because of **their lack of diversity, a.k.a. their overwhelming non-Hispanic white population.**

* The states of Wyoming, Alaska, Nebraska, Kansas, and even the swing state of Colorado, are heavily white. Heavier than other closed election states like New York and Maryland. When you compare the results of these two groups of closed election states and their demographics, it becomes easy to see why Sanders ultimately lost those states. New York, in particular, is “only” 56.5% non-Hispanic white as opposed to Colorado’s 70% non-Hispanic White population. When you remember that minorities vote heavily in favor of Clinton, which comprise 43.5% of New York, and whites are typically split between young and old, it’s easy to see that Clinton, compared to Sanders, has a huge advantage over Sanders in terms of diversity and broadness in her voter base. The split between young and old whites is less of an issue in heavily white states because inevitably there are more young white voters than old white voters. However, that split becomes an issue when you add minorities, especially blacks into the equation. Minorities staunchly in support of Clinton, young and old. That staunch support along with the split in whites is winning Clinton the primaries.

* This is the same story in Maryland where non-Hispanic whites only comprise 52.6% of the population. Clinton won even harder in Maryland than in New York (63% vs. 57%). Contrary to popular belief, open primaries would not have saved Sanders from either demographic nightmare. Unsurprisingly, Clinton’s struggled as white population increased, winning Pennsylvania by only 55% and 78% non-Hispanic white, Connecticut by 51% and 69% white. Clinton’s lost Rhode Island, 74.5% non-Hispanic White.


The third hole in his argument is that independents are only heavily influential in swing states. The idea that independent voters will have a bigger impact in deep blue states than swing states contradicts the idea of what an independent voter is. If we go back to my first argument that independent voters are the ones that decide results in battleground states the most, wouldn’t it be natural that they would comprise a higher percentage of the electorate in the swing states than in the red and blue states? If the supposed independent bloc are the ones pushing Sanders above Clinton, why didn’t he win swing states with open primaries? More importantly, why wasn’t he even competitive in them? He was blown out in both Virginia and Ohio. Was it because of demographics? Yes and no. Virginia is 63% non-Hispanic white whereas Ohio is 80% non-Hispanic white. Virginia can be chalked up to another demographic nightmare. Ohio on the other hand is peculiar. Why would an 80% non-Hispanic white state that had an open (semi-open) primary vote for Clinton. It’s a swing state, too, meaning that there are more independent voters than normal. **The answer could very well be Sanders is not as popular among independent as he or his supporter like you to believe.** Sanders is certainly more popular among independents compared to Clinton. That’s no question, the polls all show it and the primary results speak for themselves. But we must re-examine the polls. Clinton, despite being so “unpopular” among independents still leads Trump and Cruz in the polls. Despite having less popularity than Sanders among independents, she still pulls enough of their support as well as the staunch support of minorities and traditional Democrats to give her the edge over Sanders. Sanders was given two free shots at proving his cross-cutting appeal by winning the open primaries of Ohio and Virginia and he was blown out.

The real reason why Sanders is losing closed primaries is not because of the lack of independent voters, it’s because of his narrow voter base compared to Clinton. Think about it. Sanders has only been successful in heavily non-Hispanic white states, whether open, closed, semi-open, or semi-closed. The only really diverse that he’s won so far is Michigan, which is still 75.6% non-Hispanic white, a far cry from 56% and 52% shown by New York and Maryland. The idea that an open primary could’ve saved Sanders is not only preposterous, it’s insulting to the minorities who still staunchly support Clinton. Perhaps, states like Pennsylvania and Connecticut could’ve been won by Sanders had they been open. They’re mostly white, the demographics fit it. If anything, the fact that they’re not swing states, makes it even easier for Sanders. But that’s just it. If his greatest strength is his so-called independent bloc, **why can’t he win a state like Ohio or Virginia?** Don’t forget Nevada or Florida. Nevada was Clinton’s only win in the closed causes in mainland United States. Unsurprisingly, that was the least whitest of the closed caucuses: 51.5% non-Hispanic white. Florida, a closed primary is 55% non-Hispanic white. Do you people honestly think Sanders had a chance in hell of winning those primaries with those demographics? Get out.

In short, I guess I didn't prove that closed elections were undemocratic. But I sought to prove that the reasons that Sanders' supporters had for why they are undemocratic are just invalid.

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28454382100.0" user="5510" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that they are undemocratic **within the context of a two party system.**      
      
Yes, on some level it makes perfect sense to say "they are private organizations, they should be allowed to make whatever rules they want as long as the rules are transparent."  I mean if the Republicans think Trump is "hijacking" the party, they should be able to protect themselves from being hijacked.    
        
The part where it becomes undemocratic is when those parties have a near complete duopoly on political power.  If Sanders and his supporters think the Democratic party is screwing them over, then they should be allowed to go form their own party.  But the system doesn't (realistically) allow for that.      
        
Of course the answer shouldn't be forcing states to have open primaries... the answer should be changing the electoral system so that a multiparty system is viable.  But within the context of our CURRENT system, the closed primary (especially in a year with no incumbent for either side, which reduces the odds of "sabatoge") is extremely undemocratic.  "Their party, their rules" is only fair if you are allowed to (realistically) start competing or spin off parties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28454408177.0" user="spydormunkay" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. Personally, I think the alternative vote system would be best in developing a multi-party system. It allows people to both vote for the candidates they truly want and rank the ones they will accept as replacements. It removes strategic voting and it encourages people to vote for 3rd, 4th, etc. parties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28454438842.0" user="5510" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly.  But it would be fair to say that closed primaries exacerbate the undemocratic nature of the two party system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
