<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44440447184.0" user="Illustrious_Ring_517" delta="False">
    <text>Can't you say the same thing for people who allow themselves to get gat and they are just lazy cows?
Should we not uplift people? If you want to eat q0 bigmacs a day and get over 600lbs. Well buddy you do it and I hope it brings you the happiness your looking for. Same goes to the people who go to the gym and pump some weights. Why can't we be more positive than negative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443655911.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Do you use that same philosophy of "body positivity" as a reason to encourage people who are anorexic to continue being anorexic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44511410121.0" user="Illustrious_Ring_517" delta="False">
    <text>Hating on anyone for their body seems wrong and judgemental. If it's wrong to judge people that are fat then why isn't it wrong to judge someone who works out? Can't people just be happy without everyone judging them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44512439490.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not talking about hating on anyone, I'm talking about not encouraging people to be unhealthy. 

I also never said anything about people who work out, I'm talking about people who do a bunch of steroids and drop down to dangerously low levels of body fat and dehydrate themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44514809306.0" user="Illustrious_Ring_517" delta="False">
    <text>I know a few body builders that don't steroids. And who are we to tell someone what they can and can't do with there body though?

If someone wants to be fat or anorexic that's between them and their doctor is it not? 

I would like to see us grow to where we don't judge people and if they are happy then be happy for them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44515387339.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah sure there are natural bodybuilders, but they aren't able to compete at the top levels. In order to compete at the top you literally have to do steroids. 

And I'm not saying people can't do what they want with their body, I'm just saying it's stupid and shouldn't be encouraged. 

And I'm sorry but this idea of acting like obesity and steroid abuse aren't problems is silly. Especially in the case of obesity, this is a massive problem in the Western world. It's horrible for the country when over half the people are fat.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
