<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44439994026.0" user="SaberTruth2" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with most of your points other than how attractive they are perceived. People like what they like and there are plenty of women who love the idea if being with a giant human, and there are guys who geek out on the jacked girl look. Unfortunately I think the latter might be more of a fetish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440053470.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have to be a competitive body builder to be a giant human. There are lots of women who are into big muscular guys, but they aren't into the freakishly low body fat dehydrated physique that body builders have when they are on stage. 

Look up what bodybuilders look like during off season and then compare that to photos of them when they are actually on stage. Many women are definitely attracted to big muscular guys who have an athletic body comp, as in like 7 - 12% body fat. 

But the physique that body builders try to achieve on stage is dangerously low body fat and dehydration, combined with having sauced out muscles, to the point that they don't even look human. That's what I mean when I say the bodybuilder physique is unattractive, I'm talking about the physique they have after they do their dangerous unhealthy cutting to look as lean as humanly possible on the stage</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440163472.0" user="SaberTruth2" delta="False">
    <text>Understand all of this, and I don’t disagree. What I’m saying though is there are people who find muscles with muscles on top of them very attractive. Probably some people that wish it was feasible for their partner look like that all the time without the risk of dropping dead. These people live at the gym and it is their entire identity, many others at the gym members find that to be very attractive and that is who they seek. That look that we think of as gross and unhealthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440255402.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;What I’m saying though is there are people who find muscles with muscles on top of them very attractive.

Yeah and I never said otherwise. What they don't find attractive though is when those people cut down to dangerously low levels of body fat and dehydrate themselves in order to look freakishly shredded on a stage. I'm not saying that having a lot of muscles is unattractive, I'm saying the specific physique that bodybuilders go for on stage is unattractive. In fact it's actually pretty grotesque. I'm  not saying these bodybuilders look unattractive when they are just walking down the street during their off season, but the specific physique they get on stage after their cut is just not attractive at all. Maybe there are a handful of weirdos who have a specific fetish for that or something, but I doubt more than a small handful if any of those people exist. They don't even look human when they are on the stage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440639056.0" user="SaberTruth2" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, we’re going in circles. What I’m saying is there are women that find the men who are in competition state to be the peak of attraction.  What you are saying is that YOU don’t think what that looks like is attractive so in turn NOBODY thinks it’s attractive. If 4/5 girls say they think that the men in fitness competition (while on stage) are not attractive that still leaves 20% of the females in the world attracted to them. You are projecting your opinions on how attractive they are into what you are now stating is a matter of fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443675897.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>It's definitely not even close to 20% of women who find that to be attractive. Seriously, go look at pictures of the top bodybuilders on stage when they are at their most extreme, nobody finds that to be attractive</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
