<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44443434489.0" user="GreenOk8834" delta="False">
    <text>If by the label "gym-rat" you mean someone who is a casual bodybuilder (trains for mass but doesn't compete), then I fall into that category. 

When involving medical sciences into the discussion, it becomes clear that competitive bodybuilding, anorexia, and obesity (objectively) deviate significantly from the ideal human body state from a health standpoint. Taking this into consideration, I also do not condone, celebrate, or promote such things nor do I think people should do so.   
  
I personally draw the line at being Natty + not going lower than 10% BF, which should be reasonably healthy, although not the healthiest.    
  
Where I disagree with you is with the notion that bodybuilding is purely for vanity. If you compare the average natural bodybuilder with the average untrained individual, the former will be superior in most of the physical attributes you mentioned (strength, endurance, etc.). My point being that  bodybuilding (even naturally) adds significant physical capabilities with respect to an untrained individual.  

Obviously, when comparing bodybuilders to athletes, the latter will be superior in most of those attributes, but bodybuilders are still significantly more capable than untrained individuals who sit around watching TV all day and eating chips.   
  
Why do I personally prefer natural bodybuilding over athletic sports?   
  
Because I like the muscular look while having enough strength and endurance to get me through everyday activities, and it makes me happy.   
  
Are my athlete friends generally physically superior?   
  
Of course. But even if I magically transitioned into an athlete right now, I'd be miserable knowing I'd be doing something I don't enjoy or like.   
  
It's like forcing someone to major in engineering when they actually hate it and would rather study something else that might be less rewarding, yet more enjoyable for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443836269.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I personally draw the line at being Natty + not going lower than 10% BF, which should be reasonably healthy, although not the healthiest.    

Yeah I agree that is totally reasonable 

I'm more so talking about the people who drop down to ridiculously low levels of body fat and especially the ones who do a bunch of gear.

It sounds like you are mainly just someone who enjoys lifting weights and working out a lot, which is totally great. I'm talking about people who are seriously into competitive bodybuilding and push their body to unhealthy limits</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
