<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44437672495.0" user="CasualCrisis83" delta="False">
    <text>Saying someone else's interest is stupid is purely judgemental. 

 Many hobbies are unhealthy.  Something doesn't have to have a form of productivity to have value. Fun is enough.  Being challenged amd testing one's resolve is enough. 

There's nothing morally wrong with aspiring to an esthetic.  Some people spend hundreds of dollars on their hair and nails. Some people like to look ripped.so what?  When someone who  judges someone's character based on their looks it is called prejudice.

People shouldn't have to justify their interests based on some nonexistent scale of values. Let people like things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437696834.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it is judgmental, but some interests are highly self-destructive with little benefit, it is fair to call them stupid. If someone's interest was filming themselves eating tide pods, it would be fair to call that a stupid interest, no? 

Also if someone's hobby is to lift weights, work out, and channel their resolve, they are way better off focusing on achieving a healthy athletic physique rather than an unhealthy body builder physique.

I agree there is nothing morally wrong with bodybuilding, but that's not what I'm arguing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437750348.0" user="jdoe5" delta="False">
    <text>Body building can be destructive when using PEDs but that doesn’t negate that there are still underlying benefits to working out. The net result might be neutral or negative but it’s a whole lot better than hobbies like alcohol, smoking, gambling, eating tide pods, etc where there is essentially no positive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437976046.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>PEDs are a requirement in order to compete at the top levels of bodybuilding.

And even for natty bodybuilders, they still have to get to dangerously low body fat percentage and dehydration in order to achieve a stage ready physique, which itself is incredibly unhealthy and damaging to the body. 

I don't think you realize that when you are looking at a stage of bodybuilders, all of those guys are basically on the verge of death</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438034954.0" user="jdoe5" delta="False">
    <text>Was going to respond until I looked through your other responses and it’s pretty clear you’re not actually here to change your view, you just want to argue. Not worth my time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438146308.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I actually do want to change my view, but most of the comments are just making whataboutism arguments about other sports, or they are making comments that show they don't really understand what competitive bodybuilding actually entails 

I absolutely do want my view changed</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
