<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44442574461.0" user="Automatic-Sport-6253" delta="False">
    <text>You are looking at it from the wrong perspective. Bodybuilders often work as models and trainers. And in almost any trade at some point a competitive nature arises. They need these competitions to show off when they get clients. So competing and getting bigger is not just a part of their lifestyle, it's pretty much a part of their daily job. Just as staying unhealthily skinny is part of runaway models' job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443813353.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>You can be a model or a trainer without having to cut to ridiculously low body fat levels and dehydrating yourself, and especially without doing a bunch of gear 

Runway models aren't unhealthy skinny either, they aren't cutting down to like 3% bodyfat or dehydrating themselves just to look as lean as humanly possibly</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44444119791.0" user="Automatic-Sport-6253" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, you are talking about a select few who go to the ridiculous extremes to win their muscle measuring contests. Majority don't do that. And for those who do, having a bunch of trophies let them jack up the price for personal training. So yeah, they kind of have to do all of that because it pays off eventually. So it's not as stupid when they do it with a specific intent knowing what they want to achieve with that and knowing what they have to pay for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44444146629.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>No I'm not talking about a select few, I'm talking about people who are competitive bodybuilders in general. That includes local and amateur shows. They are all doing incredibly unhealthy things to their body. The main difference between the people at the top versus the people at local shows is mainly just genetics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44446578225.0" user="Automatic-Sport-6253" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any stats on how many fitness/gym rats do competitive bodybuilding?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44446781564.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>How is that question even relevant? I'm not saying there's anything wrong with being a gym rat or being into fitness. I'm specifically talking about competitive bodybuilding</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44447339005.0" user="Automatic-Sport-6253" delta="False">
    <text>It is relevant because you claim these bodybuilders are not select few. I'm saying there's not that many of them compared to the overall number of gym rats. And they do it to gain and maintain client base among other reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44447365984.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>This entire post is about competitive bodybuilders. 

People who are just regular gym rats who don't compete on stage are not bodybuilders, they are just people who lift weights. They are not relevant to this post. This post is specifically about bodybuilders, not random gym rats.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
