<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44437493173.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.

“I bet I could get [*even bigger*](https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18759381/)” 

Their mindset is somewhat disordered. It is hard to understand a kind that drives its body to ruin. But, it is a similar one to that which drives models to anorexia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437524251.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that's an interesting thought. I wouldn't be surprised if body dysmorphia is a huge motivating factor behind it. I'm sure a lot of bodybuilders suffer from this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437555978.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>That is, in my opinion, the issue with bodybuilding. In the abstract, wanting to see how buff a human can be isn’t that stupid. At least it isn’t any more stupid than wanting to see who can run the fastest, or throw a javelin the farthest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437601541.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; wanting to see how buff a human can be isn’t that stupid. At least it isn’t any more stupid than wanting to see who can run the fastest, or throw a javelin the farthest

That's where I would disagree. Simply looking the buffest is purely an achievement of vanity. Being able to run the fastest is an actual athletic feat, it showcases the capability of the human body in terms of performance rather than just appearances. Plus, if we're being honest, even in terms of vanity, the vast majority of the population would agree that sprinters have more attractive bodies than bodybuilders. 

On a practical level, other sports are way more lucrative than body building (if you even want to call it a sport). In the US, for example, you can get full ride college scholarships for track and field or any of the major team sports. The average professional soccer player makes orders of magnitude more money than the average bodybuilder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437898908.0" user="TangyMarshmallow" delta="False">
    <text>It still is a showcase of the capability of the human body. Sports may be how fast the someone can run/swim/jump as an athletic feat. Things like math and chess competitions are for intellectual feats. There are also competitions for art/singing/dance to showcase artistic achievements. Bodybuilding requires dedication just like all types of achievements, and yes it can be destructive if you take PEDs or do it in an unhealthy way. 

But then how is bodybuilding any different from things like MMA and NFL football? They all showcase achievement and provide entertainment but also put its participants in some danger.

Practically, yes there are differences in pay but that doesn't really make it stupid because then are certain sports players stupid for not picking a higher paid sport? They are doing it because that's what they are passionate about and they're able to dedicate their energy towards it to achieve a goal.

Whether or not someone's goal is stupid is highly subjective. Personally I think it's pretty cool to see the extremes what the human body is capable of physically looking like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437944736.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Bodybuilding requires dedication just like all types of achievements,

Ok but physically training for an athletic healthy physique takes just as much dedication as bodybuilding, and it results in a body that is way healthier and more physically capable 

&gt;yes it can be destructive if you take PEDs or do it in an unhealthy way. 

PEDs are a requirement for competing in bodybuilding at the highest level, and even natural bodybuilders still have to get to dangerously low body fat levels and dehydration in order to be ready to compete on a stage. Bodybuilding is inherently unhealthy and self-destructive

&gt;But then how is bodybuilding any different from things like MMA and NFL football?

I never said it was different than those sports. MMA and NFL are separate discussions, this post is about bodybuilding. This is just a whataboutism argument. 

I'd also add that MMA and NFL are way more financially lucrative than bodybuilding, and also that MMA and NFL athletes are way more physically capable than bodybuilders 

&gt;Practically, yes there are differences in pay but that doesn't really make it stupid

Bodybuilding is stupid though because the cost drastically outweigh the benefits 

And you keep trying to change the subject to combat sports which is just a different discussion entirely. 

&gt;Whether or not someone's goal is stupid is highly subjective.

If someone's personal goal is self-destructive and far more costly than beneficial, then it is stupid 

&gt;Personally I think it's pretty cool to see the extremes what the human body is capable of physically looking like.

Sure, but how is that worth all the costs of seeing the extremes of what the human body can look like? It's not worth achieving those extremes when the process of achieving it is extremely self-destructive</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438711189.0" user="MegaBlastoise23" delta="False">
    <text>Compare it to sumo wrestling.

That's purely for vanity of who can be the best anr is certainly u healthy</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
