<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44437589716.0" user="thesweeterpeter" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength

I disagree with this point. 

Unlike just about any other sport on the planet body builders are focused on working out and emphasizing every single muscle. The have to learn and master incredibly specific feats of athleticism that a conventional athlete may never even encounter. 

That's more than vanity, that's a level of skill and precision in the training that requires great athleticism but also incredible discipline. 

Just because the work out itself isn't visible in the competition it shouldn't dimish its importance to the competition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437623565.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Working out and focusing on bulking every muscle and minimizing body fat is not optimal in terms of maximizing physical capability. Even just in terms of lifting weights, power lifters outperform bodybuilders across the board. Also, when you factor in how low body builders drop their body fat percentage and how dehydrated they get to appear the way they do, preparing for a bodybuilding competition actually makes them physically weaker.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438128904.0" user="KokonutMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Working out and focusing on bulking every muscle and minimizing body fat is not optimal in terms of maximizing physical capability

You're creating a standard that doesn't really exist. Athletes train *and damage* their body to suit the competition. 

Common knowledge would suggest having a nice meal the night before a competition, yet a wrestler may skip that meal, then breakfast, then lunch, then slap on a bunch of clothes and run to sweat off that last pound before a weigh in. This is far from optimal. But wrestling is still a well respected sport. 

On the flip side, a baseball player may forgo trying to be as fast as possible. Stealing bases is useful, but injury prevention is more important in a 160. 

Contact sport athletes risk their bodies in all sorts of ways. Combat sport athletes straight up beat the crap out of one another. 

Body builders are judged on trying to hit a desired appearance. Simply looking strong is not really part of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438184893.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;You're creating a standard that doesn't really exist. Athletes train *and damage* their body to suit the competition. 

Athletes don't intentionally lower their body fat to dangerous low levels or intentionally dehydrate themselves just for the sake of achieving an appearance 

In order to compete in the top levels of bodybuilding, you are required to take PEDs, which is also even more self-destructive 

Bodybuilding is inherently unhealthy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439014576.0" user="acdgf" delta="False">
    <text>Im going to drop a bit of knowledge for you: most competitive, and virtually every professional athlete has, at some point, abused PEDs. Often this is even done in adolescence, where testing is almost inexistent.


There are many sports that are inherently unhealthy. Weightlifting, combat sports, full contact team sports, even gymnastics. Humans evolved to run, sit and solve puzzles. Maximizing performance in any other activity is dangerous, and often times unhealthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439876198.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Sure PEDs are pretty rampant in a lot of sports, but they definitely aren't a requirement. For example look at how much the MLB cracked down on PED usage. There absolutely were MLB players on PEDs and the league basically did a witch hunt against them. I can assure the majority of MLB players today are clean. 

Most sports have drug testing to try to prevent PED usage. I'm not going to pretend that a lot of athletes don't still use PEDs and get away with it, and some leagues are certainly more lax about it than others.... but I can promise you that there are a shit ton of pro athletes who actually are clean, way more than your cynical brain wants you to believe. And even the ones who do use PEDs, it's often times for injury recovery. 

In the case of bodybuilding, PEDs are just straight up a requirement to even compete in the top levels, and it's a different level than any sport. These guys are just straight up sauching up with a ridiculous amount of gear. The entire competition completely revolves around developing these freakish unhealthy physiques that are simply not even attainable without drugs. It's a completely different deal than with sports.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440071089.0" user="TScottFitzgerald" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Athletes don't intentionally lower their body fat to dangerous low levels or intentionally dehydrate themselves just for the sake of achieving an appearance

You obviously never saw UFC fighters trying to make weight. 

This statement is just patently untrue across different sports, athletes absolutely do dangerous things to their bodies all the time, to gain a competitive advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440097916.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I have seen UFC fighters doing dangerous cuts like that, that shit is unhealthy too and MMA in general is also pretty terrible for people's health. With that said, at least MMA fighters know how to fight and defend themselves, bodybuilders are just doing it for the vanity and body dysmorphia 

But that doesn't excuse bodybuilding, you're just doing a whataboutism. My point was more so that basketball players, or swimmers, or football (soccer), or whatever aren't intentionally cutting to dangerously low body fat levels and dehydrating themselves to prepare for their games. 

The whole idea of bodybuilding is literally just cutting down to unhealthy low levels of body fat and dehydrating yourself so that you can appear as lean as humanly possible on a stage. I don't think you realize it, but when you are looking at bodybuilders on a stage these guys are basically on the verge of death. Combine that with the insane amount of gear that they all do at the higher levels, the whole thing is just completely fucked. It's really not much different than anorexia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440164471.0" user="TScottFitzgerald" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;bodybuilders are just doing it for the vanity and body dysmorphia

No they don't. Where did you get that idea? You keep repeating this throughout the thread as if it's a scientific fact. Do you have any research backing this up? I don't think you understand just how patronising and condescending this sounds, not to mention ignorant of the whole concept of bodybuilding.

It's a competitive sport like any other. It just happens to focus on aesthetics, aesthetics that can only be gained through athletic work.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;But that doesn't excuse bodybuilding, you're just doing a whataboutism. My point was more so that basketball players, or swimmers, or football

You said: "Athletes don't intentionally lower their body fat to dangerous low levels or intentionally dehydrate themselves just for the sake of achieving an appearance" and I responded with an example of athletes that do. 

That's not whataboutism, you can't just ignore examples that are inconvenient to your argument. If you have a counterpoint, I'd love to hear it. UFC fighters dehydrate themselves, and so do boxers and so do any martial artists who need to make weight. Does this make them any less athletes?

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;The whole idea of bodybuilding is literally just cutting down to unhealthy low levels of body fat and dehydrating yourself so that you can appear as lean as humanly possible on a stage

Oh boy....this is where you lose me. That's not at all what bodybuilding is. If anyone from the athletic community heard you say this, you'd be laughed out of the thread. Bodybuilders bulk way more than they cut. I.e. they focus way more on gaining weight than losing it. They dehydrate themselves for a short period of time when they're on stage because it pronounces their muscles.

It just comes across as if you couldn't do some basic Wikipedia research before firing off this post. Your whole premise seems to be based on a very misguided idea of what bodybuilding is and the worst thing is that you don't even realise how limited your knowledge of bodybuilding is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440237366.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Where did you get that idea?

Because that's literally what bodybuilding is. It's getting up on a stage and showing off how freakishly jacked you are. What is that if not vanity? 

&gt;It's a competitive sport like any other

That's completely debatable to even call it a sport. It has much more in common with runway modeling than it does with basketball or track and field. It's definitely not comparable to other sports, it's purely a competition of cosmetics.

&gt;Athletes don't intentionally lower their body fat to dangerous low levels or intentionally dehydrate themselves just for the sake of achieving an appearance" and I responded with an example of athletes that do. 

So you're just pulling an "umm ahkshually" instead of actually engaging with the conversation. Yes MMA athletes do unhealthy cuts to make weight due to the stupid technicalities of how the rules work. That doesn't really address the point though. When people are preparing to play a basketball game, they are focused on training things like endurance, strength, vertical leap, dribbling, shooting, flexibility, etc. When people are preparing for a 100m dash, they are training for speed and strength. 

When people are preparing for a bodybuilding competition, they are literally just cutting down to an unhealthy low body fat and dehydrating themselves, because that's ultimately what the competition revolves around. It's a completion about who can put on a shit ton of muscle and then minimize body fat the most and try to appear the most freakishly lean and shredded. The entire point of the competition revolves around pushing your body to an extreme appearance that is super unhealthy. How do you not see the difference?

Even with MMA, yes UFC fighters do unhealthy cuts to make weight because of how the rules are enforced (which honestly they should find a way to fix this problem), but fundamentally speaking that's not the main purpose of a fighters training camp. The primary focus of a fighters training camp is still oriented around endurance, conditioning, strength, and fighting technique. 

&gt;That's not whataboutism,

Yes it is a whataboutism. Just because competitive MMA is also extremely bad for people's health doesn't excuse competitive bodybuilding. That's just a silly argument to make. 

&gt;Bodybuilders bulk way more than they cut.

I never said otherwise, obviously they have to bulk to put on that much muscle. I'm specifically talking about how they prepare for bodybuilding shows. They literally just do an insanely unhealthy cut where the drop down to dangerously low levels of body fat and they dehydrate themselves so they can look as shredded as possible. That's literally how they prepare for bodybuilding shows.

Anyway, you don't seem to be interested in actually engaging in a conversation, your entire comment is just making a whataboutism argument, a straw man argument, and then a bunch of ad hominem attacks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440452159.0" user="TScottFitzgerald" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Anyway, you don't seem to be interested in actually engaging in a conversation, your entire comment is just making a whataboutism argument, a straw man argument, and then a bunch of ad hominem attacks. I suggest you learn how to communicate and have conversations more effectively

How ironic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44444811918.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%203%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
