<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44438959700.0" user="dulcetone" delta="False">
    <text>Having read your post and comments, I'd like to try to summarize your point.

1) Bodybuilding is potentially dangerous if taken to an extreme or competitive degree.

2) The goal physique is not universally attractive, nor does it represent the peak of physical achievement as measured in athleticism or strength.

If there are other objections, I'll consider them, but I submit to you that these points alone are not enough to consider an endeavor "stupid" as there are many other similar fields of human endeavor which are not broadly considered "stupid." You can fill in examples easily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439053076.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Competitive bodybuilding is not just "potentially" dangerous, it is inherently dangerous. Getting your body fat to those dangerously low levels and dehydrating yourself to get ready for the stage are terrible for your health 

And in order to actually compete in the top tiers of bodybuilding, heavy PED use is required

You're also ignoring the fact that the vast majority of competitive bodybuilders make very little if any money for it. It's not a lucrative "sport" whatsoever

It's a lot of negatives for very little if any benefit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439134793.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>Humans are not rational actors. You don't want this CMV shifted to any other sport, but most don't have logical benefits that outweigh their costs. Most hobbies don't. Most daily actions show that humans do not act logically. Why would that be expected of someone who participates in bodybuilding?

Humans do things largely because they do not consider the cost, or if they do, go with what they want in the moment. I can't imagine what you are expecting in response. People engage in bodybuilding for a variety of reasons. They reserve the right to make that cost analysis if they wish and ignore it as well. I don't see how you can be convinced it isn't "stupid" if you dont believe desire outweighing costs isn't enough. It just seems arbitrary to choose out of all the existing sports/hobbies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439598300.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>That's not true, most sports actually do have benefits that exceed the costs. 

Someone who is really good at basketball can get a full ride scholarship to play in college, or maybe even make it to the NBA and make millions. Even if you just play basketball for fun, it's actually a healthy activity that is good for your cardio and has pretty minimal injury risk (unless you are playing at the highest level and playing high intensity games every other night, in which case you are being well compensated financially for playing anyway).

Competitive bodybuilding on the other hand is just inherently unhealthy. Cutting down to dangerously low levels of fat and dehydrating yourself to get stage ready is horrible for your health. And if you want to compete at the higher levels of bodybuilding, you're required to take a shit ton of PEDs. 

As for your argument about desire outweighing cost, I honestly think the main driving force is more so body dysmorphia, which is a form of mental illness, or at the very least an eating disorder similar to anorexia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44441372471.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>Every form of MMA, Boxing, American Football, Hockey, Arm wrestling, Rugby (to a lesser degree), gymnastics (especially female), collegiate wrestling, powerlifting. Even esports (sitting is not good for your health)... Very few athletes make millions. Most never will. It's illogical for them to even think they can, especially without PEDa, but even then, they won't.

Bodybuilding is horrible for your health, and so is obesity, driving a vehicle for a statistically significant number of people, eating the most popular foods, drinking alcohol, using the majority of illicit drugs, smoking, gambling is entitely illogical, etc.

If someone does a sport for the small possibility of fame, they aren't more or less delusional than others for doing it. It's all around extremely unlikely.

"If you are playing for fun" - well yeah, most local gym "bodybuilders" aren't that unhealthy either. They aren't dehydrating themselves, taking very many PEDs, and actually doing cardio.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443743925.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that most people are not good enough at any sport to go pro, but most sports also don't require people to do incredibly unhealthy things to their body either, that's the point. 

&gt;Bodybuilding is horrible for your health, and so is obesity

Yeah and obesity shouldn't be encouraged either, this is just a whataboutism 

&gt;driving a vehicle for a statistically significant number of people, eating the most popular foods, drinking alcohol, using the majority of illicit drugs, smoking, gambling is entitely illogical, etc.

Yeah we shouldn't encourage people to abuse alcohol or recreational drugs either, we shouldn't encourage people to be gambling addicts. You're just making a bunch more whataboutism arguments, they are irrelevant 

&gt;most local gym "bodybuilders" aren't that unhealthy either.

Yes, they actually are incredibly unhealthy. Anybody who competes in bodybuilding and gets on stage is doing incredibly unhealthy things to their body, especially of they are on a bunch of gear 

&gt;They aren't dehydrating themselves, taking very many PEDs

Yes, they actually are. Obviously there are natural bodybuilders, but even they still cut down to dangerously low body fat and dehydrate themselves to get on stage. That's just the nature of competitive bodybuilding. The main difference between the top professionals and the people who just compete at local shows is simply just genetics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443923660.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that this is becoming off topic, but try to recognize your role in that. I didn't bring up other sports first.

The entire focus is whether it is "stupid" or not. The point is, this is a bit of a silly way to approach the topic at hand. Humans are not rational. You are attempting to apply purely logical cost-benefit to bodybuilding while applying entirely subjective beliefs to it. A cost-benefit only works if we apply the same values to those items, which humans clearly do not do.

It may not be worth it to you, but it may be worth it to me. Even if it wasn't, does it matter? Your concept behind body dismorphoa has been researched, and that would be a more objective approach to take, rather than calling sport engagement "stupid."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443959894.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I get what you are saying, but if somebody said that it was worth it for them to become an anorexic because they like being emaciated and freakishly skinny, would you encourage them to continue being an anorexic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44443989848.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>No, but I would not call that desire "stupid" either.

I don't encourage bodybuilding, nor do I encourage sport obsession/engagement beyond a hobby level. I may personally enjoy it, I won't tell others not to, but it is reasonable to recognize the costs.

If someone does that and chooses to engage anyway, they have a couple of options. Accept it as what they desire or apply a DSM-5 diagnosis to it if necessary by a medical professional.

Regardless of the outcome, i wouldn't consider it stupid. One would be a disorder that requires treatment, and one would be the choice of an individual, which does not cause direct harm to others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44444025805.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Well if you're going to devote that much time and effort into training and nutrition, then why apply that effort to competitive bodybuilding and not something that is more healthy? It seems like it defeats the purpose</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44444163212.0" user="idkmelvin" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't a logical reason that'll satisfy anyone who doesn't accept that humans do not act rationally all, or even most, of the time.

It is unlikely for one reason to be the answer. Humans don't do things for only a single reason. Humans are complex biological machines that respond to external stimuli.

Some bodybuilders likely suffer from forms of body dismorphia. Some might believe it is healthy. Some likely believe it isn't that bad for them, that they are an exception. Some like the immediate benefits and do not consider long-term consequences. Some do and just disregard them (e.g. tomorrow's problems for tomorrow's me).

Or a mix of many reasons. People do things even when they know it'll make them immediately miserable. Except, bodybuilding likely makes them feel immediately good. Whether that be due to praise, gawking, vanity, achievement, etc., all of those reasons are valid if the individual places greater weight to those than other activities.

Personal experience: I love strength sports. I cannot convince myself to engage in exercise if I do not compete to be better than others at given activity. I have allowed myself to be obese during periods where I couldn't compete. Competing isn't healthy, I am aware of that. I do personally make conscious trade-offs (body weights that force me to use a CPAP, have a hard time tying my shoes, being unable to finish during intercourse due to cardio, etc). I frequently back off if I do not like the side effects, but I know plenty of others that don't mind them as much as I might. I have shifted over time, but I distinctly remember the thought process of not caring about how long I live, if it means I can't be what I want to be.

It is not logical to be inactive, to eat poorly, to weigh much, but I don't believe my health is as affected as an average person's might be. It could be purely in my head, but it doesn't matter, I do it anyway because I believe it brings us me greater satisfaction than not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439632414.0" user="dulcetone" delta="False">
    <text>I'm aware of these things, and it is a bit rude to presume I'm not.

None of those objections are relevant to the categorical distinction you're trying to raise. You just don't like bodybuilders or bodybuilding and are trying to make a case for a categorization of "stupid" when all you can really present are reasons you don't like it or think it's right for you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439657888.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have any issues with bodybuilders as people, just as I don't have a problem with anorexic people as people. I just don't think that anorexia should be celebrated or encouraged, just like competitive bodybuilding shouldn't be celebrated or encouraged. 

Sure, at the end of the day if people want to intentionally starve themselves and put their health in jeopardy, they have that right, but let's be real most of the time it stems out of body dysmorphia, which is a sort mental illness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439711769.0" user="dulcetone" delta="False">
    <text>So your point is not, "bodybuilding is stupid," as you claim in the OP, but rather "bodybuilding is a mental illness."

Which, frankly, is an idea so ridiculous that it is impossible to talk you out of, as evidenced by the growing exasperation of many of your correspondents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439732839.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I think that competitive bodybuilding is stupid, and that a lot of the people who participate in it are motivated by body dysmorphia. I never said that bodybuilding is a mental illness, I'm saying that body dysmorphia is a mental illness, and that some people with body dysmorphia end up becoming bodybuilders. 

Your issue is that you are just making a straw man argument, you aren't accurately representing what I said, instead you are twisting my words and then calling the straw man you created "ridiculous" instead of engaging in an actual discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
