<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2705522192.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18qsqa8/cmv_bodybuilding_is_stupid/">
    <title>CMV: Bodybuilding is stupid</title>
    <original_poster>RaindropDripDropTop</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to be clear, I'm not talking about lifting weights in general, I'm specifically referring to competitive bodybuilding, especially when it involves cycling a bunch of gear (using PEDs), and getting to dangerously low body fat levels and severe dehydration to go on stage.  

I definitely recognize that competitive bodybuilders have insane levels of dedication and training. It is without doubt incredibly difficult to achieve those type of physiques, even for people with top tier genetics who use PEDs. Even the most genetically blessed and steroid enhanced bodybuilders still work insanely hard. I am not doubting their work ethic and drive. What I think is stupid about it is why do people think that this is worth it. 

For starters, it is purely for the sake of vanity rather than athleticism or strength. A bodybuilder might look absolutely insane, but functionally speaking, actual athletes who train to maximize athletic ability have way more physical capability depending on what sport they train for. Whether it's strength, speed, endurance, acceleration, vertical leap, flexibility, dexterity, or a combination of all these things, bodybuilders just aren't nearly as physically capable as actual athletes who put in similar time and effort into their training.

On the topic of vanity, bodybuilder physiques don't even look attractive or aesthetically pleasing. Obviously this is subjective, but the vast majority of the population is way more attracted to a healthy athletic physique than they are to a bodybuilder physique. I get that bodybuilding isn't really about looking attractive, rather it is about pushing the limits of what is possible with the human body, but it's honestly kind of just a freak show.

The biggest reason bodybuilding is stupid is that it is insanely unhealthy. Even for natural bodybuilders who don't use PEDs, they are still getting to dangerously low body fat levels and becoming extremely dehydrated in order to achieve their stage physique. This is incredibly taxing on the body, and it's extremely common for bodybuilders to suffer severe health issues because of this. For the ones who do use PEDs, which is basically a requirement to become a top level bodybuilder, the damage to health is even more severe, and they suffer many side effects as a result, especially ones who are not properly educated on the drugs they are taking.

One might argue that bodybuilding might be worth it for the money, but the reality is that only the top few bodybuilders in the world are making significant money through this career. The vast majority of bodybuilders, especially amateurs and people who do regional or local shows, aren't actually making much if any money through this. They also have to dedicate insane amount of time and effort into training, and if they are using gear, they are spending a ton of money on drugs. Moreover, there are similar alternatives to bodybuilding that are way more lucrative and more accessible to most people, such as becoming a fitness influencer or something (not saying that many people can break into that field either, but it's more achievable than making money through competitive bodybuilding).

The reason I am asking for my view to be changed is because I want to hear opposing perspectives, and maybe someone can shed some light on what I am missing. Like I said, I respect the work ethic and drive of bodybuilders, I just have a really hard time wrapping my head around it. I totally respect people's rights to do whatever they want with their body so long as they aren't harming others, I'm really just trying to understand the mindset of a bodybuilder, or at least understand what the appeal is.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44437483791.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>The appeal is 'I like looking this way'.

That is about it, and that's all there really needs to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437511678.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I get that, but my point is that it's not worth the cost. Even if you like looking that way, how is it worth doing that much damage to your health and putting in that much time and effort into something that is not even optimal in terms of physical capability or physical attractiveness? And for the bodybuilders who use PEDs, that comes with even more cost. 

I guess I just don't really see how the benefits come close to outweighing the costs</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437521202.0" user="kevin916" delta="False">
    <text>Isn’t this true for most sports though? Boxers, NFL players, mma etc..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437536569.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>It depends on the sport. For combat sports and other sports like American football and hockey this is certainly a topic to be debated 

I don't think it applies to every sport though, or even most sports. For example track and field, swimming, basketball, football (soccer), baseball, etc. I think damage to physical health is more specific to violent sports</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437624609.0" user="titangord" delta="False">
    <text>Its clearly worth the cost to plenty of people.. so your opinion is irrelevant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437634704.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>How is it worth the cost though? In what way do the benefits outweigh the costs ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437642701.0" user="titangord" delta="False">
    <text>Financial for one.. being in the annals of history.. etc.. woth social media you dont even have to win shows to make a shit ton of money</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437674839.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>The vast majority of bodybuilders are not making much if any money by doing it, most of them are losing money because of how much they are spending on training and drugs. I already addressed this in the OP, btw. Bodybuilding is not a lucrative field whatsoever

&gt;woth social media you dont even have to win shows to make a shit ton of money

You also don't even need to compete in the shows at all to become a fitness influencer. That's actually an argument against bodybuilding. Fitness social media is a way more lucrative field than bodybuilding, and also more accessible. You don't need to get to dangerously low body fat levels or dehydration to be a social media influencer, but you do need to do those things to compete in bodybuilding shows. You also don't need to do PEDs to be a fitness influencer, but you do need to use PEDs to become a top level bodybuilder</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437720311.0" user="titangord" delta="False">
    <text>Fitness influencers go to the same lengths to look good on social media that bodybuilders do to get on stage, if you dont think so, you dont know anything about PEDs or the fitness industry.

The vast majority of people in any profession dont make much money, the field is lucrative to a larger sect of the fitness industry than ever and ever increasing due to social media. Anyone can blow up at any time, and that makes it worth the cost to many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437986426.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Some fitness influencer do PEDs and drop to dangerously low body fat percentage, but those things are not required to be a fitness influencer.

PEDs are required to compete at the top levels of bodybuilding, and even for natty bodybuilders, they still have to get to dangerously low body fat percentage and dehydration in order to be ready to go on stage. Bodybuilding and competing on stage are inherently self-destructive and unhealthy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438005807.0" user="titangord" delta="False">
    <text>You dont understand PEDs, you think to use PEDs you need to be shredded and huge, thats not the case, you clearly dont know anything about it, yet formed an opinion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438033324.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>When did I say anything about needing to be shredded and huge to use PEDs ? You're just putting words in my mouth, I literally never said that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438236196.0" user="titangord" delta="False">
    <text>Its inferred by your description of fitness influencers.. tell me one fitness influencer that makes a ton of money and  you think doesnt take PEDs? You dont know what you are talking about.. I dont know what view you are wanting changed here, it doesnt seem like you want to learn anything about the fitness industry, you think you already know everything</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437642071.0" user="kevin916" delta="False">
    <text>Violet sports we “allow” / accept this. Even track and field is rife with injuries. To a certain extent Cheer Leading is a more dangerous sport than NFL just by counting injuries per person 

So many activities constitute as “stupid” but we accept them, why single out body building? Is it because instead of someone hitting you, it’s yourself via PED? Or in case of cheer leading instead of the floor, it’s yourself ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437715598.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Yes every sport can have injuries. Everything in life has risks, like driving a car for example. Also injuries per person is not a meaningful metric, the severity of injuries is more important, especially when it comes to long term health 

That's not really comparable to something like bodybuilding where you are intentionally doing something self destructive. 

And in the case of the NFL, for example, that's a separate discussion. You could argue that playing football is stupid, but that's not what this post is about. Although I will mention that the NFL is way more financially lucrative than bodybuilding, and even college football can at least give people access to full ride scholarships</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437946589.0" user="Drakulia5" delta="False">
    <text>Combat sport athletes cut weight like crazy and experience serious health detriments from it. The fact they suaully still come into fights dehydrated makes the risks for more severe brain trauma higher. That doesn't include the weeks and years spent making your body go through hours of physical strain and blunt impacts to train and compete. 

A big issue in the industry rn is the low pay most fighters receive despite putting in comparable effort to big draws and champs. Yet fighters still fight even ones who remain journeymen and gatekeepers. 

Costs are subjective to each person. Just because you would not find the potential risks or rewards if bodybuilding to be an acceptable balance does not mean others weigh things the same. You're going to have to understand that money isn't the end all be all fo every athletic endeavor. Lots of people do bodybuilding simply because of how they desir etc look and feel and while this can reach very unhealthy levels (as any sport, athletic endeavor, competition, or interest can) there is a wide berth wherein people can and do find deep fulfillment without completely destroying themselves. Fulfillment is not ubiquitous in how it appears for each person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438058796.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Combat sport athletes cut weight like crazy and experience serious health detriments from it

I agree. What's your point? This is a post about bodybuilding, not combat sports. You're just making a whataboutism 

If you want to also argue that combat sports are self destructive, that's certainly debatable, but it's a separate topic. 

The simple fact is that bodybuilding is self-destructive. MMA also being self-destructive doesn't mean that bodybuilding isn't 

Also, at least MMA fighters know how to fight and defend themselves. Bodybuilding is just about vanity</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438221579.0" user="TenneseeStyle" delta="False">
    <text>I hate to tell you, but just about all the examples you gave have LOADS of people using steroids and other PEDs with all the side effects and hazards that come with that. Just because you don't think they're doing damage to their health doesn't mean they aren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437683713.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Most people 'put that much time and effort into something that is not even optimal in terms of physical capability or physical attractiveness? ' so it feels weird to single out bodybuilders. Especially since you are not the arbiter of what is physically attractive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438000309.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>They are putting that much time and effort into something that is self-destructive and incredibly unhealthy, that's the point 

I also never said I am the arbiter of what is attractive, I'm saying the vast majority of the population find healthy athletic physiques more attractive than body builder physiques</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438134338.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty of people put time and effort into things that aren't healthy. It's kind of how humans work; most people need a break from 'healthy' stuff. Most hobbies aren't the healthiest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438169287.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Ok but if someone's hobby is lifting weights and training, they should focus on a healthy athletic physique, and not an unhealthy bodybuilder physique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437865937.0" user="1kSupport" delta="False">
    <text>“Worth” is subjective.

Your issue here is that while it isn’t worth the cost for you it could be for others.

For an extreme imagine a case in which someone is on the verge of suicide and finds meaning in bodybuilding. Obviously in this case the bodybuilding would be “worth it” to this individual.

Everyone’s life goals are different</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44437957591.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, worth is subjective, but practically speaking you can determine this by doing a basic cost benefit analysis 

Bodybuilding is extremely self-destructive, it's not a very lucrative field at all, and the only benefit is something that is just pure vanity (which I might add is not even attractive to the vast majority of people, so it even fails at vanity in a way)

&gt;Everyone’s life goals are different

And if someone's life goals are self destructive, that is a problem</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438003775.0" user="1kSupport" delta="False">
    <text>I know plenty of people in the sport who find it deeply fulfilling. It helped their mental health. I have one friend who probably would be dead if it weren’t for competitive bodybuilding. Yeah gear is unhealthy for him but it’s more healthy than suicide. Again CBA is situational as costs and benefits very by person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438040784.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Instead of bodybuilding they would be way better off instead focus on developing a healthy athletic physique. It would have the same positive impacts.om their mental health without destroying their body</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438520482.0" user="SpoonyDinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Define "destroying their body."

PEDS are leagues stronger than they were in the early 1980s, it's why if you compare the elite bodybuilder of that time, to those today, they are like completely different humans.

Take Arnold Schwarzenegger versus Ronnie Coleman. They're both top tier bodybuilders pushing themselves to the max, the only difference being that the drugs are **much** stronger. It's why Arnold was probably 100 lbs lighter during the contest versus Ronnie.

Both pushed their bodies to the limit, train for hours a day, the *only* difference is that PEDs are much much stronger.

I'll agree that *today's* bodybuilders aren't "attractive" but you'd likely find few women who thought Arnold was nothing less than a god. (He was notorious for being a Playboy; literally an icon to men)

I've been a bodybuilder over 15 years, and it's about pushing your body to the limits and beyond. Yes when you introduce PEDs they can harm organs, excess weights can hurt joints, etc.

However I'd argue that the extreme dedication required in your diet, training, etc is better than someone who is completely sedentary.

Arnold is 76 years old, most men his age look like walking corpses, he looks like he could punch a hole through a brick wall.

I think the "sport" aspect is "stupid;" dehydrating and cutting carbs a week before a comp, but all the time between that is better than sitting on your ass doing nothing or just occasionally picking up some weights.

As you age your bones, muscles, and overall health deteriorate; bodybuilding effectively slows that. It's the closest you'll get to the fountain of youth.

I'm closer to 40 than 30 and I have more endurance, less pain, sleep better and look 10x better than I did in my 20s. While I'm natural, (outside of supplements) I train and eat very similar to a pro.

I guess I'm conflicted as I see your point. Those that are rocking tren year round are doing damage, I just don't know if you can make an argument that that's worse than no activity or even casual activity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439291585.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I think you make a lot of good points and it's good to hear from someone who is actually a bodybuilder and is so knowledgeable about this subject. 

Cutting down to dangerously low body fat and dehydrating yourself to get ready for a stage absolutely is unhealthy, it's not a coincidence that so many bodybuilders suffer from major health issues when they get older. 

I'm sure you can be a fully natural bodybuilder who doesn't do dangerous cuts, but the reality is you most likely won't be able to compete at the top levels if you don't. That's what it takes get to the ridiculous physiques that the top bodybuilders have. 

Also, instead of bodybuilding you'd be way better off focusing on cardio and trying get a healthy and athletic physique, rather than just going for the most jacked looking body possibly. I definitely don't agree that bodybuilding is a "fountain of youth" either, again, it's not a coincidence so many competitive body builders end up having so many health issues

And rocking tren year round absolutely is worse than someone who just has a casual exercise routine and a healthy diet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44445090138.0" user="SpoonyDinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>I probably can't change your view as I largely agree that the "pro/sport" elements are not healthy; doing *anything* to extreme excess is harmful. It's like comparing average marathon runners to ultra runners. (These folks do 50-100 miles) It's *extremely* hard on your body no matter how you spin it to compete in those races.

However I guess I'll leave it at this. Just like ultra runners, pro bodybuilders are only putting themselves in these conditions for a few times of the year. Yes using insulin, dehydrating and cycling is dangerous, but most pro bodybuilders aren't rocking PEDs year round, are getting their blood levels tested regularly and doing everything they can to mitigate long term damage. So while *many* have chronic issues later in life, many do not. (again look at Arnold, Jay Cutler, etc)

Similarly, ultra runners usually train year round but will only do those extreme races once every few years.

You're correct, even "natural" bodybuilders are putting themselves at risk but it's typically a month out from a comp; the rest of the time they are "simply" training extremely hard and dialing their diet to a perfection.

Like while I don't compete, I sit around ~9-10bf year round; achieving less than that is **extremely** difficult. (Usually massive carb limiting and excessive cardio)

It's hard to argue if something is "stupid" as that's a bit subjective. Is it stupid to want to be one of the best in the world at something? Training/eating well regularly may be just as beneficial from a health perspective, but then that's no longer impressive.

I do think the sport is silly, but I understand those who want to push their bodies past what's normally possible.

It's almost like saying "The World's Strongest Man" is stupid; they're lifting and conditioning way past excess, there's little "benefit" other than the chance to be considered the strongest in the world... But that's the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439104869.0" user="PrivilegedPatriarchy" delta="False">
    <text>Bodybuilding involves a certain level of dedication and regimented training, nutrition, and recovery that almost no other sport even approaches. Top level bodybuilders don’t have days off, almost every single one of their meals are intentional and planned. It provides an immensely structured lifestyle that many people find stabilizing to the rest of their life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439630182.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I already said that in the OP. You should read the post before responding because you're talking about things I've already addressed. I'm not saying they don't work hard, they definitely do have insane dedication and work ethic, it's not easy to achieve those physiques. My point is that it's not worth it for all the reasons I outlined. Competitive bodybuilding is incredibly unhealthy and self destructive, it's purely an exercise in vanity, and it's also not very financially lucrative at all. The costs far outweigh the benefits. 

And you can have that same kind of regimented lifestyle and hardcore training and nutrition without destroying your health through competitive bodybuilding. You're way better off trying to build a healthy athletic physique, rather than an unhealthy bodybuilder physique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438074428.0" user="NoCrust101" delta="False">
    <text>There is not much cons if you think about it.
Reduced life span ? Not everyone wants to live til 100 and be miserable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438126744.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that is extremely unhealthy and self-destructive towards your body is a pretty huge con</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438165542.0" user="NoCrust101" delta="False">
    <text>Not rly, if you do it right. You can recover your testosterone levels within months</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438256592.0" user="Deep_Space_Cowboy" delta="False">
    <text>Like others have said, your opinion isn't wrong; it means you aren't interested in body building. 

Every sport has costs. Most sports aren't healthy, because they require extreme lifestyles. Most sports also involve PED usage. 

Every sport would be better if we could control what an athlete does with their body, but we can't yet. Testing is always outpaced by methods of doping.

Humans are obviously a biological system, which naturally isn't optimised "out of the womb." A lot of science and medicine is dedicated to working this stuff out, and defining 1) what is the healthiest for a human, and 2) what is most optimal (performance) for a human. 

One day, we can get these to intersect, and maybe it will reduce all competition to skill and negate differences in health and fitness, and that will be a peculiar world.

For the time being, some people are going to abuse steroids and get as jacked and tan as possible.

Is it worth it? Well, yeah, to them it is, isn't it? They might change their mine one day and realise they would've preferred a different life, but such is the way of things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439093519.0" user="PrivilegedPatriarchy" delta="False">
    <text>It may not be worth it *for you*, but clearly there are tons of people out there who do find it valuable enough to sacrifice their health and well-being for it. Yeah, you’re not athletic, you’re not attractive, you’re not healthy, but who cares? If someone deems it “worth it” to sacrifice these things for bigger muscles, how can anyone say that they’re wrong about a personal value judgement?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439641632.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>But why would somebody deem it worth it to sacrifice all those things just to look freakishly jacked? I honestly think the vast majority of them are people with body dysmorphia, and it shouldn't necessarily be encouraged. I don't really see how it's much different than people who are anorexic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439657643.0" user="PrivilegedPatriarchy" delta="False">
    <text>It may be the case that mental health issues like body dysmorphia run rampant amongst bodybuilders (it’s probably relatively commonplace) but a personal value judgment is not something you can argue against. It is entirely a subjective assessment. If someone truly values being “freakishly jacked”, or they value the competitive process (this is probably more common tbh, bodybuilders tend to be very competitive in my experience), then it simply is the case that they value these things heavily. To flip the subreddit on its head: could you change the view of a bodybuilder who says “yeah I highly value being freakishly jacked/being the best bodybuilder I can, enough to outweigh the sacrifices”? What would you say to such a person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439717813.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree with you that subjective value judgments can't be argued. They absolutely can be discussed and I'm open to having my mind changed. I just need to see valid reasons. 

So far out of this entire thread, the only person to change my view was someone who actually is a body builder themselves and their argument is that some people view bodybuilding as an art and that people are making these sacrifices for the sake of making art. I thought that was a good point.

My only hesitation with that idea is that I don't really buy that bodybuilding has any real artistic merit to it compared to a great painting or symphony, for example.

&gt;To flip the subreddit on its head: could you change the view of a bodybuilder who says “yeah I highly value being freakishly jacked/being the best bodybuilder I can, enough to outweigh the sacrifices”? What would you say to such a person?

I would assume that person probably has body dysmorphia and body image issues.

That would be similar if someone said they valued being emaciated and freakishly thin more than they value their health. I don't think we should then encourage that person to continue on with being anorexic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438109208.0" user="dulcetone" delta="False">
    <text>Amen! How about some body positivity for the gym rats?? There are people out there who would be hopelessly lost and depressed without the structure of a regular gym and diet habit. Have some compassion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438435982.0" user="No_Scarcity8249" delta="False">
    <text>Should we be positive when improper are actually endangering their health? We may as well celebrate anorexics for how skinny they are. Honestly should we not be addressing this as a disorder?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44438672234.0" user="dulcetone" delta="False">
    <text>Some bodybuilders need interventions, so do not. Just like the rest of us.

We all agree exercising is healthy. Some people obsess over it and potentially damage their health.

I don't think there's any field of human endeavor where a certain few will not obsess over it to their own personal detriment. Are we going to start "addressing" writers or musicians who obsess over their craft or profession to the degradation of their mental and physical health? Businessmen? Teachers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439794050.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not talking about people who just exercise, I'm talking about competitive bodybuilders who actually compete on the stage. 

In order to compete in bodybuilding shows they basically just cut to dangerously low levels of fat and dehydrate themselves. And to compete at the top levels of bodybuilding, you are required to do a ton of PEDs. All of it is extremely unhealthy and self destructive, it shouldn't be celebrated or encouraged, just like anorexia shouldn't be celebrated or encouraged.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440452251.0" user="Illustrious_Ring_517" delta="False">
    <text>You say that but are we not pushing fat acceptance when it is also unhealthy?!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44439780391.0" user="RaindropDripDropTop" delta="False">
    <text>This post has nothing against gym rats who just like to lift weights.

I'm specifically talking about competitive bodybuilding which is a different thing entirely. The types of cutting and dehydrating they do to get ready for the stage is insanely unhealthy. 

And let me ask you, do you apply your body positivity philosophy as an excuse to encourage people who have anorexia to continue being anorexic? 

Competitive bodybuilding is basically just another form of anorexia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44442547862.0" user="Automatic-Sport-6253" delta="False">
    <text>We have body positivity movement for people on a heavier side but there's no serious competitions for obese people where they are incentivized to get as fat as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44440051615.0" user="TScottFitzgerald" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what drives competitive bodybuilders, they're athletes like any other athlete.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
