<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2709266638.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18t0zim/cmv_gaza_could_be_free_if_hamas_would_stop/">
    <title>CMV: Gaza could be free if Hamas would stop attacking Israel</title>
    <original_poster>Ok_Contribution_6321</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not trying to debate the whole Israel-Palestine conflict but just a small part and I'm very open to changing my view. My thought process is:

* Israel is not trying to settle/colonize/etc Gaza - quite the opposite given that they pulled out and removed settlers in 2005
* The blockade, border wall, and bombings are a response to attacks by Hamas (even if you consider them disproportional)
* Without giving up its territorial claims for all of Israel, Hamas could truly disarm, stop firing rockets and building tunnels, renounce genocidal claims, etc, and instead focus on putting all the aid money toward the people of Gaza
* If they did that in a verifiable way, Israel would have no justification for the blockade or attacks and Gazans could live in peace rather than an "open air prison" as some like to say

tldr; Gaza could have peace and prosperity if Hamas would stop attacking Israel. This would be without renouncing their territorial claims over all of Israel.

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44460828906.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>Would it be equally true to say Israel could stop what they're doing and free Gaza?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460866890.0" user="ManufacturerSea7907" delta="False">
    <text>Israel is freeing Gaza by destroying Hamas</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460890416.0" user="Fby54" delta="False">
    <text>Israel has killed 10 civilians for every 1 fighter amounting to 22,000 civilians killed, 70 journalists, and over 60% of Gaza leveled. What this is doing is making every child who looses their parents, every parent who looses their children, in a bombing raid on a refugee camp or hospital, into a Hamas fighter because in their eyes, Israel has kept them in a Ghetto and then murdered their whole family. Of course they will join Hamas. The same happened to the Americans in Iraq and Afghanistan as well as in Vietnam.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460915309.0" user="ManufacturerSea7907" delta="False">
    <text>Source on those #’s? Israel claims ~7k fighters, Hamas claims ~21k total people. So 14k civilians, 7k fighters, 2:1 ratio. That would be the same as WW2 (which was easier since the Nazis fought in the open field instead of hiding behind civilians). 

Obviously these numbers could be higher, but even a 4:1 or 5:1 ratio would be pretty average for this kind of war.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460949484.0" user="Fby54" delta="False">
    <text>By the population in Gaza and the number of people killed, the best possible ratio is 7:1 if we assume every man that has been killed is a fighter. Israel has also killed Israeli hostages believing them to be Palestinians wearing hijabs so are we really going to take their kill count at face value?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461014294.0" user="ManufacturerSea7907" delta="False">
    <text>Are we going to take Hamas’ number at face value? I think you are also doing your math wrong. 

The PA health ministry said on Tuesday about 70% of Gaza's dead were women and children under 18, but it has released no breakdown of age categories since its Oct. 26 report.

If we take numbers from Hamas at face value, say that this demographic has continued since oct 26, assuming males are Hamas (for clarification on your point), it would be a CCR ratio of 3.5:1.5 . This is between 2:1 and 3:1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460987011.0" user="20000lumes" delta="False">
    <text>So far the count is 2 civilians for every terrorist killed when the us killed 3 in iraq and Afghanistan which both weren’t as urban or dense unlike palestine and Vietnam. Vietnam had around 2 million civilian casualties according to their authorities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460995441.0" user="Fby54" delta="False">
    <text>All the same for every child you kill their father hates the occupation that much more</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460883583.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>No.

1. Israel is not the only entity blockading Gaza. Egypt is also blockading Gaza, because of Hamas.

2. Palestine / Gaza / Palestinians wouldn't be *free* if Hamas remains in power. They're an autocratic military junta that deprives Palestinians under their control of basic human rights. 

3. Hamas has committed to destroying the state of Israel and driving the Jews out of the territory that they conquer. Israel "freeing" Gaza doesn't stop this warmongering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461344070.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>It’s essentially all Israel blocking Gaza. Rafah crossing, while “owned” by Egypt is still controlled by Israel with Israel having control of approving or disapproving what imports can go through.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460929708.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't believe so. Hamas would not stop attacking Israel unless it ceased to exist. What does "free Gaza" mean to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460959749.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>Well what do you mean by free Gaza when you say it could be achieved if Hamas stopped attacking?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461021504.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>I mean Gaza could be free of the blockade, have free trade, no restrictions on travel, and not have these reprisal bombings. These are Israeli (and Egyptian) responses to Hamas attacks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461046522.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>Was Palestine free from apartheid before Hamas took power?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461060865.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure how you define apartheid but the answer is very clearly yes.

Israel pulled completely out of Gaza in 2005. They had complete control to do nearly anything they wanted</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461106329.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>I dated a Palestinian. There has been no liberty or freedom for a Palestinian for many decades.

Israel can't pull out of Palestinian lands; they were gifted Palestinian land by the west. Look at the size of Israel from 1950 - present. There is zero justification for what they've done, I don't care what holy scriptures say, its no justification. 

It's fucking genocide, and it's deplorable hearing people justify it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461125383.0" user="ilikebooty345" delta="False">
    <text>They shouldn't have fucked around in 1947, Israel could be a lot larger if they didn't give land back after winning a defensive war</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461140672.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>Israel has been gifted everything they have, they'd have nothing on their own. I still don't get all this hate, can everyone fucking grow up</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461204174.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>So has Israel gotten bigger after winning wars or did it just get gifted that territory for some reason coincidentally at the same time it militarily defeated other powers?

Every expansion has been Israel’s own doing, but none of it would have happened if they were not first threatened or directly attacked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461250466.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>Israel has been given billions by the west, and armed to the teeth. Yes, Israel killed those people themselves,  hoorah! With weapons and money from the west. Israel has continued to push and take land from Palestinian people illegally ever since. Is every provocation going to go without someone angrily throwing a rock in defiance? No. None of their expansion has been through defence. I'll say it again, #none of their expansion was defensive 

Why do you support Israel so much? I do not support Hammas, most Palestinians now do not. But cage someone, and they'll make drastic choices</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461408275.0" user="ilikebooty345" delta="False">
    <text>Yes they're armed to the teeth because they keep getting attacked by their neighbors. We will support our western ally despite propaganda when evidence shows again and again they are not the aggressor. The real issue is the neighboring countries want to walk in and capitulate Israel while they have nothing and the West won't let that happen. Ceasefires have been declined by both Israel and Hamas with the only real two state solutions being proposed by Israel, Palestine has and forever wants the dissolution of Israel which we will not let happen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461585366.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't answer my question. Their illegal capture of land is not defensive 

Palestinian people have been confined to a tiny small space of land. They can not freely move around. People are not allowed to share the same space equally. They have been brutally treated for many, many years now. It has been an apartheid for ages! Pull back the wool, dude

Yes, there's a lot of conflict there in that part of the world over religion; Israel is heavily backed by the US for that reason too.

Israel has never wanted or favoured a two state solution, and it's clear now what their stance is towards that notion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461680835.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>Every single thing you wrote in your second sentence applies to Israel when you look at the wider Arab world.

Israel just took the liberal democracy approach, and didn’t needlessly go for revenge after wars ended.

And now Israel is the most powerful nation in the region.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461701595.0" user="ilikebooty345" delta="False">
    <text>There wasn't a question you're refusing to acknowledge that Israel was attacked, won, and gave the lands back. You want everyone to overlook all transgressions against Israel and hyper focus on the ones they've committed because you don't think it's fair Israel gets to have weapons from the west and you can't eradicate them. Israel also literally asked for a permanent ceasefire with a two state solution last week that Hamas rejected. Because unlike Israel, Palestine doesn't want peace they just want Israelis gone so they can go and eradicate the next group of people they believe transgressed them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461720504.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>Fuck bro, you're too far gone to talk with

I have no idea where you get your info from, but at this point I'm discussing fiction with you.

Try looking at info not from YouTube or your biased new station, go straight to some real sources. Laterz</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461727708.0" user="ilikebooty345" delta="False">
    <text>Bro doesn't like the facts so walks away typical Hamas supporter 😂</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461754172.0" user="roodeeMental" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure I know how to speak potato well enough for us to converse. Pray I get a lobotomy so that I can understand your alternative facts</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461277470.0" user="ilikebooty345" delta="False">
    <text>Okay so we should give all the land back to the British since they initially owned it to be gifted</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461112466.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>So you think from 1948-2004 Israel recognized Gaza as part of a free state with sovereignty and the right to UN recognition?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461175358.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>Who do you think controlled Gaza from 1948-1967?

What would Gaza have been under the original partition plan in 1947?

Why did Israel pull out in 2005?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461252020.0" user="jimmytaco6" delta="False">
    <text>None of these are relevant to the question I asked you. You said that, without Hamas attacking Israel, Gaza would be free. Hamas took power in Gaza in 2005. Was Gaza free in 2004?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460959138.0" user="20000lumes" delta="False">
    <text>Hamas wouldn’t stop attacking Israel if Israel wasn’t attacking them otherwise there would’ve been no October 7</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460971461.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>October 7th happened because a lot of Palestinian men and boys are sexual predators and pedophiles and this gave them a chance to rape Israeli girls.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460984804.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think they are that way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460992526.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>Why is Harvey Weinstein the way he is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461009869.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>You think the answers to those questions are the same?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461014672.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>yes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461105150.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>So what do you think the answer is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461119303.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>Some people are sociopaths. We don't really know why. Probably some combination of genetics, bad parenting, and possibly being sexually abused as kids themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461137077.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>So would it be equally true to say that about all people, instead of specifically Palestinians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461145631.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>The OP is about Gaza. Think this is starting to get off topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461185781.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>You seemed to think that the terror attack was because Palestinians wanted to commit rape. So I'm curious if you think is true about them to a different extent to everyone else. Because this sounds like an argument that there's some genetic or cultural factor that makes them different from everyone else. Otherwise the question is why it happened here and now and not elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461239119.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>Most schools and parents in the West are going to teach their boys about consent. Gazan parents and schools don't teach their boys about consent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461156487.0" user="crispy1989" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it's a general principle that understanding the origins of a behavior do not change the present reality of that behavior.  E.g. we can understand that a serial killer was abused as a child; but that doesn't change the fact that they're a serial killer and need to be dealt with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461202706.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>And how do you deal with them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461238174.0" user="crispy1989" delta="False">
    <text>In the case of the serial killer analogy?  Prevent them from doing further harm by removing them from society.

In the case of entire broken society, like Imperial Japan, terrorist Palestine, Nazi Germany; historically, this has required massive aid, rebuilding, and deradicalization campaigns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461291675.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, understanding why something happens isn't necesserily a justification. But understanding why it happens can inform what we do about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461778562.0" user="Leirnis" delta="False">
    <text>Very civil and meaningful exchange between the two of you, I enjoyed it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461080235.0" user="20000lumes" delta="False">
    <text>it was more about murder than rape</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461427258.0" user="ResponsibilityAny358" delta="False">
    <text>This is pure Islamophobia, just as what the extreme right does by calling Jews pedophiles, using famous Jews or the laws of Israel as an example, is anti-Semitism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461436877.0" user="Miserable_Amoeba7217" delta="False">
    <text>It's not Islamophobia. If there weren't a lot pedophiles living in Gaza, October 7th never would have happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461494570.0" user="ResponsibilityAny358" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/how-jewish-american-pedophiles-hide-from-justice-in-israel/

https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/israel-safe-haven-paedophiles-jerusalem-sex-abuse-jewish-community-watch-a7445246.html

This is widely publicized by people on the extreme right, again, it is dangerous to use this rhetoric that cannot be private, because it will spread to everyone, including this coming before the war.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461067437.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>In what way was Israel attacking Gaza?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461160937.0" user="20000lumes" delta="False">
    <text>they attacked a few launch spots for palestine shooting rockets at civilians before October 7 but there wasn’t anything as large as the war beforehand unless you count the war of 1967</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461011623.0" user="Bai_Cha" delta="False">
    <text>No, unfortunately that can't work. The restrictions on Gaza are aimed at stopping terrorists from moving freely from Gaza to Israel. This comes from many decades of experience and experimenting, and Hamas has outright said that they do not plan to stop terrorist attacks until Israel is completely eliminated. 

Israel cannot allow free movement without putting its citizens at risk of terrorist attacks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461115366.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Israel cannot allow free movement without putting its citizens at risk of terrorist attacks.

And that's worse than the current situation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461156295.0" user="Bai_Cha" delta="False">
    <text>Israel got complacent with their border security, and ignored multiple warning signs. But allowing free movement would make it infinitely harder. They won't be ignoring intelligence again any time soon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461219462.0" user="One-Organization970" delta="False">
    <text>You understand that raising generations of people under prison rules will never cause them to view you as anything other than an existential, evil enemy? What's the endgame here? How does this strategy eliminate extremism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461273156.0" user="Bai_Cha" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I understand that, as does everyone involved in making these decisions. But there is no world in which Israel is going to open itself up to more terrorist attacks for a generation. That's simply not going to happen. No matter what anyone thinks about the situation, that is the one possible "solution" that will never happen. If you were a completely rational and compassionate Israeli citizen, this would not be something that you would be in favor of. 

There are a few possible outcomes - some better than others. But Israel allowing free movement around Gaza is not one of those possible outcomes.

In my mind, probably the best possible outcome would be an international organization administering Gaza for a period of time. This would likely turn out like the US in Afghanistan (i.e., would likely fail), but it's at least something that could be attempted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461324938.0" user="One-Organization970" delta="False">
    <text>They said the same things about South Africa under apartheid. At a certain point, you have to stop talking about Israel like they are this unstoppable force of nature which cannot be dissuaded from its path. They do what they do because they're able to hide behind the United States. Our government's refusal to even lightly tug the leash is going to be viewed very unfavorably by history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461372571.0" user="Bai_Cha" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that in South Africa, the leaders of the  opposition party weren't publicly promising to commit terrorist attacks if they were allowed freedom of movement.

The Israel/Palestine situation is not similar in meaningful way to South Africa. Israel really, really wants Gaza to be independently governed. The problem is that the leaders there have made their intentions clear, including about what they intend to do with more freedom of movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461387908.0" user="One-Organization970" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that the West Bank puts the lie to this whole concept. The "freedom" enjoyed by the Palestinians not living under Hamas is still designed to engender permanent hatred for their occupiers. Like, I'm gonna be honest dude - nobody will cry tears of joy to live under West Bank conditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461507567.0" user="Bai_Cha" delta="False">
    <text>It would be amazing to separate the West Bank from Gaza. Both the Israel government and the PA hold responsibility here.

Israel's continued colonization of the West Bank is inexcusable. The US should (and should have for a long time) been much more strict about this. But the PA also has to be willing to decouple the Gaza and West Bank conversations, which so far they have not been willing to do. I completely agree that this is a much more complicated situation with significantly more blame on Israel. 

This does not change the fact that Israel has no feasible path to allowing freedom of movement in Gaza though. Just to be clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461214704.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>Its simply not Israel's job to protect foreign citizens above its own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461238052.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>So how many foreign lives should one citizen's be worth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461694548.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever the citizens of the democracy have decided.

And Israelis understandably value the suicide bombers significantly less than their fellow Israelis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461780311.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>So a country could vote to value the lives of anyone who wasn’t a citizen at 0?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44462514803.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think the point of a country is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44465583665.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>If the point of a country is to define who it’s okay  to kill then maybe countries are a bad idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44467877611.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>Stop assuming what you think I think the point of a country is and answer the question, because you obviously haven't considered it before.

Why do people form countries?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44467896556.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;because you obviously haven't considered it before.

What makes you think I haven't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44467923332.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>Because your answer is either not in line with the rest of your position or wrong.

So what is your answer?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44467977683.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't answered yet. I was responding to the implication the point of a country was to assign people outside of the country less value. I'm not saying that is the reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44468189490.0" user="SeparateNewspaper810" delta="False">
    <text>Answer the question in your next response or I won’t be responding again.

What is the purpose of a country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44468249775.0" user="Vesurel" delta="False">
    <text>Then I'm happy to conclude here. Thanks for your time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
