<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2709266638.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18t0zim/cmv_gaza_could_be_free_if_hamas_would_stop/">
    <title>CMV: Gaza could be free if Hamas would stop attacking Israel</title>
    <original_poster>Ok_Contribution_6321</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not trying to debate the whole Israel-Palestine conflict but just a small part and I'm very open to changing my view. My thought process is:

* Israel is not trying to settle/colonize/etc Gaza - quite the opposite given that they pulled out and removed settlers in 2005
* The blockade, border wall, and bombings are a response to attacks by Hamas (even if you consider them disproportional)
* Without giving up its territorial claims for all of Israel, Hamas could truly disarm, stop firing rockets and building tunnels, renounce genocidal claims, etc, and instead focus on putting all the aid money toward the people of Gaza
* If they did that in a verifiable way, Israel would have no justification for the blockade or attacks and Gazans could live in peace rather than an "open air prison" as some like to say

tldr; Gaza could have peace and prosperity if Hamas would stop attacking Israel. This would be without renouncing their territorial claims over all of Israel.

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44460830784.0" user="GoSouthCourt" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know, Bibi is pretty clear that he wants all of Hamas dead. He wouldn't accept a Gaza run by Hamas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460995262.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's hard to blame him given that Hamas doesn't seem to be willing to stop attacks. I think it's fair to say that Hamas attacks are aggressive in nature and Israeli attacks are reprisal, i.e. Hamas is randomly firing missiles at Israel and Israel is reacting (or maybe overreacting).

&gt;Also, Hamas is not claiming all of Israel, they recognize the Green Line.

That's rather hard to believe given all of their previous statements. So they're willing to accept a two-state solution now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461016409.0" user="GoSouthCourt" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. It's in their [2017 charter](https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/hamas-2017-document-full) to recognise the Green Line as the border of Palestine. 

&gt;Hamas considers the establishment of a fully sovereign and independent Palestinian state, with Jerusalem as its capital along the lines of the 4th of June 1967, with the return of the refugees and the displaced to their homes from which they were expelled, to be a formula of national consensus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461046179.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>It also doesn't recognize Israel's right to exist as a state so it's hard to view it as a two-state solution.

Based on Hamas's actions it certainly doesn't seem they are looking for a peaceful two-state solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461058026.0" user="GoSouthCourt" delta="False">
    <text>But they are not claiming all of Israel. That part remains true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461129534.0" user="Ok_Contribution_6321" delta="False">
    <text>So basically, the true part is they are not publicly claiming all of Israel/Palestine but they're also not not saying Israel should be destroyed?

Fair enough though their past and recent actions and statements suggest genocidal intent towards Jews/Israel so it'd be hard to blame anyone for simply seeing it as a PR stunt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461157706.0" user="GoSouthCourt" delta="False">
    <text>Based on their charter, I believe what they are saying is that Israel should not be ruled by Zionist, because they see Zionists as the real enemy. They have very limited mention of the word "Israel", so what that means practically I do not know.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
