<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2709266638.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18t0zim/cmv_gaza_could_be_free_if_hamas_would_stop/">
    <title>CMV: Gaza could be free if Hamas would stop attacking Israel</title>
    <original_poster>Ok_Contribution_6321</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not trying to debate the whole Israel-Palestine conflict but just a small part and I'm very open to changing my view. My thought process is:

* Israel is not trying to settle/colonize/etc Gaza - quite the opposite given that they pulled out and removed settlers in 2005
* The blockade, border wall, and bombings are a response to attacks by Hamas (even if you consider them disproportional)
* Without giving up its territorial claims for all of Israel, Hamas could truly disarm, stop firing rockets and building tunnels, renounce genocidal claims, etc, and instead focus on putting all the aid money toward the people of Gaza
* If they did that in a verifiable way, Israel would have no justification for the blockade or attacks and Gazans could live in peace rather than an "open air prison" as some like to say

tldr; Gaza could have peace and prosperity if Hamas would stop attacking Israel. This would be without renouncing their territorial claims over all of Israel.

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44462587136.0" user="nyce06" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to give you the benefit of the doubt that you are coming from a place of genuine curiosity. I'm typing from my phone so I apologize for not including sources in advance, but am happy to provide for each point later when I'm at a computer if needed.

My immediate rebuttal is that Israel's past and current simultaneous hostilities to the residents of the West Bank reflect that the common denominator isn't Hamas, but the Israeli government policy of state supported colonization. What does what happens in the West Bank have to do with the current situation in Gaza: Hamas has no authority in the West Bank and yet still experiences many of the same issues due to Israeli government policy. Freedoms in Gaza and the West Bank have been systematically taken away decades before Hamas came into existence and may continue to be taken away even if  Hamas disappeared tomorrow, because at the heart of the matter the Israeli government policy is that Palestinians do not deserve freedom.

It is a policy choice to detain Palestinian civilians indefinitely without charge and to try those who are charged in military court with a 99% conviction rate despite evidence proving the defendants claims of innocence. At the same time, while settler activities are still technically illegal and rogue IDF soldier abuse civilias on a frequent basis, those same settlers/soldiers often get tried in civilian court and despite evidence proving their actions they are rarely punished. 

It is a policy choice to destroy homes, civilian infrastructure, agriculture, places of worship, cultural landmarks, and more. It is a policy decision to kill journalists, aid workers, doctors, hostages and more without having to answer for those deaths. 

It is policy choice to create a system of checkpoints and barriers that forces Gazans to think about every step they take because crossing a sidewalk or turning at the wrong corner could lead to imprisonment or worse death. It is also a policy to criminalize freedoms many of us take for granted such as eating chocolate, collecting rainwater, foraging, and even publicly celebrating when family members are released from prison.

What Hamas did on Oct 7th was horrible and I will not attempt to justify it, but it was policy to receive intelligence in advance of the attack and to not act on it. It is policy to inflict disproportionate punishment ever since causing many Gazans who were already previously displaced in the first place to be displaced yet again while they are dealing with famine, disease, and constant bombardment for nearly 3 months. It is policy to dehumanize Gazans and Palestinians around the world so that people who have never thought of them before Oct 7th question whether they deserve freedom at all.

So in closing to your original question - no, even if Hamas stopped attacking and even disappeared from the world, Gazans would not be free because it is the Israeli government's policy that they do not deserve freedom.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
