<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2709266638.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18t0zim/cmv_gaza_could_be_free_if_hamas_would_stop/">
    <title>CMV: Gaza could be free if Hamas would stop attacking Israel</title>
    <original_poster>Ok_Contribution_6321</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not trying to debate the whole Israel-Palestine conflict but just a small part and I'm very open to changing my view. My thought process is:

* Israel is not trying to settle/colonize/etc Gaza - quite the opposite given that they pulled out and removed settlers in 2005
* The blockade, border wall, and bombings are a response to attacks by Hamas (even if you consider them disproportional)
* Without giving up its territorial claims for all of Israel, Hamas could truly disarm, stop firing rockets and building tunnels, renounce genocidal claims, etc, and instead focus on putting all the aid money toward the people of Gaza
* If they did that in a verifiable way, Israel would have no justification for the blockade or attacks and Gazans could live in peace rather than an "open air prison" as some like to say

tldr; Gaza could have peace and prosperity if Hamas would stop attacking Israel. This would be without renouncing their territorial claims over all of Israel.

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44461157182.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>They removed roughly 9,000 illegal settlers from Gaza in 2005. In that same year there were roughly 250,000 illegal settlers in the West Bank, 180,000 in East Jerusalem, and around 18,000 in the Golan heights totaling around 460,000 settlers. 

In the West Bank alone as of 2022, there were over 490,000 settlers. This represents more than the entirety of settlers from 2005 just in the West Bank which has nearly doubled. 

Pulling out of Gaza didn’t end their illegal settlements which have only grown year after year after year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461184279.0" user="Vegasgiants" delta="False">
    <text>There are no illegal settlements.  Only Israeli law applies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461217921.0" user="FerdinandTheGiant" delta="False">
    <text>The vast majority of the international community disagrees with your conclusion, though I am sure you are aware of that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
