<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2709266638.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18t0zim/cmv_gaza_could_be_free_if_hamas_would_stop/">
    <title>CMV: Gaza could be free if Hamas would stop attacking Israel</title>
    <original_poster>Ok_Contribution_6321</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not trying to debate the whole Israel-Palestine conflict but just a small part and I'm very open to changing my view. My thought process is:

* Israel is not trying to settle/colonize/etc Gaza - quite the opposite given that they pulled out and removed settlers in 2005
* The blockade, border wall, and bombings are a response to attacks by Hamas (even if you consider them disproportional)
* Without giving up its territorial claims for all of Israel, Hamas could truly disarm, stop firing rockets and building tunnels, renounce genocidal claims, etc, and instead focus on putting all the aid money toward the people of Gaza
* If they did that in a verifiable way, Israel would have no justification for the blockade or attacks and Gazans could live in peace rather than an "open air prison" as some like to say

tldr; Gaza could have peace and prosperity if Hamas would stop attacking Israel. This would be without renouncing their territorial claims over all of Israel.

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44460896525.0" user="ResponsibilityAny358" delta="False">
    <text>More than 70 days of war and there are still people who believe that Israel wants to end Hamas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44460952814.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>His Hamas still active? Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44461381483.0" user="changemyview-ModTeam" delta="False">
    <text>Comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%201%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
