<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2711667553.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18ugg2p/cmv_without_love_life_is_not_worth_living/">
    <title>CMV: Without love, life is not worth living</title>
    <original_poster>No_Professional_3218</original_poster>
    <original_post>You are operating a vessel of flesh, working day in and day out, simply to maintain your existence. Everything around you is slowly killing you and making your body/mind worse. In order to maintain your existence, you must live by every last dollar and every last bit of energy you have left.

Sure, you can go enjoy hobbies or something, but only with the money you use to maintain said existence. You perpetuate a system every day that hates you and wants you dead, but we continue on anyway.

We live an absurd and meaningless existence. Feeling desired is simply a recognition of your value as a person. I’m not saying everyone deserves it, but not a lot of otherwise good people suffer without it

I can cite plenty of studies that show that people in relationships last longer, are beneficial to mental health, and can empower you to improve in the future. Without these things, you are already starting off in a losing battle.

Do some people crawl out of the depths to eventually meet societal standards to meet a partner? Sure. But it’s getting harder and harder everyday for everyone both men and women alike. Things like dating apps isolate people and make them socially retarded to the point where they forgot how to communicate with people after 2020. People are too busy working to enjoy themselves anyway. 

If I end up 40 and never married, I’m probably going to kill myself. I’m willing to wait until then though. Otherwise I am failing to see the point in all of this. I only care about my dog, and when he goes and there’s 0 companionship I might end up dead</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44476304649.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/No_Professional_3218,

The mods of CMV are concerned about your submission, as it looks like you are in a tough situation right now. We want to help, but there are other places on Reddit where your submission would be better placed - with people ready to talk and listen. Whenever you are ready, you can visit or post to r/suicidewatch instead, or call any of the [local resources](https://www.reddit.com/r/SuicideWatch/wiki/hotlines) available.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
