<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44495279319.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>To /u/Guilty-Hope1336, *Your post is under consideration for removal for violating Rule B.*

In our experience, the best conversations genuinely consider the other person’s perspective. Here are some techniques for keeping yourself honest:

- Instead of only looking for flaws in a comment, be sure to engage with the commenters’ strongest arguments — not just their weakest.
- Steelman rather than strawman. When summarizing someone’s points, look for the most reasonable interpretation of their words.
- Avoid moving the goalposts. Reread the claims in your OP or first comments and if you need to change to a new set of claims to continue arguing for your position, you might want to consider acknowledging the change in view with a [delta](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=usertext&amp;utm_name=changemyview&amp;utm_content=t5_2w2s8) before proceeding.
- Ask questions and really try to understand the other side, rather than trying to prove why they are wrong.

Please also take a moment to review our [Rule B](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_b) guidelines and _really_ ask yourself - am I exhibiting any of these behaviors? If so, see what you can do to get the discussion back on track.  Remember, the goal of CMV is to try and **understand** why others think differently than you do.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
