<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44491963183.0" user="CathanCrowell" delta="False">
    <text>It's a little bit same reason why most of modern countries have some kind of of the Labour Code what cannot be broken.

"But I want to work 18 hours in day and during holiday! It's my mind and body!"

Yes, maybe, but the Code exists to protect all the people from greed and injustice.

It's not like your opinion does not have any point, you we don't and we won't live in the world where it could not work without any exploitation. 

Another reason is that any society should not allow to literally selling pieces of yourself because there is social injustice, it's actually kind of dystopic idea. Imagine that "I had to sell  my kidney to have money to my education". See the problem? Yes, many people would do that and it's their choice, but point is that it never should work like that, because it's just incredibly unfair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491976337.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>Then fix society. Not ban bodily autonomy. If a person got an education, became wealthy and had a good life because he could sell his kidney, why should we stop him?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491993274.0" user="Such-Lawyer2555" delta="False">
    <text>Because if we actually fix society people won't need to sell parts of them to become wealthy and have a good life.

What you aren't describing isn't fixing society, it's making it worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492038899.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>If we fix society, people would still need kidneys every once in a while, and offering to pay for Simone to donate one seems reasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493865838.0" user="Such-Lawyer2555" delta="False">
    <text>Why would pay be the essential incentive? What about helping people? If society is fixed people won't have as much need for money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496842593.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Why would I want to be poorer, and exposed to more risk pointlessly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44497392784.0" user="Such-Lawyer2555" delta="False">
    <text>What would poverty even involve in a "fixed" society? You're thinking in terms of your current situation where you need a financial incentive. I'm talking about a future where helping people doesn't need to come at such a cost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44497518877.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>The system you are proposing doesn’t remove poverty. It’s just a bad way to organize ownership that exposes people to too much risk, and involves quasi indentured servitude for people who can’t afford to buy in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44506452086.0" user="Such-Lawyer2555" delta="False">
    <text>What system have I proposed? I've suggested fixing the system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491994417.0" user="CathanCrowell" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Then fix society.

I do what I can :)

&gt;If a person got an education, became wealthy and had a good life because he could sell his kidney, why should we stop him?

Because sell of their kidney can cause health problems what young person cannot understand or will ignore it or downplayed because of desperation and it actually does not have to lead to being wealthy and have good life. 

To be fair, student loans in USA are not so much better :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492067725.0" user="_whydah_" delta="False">
    <text>You’re young but as you get older you’ll understand better and better that you cannot fix society, at least not this part. It just is what it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492073799.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>Then why ban organ selling?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492116582.0" user="_whydah_" delta="False">
    <text>“But why male models?”

But seriously the other commenter explained it. I don’t understand your question or what you’re confused about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492101820.0" user="Walui" delta="False">
    <text>Man why didn't we think of that??? We just had to fix society all along. You're a genius, future Nobel price for you mate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492104189.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492441850.0" user="Lifeinstaler" delta="False">
    <text>Do you see the labour code and also think society should be fixed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493389143.0" user="YardageSardage" delta="False">
    <text>"This would work if society was more just" is a great hypothetical, and a nice goal to maybe work towards, but it's a pretty fruitless thing to argue for now. We currently live in *this* society, where people can be and regularly are exploited, and the realistic result of what you suggest would be people in poverty having to give up literal important parts of their bodies in order to survive. And that's bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494787394.0" user="Hayden371" delta="False">
    <text>Because selling your kidney is bad, it is a bad thing to do, there is no two ways about it. You compare it to selling sperm, that's replacable. Blood donating is legal because you don't get paid for it (generally!) And is not permanently damaging.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491997434.0" user="NegativeAd9048" delta="False">
    <text>This, generally.

The point of government interceding over things that it *seems like* people should have every right to do is to reduce exploitation, hopefully, to zero, because the ultimate consequence is a race to the bottom, as corporations seek to impoverish workers, to exploit more people at a cheaper cost. 

Advanced economies work because workers are rewarded for exceptional productivity, and spend that extra money on stupid but awesome shit. 

In classical economic philosophy, you don't own anything after you die (wills don't matter). In China (don't know if this is still the case) the State owns your body after death (a rarely exercised state prerogative).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492047286.0" user="SendMeYourShitPics" delta="False">
    <text>You can sell your plasma/blood. That "coerces" the poor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492082362.0" user="saintofsadness" delta="False">
    <text>1. At our current knowledge, blood regenerates completely and donating it is only a temporary setback with no long-term consequences. Like donating hair.

2. Selling (your own) blood/plasma is most certainly _not_ legal everywhere. There are only a few countries where this is legal. The US is not the world.

3. What you mention is exactly a criticism that is raised against it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44499154380.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>Even in the US, paying someone to donate whole blood is illegal. You can only be paid to donate plasma, which is the watery part of our blood. It also regenerates faster than other blood components, that's why it's allowed to be sold. It's safer to frequently donate plasma.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492220124.0" user="ZBlackmore" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that the alternative to your example could be “They told
Me I couldn’t sell my kidney so I never got an education and lived in poverty my whole life”. So “I” remained poor but at least “they” end up feeling better about the world since the world doesn’t allow this kind of a dystopian scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492441502.0" user="VarencaMetStekeltjes" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Yes, maybe, but the Code exists to protect all the people from greed and injustice.

Does it? How? So long as sufficient options exist with companies that offer a 8 hour contract, I don't see how banning 18 hours protects anyone.

In fact, I live in a country which requires companies to offer part time work. They are required by law to offer 40, 35, 30, 25, 20, and 15 hour work weeks unless it absolutely can't be done, in which case they have to make a show and convince a court that it's not feasible in their specific line of work. This could easily be extended to include 45, 50, 55 and 60 hour work weeks. Who exactly is being protected here by not allowing that?

&gt; Another reason is that any society should not allow to literally selling pieces of yourself because there is social injustice, it's actually kind of dystopic idea. Imagine that "I had to sell my kidney to have money to my education". See the problem? Yes, many people would do that and it's their choice, but point is that it never should work like that, because it's just incredibly unfair.

Banning organ sale won't stop that unfairness. It will simply mean the people that thought a kidney was worth an education, which it might very well be, aren't getting an education and will be even worse of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494500554.0" user="c0i9z" delta="False">
    <text>In order to build a wall you need brick layers and brick makers. Let's say making a wall pays 120$ an hour and making those bricks costs 20$ in material and takes an hour, too, so there's 100$ to split between the two.

Once, there was one brick layer and one brick maker. They split the money evenly, so each got 50$ an hour.

But then, a second brick maker came to town. And so, the brick layer said 'whoever sells me their bricks the cheapest, I will buy from'. 

"I will do 70$, as I always have," the first maker said.

"69$," said the second, as making all the bricks for 69$ was better money than splitting the work.

"68$," replied the first, for much the same reason.

And so, it continued. 41$, 40$, both started to panic. This soon wouldn't be enough money to live, to feed their families. But it was more money than nothing. And there seemed to be no floor, no point where a tiny bit of money wasn't better than no money. 

And so, desperate, they tried to find a solution. They could make an agreement between each other, a contract, which would force them both not to sell bricks at less than 70$. By imposing a restriction on each other, this would then create a better result for both of them.

This, however, wasn't enough. Tomorrow, a third brick maker could come. That one could undercut them both and they, both stuck in their mutual contract, would never find work again.

And so, they went to the people, stating their trouble and warning that if this wasn't resolved, no more bricks could be made, and no more walls, without creating great misery. The people saw the trouble and agreed. They has seen the same thing many times happen in many different ways. And so, they agreed, they would all impose a restriction on each other. No work was to be done for less than 20$ an hour. 

And so, by unable to offer their services for less than 20$, neither brick maker was forced to offer their services for less. And the brick layer profited, too, though he didn't realize it yet, because soon, a second brick layer would be coming to town.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492824946.0" user="mattoisacatto" delta="False">
    <text>I mean theres still plenty of industries that don't follow those laws in the slightest, although I do see your point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493035188.0" user="treelager" delta="False">
    <text>OP said they found the commodification argument “stupid.” I agree with your take and it’s the general consensus of ethicists but how can you come to CMV while immediately calling opposing arguments stupid like you’re not open to them?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
