<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44495348974.0" user="theredmokah" delta="False">
    <text>In addition to my other point, note that the second we incentivize organ donation, capitalism will manifest itself into the process.

Good quality, government approved organs will go towards the rich. They will be very expensive. So if you're working class you will have to put yourself in serious debt, even with insurance to afford one. If you're homeless or lower income, just forget about it. The wait times you see now, will balloon even worse. 

On top of that, a black market of lower grade organs will be sold. Think smokers lungs, alcoholic livers, genetically defective hearts. These will be sold to the poor people desperate enough just to give their child/brother/mother etc. that extra five/ten years of life. They'll undersell the risks, undersell the QoL, undersell the debt (because these won't go cheap either). 

This will also prop up rich people being able to just brutalize their own bodies with vices such as smoking/drinking because they know they can pay for a clean/new liver/kidney etc. The poor will be used like farm animals.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
