<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44498238490.0" user="NoBottle3526" delta="False">
    <text>I can see where you are coming from, but this seems to be an especially troubling subject.

&amp;#x200B;

One question is do any countries actually legalize organ sales?  Well, sure, you can go right over to. .[Iran](https://www.latimes.com/world/middleeast/la-fg-iran-kidney-20171015-story.html)!  I think most would pass on trying to model Iran for anything.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them?

Ok, yes.  Nice point.  But in the case of something with major risks like offering your bodily organs as commodities, would there be more risks than rewards?   Sadly, many in lower income classes do not have equal access to healthcare so that alone seems to be one indicator of increased risks for low-income people that may consider selling organs. 

A similar point is would offering cash for kidneys or bone marrow would actually lead to more people wanting to give their organs away.  They are not replenishable like blood, sperm, eggs, or plasma.  Really only the kidney could be easily sold by a living donor.  And even with those you've only got two!

It is hard enough to donate plasma.  You have to receive a medical examination and pass a rigorous questionnaire that tracks many intimate details of your medical and personal history.  Many donors face minor or not-so-minor side effects.  There is a small risk of serious health complications.   

One major thing here to also point out is that [most organ donations](https://unos.org/transplant/facts/) and types of donated organs come from deceased who opted to offer their organs in the event of passing.  Would it be more effective to advocate for more people to opt in for organ delivery rather than push for the legalization of organ sales which may be an uphill battle in most countries or jurisdictions?  Or why not advocate for more extensive stem-cell research?  There is the promise in the not-so-distant future that organs could be harvested from stem cells--ensuring a whole new age of organ availability and fewer risks for organ donors overall.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
