<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44491946379.0" user="Crispy--Lettuce" delta="False">
    <text>You just opened a large black market for organ harvesting. Effectively we would see “organ laundering” where victims bodies would be harvested and passed off as ethical, clean organs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491969802.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>And that's currently prevented how?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491992229.0" user="Crispy--Lettuce" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not perverted now but it’s also not easily accessible and there’s no legal way to sell an organ, so it’s naturally discouraged by the fact that you have to sell an organ in a shady way, under the table, to a buyer who’s also doing illegal business. 

Legalizing 90% of that leads to a much bigger market where right now the risk isn’t generally worth the reward.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491999168.0" user="Such-Lawyer2555" delta="False">
    <text>It's currently a black market, ie illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492057264.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>You can't just drive up to a hospital with a kidney in a cooler and ask them to pop in you. Organ transplants have heavily regulated. You also can't show up with someone and say, "Hey, they totally agreed to donate to me." There's extensive screening, both physically and mentally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492081173.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>And what makes you think organ selling will make it legal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492088151.0" user="Moderator_of_Silvest" delta="False">
    <text>So in your world only specific organizations would be able to sell organs? 

See where we’re going with this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492103105.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, the government</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492225864.0" user="JadedToon" delta="False">
    <text>You do know that currently it's not the goverment organising and running all the transplants and donations. Those are all private organisations, there is some governmental oversight, but not control.

Do you actually trust the goverment not to abuse a system like that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492331050.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do you actually trust the goverment not to abuse a system like that?

More than deals between private individuals,yes, absolutely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492368865.0" user="JadedToon" delta="False">
    <text>That feeling is far from universal, there are plenty of corrupt governments who'd exploit this system to the hilt. Leverage a poor population to be used as organ farms for the wealthy nations.

Private deals are hardly better, I agree. Best option is autonimous bodies that are regulated by multiple entities. Essentially what is in place now. Adding a financial element injects too much uncertainty and bad faith motivation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492385270.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't suggesting we go to a China-esque execution of prisoners for organs. I was merely saying that if the only choice is government controlled or private free market buying and selling of organs, then I would choose government controlled.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492093293.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>If you make it possible for organs to be exchanged through a private transaction, you open the possibility of black markets where people are coerced and forced to donate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
