<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492044362.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

Because they could die. Organ donation is not without risk. And you might argue that jobs can also be dangerous but I doubt even dangerous jobs carry the same rate of death as major surgery. And when you combine that with financial desperation, people are unlikely to realistically evaluate the risks.

&gt; Why should we treat organs differently? 

Your energy, your intelligence, and even your sperm are not finite resources. You make more. You only have two kidneys and one liver. If you donate, you set yourself up for a lifetime of potential medical complications and the possibility you might need an organ in the future. 

This isn't to dissuade anyone from donating an organ, but it is a huge decision with very real, potentially very serious consequences. It shouldn't be a decision made out of financial desperation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492066328.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>The chances of death are around 1/4000. So the same as driving a car. You can regenerate your liver and you can live easily on one kidney.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492079434.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>

&gt;You can regenerate your liver and you can live easily on one kidney.

You live with a lifetime of potential complications. If you only have one kidney, what do you think happens if it fails? I'm not saying people shouldn't donate, I'm saying they shouldn't be coerced into donating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492364506.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The chances of death are around 1/4000. 

That might be true... but you also failed to mention that the risk of complications for donors is between 3% and 22%, depending on what you donate. That might mean some minor, or it might be that impacts you for the rest of your life.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
