<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2713943323.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vt82j/cmv_the_sale_of_organs_should_be_legal/">
    <title>CMV: The sale of organs should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>Guilty-Hope1336</original_poster>
    <original_post>One of my most radical political opinions is that organ sale should be completely legal. It should of course, be regulated so that people aren't taken advantage of and the rich don't get a monopoly on organs. But it should be legal. Like organ wait times are insane for people, something like 3-5 years for a kidney, and if allowing people to sell their organs lowers this wait time, then we should do it. 

The biggest argument I have heard is that the poor will be coerced into selling their organs because they need money. But then why shouldn't they be able to? It's their body, they should be able to do with it what they want. If they want to use it make money, why should we stop them? If it will save a life, why should we stop them? 

I also find the argument of commodification stupid. Just because it feels uncomfortable doesn't mean anything. People sell their labour and thus, their muscle strength in physically demanding jobs like construction. People in Universities sell their ideas and, thus their brain power. You can also sell your sperm. Why should we treat organs differently? We all sell some portion of ourselves to make money, so why not organs?

My preferred system would be that people sell their organs to the government, who pays them a fair price and the organs will be distributed by the triage system, as is currently utilised. This way we can ensure that the people who truly need organs can get them, not just those who can pay more. But I would also allow people to sell their organs to a specific individual, if they so choose. This would also apply to blood and bone marrow.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44491931761.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>Why would anybody be so stupid as to sell their organs to the government for a 'fair' price, when they could instead sell them to rich individuals for outrageous prices?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491967686.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>People currently donate organs without any price</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491976769.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>Once they're dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491978889.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>You can donate your liver and kidney while you are alive to an organ registry</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491981423.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>And you think they take them while you're alive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491988420.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>Uh, yeah</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491991555.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>So how much of your liver do you think they take? How many kidneys do you think you have? How many so you need?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491996880.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>Half the liver and one kidney</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491998414.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>How much do you need?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492040889.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Half a liver, and one kidney.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492056347.0" user="SendMeYourShitPics" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, you seriously didn't know that people donate organs while alive? Really???</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492061170.0" user="Hemingwavy" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm asking because I know and I think people reaching the conclusion I have on their own is more convincing you dipshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44517832269.0" user="pro-frog" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;subject=Rule%202%20Appeal&amp;message=Author%20would%20like%20to%20appeal%20the%20removal%20of%20their%20post%20because\.\.\.) within one week of this notice being posted. **Appeals that do not follow this process will not be heard.** 

Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492268426.0" user="really_random_user" delta="False">
    <text>The liver regenerates rather quickly

Kidneys on the other hand...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492005599.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>Living donors exist for kidneys and a lesser extent liver (you only donate a small portion of your liver). But these donations are almost exclusively between relatives or close friends that happen to be matches. It is very rarely complete strangers, and donors have to be psychologically screened before donation. People who are champing at the bit to donate to strangers often don't pass the psychological evaluation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491979109.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>To specific people they know and care about, or else, after their deaths. What makes you think that would continue under your policies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44491983761.0" user="Guilty-Hope1336" delta="False">
    <text>You can donate blood, bone marrow, liver and kidneys while you are alive to a general registry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492007323.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>And why would anybody be so stupid as to do so unpaid when, with your policy, they could get paid hundreds of thousands of dollars by some rich asshole</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492086769.0" user="saintofsadness" delta="False">
    <text>Most people don't have access to rich people that are willing to buy their organs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492094192.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>Presumably they would under OP's policy, right</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492788236.0" user="Squirrel009" delta="False">
    <text>Only because it's illegal. You don't think a market would pop up by the end of the week if it were legalized?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492886743.0" user="apri08101989" delta="False">
    <text>Right? There's literally a market right now while it's illegal. They'd just be giving those rings carte blanch to advertise.openly</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492067724.0" user="Medical_Conclusion" delta="False">
    <text>You can... but almost no one does. At least not organs. Blood and bone marrow are one thing. Our bodies produce more. But organs are rarely donated to complete strangers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
