<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44493110673.0" user="Kalekuda" delta="False">
    <text>On the subject of chinese EVs, the simple realities are thus:

They're made in china to chinese specifications and with chinese construction quality. Make of that what you will, but I'd support heightened scrutiny on their safety test results and their product specifications. If they are found to be misrepresenting their product's specifications (again) than a ban may be justified. 

Protecting local manufacturing industries from being replaced by a globally belligerent nation is just good statecraft.

They aren't competing for the same market sectors. Chinese evs are budget low end vehicles, while european evs run the gambit of quality from consumer to luxury. Greece and italy's poorest would prefer the imports, but the majority of the EU would likely still prefer european evs on feature completeness and quality of construction.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
