<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492893627.0" user="FlyingNFireType" delta="False">
    <text>You're confusing capitalists with rich assholes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492963775.0" user="Nijajjuiy88" delta="False">
    <text>Capitalists's goal is to maximize revenue, they are not the ones responsible for keeping market free. It's only natural that every single capitalist to some degree would indulge in this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493217166.0" user="FlyingNFireType" delta="False">
    <text>You're confusing ideological belief in capitalism with min/maxing game theory business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493658271.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>A capitalist is someone who owns capital.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493680862.0" user="FlyingNFireType" delta="False">
    <text>lol no. A capitalist is someone who believes in the ideals of capitalism. Someone who owns capital is just a capital owner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496265524.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>Capitalist - Merriam Webster: "a person who has capital especially invested in business".

Capitalist - Cambridge: "someone who has a large amount of money invested (= given hoping to get more back) in business".

Capitalist - Oxford: "a wealthy person who uses money to invest in trade and industry for profit in accordance with the principles of capitalism".

A capitalist can also be someone who supports capitalism, but realistically, the definition of a capitalist is someone who owns capital. Someone who participates in capitalism rather than being on the receiving end of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496280966.0" user="FlyingNFireType" delta="False">
    <text>Literally everyone has capital... that'd make you a capitalist for having 5 "capital" in your bank account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496966201.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>Capital - Oxford: "wealth in the form of money or other assets owned by a person or organization or available or contributed for a particular purpose such as starting a company or investing."

I like how at this point you're just arguing with the dictionary. I don't even have to do anything.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
