<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492872921.0" user="Archerseagles" delta="False">
    <text>The examples you give are not of capitalism hating the free market, but rather of capitalism not being fair to smaller businesses (by a subjective measurement of fair). The examples you give are of a free market, the larger company is free to try to buy the smaller company, the smaller company if free to accept or not. If it is not accepted the larger company is free to do what is legally allowed to push out the smaller company from that space.

&amp;#x200B;

Let me give an analogy. If we have a free fight between you and Conor Mcgregor, you will probably lose every time. Is it an unfair fight? Probably. Is it a free fight? Yes absolutely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493636115.0" user="doge_gobrrt" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;The examples you give are not of capitalism hating the free market, but rather of capitalism not being fair to smaller businesses (by a subjective measurement of fair).

While those companies don't hate the free market they also don't want to be subject to all its effects. If it's fair or not is besides the point as the effect the actions of very large corporations have is more important along with the paradoxical motives demonstrated by these actions. Corporations both depend on the free market to do what they do but also have a vested interest in institutionalization of their economic dominance be that through policy, economic practicality, oor some other factors. Vested interest is the right word not hate.

&gt; The examples you give are of a free market, the larger company is free to try to buy the smaller company, the smaller company if free to accept or not. If it is not accepted the larger company is free to do what is legally allowed to push out the smaller company from that space.

What I get from this is a refutation of the effects of those actions along with their logical motivations. While it is indeed true companies are free to institute practices that put pressure on smaller or other companies along with the buying or selling of those companies that does not mean certain actions allowed in a capitalist system cannot progress the economic status quo away from capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496643614.0" user="Archerseagles" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument appears to me to be that if one company is able to dominate, then it is not a free market. I don't think that a free market requires that one company is not able to dominate. A free market is one where a company can dominate if they are able to so, in fact I think pure capitalism and free markets tend towards monopolies (which I see as a problem, but that is irrelevant to the OP).

I will concede one aspect that you mentioned, which is political lobbying to affect policy decisions. That is outside of a free market, so the lobbying done by large companies can be considered as not adhering to a free market. But economic domination is well within the confines of a free market.

Look back to my analogy of a fight. If you fought a MMA champion in a free fight, they would dominate and crush you every time. You are free to punch him, he is free to punch you, even though he will dominate and defeat you every time, it is still a free fight.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
