<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492379763.0" user="BJJnoob1990" delta="False">
    <text>This is a just a nonsensical view.

By buying smaller companies they are literally taking advantage of the “free market”. 

Making deals with other companies and lobbying government is also possible because of a free market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493332357.0" user="HeckaCoolDudeYo" delta="False">
    <text>They're arguing about the economic concept which in theory is supposed to breed innovation through competition. But in modern times companies will do anything they can to squash competition and avoid innovation in favor of the status quo. The oil industry as a whole is an example of refusing progress in favor of profits. If oil companies had invested in alternative energy decades ago they would be at the forefront of the market now. Instead they have spent decades using time and money to keep thing exactly the same. If you are arguing that this is capitalisms intent then you must admit its a flawed system.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
