<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492324580.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>The point of most start ups isn’t to try to one day replace google, but they get bought instead. Normally their plan is to develop a risky, likely niche product, then either IPO or get sold so that they get the money to take their product mainstream. This isn’t anti market, this is a mutually beneficial arrangement, for the start up, investors, consumers, and whoever buys the start up.

Preemptively buying competing companies doesn’t remove competition. Start ups are a dime a dozen. If demand exists, you’ll be back where you started in under a year, and bankrupt if you keep buying companies you can’t increase the value of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492685205.0" user="belindamshort" delta="False">
    <text>This feeds into monopoly though, which is not competition at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492730128.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Companies rarely but directly competing status. Besides, companies felt created, bought, merge, and shut down every day. That’s a normal part of any market, and unrelated to a monopoly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492879150.0" user="Purga_" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; The point of most start ups isn’t to try to one day replace google, but they get bought instead

If there was no economic culture of big companies buying out smaller companies, do you still think that the main goal of these small businesses would be to get bought out? 

Or rather is it more probable that it's the reverse: that the water fits the puddle, and the origin of the tendency of buying out smaller companies has little-to-nothing to do with the intentions of the smaller companies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496882859.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody is forcing them to sell, it’s just a mutually beneficial agreement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44498312685.0" user="Purga_" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I'm certain it's very beneficial for the company heads involved. However, when discussing competition, the focus is on the benefit of the general populace. The infanticide of buying out fledgling companies hinders innovation and economic development.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44498705306.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Buying start ups like this is how R&amp;D works, and it’s a much better system for all involved than the old model more like bell labs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493299124.0" user="HeckaCoolDudeYo" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think that if there was a realist path to growing their own business they wouldn't take it instead of selling out? You act as though that is the primary goal for most of these start ups but id argue that's only the case because of the system in place. No one dreams of building a company just to sell it to the highest bidder. Thats just the most practical solution at this point because you will never compete with Google, Amazon, Walmart, etc. And they will run your company into the ground if you manage to cut into so much as 0.5% of their margins. What you're describing is a symptom of a broken system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493637059.0" user="cursedbones" delta="False">
    <text>They don't have a choice. They are bought or their products gets copied and lose everything. There's endless examples of Google, Meta and Apple buying smaller companies just to kill them later.

Cof cof *Snapchat* Cof Cof.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496852604.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>They where making a generic, non patented product.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
