<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492400345.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who works in a big tech company that has done its fair share of aquisitions: Almost all of these aquisitions are of the varieties "Oh snap, they're doing something so cool that we want to do but it would be extremely expensive to do ourselves." or "They've managed to get a foothold in an industry we were unable to penetrate. Be aquiring them we can combine forces to scale there very quickly."

We *love* competition. Our jobs, all day, every day, is to figure out ways to make our product better for our users. Competition gives us valuable information on how others are solving similar problems and helps refine the accuracy of our estimations. In short, competition allows us to build a better product, faster. In the end, that's the goal of the majority of people who work at these companies; at least based on my first hand experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493517715.0" user="jetjebrooks" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; We 
&gt; love
&gt;  competition. Our jobs, all day, every day, is to figure out ways to make our product better for our users. Competition gives us valuable information on how others are solving similar problems and helps refine the accuracy of our estimations.

on the other hand, without competition you could sell all your half-baked product because it's the only option available for consumers. 

more than competition, dont companies love being the only choice in town more?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493600391.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe some rare people do, but the people I work with on a day to day basis are either just doing their jobs or genuinely want to make the world a better place through the work they do. We sometimes have weeks of discussion on what most people would consider very small changes for exactly this reason.

We're still a business, of course. And the primary job of any business is to make money (technically it's to benefit shareholders). The way we do it is by building a really good product people want to use.

Where some confusion may enter the picture is around gaining market share. We are absolutely tracking market share and using it as valuable information. Gaining market share is a very positive sign. Not because it means that we're "winning from the competition" (the world is not a zero-sum-game, usually the market just grows when you're both doing well), but because it's a signal that the choices we're making are experienced positively by our customers, and we should spend more effort in those high impact areas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493642780.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;the people I work with on a day to day basis are either just doing their jobs or genuinely want to make the world a better place through the work they do

Do those people own the company? If not, why mention them at all?

&gt;We're still a business, of course. And the primary job of any business is to make money (technically it's to benefit shareholders). The way we do it is by building a really good product people want to use.

If the purpose of the business is to make money, isn't the best way to make money "having a captive audience that has no choice but to buy at whatever price you set"? Competition is good for consumers and bad for producers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493677559.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do those people own the company? If not, why mention them at all?

I mean... It's a publicly traded company and stock is part of people's compensation, so... I guess? Not even the CEO owns the company; the shareholders do.

&gt;If the purpose of the business is to make money, isn't the best way to make money "having a captive audience that has no choice but to buy at whatever price you set"?

Like I said, maybe there are some people who think this way, but in my experience this is an extreme rarity. The vast majority of the people want to make the world a better place, and leaves worrying about shareholders to the C suite. For example, any time we're talking about any kind of price increase, it's always met with extreme pushback and analysis on whether it is actually necessary to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496283635.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Not even the CEO owns the company; the shareholders do.

Yes, the shareholders own the company. The employees may have some amount of control, but I'd be willing to bet that all the employees added together are less than 51% of the company's shares. Even in ESOPs which are explicitly designed to be "100% worker owned", the upper echelons of the company generally have a majority of the shares.

&gt;The vast majority of the people want to make the world a better place, and leaves worrying about shareholders to the C suite

But the shareholders are the ones who run the company...so why are you acting as if they're irrelevant?

&gt;For example, any time we're talking about any kind of price increase, it's always met with extreme pushback and analysis on whether it is actually necessary to do so.

And do the people "pushing back" make those decisions or do they just voice complaints?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496412482.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>Shareholders of Google don't run Google. They just own it. They make very few decisions.

Decisions are made collaboratively. I'd say that about 70% of the time the price increase is reduced, pushed back or entirely eliminated as a result of the pushback. I have a limited sample size here, though. Haven't seen the topic come up a lot at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496955898.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Shareholders of Google don't run Google. They just own it. They make very few decisions.

The shareholders can override or replace the CEO. Is the same true in the opposite direction? Also, the company you're talking about is *Google*? That's the spunky ethical startup we shouldn't be concerned about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496991377.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>The shareholders can assigns the board of directors who can fire the ceo. Overriding decisions is virtually never in their best interest, simply due to a lack of information. You're arguing like this is common practice to do, but it is exceedingly rare... 

Google is not the company I work for. I'm just using it as an example of a big tech company here to maintain anonymity on my company.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558262876.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>So I know it's been a week, let me just reiterate what this argument is:
1. You believe that the average tech company worker is good and righteous ("The vast majority of the people want to make the world a better place").
2. You believe that, even though shareholders might have selfish motives, they are functionally subservient to the workers ("Shareholders of Google don't run Google. They just own it. They make very few decisions. Decisions are made collaboratively.")
3. The fact that the shareholders literally own the company and can override any decisions made by its employees simply doesn't matter to you ("Overriding decisions is virtually never in their best interest, simply due to a lack of information.")

Do you know what capitalism is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558607366.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>I think there is a fundamental misunderstanding around the kind of argument I'm making here. I'm not making some idle argument based on arbitrary hypotheticals. My argument is not theoretical in nature, is observational. To an extent, this makes my argument an appeal to authority, which is a fallacy.

All I'm saying is that I've worked for years inside one of these faceless mega tech cooperations. In my time I have exclusively seen righteous or apathic intentions, I've seen a lot of decisions that go directly against the recommendations and desires of the shareholders, and I haven't seen any instance where the shareholders attempted to override these decisions. This dynamic has been very lucrative for those same shareholders. Presumably they didn't move to remove the CEO because the CEO managed to establish an appropriate level of trust and/or there were no better alternatives. 

Again, this is not theoretical. This is purely anecdotal and observational. You need not trust the authority of this observation, but if you do then any contradictory theory is inconsequential, because it does not alter the reality. Note also that this is not a generalized claim. It's one company.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558700605.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;My argument is not theoretical in nature, is observational.

It is pretty much theoretical because you are making systemic claims based on your own incomplete observations of how your own company works. Case in point: you started talking about Google and how Google works ("Shareholders of Google don't run Google. They just own it. They make very few decisions.") even though the company you work for **isn't Google**. So that's not anecdotal evidence, it's a theory.

&gt;I've seen a lot of decisions that go directly against the recommendations and desires of the shareholders, and I haven't seen any instance where the shareholders attempted to override these decisions. This dynamic has been very lucrative for those same shareholders.

This seems like a contradictory statement. First you say that the workers override the shareholders, which plays off the idea that shareholders are obsessed with profit while workers are more moral. Then you say that the overridden decisions result in more profit for the shareholders...so, uh, what was the point of the workers exercising their independence? Unless you are of the belief that the most moral decision is **also** the most profitable one in **every instance**, this dichotomy seems pointless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558764310.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>Maximizing profit is a finite game. It can bring short term success, but is ultimately destructive in the long term. In the long term, the infinite game of sustainability and longevity comes into play.

Sometimes they overlap, sometimes they don't. Most investors just want a good return on their money; they don't care about maximizing profits, unless they are afraid of losing their investment otherwise.

In either case, this discussion seems to have devolved into a chaos of strawman arguments at this point, so I'll be stepping back from it further.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558810082.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Maximizing profit is a finite game. It can bring short term success, but is ultimately destructive in the long term. In the long term, the infinite game of sustainability and longevity comes into play.

...and? So what? That hasn't stopped companies from doing it. What you just said has nothing to do with the reality of how companies are run.

&gt;a chaos of strawman arguments at this point

Nothing I've said is a "strawman argument". They're provable facts. If you think I'm misrepresenting something you've said you're free to address it. But the things I just said about you - that you were making anecdotal statements and then acting as if they were representative of systemic design - is completely and objectively true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558890089.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>So what are your objectives within this conversation? What are you hoping I can help you achieve?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44558952004.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;So what are your objectives within this conversation?

Originally I was publicly countering your claim that companies are effectively run by their morally upright workers. Your statements are akin to pro-capitalist disinformation as far as I can tell, and I had a moral responsibility to combat those claims by pointing out why they are wrong.

Of course, now it's a week later and we're the only two people reading this, so that motive no longer applies. I guess now I'm driven by curiosity. Like, do you *actually* believe the things you're saying, or have you just not thought them through? I get that you have a positive vision of capitalism, but you seem to be willfully disregarding any of the very obvious negative effects that it can have. In your worldview, companies are run by their workers, the workers do not functionally answer to the shareholders, and everyone just wants to make the world a better place.

I'd suggest you look into Market Socialism or Distributism if you want an economic system that works in the way you believe capitalism does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44559037356.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>Here's what I'm hearing you say:

&gt; I believe that a capitalist economic system is morally apprehensible, and that the systems created under capitalism are, for profit motivated above anything else. In a crude word: evil. The claims / argument / information you're sharing counter this, seemingly without any clear evidence. I'm seeking to understand whether I am missing some peliece of information in my worldview, or whether you have simply not spent sufficient time thinking about the implications of a capitalist society.

Does this sound accurate? Where is my understanding still missing something or incorrect?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44559111659.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say that's mostly right. Although really, capitalism being morally reprehensible doesn't have anything to do with what I'm saying. I'm saying that capitalism is *profit-driven*, you're acting like it's not. I'm saying that capitalism is *owner-driven*, you're acting like it's not. Someone could say that capitalism is completely moral while still agreeing that it is profit-driven and owner-driven.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44559472080.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, cool. So what happened is that we were simply not having the same conversation.

The OP used a particular example of how acuisitions in big companies are necessarily anti-competitive and an attempt to create or maintain a monopoly.  My original comment was a rebuttal of this idea; saying that aquisitions (also) happen for other reasons. (Although I didn't mention it in the initial post, aquisitions with such goals are also highly illegal and megacorps tend to have a lot of mandatory training in place to try and avoid that kind of thinking. I'll leave it as a side note whether this is for moral reasons or the fear of legal reprecussions.)

It never was about the system of capitalism as a whole. In that I actually agree with you, although I'd rephrase and combine both of your points to be "Capitalism is owner-benefit-driven". I'd also note that I'm frankly not very educated on alternative economic systems that would be feasible within respresentative democratic societies.

Now for the nuance: Being owner-benefit driven does not necessitate maximizing profit, or being owner controlled. To draw a really silly analogy: Although most parents are "child benefit" driven, the child rare gets all the candy they want (profit), nor does the child get control over the dynamic. Of course this is a very flawed analogy, but Apple is 70-80% publicly owned, and I can guarantee you that the shareholders are not involved in 70-80% of the decisions being made. That's exactly what you hire employees for. (Or in more capitalistic terms: You allocate capital to the skillful management of your investment.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44559539618.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;aquisitions with such goals are also highly illegal

They're illegal because society understands that companies would pursue monopolies if they could, because it would be the best option available to them...which is literally exactly the point that the person you were arguing with was making. From a market perspective, pursuing a monopoly is objectively the best idea, which is why society bans it. Meanwhile, your counter-argument to this claim was to say that the people in your company are nice and would not do something mean like that. Which is not how capitalism works.

&gt;To draw a really silly analogy: Although most parents are "child benefit" driven, the child rarely gets all the candy they want (profit), nor does the child get control over the dynamic.

It is a silly analogy because it's backwards. Parents "own" children. Parents can countermand children, not vice-versa. Children can be left to their own devices a lot of the time, but if the parent chooses to intervene then the child must submit to their authority. Parents are owners, children are workers. For some reason you arranged the analogy so that the children are shareowners even though the shareowners are the ones who have veto power! Children cannot fire their parents!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44559642577.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;companies would pursue monopolies if they could, because it would be the best option available to them...which is literally exactly the point that the person you were arguing with was making. 

This is an extreme generalisation, and one I acknowledged in the same phrase. Though if the generalisation were true, then every business owner ever would want to turn their business into a megacorporation that dominates the world. Yet there are so many mom-and-pop shops that are perfectly happy doing what they do. The idea of "objectively optimal" frankly has no place in real world business. Business remains to be a human endeavour, and humans are unsurprisingly subjective.

&gt;It is a silly analogy

 The analogy wasn't about an owner dynamic, it was about how benefitting group X does not necessitate control or profit for group X.

Do you notice how you're intentionally picking the least favourable possible read of my argument and ignoring everything else? In this entire response you have contributed nothing substantial to the conversation. All you've done is turn a conversation which had moved into a collaborative space back into an adverserial dynamic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44559737548.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Yet there are so many mom-and-pop shops that are perfectly happy doing what they do.

Does a minnow *choose* not to turn into a shark? No, it's just that they *can't*.

&gt;The analogy wasn't about an owner dynamic, it was about how benefitting group X does not necessitate control or profit for group X.

Then it was *very* silly, and unfortunately not very applicable to businesses. A shareholder is not akin to a child, because a child has no control over their environment, and their parents force them to do things for their own good. Whereas a worker does not force a shareholder to do anything - the best case scenario that you've illustrated is simply that the shareholder does not *care* enough to forcibly override the worker.

&gt;In this entire response you have contributed nothing substantial to the conversation.

You said that a poster was wrong about monopolies because monopolies are illegal. I pointed out that monopolies are illegal *because* of the reason that the poster said that companies would pursue them. A direct refutation of your claim seems pretty substantial to me! On the other hand, "complaining about my tone" seems pretty insubstantial. Why do you spend so much time doing it?

&gt;All you've done is turn a conversation which had moved into a collaborative space back into an adverserial dynamic.

If you stuck to the logical arguments we would be having a normal conversation but again you are interrupting yourself every five seconds to complain. If that's all you've got then I am not interested. My initial purpose (publicly correcting misinformation) no longer applies, and my secondary purpose (curiosity about your understanding of capitalism) has been satisfied as well. My conclusion is that you're pointlessly optimistic about capitalism because you simply ignore the actual mechanisms by which it operates. To what end or purpose I cannot say, but I don't really care about that, so there's no point discussing further. Goodbye.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44560708243.0" user="Rataridicta" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sticking exclusively to logical arguments because I don't believe it to be the most relevant point in this conversation, half the comments made are just fallicious without new arguments, and appealing to emotion is often more beneficial than appealing to logic. The "interrupting to complain" here is mostly pointing out those fallicious arguments btw. But I'm happy to oblige with a slightly more formal treatise:

&gt;Do those people own the company? If not, why mention them at all?

Are you claiming that anyone that is not an owner has no effect on the business?

&gt;isn't the best way to make money "having a captive audience that has no choice but to buy at whatever price you set"?

No. This depends on the size of the audience and the marginal differential in price compared to the marginal differential in audience size. 10\*2 &gt; 5\*3

&gt;the shareholders are the ones who run the company...

Categorically and provably false for major companies. This is also inconsistent with the tennants of capitalism you preach, which uses the allocation of capital to increase it, but has no necessary ties to allocating your time to the same endeavour.

&gt;And do the people "pushing back" make those decisions or do they just voice complaints?

You ignored the answer to this question, which is cherrypicking

&gt;The shareholders can override or replace the CEO. Is the same true in the opposite direction?

Moving the goal post.

&gt;That's the spunky ethical startup we shouldn't be concerned about?

Inductive fallacy and irrellevant conclusion. (The comment these last 2 are from are also cherry picking.)

Beyond this, it's a weird authoratative moralistic argument. You're appealing to the obvious moral failings of Google.

&gt;You believe that, even though shareholders might have selfish motives, they are functionally subservient to the workers

False equivalence and strawmanning.

&gt;The fact that the shareholders literally own the company and can override any decisions made by its employees simply doesn't matter to you

Quoting out of context / cherry picking, inductive fallacy and irrelevant conclusion. Also strawmanning.

&gt;It is pretty much theoretical because you are making systemic claims based on your own incomplete observations of how your own company works. Case in point: you started talking about Google and how Google works ("Shareholders of Google don't run Google. They just own it. They make very few decisions.") even though the company you work for isn't Google. So that's not anecdotal evidence, it's a theory.

I forget the name of this fallacy, but the one that's about how a poorly worded argument is not neccessarily false due to its poor wording. i.e. not working for google now does not mean I haven't worked there before, have some "insider" knowledge, or that the information provided is inaccurate. In that way, this is also a case of the inductive fallacy. In a similar vain, it's guilty of the fallacy fallacy: You're ignoring the point and focussing on the fallacy.

&gt;which plays off the idea that shareholders are obsessed with profit while workers are more moral. 

False attribution.

&gt;so, uh, what was the point of the workers exercising their independence? 

False dichotomy and inductive fallacy. This assumes that decisions without profit as objective cannot be profitable, and that decision which create benefits for shareholders are controlled by shareholders. (Or that independence / control are irrelevant, which would add a bunch more fallacies and blast your own argument to bits.)

&gt;Unless you are of the belief that the most moral decision is also the most profitable one in every instance, this dichotomy seems pointless.

Strawmanning and moving the goalpost.

Rebuttal to the contradicting statment: It's not contradictory (see fallacies above), and the point of the argument was an expression of control. i.e. The shareholders are cool letting the workers be in control.

&gt;...and? So what? That hasn't stopped companies from doing it. What you just said has nothing to do with the reality of how companies are run.

Argumentum ad lapidem. (Appeal to the stone) 

&gt;They're illegal because society understands that companies would pursue monopolies if they could, because it would be the best option available to them.

This isn't even begging the question, this is just a proof by assertion. (Technically so is the previous one.)

&gt;From a market perspective, pursuing a monopoly is objectively the best idea...

Quantitative fallacy

&gt; ...which is why society bans it

Inductive fallacy

&gt;your counter-argument to this claim was to say that the people in your company are nice and would not do something mean like that.

False attribution and missing the point. (point: Here's a counter example of at least 1 company) 

&gt;Which is not how capitalism works.

Assuming you accept the counter example as true this is an "accident" attribution.

&gt;It is a silly analogy because it's backwards.

Another case of cherry picking to strawman.

&gt;Does a minnow choose not to turn into a shark? No, it's just that they can't.

Ignoring the silly false analogy, you're incorrectly asserting that people don't create megacorps because they can't as opposed to don't want to. This is probably true for some, but not for most businesses. Falliciously, this is an inductive one.

&gt;the best case scenario that you've illustrated is simply that the shareholder does not care enough to forcibly override the worker.

This is not something you've refuted, though. I'll also add into this the feasibility of getting 51% of voting shares to agree on such decisions. The bar for caring and the lack of trust must be pretty high, no?

&gt;You said that a poster was wrong about monopolies because monopolies are illegal.

False attribution and strawmanning. I said the poster was wrong about the exclusive reason for aquisitions being to create monopolies by providing counter examples of other reasons.

&gt;On the other hand, "complaining about my tone" seems pretty insubstantial. Why do you spend so much time doing it?

Because when I'm complaining about your tone, I'm mostly complaining about the intellectually dishonest / fallicious arguments you're making, and writing a post like this that actually picks them is exhausting for no reason. (But good practice, so what the hey)

&gt;and my secondary purpose (curiosity about your understanding of capitalism) has been satisfied as well

Note that you didn't actually move the conversation towards capitalism at all. I described to you how we were having miscommunications due to having different conversations, you did not acknowledge this fact and instead critisized the original post to OP, which was not about capitalism but about aquisitions. This is another case of strawmanning and cherry picking.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
