<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492319244.0" user="Zandrick" delta="False">
    <text>Tech companies mostly buy small companies to get their employees and IP. It’s not about destroying competition. Those smaller companies aren’t competition, and frequently getting bought out is their whole goal. The big ones are competing with each other though make no mistake about that. Amazon would love if people would buy their tablets instead of an iPad, for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492550653.0" user="pickles55" delta="False">
    <text>It's called killing your competition in the crib. They eliminate potential future competitors while they're very small and vulnerable because waiting for them to get bigger would be stupid</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492640037.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>No, they don’t buy start ups with a dozen employees because they think they will one day compete with them. They want to use their IP and hire their team.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492681929.0" user="belindamshort" delta="False">
    <text>It's both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496194585.0" user="Zandrick" delta="False">
    <text>It’s really not. The start ups are also competing with each other to be bought. The big guys buy those smaller ones because they created value. That’s really the point of the free market, working as it’s supposed to. Competition creates value. 

If we saw a big merger between like, google and apple. Then we can be concerned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492630422.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>Read an article about an interview with the devs, or ceo or something of the app MSQRD app (pronounced Masquerade), it was a fun app with facemask filters. And he said. *Facebook made us an offer and we stand before a choice, take the offer and be eaten by a giant corp we don't like, or deny the offer and get destroyed by them copying your app and become irrelevant.*not a real quote. 😅

They took the offer, facebook killed the app, you can't find it anymore in the Play Store, I don't know what happened to them if they still work at facebook. But you have the filters in the facebook apps now, so enjoy the free market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492650936.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>So Facebook said they would either buy them, or make their own version. What’s the problem here? I don’t think they ever owned the patent on face filters to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492669418.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>Meaning you don't believe in the free market, which is just in theory but it's all controlled by big corpos, monopolies, killing competition, buying them out, firing the personnel, making shitty, proprietary products, walled gardens, own ecosystems, to lock you into their system, then increase pricing, like streaming, which is all bad for consumers and environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492740833.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly do do you think a free market is? Because the situation you just described is sinister language over a banal transaction. ‘Either sell me your apple or I’ll be destroy you by growing my own!’</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492772565.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>Free market is exploitation by corpos, if you didn't get it from my comments already, where the capitalists, have all the power over people, society, and government. Proof in the US where 2 percent own 95 percent of wealth. 
Also history taught us like the whole Belgian history how it evolved into a more socialist democratic society, from a capitalist mindset. That's why Europe has the Brussels effect where EU regulates corpos, and other countries follow. Which is only favourable for consumers, people and society in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492877664.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.reddit.com/r/mildlyinfuriating/s/iA3qwDjYZN proof of free market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493273187.0" user="HeckaCoolDudeYo" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely not the same thing😬 apples grow on their own and have long before people got here. Realizing someone else has a good idea and coercing them into selling it to you with threat of financial ruin is not the same thing as "I dont wanna buy your apple so ill grow my own" and it doesn't take a genius to realize that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496904523.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Face modifying filters aren’t anything special or new.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493227066.0" user="gobblegobblechumps" delta="False">
    <text>Meta leveraging its capital to acquire (or obsolete) a competitor is perfectly in line with what a "free market" means</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493271859.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>That's the whole point, when a corpo gets too big, they abuse their power, by killing competition with their capital. You just explained it yourself. EU is even looking into breaking up big corpos.
We are an example how to regulate the market, and give competition a chance. You can thank us for iphone USB-C.

https://www.ft.com/content/15bf2e24-284f-4819-89ff-2520676e29ed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493593370.0" user="gobblegobblechumps" delta="False">
    <text>"free market" does not mean "enforced competition", it means no third-party intervention by regulation.

I'm not saying it's better for consumers or it's better to have kess competition -- I'm saying that "when a corpo gets too big, they abuse their power, by killing competition with their capital" is exactly what happens in a free market system. 

Great so the EU may break up big tech -- that's not anything close to "free market" because it's the direct result of government intervention</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493666594.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>True, your comment explains the free market, but my point is that the free market doesn't create competition, it kills competition and has no reason to innovate as long as they can milk the same tech, design for years as shill keep buying their products.

I advocate against a pure exploitative free market, but a controlled and regulated market like the EU, giving competition a chance, and breaking up big corpos so they have to start innovating. Which is good for consumers and society as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493754341.0" user="gobblegobblechumps" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it "kills" competition as much as it makes a much higher barrier to market entry. Especially in tech etc. 

I work in an industry with a HUGE amount of fast entry and fad products with companies always looking to grab and keep market share. And although i work for one of the bigger corporations that is known to be pretty aggressive in acquisitions, I don't think that it kills competition in the industry as much as it means my org has the resources to fast track competing product development that may have taken a startup a little while to get onto the market. The flip side of it is that smaller startups are willing to take more risks while my org is fairly risk averse</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493791367.0" user="CyberxFame" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't think it kills competition why do acquisitions need to go through the FTC, EU and other regulatory bodies. And why is the EU looking to break up big corpos, walled gardens, locked eco systems like apple store, IOS systems and so on. Maybe you worked for too long for a big corpo, you can't see the wood for the trees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44496261508.0" user="Zandrick" delta="False">
    <text>So again, you’re missing the point where the big ones are still competing with each other. All the FAANG companies are competing with each other, too. It’s not just big vs small and small always loses. It’s big vs big and small vs small. The small ones are often competing specifically to be bought out. There are several levels to it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
