<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492365996.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>Amazon, Google and Microsoft are all competing with each other on big data and storage markets. Most websites are hosted by one of the three.

But there are a lot of small innovative (and often open source) data solutions that operate within these clouds. But these are never bought.

Companies make their own versions of the products. For example with the popularity of Databricks Microsoft launched their own Fabric solution.

Competition on the free market is happening but RnD power of the big companies means they can replicate a lot of solutions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492377496.0" user="JadedToon" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Amazon, Google and Microsoft are all competing with each other on big data and storage markets. Most websites are hosted by one of the three.

Corporate consolidation is a thing. All three have their own niche where the others won't come in. Windows, the amazon marketplace and google being well...google. 

Similar to cable companies cutting up territories as not to compete.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492436986.0" user="Z7-852" delta="False">
    <text>And yet you have Azure, AWS and Cloud. Practically identical products competing with each others.

And just like your local Falafel joint doesn't sell pasta it doesn't mean they are not competing with the Italian restaurant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493007667.0" user="GeorgeMaheiress" delta="False">
    <text>Google competes with Windows with Chromebooks and Android. Microsoft Bing competes with Google Search. Online shopping is labour and physical-capital-intensive, which are not the typical strengths of tech companies, but other companies like Wal-Mart and Ebay compete with Amazon shopping. Any one of these companies would be very happy to gain market share from the others, it's just difficult to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
