<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="42" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44493794328.0" user="Ginden" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it's totally correct. The most beneficial position for anyone is to fuck up other competitors, but keep all market power for themselves.

This is visible beyond companies - alcohol shop owners will oppose new liquor sale licenses, physicians oppose increase in physician training, homeowners oppose new housing, landlords oppose new housing, Pornhub will support mandatory age verification laws, big companies will support mandatory safety requirements etc.

Big pharmaceuticals companies tried to effectively ban generics, both in US and EU, because they don't want to share profit with smaller companies. For patient's safety, of course, what if you sprout tentacles from generic ibuprofen?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493967282.0" user="sourcreamus" delta="False">
    <text>This is a great point. Regulations and complexity are subsidies to big business much of the anti social media hysteria is fueled by older media companies hating competition. If you look you can see it everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
