<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492374829.0" user="Taolan13" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with modern free market capitalism isnt the market or the capitalism, the problem is the remnants of feudalism that lead to wealth hoarding.

Wealth hoarding is actively detrimental to our economy, so much value is tied up in static assets and inflated accounts that don't change hands for years or decades. Wealth hoarding is a blood clot on the economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492617477.0" user="NimrookFanClub" delta="False">
    <text>Unless they are literally sticking it under a mattress, “hoarded” wealth is still economically productive.

When rich people (or any person) is saving money, they either put it into the stock market or a bank.  If they buy stock then the person who sold them the stock now has cash to reinvest in the economy.  If it goes in a bank the bank can now turn around and lend that money to someone looking to buy a house or start a business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493347914.0" user="HeckaCoolDudeYo" delta="False">
    <text>So what about offshore bank accounts? Also I would argue that's not generally how stocks work irl. Most money in "the market" stays in the market. Also good for the DOW doesn't usually translate to good for common people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493422084.0" user="NimrookFanClub" delta="False">
    <text>By definition money can’t “stay in the market” in the way you are suggesting.  People transact stock for cash.  If those people reinvest that cash back into the stock market (which I think is what you are getting at) it serves an important function in the economy to direct capital towards more productive uses.  More profitable firms’ stock price goes up and it spurs investment in better run companies at the expense of worse run companies.  This self-clearing mechanism promotes efficiency.  This is also why the Dow is a good indicator of the overall health of the economy.

But the Dow is good for more people than you’re suggesting.  While much of the working class doesn’t benefit from a strong stock market directly, the middle class does through 401k and pension funds that are dependent on the stock market.  For the working class, the stock market is a leading indicator of the overall economy, which means a strong stock market leads to companies hiring and vice versa.

I agree that offshoring money is not good for the economy.  Trying to police it is a tricky proposition though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494482700.0" user="HeckaCoolDudeYo" delta="False">
    <text>I understand all of this, but you've still yet to explain how this is beneficial to anyone but the top 1% of earners. Yes, if your pension is wrapped up in the stock market you're gonna want the market high. Many people in this country don't have pensions and many that do will never see them fully mature. While I understand the point you're making, I fear its largely  theoretical. The average person doesn't care about the stock market because it doesn't directly affect their life. The price of goods and services do as well as stagnated wages. All consequences of this countries half in, half out form of capitalism. This countries system has always and will always work incredibly well for the wealthy and moderately well for the middle class, while sucking the working force dry. Until there is no one left to work for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494496619.0" user="HeckaCoolDudeYo" delta="False">
    <text>I'm only 28 and I've lived through many periods so far where the market was high but regular people couldn't afford enough food.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
