<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492395797.0" user="Mcwedlav" delta="False">
    <text>Your example with European EVs makes only sense if there would be a free market to begin with. However, China protects its own market, to the point that EU has several law suits ongoing. For example, the European cars sold in China are almost exclusively produced there, otherwise China wouldn’t let them in (or impose absurd tariffs). 

And this you can continue further and further. EU runs an insane subsidy scheme to protect and keep its farmers competitive, US subsidizes high tech and arms, and many more. 

So, it’s important to consider all these protective and subsidy schemes that are in place to protect national interest industries before drawing conclusions. 

If it comes to start ups: As I am often involved in the take overs/ sales of tech firms: large companies don’t buy because they feel threatened (sometimes they do, but this is a huge exception) but to improve their position against large competitors. If you will ask founders, many found with having the exit in mind already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493366284.0" user="_robjamesmusic" delta="False">
    <text>i feel you’ve explained OP’s point in different words</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493621699.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that it's not the businesses (IE the Capitalists) that are pushing these policies because they hate competition. It's the national governments that are pushing them, intervening in the market whether they are capitalist countries or nominally communist ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493804841.0" user="Mcwedlav" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. That’s what I meant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494011695.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>capitalists do hate competition , what drives then is money and competition needs money to be spread out evenly. monopolies and cooperation make will make then more money.  
 and they certainly support subsidies and protection to their industry as those means they will make money</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494230511.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>Eh, Monopolists hate competition. But monopolists long predated any modern form of capitalism. Government-sponsored monopolies were a common thing in the medieval period. Statutory Monopoly, subsidy, and protectionism were the default until the modern period. We're gradually moving away from it, and while some who own businesses are eager to see themselves 'heavily regulated' in a way that benefits themselves the long term trend is leading us away from such things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494350761.0" user="aluminun_soda" delta="False">
    <text>"monopolists" are capitalists dont try and separate then.

 theres no private property without goverment , but its not like its just the goverment pushing for private property so dont blame only the goverment either.  
protectionism and subsidies definitely weren't the norm till modern periods.  
for one there was less production before the industrial revolution so local economies hardly faced probrems like that.  
and there were hardly any monopolies even the richest landowers wouldnt have was much farmland as someone like billgates today</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494529080.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>Except monopolists existed long before capitalists did, and capitalism is a reaction against older economic orders that prominently featured state monopolies. A major driver of the Personal Rule of King Charles I of England was the fact that he ruled without parliament because he was able to fund his household via other means, one of the biggest was taking money to grant royal monopolies on everything from trade with Russia to soap. It was *incredibly common* for medieval tradesmen to get royal charters that prohibited anyone else from making this or that, where did you think concepts like intellectual property and patents and trademarks came from? 

Protectionism was *MUCH WORSE* in the ancient period where foreign goods were basically inaccessible and banned by default, with foreign merchants requiring approval from the local king or chieftain to exist in their territory much less do business. Free trade is something that has been historically flirted with, but concepts like "freedom of the seas" didn't become real things until the modern period. Just because you're unfamiliar with historical norms doesn't mean that they don't exist.

Private property is something defined by law, but it is also driven by the desire of the government to tax. It's hard to tax collectively, there's far more power opposing the government and a nearly infinite kinds of sleight of hand to hide property from the government when people cooperate. It's far easier to tax people more when you're taxing an individual.

&gt; and there were hardly any monopolies even the richest landowers wouldnt have was much farmland as someone like billgates today

And next you're going to tell me that people that Mansa Musa weren't as wealthy as Bill Gates.

Or that the British East India company wasn't a government-chartered monopoly that was at it height bigger than any tech giant today.

If you're going to make assertions about the past please at least make them plausible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494020473.0" user="ampillion" delta="False">
    <text>The US is a representative democracy. The national government is composed of hundreds of representatives, many of whom are largely bankrolled by... capitalists. While some might themselves be wealthy, they all employ copious amounts of money from national political parties, that all get that money from... capitalists.  


Am I supposed to believe that large amounts of money spent at donor dinners, setting up PACs, and getting representatives elected is ENTIRELY SEPARATE from the actions of the government that push or intervene in the markets? Or, in the reverse, that the government is just suddenly going 'Oh, man, we should definitely stop doing public education or package delivery, so we can instead pump money into private companies and charter schooling', because that... doesn't sound like a particularly smart move by a government that itself is concerned in intervening in markets.   


Because that doesn't sound particularly logical. We can't pretend that money is the biggest problem in politics, but also separate that from the reality of what that money is supposed to buy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494271720.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>So capitalists can influence some of what the national government does. Are you now asserting that politicians have no agency of their own and are nothing more than puppets?

Money is a problem in politics, but it's not the be all and end all. Any politician could do whatever they want and still get all the campaign contributions they want from businesses generally. They are as exactly as beholden to business as they want to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494340954.0" user="ampillion" delta="False">
    <text>Please explain to me why a capitalist would give money to a politician that doesn't do the things they want?

Do you regularly pay for services that you don't intend to get?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494445593.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>They pay for access, not for results, and quite often they don't get what they want on this or that topic but in order to have the chance to influence future legislation they continue to contribute. If they don't then they are simply ignored.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494684679.0" user="ampillion" delta="False">
    <text>So what happens when they get ignored? Do they just continue to shell out money to the same politician? Or do they find a less scrupulous politician that'll be more willing to push for the things they want with their access?  


Because if the answer is no, they'll just keep giving money to whoever regardless of the results, then the reality is that money isn't a problem in politics, and political parties should take money from anyone and everybody under the sun, including foreign powers, because it doesn't matter. After all, the only time it does matter is when the government actually acts on those requests.   


Clearly requests are acted upon, because businesses and wealthy people still contribute large amounts of money, which would seem like a silly waste if politicians never acted upon their requests. What I'm saying is that, if your system requires you to get funding to get elected, or be independently wealthy, then there's always a greater chance that a politician will absolutely fulfill the requests of a donor. Otherwise nobody would ever donate to a politician if there was no ROI.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44494794565.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>If they get ignored nothing happens. They might try to put more money behind someone in a primary, but political parties don't have a lot of control over who people vote for campaign contributions or no. So, it's more of a just in case sort of deal.

The problem isn't that already established politicians are being bribed. The problem is that people who are aggressively anti-business never get started in the first place. And the access means that companies can write draft legislation about something the politician is trying to do something about that they then pass along for consideration as their own work, it's the lazy rather than the actively corrupt that messes with the institutions we rely on. It's the reason why so many business groups are anti-regulation, wait a few years, and then pass a new set of regulations. They want *their* regulation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44495208478.0" user="ampillion" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;it's the lazy rather than the actively corrupt that messes with the institutions we rely on

Why can't those be one in the same? After all, a lazy politician would be very easy to actively corrupt, because a business interest would basically do all their work for them.  


And while sure, political parties can't actively control who people vote for, they can actively try to shape messaging that steers lower-information voters towards particular candidates. So if the party hates, say, Sanders' universal health care initiatives because large health care interests want to keep ahold of a cash cow, they might drum up messaging that tries to make those plans unrealistic, or undermine the messenger in other ways. Just as parties shape the candidates for other parties (Such as RFK jr being funded by Republicans, and Democrats pushing for Trump in the primary, because they think it helps them to put those people forward.)   


It doesn't guarantee votes, it doesn't always mean that whoever spends the most money wins, but if money is access, then having more access means more opportunity to spread your messaging, and in smaller races, having any sort of decent funding backing you is a far bigger boon than in larger, nation-wide races.   


&gt; It's the reason why so many business groups are anti-regulation, wait a few years, and then pass a new set of regulations. They want their regulation.

This kinda goes back on the initial premise though doesn't it? It isn't the *government* that's requesting regulation in this instance. It's the businesses lobbying for things to go their way. Which, in fact, would agree with what I asserted from the beginning, that it isn't the government interfering with markets because they can, but because lobbying groups want them to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
