<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492558584.0" user="scenia" delta="False">
    <text>In my opinion, this can't be properly addressed without first clarifying what exactly you mean by "free market". The theoretical construct used in economics, for example, assumes fully independent actors with independent preferences, perfect information and absolute agency regarding their choices. Such a market doesn't exist in reality, and arguably can't.

What is often referred to as "free market" by libertarians specifically is a market with no governmental involvement, so no taxes, tariffs, regulations, subsidies, or similar interventions. But this is, in practice, often further from the theoretical construct used in economics than the regulated markets we have because real markets are affected by a variety of limitations, including but not limited to asymmetrical information, externalities, dependencies and natural monopolies like network effects.

So what exactly defines a free market in the context of your view?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
