<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44493703749.0" user="phoenixthekat" delta="False">
    <text>Capitalists look for competitive advantages. The easiest one is money. Yes, large companies try to simply buy out smaller companies. It's a cost of maintaining market position but if the small company refuses, all their money is meaningless. 

This is when shit gets stupid and most of you get so close to seeing the real problem but somehow miss it. These large companies then instead use government to kill their competitors either through regulation, which make it harder for competitors to even exist, or outright ban competitors like you've seen social media companies try to do to TikTok. 

In the end, companies just do whatever they can to maintain or improve market position. The actual real problem that creates these permanent, "too big to fail" type companies is government. Government cronies creates the conditions for a monopoly to exist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
