<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2714002651.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18vuhuj/cmv_capitalists_hates_the_free_market/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalists hates the free market</title>
    <original_poster>SulemanDawood</original_poster>
    <original_post>Big businesses hat the idea of smaller companies rising up and challenging their market dominance which is why they try their absolute hardest to buy out every single startup they can. FAANG companies are notorious for this. They spend absurdly large sums of money which could be used to innovate on pointless mergers and acquisitions to avoid having to deal with the 'free' market. This is true even in the EU. The recent rise of Chinese EVs is driving european EVs out of the market and these companies are actively seeking to get them banned to save their own skins. Google, Amazon and Apple all continuously engage in anti-competitive practices to drive out competition because they can't deal with the fact that they can not innovate like smaller firms can. In the end capitalists are the ones destroying capitalism.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44492687221.0" user="MarsupialFar4924" delta="False">
    <text>The "free market" is a libertarian fantasy that has never existed in practice in the modern age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44492745676.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn’t describe real life as a libertarian fantasy, they never had that much power. At least outside of Argentina for the last few weeks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493656707.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>They're saying that the "free market" doesn't exist in real life and all markets that have actually existed have been regulated in some way. Any discussion of a real "free market" is libertarian theory rather than something that exists in practice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44493846120.0" user="MarsupialFar4924" delta="False">
    <text>It's less about regulation and more about how corporations have always manipulated markets. Free market assumes everyone is playing by the rules of the game, when in reality companies do things like work with their competitors to engage in price fixing, inflate their values then dump stocks, and bribe politicians to influence legislation in their favor. It's always been that way. Free market is a myth.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
