<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="272376242.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4i5yuq/cmv_premeditated_1st_degree_murder_is_never/">
    <title>CMV: Premeditated 1st degree murder is never absolutely and objectively the wrong thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>eobversion1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Murder being morally wrong is determined by a consensus of opinions of the electorate, supported by politicians and written into the constitution of every country. I would argue that differences in circumstance and moral relativism will never make it a black and white issue. It's easy to think of it that way and most people take it for granted. Even in cases of genocide there was conviction on the part of the perpetrator that it was somehow morally justified, you and I may viciously disagree with their stance and international criminal courts might put them to death because of it but to them and at that moment it was the right thing to do. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28471918137.0" user="errhhbrerrh" delta="False">
    <text>Morality is a tool used for justifying actions that are illogical.  
Objectively, morality has no place in law. Crime is followed by punishment. Murder is a crime. So, if someone commits murder, they are punished. 

A premeditated murder will be morally right or wrong to different people. 
But, laws are not for creating morality, but for maintaining order and lowering the level of chaos in society.  
Whether or not a murder is "right" or "wrong",  murder is a crime.  

 


</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
