<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="272376242.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4i5yuq/cmv_premeditated_1st_degree_murder_is_never/">
    <title>CMV: Premeditated 1st degree murder is never absolutely and objectively the wrong thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>eobversion1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Murder being morally wrong is determined by a consensus of opinions of the electorate, supported by politicians and written into the constitution of every country. I would argue that differences in circumstance and moral relativism will never make it a black and white issue. It's easy to think of it that way and most people take it for granted. Even in cases of genocide there was conviction on the part of the perpetrator that it was somehow morally justified, you and I may viciously disagree with their stance and international criminal courts might put them to death because of it but to them and at that moment it was the right thing to do. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28471937865.0" user="GenderNeutralLanguag" delta="False">
    <text>Your arguing a tautology isn't a tautology.

Murder is the case where killing someone is absolutely and objectively and morally the wrong thing to do.

There are many cases where killing someone IS NOT wrong, but these cases are not murder.

Murder is the word for when you kill someone AND it is wrong to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28472569929.0" user="fryamtheiman" delta="False">
    <text>No, murder is the word for a crime which certain elements apply to, regardless of whether the law recognizes the particular act as right or wrong (justified or unjustified). When a person on trial for murder claims self defense, they are not contesting the fact that a murder occurred. Self defense simply claims there was a legally justifiable excuse for committing the crime which nullifies the legal consequences for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28472711362.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Not quite. Homicide is defined as the killing of a human being by another human being. Murder is defined as an unlawful homicide. Executing a condemned prisoner is a homicide, but it's not unlawful. Murder is further defined as an unlawful homicide with malice aforethought. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28472773932.0" user="fryamtheiman" delta="False">
    <text>Affirmative defense:

&amp;gt; A defense in which the defendant introduces evidence, which, if found to be credible, *will negate criminal or civil liability, even if it is proven that the defendant committed the alleged acts.* [Source](https://www.law.cornell.edu/wex/affirmative_defense)

&amp;gt; In some criminal cases the defendant *admits committing a criminal act.* A legal excuse or justification may exist. This is an affirmative defense. [Source](http://www.shestokas.com/general-law/affirmative-defenses-to-criminal-charges-self-necessity-entrapment-insanity/)

&amp;gt; With an affirmative defense, *the defendant admits guilt to committing the crime*, but uses an affirmation defense to introduce additional facts or explanation to justify his or her conduct. [Source](http://criminal-law.freeadvice.com/criminal-law/criminal-law/affirmative-defenses.htm)

From the same source as above:

&amp;gt; Justification defenses say that, *though the defendant did the crime, there were very good reasons for doing so*. The above example in which the defendant used self-defense as a justification for killing her husband is an example of this type of affirmative defense. Other justification defenses include defense of property, defense of others, law enforcement defense, and necessity.

Another affirmative defense which does this is the necessity defense. 

&amp;gt; A defense that *permits a person to act in a criminal manner* when an emergency situation, not of the person's own creation compels the person to act in a criminal manner to avoid greater harm from occurring. [Source](http://nationalparalegal.edu/public_documents/courseware_asp_files/criminalLaw/defenses/NecessityandDuress.asp)

If I break into a house in order to call the police because someone is chasing me and trying to kill me, I did commit the crime of breaking and entering, but I am legally justified in doing so. 

As for murder, I had specifically said: 

&amp;gt; murder is the word for a crime *which certain elements apply to*

The use of the word "elements" clearly states (to those familiar with law) there are certain stipulations that are required for proving murder, which includes malice aforethought. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
