<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="272376242.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4i5yuq/cmv_premeditated_1st_degree_murder_is_never/">
    <title>CMV: Premeditated 1st degree murder is never absolutely and objectively the wrong thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>eobversion1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Murder being morally wrong is determined by a consensus of opinions of the electorate, supported by politicians and written into the constitution of every country. I would argue that differences in circumstance and moral relativism will never make it a black and white issue. It's easy to think of it that way and most people take it for granted. Even in cases of genocide there was conviction on the part of the perpetrator that it was somehow morally justified, you and I may viciously disagree with their stance and international criminal courts might put them to death because of it but to them and at that moment it was the right thing to do. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28471767468.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Are you coming from the belief that NOTHING is absolutely and objectively wrong?  If so, then this isn't really about murder but about objective morality.

If not, then can you tell us something that IS objectively wrong, so we can better understand your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28471785228.0" user="eobversion1" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that individual morality cannot make murder objectively wrong no matter how popular and lawful that idea is. 

Something that is objectively right are what I believe are only concrete historical (the Japanese bombed Pearl Harbour) mathematical (1+1=2) and scientifically proven (gravity) truths. I would argue that attempting to deny such truths is objectively wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28471827153.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>Morality and mathematics are very similar in this actually. 

Whether something is true or not in math depends entirely on what fundamental assumptions you are making. The truth of a statement like 1+1=2 depends on whether it agrees with the axioms we assume to be true. We can even construct new branches of mathematics by making different assumptions. 1+1=2 is objectively true in the math we use every day, but it's not necessarily objectively true in any arbitrary system of math.

Morality is the same. Morality is the question of how you should act based on your values, and your values are the axioms of this system. Just like the axioms in math, the values you select are largely arbitrary, and having different values will give rise to different moral systems. Once you've established a moral system, you can make some pretty objective statements about what is moral and what is not. But you can do this in mathematics too. In one system of mathematics you can objectively state that 1+1=2 and in another system it's not true.

Ultimately asking whether murder is objectively wrong in some universal sense isn't really a meaningful question. You can't evaluate one moral system using the values of another just like you can't evaluate truth of a claim made in one system of math using the assumptions of another system of math.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28471871366.0" user="ThatBelligerentSloth" delta="False">
    <text>But we don't work with different definitions of math, but we do work with different definitions of morality, in facts it's almost guaranteed under your system. Moreover it just speaks to the huge gap between how agreeable the intuitions math is based on and the intuitions which we use to pick up morality are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28471891791.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But we don't work with different definitions of math

Sure we do. For example, if you drop the axiom that parallel lines never intersect then you can get [non-euclidian geometry](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-Euclidean_geometry) , which does have applications.

&amp;gt;but we do work with different definitions of morality, in facts it's almost guaranteed under your system.

I'm not really clear what you're saying here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28472702774.0" user="HarryWragg" delta="False">
    <text>Sure we do. In high school, you probably talked about Imaginary Numbers. How did they come about? Someone just said "What if sqrt(-1) *did* exist?" 

The more math classes you take in college, the more true you find this. Abstract Algebra, for example, is a way of proving theorems about sets that have specific properties (such as having operators that are associative, commutative etc.) without having to know anything specific about what those sets contain. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28471876773.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't believe in objective morality, what do you see as the point of discussing whether a particular act is objectivity wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28471909744.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>I believe the point being made is that **nothing** is objectively wrong.  Murder, I think, is just being used as an example to illustrate the point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28472264195.0" user="eobversion1" delta="False">
    <text>Murder being morally wrong depends on what weight you attach to that value and what circumstances it takes place in. My argument is that you cannot come to an absolutist conclusion that the act of murder is wrong. This is opposed to other matters of fact that are true whether or not you believe in it, like 25 being a bigger number than 3. There's no black and white answer to that. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
