<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="272376242.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4i5yuq/cmv_premeditated_1st_degree_murder_is_never/">
    <title>CMV: Premeditated 1st degree murder is never absolutely and objectively the wrong thing to do.</title>
    <original_poster>eobversion1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Murder being morally wrong is determined by a consensus of opinions of the electorate, supported by politicians and written into the constitution of every country. I would argue that differences in circumstance and moral relativism will never make it a black and white issue. It's easy to think of it that way and most people take it for granted. Even in cases of genocide there was conviction on the part of the perpetrator that it was somehow morally justified, you and I may viciously disagree with their stance and international criminal courts might put them to death because of it but to them and at that moment it was the right thing to do. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28472012829.0" user="TryUsingScience" delta="False">
    <text>Other people are taking other tacks, so, what is your definition of "wrong?" Do you only mean morally wrong? What about incorrect?

For example, let's say I think my friend's boyfriend is abusing her. So I lie in wait for him and then shoot him dead. But it turns out that they were in a healthy and mutually enjoyable BDSM relationship. She loved him, he was a great guy, and she is now grief-stricken. 

My goal in killing him was to kill a terrible person and improve my friend's life, but it turns out I've done the opposite of both those things. Was I not then wrong to have killed him?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28472108629.0" user="eobversion1" delta="False">
    <text>You were mistaken in your assumption about the nature of their relationship, it has no impact on the crime. What if doing that isn't a big deal to you? Maybe that same guy was behind on his car loan repayments, it doesn't justify you killing him but it throws shade into the question however small that might be. My point is that killing someone that there will always be shade in question, you can never blacken the act of murder so badly that it would be THE WRONG THING TO DO by EVERYONES DEFINITION. Circumstance and morality don't allow for that to be the case. It touches the very tenants of human and animal nature to colonise and reproduce and preserve what we have built. It mightn't legally and socially be the acceptable thing to do but it'll never be something that's objectively wrong like saying water is dry.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
