<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="276378140.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4kjqqk/cmv_the_fact_there_are_certain_weapons_that_i_as/">
    <title>CMV: The fact there are certain weapons that I as a private citizen can't own is inconsistent logic of the use of the Second Amendment.</title>
    <original_poster>quixoticromantic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The second amendment: A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.

Arms: Weapons and ammunition; armaments

As you can see, the second amendment doesn't define what arms really mean, so I also provided Oxford dictionary's definition of arms. 

As a private citizen, there are certain weapons and ammunition that I can't own. To me this suggests that there is a certain definition of what constitutes arms and it's up to our current society and current legislature to define what that means. With the logic I am using, this means that guns aren't inherently arms or fall within the second amendment. It would not be unconstitutional to outlaw guns if society decides to do so. Guns aren't inherently protected under the second amendment in other words. It is only this current society and legislature that does include it.

So basically to sum up my argument and, at least to me, keep the logic consistent, I should be able to own any and all weapons available or guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment.

Change my view!

Edit: Two redditors have succesfully convinced me that the second amendment does limit the owning of certain weapons. However this doesn't mean that my other view point has changed. Guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment, and the outlawing of guns could still be possible without getting rid of the Second amendment

Second Edit: to clarify how to now change my view, you have to convince me that the limitations that aleady exist in the second amendment can't somehow be extended to any and all guns.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28505480457.0" user="Mofroman007" delta="False">
    <text>In the Era of the writing of the second amendment, weapons were different in their potency and ability for abuse. Modern advances in weaponry has made it so that there are unintended dangers that simply didn't exist back in the late 18th century. If someone snapped, you couldn't go on a shooting spree with a musket. If a 6 year old found his dad's musket, there wasn't a danger of the child killing someone. The second amendment made perfect sense in an Era, but in an age of semi-automatic handguns and fully automatic rifles, there are additional caveats that the writers of the bill of right could not have foreseen or accounted for in their laws. 

In short: the modern definition of arms could not have possibly been the same as the during the writing of the bill of rights. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505488331.0" user="ryan_m" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The second amendment made perfect sense in an Era, but in an age of semi-automatic handguns and fully automatic rifles, there are additional caveats that the writers of the bill of right could not have foreseen or accounted for in their laws.

They wrote it that way because the arms are meant to be used for self defense and resisting the government. They had just finished fighting a war in which the soldiers regularly used their own weapons and saw a clear utility in allowing citizens to keep "weapons of war" in case it needed to be done again. They were *very* clear on this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505569710.0" user="Mofroman007" delta="False">
    <text>But talking about "weapons of war" at time made sense purely because these weapons only made sense as a weapon of war. In the 1700s, "weapons of war" were not rapidly deadly enough to be abused by civilian use. I'm not arguing what should be allowed or not, I'm only explaining why certain arms are not allowed under current law and why the definition of "weapons of war" meant something different over 200 years ago. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505584930.0" user="ryan_m" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In the 1700s, "weapons of war" were not rapidly deadly enough to be abused by civilian use

So because of mass shootings, we're going to limit a Constitutional right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505593272.0" user="Mofroman007" delta="False">
    <text>a.) Once again, I am explain why something is the way it is, not the way it should be and b.) And yes, it would seem as though some people believe that preventing mass shootings by limiting the second amendment is a valid tradeoff. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506756152.0" user="Brimshae" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In the 1700s, "weapons of war" were not rapidly deadly enough to be abused by civilian use

1&amp;gt; Repeating rifles have been around since the 1600s. Kalthoff, Lorenzoni, Cookson (who basically marketted his own version of the Lorenzoni) all had early multishot rifles named after them.

2&amp;gt; The Belton Flintlock could fire 20 rounds at up to four rounds a second. The only reason the US didn't adopt these as a form of service weapon is because Belton wanted to much money for them, and the newly formed Congress turned down his bid. It was also available in a handgun size. 

3&amp;gt; Puckleguns were basically a proto-Gatlinggun, the rounds were preloaded in a manner similar to modern removable-cylinder revolvers and could be changed in a similar manner. 

4&amp;gt; Additionally, artillery (cannons, mortars, pre-Congreve rockets) were commonly owned by private citizens. 

5&amp;gt; I fail to see why or how advancement of one technology would advance it out of legal protection. The very idea strikes me as very regressive and backwards, but you're welcome to try to CMV. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505509898.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you. That's why I believe that the logic is guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment and that is up to our society to decide what arms constitutes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505597335.0" user="SpenceNaz88" delta="False">
    <text>The Girardoni air rifle existed at that time. It had a 20 round capacity and fired .46 caliber balls. The air reservoir was good for 30 shots, and soldiers equipped with these rifles carried multiple reservoirs in reserve. You could easily fire 20 shots with one of these in less than a minute. I think it's well within reason to think that those who wrote the 2nd amendment were intelligent enough to know that technological advances would be made and the possibility of repercussions. I think it's more about the ability of the individual than just "everyone is allowed to have muskets".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506734954.0" user="Brimshae" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  If someone snapped, you couldn't go on a shooting spree with a musket.

No, repeating rifles were a thing even during that era. One could use those, instead. 

The Girandoni air rifle fired a round slightly smaller than common anti-materiel rifles of today, and had a 22-shot capacity. 

It took a while to initially pump up, was quite capable of killing any number of creatures, man or beast. 

[Lorenzoni repaters](http://firearmshistory.blogspot.com/2014/02/the-lorenzoni-repeater.html) were available in what we might now call pistol and rifle configurations. They were developed in the mid-1600s. 

&amp;gt;To reload this firearm, the user points the gun downwards and rotates the long lever forward and back. On the forward motion, a measured amount of gunpowder and a single ball fall from their respective magazines into their separate chambers in the revolving breech drum.

This would be a fire rate roughly equivalent to a modern single-action revolver or bolt/lever-action rifle, which can be quite fast with a bit of practice. 

Cannons, mortars, other artillery were commonly owned by private citizens and many were employed for defense of both home and country. 

&amp;gt;In short: the modern definition of arms could not have possibly been the same as the during the writing of the bill of rights. 

Does this mean you can and/or should be censored from making non-threatening, non-libelous statements by way of your computer?

The modern definition of speech could not have possibly been the same as during the writing of the Bill of Rights. 

Does this mean that our cars, cell phones, and computers are not protected by the Fourth Amendment? Your desktop computer and, for many, your laptop are not personal items commonly worn or carried about your person.

The modern definition of what is protected ("persons, houses, papers, and effects") could not have possibly been the same as during the writing of the Bill of Rights. 

I fail to see why or how advancement of one technology would advance it out of legal protection. The very idea strikes me as very regressive and backwards, but you're welcome to try to CMV. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
