<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="276378140.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4kjqqk/cmv_the_fact_there_are_certain_weapons_that_i_as/">
    <title>CMV: The fact there are certain weapons that I as a private citizen can't own is inconsistent logic of the use of the Second Amendment.</title>
    <original_poster>quixoticromantic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The second amendment: A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.

Arms: Weapons and ammunition; armaments

As you can see, the second amendment doesn't define what arms really mean, so I also provided Oxford dictionary's definition of arms. 

As a private citizen, there are certain weapons and ammunition that I can't own. To me this suggests that there is a certain definition of what constitutes arms and it's up to our current society and current legislature to define what that means. With the logic I am using, this means that guns aren't inherently arms or fall within the second amendment. It would not be unconstitutional to outlaw guns if society decides to do so. Guns aren't inherently protected under the second amendment in other words. It is only this current society and legislature that does include it.

So basically to sum up my argument and, at least to me, keep the logic consistent, I should be able to own any and all weapons available or guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment.

Change my view!

Edit: Two redditors have succesfully convinced me that the second amendment does limit the owning of certain weapons. However this doesn't mean that my other view point has changed. Guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment, and the outlawing of guns could still be possible without getting rid of the Second amendment

Second Edit: to clarify how to now change my view, you have to convince me that the limitations that aleady exist in the second amendment can't somehow be extended to any and all guns.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28505531312.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>The Second Amendment has a preamble for a reason.  "A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State"

In other words, private citizens should hold and train in the use of arms such that they can form a militia at a moment's notice.  The common people thus need to possess any weapons an army might possess.  Hence Article 1 Section 8 provides that when Congress raises an Army, it can be for no longer than two years.  

Now a Navy is a different beast.  Congress can maintain a standing Navy, because warships are expensive and complicated to maintain.  Not to mention, it is not an important bulwark against tyranny that private citizens possess warships - those would be too expensive for general use, and a few people with warships doesn't provide the same security against oppression that a general populace with rifles provides.

There are certain armaments that were invented after the Constitution (planes, ICBMs, etc) that are not specifically mentioned.  Perhaps these deserve an Amendment to make the Air Force Constitutional.  Alternatively, by the "living Constitution" approach, when determining whether to treat these as rifles for a Militia or Army or to treat them as warships for a Navy, I think the key question is expense.  Are they cheap enough that random surgeons might realistically play with them as a hobby and field them in wartime?  Or are they so expensive that the men who could afford them would all know one another?  Nukes and stealth bombers clearly fall in the latter category.  Tanks clearly fall in the former category.  We can argue over attack helicopters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505542505.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Correct me if I'm wrong, but there numerous automated weapons well within the budget of thousands of citizens that are still banned. 

Also if the point of a militia is to fight against an army, then how will a militia armed with pistols and hunting rifles fight against the US army?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505656211.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Correct me if I'm wrong, but there numerous automated weapons well within the budget of thousands of citizens that are still banned.

Agreed.  It is my belief that assault weapons bans, bans on tanks, etc are Unconstitutional, but that bans on bombers and warships are Constitutional.

&amp;gt;Also if the point of a militia is to fight against an army, then how will a militia armed with pistols and hunting rifles fight against the US army?

The point of a militia is in part to *be* the US army.  As such, I think militias ought to be armed with automatic rifles.  

However, militias could certainly face the US army. They have in Afghanistan, and would do even better on US soil if they had a just cause.  If they could stand long enough against the first troops sent, then we'd expect soldiers and officers to defect in droves with their equipment.  As we saw in so many countries recently (most dramatically Libya), most soldiers are only willing to fire on their countrymen if they don't think.  Give them time to think about it, and they will refuse such orders and join a rebellion.  Mercenaries may feel differently which is why Gaddafi had to rely so heavily on Tuareg mercenaries once people started fighting back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505712907.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Can you clarify what exactly makes a weapon constitutional? You stated early that a militia should possess weapons an army should possess. But would that not include tanks and navy ships? But later in your first comment you talk about the main factor being expense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505761276.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>An army, which the Consitution permits to exist for two year stretches when needed, possesses tanks.  A militia can and should possess those.  Otherwise, how could the army get them up and running in wartime?  

A navy possesses warships while an army does not.  We need a standing navy because if we tried to raise one for a two year period we'd be decommissioning ships before they were even finished being built.  Hence the Constitution permits a standing navy and does not require it to be a two year temporary navy.

I understand that the US currently operates under a ridiculous loophole where we promise to everyone that our army's funding will be renewed indefinitely and will not disappear in two years.  To the point that contracts go past two years, soldiers are enlisted for longer than two years, etc.  If the Founders had intended this, they would not have put in the two year funding clause for the army.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506122271.0" user="pollandballer" delta="False">
    <text>You can't be serious, can you? Because you realize that the United States Army would be defeated in battle in short order if it didn't have a full-time, standing army component, and then we wouldn't have any Constitution at all, would we? Surely you are joking when you imply that the US should be activating Guard units or the Army of the United States ever single time it needs to fight a war in an era when a real WWIII would be decided in weeks, or, with nuclear weapons, hours. I also really, really hope that you think the Air Force is constitutional as well, because you are capable of reading beyond the literal letter of the law when deciding what is legal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506147369.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can't be serious, can you?

Of course I am.

First off, the US Army would not be defeated on our own soil, only on adventures abroad.  Second, something being good or necessary doesn't make it Constitutional.  By all means amend the Constitution if necessary.  But understand its words as they were meant, not as it would be convenient to mean them now.  The goal was to allow the citizens to be the army when necessary.  If hypothetically that goal is no longer a worthwhile one, that doesn't change what was then meant by the Second Amendment.

&amp;gt;I also really, really hope that you think the Air Force is constitutional as well

I think it would be reasonable to consider it under the same terms as the Navy, since it's not capable of being an occupying force like an army is and since it needs those expensive ships.  It doesn't bother me to think of it as using the same concept as the Navy and not the same concept as the Army.  Though it would have been cleaner to just amend the Constitution to make that explicit.

Also, um, WWIII?  A major goal of the Constitution was to ensure we would never enter a world war.  By all means, amend it as necessary, but don't say the Constitution "couldn't" mean a thing because it's convenient to do things the Founders wanted to prevent us from doing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506185374.0" user="pollandballer" delta="False">
    <text>I know the founding fathers didn't exactly love standing armies, but even they had to compromise on this one. George Washington himself created the modern standing US Army and every founding father who was President maintained a standing Army as well. Since there's no clause prohibiting indefinite renewal of the Army's peacetime funding, I see no reason that the standing army would be unconstitutional. Finally, there is another major problem in your idea: the fact that the Army's strength is contained in more than just tanks, but in the skills of professional NCO's and officers with 10-20 years of active experience. Without these, an army can be defeated on its own soil, as the experience of the post-purge Red Army in WWII demonstrates. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506817867.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I know the founding fathers didn't exactly love standing armies, but even they had to compromise on this one. George Washington himself created the modern standing US Army and every founding father who was President maintained a standing Army as well.

For a reason: the US was at war.  It was at war during Washington's entire tenure, and it has been at war all but 21 of its years of existence.


&amp;gt;Since there's no clause prohibiting indefinite renewal of the Army's peacetime funding, I see no reason that the standing army would be unconstitutional.

There's certainly no reason not to renew the Army in wartime.  It seems contrary to the Founders' intent to renew it during peacetime.  It seems Unconstitutional to sign contracts and enlist men for terms longer than the two year break.

I don't mind changing the Constitution to allow a standing army, and I'm sure that amendment would pass.  My claim is more about the Second Amendment, which would have to be changed separately, and would likely not be.

&amp;gt;the fact that the Army's strength is contained in more than just tanks, but in the skills of professional NCO's and officers with 10-20 years of active experience... post-purge Red Army

The hit to professionalism that we'd take having our NCOs and officers practice in militias and military leagues on weekends rather than having soldiering as their sole career is much smaller than the hit to professionalism that we'd take if we murdered our best men.

But again, if the Court made it clear that it intended to actually uphold the Constitution as written, I would expect an immediate amendment rather than an actual change in the Army.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
