<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="276378140.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4kjqqk/cmv_the_fact_there_are_certain_weapons_that_i_as/">
    <title>CMV: The fact there are certain weapons that I as a private citizen can't own is inconsistent logic of the use of the Second Amendment.</title>
    <original_poster>quixoticromantic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The second amendment: A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.

Arms: Weapons and ammunition; armaments

As you can see, the second amendment doesn't define what arms really mean, so I also provided Oxford dictionary's definition of arms. 

As a private citizen, there are certain weapons and ammunition that I can't own. To me this suggests that there is a certain definition of what constitutes arms and it's up to our current society and current legislature to define what that means. With the logic I am using, this means that guns aren't inherently arms or fall within the second amendment. It would not be unconstitutional to outlaw guns if society decides to do so. Guns aren't inherently protected under the second amendment in other words. It is only this current society and legislature that does include it.

So basically to sum up my argument and, at least to me, keep the logic consistent, I should be able to own any and all weapons available or guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment.

Change my view!

Edit: Two redditors have succesfully convinced me that the second amendment does limit the owning of certain weapons. However this doesn't mean that my other view point has changed. Guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment, and the outlawing of guns could still be possible without getting rid of the Second amendment

Second Edit: to clarify how to now change my view, you have to convince me that the limitations that aleady exist in the second amendment can't somehow be extended to any and all guns.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28505466769.0" user="appropriate-username" delta="False">
    <text>Should you be able to own nukes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505476912.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>I'm more concerned with the logic behind the second amendment rather then the second amendment itself.

To give an ambiguous answer, I believe that lethal force should only ever be used in self defense. I also don't really distinguish any one type of lethal force from another because they all accomplish the same thing. However I believe that having the privilege of thought and reason gives me the responsibility to use that logic and reason before I jump to any decisions that might have consequences that I don't want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505481091.0" user="appropriate-username" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; they all accomplish the same thing

I think it's quote obvious that nukes and knives (or rocks or sponges wielded as weapons) accomplish vastly different things.

&amp;gt;reason gives me the responsibility

Do you trust everyone else's thought and reason (and continued sanity) enough to give them nukes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505499502.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that the consequences of certain lethal force ( nuclear radiation for example) is outside of the right itself of using lethal force, and is up to the individual or this case societies discretion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505508355.0" user="appropriate-username" delta="False">
    <text>So...why not apply this to other weapons? Society has decreed that the consequences of fully automatic rifles (high chance of unintended casualties) are outside of the right of using lethal force and thereby banned them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505514563.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>I am applying this to all weapons. That is why I'm saying guns themselves (even simple pistols) aren't inherently part of the arms named in the second amendment. I'm saying the second amendment can still exist without the right to own any gun.

Edit: in other words, society can declare that the use of any gun is outside the right of using lethal force. Having guns inherently be part of the Second amendment is inconsistent logic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505523386.0" user="ryan_m" delta="False">
    <text>Just so you know, the Supreme Court [disagrees](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/District_of_Columbia_v._Heller) with your interpretation of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505526337.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>At one time, the supreme court agreed that separate but equal was constitutional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506549457.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>That is not a sound argument.

Holding an incorrect position at some arbitrary time in the past doesn't mean their current rulings can be discounted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507195593.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>He used a logical fallacy called Appeal to Authority. I wasn't going to waste time arguing with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507228118.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>It's not an appeal to authority when the authority is specific to the topic being discussed.

Just like it isn't an appeal to authority to cite doctors for medical advice.

It's asinine to say the supreme court's rulings regarding a matter of constitutional law are an appeal to authority when it is literally the definition of the supreme court's job to make rulings regarding constitutional law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507279196.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>You are right. I was quick to dismiss it. I know the supreme court's opinion on it. I know my opinion is contrary to it. I just felt it didn't really add anything to the argument.so my quick response being aware of the fallible nature of man and by extension the supreme court was to give that example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28508821184.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I just felt it didn't really add anything to the argument.

The supreme court is the *supreme* authority on the definition of the constitution.

Their opinion on what it means is pretty relevant to a discussion on the definition of a constitutional amendment.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509303259.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Check out rule 5 of changemyview. That's what I meant by it not adding anything to the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509314311.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>So instead of responding to the fact that the supreme Court disagrees with your definition of what constitutes arms you are saying the poster who went to all that trouble to link that is making low effort posts?

That's pretty low effort of you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509323658.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Well of course my response to what is clearly defined by the rules as a low effort post was low effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509335128.0" user="PrimeLegionnaire" delta="False">
    <text>You are not the arbiter of low effort.

If you believe a post to be low effort you report it to the mods.

You do not get to use your interpretation of low effort as a shield against a valid criticism of your position if you want anyone to take you seriously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509355653.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>You are right. I handled the situation poorly. I was too quick to dismiss it. I'll do my best to either respond to the question appropriately or contact the mods if something else like this occurs. And I'm sorry for this scuttle that we have been having. I went on the defensive without even really being able to justify my actions. While this argument doesn't really relate to my post so much anymore (so I can't award a delta), you have changed my view!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28508645173.0" user="Hadrianunlimited" delta="False">
    <text>in this case the supreme court is the authority on what the constitution means</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28508897171.0" user="paganize" delta="False">
    <text>After reading your comments, I doubt I can change your view. it would depend on the answer to this: Do you think the 2nd amendment is a collective right, and think this for a reason you can support logically? if the answer is yes, I'd love to see your argument, really.

If no... I honestly, probably could.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509306930.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Can you clarify what you mean by a collective right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509649351.0" user="paganize" delta="False">
    <text>It's one of the bigger arguments? Individual right to bear arms, or collective right to bear arms. [this link](http://ivn.us/2012/12/21/second-amendment-individual-rights-vs-collective-rights/) explains it fairly well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28509692886.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>From reading this and the Wikipedia article on this, I'm understanding collective rights to be rights possessed by a group, and if you are not part of that group you no longer possess those rights. You can correct me if I'm wrong. But based on this, and my slight leaning towards objectivism, I would say it's an individual right.

Edit: let me clarify, I'm talking about the right to use deadly force in self defense or for one's own safety</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28510068037.0" user="paganize" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm. that is almost a totally separate argument, so I'm not sure how to reply. 

Oh, what the hell.
I'm of the opinion that very, very few people actually understand the 2nd amendment, on both the pro and the con side. If you stick to simply interpreting it's literal wordage, ignore it's context, and ignore the Laws made at the same time that expanded on it's meaning, it's ambiguous. Like all the other Amendments would be.

If you did do that, though, and apply it to the question of whether it could be used as a justification for using arms in self defense, and whether certain weapons could be restricted from legal use in that role? If you go out of your way to avoid anything but analyzing the sentence structure, I'd say yes. Just like the 1st amendment wouldn't support fair use, or parody.

Without going to deep into the "changing your view" thing, though, I'd suggest you take a look at The 2nd Militia Act of 1792, specifically part 1, [wiki link](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Militia_Acts_of_1792#Second_Militia_Act_of_1792).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28510765006.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that even the founding fathers recognized that society would evolve and created the constitution in a way to address this issue. I looked at the link, and it specifies what constitutes a militia man and what arms they shall possess. But I also see two other amendments made to the constitution that redefined the militia. If we were to define what arms are available to militia men in the context of the first act, the only thing available to own would be a bayonet and a musket. Obviously this is not the only thing available to own today because as society and technology evolved so too did what makes up arms. Frankly the fact it was amendended twice just furthers my belief that it can be amended again to exclude guns from the arms a militia may possess. But ofcourse, if my understanding of the act is wrong, go ahead and point it out</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28511079824.0" user="paganize" delta="False">
    <text>Odd, I could have sworn it said " with a musket, bayonet and belt" and a little later, "Men owning rifles were required to"...the full text of the act does a fair job of mentioning every type of small arm that was available at the time, Muskets, Firelocks, Rifles, swords... if you go down to section 4, it includes Pistols, sabres, and various types of gear. All of the gear common to a Soldier of the era, aside from the big stuff. 

To recap: right after the 2nd amendment was written, every Male citizen of the united states capable of bearing arms was, by Law, a member of the militia; they were expected to have and, oh, lets say, Bear? these arms. other concurrent laws set up programs to help those who couldn't afford them. Organizations were set up in each state to make sure the Militia was prepared (and, BTW, that organization still exists).

As a short step to one side...only weapons appropriate to a individual soldier are mentioned. No cannon, ships, mortars, etc. it might be mentioned somewhere I haven't read, but anything suitable for a basic soldier is covered. shoulder fired weapons and pistols. 

Moving right along.
"But I also see two other amendments made to the constitution that redefined the militia."

Really? where?

There are some laws that redefine the Militia; quite a few, actually. the big ones are the Militia Act of 1903, and current U.S. Code.

The Militia Acts of 1902 &amp;amp; 1903 established 2 groups; the organized Militia, which received federal funds and equipment and became the National Guard eventually, and the rest of the citizens of the US into the "reserve militia". So...it didn't do away with the old militia concept, it formed a new group in addition.

Another quick aside: I can't find the place in actual US Code that says the Militia Acts of 1792 were repealed; I've found places were it says superseded... but that really isn't the same thing. You anti-gun types should find that for me.

Next, Modern US Code. [10 U.S. Code ยง 311 - Militia: composition and classes](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/10/311).
"(a) The militia of the United States consists of all able-bodied males at least 17 years of age and, except as provided in section 313 of title 32, under 45 years of age who are, or who have made a declaration of intention to become, citizens of the United States and of female citizens of the United States who are members of the National Guard." (more details follow)

So: If you are a US Citizen capable of bearing arms and at least 17, and not already a member of a established military organization, You ARE a member of the Militia.

to re-recap: Anyone who tries to say "when they said "arms" they meant "muskets" can't read. Muskets, flintlocks, rifles, pistols, swords, they went out of their way to describe every type of individual weapon commonly used in the military of the time. I see nothing about "but when they invent Laser Pistols, those won't count". Infantry Small Arms are covered.

The Militia laws have been amended. But not in any way a person could honestly and logically say changes the role of the Militia. No amendment *that I have found* in US Code has said anything about restricting the militia/reserve militia/unorganized militia from Infantry Small Arms, in fact it's quite the opposite.

OK. The "Iffy" section.
1st would be "Why did they put the 2nd amendment in with our highest, most important laws?" there are a bunch of answers to this. Some of the answers are partially right, some are intentionally wrong. I think anyone who says anything but "For a whole bunch of reasons, some of those reasons were kinda messed up, but the majority of people who insisted on it had a fairly good one"

That might be a different argument though?

2nd: Now, you're original thing was "why aren't all weapons allowed by the 2nd amendment"; my answer is "because they never have been, the laws that explain, detail and spell out the 2nd amendment Clearly define weapons appropriate to a individual member of the army. There are some laws that could be considered as justifying personally owned crew served weapons, actually, but they are really specific and I think they were intended as specific exceptions. Laws and ordinances that detail where the Militia is supposed to get the Cannons and other big stuff DO exist, but I can't find anything that doesn't predate the Constitution.

OK. If I haven't misrepresented anything, lied, made anything up, taken anything out of context, I should have changed not only your stated view, but also your covert one. If I haven't, I am seriously, seriously asking you to show me where I messed up or missed something.

except for "My argument is that even the founding fathers recognized that society would evolve and created the constitution in a way to address this issue". I can't argue with that. The Constitution could be amended to do away with the 2nd amendment, or change it, or whatever. But a Law that is in conflict with the Constitution or the bill of rights is a invalid law, and is not the same as an amendment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28511608731.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All of the gear common to a Soldier of the era, aside from the big stuff
&amp;gt;As a short step to one side...only weapons appropriate to a individual soldier are mentioned. 
&amp;gt; they went out of their way to describe every type of individual weapon commonly used in the military of the time. 
&amp;gt; Clearly define weapons appropriate to a individual member of the army. 

After a quick search of what standard equipment is available to a US soldier, and then a search of what is available to purchase I found they match almost perfectly. &amp;amp;#8710;

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506607525.0" user="cp5184" delta="False">
    <text>The dirty little secret of the second amendment is that when it was passed there was no standing army.  There was no US military.  Without the second amendment, there would be no law saying that the president, the commander in chief of the military, could bear a weapon.

It's not that the 2nd amendment militia was supposed to help the military, the 2nd amendment militia WAS the entire military.  There wasn't anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
