<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="276378140.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4kjqqk/cmv_the_fact_there_are_certain_weapons_that_i_as/">
    <title>CMV: The fact there are certain weapons that I as a private citizen can't own is inconsistent logic of the use of the Second Amendment.</title>
    <original_poster>quixoticromantic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The second amendment: A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.

Arms: Weapons and ammunition; armaments

As you can see, the second amendment doesn't define what arms really mean, so I also provided Oxford dictionary's definition of arms. 

As a private citizen, there are certain weapons and ammunition that I can't own. To me this suggests that there is a certain definition of what constitutes arms and it's up to our current society and current legislature to define what that means. With the logic I am using, this means that guns aren't inherently arms or fall within the second amendment. It would not be unconstitutional to outlaw guns if society decides to do so. Guns aren't inherently protected under the second amendment in other words. It is only this current society and legislature that does include it.

So basically to sum up my argument and, at least to me, keep the logic consistent, I should be able to own any and all weapons available or guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment.

Change my view!

Edit: Two redditors have succesfully convinced me that the second amendment does limit the owning of certain weapons. However this doesn't mean that my other view point has changed. Guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment, and the outlawing of guns could still be possible without getting rid of the Second amendment

Second Edit: to clarify how to now change my view, you have to convince me that the limitations that aleady exist in the second amendment can't somehow be extended to any and all guns.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28506176828.0" user="drogian" delta="False">
    <text>The second amendment speaks to your right to own all arms.  Prima facie, it would protect your right to knives, pistols, M240s, bazookas, and cruise missiles.  

Every right in the Constitution, however, has been found to be limited.  You have a right to free speech, but you can't yell "fire" in a crowded theater.  You have the right to avoid quartering soldiers in your home, but you can't stop cops from using your home for a stakeout.  You have a right against warrantless searches, but not when an officer is in hot pursuit.

The individual rights that the Constitution attempts to grant are balanced by what is best for society--the common good--such that the rights we have in effect are more limited than what the amendments actually say.  But that doesn't change the meaning of the amendment's text--it simply changes how we *interpret* that text when applying it to real-world situations.

So the 2nd amendment speaks to your right to bear any arms, including guns, but we willfully interpret the text of the 2nd amendment in a manner that *balances* your right (as written) with the common good (which is not written).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507228993.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, two other redditors have convinced me of the need for limitations. But couldn't that logic also be extended to guns if it's not what's best for the common good? Could we as a society decide that guns are longer needed (ban them) while still retaining the second amendment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28508335702.0" user="drogian" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely!  But guns are still part of the second amendment.  I'm trying to point out that you're making a false dilemma--guns can be part of the second amendment and still not be protected due to interpretation of that amendment which is different from its text.

So it can be true simultaneously that you shouldn't be allowed to own guns AND that guns are part of the second amendment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
