<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="276378140.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4kjqqk/cmv_the_fact_there_are_certain_weapons_that_i_as/">
    <title>CMV: The fact there are certain weapons that I as a private citizen can't own is inconsistent logic of the use of the Second Amendment.</title>
    <original_poster>quixoticromantic</original_poster>
    <original_post>The second amendment: A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.

Arms: Weapons and ammunition; armaments

As you can see, the second amendment doesn't define what arms really mean, so I also provided Oxford dictionary's definition of arms. 

As a private citizen, there are certain weapons and ammunition that I can't own. To me this suggests that there is a certain definition of what constitutes arms and it's up to our current society and current legislature to define what that means. With the logic I am using, this means that guns aren't inherently arms or fall within the second amendment. It would not be unconstitutional to outlaw guns if society decides to do so. Guns aren't inherently protected under the second amendment in other words. It is only this current society and legislature that does include it.

So basically to sum up my argument and, at least to me, keep the logic consistent, I should be able to own any and all weapons available or guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment.

Change my view!

Edit: Two redditors have succesfully convinced me that the second amendment does limit the owning of certain weapons. However this doesn't mean that my other view point has changed. Guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment, and the outlawing of guns could still be possible without getting rid of the Second amendment

Second Edit: to clarify how to now change my view, you have to convince me that the limitations that aleady exist in the second amendment can't somehow be extended to any and all guns.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28505480868.0" user="sirjackholland" delta="False">
    <text>The second amendment just says you have the right to bear arms, not bear all arms all of the time. Why would you assume such a black and white, categorical  of the document?

You can't bring guns on an airplane. Is that an infringement of the amendment? No, because we recognize that the right to bear arms *in general* does not imply we can specifically bear guns on a plane.

Similarly, you can't own chemical weapons. Those are still arms, but they're clearly not needed for a well regulated militia or for any kind of practical defense. The Constitution does not say you can own anything that falls under the definition of "arms" just that you're entitled to bear some kinds of arms in some circumstances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505507386.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text> you're entitled to bear some kinds of arms in some circumstances.

I provided the second amendment. I don't see the word "some". I don't see any ansteriks. I don't see any fine print or hidden clauses. Show me where the second amendment limits and I'll change my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505521351.0" user="sirjackholland" delta="False">
    <text>That's not how language works. If I tell you "I like fruit" does that mean I like *all* fruit? No, of course not. It means I generally like fruit, even if I think papaya is gross.

I don't see the word "all" in the amendment. So why are you assuming it's there?

Let's look at the actual language again:

&amp;gt; the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed

It doesn't say the right to keep and bear *all* arms, it just says arms. If the founding fathers intended to say "all arms" then they would have. But they didn't. They just said "arms".

Think about how easy it is to abuse your interpretation of the amendment. If you had the right to keep and bear all arms then anyone would be legally allowed to buy nuclear weapons, sarin gas, and anthrax because those all fall under the definition of "arms".

In fact, all it would take is a campaign to change how we use the term "arms" and you could make it legal to have anything you wanted. Why would anyone design an amendment so easily exploitable? They wouldn't, which is why they didn't. The amendment just says you have the right to bear arms, not all arms regardless of their nature.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505530786.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp;#8710;  your use of the word infringe does cap the more extreme side of my view point. However it just furthers the more lesser view point that guns aren't inherently part of the Second amendment and won't infringe on the individuals right to not own a gun.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505760387.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that a definition is not absolute doesn't mean that it doesn't have useful meaning.

As soon as you start talking about "arms" in a way that excludes the most useful weapons for defending a free state, you start to diverge from any reasonable interpretation of what the intent of the 2nd Amendment might have been. At the present time, that definitely includes guns, and saying that it doesn't is just a non sequitur.

My suggestion: try to stop having *any* absolutist view of anything. It's simply not true that the only 2 options are "everything that could be called arms are protected" and "nothing is definitively an arm that is protected". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507209614.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the present time, arms includes guns. I'm saying that if society so chose however, we could exclude guns from the second amendment. Is not an absolutist view that guns will always be part of the second amendment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507404375.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>If guns, as currently envisioned, ever stop being the weapons of choice for self defense or defense of the country (or for that matter, hunting), then theoretically, yes. We've already excluded swords in many places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507440986.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Okay so yes. That's where I thought the logic should extend to. However, I have also been told both explicitly and implicitly that guns will always be under the branch of the second amendment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507687936.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>People having a hard time imaging a time in which something called a "gun" isn't included in that category. 

And, honestly, it's likely that they are right. Projectile weapons are simply a win in terms of portability, efficiency, ease of use, and effectiveness.

But even if we all switch to laser pistols we'll probably still call them "guns". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28505531654.0" user="z3r0shade" delta="False">
    <text>"a well regulated militia" the argument could easily be made that you only have the right to bear arms within the context of a well regulated militia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28506718538.0" user="Brimshae" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Who are the Militia? They consist now of the whole people, except for a few public officers. -George Mason

If that's not sufficient for your delta, there's a federal law that defines the militia, [10 U.S. Code ยง 311 - Militia: composition and classes](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/10/311)

&amp;gt;The militia of the United States consists of all able-bodied males at least 17 years of age and, except as provided in section 313 of title 32, under 45 years of age who are, or who have made a declaration of intention to become, citizens of the United States and of female citizens of the United States who are members of the National Guard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507225188.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Can you clarify why your militia only standpoint? I see the the right of the people clause right after so I'm a little confused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507527552.0" user="Brimshae" delta="False">
    <text>I'm arguing that "only the militia have a right to arms " is a moot point, as Mr. Mason's above-cited opinion shows the intent of what is an otherwise straightforward statement that some people seem to want to (very loosely) interpret as saying this one specific right (bearing arms) applies only to the government*. 

George Mason is literally saying "The militia consists of all citizens of the United States". By that definition of militia, saying "the Second Amendment only applies to members of militias" is word-for-word equivalent to saying "the Second Amendment only applies to all citizen of the United States". 

Modern law (10 U.S. Code ยง 311, cited above) also codifies that the militia consists of a large majority of the people. 

To put it another way: I'm stating that, both written as intended (based on evidence provided by historical quotation), and *modern law as written* say that all people have a right to bear arms. 

----

In fact, one could make an *equal protection under law* argument and say that 10 U.S. Code ยง 311 should be expanded to include all persons over 17, male or female, as opposed to just dudes 17-45 and women in the National Guard. 

I'm all for people having more rights. I have a 1911 and an XD-40 under my computer desk (it's just kinda where they ended up, and it's practical), a couple of rifles , a shotgun (that I finally got a stock for after five years...), and am currently shopping around either for parts to finish off one of [those evil black rifles](http://blog.riflegear.com/post/2007/12/26/hello-kitty-ar-15-evil-black-rifle-meets-cute-and.aspx) that I started, or some Kalashnikov knock-off.

I've also taught a dozen or so people how to shoot, and taken them to their first time at a target range. 

But again, I'm saying that anyone can make the "2A is militia only!" argument all they want, as the militia is everyone.

^^^*And ^^^yet ^^^every ^^^other ^^^article ^^^of ^^^the ^^^Bill ^^^of ^^^Rights ^^^protects ^^^the ^^^rights ^^^of ^^^the ^^^people? ^^^That's ^^^some ^^^mental ^^^gymnastics ^^^now, ^^^isn't ^^^it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507593238.0" user="quixoticromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Oh okay! That was where my confusion was. I thought you were agreeing with him but implying the opposite. I agree that the right should not just be guaranteed to those in the militia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28507600870.0" user="Brimshae" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying the militia-or-not-argument doesn't matter, because EVERYONE is in the militia. 

Law and Founding Father opinion back me up on this. :-)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
