<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28568651704.0" user="vomitore" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confused. Are you saying you want your view changed so that you DO find jump scares scary or are you saying that jump scares in general aren't scary?

Just because you're not scared doesn't mean it doesn't scare someone else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28568748815.0" user="thelamehelptheblind" delta="False">
    <text>They might scare someone else, but I doubt that anyone gets to experience true terror or its after effects from jump scares. Convince me otherwise, I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28568759026.0" user="twentyonepoots" delta="False">
    <text>I am a living anti-testimony towards your case. I think about jump scares for days after I watch horror movies, not kidding. Any horror movie terrifies me, jump scares or not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28568834389.0" user="TheMadSun" delta="False">
    <text>Jump scares are the only thing scary about horror movies for me. I'll watch the whole movie calmly, but any time I start to expect jump scares I'll start sweating and fidgeting, then if they happen I'll flip shit. Gore or scary storylines don't really bother me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28568979267.0" user="TheDeza" delta="False">
    <text>Have you watched the Babadook (*dook dook dook*)? Perfectly scary with relatively few jump scares.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569147649.0" user="CannibalIowa" delta="False">
    <text>I feel I'm the only one in saying that it wasn't really scary at all, it was an awesome movie, but there wasn't a single scene that had me scared or even all that tense. I hate the reveal at the end, but even though it wasn't scary to me, I still enjoyed the story. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569511501.0" user="fantastic_lee" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, I liked the intellectual storyline underneath the plot but found it pretty bland as a horror movie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569888455.0" user="Savv3" delta="False">
    <text>its not pure horror, its horror comedy in a lot of ways. a forgotten genre.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28570386256.0" user="CannibalIowa" delta="False">
    <text>What the hell was comical about it? I thought of it more as a drama. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28570395981.0" user="Savv3" delta="False">
    <text>it has some comedic element, im not saying its a comedy. it makes you chuckle a bit from time to time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28570404493.0" user="CannibalIowa" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, ok, I didn't really get that at all from the film, but maybe that's just me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28568873098.0" user="CompGrl323" delta="False">
    <text>I HATE jump scares. I don't watch a whole lot of horror movies, but I prefer the psychological horror ones cause I like the way they mess with your mind. But jump scares scare the shit out of me. When I was a kid I had asshole friends that would link me to jump scare youtube videos and they would send me into legitimate panic attacks and I had nightmares for years. When I think about it too much, I get too scared to click any suspicious youtube links because I'm afraid it'll jumpscare and make me panicky for the rest of the day. I have an anxiety disorder so I'm probably worse about this than most people, but that's my experience.

I agree with your original post that they're cheap scares, but they DO scare me, and not in a fun way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569438008.0" user="sonofaresiii" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is, you're qualifying different kinds of terror. But that's the *filmmaker's* prerogative, not yours. A rollercoaster may not elicit "true" terror according to your definition-- the scares of a rollercoaster are obvious, simple, and telegraphed, much like a jumpscare-- but some people still enjoy them.

The "terror" that comes from a jump scare may not be the same kind of "terror" that you find in [insert your favorite scary movie], but that doesn't make it any less valid. If that's how a director chooses to set the tone of their movie, and if there's an audience out there who enjoys that, you can't really say it's wrong.

Mostly, I agree with you. I tend to just roll my eyes or get annoyed at jump scares. I tend to think they're lazy, but that just means they're not for me. It doesn't make them objectively bad, just because it's different from movies that induce terror in other ways. Jump scares are like rollercoasters-- if that's the kind of thrill you're into, that's cool, but it's not really my thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569864790.0" user="IAMADeinonychusAMA" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that jump scares have the effect of startling, not scaring?

Otherwise, if we take them at face value (jump *scares*),  then by definition they should be scary, and thus perfectly fitting for a horror movie which is intended to scare by definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28570242783.0" user="TwistedPerson" delta="False">
    <text>Ever had a jump scare IRL? Like when you thought you were alone and then you see someone behind you as you turn? That's absolutely terrifying. It's the same as when you mistake something in your vision for a person</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
