<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28568809114.0" user="RexDraco" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like your argument is solely based off of personal preference and personal standards, something people simply cannot change your view on without rewiring your brain to think otherwise. Horror is to do what it does, make people feel scared in a safe environment. Horror is to make people scared for a good laugh, it always has been. The original origin of Horror as a genre was for movies that were not at all scary, even for its time. The movies required immersion, which made people uncomfortable and used tricks to scare people in a temporary pace rather than a long lasting impact in order to get a good laugh out of the audience. Movies regularly got people in suspense by playing the right music, to set up for the scare on screen, all for entertainment. 
Modern Horror movies use similar chemistry, but in different ways. Sometimes they use gross or disturbing elements in order to impact individual's discomfort, but once again in a safe environment, in order to induce temporary fear. Jump scares too use the same chemistry. Here you are, in a safe setting, randomly get startled by a jump scare. You are temporarily horrified, but in a safe manner, which is what movies are for. Whether you wish to consider them cheap tactics to horrify people or not, that's up to a whole different debate on whether or not it's relevant. People watch horror movies to be horrified, maybe elements that gets the job done is necessary. Perhaps having a lot of jump scares, though having them alone might be of bad quality, is both necessary and a healthy part of diverse ways to horrify horror movie goers. 

The next argument to consider is, well, definitions. Horror doesn't technically HAVE to scare the audience to be considered horror. In fact, horror is more about the character's experience than the audience. Just like mystery as a genre, in fact. Did you know there is several mystery genre shows about not solving a mystery but rather how they solve the mystery? Technically, there is no mystery for the audience to experience, they're witnessing how the mystery is being solved. The most legitimate argument is rather they're solving the mystery in how they solve the mystery, but that doesn't necessarily mean the audience themselves are regularly participating in the mystery itself. No, in fact, it is the characters that are experiencing all the mystery. Just like how it's the characters that experiences all the action, the drama, the war, etc. Horror is sometimes a genre where we witness characters experiencing THEIR horror. So, if the movie can be called a horror film, despite NEVER intending to horrify the viewers... why can't movies that at least try to with jump scares? I mean, if it at least tries, it technically is... right? If a comedy movie tries to be funny but isn't, it's still a comedy movie, right? It would then just be called a bad comedy movie, just like how some horror movies would just be called bad horror movies. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
