<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="31" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28569920348.0" user="Micp" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"The 3 types of terror: The Gross-out: the sight of a severed head tumbling down a flight of stairs, it's when the lights go out and something green and slimy splatters against your arm. The Horror: the unnatural, spiders the size of bears, the dead waking up and walking around, it's when the lights go out and something with claws grabs you by the arm. And the last and worse one: Terror, when you come home and notice everything you own had been taken away and replaced by an exact substitute. It's when the lights go out and you feel something behind you, you hear it, you feel its breath against your ear, but when you turn around, there's nothing there..."  
-Stephen King

Horror is exactly what jumpscares are, it's just that you don't want horror, you want either a gross-out (if you are inyo the campier style of scary movies) or terror.

Jump scares have a place in scary movies I think. You say that it's not "fair" because jump scares use a bodily, reflexive response against you. But movies have been doing that pretty much for as long as there has been movies. They use effects like lighting, coloring, editing, angles, depth and sounds whether subtle SFX or grandiose orchestrated scores to "trick" you into feeling certain thing.

One famous example of this is the Dutch angle where you tilt the camera a little bit so that the audience will feel a little uncomfortable watching even if they aren't necessarily aware of it because the view on the screen is just slightly unnatural.

A jumpscare isn't too different from a Dutch angle in that regard.

That said I will grant you that jumpscares are a trick, and any trick not used in moderation is cheap. An entire movie shot in the Dutch angle wouldn't be that good either. But that's a point about moderation not about the trick itself.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
