<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28569312173.0" user="Vomix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ...and movies that are full of them *shouldn't be considered horror*

Emphasis above my own. I think there's a distinction to be drawn between horror as a *genre* and the quality that some movies have of being *scary.* Not all "scary" movies are in the horror genre ("Fatal Attraction," anyone?), and unfortunately, not all horror movies are actually scary. I'd liken it to the difference between a "funny" movie and a Comedy - one about your reaction to it as a viewer, the other is about about intent.

If a movie is in the horror genre, we as viewers can expect certain tropes, certain kinds of characters and plots, and it's entirely reasonable to expect it to be scary as well. But failure to achieve liftoff on the "scary" aspect doesn't mean that it's not a horror movie, it just means that it's not a very good one. If jump scares don't do it for you, you'd be within your rights as a viewer to be irritated by that, but saying that it's not within the genre of horror seems a bit extreme. If a movie is about a bunch of people running from ghosts in a haunted house during a spooky thunderstorm and the movie is meant to be scary but relies on jump scares over all else, would you *really* say that it shouldn't be considered "horror," despite the clear intentions of the movie to be a horror film?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
