<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28568679163.0" user="Hull_City_Hate_Crew" delta="False">
    <text>If we're arguing about definitions here, what do you think  should define a horror film? You could say that jump scares are not a part of that definition, but I would think that a movie that is full of jump scares is also going to have elements that meet the criteria of horror</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28568770017.0" user="thelamehelptheblind" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe it depends on how you view horror movies. When I watch a horror movie, I'm usually hoping for it to be a pretty 'serious' experience. I feel like jump scares have a more comedic effect. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569259409.0" user="space_guy95" delta="False">
    <text>I noticed you pointed out Paranormal Activity as an example in your post, but I think that film did pretty well to *not* make the jump scares the main source of fear and horror in the film, since you never actually see anything in the entire movie. 

I remember when I watched it, the scariest part was when she's stood in the corridor and you see that the "demon" or whatever it is, is breathing down her neck. It didn't do anything to startle the viewer, and it didn't show you anything that out of context would look frightening, but the psychological aspect of it was very powerful. 

However, if you're talking about the sequels, I agree. They left behind most of the clever film making tricks the first one used (probably because the production budget was an order of magnitude bigger for them so they had more options) in favour of the usual horror movie tropes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569259574.0" user="space_guy95" delta="False">
    <text>I noticed you pointed out Paranormal Activity as an example in your post, but I think that film did pretty well to *not* make the jump scares the main source of fear and horror in the film, since you never actually see anything in the entire movie. 

I remember when I watched it, the scariest part was when she's stood in the corridor and you see that the "demon" or whatever it is, is breathing down her neck. It didn't do anything to startle the viewer, and it didn't show you anything that out of context would look frightening, but the psychological aspect of it was very powerful. 

However, if you're talking about the sequels, I agree. They left behind most of the clever film making tricks the first one used (probably because the production budget was an order of magnitude bigger for them so they had more options) in favour of the usual horror movie tropes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569580711.0" user="Junior1919" delta="False">
    <text>Paranormal Activity 3 has maybe the best camera trick in a horror movie from the past 10 years. The rotating fan camera mount in the middle of the movie is genius, and it is used as both a growing scare and a jump scare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569640632.0" user="Jonah_and_the_Quail" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't seen this movie and I'm not finding anything from your description (just found a collapsing sheet behind a babysitter in a kitchen, that was cool, though). Any chance you can find a link to the scene?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28569707706.0" user="Junior1919" delta="False">
    <text>That's half of it. The other half doesn't seem to be on YouTube or anything, but it involves the kitchen getting destroyed. PA3 isn't some game-changer or anything, is just a really scary movie with some clever conceits.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
