<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28569324681.0" user="GreatBigJerk" delta="False">
    <text>They're great when used well and terrible when used poorly.

They're intended to be a way to make the the audience feel tense. It gets their nerves rattled and leaves them expecting more jump scares in quiet moments.

The best use of a jump scare is early on in the movie/game/whatever, and then don't do another one until near the climax of the story. 

In between and after those scares you offer up true horror scenes that can play off of the tension the audience is feeling. This would include quiet scenes with tense music that the audience will expect jump scares to happen in, but the jump scare won't happen and this will make them even more tense.

If use poorly, as in using them all over the place, then the effect doesn't work and people just start predicting when the next scare will happen and don't react as strongly.

Most horror movies and games unfortunately just put in jump scares everywhere and ruin the experience, but when done well they are an effective way to get emotions out of the audience.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
