<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="283879410.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4p0ir6/cmv_jump_scares_are_a_cheap_party_trick_and/">
    <title>CMV: 'Jump scares' are a cheap party trick, and movies that are full of them shouldn't be considered horror</title>
    <original_poster>thelamehelptheblind</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Lately I've noticed that most horror movies rely on jump scares. Something will unexpectedly pop out at the audience, a loud noise will startle everyone, you know the works. Sometimes the movie tries to trick people into believing that a certain scene will have a jump scare, to make the viewer feel safe, and then do a jump scare in the next scene.

I think that movies like Paranormal Activity, The Conjuring and The Darkness do not do their best to scare the audience in a creative way.

Jump scares do something physical to your body. Sometimes my mom jumps out at the me when I walk through the door, to elicit a scream or a 'fear' reaction from me. However, a second later I'm just laughing because it's silly and not at all scary.

When I go see a movie at the theater that has a lot of jump scares, most of the audience members just seem to be laughing. You may hear a collective gasp or a scream, but that's just a reflex. 

Most movies riddled with jump scares do not leave an impression on me. I find them annoying.

Jump scares do not tell a story that sends shivers down your spine and causes you to lay awake at night. Jump scares do not show you a gruesome scene that will be burned into your mind for the weeks to come.

Jump scares are cheap party tricks. They are annoying and do not elicit any feelings of terror. 

Change my view. 
_____
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28569441123.0" user="AemsOne" delta="False">
    <text>I think the Jump Scare has its place in horror, but I definitely agree that modern horror films rely on them massively. I love a good horror film, but I can't remember the last time I was actually scared by one. Some of the most promising recent horror films have been good for the first two thirds of the film before they reveal a crappy CGI witch or ghost or demon, when the film would have been a million times more effective had they just never visually revealed the "villain" at all.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
