<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579969180.0" user="clickstation" delta="False">
    <text>I hope I don't come off as being personal... 

It seems like you're just young. America has been having eight great years with Obama at the helm. But Obama is an anomaly. Most of the time, people choose between two politicians (who act Iike politicians). 

Is Clinton a crook? Probably. But that's not the question you should ask yourself when it comes to elections. Between the two choices, would America (and the world) be better off if she's elected, compared to the alternative? **That** is the question you should ask yourself. This election, and most probably the subsequent elections, you'll most likely choose between two crooks. One might be more apparent than the other, but politicians are politicians. No one is ever going to be 'fit for presidency' if Sincerity is one of the criteria. 

Sincerity is Sincerity, but outcomes are outcomes, and that's what's important. I'd rather vote for a crook who has enough common sense to steal what she can steal but leave the rest of the country intact, rather than someone who's going to run the country to the ground, Sincerity be damned. 

It's like choosing a babysitter. Option A is a babysitter who's only in it for the money, and they're not going to do a perfect job at it. They're probably going to just watch TV or maybe sext their boyfriend while ignoring my kids. Maybe she'll even steal some of my food. But at least I know they'll be tucked in, and taken care of if something happened. 

Option B is a babysitter who cares so much about my kids that they're going to pay close attention to them... And share her "wisdom" teaching my kids to be fearful hateful bigots who can't play nice with others. And feed my kids dangerous new age food. 

I'd choose babysitter A any day. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
