<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="58" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28583468820.0" user="TheManWhoWasNotShort" delta="False">
    <text>I experience a lot of cognitive dissonance when I see the view many, especially young people, have of Hillary Clinton versus the reality I see when following her career closely. These young liberal critics of Hillary see her as a political opportunist with very little accomplishments that is a smooth politician who will say anything and take any view to get elected. Watching her career, I can't help but see a brilliant policy wonk dedicated to liberal goals who is an absolutely dreadful politician. The last part, especially, I seem to be constantly at odds with public opinion on who is a slick talker and who is not.

I always hear the criticism that Hillary Clinton is unaccomplished and has no track record of fighting for progressive values and policies.  Considering this is the woman who forever tanked national public opinion of her fighting for universal health care at a time when the nation was still wildly conservative and worshipping the ground Reagan walked on, I'm dumbfounded. This is the person who as First Lady took a huge personal safety risk and flew in to then-still-very-communist China and delivered a speech about Women's Rights as human rights the the UN Human Rights Council, which caused them to formally recognize women's rights as human rights.  Who again lobbied the UN as Secretary of State years later to recognize LGBT rights. And they did, with familiar wording: "LGBT Rights are Human Rights". She also created a position at the State Department as an Ambassador of Women's Rights to the UN. On the issue of Social Justice, she was an early advocate for civil unions, an early advocate for gays to be in the military, a leading vocal supporter of the Violence Against Women Act, and a huge supporter of abortion rights.  On the issue of helping the poor, her two causes she championed alongside universal health care were CHIP, which provides healthcare to poor children, and the Family and Medical Leave Act, which protects the jobs of women who have a child and people who need to take an extended leave of absence due to illness.  She has also been a major champion of Universal Pre-K and her campaign has spoken at length about a huge plan to subsidize child care so that daycare takes up no more than 10% of a family's budget.  While she was First Lady of Arkansas, she ran Bill's Urban Redevelopment project, which brought health care coverage to the poorest communities of Arkansas and turned their school system from the nation's worst to one of the best while Bill was governor.  She went on to advocate for education reform as First Lady of the US.  Her accomplishments are many, and many of them are incredibly significant and would not have happened without her.  And that doesn't even begin to touch the global work her charity does, particularly in Rwanda, to provide basic health care and improve the quality of life of the world's poor.  I can't think of a single more accomplished liberal figure besides MAYBE Barney Frank, so it blows my mind that the attack that Hillary has not accomplished anything gets any weight.

The other part is the attack that she is a smooth politician who will say and do anything to get elected.  I don't understand it.  Because while I think Clinton is a tremendously accomplished person, when playing politics she... is genuinely terrible.  Half of American permanently hates her and her public image is trash.  She says some headscratching things frequently, like the Bosnia sniper fire story.  She commits a lot of unforced errors, like the Email scandal.  When she is seen in public a lot, her popularity tanks and people find her "shrill".  When she changes her stance on an issue, she rarely bothers to explain why in detail, even when there are really obvious reasons for doing so, like on the TPP and on the Iraq War. People think she seems fake and manufactured. None of this is the mark of a skilled politician at all.  A smooth talker convinces people to believe him, can talk his way out of any hole, and appears like a scandal-free polished jewel.  Obama was a skilled politician. Bernie Sanders is a skilled politician.  Hillary is a poor politician and a poor political tactician.  Then again, it's always the ones who seem fake that are considered the "good slick politicians" and those who are able to where the mask of a genuine man of the people who are praised for being a straight talker, so perhaps it's just that people are easily deceived.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
