<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579956213.0" user="42696" delta="False">
    <text>1. That first source you posted is ridiculously biased.

2. Everybody takes money from companies. As our system currently stands, that's the only way to run a campaign.

3. Trust me, Wall St. speeches are not that exciting. She didn't release the transcripts to control the narrative. If they were so bad, don't you think someone who worked on Wall St. would have blown the whistle by now?

4. Last I checked breaking up the banks wasn't in her plans. Unlike Bernie, she supports common sense regulation that is actually effective at mitigating risk without crippling the banks that are critical to keeping our economy competitive globally. 

5. She doesn't take money from Saudi Arabia. Saudi Arabia donated to the Clinton Foundation, which has no direct connection to her campaign. The Clinton Foundation does, however, have an astoundingly good record at doing good, charitable work all around the world. 

6. Going into detail on the flip-flopping image:

* The war in Iraq, at the time, had vast bipartisan support based on bad intelligence. In hindsight it was a bad move. She acknowledges it was a mistake.

* Obama was also against gay marriage, and then for it. So was the whole democratic party. So was the country. She's been in politics for decades, times change, and she shows the flexibility and open-mindedness to change with the times. 

* She supported universal healthcare. Obama made a political compromise and got the Affordable Care Act. Given this, she recognizes that the best way forward is to build on that, rather than have a tantrum that it didn't happen the way she wanted and throw away all the progress we've made in hopes of an unrealistic goal. 

* I support the TPP, yet somehow Trump and Bernie have convinced the American people that free trade is bad (the climate change denial of economics), to the point where it would be political suicide to support it.

* She supported the 2001 bill because she was able to attach a provision that protected children by making sure that custodial parents would still get child custody payments. The 2005 bill did not include this provision. 

7. Do you have any examples of a policy she has changed because of a donation? I can't find any. The Bernie campaign couldn't find any. That's because they are simply non-existent.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
