<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28580034990.0" user="Glowwerms" delta="False">
    <text>I've been a Sanders supporters through the primaries and will continue to be, but my perspective on Hillary is that although she is very obviously cut from the same cloth as every politician before her, she is incredibly qualified. I would much rather have someone who can maintain what we have than someone who is unpredictable and dangerous with their rhetoric and frankly, probably doesn't even understand how government truly works. Just based on foreign relations alone, Trump becoming president would be an absolute shit-show. I love that so many non-traditional candidates have gained attention this year but I would vote for Clinton over Trump simply based on how much more qualified she is than him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580071423.0" user="spitterofspit" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed here. Saying she's unfit is basically calling the almost the entire political class for the past several decades unfit. Now that being said, I'd really like to see that change, but singling Hillary out for your above reasons and NOT applying this same reasoning to almost every other politician is being inconsistent. Again, I wish it weren't this way and I hope my generation helps to change these things, but really, this is just business as usual.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580194883.0" user="stanthemanchan" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine you're considering two people for the job of a bus driver. One person has been driving for 20 years, with a couple of points for speeding and maybe a few parking tickets. The other person is blind and crazy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580340154.0" user="Crocodator" delta="False">
    <text>Or, you own a bus company and one of your drivers has been selling parts off of the bus. She has been caught a few times, but she generally either lies to cover it up or destroys the evidence.

Your other potential driver has no qualifications at all.

Sucks to own a bus company around here!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580699085.0" user="JamieHynemanAMA" delta="False">
    <text>You could also consider it as one person with 20 years experience who wrecked 3 buses, killed 4 passengers, and slept with the superintendent to get the job.

The other candidate has a clean record but doesn't have a class C license. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581086151.0" user="stanthemanchan" delta="False">
    <text>You must have an incredibly interesting definition of "clean record".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580772687.0" user="whyhellotherejim" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. She's certainly not a progressive and will just continue the corruption and whatever else, but she won't destroy what we as a country have built up over the past few decades. I'm still hoping for an indictment, but I realise the odds of that are tiny.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
