<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579629066.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>My goal with this post is to show you that she is as fit for the Presidency as many other presidents were.

&amp;gt; Hillary Clinton is corrupt.

This is a very loose definition of corruption. It is absolutely routine in politics for donors to Presidential campaigns to get appointed to spots on various advisory boards and [ambassadorships](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/worldviews/wp/2014/02/10/this-very-telling-map-shows-which-u-s-ambassadors-were-campaign-bundlers/).

Not releasing speech transcripts is also typical behavior; I've never seen accusations that Trump or any other candidate release their remarks at private fundraising dinners. Obama's "cling to guns and faith" comment was at a private event without a transcript, as was Mitt Romney's "47%" comment. It seems unreasonable to ask a candidate to release all records of all remarks they have ever made - if anything noteworthy was said, people in the crowd could talk about it. More than likely, Clinton got some things wrong in those speeches; everyone is more accurate with hindsight. Why should she release information that will help her opponents when Trump won't even release his tax returns? This feels like a double standard.

&amp;gt; She takes huge sums of cash from wall street

So did Obama and every candidate. Our politics requires lots of fundraising and Wall Street has money. I'm all for changing the fundraising system. Also, if Elizabeth Warren is backing Hillary, then I think we can trust her to try to take some action about the banks.

&amp;gt; She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia.

This is a little misleading. She gave a very important speech about women's rights in Beijing that was and is widely considered to be one of the most signifiant speeches on women's rights in history. That's just a fact; her words reverberated widely and were widely cited. The money her foundation takes from the Sauds is directed charitably - would you prefer we cut off all ties from anyone not like us?

&amp;gt; She seems to say anything to get elected.

Welcome to politics; its good when leaders change positions to represent the people that they want support from. However, what we have seen is that Clinton can govern. She's done real work with real accomplishments in the real world, and has much more to show for it than Sanders's protest votes in the Senate. Yes, she was wrong about Iraq (though not in the same way Bush was), but she's normal. Trump isn't normal - Trump is dangerous. 

&amp;gt; She held secret government files on a server that was hacked multiple times

This isn't true. Servers all over the internet get pings and attempts to hack into them. There's no evidence the e-mails were leaked or taken, just standard computer security stuff that everyone deals with. The e-mail was a mistake, yes, but it wasn't evil. Did you know the Bush White House did all of their e-mail on RNC servers to avoid recordkeeping?

&amp;gt; Is there something that I'm missing?

I think you've gotten lost in Clinton's flaws and missed that *all politics is flawed this way.* Obama succeeded in his campaign partly because he took in a lot of money from rich donors early on. He passed healthcare with a semi-bribe to Nebraska - the "Cornhusker Kickback."

You're right that Clinton isn't a big threat of change to the system, but Obama also didn't do much to change the system despite his promises. Clinton is a typical, well-versed candidate who can do the job. I don't think Sanders has the same experience (esp in foreign affairs) and Trump is SO DANGEROUS that she's the only choice.

That's not to say that Clinton is my favorite; I was an Obama supporter for many reasons you cite. However, I think she's a fair choice for the office. Also, the double standard that people and the media subject her to is crazy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579667093.0" user="Concord913" delta="False">
    <text>Almost every rebuttal you give is backed by saying "that's not true - plus even if it was, everyone is doing the same stuff so it's ok" ... There was no citations to back your contradicting statements and "everyone's doing it, she's just as bad as everyone else" is not sufficient qualification for presidency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579712469.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>What bar for qualification are you using? Is every past president in the past century disqualified?

I'm happy to provide citations but its not clear what you want. Something like this? https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bush_White_House_email_controversy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579691787.0" user="YoungSerious" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think you've gotten lost in Clinton's flaws and missed that all politics is flawed this way.

This isn't an argument. It's a complete lack of an argument. It's the same as saying "She doesn't have problems because everyone has problems." 

My biggest issue with her is her inconsistency. As far as the money, I wouldn't care about receiving donations to campaigns, except that it means that whatever candidates say now is irrelevant because once they take power they are going to do whatever serves their donors best.

Despite her flaws, Trump is clearly the worse choice. But being better than Trump by no means indicates that she is fit for presidency, just that Trump is so drastically unfit that almost any other choice is superior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579709663.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This isn't an argument. It's a complete lack of an argument. It's the same as saying "She doesn't have problems because everyone has problems."

Fitness is relative. By the OP's standard, LBJ, JFK, Roosevelt (who lied routinely), and many other Presidents would be disqualified as unfit.

I hear you saying that the system is broken and must change. I would also encourage you to look at Obama and how his attempts to change the system completely failed - not because he did a bad job, but because people empowered his opponents and were mislead by lies.

Being honest doesn't make you a good politician, unfortunately. The problem is us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579767183.0" user="YoungSerious" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Being honest doesn't make you a good politician, unfortunately. The problem is us.

That depends on how you qualify them as "good". The perfect politician is someone who represents their constituents accurately and is capable of achieving change as their representative. Historically, politicians have either done one or the other, but rarely if ever both. 

Saying the problem is us (while technically true) is also only true because of the incredibly vague nature of the statement. It's functionally meaningless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579824214.0" user="tlk742" delta="False">
    <text>When you define someone as representing the constituents accurately, I'm hoping you can expound upon that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579836803.0" user="YoungSerious" delta="False">
    <text>Haha I'll try. Elected officials in a democracy exist under the ideal that they are chosen by a group because that person agrees with and will pursue change in a certain set of concepts or areas (the components of that person's platform). Accurate representation of your constituents (IMO) would mean continuing to do so in the manner represented during your campaign. Or, to paraphrase, sticking to your position on the issues that got you elected. 

I understand this is an idealistic view of politics, but when you are going to throw the word "good" around, you really need to have a baseline of what they are "good" in reference to. 

This is also why I hate talking about politics, because nothing works the way it was intended.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579860450.0" user="tlk742" delta="False">
    <text>So true about nothing working the way it is supposed to.

And I agree with the concept of a vote to the candidate you vote for should be them sticking with what you vote for.  What you vote for should be what you get, the problem is that situations aren't static and what may by popular then, the exact opposite can be true months later.

But let's say, for example, a candidate runs on an isolationist platform in 1942, and Japan then bombs Pearl Harbor, should said candidate vote against going to war with Japan?  I'll be honest, I'm not sure what the right answer is here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579899612.0" user="YoungSerious" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But let's say, for example, a candidate runs on an isolationist platform in 1942, and Japan then bombs Pearl Harbor, should said candidate vote against going to war with Japan?

That's a great example, and it's impossible to truly say what the "right" or "wrong" decision would be. Any decision now about that particular event is tainted by the knowledge of the outcome from those events. 

You can't plan for something like that. It's a drastic event that changes the political landscape. You can take into account their current position and sort of guess how it might affect their decisions in a time like that, but accurate prediction is impossible. I think the best you can do is decide based on "In the absence of an unusual significant event, would this person represent my position well". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579932030.0" user="tlk742" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, and I agree hindsight does ruin any chance of delving deeper into that example.

But then it begs the question of what defines something as a "significant event". An attack on US soil may be one, but an intelligence report or a constituent reaching out to a candidate with a specific argument can also be a significant event. It's so many layers of grey (gray?).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580411601.0" user="getlough" delta="False">
    <text>Gray and grey are both right. English is stupid sometimes
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579943125.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Saying the problem is us (while technically true) is also only true because of the incredibly vague nature of the statement.

I should be more specific. We, as voters, reward unethical and manipulative behavior by our politicians by electing and re-electing then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582251782.0" user="waydownLo" delta="False">
    <text>Bingo. "Throw the bums out!" is a great way to collectively abet individual malfeasance. 

If you think both sides are equally to blame, that "all politicians lie [equally]," you're rewarding whichever party decides to lie more.

If you want to see this in action, look at the fratricide that erupted after Bernie released his economic plans. Compare the liberals tearing apart each others' policy plans because they're not perfectly internally consistent to the GOP's gleeful embrace of economic theories which are arithmetically unsound enough to be correctly understood as performance art instead of public policy. 

That's the rub about living in a putative democracy: all responsibility for generational errors ultimately accrue to the electorate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579694788.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that saying "everyone does it" makes it OK for Hillary to do it, but that's what the majority of your argument revolves around. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579703483.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that you are both exaggerating her flaws and that her flaws are well within standard practice. The thing is, politics has been flawed like this through all of our history. The only "pure" person to occupy the Presidency was Carter, and his administration wasn't effective.

We need idealists who work to help real people combined with realists who deal with the world as it is. Everything we know about Hillary says that she's both someone who gives a shit and someone that knows the world for what it is.

What else do you want?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579734468.0" user="REMSheep" delta="False">
    <text>Even Jimmy Carter has blood on his hands, he supported an authoritarian crack down in El Salvador that led to the deaths of 40,000 people. These people are unfit to lead what America claims to be, but are quite fit to be the imperial monster we actually are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581043117.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Okay then no president was fit and you finally realized the US is an imperialist power.

Guess what, you aren't going to change that with voting. You never have and never will. Your vote is powerless and useless in changing the source of this all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581276706.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>Don't forget that Carter and Ford backed Suharto's genocidal regime in Indonesia when he invaded East Timor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579741124.0" user="Diced" delta="False">
    <text>Its pretty easy to construct narratives that either overemphasize or downplay the degree to which Clinton participated in these practices. 

That's really the core issue. Was her behavior typical? How does her conduct compare to her peers? It's not exaggeration if she goes steps father than others would. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579745857.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Was her behavior typical? How does her conduct compare to her peers?

True, but comparing people is difficult. There aren't many people to have lived in the White House, been a Senator, and been a Cabinet Official.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579951051.0" user="GayForChopin" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention, is the typical behavior acceptable? If you ask me, it is not. Not to suck sander's dick here or anything, but he hasn't demonstrated the type of behavior and thinking that has seemed to cause the problems that are impacting well over half of Americans. 

If we elect someone that has the same mentality as the people who have gotten us into these problems, how do we ever expect anything to change, or any of these problems to be solved?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579982441.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; he hasn't demonstrated the type of behavior and thinking

He also hasn't done much in his career to actually change things or get reform done. Being a reliable liberal doesn't get others to join your side.

&amp;gt; If we elect someone that has the same mentality as the people who have gotten us into these problems, how do we ever expect anything to change, or any of these problems to be solved?

I agree with this, but am not sure which candidate in the field does this. My overall point is that Trump is much much worse than Clinton - elections aren't just about who can fix problems, but also who won't take us deeper into problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580079531.0" user="saskatchewan_kenobi" delta="False">
    <text>What has hillary done to change or reform things though? Through all the scandals and corruption shes been apart of, i cant think of one issue she has championed for and been seriously putting resources into to improve it. All her moves politically have been to move her career forward and climb the ladder up to becoming president, not to change america for the better. Obama had health care and now gun control that he feels so passionate for that he wants to change. Trump at least has immigration. Bernie sanders has the wealth gap, and college education. Hillary only has a platform that she borrowed and hoped on the bandwagon for after calculating that it would improve her campaign, and her track record is not good. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580096455.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>It's odd that you use this argument, since Clinton used the same exact attack on Obama and his fairly sparse legislative record compared to her own.

http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2015/09/carly-fiorina-debate-hillary-clintons-greatest-accomplishment-213157
https://clinton5.nara.gov/WH/Accomplishments/eightyears-01.html
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580591977.0" user="thesweats" delta="False">
    <text>It's odd that you use this argument, since you're the one who brought it up:

&amp;gt;He also hasn't done much in his career to actually change things or get reform done. Being a reliable liberal doesn't get others to join your side.


And the strangest thing is that he has done very much to change things and get reform done. He is one of the few people that has built bridges between opposing parties.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580608489.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; He is one of the few people that has built bridges between opposing parties.

My point was that you should compare the candidate Obama to the candidate Clinton. If she's elected she can do much more on national policy, just like Obama did.

And while I think Obama is great, I'm not sure he's built bridges as much as he wanted to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579819568.0" user="SenorBrown" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't we just call them "oopsies" and just forget this all ever happened. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579941225.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>not sure what you are saying here, but people have tried again and again to invent perfect societies and it doesn't work out well. We're all flawed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580949847.0" user="Shadow_Jedi" delta="False">
    <text>In fact, the first version of the Matrix was a utopia. We rejected that like a week old truckstop sandwich! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579939818.0" user="object_on_my_desk" delta="False">
    <text>Washington seemed like a pretty good guy, all things considered. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580210129.0" user="Lazy_Scheherazade" delta="False">
    <text>Except for the slaves. George Washington owned slaves, so how could anybody trust him not to be massively corrupt??

*That* is why the "everybody does it" argument is meaningful: obviously Washington, Jefferson and plenty of the other founding fathers wanted to end that economic system - but refusing to participate in it would have kept them out of power and made change impossible. The Declaration of Independence almost went unsigned because Jefferson refused to remove a clause addressing the evils of slavery. He did this at the same time he owned a slave plantation. Almost *nobody* we look up to from that generation was completely innocent of this great evil. Even in the North, where slavery was illegal, much of the shipping economy relied on transporting slaves around the globe. Public opinion and economic reality both made abolition untenable for that generation. But the Founding Fathers still managed to create a system that would allow abolition to (eventually) succeed.

In a similar fashion, when Teddy Roosevelt broke up the oil monopoly, one oil baron remarked: "We bought him; but he didn't *stay* bought."

Hypocrisy is how shit gets done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580329053.0" user="object_on_my_desk" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I'm of the camp of viewing historical figures as a product of their time.  That's what I meant by all things considered.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581036408.0" user="YourKneesAreWeird" delta="False">
    <text>But the problem, as mentioned above, is that they did consider the practice evil in their time. They still had slaves. That's where the "product of their time" thing breaks down for me. They knew it was evil and did it anyway because it was good for them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581118033.0" user="TheNosferatu" delta="False">
    <text>Wasn't Abe Lincon considered 'pure' as well, though? Just curious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581525876.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely not. The dude ignored Habeas Corpus, which was unconstitutional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579735926.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>So do you think just about every president in the past half century or so has been "unfit for presidency"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579831498.0" user="From_Deep_Space" delta="False">
    <text>It is a well-known fact that those people who must want to rule people are, ipso facto, those least suited to do it... anyone who is capable of getting themselves made President should on no account be allowed to do the job.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579855646.0" user="Irishfury86" delta="False">
    <text>That isn't a fact and it isn't as deep as you think it is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579882543.0" user="HippyHitman" delta="False">
    <text>The "deepness" of the comment is subjective and irrelevant. Do you believe it's inaccurate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579883835.0" user="Irishfury86" delta="False">
    <text>Of course.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579886185.0" user="HippyHitman" delta="False">
    <text>Care to explain? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579941598.0" user="Status_Flux" delta="False">
    <text>In any other area of work, would you specifically seek out someone who didnt want to do the job?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579891743.0" user="t0t0zenerd" delta="False">
    <text>It's just a quote from H2G2</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579893373.0" user="ZentharTheMagician" delta="False">
    <text>It's a quote from a Douglas Adams book. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579924506.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; anyone who is capable of getting themselves made President should on no account be allowed to do the job.

I don't think this is quite true. We've had many strong presidents, some of whom weren't well regarded for the role. Lincoln is the obvious example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580015872.0" user="dubalubdub" delta="False">
    <text>Eh, it's a well known saying but it's mostly nonsense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579739757.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>If everyone does it, then your argument must be that either everyone is unfit for the presidency, or that Hillary is no more unfit than any other candidates. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579874321.0" user="Spider_pig448" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, good point. OP's arguing for a question he didn't ask now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581044317.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Because OP is a fucking soap boxer and the mods aren't doing shit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579879386.0" user="badwig" delta="False">
    <text>Surely there must occasionally be a successful candidate who is willing to not take money from special interests? They would make it a cornerstone of their campaign and it would prove popular, people would think this is a refreshing change, even if they disagreed with policy detail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579910918.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>If not taking money from special interests is the only metric by which you define a fit candidate, then sure.  My point, though, is that any measure of fitness which excludes 99.9% of actual successful candidates is a bit absurd and divorced from reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579917772.0" user="badwig" delta="False">
    <text>Careful, you sound a little like Remain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579937389.0" user="object_on_my_desk" delta="False">
    <text>Not possible until the rules change.  Money is SO much of an advantage.  We can estimate pretty accurately how spending money in a certain state will give you a boost in supporters.  I guess my point is until the Republicans agree not to take special interest money, I want my candidates to take the money too. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579997283.0" user="Enchanted_Bunny" delta="False">
    <text>It depends. Plenty of candidates outspend others and still lose. There's a minimum you need to spend to get enough exposure to be viable. But after that, there's a diminishing return. Remember how Ron Paul broke all sorts of fundraising records in 2008 and all that netted him was a 2nd or 3rd showing in Iowa? People see the successful candidates get tons of money and think the money is why they're popular. In reality, candidates that are the most popular draw more donations and attention. Ron Paul could have had a billion dollars and not done any better because Republicans weren't and aren't sold on libertarianism and that wasn't going to change no matter how much money he had. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580335597.0" user="object_on_my_desk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Plenty of candidates outspend others and still lose

Of course, and I'm not saying that more money = guaranteed win.  But it goes beyond just viability.  A good attack ad or issues ad can sway voters.  Not to mention paying for top tier political operatives to actually run the campaign.  If you can't pay for those then you're going to get destroyed at some point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580387057.0" user="Enchanted_Bunny" delta="False">
    <text>Right. That's the minimum required to play at that level. I was just pointing out that it isn't a linear relationship between money spent and votes. If your platform is not palatable to the mainstream voter, it doesn't matter how much you spend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579881320.0" user="thebroncoman8292" delta="False">
    <text>They are all unfit.  Can we elect a cat to the presidency? I trust a cat with the nuclear launch codes more than trump or Hillary.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579907554.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>I think this comment belongs on /r/politics rather than /r/cmv.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581227982.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>this whole thread does</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581047065.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>You trust an animal with no concept of civilization and mass destruction nor the empathy for billions of human beings, nor the ability to communicate, with the mental age less that a toddler to handle nuclear launch codes? That's how you kill us all, are you delusional or trying to be daftly hyperbolic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579986869.0" user="Enchanted_Bunny" delta="False">
    <text>Bingo.the only candidates you can vote for are the ones on the ballot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580442649.0" user="sllewgh" delta="False">
    <text>That's not true, actually, but you aren't likely to get anywhere with a write-in, so the point is valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580952355.0" user="Shadow_Jedi" delta="False">
    <text>I'm still undecided between the douche and the turd sandwich. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581227582.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>if you try to relate real life to south park then you're beyond help</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581621350.0" user="steeleworks" delta="False">
    <text>South Park has been the *worst* thing to happen for political discussions. (remember the "safe space" fiasco?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580968787.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>That's not true. You're allowed to write in any candidate you so choose. Most people don't like this option because they feel like it decrease the chances of your preferred party winning, increasing the chances of the other party winning... but you can do it. I have a feeling there's going to be a number of independents writing in candidates this year. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581226953.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's not true. You're allowed to write in any candidate you so choose

IIRC not in every sate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580247773.0" user="navf60" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. Basic logic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579748457.0" user="lord_fishsticks" delta="False">
    <text>Essentially what he is saying is that she is held to a different standard than other candidates. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580532791.0" user="dontrumpreee" delta="False">
    <text>Or, I would say "she is doing the status quo, which is bad, whereas Trump has not done anything near as bad." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579753720.0" user="CommieTau" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is that Hillary is corrupt and a liar, therefore she cannot be president.

The counter-argument is that most presidents are corrupt liars, therefore she's pretty well suited to the role.

I'd say she's pretty much your standard politician for the status quo. It's just a sad reflection on democracy that these are the kind of people who end up in power. She's just a product of the system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579786317.0" user="crisisofkilts" delta="False">
    <text>I think dude's argument began with OP's extremely loose definition of 'corrupt'. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579922077.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>+1. Yes. Money is a problem in American politics, but "corruption" is something we overinflate here because you don't have to bribe the cops to avoid BS tickets. That's the norm in other places.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579921472.0" user="Fuck_da_Mods_bitch" delta="False">
    <text>So... We're going to change the system by sticking to the status quo? Good luck with that👍.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579932986.0" user="CommieTau" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, absolutely not. I neither advocate nor discourage voting for her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580023068.0" user="AziMeeshka" delta="False">
    <text>I would rather have the status quo for 4-8 more years rather than just change for the sake of change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580430322.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Many different kinds of change. Trump is not the right one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580469520.0" user="AziMeeshka" delta="False">
    <text>That's what I mean. Even well thought out and well intentioned change is likely to fail more often than succeed, but just blindly voting somebody into office because you want to disrupt the status quo is suicide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581229717.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>*cough* brexit *cough*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580055005.0" user="punninglinguist" delta="False">
    <text>Can you think of any political system, *ever*, in which ambitious, intelligent, self-serving, dishonest people did not routinely rise to the top?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580481080.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Pope Francis seems pretty decent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580625848.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>"routinely". Piecemeal examples to the contrary do not disprove the point. Historically Pope's have been routinely... not great.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580628250.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Was trying to be funny. I enjoy the multiple popes that fathered children while in office.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581097571.0" user="whambamthankyoudamn" delta="False">
    <text>Are you serious?  He's Catholic, first off</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580499582.0" user="danielkuzmin" delta="False">
    <text>This comment has been overwritten by an open source script to protect this user&amp;amp;apos;s privacy.  It was created to help protect users from doxing, stalking, harassment, and profiling for the purposes of censorship. 

   If you would also like to protect yourself, add the Chrome extension [TamperMonkey](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tampermonkey/dhdgffkkebhmkfjojejmpbldmpobfkfo), or the Firefox extension [GreaseMonkey](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-us/firefox/addon/greasemonkey/) and add [this open source script](https://greasyfork.org/en/scripts/10380-reddit-overwrite).   

 Then simply click on your username on Reddit, go to the comments tab, scroll down as far as possible (hint:use [RES](http://www.redditenhancementsuite.com/)), and hit the new OVERWRITE button at the top.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580784793.0" user="punninglinguist" delta="False">
    <text>I think in the few occasions when it's been tried, you still wind up with charismatic liars at the top, even though there's no formal top.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581048496.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>In the few occasions anarchisn has occured, they fell from capitalist and fascist invasions, or forced integration by orher socialists</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582029765.0" user="punninglinguist" delta="False">
    <text>Who said anything about falling? It's very common for Machiavellian leaders to be good for an organization rather than bad for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580769499.0" user="oi_rohe" delta="False">
    <text>Should not, it seems to me, not cannot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579801050.0" user="eternallylearning" delta="False">
    <text>I think the point is more that your definition of "fit for president" seems to eliminate just about every modern president as well as just about every realistic candidate for president.  It seems to me that the system is set up to elect people exactly like her and that her biggest flaws comoared to other presidential candidates all revolve aound not being quite as slick, not getting the public to move past her scandals efficiently, and running for office in an environment where the scrutiny of presidential elections is at an all time high and the American people are starting ti actually care. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579889813.0" user="RichardRogers" delta="False">
    <text>Most people who hate Hillary think she is the latest in a long line of unsavory politicians that don't deserve power over the common man. The comparison to Obama and Romney doesn't do her any favors, and I can't even begin to fathom how "You only dislike her because she's a worse manipulator of public opinion than her predecessors" is supposed to be a defense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579920332.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I can't even begin to fathom how "You only dislike her because she's a worse manipulator of public opinion than her predecessors" is supposed to be a defense.

The point is that in this election, we need to support Clinton. 100%. Opting out is not a valid option. I wouldn't have said this about Rubio, Kasich, or even Cruz to some degree (he can have an intelligent conversation). Trump is a whole other level of unacceptable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579905998.0" user="AirBlaze" delta="False">
    <text>What's wrong with saying modern presidents were unfit? In my opinion, we haven't had a president who was, in OP's words, "fit for president" in a very long time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579936730.0" user="eternallylearning" delta="False">
    <text>What does fit mean then?  Fit to win an election?  Fit to get done what they were elected to do?  Or is it fit to stand up to the closest scrutiny?  Maybe she's done some shady shit, but if what she does as president ends up being what her supporters and voters more or less expected her to do then how could she truly be said to be unfit.  Compare that to either Trump, who hasn't given a realistic plan for anything and seems to consider himself the expert on everything no matter how ignorant on such matters he reveals himself to be, or Sanders who doesn't stand a chance of getting almost anything done besides changing the conversation.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580026928.0" user="SpaceOdysseus" delta="False">
    <text>I think if you have standards that eliminate essentially everyone and that you say every mod3rn president was unfit for their job, I'd say your an unfit judge. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580052921.0" user="punninglinguist" delta="False">
    <text>Therefore, OP should change his/her view on what it means to be fit for the presidency. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579913331.0" user="ClamMarino" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely don't care for Hilary's policy, I don't know her so I can't comment on her as a person, but I feel like Hilary's weakness is her PR. She can be very robotic and is not a natural in front of the media, and many of her strategies come off as pandering. In many ways she acts too much like an attorney. Of course that doesn't disqualify anyone from being president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579982928.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580065120.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry Pipette-Queen, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+5+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=Pipette-Queen+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4ns7yo\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580653305.0" user="macinneb" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like the reason she has to come across as robotic is so the whole "OMG WOMEN ARE SO EMOTIONAL WE CANT LET HER HAVE THE NUKE BUTTON" arguments aren't given a foot to stand on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581332720.0" user="rrmains" delta="False">
    <text>I suspect that much of the criticism of HRC is veiled sexism. Men are aggressive, women are bitches. Men are calm and calculated, women are robotic. Men are shrewd, women are conniving.

Then when you point out that everyone (read: all prior *men*) does this, you get some kind of push back that somehow SHE shouldn't. It's okay for men...and it's even okay to not be okay for men cuz, you know, boys will be boys...but when she acts like a shrewd, aggressive, and calculated politician, she's called out on it like she's the devil.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580664274.0" user="m_plis" delta="False">
    <text>Many people believe that she's more comfortable and effective when she's actually working in an elected office versus when she's campaigning for elected office. For example, her approval ratings were very high while she was secretary of state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580669746.0" user="epiphyte2" delta="False">
    <text>Pandering is big part of all politicians' tools/skills set. Also many politicians come from a legal background. I'm not a fan of hers either, but neither of these things are unique to her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580780120.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>That's true. If she had half as much charm as Obama I would be much less scared of Trump.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581069908.0" user="mhornberger" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She can be very robotic and is not a natural in front of the media

Maybe we should focus less on the candidate being telegenic and 'natural' on camera.     Reagan 'connected' with people on camera and in the media because he was all folksy and homespun and relaxed.    Meaning, he was an actor who knew how to project a character.   It is a particular skill set, but not one that maps to being a good President.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581268280.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>I know this goes against conventional reddit wisdom, but Reagan was the best president in recent memory (by which I mean from Kennedy onwards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581284292.0" user="mhornberger" delta="False">
    <text>I can't speak of conventional wisdom, but there is a great deal of disagreement over Reagan.   The folksy homespun thing didn't do it for me, and I don't think his record is all that great.    

I doubt conservatives of today would be that much in love with him.    He doubled the national debt, was for amnesty for undocumented immigrants, quietly withdrew when hundreds of Marines were killed by a terrorist bombing, etc.    I'm not saying these are all horrible, just that they stand at odds with what many modern conservatives ostensibly find important, even non-negotiable.   

I thought Clinton's Presidency was better for us, but even then his record is not uncomplicated.   Clinton signed off on much of the deregulation that caused that financial meltdown, and also perpetuated the wage stagnation of the middle and working classes.  

In any case, my point was not to slam Reagan.   My point was that being 'robotic' on camera is not something that really worries me.   We put far too much focus on surface polish and glam.    This is why I don't watch TV, or even listen to speeches.    I'll read a speech to get what the person is saying, but if you watch or listen you're being swayed by their cadence, their looks, their height, their hair, etc.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581428552.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I doubt conservatives of today would be that much in love with him.

Oh, they certainly wouldn't, and that's a part of why I like him. In some ways Bill Clinton had more of an ideological connection with the modern-day Republican Party than Reagan did. I'm not sure how the debt relates to that though, Bush doubled the debt too.

And I'd add to your list of things modern Republicans would hate about him:

* Reagan glorified unions, claiming that [collective bargaining "has played a major role in America's economic miracle"](http://www.americanthinker.com/articles/2015/05/reagan_and_unions_setting_the_record_straight.html) and that ["where free unions and collective bargaining are forbidden, freedom is lost"](http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2011/03/ronald-reagan-loved-unions-and-collective-bargaining/72633/).

* Reagan signed [the UN Convention on Torture](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Nations_Convention_against_Torture), which states that no circumstance whatsoever can be used as justification for torture, including "torture by proxy" (that is, bypassing anti-torture laws by extrajudicially transferring people to countries that are known to practice torture, [which Clinton did anyway](https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/arrest-bill-clinton/2011/12/12/gIQACQ7wpO_story.html)).

* [Reagan was an early proponent of the idea that homosexuality is not a choice and people who knew him generally claim that, contrary to popular belief, he was very accepting of homosexuality for his time](http://www.advocate.com/commentary/2014/06/05/op-ed-gay-truth-about-ronald-reagan).

* [He supported limited gun control.](http://www.nytimes.com/1991/03/29/opinion/why-i-m-for-the-brady-bill.html)

* [He supported giving the Palestinian territories autonomy](http://www.cfr.org/israel/reagan-plan-us-policy-peace-middle-east/p14140) and [was more willing to condemn the Israeli government than any President since](http://www.haaretz.com/blogs/west-of-eden/if-obama-treated-israel-like-reagan-did-he-d-be-impeached-1.400542).

* Compared to other recent Presidents (Jimmy Carter being an obvious exception), his Presidency was quite peaceful, with the only major intervention on his watch being an invasion of Grenada that lasted less than 2 months and killed less than 100 people total. And, of course, he was willing to engage in diplomacy with the Soviets once Gorbachev came to power, a step that even at the time conservatives generally regarded as a huge mistake.

In any case, I think the telegenicity of Reagan actually did, in a way, make him a much more successful President. [According to Gorbachev](http://www.nbcnews.com/id/5148407/ns/us_news-the_legacy_of_ronald_reagan/t/gorbachev-calls-reagan-great-president/#.V2_jdzc_aJg), Reagan had a "personal warmth" and "communicativeness" that bolstered their relations and helped to arrange normal relations between the two countries. [Reagan said quite similar things about Gorbachev.](http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/americanexperience/features/biography/reagan-gorbachev/) I think how a politician comes across is important, because a big part of success in politics-in getting legislation passed, in diplomatic negotiations, etc.-is getting people to agree with you, and people are more inclined to agree with someone they like.

And I'm not a big fan of Bill Clinton. His economic policies were pretty good, sure, but weighing that against his ignoring the Rwandan Genocide for years, the sanctions on Iraq that led to hundreds of thousands of deaths, the bombing of a pharmaceutical factory in Sudan based on shaky evidence, and [his largely-ignored role in the deception leading up to the Iraq War](http://www.democracynow.org/2005/10/21/scott_ritter_on_the_untold_story) [(including a bombing campaign in Iraq that killed 1400 Republican Guard members based on a lie](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bombing_of_Iraq_(1998)), and the aforementioned "torture by proxy", I'm inclined to say he did more bad than good.

If I had to rank them from best to worst, it'd go something like:

Ronald Reagan

Lyndon Johnson

------

Jimmy Carter

George HW Bush

John F. Kennedy

Gerald Ford

------

Barack Obama

Bill Clinton

Richard Nixon

-----

-----

-----

George W. Bush</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582187329.0" user="waydownLo" delta="False">
    <text>Did you forget about Iran-Contra? Nicaragua more generally? Invasion of Grenada? Able Archer 84?

He was about as close to a "loose cannon" as the republic had seen until Bush 43 rolled along and secured his place in history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582267371.0" user="funwiththoughts" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm well aware of all of those things. Every single one of the people on that list could reasonably be tried and arrested (if not executed) as a war criminal.

* With regard to Iran-Contra, it is still unknown whether or not Reagan authorized the diversion of the funds to supporting the Contras, and even if he did, it is worth noting that they were the lesser of two evils in Nicaragua. He definitely did authorize illegal sales of arms to Iran, but I do have some sympathy for him here since, according to the notes of his Defense Secretary Caspar Weinberger, [he did it primarily because "he could answer charges of illegality but couldn't answer the charge that 'big strong Reagan passed up a chance to free the hostages'."](http://nsarchive.gwu.edu/NSAEBB/NSAEBB210/14-Weinberger%20Diaries%20Dec%207%20handwritten.pdf)

* I actually explicitly mentioned Reagan's invasion of Grenada by name, but nearly every Cold War-era president invaded other countries unprovoked. What Reagan did in Grenada was no worse than what was done by Eisenhower in Iran and Guatemala, nor JFK in Cuba, Nixon in Cambodia, Laos, and Chile, or Bush I in Panama, to say nothing of Vietnam or Iraq. The invasion of Grenada lasted about 2 months and killed less than 100 people total-as far as US military interventions go, that's nothing. Plus, Reagan at least had the decency to allow a democratic government to form in Grenada once the totalitarian regime had been deposed, rather than setting up a puppet dictator like, say, Eisenhower would have done. [EDIT: And the Grenadians certainly seem to think they're better off for it-in Grenada, "Thanksgiving Day" refers to the date on which Reagan invaded]. It was unnecessary, illegal, and probably immoral, but not *very* immoral.

* Do you mean Able Archer 83? Because if so, how much of an effect that actually had is still a subject of much debate, and [CIA documents declassified in 2003 show that there was no strong evidence that the USSR was preparing for war or perceived an imminent danger of one.](https://web.archive.org/web/20060724160027/http://www.isn.ethz.ch/php/documents/collection_17/texts/ermarth.pdf)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580295893.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>I agree.  I don't think we've ever had a president who was fit for the presidency, and I mean *ever*.  Washington is probably about as close as you'll get, but most presidents the U.S. has ever had were wholly unfit for the job, IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581039619.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Wow I wonder how we were able to last 200 years and become a superpower with "unfit" leaders</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581524205.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>Probably because every other country in the world faces the same problem?  It's a seemingly unavoidable paradox - the only people who have the means and desire to rise to positions of power are generally those who are totally unfit for the job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581546598.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>When has there ever been a case that a leader was rightly chosen because they DIDN'T want the job? Now you are saying that literally every leadership position has only been filled with unfit people. McDonalds managers, corporate team leaders, president of a school club, because all of them wanted it. Wow.

Your idea of fit is so ridiculously utopian and totally unachievable that it should be thrown out of the discussion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581579800.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>Its a position of power that is distinctly different from a McDonald's manger or anything else, really.  Being president, king, emperor, or something similar puts one on the top tier of power in the world.  Wanting to be a McDonald's manager isn't unreasonably ambitious, but to say to yourself "yes, I deserve to be in the &amp;lt;1% of people who control the lives of all my fellow humans" is definitely a statement of character.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581072319.0" user="weeyummy1" delta="False">
    <text>Hilary gets judged much more than other candidates. Bias against aggressive women is real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581169116.0" user="eternallylearning" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps, though bias towards perceiving disproportionate negativity is real too.  Certainly she's received more flak from her own party than many candidates, but I would tend to attribute that more towards Sanders and his run than pure sexism.  Also it's pretty undeniable that the things she's become mired in are real and equally undeniable that she is just not as good as many other politicians at damage control and spin.  

That all aside, I really think Trump has earned the label of "most judged" this cycle.  I mean hell, I head an Illinois senator has started running ads touting that he doesn't support Trump as a positive thing.  Everything he says gets torn to shreds (and rightfully so IMO) but he's just way better at deflecting and manipulation of the public and media than she is.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579813920.0" user="Scipio229" delta="False">
    <text>Sadly it does (though I agree with your sentiment). By presidential standards, she is not corrupt. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579841290.0" user="clutchtho" delta="False">
    <text>how is that not a valid argument? Sure she isn't fit to take an office if it was held by people who do none of these things. But they all do, and she is just continuing.

What I think you have done is learned a different definition of "office" and believe in a set of traits that should be expected of our president and by that, you are correct. However in the real world, this definition does not exist. If everyone has done many of the things she has done, then does that say more about the candidates or about the office they hold? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579849004.0" user="anxiousgrue" delta="False">
    <text>I think the point of showing that everyone does it is to describe both the reality of the current political environment (how difficult it is to be pure, so to speak) and how you might be judging her on a double standard (if Hillary is corrupt, who are you supporting instead, and are they corrupt too by the same metrics? If so, they wouldn't deserve your support either).

Additionally, if Hillary is equivalent to other candidates based on corruption and trustworthiness, then we can start comparing based on other factors, from accomplishments to political experience (ability to pass legislation).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579865598.0" user="martong93" delta="False">
    <text>You're arguing her competency, which is necessarily a relative argument to make. Pointing out that she doesn't fail any competency criteria that others don't also fail means that she isn't incompetent.

It *is* important to note double standards. Choosing presidents is about hiring someone for a job, not choosing who you should view as your personal lord and savior messiah figure. The double standards that are central to the debate of her competency don't actually have anything to do with her overall ability to do said job.

This is less so about Hillary Clinton being corrupt or incompetent than it is for our collective contempt for the idea of the office of presidency. We're disappointed that such a symbolically important job isn't automatically filled by someone greater than human, and we're disappointed that the office is less a symbol in itself than we were hoping it could be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579926950.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is less so about Hillary Clinton being corrupt or incompetent than it is for our collective contempt for the idea of the office of presidency. We're disappointed that such a symbolically important job isn't automatically filled by someone greater than human, and we're disappointed that the office is less a symbol in itself than we were hoping it could be.

Well said. I think we used to fool ourselves into thinking Presidents were gods when we know from history they weren't. We know more of the truth now, and we don't like it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579901299.0" user="LeakyLycanthrope" delta="False">
    <text>But you yourself are singling her out. The point of u/falsehood's comment was not to defend the system, it was to counter the argument that she is the only or worst example, or even a rare example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579909907.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580994043.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry thefish12, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 3\. "Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view. If you are unsure whether someone is genuine, ask clarifying questions (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting ill behaviour, please message us." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+3+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=thefish12+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4nqnmb\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581049907.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Are you joking? Have you even read OP's posts? When a poster addressed every single point the OP had, the OP changed his CMV to avoid giving a delta and now everyone has to remake their arguments to address a CMV within a CMV. He's soap boxing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581052428.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>There's a reason there's a **report** button. Breaking the rules is not a good way to bring this up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579922223.0" user="brauer1" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that "everyone does it" and that they have managed to achieve the goals despite this and often times directly because of this. Obama is the first example that comes to mind. He could have never been able to be elected had he not done what every politician does and we would have been in a worst situation from a progressive point of view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579973252.0" user="VortexMagus" delta="False">
    <text>Ask yourself why you're moving the goalposts for Hillary alone, and no other presidential candidate. 

Most presidents, including Obama, Bush, and alllll the way back to Reagan and Nixon all have nearly identical problems to your two salient points. All of them took money from prominent lobbyists and exchanged it for political favors and appointees, just like Hillary did. All of them said things that they later flip-flopped on, or straight up lied at points. The United States seemed to do okay under their leadership anyway.

So why is Hillary the first candidate you're trying to claim is corrupt and unsuitable, when this has been happening for decades? I would consider her less corrupt than most, actually. She was one of the democrats who voted to reform campaign financing and impose limits on financing from private donors and superPACs. This bill, which would have taken an enormous amount of money out of presidential elections, was blocked by Republicans. In *this* particular vote, she was one of the people trying to *reduce* corruption, not increase it.

I think you're just getting baited by propaganda and smear campaigns that have been going out on social media. She's corrupt, sure, but not significantly different from any other presidential candidate. It actually shows how clean she is that the only complaints people can make against her are ones that apply to virtually every president for the past 30 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580178559.0" user="Second_Foundationeer" delta="False">
    <text>Probably because we have better access to information beyond the old methods of propaganda, and also because we had a candidate who wasn't like this. But, you know, let's just pretend it's the media and sexism because Angela Merkel and other actual glass ceiling breakers don't exist because murica.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581037495.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581057862.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581062846.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581074010.0" user="Second_Foundationeer" delta="False">
    <text>Well, maybe, but unfortunately, we know she's spent millions on Internet shills so.. not farfetched at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581100222.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry MisandryOMGguize, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=MisandryOMGguize+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4ofd8e\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581081130.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Someone is gonna pay a random redditor like me money just to reply to you?

In the meantime maybe you should look into the war crimes your despicable country and imperialist army is responsible for since apparently you just realized some people aren't innocent. Every president you have had is a war criminal.  It doesn't matter who you vote for. Your armed forces are going to continue to slaughter hundreds of thousands of brown people and bomb the middle east back the stone age, and when your national bourgeoisie has exploited the situation to the fullest, they will move to a new target. I wonder what it will be, another fake attack on the US to start a war? More chemical agents to brutally kill thousands of civilians and give defects to magnitudes more? Or is it going to overthrowing some more democracies? The US might be due for another global and illegal round of human experimentation. Are ya'll gonna drug an entire town and make them kill each other again?

You focus way too much on Clinton and seemingly are blind to the worst injustices in history. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581091547.0" user="Second_Foundationeer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm more than aware of the US's crimes. Why perpetuate it with another criminal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581094668.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>It will never stop until your people hold the bourgeosie responsible and remove them completely from political and economic power, then cease all imperialist activities and abolish/reform your armed forces. None of that will happen with a vote, it never did and it never will. I honestly don't see your people doing this anytime within the next 20 years, lack of class consciousness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581099791.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry Second_Foundationeer, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=Second_Foundationeer+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4of9dy\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581099703.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry 2k16throwaway, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=2k16throwaway+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4oeto7\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581140477.0" user="SoundWolves" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really think Merkel is a good example of a woman (heck, it isn't even about her sex, let's just say *person*) doing a job right, just saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581156640.0" user="Second_Foundationeer" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, just saying that she broke the glass ceiling! But even more awesome is that she was a physicist who is in a pretty strong position (not necessarily doing a good job). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582994929.0" user="abstract_warrior" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know that we do have better access to information. We have _more_ access to _text_ and other _media_, but that doesn't mean we are actually any more informed. In fact, the huge amount of data we are barraged with means we get to filter it to the things we want to hear, not the things we need to hear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582998053.0" user="Second_Foundationeer" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good point, and I agree. However, I really meant that we have *better access* and not *better information*. Our information is still as crappy as it was before for the exact reasons you point out (self-filtering, ie. Republicans stick to Fox "News"). But we do have better access because we aren't limited to local print newspaper, or whatever is being broadcast on the television schedules.. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580818851.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just really excited to see someone back up Hillary by comparing her to GWB. 

This has made my night.

I get that the argument is solid. If he can be president, why can't she? I also agree she'd be better than he was by a wide, wide margin. 

It's just delicious though.

In the democratic race, we've had an uncompromising progressive, who's always been willing to stand on the margins for his beliefs. This year, for whatever weird ass reason, he's become relevant. As a Vermonter, I feel a sense of pride in the votes I've given him over the years, but I digress.

She has had to stand up against a candidate who, as Josh &amp;amp; Sam came together over in the first episode of The West Wing, is "The Real Deal" - and you're arguing that she's good to go because Bush won.

I just love this wabsite sometimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28585296561.0" user="Endofa" delta="False">
    <text>The truth is a lot of the country just plainly won't vote for him.  Remember, in this country most people think of the word "socialist" as an insult.  He might be winning in head to head match ups right now, but that's because he hasn't been attacked repeatedly from the right--not to the extent that she has for the past 20 years.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580938361.0" user="jklinger410" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Ask yourself why you're moving the goalposts for Hillary alone, and no other presidential candidate. 

Most people have been uncomfortable with these parts of American politics from the moment they **learned** about them. You do not see, 99% of the time, someone saying something like "I hate the way Hillary is a traditional politician" in the same breath as supporting other traditional politicians. Yet this is your line of defense? As if this person complaining about money in politics has been tacitly supporting it for years. Newsflash: they haven't ever been supporting it. It is not "moving the goalposts" because the corrupt politicians have been *setting* the goalposts. We are just moving those posts to a place they should already have been.

This is among the chief counterpoints for Hillary people, and I cannot for the life of me understand how they don't consider themselves "the bad guys" when they defend their candidate with that type of rhetoric. 

"Everyone else does it" has never, ever been a proper defense. Maybe I would feel pity that you were the one who got in trouble for what everyone else does, but it certainly is not a defense of what you did. Specifically when we're talking about the president of the United States.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581393760.0" user="CosmicWy" delta="False">
    <text>Every else does it is a perfectly fine defense in our current state of government. There are not so many knocks against Hillary that do not broadly apply to the system as a whole and she's not an egregious offender.  Voting in Trump will now eschew this behavior from American politics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580004481.0" user="Green_gello" delta="False">
    <text>You could say that, but then you're also saying that no one who has run for president, win or lose, has been fit for the job in the last hundred years or more. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580051756.0" user="punninglinguist" delta="False">
    <text>It changes *your* argument from "Hillary Clinton is not fit to be president" to "Most presidents, including some excellent ones, have not been fit to be president."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580177926.0" user="adidasbdd" delta="False">
    <text>This is the real answer. Although I can't think of a similar example where a candidate used gross negligence in the handling of sensitive and classified material.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580534325.0" user="MCRemix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; where a candidate used gross negligence in the handling of sensitive and classified material.

To be fair, she used (arguably gross) negligence in the handling of an unclassified email server.  

The way our government handles information, no classified information should have ever been introduced to that server because no classified information should *ever* be anywhere other than on the Secured/Classified network (aka SIPRNet).

However, as far as I know, there have been no established facts that show she mishandled information that was classified or intentionally introduced it to her unclassified server, only that information on her server was later re-classified or deemed classified.  (I think we're all a little unclear on that last part, but it sounds to me like alot of inter-departmental bickering about what the classification should have been.)

Now...the reason I draw this distinction is that AFAIK, the Bush White House did the same thing (using off-site RNC servers to handle their unclassified email).

Which would mean that her lapse (setting up a private unclassified server) was something a prior candidate/office-holder had done.  

To be frank, none of them should have done it, it's all dangerous and we should condemn all of them.  But it's not unprecedented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580558460.0" user="adidasbdd" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know about her predecessors but she was maintaining and had full access to private government files for years after leaving office. Someone might send the SOS some very sensitive information, of course it wouldn't be classified until it was reviewed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580055236.0" user="Echuck215" delta="False">
    <text>But your view wasn't that her behavior "isn't ok".  Your view was that her behavior made her unfit for the presidency.

So, in that context, it seems perfectly appropriate to compare her behavior to past Presidents.  Unless you think they were unfit as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580137845.0" user="TheMormegil92" delta="False">
    <text>The following hinges on the premise that rational thinking is what we should use to guide our choices - as opposed to feelings and emotions.

If you have an optimization problem with a function which has a negative local maximum, you still take the parameter which gives the local maximum. That is literally the best choice.

Saying "this is the least of two evils" sounds a lot scarier than saying "this is the best choice", but they are logically equivalent*. They refer to the same situation with the same parameters, only one shines a negative light on the whole thing and the other doesn't. The rational choice is still the local maximum, despite it being negative.

So you saying that "everyone does it" doesn't make it ok is true, but I could state the same thing with "we need deep reform of political infrastructure" and suddenly it's not a problem with Hillary Clinton anymore. I am reframing the optimization problem, without changing any of the outcomes.

You are choosing a particular way to word things and I believe that is clouding your judgment of the issue as a whole because the wording you chose evokes strong emotions. This is normal - we take our news from tv and newspapers (online or not), and this is what journalism is all about; after all emotions sell, and clinical fact analysis is boring to read. The way you think, the words you use in your head, come from somewhere. Usually, people and media around you.

This whole thing is not to say that you should change your opinion that Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency. I am fine with you stating that. Indeed, you can put your baseline level at any point you'd like, have as high or low a standard as you like.

But elections are an optimization problem (they really are), and constants don't influence derivatives. Your personal choice of height of standard doesn't influence what the best objective choice is. Is it HRC? Is it not? Who knows. I don't.

So, is Hillary fit for presidency? I don't know, but the correct answer is "it doesn't matter when voting".

---

\* there is something to be said about choosing not to vote. Which is: don't.

More seriously, the choices in an election are traditionally among all possible participants, but there is another option which is often not considered - not voting at all. That is effectively relinquishing all control over the outcome of the optimization problem.

It could be argued that if you don't know what the best answer is, then you could choose not to vote in order to immunize the result from your own polluted answer. I believe the overall news to be sufficient to make an "informed guess" - that is, even if you have no idea what the payoff structure is for your options, you still can figure out a vague shape. In a decision as drastic as the presidential election, I am confident to say you can be reasonably sure of which option benefits you the most.

It could also be argued that not voting sends a signal. Which is hilarious, because politicians still get elected anyway; usually politicians you don't like, since you aren't voting. The signal you are sending is "don't care about me, I'm not even voting anyway".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581665005.0" user="asianbison" delta="False">
    <text>This is exactly what many people need to realize. If you buy into the emotional arguments this election cycle, you will fall prey to Trumps speeches and accusations. 

However, since the "optimization cycle" as you describe it is unfortunately not based on what's "best for the nation" in a typical voters eyes, it's more along "what's best for me and my family" gets optimized. 

Since most voters mindset is self centered then that's how they are more affected by Trumps speeches that rely on pathos. The fear mongering with terrorism trump uses is a primary example. 

The example that applies here is his accusations of Hillary being a liar etc. People focus on issues that they can relate, which is why they focus on the accusations creating distrust, because after all distrust is a personal issue we've all experienced. Being a politician, is not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581843534.0" user="TheMormegil92" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the idea behind democracy is that if everyone optimizes what's best for them, overall we will find something close to the best possible result. Again, it's a heuristic strategy - much like most of ethics - and we have no way to either prove or disprove it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581903831.0" user="asianbison" delta="False">
    <text>Yes it's speculative but it does have merit, unlike the OP's overly vitriolic attitude toward Hillary. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580139068.0" user="CANOODLING_SOCIOPATH" delta="False">
    <text>All other Presidents do this. 

Is Obama not fit to be President? 

And you should remember, if Sanders was the nominee there would undoubtedly be Wall Street organizations that would back him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580144311.0" user="Mr24601" delta="False">
    <text>You're saying that she will do what banks, investment groups, and large corporate interests want because she is being funded by them, like everyone else does. 

You're absolutely right that Clinton, in 2016 so far, has raised over $13,000,000 from finance/insurance/real estate [1](http://www.opensecrets.org/industries/recips.php?ind=F&amp;amp;recipdetail=A&amp;amp;sortorder=U&amp;amp;mem=Y&amp;amp;cycle=2016) out of $256,000,000 total [2](http://www.opensecrets.org/pres16/candidate.php?id=N00000019) . So she is about 5% owned by the finance industry!

However, did you know that Obama broke records with donations from the same sector in 2008? [3](http://www.opensecrets.org/industries/recips.php?ind=F&amp;amp;recipdetail=A&amp;amp;sortorder=U&amp;amp;mem=Y&amp;amp;cycle=2008). He then pushed to law the toughest regulations since the great depression (Dodd Frank, etc). Don't believe they were tough? Look at donations to Obama from the same sector in 2012! ([Bank support for Obama plummeted](http://www.opensecrets.org/industries/recips.php?ind=F&amp;amp;recipdetail=A&amp;amp;sortorder=U&amp;amp;mem=Y&amp;amp;cycle=2012)). 

I'm also not sure if you know that Citizen's United was about an attack documentary against HC - she was the defendent in that case. She has even said that a litmus test for supreme court nominees would be wanting to repeal Citizen's United. (https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-politics/wp/2015/05/14/hillary-clintons-litmus-test-for-supreme-court-nominees-a-pledge-to-overturn-citizens-united/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581620083.0" user="steeleworks" delta="False">
    <text>Also while the donations are claimed to be coming from industries like "financial" or "pharmaceutical" (or whatever "shady" industry you'd like), a majority are actually coming from their *employees* who have to declare their employer.  Their donations aren't counted as individual donations, but as donations from their industries.  So the numbers are wildly misleading too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580177242.0" user="boobbbers" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, now you're saying two different things here. Your original post was on *Hillary's fitness for presidency*. 

However, this statement:

&amp;gt;I don't think that saying "everyone does it" makes it OK for Hillary to do it

isn't about Hillary's fitness for Presidency, but it's about the *moral permissibility of her behaviors*. 

It's the difference between an end and a means to an end.

---

**Argument Recap**

So, your initial argument is that she's *unfit for presidency* because of x, y, and z behaviors, and our common retort is that majority of previous presidents (people who are clearly fit for presidency because they obviously became presidents) also had x, y, and z behaviors. 

Your response was is "it doesn't mean it's ok for her to do it because everybody else did" doesn't attack the fact *that previous presidents have the attributes that you claim make them and her unfit for presidency.* It may be the case that it's not morally permissible for **any** of those previous presidents to have those attributes. However, there's a difference between them having it, and wether or not they should or should not have it. 

In conclusion, if you want to win the argument that Hillary is unfit for President, don't list attributes that previous presidents share!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580721098.0" user="mkurdmi" delta="False">
    <text>Its perfectly reasonable to claim Hilary is unfit for presidency based on attributes other presidents had. That just means those other presidents might also have been unfit to be president. There's no logical contradiction there, just because someone was president doesn't mean they were fit for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581040591.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Then you woild be saying all presidents were unfit. The fact the IS is a superpower and lasted 200 makes this sound fucking ridiculous. Does it really matter then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581058121.0" user="mkurdmi" delta="False">
    <text>Just because something is morally or ethically unacceptable (which is what we seem to be defining 'fit' to be here) doesn't mean it can't work from a logistics standpoint. Sure, the country probably won't go down in flames because Hilary is president, that's not the point of the post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581226425.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>but considering other president's proved themselves capable and fit with the same issues that OP listed then she is not unfit because of them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581235289.0" user="mkurdmi" delta="False">
    <text>Fit and capable are not being defined synonymously here. Fit is being used in the sense that it is ethically permissable for ghe person to be in charge. Other presidents being capable has, very literally, no relevance to the topic. 

As far as other presidents being fit for the job (morally/ethically), it's arguable that many were when placed in the context of the times they lived (though they might not necessarily be today). Humanity's undersanding of ethics has evolved since then, though, and because of that we should be pushing for stricter standards as we move forward - standards that Clinton is just absurdly far from meeting. So yeah, I'd argue Clinton is *absolutely* not fit to be president, and it's not even close. The fact that many other presidents weren't either and that we don't have any other reasonable options at the moment (baring Clinton actually being indicted and Sanders magically winning the primary) really just doesn't make a difference there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581372016.0" user="HollerinScholar" delta="False">
    <text>Then you're admitting the point of the post is beating a dead horse, because if the point of the post is to change OP's view that Hillary is unfit, and they want to toss out perfectly logical points, then it's a pissing match.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581230494.0" user="boobbbers" delta="False">
    <text>Then please tell me, what's the criteria that makes a person fit to be president?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581238359.0" user="mkurdmi" delta="False">
    <text>See my other responses. Being fit for the job and capable of the job aren't the same thing. So no, anyone that demonstrates absurdly unethical behavior is not 'fit' to be the leader of a modern nation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581244244.0" user="boobbbers" delta="False">
    <text>So, by your criteria, do you agree with the following statement: "a vast majority of leaders of modern nations are unfit for the position they once held or currently hold."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581261590.0" user="mkurdmi" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582056070.0" user="boobbbers" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So no, anyone that demonstrates absurdly unethical behavior is not 'fit' to be the leader of a modern nation.

Idealism aside, I think modern statesmanship, especially post Machiavelli, has demonstrated that morality isn't the indicator of people who are fit to successfully run a nation. Some of the most successful nations are run by morally corrupted peoples. 

Also, moral codes are different, and if we look at the middle east, where their leaders are elected based on religious morality, and those civilizations aren't at their highest point in history. 

I do think you have a point, that morality is an indicator of person's fitness for leadership, but historical facts seem to tell us otherwise, and the facts show that nations run by people with corrupted morals can still be very successful. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580238939.0" user="SF1034" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument made it sound like she was the only one who did those things.  You're highlighting all the things she has done, as if they're these unprecedented horrors, when it's fairly standard practice of politics.

&amp;gt;She seems to say anything to get elected.

This is politics 101 for any country in the world.  Find me a President/premier/chancellor/MP/whoever who has delivered on everyone of their campaign promises.  I won't wait up.  Ffs, Newt Gingrich was promising a damned Moon base when he was jockeying for the Republican nomination in 2012.

&amp;gt;You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie 

Because at the time that was her main opponent.  Of course it had to change, because at first Sanders wasn't a serious opponent, but then he gained a lot of traction very rapidly.  Basically, you don't bring a knife to a gun fight.

&amp;gt;She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia.

She takes those millions and directs them towards charities.  
Taking money from people who stand against something you firmly believe in and using it for good?  That sounds pretty badass to me.

&amp;gt; I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in this  image.

Let's just use the beginning of Bill's presidency as the time of reference for that first image. He was sworn in on 20 January, 1993.  Which, as of the next inauguration will be 24 years ago.  Assuming that's your birth year in your username, you're 28 years old at the oldest.  Do you hold all the same views today that you did when you were a kid?  Do you still think you'll have the same views 24 years from now?  Better yet, go ask anyone who is over the age of 50 what their views were in their mid 20s compared to what they are today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580773877.0" user="oi_rohe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; &amp;gt;She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia.

&amp;gt; She takes those millions and directs them towards charities.

She also directed smear campaigns against people who came out against her husband's sexual advances against them.  I believe it is a direct quote, "Who know's what you'll find if you drag a 100 dollar bill through a  trailer park."  That hardly sounds like someone supporting women's rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580918086.0" user="SF1034" delta="False">
    <text>I'll concede that point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581398780.0" user="t_hab" delta="False">
    <text>James Carville said that, not Hillary. 

I assume Hillary also wasn't pleased with Paula Jones, who came forward as the Lewinsky affair was dragging their relationship through the public grinder, but that oarticular quote wasn't hers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580310166.0" user="pxdeye" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument was that these make her unfit for presidency. These arguments prove otherwise. You don't need to be morally squeaky clean in order to be a good president or fit for the presidency. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580473540.0" user="jthill" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem here is, we're going to wind up with a President.  "None of the above" not being a plausible option, and the only apparent alternative sharing more than just initials with the characteristics of severe alcohol withdrawal, I don't really see the point of unconstructive criticism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580495853.0" user="Alacritous" delta="False">
    <text>Singling out Hillary for criticism for doing something that is not out of the ordinary is disingenuous. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580536479.0" user="kinpsychosis" delta="False">
    <text>It is not a question of morality though, a political theorist by the name of Machiavelli made a compelling argument that "you can't be a good person and hope to be a good politician at the same time, a good politician will make hard choices for the good of the country."

You're main argument was "hillary clinton is unfit for presidency"

If she is able to act like a politician and do as a politician would for the countries best interest, wouldn't the opposite be true?

Sure just because others did it, doesn't justify her doing it, but that isn't the point of the argument, it is simply a matter of if she is fit to lead the country or not and not morality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580580813.0" user="Hero-Sloth" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't make it okay.  OP is trying to argue that Clinton is just as for four president as anybody else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580778840.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>She basically the same as all our other presidents, is the arguement here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580918108.0" user="fastrx" delta="False">
    <text>And this is exactly Hillary's rebuttal every time she is called out on things. She says well, everyone else does it! 
 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581000035.0" user="exosequitur" delta="False">
    <text>Also,  there is very damning evidence that the Clinton server was indeed hacked. Not once,  but multiple times.  As an IT professional who has been responsible for infrastructure systems,  I can tell you that if you put an unpatched email server online naked,  it will be compromised in less than a day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582870431.0" user="rudditavvpumnt" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic essentially every modern president was unfit for the presidency. I assume you didn't support any of them? If you did, then you clearly must have some other reason for not liking Hillary. Try to figure that out first. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579701805.0" user="SdstcChpmnk" delta="False">
    <text>It's really really dangerous to me that you have no concept of how bad her email situation is. There is currently a hacker in government custody that took EVERYTHING from her server. Without even trying. Everything he has claimed has turned out to be true, and all of Hillarys emails are available to download via hackers RIGHT NOW. You absolutely 100% cannot claim that "There's no evidence the emails were leaked or taken..." when all of the emails that she "deleted" are currently in the hands of the FBI because of multiple sources. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579730472.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I think you have been mislead.

&amp;gt; There is currently a hacker in government custody that took EVERYTHING from her server. 

Can you cite that? The Wall Street Journal [reported the opposite](http://blogs.wsj.com/washwire/2016/06/23/donald-trump-pressed-on-claim-clintons-email-server-was-hacked/) two days ago.

If you are talking about the Romanian hacker, his claim seems to be that he breached [someone else's AOL account](http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2016/05/23/romanian-hacker-who-says-breached-clinton-server-finalizing-plea-deal.html). 

Can you cite the full download please? If you are talking about Wikileaks, the State Department released those files: https://wikileaks.org/clinton-emails/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579706402.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579868273.0" user="bubi09" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry daftmonkey, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+5+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=daftmonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4nmale\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579732193.0" user="FierceDeity_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She seems to say anything to get elected.

That's one thing I really hate about politics in general. I think politicians should be bound to anything they promise. They should at least try, even if they fail. 

We in Germany really feel it the most as we are going towards votes again (2017). Some politician promised something they could do right now if they wanted to, it's a little while until the votes. But no, after the votes... Well, not going to happen as always. 

It goes so far that the party they belong to is colloquially called the "traitor party" 

The lying really seems more of a part of the system if anything...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579739907.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's one thing I really hate about politics in general. I think politicians should be bound to anything they promise. 

I agree, at least that politicians should be honor bound to name their changes in position clearly. I think it is certainly possible to change some positions with principle, and political compromise is hugely important.

I sometimes think of politicians as business people who seek votes and not dollars. If the market punished them for lying, they wouldn't lie. The problem is that humans aren't perfect, so our political systems should be built to compensate for our flaws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579786999.0" user="FierceDeity_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; at least that politicians should be honor bound to name their changes in position clearly

Really, yeah. Germany is horrible there. They do 180° turns because what you said yesterday isn't worth a penny. 

&amp;gt; I sometimes think of politicians as business people who seek votes and not dollars

Many seek the Dollars. The votes are just a means to get there. Get votes, decide for the highest bidder, suddenly appear in a high position in that company... Often enough. 

One nice thing is that politicians have to open up "side" income (which is mostly higher than the main income as a politician). There's a graphic here: http://www.faz.net/aktuell/politik/inland/interaktiv-so-viel-verdienen-unsere-abgeordneten-nebenher-13148777.html Scroll down into the bubbly graphic. Look at the huge bubble. One guy earning 1.8 million on the side. He's also an euro sceptic, full program. The black party is the [CDU](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christian_Democratic_Union_of_Germany). Wikipedia doesn't say anything where Gauweiler is right now, but I almost suspect in some company.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579947676.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Get votes, decide for the highest bidder, suddenly appear in a high position in that company... Often enough.

In the US we call that the revolving door. It's horrible, and IS absolutely an example of corruption. The moment you are seeking work after public service, you are corruptible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580050690.0" user="peekay427" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is the heart of a lot of people concerns with Clinton. A friend the other day said to me "what she did in the past has no bearing on what she'll do in the future." And now she's saying some things that are more progressive than previous stances that she's taken but don't seem to jive with her major donors. So if there is no accountability for campaign promises how can we trust someone who changes their positions that much to not just be pandering to us, but to actually hold to her promises?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579867499.0" user="LUMiNARY_ATL" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like you're saying that because other politicians do it, she's in the clear. I'd say, not so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579938849.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say that. The CMV is that she's "unfit" for the presidency, and my comment is saying that she is as fit for the Presidency as many other presidents were.

This isn't a binary. She's not the best, but she's also nowhere near Trump.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579984384.0" user="LUMiNARY_ATL" delta="False">
    <text>Other presidents having been voted in isn't really a metric for "fitness for presidency".

Nixon and Ulysses S. Grant were most likely not fit to be president, yet they were.

Additionally, regardless of political opinions, it's pretty likely that Hillary Clinton would be a felon if she didn't have the power to protract the findings. That would make her unable to run for president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579990343.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Additionally, regardless of political opinions, it's pretty likely that Hillary Clinton would be a felon if she didn't have the power to protract the findings

What? Where do you get that? Because of the e-mails? By that standard, [this dude](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Petraeus) should get life in prison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580060896.0" user="LUMiNARY_ATL" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, glad you brought up Patreus. What he did actually included less damaging information, less counts of the crime, and was passed to someone with a clearance also. He had to plea down to a misdemeanor with a suspended sentence and he lost his career over it.

I wasn't specifically talking about the emails too. I was thinking more about her accepting donations from foreign dignitaries and the financial management of the Clinton Foundation.

If you were to go a bit conspiratorial, you could also consider the Clinton body count, but that's a stretch, so I wasn't considering it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580068192.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>However, Petraeus actually leaked info. The accusation against Hillary is that she put info in a less protected spot, not that anything leaked. (unlike the Manning leak, or the OPM hack)

&amp;gt; accepting donations from foreign dignitaries and the financial management of the Clinton Foundation.

Can you provide some links? All I've seen about the Clinton foundation is complaints that some of the donors aren't good people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580097080.0" user="LUMiNARY_ATL" delta="False">
    <text>It's debatable what was worse. Patreus gave information to a woman with a clearance and Hillary stored secret or above documents on a private server, which was hacked, possibly by at least 1 foreign government, doing damage to the country. Additionally, she failed to follow data retention laws governing the management of the data. Either way, both Petraeus and Clinton, most likely committed felonies. Petraeus 1 count, Hillary, multiple. Either way, that should bar them both from presidency.

If you actually do care to read it, take a look at Charles Ortel's analysis:


http://charlesortel.com/tag/Clinton%20Foundation

It's pretty clear that there's some fraud there. The donations reported by donors are discrepant to that reported by the CF in the range of billions.

At worst, this is extreme fraud, at best it's failure to follow proper self-auditing regulations required by the foundation.

You add that together with all her other scandals and I think it's safe to say, regardless of her opponent, she is not fit to be president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580128667.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a private server, which was hacked, possibly by at least 1 foreign government, doing damage to the country.

I think you are falling for a rumor. http://blogs.wsj.com/washwire/2016/06/23/donald-trump-pressed-on-claim-clintons-email-server-was-hacked/

Using a private server isn't illegal any more than a federal civil servant sending a work e-mail on their Gmail. Is the latter a felony? What about Colin Powell - felony? Or the Bush WH people that used rnc.com e-mails?

Her choice was still wrong, but it's not disqualifying.

&amp;gt; Charles Ortel's analysis:

This guy seems like a conspiracy theorist. He makes a lot of claims, but I read the citations and the actual problems he noted seem pretty mundane. What fraud are you talking about?

His cited "hard evidence" is that filings were late, an audit was too quick, two pages of an auditor's report weren't made public, the Clinton website has incomplete info compared with what was filed with NY State, the money spent on fundraising vs programs isn't broken out, a incorrect number in a brochure, a change in how they reported UNITAID $ (I can't really understand what he's saying here), the CEO left suddenly, directors not logging enough time "directing," and the foundation changing focus to HIV/AIDS.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579900573.0" user="tehallie" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Hillary Clinton is corrupt.

&amp;gt; This is a very loose definition of corruption. It is absolutely routine in politics for donors to Presidential campaigns to get appointed to spots on various advisory boards and ambassadorships.

That doesn't make it right.  It's a 'technically legal' form of patronage and nepotism, both of which of polar opposites of ethical and transparent behavior.  

&amp;gt; Not releasing speech transcripts is also typical behavior; I've never seen accusations that Trump or any other candidate release their remarks at private fundraising dinners. Obama's "cling to guns and faith" comment was at a private event without a transcript, as was Mitt Romney's "47%" comment. It seems unreasonable to ask a candidate to release all records of all remarks they have ever made - if anything noteworthy was said, people in the crowd could talk about it. More than likely, Clinton got some things wrong in those speeches; everyone is more accurate with hindsight. Why should she release information that will help her opponents when Trump won't even release his tax returns? This feels like a double standard.

You're correct, but she's not being asked to release ALL remarks she's ever made.  She's being asked to release remarks to the financial sector that she charged [$225K \(plus perks\)](http://dailycaller.com/2016/06/22/leaked-documents-reveal-hillarys-luxurious-demands-for-private-speech/) for.  Part of this fee includes a stenographer, which means the speeches DO have transcripts.  Given that she has faced increasing criticism over the years for her close ties to Wall Street, it makes sense for her to be "[the most transparent official](http://thehill.com/blogs/ballot-box/presidential-races/271879-clinton-im-most-transparent-public-official-in-modern)" and release the transcripts.  

&amp;gt; &amp;gt; She takes huge sums of cash from wall street

&amp;gt; So did Obama and every candidate. Our politics requires lots of fundraising and Wall Street has money. I'm all for changing the fundraising system. Also, if Elizabeth Warren is backing Hillary, then I think we can trust her to try to take some action about the banks.

Our politics has become a pay-to-play system, and is a slap in the face to the principles of democracy and republic.  Our system is founded on the idea that the people elect representatives who listen to, and act as a voice for those who elected them.  This has been perverted into "We 'listen' to everyone, but only act as a voice for those who can make it worth our while."  And even if Warren is backing Clinton, I think we'll only see [Clinton pay more lip service to the people](http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2015/11/hillary-clinton-told-wall-street-to-cut-it-out-not-so-much-the-record-shows-213363), while continuing to enrich the financial industry.  

&amp;gt; &amp;gt; She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia.

&amp;gt; This is a little misleading. She gave a very important speech about women's rights in Beijing that was and is widely considered to be one of the most signifiant speeches on women's rights in history. That's just a fact; her words reverberated widely and were widely cited. The money her foundation takes from the Sauds is directed charitably - would you prefer we cut off all ties from anyone not like us?

[The speech you're referring to was given in 1995](http://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/hillaryclintonbeijingspeech.htm).  
You're glossing over the charge of the question: Saudi Arabia has continually restricted the fundamental rights of women, and yet Hillary Clinton takes their money.  Even if it's used charitably, this would be comparable to Eliot Ness and Andrew Mellon taking money from Al Capone, and using it for hospitals.  The money is still dirty, no matter what it's used for.  


&amp;gt; &amp;gt; She seems to say anything to get elected.

&amp;gt; Welcome to politics; its good when leaders change positions to represent the people that they want support from. However, what we have seen is that Clinton can govern. She's done real work with real accomplishments in the real world, and has much more to show for it than Sanders's protest votes in the Senate. Yes, she was wrong about Iraq (though not in the same way Bush was), but she's normal. Trump isn't normal - Trump is dangerous.

It's good when leaders change their positions in response to changing data, but not good when it's in response to changing opinion polls.  Hillary Clinton has changed her position on the TPP, gay marriage, minorities...the only thing she seems to NOT have changed her position on is how much she likes money.  

&amp;gt; &amp;gt; She held secret government files on a server that was hacked multiple times

&amp;gt; This isn't true. Servers all over the internet get pings and attempts to hack into them. There's no evidence the e-mails were leaked or taken, just standard computer security stuff that everyone deals with. The e-mail was a mistake, yes, but it wasn't evil. Did you know the Bush White House did all of their e-mail on RNC servers to avoid recordkeeping?

Yes, [Bush used an RNC system, and was roundly attacked and criticized for it, just like Hillary.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bush_White_House_email_controversy)  We've seen evidence that people were able to penetrate her system, and that basic security procedures were not followed.  

&amp;gt; &amp;gt; Is there something that I'm missing?

&amp;gt; I think you've gotten lost in Clinton's flaws and missed that all politics is flawed this way. Obama succeeded in his campaign partly because he took in a lot of money from rich donors early on. He passed healthcare with a semi-bribe to Nebraska - the "Cornhusker Kickback."

You're ignoring the SCALE that Clinton is corrupt on.  This isn't political dealmaking, which is distasteful, but absolutely happens.  This is taking money from industries she's going to charged with regulating, and who have the potential to crash the world's economy, AGAIN.  I'd expect a higher standard.  

&amp;gt; You're right that Clinton isn't a big threat of change to the system, but Obama also didn't do much to change the system despite his promises. Clinton is a typical, well-versed candidate who can do the job. I don't think Sanders has the same experience (esp in foreign affairs) and Trump is SO DANGEROUS that she's the only choice.

She's well-versed, yes, but in lining her own pockets and being a war hawk.  

&amp;gt; That's not to say that Clinton is my favorite; I was an Obama supporter for many reasons you cite. However, I think she's a fair choice for the office. Also, the double standard that people and the media subject her to is crazy.

Y'know what?  I'll absolutely agree there's a double standard, but Hillary created it.  She's gotten so good at deflection, obfuscation, and downright lying that the media's given up asking her serious questions.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579936483.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I think your points are generally strong and correct that we shouldn't be down with what Clinton has done, though I think that standard should be applied to all politicians. (Why aren't people talking about the past-minute Clinton pardons?) I will say, though, that that doesn't make her "unfit," and it doesn't mean there is ANY equivalence between her and Trump.

I'd also suggest [this piece](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/mar/28/hillary-clinton-honest-transparency-jill-abramson), which discusses how her lack of transparency looks like corruption. My guess is that a strong democratic opponent this cycle could have beaten her, and I wish someone besides Sanders had gone for it.

&amp;gt; the only thing she seems to NOT have changed her position on is how much she likes money.

I'm also not sure this is quite true. Advocating for health care reform is a consistent refrain for her, for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579957907.0" user="tehallie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; (Why aren't people talking about the past-minute Clinton pardons?)

Agreed, but if I had to guess, it's because she herself didn't issue the pardons.  She may have had a hand in them, but in the end it wasn't her hand that signed them, y'know?

&amp;gt; I'm also not sure this is quite true. Advocating for health care reform is a consistent refrain for her, for example.

Ehhh...I disagree.  Saying that you're for 'health care reform' is a goalpost that you can move to anywhere when it's convenient for you.  You can claim to be for it because you think ER's should only be able to charge $4900 instead of $5000 for a visit, but that isn't true reform.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579975078.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Saying that you're for 'health care reform' is a goalpost that you can move to anywhere when it's convenient for you. 

Well, sure - but https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_Children%27s_Health_Insurance_Program and Hillarycare weren't small efforts of reform.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580405829.0" user="MCRemix" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding health care reform, with all due respect, you need to read up on her battle for Hillarycare, where she went toe to toe with the health care industry and got burned in the end. 

To a large degree, it will help you understand why she isn't in agreement with Bernie on tactics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580001774.0" user="ListenHear" delta="False">
    <text>They absolutely have given up asking tough questions. It's all come down to "How does it feel to be the first woman nominee? Do you feel the weight on your shoulders?" (Which isn't true she's not the first). They are going to spin this into trapping people into caring about her gender and "history making" rather than her policies and views (not that Trump is any better, they can both go rot away on an island together for all I care) but you're right, the media has completely given up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580052816.0" user="Puggpu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;she's not the first

I know you're probably referencing Jill Stein, but come on. Clinton is the first major party nominee, that's what matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580045238.0" user="Royale_mit_kase" delta="False">
    <text>Your being outright pedantic and incapable of any sort of reasonable compromise. No political candidate is perfect. As a citizen of a democracy it's your duty to vote for whoever best represents your interests. If you can't understand this go back to S4P and pretend the indictment is coming. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580153073.0" user="tehallie" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying a political candidate needs to be perfect.  Clinton is (and has been throughout her career) slimy, untruthful, and displays an attitude of entitlement.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580184787.0" user="Royale_mit_kase" delta="False">
    <text>Still miles better than trump</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580679023.0" user="Onorhc" delta="False">
    <text>I'm tired of choosing between a douch and a turd, and you should be too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580739331.0" user="QuazAndWally" delta="False">
    <text>What other options are there in this two party system?  Move?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580751704.0" user="Onorhc" delta="False">
    <text>Having and sticking to your principals? If enough people did that we would have a three or more party race. 

This is kinda the way things work in Canada, and for all its faults it feels less decisive than the US system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581083785.0" user="Royale_mit_kase" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have to change your principals. You just need to grow up, Bernie lost get over it. Now there's only one candidate who can beat Trump. Inches seperate HRC and Sanders. Trump might as well be on the moon. There'll definitely be another Bernie type candidate on the future. But elections aren't about you. I love how you guys say, "hey those guys have this over there! Why can't we have it?" You know how to change things, you vote, which is something Bernie supporters couldn't care enough to do. But if you care about progressive principals then you should vote to preserve them in this country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581352979.0" user="Onorhc" delta="False">
    <text>M8, you sound angry. Grab a snickers while the big boys talk politics.

You can decide which bully you want to give your lunch Money to, I will decide who fits my platform best.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581076023.0" user="Royale_mit_kase" delta="False">
    <text>One is the status quo. Basically 4 more years of Obama. The other is a hard-line conservative bigot who has dangerous plans for the economy and women's reproductive rights. I like how you Berners believe HRC is the devil whereas Trump is the real enemy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581356153.0" user="Onorhc" delta="False">
    <text>... I'm tired of being labeled by what option I align closest with.

That's probably the biggest pisser in this whole election. The regular belittling of our views as unattainable with the backhanded slap of telling us to get in line.

Not sure if your a trumpet or a clintmouse, but you sound like someone I don't want to align my vote with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580410085.0" user="parolang" delta="False">
    <text>But isn't the question whether Clinton is "fit" for President? To me this is weaker criteria than having upstanding character.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579932386.0" user="Man898989moon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She gave a very important speech about women's rights in Beijing that was and is widely considered to be one of the most signifiant speeches on women's rights in history. That's just a fact;

um. That is an opinion sir.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579973048.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; widely considered to be one of the most signifiant speeches on women's rights in history

That is a fact, proven by the number of citations in textbooks, discussions in the press, and is ranked #35 on this list of American rhetoric. You might disagree with all of the other authorities, and *if it was significant* is an opinion, but I can represent the views of others factually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579985548.0" user="Man898989moon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She gave a very important speech about women's rights

Still an opinion.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579988402.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She gave a very important speech about women's rights

Ok. Fair. I will retract the word "important" if you accept the latter clause.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579994453.0" user="Man898989moon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She gave a very speech about women's rights

Sounds like English. No but really Im not disagreeing with you, I haven't actually seen the speech you're talking about but i just wanted to make it clear that it was an opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579999155.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>You are being semantic and I am being semantic right back.

&amp;gt; She gave a speech about women's rights in Beijing that was and is widely considered to be one of the most signifiant speeches on women's rights in history. That's just a fact.

That's what I intend to say. It's is factually accurate to say that "Hamilton" is widely considered to be a significant work of theater, and "The Godfather" is widely considered to be a significant work in film.

You may disagree with most people, but describing what others say is a factual exercise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580009466.0" user="Man898989moon" delta="False">
    <text>Can we just not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580029242.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>Don't start a semantic argument if you don't want to argue semantics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579934041.0" user="kf7zde" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm.. I like your last point.

Basically a TLDR of the system. Maybe broken to some perspectives, but definitely flawed. But such is the tragedy of power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581567728.0" user="Cyclotrom" delta="False">
    <text>The tragedy of power is just the fruit of having to represent a wide range of people which necessarily leads to compromise, compromise and purity are often at odds. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581992628.0" user="kf7zde" delta="False">
    <text>My understanding of the tragedy power does not have to deal with compromise or representation at all, but is purely that any decision is flawed. That there is always, when in a position of power, no matter what, some effect that is detrimental. That is simply reality, in all aspects of life, because everything is finite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579965097.0" user="Enchanted_Bunny" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention that the only reason Obama won the 2008 primary was because the DNC literally just assigned uncommitted votes to him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580019089.0" user="cam_man_can" delta="False">
    <text>I think you said it perfectly. Maybe Bernie is more trustworthy than Clinton, but he's so ideologically rigid that he would get absolutely nothing done as president, and further the gridlock in congress. Clinton has her problems, but I feel like she's been made to look like Satan on Reddit when in reality she's just a standard cold and calculated politician. 

I don't think there's anything inherently evil about her. In my opinion, she just knows that to get shit done in Washington you have to play the Washington game, and sometimes that means getting involved with big corporations, or changing your stances on things to align with voters. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580080099.0" user="KallistiTMP" delta="False">
    <text>Couple points: 

First, **most** political candidates take money from wall street, Sanders is a notable exception that should be mentioned given the context.

On the emails, it's important to understand that the reason she used a private email server was almost certainly to use a loophole that would allow her to avoid FOIA-requests, which is arguably somewhat evil. Also, given the total lack of any meaningful security on her server, and her high profile in military matters, it's an absolute certainty that her emails were compromised. We haven't heard of any specific compromises because that would be seriously classified information that is likely currently under separate investigation by the CIA, NSA, and/or DOD. But the lack of security on her server was criminally negligent to the point that it might as well have been a paper sign that said "plz don't hack us, kthx". Given the amount of effort that many foreign countries put into espionage, it's an absolute certainty her server was hacked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580093217.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; almost certainly to use a loophole that would allow her to avoid FOIA-requests

No? All of her e-mails with state people were archived by the state systems......the entire justification by her lawyers was that sending e-mails to state.gov was the same thing as using state.gov. She used the private server so that her personal e-mails wouldn't be subject to FOIA and so she could use one device.

&amp;gt; Also, given the total lack of any meaningful security on her server, and her high profile in military matters, it's an absolute certainty that her emails were compromised. 

This is naive of how servers and computer security work. If the server is only running e-mail, there aren't many attack vectors unless you leave a port open that you shouldn't.

&amp;gt; We haven't heard of any specific compromises because that would be seriously classified information that is likely currently under separate investigation by the CIA, NSA, and/or DOD.

Why would that be classified? The OPM breach was reported, as other breaches have been.

Again: the e-mail choice was a mistake, but one with precedent from Colin Powell, the Bush White House, and others in government. The State Department issued explicit rules during her tenure. Her choice was wrong, but by that standard Trump disqualifies himself every time he opens his mouth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580084722.0" user="anothercarguy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; &amp;gt;She held secret government files on a server that was hacked multiple times

&amp;gt;This isn't true. Servers all over the internet get pings and attempts to hack into them. There's no evidence the e-mails were leaked or taken, just standard computer security stuff that everyone deals with. 

I read the hack. Your statement is false. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580099229.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I read the hack. Your statement is false.

http://blogs.wsj.com/washwire/2016/06/23/donald-trump-pressed-on-claim-clintons-email-server-was-hacked/

Did you read the e-mails released on Wikileaks or actually get a copy of the e-mails? If you did read the hacked e-mails, the Wall Street Journal would like to know. (and so would I)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580102661.0" user="anothercarguy" delta="False">
    <text>the copy like everyone else. Did you bother reading the russian stuff? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580136025.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah.....dude you are falling for lies and hearsay. The russia stuff, when you look at it, is stuff sent by a dude named Sidney Blumenthal, who had an AOL account that was hacked by a Romanian.

The hacker has "claimed" that he also got into Clinton's e-mail as well, but there's zero proof of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580223911.0" user="Fuck-The-Cards" delta="False">
    <text>Just because it's common behavior doesn't mean we have to continue allowing it. She is unethical. By electing Hillary we roll over once again. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580447924.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She is unethical. By electing Hillary we roll over once again.

That's a fair statement. But by your standards of ethics, LBJ, Roosevelt, Kennedy, Reagan, Nixon, and most of the rest of them were just as bad or worse. Obama came into office to change the game and failed because the other side realized that blocking literally everything he wanted to do was good politics.

I wish someone else had gone for the democrat primary, but they didn't. I think voting for Sanders is entirely a fiar choice for people to make.

I don't think that's the case for Trump. He truly is unfit for the Presidency. Clinton is like many other politicians, and she's not going to burn the house down.

As much as politics sucks, it doesn't involve resolving disputes with violence. That's what Trump is about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580267972.0" user="tinyjb" delta="False">
    <text>Just because someone else did something wrong doesn't make it okay for her to do it either.

You're using the "they did it, so can I" argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580442545.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Just because someone else did something wrong doesn't make it okay for her to do it either.

Nowhere in my post did I say that anything she's done is "okay." I don't think it is.

The sad conclusion that I've reached, though, is that a politicians that tries to do everything in a morally good, straight forward way gets treated like Jimmy Carter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580285949.0" user="iGotDatDainbramage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've never seen accusations that Trump release his transcripts

Because when Trump gave those speeches, he wasn't a sworn public official. That's the difference.

 If you don't see how it's not okay for a sworn public official to take millions of dollars from powerful banking institutions that played a large role in the collapse of the economy in the late 2000s and then NOT tell the people she is sworn to serve what she told them, I don't know what to tell you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580440586.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Because when Trump gave those speeches, he wasn't a sworn public official. That's the difference.

When Clinton gave her recent speeches, she wasn't an official either. Now, that doesn't make getting a lot of money from Wall Street ok, but she also gave speeches to many industry and trade groups - I know people that went to several of them. She's as bought as any other politician - including Obama and Bush.

I would prefer that Clinton release the transcripts, but I also see a double standard. And again, could there be anything in those transcripts close to what Trump has said in public?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580371693.0" user="farfromjordan" delta="False">
    <text>The Wall St transcripts became an issue when she was head to head with Bernie Sanders, not Trump. To date she is not the nominee and even after the 2016 Democratic convention comparing her to Trump is a false equivalency. Trump-baiting is the definition of low effort. 
Whitewater washing the Clinton history with the implicit notion that identity politics is more important than ethics is a hypocrisy that only serves to embolden those that mockingly call out the 'Regressive' Left. For shame!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580432514.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Whitewater washing the Clinton history with the implicit notion that identity politics is more important than ethics is a hypocrisy that only serves to embolden those that mockingly call out the 'Regressive' Left.

You have a lot of buzzwords in here and I'm not sure what you're saying.

I've never said she's my favorite for the office. My statement is that she is as fit for the office as many of her predecessors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580436743.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My goal with this post is to show you that she is as fit for the Presidency as many other presidents were.

lol lofty goals

its telling that this is the most anyone can even attempt</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580456544.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; its telling that this is the most anyone can even attempt

Yep. Then again, I would take her over GW Bush (his presidency really was a huge mess), her husband, Reagan, Nixon, and Kennedy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580462707.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>bush was outwardly dopey which made him slightly more endearing

like you didnt think hed be capable of making a convincing lie to your face

hillary you can never ever tell if shes sincere, she lies constantly and her demeanour makes it really hard to tell whats going on

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580479829.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; she lies constantly 

Odd thing to say. Have you ever compared a clinton speech to a trump speech? I'm pretty sure one of them is going to be full of truth and fact and one will be full of lies.

But yeah, she's not very likeable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580512246.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>trump may say stupid shit but in reality he lies far less than hillary

youd be pressed to find one thing in a hillary speech she was being sincere about</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580580345.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; youd be pressed to find one thing in a hillary speech she was being sincere about

I think you've fallen for lies from people that stand to profit from you hating Clinton. She may be ambitious and not great and getting people to like her, but she's not crazy, she works hard, she gives a shit, and she's been a productive person in public life. She's learned from the collapse of Hillarycare, and while you've been told again and again that she's awful I promise she's not dangerous.

Trump is dangerous. When Clinton lies, she admits it - she deals with it. She goes to hearings and answers questions for 10 hours. Trump lies freely and with abandon. The truth doesn't matter to him. **You** don't matter to him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580611651.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think you've fallen for lies from people that stand to profit from you hating Clinton.

such as...

you can hear everything she says in her speeches (well except for the ones to her donors), theres no way to twist that into someone elses fault

she has no standards, shell say whatever people who give her money tell her to and thats *always* been the case

&amp;gt;not great and getting people to like her

why do you think this is tho

its not incidental, its central to her aloof attitude

you cant laugh off serious allegations every single time and retain peoples trust

&amp;gt; but she's not crazy, she works hard, she gives a shit, and she's been a productive person in public life.

citation needed really

&amp;gt;and while you've been told again and again that she's awful I promise she's not dangerous.

well frankly i lived through the last few decades so im not going to be easily convinced

hillary is known as a liar even among her own circle

&amp;gt;Trump is dangerous.

how so

&amp;gt;When Clinton lies, she admits it - she deals with it

lol what what does this even mean

clearly she hasnt or she wouldnt be under criminal investigation 

&amp;gt;Trump lies freely and with abandon. The truth doesn't matter to him. You don't matter to him.

what has he lied about

and i should hope i dont matter to him i live in australia </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580617811.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Trump lies - this is from 4.6 hours of him speaking: http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/03/trump-fact-check-errors-exaggerations-falsehoods-213730

&amp;gt; clearly she hasnt or she wouldnt be under criminal investigation

She's admitted everything about the e-mail server....I think you are falling for internet rumors. Look at how many lies about her are out there: http://www.snopes.com/tag/hillary-clinton/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580636949.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Trump lies - this is from 4.6 hours of him speaking

lol thats like politifact levels of spin

if you really want to criticise trumps ideas it really isnt hard to do it legitimately, its not like hes a great politician

but that article is just petty

&amp;gt; She's admitted everything about the e-mail server

she also said "it was allowed" "its an internal security review" and "what, with a cloth?"

shes not being honest about it in the slightest

also snopes is for urban legends, when they try to get political its cringeworthy and inaccurate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580663328.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; she also said "it was allowed" "its an internal security review" and "what, with a cloth?"

From her standpoint, it was allowed under FOIA and precedent from the Bush WH and Colin Powell. I don't think she considered the security issues. It was a move of convenience to avoid carrying two devices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582113993.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>shes wrong and lied about it, it was never allowed and she knew it

you really shouldnt fall for her clumsy old grandmother act this shit is calculated</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582260962.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; shes wrong and lied about it, it was never allowed and she knew it

Then why the fuck would she have ever done it - knowing it would cause this shitstorm? It wasn't like her e-mail address was a secret in the government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582305322.0" user="captainpriapism" delta="False">
    <text>she thought she could get away with it, and it was easier for her than doing the right thing

most of the time people like her do some stupid ass borderline illegal shit theyre able to cover it up or just laugh it off in an interview

best believe nobody in her camp thought shed be taken to task

have you only just heard of hillary or something this isnt out of character *at all*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580451999.0" user="d4shing" delta="False">
    <text>Lots of candidates raise money from Wall Street (and PACs and big business), I agree, but she and her husband have collected $150,000,000+ in personal speaking fees, buying them multiple mansions, a townhouse in Georgetown, etc.  That is prodigious and completely unprecedented.  No other politician has a haul even 1/10th as large, and generally people like Condoleeza Rice or former Senators don't work the speaking fee circuit until they're done with public office (it's illegal for sitting legislators).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580476848.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No other politician has a haul even 1/10th as large

I'd love a citation for that. I would also note that most couples don't have past experience as a governor, senator, president, and secretary of state between the two of them.

I'm also not sure if the amount of speaking fees impacts fitness for the Presidency. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580528153.0" user="d4shing" delta="False">
    <text>Here are some comparables: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-politics/wp/2013/07/11/hillary-clinton-isnt-alone-former-politicians-rake-it-in-on-speaker-circuit/

George W. Bush, 15 mil; Rudy Giuliani, 9 mil...  

That's a lot of money, too, and it's gross and should be illegal, but still not made-for-life, flying around on private jets between your multiple mansions and your private island kind of money.  I think it shows unspeakable avarice and next-level corruption.  

And I genuinely don't even understand it! They could have stopped at 20 or 30 mil and been perfectly comfortable and not even an outlier.  Bill could have stopped taking money from foreign governments for the Clinton Foundation while his wife was Secretary of State; like get them to give to the Gates Foundation instead for a couple years. These people are sociopaths.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580590458.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think it shows unspeakable avarice and next-level corruption.

I'm still confused. How does the number of paid speaking engagements someone does show avarice and corruption?

Forget the Clintons for a second. If Teresa Kerry had a foundation and took donations right now, would that be so awful? (Except wait, [she does](http://www.heinz.org/))

Getting donations to your foundation doesn't make you a sociopath. It just doesn't. The hatred that people have shared and spread for the Clintons since the 90s isn't about what they do; it....I don't even know where its from. I'd recommend the book "Blinded by the Right" for more on the subject and how rabid people have been about the Clintons.

I get how its distasteful and I don't like it for someone considering office (though if I could make that money from speaking, I would certainly put a few million in the bank :P ), but it doesn't make someone evil incarnate. 

Trump is the danger. Clinton is boring, normal, and not going to turn the country into a trash fire. This election, that's enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581402608.0" user="d4shing" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you're confused - avarice is greed.  If you amass a dragon treasure pile of gold, far in excess of what any human could spend in their lifetime, that is greed.  When you get that money by giving 'speeches' to the exact predatory corporations you're supposed to be protecting people from, that's corruption.

Teresa Kerry is not seeking further public office (did she ever hold any?).  She was also already a billionaire due to ketchup.  Did her foundation take money from sovereign nations that were seeking approval for multi-billion dollar arms deals while her husband was secretary of state and deciding whether or not to approve those exact deals?  If so, yes, that's also corrupt and behavior unworthy of a public servant in a democracy.

A few million is par for the course, 150 is unprecedented and next level.

This country survived a civil war, two world wars, Richard Nixon, and George W Bush.  If you think Trump is bad, wait until you see what happens after 4 years of Clinton -- if she manages not to blow it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581538824.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I don't love Clinton, but I don't understand the hatred I'm seeing her. **We saw the Clintons in the White House for eight years** and the worst thing that happened was a domestic sex scandal and in foreign affairs, Rwanda. Are you suggesting that she's somehow going to blow the thing up when she's in office?

&amp;gt; When you get that money by giving 'speeches' to the exact predatory corporations you're supposed to be protecting people from, that's corruption.

First, I dispute that public service is about protecting people from corporations. There are plenty of companies that seek to do well and contribute to their communities. Second, many of her speeches weren't to corps, but to [industry trade groups](https://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/47v0h9/list_of_all_of_hillary_clintons_paid_speeches/). Third, if your problem is with rich people, then why not target Donald Trump, who has been documented to make money by exploiting people and tenants? His policies and practices have hurt people far more, even as a private businessman, than anything Clinton has done.

&amp;gt; Did her foundation take money from sovereign nations that were seeking approval for multi-billion dollar arms deals while her husband was secretary of state and deciding whether or not to approve those exact deals?

Is this the Haiti donation thing? I thought all parties acknowledged that was an error and was done without Sec. Clinton's knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581637679.0" user="d4shing" delta="False">
    <text>They're smart people, no question - they deliberately kept stuff from blowing up while Bill was in office.  Classic example is welfare reform, which multiplied extreme poverty in this country and, coincidentally, largely did not take effect until the year 2000. See, also: the repeal of Glass-Steagall.  You had the stock market bubble peak in early 2001, less than two months after he left office.

I think the top priority in our political economy today should be protecting people from corporations.  Corporate profits as a share of GDP is at an all-time high, wages and labor force participation are at post-war lows, industry consolidation has been relentless  and competition is at record lows, and all of the gains of the decade to date have gone to the top 1% as everyone else falls behind.  If we were Denmark or Indonesia, I would agree that other priorities would rank higher.

I actually think exploiting the system to your own advantage is less morally blameworthy than designing an exploitative system in exchange for kickbacks.  Starting some dogshit degree mill university -- bad, no question.  Helping design the legal and economic framework that allows these degree mills to exist, and then pocketing speaking fees, campaign contributions and donations from the people that set them up -- worse, in my opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581648211.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Corporate profits as a share of GDP is at an all-time high, wages and labor force participation are at post-war lows, industry consolidation has been relentless and competition is at record lows, and all of the gains of the decade to date have gone to the top 1% as everyone else falls behind. If we were Denmark or Indonesia, I would agree that other priorities would rank higher.

I think I would use similar language to describe income inequality, but I think the gains of the 1% are more about investments in domestic and international groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580879472.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's a lot of money, too, and it's gross and should be illegal,

Why should it be illegal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580454197.0" user="Noexit007" delta="False">
    <text>I have read through your comment, and many others in this thread and there seems to be a HUGE amount of people who are simply stating in no uncertain terms:

"This is normal in politics so its ok"

The question you should then ask yourself is, but does that make it ok?  Shouldn't we be striving to CHANGE politics to be better?  Shouldn't we hold those we vote for to a higher standard and not accept such behaviors? 

I feel like this is the argument children use when they get in trouble with their parents.  The old "but everyone else does it".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580472822.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The question you should then ask yourself is, but does that make it ok? Shouldn't we be striving to CHANGE politics to be better? Shouldn't we hold those we vote for to a higher standard and not accept such behaviors?

Great comment and questions. No, its not ok, and yes, it should be better. 100%. Remember the CMV was that she was "unfit" - not that she was less ethical than I would like.

I do hope my post doesn't say that her actions are all "ok" - my point is that they are "not ok" in the normal sense, vs the trash fire of Trump's candidacy. It is dangerous to assume an equivalence between them; in fact, I would say that Kasich, Rubio, Cruz, and many other GOP nominees are also "fit" by the standard I used.

Trump is a special case and a special danger that must be resisted by all parties and all ideologies. Whatever issues we have with Clinton, he is far far worse. That's why I spent the time to write the comment.

Now, in terms of making it better, I think you should look at what happened to Jimmy Carter and Obama. Both of them are generally known to be good men, and their White House were not beset by scandal. Yet, Obama's efforts to find bipartisan compromise completely and entirely failed. In the end, his reform efforts relied completely on democrats and the voters punished him for not being bipartisan when he tried for that - several times.

If you want politicians who do good, we have to reward good. But we aren't doing that. Instead, we punished Obama in 2010. People I know that supported the President didn't turn out for midterm elections.

If you want to change politics, we have to change the people. That is happening - I think some parts of homophobia will die out with the older generation, but we can do better. I'd welcome your ideas of what we can do, though I think a lot of it is making people accept their responsibility as citizens.

And sadly, it means punishing the party that hasn't tried to help govern - the GOP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580525367.0" user="Noexit007" delta="False">
    <text>Let me start off by saying I appreciate the response, and actually agree with the sentiments for the most part.  I really dont want to bring Trump into this, because I do think hes a special case.  However I will say that I am someone who thinks hes a lot of talk and will likely be much less "extreme" in the end then he may appear.  That doesn't mean hes not a danger, but I also think folks calling him the next Hitler are ignorant.  But enough of him, as thats not the debate.

I dont disagree that part of the problem is the system as a whole (which includes the "people"). Unfortunately the people can do very little to change things without a full on revolution.  The likelihood of that is slim to none because there simply is no way for most to be able to afford taking such a drastic stand, and there are enough powerful voices out there to fight tooth and nail at every turn.

You say "we need to change the people".  People will always change with time, as the world evolves.  Sometimes its for the better, sometimes for the worse.  However what you ask is likely pointing towards something near impossible to fix;  human nature.  Realistically the root of the political problem in this country is the human condition.  Just as there will always be those who are bad or good, such things will always affect politics as long as people participate. 

Power often corrupts, and its very easy for a good person to turn bad or if nothing else, stand back and watch.  Throw in the money that flows throughout politics in mass, often from big corporations or powerful individuals, and the basic problem of human nature becomes a monster.  

While it may be impossible to change human nature, it might be possible to minimize the issues that could arise by controlling the money flow in politics.  But of course, now we are back at the original issue of the ability to take such a stand on the matter.  For the sources of such money, are often the ones who have massive control over the lives of those wanting the change.  Whether through the media's ear, political sway, job control, economic power, or other such things.

My fear (and this relates to why I would rather not vote for Hillary, even if it accomplishes little), is that no matter what, we have walked or run too far down the path of no return in terms of money and the power it provides (especially when it comes to politics).

Now I hope I am not coming off as a crazy, but I hope you understand my concerns, and why I would rather stand up for what I think is right, even if its standing against what is accepted, or ignored.  And even if it is a risk played against the future.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580604768.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your sentiments about human nature. I think the US has gotten by with a gridlock-prone system because people made it work in decades past, but polarization is threatening that.

100% agree Trump is a special case. I wouldn't be out here taking so much time to defend Clinton if it wasn't him on the other side.

I don't know if I agree that a revolution is needed. If you want to change the leadership, you just need votes. That's it. If you have enough people for a revolution, you have enough to kick leaders out via the ballot box. That's what the UK just showed us, against the advice of every expert in the country.

&amp;gt; we have walked or run too far down the path of no return in terms of money and the power it provides (especially when it comes to politics)

I totally hear the frustration and I agree that the systems have built up. What do you suggest as an alternative? Violence and death won't fix the human condition.

I guess I would say that even with the problems and flaws, we still have millions of people that want to immigrate here because we have it much better than other countries.

Here, you can travel freely without having to pay bribes. You can get goods from around the world at low prices. You can generally go through life without fear of crime, buy land, and live in peace and quiet. We don't have the war that affects so many others in the world, and we have clean water (with a large current exception) and trustworthy food.

"It could be worse" is a shitty argument, but a valid one. The US had an incredibly favored economic situation after the war when every other power had been devastated, allowing the average person to support a family and buy a house on factory wages. That might have been a historical aberration. We need to reduce income inequality and raise marginal taxes.

I guess my fear about doing that, though, is that any country that raises taxes too much will lose many of their rich people. The connected world makes that a real threat, which suuuuucks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580630815.0" user="Noexit007" delta="False">
    <text>Votes only work to a degree, because even if you vote in someone, they have to work within the broken system, and to think that they can walk in and fix it is sadly a pipe dream. 

I honestly dont know what the alternative is.  Like I stated before, the only obvious thing would be to remove big money from politics, meaning those voted in, would be more likely to represent the votes as a whole, rather then a special few (individuals or groups/corporations) that donated more, or have more power.

This is a big reason I have been staunchly against Hillary (despite not really truly liking any of the candidates wholeheartedly). I feel as if shes way too tied up in the broken system and so wrapped up in the "political money game" as I like to call it.

I think we understand each other.  But whereas you view Hillary as an acceptable option to avoid Trump, I view her as just as bad, but in vastly different ways.  And while her "bad" may not be seen as potentially dangerous as Trumps "bad", if only because some of it is fairly common in politics, its not acceptable to me.

This is certainly going to be a tough election if it truly does come down to Clinton V Trump, and may very well be the most true example of "lesser of 2 evils" for many many Americans, we have ever seen (regardless of which side you choose to fall on).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580652422.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I feel as if shes way too tied up in the broken system and so wrapped up in the "political money game" as I like to call it.

Entirely fair view, but I'd encourage you to look at the ways Trump has gone way the hell outside of political norms in harmful ways:

* Encourages violence against people who speak against him
* Bans press reporters that don't cover him to his liking
* Encourages discrimination against people by their religion (which will harm national security)
* Routinely lies to his supporters, so much so that politico found 60+ statements in 4.6 hours of speeches that were basic errors.
* Denies basic science
* Demonstrates no ability to compromise
* Blames and creates "the other" as the root of harm
* Voices support of "strong men" like Putin that assassinate political opponents.

I would ask you to compare the potential harm of four years of Trump compared to four years of Clinton - remembering that Trump is known for making risky bets and then leaving the public to hold the bag after his investments declare bankruptcy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580603370.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>How is Trump dangerous?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580611601.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Most fundamentally, he has encouraged violence against people he disagrees with.

I'll let this recent Op-ed by a GOP Treasury Secretary say the rest: https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/when-it-comes-to-trump-a-republican-treasury-secretary-says-choose-country-over-party/2016/06/24/c7bdba34-3942-11e6-8f7c-d4c723a2becb_story.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580631987.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>He has not encouraged violence against people he disagrees with. This is an opinion piece based off of his interpretation of Trump more than actual facts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580659018.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>You've been mislead:

&amp;gt; Donald Trump is the instigator. When confronted by protesters–the vast majority of which are peaceful and quiet–Donald Trump has told his foot soldiers to “Knock the crap out of them. Just knock the hell out of them” and that “they should be carried away on stretchers.” Trump has also said that protesters should be “roughed up.” Trump finds violence to be “fun.” His encouragement and endorsement of violence includes statements such as, “I promise you I will pay for the legal fees”; “And they started punching back…it was a beautiful thing”; “Part of the problem is that nobody wants to hurt each other anymore”; “The audience hit back, that’s what we need more of”; and “Treat them very, very rough.” Donald Trump has threatened to personally engage in fisticuffs, telling one protester that, “I’ll beat the crap out of you.”

Source: http://www.salon.com/2016/06/07/this_is_how_you_fight_a_bully_donald_trumps_violence_and_hate_needs_a_careful_response/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580889636.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>He said he would look into it as far as the legal fees went. If he's doing nothing but inciting violence, why is it always other people attacking Trump supporters? I am not misguided, you are misguided by the mainstream media and the narrative that tries to make Trump seem like literally Hitler.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580928426.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; why is it always other people attacking Trump supporters?

It's not. There have been examples of violence from people against and for Trump, both. The difference is that only one candidate is speaking in any support of the violence.

I have watched Trump rallies and speeches myself; I'm not going with what someone else is telling me. When I tell you that Trump sounds like a fascist sometimes, with his praise of Putin, that's not the media talking - that is me. Right here.

From the claim that Mexico will pay for the wall to his ignorance of foreign affairs, Trump is a delusional, arrogant, risk-taking, and routinely lying fool.

Now, he's done some useful things, and I wish other candidates borrowed his candor in some areas. As a possible leader, he is not qualified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580965738.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>That's strange because I don't recall any Bernie or Hillary rallies being protested or attacked in near the same severity. Yet, Trump is the one inciting violence? It's easy to use buzz words to call Trump racist, ignorant, unintelligent, unprepared, clueless, etc. But calling someone racist or dumb isn't a valid argument and it doesn't adequately support the argument that he is unfit for office. You can make him out to be as irrational and unpredictable as you want, and he may not be a career experienced politician, but a successful businessman cannot be successful while also being a "racist, bigoted, stupid, unintelligent, unprepared, loudmouth, person who doesn't think things through before he says them." I know everyone wants it to be true that Trump is a joke and unfit for office, but someone who is not a good leader or uncapable, or has help through enough quid pro quo and backroom deals(Hillary) could have made it this far. So to say he is Ill-prepared or unfit doesn't make any sense as there are no requirements to become president other than the normal age, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580994709.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you are ignoring all of the quotes I posted and moving the goalposts. Also, you are putting words in my mouth with quotes I didn't say. What would you need to see to stop supporting Trump?

Businessmen can be very successful while also being many of the things you named, though we don't know how successful Trump has actually been since unlike Clinton, he won't release his tax return.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581413089.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>He is in the middle of a tax audit and while, yes, other people have released theirs during an audit before, he was advised against it. More importantly, though, when is Hillary going to release her paid speeches to Goldman Sachs, the kind of company she's supposedly fighting against? I mean, they paid her over $200,000 each time she spoke, so I'm more interested to know her relationship with wall Street than I am to know Trump's business acumen. What will it take to make you see how corrupt and unfit Hillary is for presidency? Edit: as far as quotes go, each one is "hit them BACK", " punch them BACK". People were being attacked by protestors attempting to silence their political opinion and their right to vote for who they wanted. I want a leader who would tell us to fight against our attackers to defend ourselves rather than just lie there and take it. He does not incite or encourage violence, he encourages people to not take it from a bunch of jackasses trying to silence the political voice of others. Once again, Trump supporters aren't the ones attacking Sanders or Clinton rallies, and they aren't the ones starting the attacks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581554693.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Why are Clinton's speeches more important than Trump's tax records?

You know, [there have been paid speeches by many GOP candidates, including Trump.](http://www.salon.com/2016/06/01/trumps_paid_speech_scandal_the_political_press_has_murdered_hillary_for_so_much_less_partner/) Did you also demand they release the transcripts of those speeches?

If you haven't heard about those other speeches at all, I would question the apparent double standard.

And on if its corruption, that doesn't make sense to me. Corruption is under the table / backroom deals where people do favors for others. There's no evidence of that with these speeches (ahem, unlike the pardons when the Clintons left the White House). The speeches and the fees paid are public.

Let's say she hadn't spoken to wall street. Would you trust her?

&amp;gt; Edit: as far as quotes go, each one is "hit them BACK", " punch them BACK"

No. You've been mislead and lied to. Have you seen the videos? Here's one where a fellow was attacked for speaking "Black Lives Matter" http://thinkprogress.org/politics/2015/11/22/3724879/donald-trump-black-lives-matter-protester-beating/

Violence is not an acceptable answer to speech, ever. Trump supporters are attacking people who protest at his rallies and who don't hit anyone. If you were surrounded by an angry crowd, why the hell would you throw a punch? Instead, people don't like the protests so they go after the protestor.

I feel like you are twisting the evidence as hard as you can to put Trump in the most favorable light instead of just reading the quotes and watching the videos. Do you hate the people that come to his rallies to protest?

There are plenty of people who have attacked Trump supporters (San Jose being the worst example) and I tell them the same thing. Tomatoes, likewise, are not acceptable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580663343.0" user="Dan4t" delta="False">
    <text>Well, for one, he is untested. He's never been in a position of political power where we can see what he would actually do. Taking risks like that over the most powerful position in the world is dangerous imo. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580892900.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>Well imo letting in someone who has a political record of corruption, is under FBI criminal investigation, and whose opinions are open to the highest bidder seems alot more irresponsible and risky. Just because she has political experience doesn't mean it is the kind of experience that would be beneficial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581523544.0" user="Dan4t" delta="False">
    <text>Being investigated should never ever be a reason to oppose someone. Innocent until proven guilty, and after all the digging they have done, they have yet to find reason to press charges. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582108999.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>Wrong, they just haven't pressed charges yet, it doesn't mean they don't have evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583073672.0" user="Dan4t" delta="False">
    <text>So you have a time machine? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583470205.0" user="DoctorBees69" delta="False">
    <text>What? The FBI is taking their time with this case because that's what you do in an investigation. The fact that it is taking them this long means that they're building a case, not that there is a lack of evidence and they are desperately seeking some.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580630548.0" user="BigDecks" delta="False">
    <text>To summarize 80% of your points: well most politicians are corrupt so its okay. Lol you're not changing anyone's view today, that's for sure. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580633971.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying its okay. I'm saying she is as fit as other candidates and more qualified. If you want better candidates, get people not to vote for politicians that lie and cheat.

Trump is dangerous and encourages violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581146660.0" user="BigDecks" delta="False">
    <text>Hillary is a warmonger who creates violent conflicts. She also helped the Bush administration push the narrative the Iraq had WMD's. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581527104.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Citation? I thought her crime was voting for the resolution and trusting the Bush admin to do well with the war-making powers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581601831.0" user="BigDecks" delta="False">
    <text>https://youtu.be/DkS9y5t0tR0

  As for her general war mongering, please see Syria and Lybia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581633371.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing in that speech is warmongering. I think the point for some dems at the time was that threatening war would get better sanction enforcement. Also, didn't the Obama Admin decide against military action in Syria?

I promise you, if we hadn't intervened in Libya and Gaddafi had killed all of those rebels, people would be saying the blood was on her hands. Seems like a lose-lose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580836030.0" user="GunOfSod" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; all politics is flawed this way

No it's not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580842709.0" user="navybro" delta="False">
    <text>You mention Clinton has done real work with real accomplishments. I know this may be a stupid request since we've told repeatedly how experienced Clinton is, but what are her landmark pieces of legislation? 

I can't remember Clinton be passionate about anything back in those days, with the exception of how much she hated GTA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580848280.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Probably SCHIP. More here: http://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2015/09/carly-fiorina-debate-hillary-clintons-greatest-accomplishment-213157

Not much dem legislation going on in the GWB era, I don't know much about other clinton legislation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580854103.0" user="PM_ME_YOUR_MANGA" delta="False">
    <text>This is due to the broken nature of the system. The only way to gain campaign and win voters is by selling your integrity to corporate interests. 

Using Obama as an example proves nothing because Obama is corrupt in his own right. Right now he is championing the [TPP](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KnyPsKw_gak).

I don't think it's very sound logic to say "But it's perfectly acceptable to do these shitty things because everyone else gets away with it too" There needs to be some kind of disapproval to these things or the will continue to happen. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580931236.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There needs to be some kind of disapproval to these things or the will continue to happen.

Agreed, and that can come from voters. But between Trump and Clinton, there't only one choice. I wouldn't have said that about Cruz Rubio, or Kasich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580865138.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It is absolutely routine in politics for donors to Presidential campaigns to get appointed to spots on various advisory boards and ambassadorships.

And I think if we look at it, historically, most people believe it to be objectively bad if the appointee was unqualified for their post. Saying that other people did it is not a justification for someone being fit to lead; it just means you're going to get exactly what you've gotten for the last three decades (which, perhaps, were three decades of shitty presidents).

&amp;gt;Not releasing speech transcripts is also typical behavior; I've never seen accusations that Trump or any other candidate release their remarks at private fundraising dinners.... Trump won't even release his tax returns? This feels like a double standard.

It is atypical in a world of information. **Hillary Clinton has lied, on camera, about the content of her speeches to Wall Street during/after the 2008 crisis.** Don't you think the other speeches might matter, considering she's backed out of promises to the people and held up her promises to those who pay for her campaigns?

As for Trump's tax returns, he's being audited and it is foolish to release them. If you're worried about him doing something illegal with his money, the audit will catch it. Trump has not, on camera, said he has evaded taxes but refused to disclose that information. Therefore it is not a double standard.

&amp;gt;So did Obama and every candidate... Also, if Elizabeth Warren is backing Hillary, then I think we can trust her to try to take some action about the banks.

Warren belongs to a party; she knows when to fall in line. If you think her endorsement means a damn thing, you are putting way too much trust in the Democratic Party. Hillary has shown a history of favoring donors over the people. So has Obama. This preference towards the donor class, in my opinion, makes them unfit to be Presidents.

&amp;gt;Welcome to politics; its good when leaders change positions to represent the people that they want support from. However, what we have seen is that Clinton can govern.

This is horseshit; she has flat-out lied to the American people. Bosnia? Wall Street Speeches? Gay Marriage? Even Elizabeth Warren has gone on camera explaining how little integrity Clinton has in an elected office. This is **not** an indicator for good governance, it is the epitome of its absence.

&amp;gt;This isn't true. Servers all over the internet get pings and attempts to hack into them. There's no evidence the e-mails were leaked or taken, just standard computer security stuff that everyone deals with. The e-mail was a mistake, yes, but it wasn't evil. Did you know the Bush White House did all of their e-mail on RNC servers to avoid recordkeeping?

You're talking to the wrong people if you think going to Bush as an excuse is even remotely applicable. Bush was equally unfit to be President; you're comparing a corrupt hack to another equally corrupt hack and saying it's justified. And I just don't see it.

&amp;gt;Also, the double standard that people and the media subject her to is crazy.

She has no standard in the media. She openly lied about TONS OF SHIT and they completely leave it alone. Trump says something even remotely controversial? 24-hour coverage. 

I don't even really see how you can argue this sort of thing. Do you want more Obamas? Bushes? Nixons? Because that's how you're justifying things. You even said it yourself, Obama "didn't do much to change the system despite his promises." Because he wasn't beholden to you, he was beholden to the special interests that got him elected.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580947158.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>I hear you saying that the system needs to fundamentally change and I agree with that. I think Obama tried to fundamentally change it (kinda), but most of his reforms no one gave a shit about. He banned lobbyists from fundraising and no one cared (save the lobbyists) and tried for bi-partisan legislation and had that thrown in his face.

If you want things to change, you need voters and a public that reward honesty and punish lies. You need a population that does its own research instead of forwarding chain e-mails. You need to run a candidate to beat a Hillary Clinton who has more experience and accomplishments than Sanders.

&amp;gt; Hillary Clinton has lied, on camera, about the content of her speeches to Wall Street during/after the 2008 crisis.

Citation? I googled without luck.

&amp;gt; As for Trump's tax returns, he's being audited and it is foolish to release them.

Why? I don't understand why an audit is an excuse not to release your returns.

&amp;gt; This preference towards the donor class, in my opinion, makes them unfit to be Presidents.

That is a mass disqualification of most recent Presidents, but is consistent. Note that what I said in my post: "My goal with this post is to show you that she is as fit for the Presidency as many other presidents were."

And another point: Trump is NOT FIT. Like the NPR guy said, Clinton is wrong, but within normal parameters. Trump can do far more harm than she would ever do.

&amp;gt; This is horseshit; she has flat-out lied to the American people

I never said otherwise; the OP was talking about changing positions. Additional commentary: https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/mar/28/hillary-clinton-honest-transparency-jill-abramson

I'm not saying she's been universally honest; no politician has been AND we should work to change that by throwing liars out of office everywhere.

&amp;gt; Bush was equally unfit to be President; you're comparing a corrupt hack to another equally corrupt hack and saying it's justified. 

**NO.** Please stop with this. Conducting all of one's government business on private e-mail so its not available to any federal recordkeeping is substantially different than doing e-mails where one party is on @state.gov and the other isn't. My point is that Clinton's choice had precedent (and in fact was an improvement), not that it excuses her from being lazy about wanting one device.

These choices aren't binaries; Bush was far more unfit in his judgment and leadership than Clinton has shown.

&amp;gt; She openly lied about TONS OF SHIT and they completely leave it alone.

I would challenge you to compare one week of Clinton statements to one week of Trump statements and count up the number of inaccuracies. We can just do one speech apiece if you want. Trump lies much more than any other candidate because he's willfully ignorant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581432337.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Obama tried to change it? [He claimed he would have the most transparent administration to date and has been one of the most secretive.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/style/obama-promised-transparency-but-his-administration-is-one-of-the-most-secretive/2016/05/24/5a46caba-21c1-11e6-9e7f-57890b612299_story.html) And basically [every promise he made that might disadvantage bankers and the wealthy he has gone back on](http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/promises/obameter/rulings/promise-broken/). He has shown, with remarkable clarity, how little he cares about the people and about "changing the system." His "Hope and Change" is a joke.

&amp;gt;If you want things to change, you need voters and a public that reward honesty and punish lies.

I am quite literally in the middle of campaigning for a congressional candidate that seeks to change these things. You are preaching to the choir.

&amp;gt;Citation? I googled without luck.

[Kind of speaks for itself.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-dY77j6uBHI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=5m41s)

&amp;gt;Why? I don't understand why an audit is an excuse not to release your returns.

[Because an audit has legal consequences, while having the public look at his returns has only political consequences. Mixing the two is stupid.](http://www.forbes.com/sites/taxanalysts/2016/06/24/no-trump-should-not-release-his-tax-returns/#38a979967518)

&amp;gt;That is a mass disqualification of most recent Presidents, but is consistent. Note that what I said in my post: "My goal with this post is to show you that she is as fit for the Presidency as many other presidents were."
And another point: Trump is NOT FIT. Like the NPR guy said, Clinton is wrong, but within normal parameters. Trump can do far more harm than she would ever do.

You haven't presented any arguments for why Trump is not fit other than you just fear him, so I'll ignore that. In my opinion, Clinton is worse than the presidents you mention. Think of how ludicrous her term will be when she's consistently surrounded in scandal **before she's even elected.**

&amp;gt;Conducting all of one's government business on private e-mail so its not available to any federal recordkeeping is substantially different than doing e-mails where one party is on @state.gov and the other isn't. My point is that Clinton's choice had precedent (and in fact was an improvement), not that it excuses her from being lazy about wanting one device.

Less than 1% of ALL HER EMAILS were captured on the state server, according to the inspector general report. [According to the New York Times, nearly all of her State Dept. work was completed on the private server.](http://townhall.com/tipsheet/katiepavlich/2015/03/03/hillary-clinton-didnt-use-her-government-email-account-as-secretary-of-state-n1964994) And when asked for those emails, she happened to have just deleted half of them. Whoops!

&amp;gt;I would challenge you to compare one week of Clinton statements to one week of Trump statements and count up the number of inaccuracies. We can just do one speech apiece if you want. Trump lies much more than any other candidate because he's willfully ignorant.

Go for it. You're the one making the claim, burden of proof is on you. And I'm not talking about inaccuracies, I'm talking about *lies*. Trump does not lie "much more than any other candidate," and [considering Hillary's proclivity for lying](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-dY77j6uBHI) I really do want to see this "challenge."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581591355.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>The Forbes author believes no candidate should release their returns. The linked piece does not support your quote that an audit means you shouldn't release your returns; the point appears to be that audits are the right way to hold people accountable, instead of public release.

&amp;gt; You haven't presented any arguments for why Trump is not fit other than you just fear him, so I'll ignore that. 

All of the corruption people have accused Clinton of, Trump has done for real. All of the harm they have accused Clinton of, Trump has done for real. He lies routinely, doesn't educate himself, refuses to disavow racists, and supports violence.

&amp;gt; Less than 1% of ALL HER EMAILS were captured on the state server, according to the inspector general report.

Citation? My point is that @state.gov captures an e-mail on the recipient's end. I think you are quoting something saying she barely used the state.gov account, which is widely known.

And on lying, here you go! Both of these speeches are from the past week:

* http://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/election/article85591407.html
* Full remarks by Clinton: http://time.com/4378959/hillary-clinton-raleigh-speech-economy/
* https://www.rawstory.com/2016/06/here-are-5-bald-faced-lies-trump-just-told-in-his-major-anti-hillary-speech/
* Full remarks by Trump with additional annotations: http://www.npr.org/2016/06/22/483100251/fact-check-trumps-speech-on-clinton-annotated

What do you think? Do you want to do a separate analysis than the pieces linked?

let's take the one example you just linked about Clinton and Wall Street.

&amp;gt; Kind of speaks for itself.

It doesn't. The video shows an [excerpt of longer remarks](http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/ws/index.php?pid=77081), which I looked up. Do you think Clinton misrepresented her remarks below?

&amp;gt; If we're honest, we need to acknowledge that Wall Street has played a significant role in the current problems, and in particular in the housing crisis. A "see no evil" policy that financed irresponsible mortgage lending. A bond rating system riddled with conflicts of interest. A habit of issuing complex and opaque securities that even Wall Street itself doesn't seem to understand. [...]

&amp;gt; So I'm here today to call on Wall Street to do its part - to help end the foreclosure crisis that is devastating middle class families and threatening the health of our economy.

&amp;gt; Wall Street needs to be part of a comprehensive solution that brings to the table all those responsible and calls on them to do their part. Wall Street helped create the foreclosure crisis, and Wall Street needs to help us solve it.

&amp;gt; Over the past seven years, as incomes fell and wages stagnated, many families were lured into risky mortgages with rates that later jumped beyond what they could afford. Now, we can debate what was technically illegal; we can debate what should be defined as predatory. But there is no debate that what happened did not reflect the best of our financial system.

&amp;gt; Now, who's exactly to blame for the housing crisis? Well, that's always a question that the press and people ask and I think there's plenty of blame to go around.

&amp;gt; Responsibility belongs to mortgage lenders and brokers, who irresponsibly lowered underwriting standards, pushed risky mortgages, and hid the details in the fine print.

&amp;gt; Responsibility belongs to the Administration and to regulators, who failed to provide adequate oversight, and who failed to respond to the chorus of reports that millions of families were being taken advantage of.

&amp;gt; Responsibility belongs to the rating agencies, who woefully underestimated the risks involved in mortgage securities.

&amp;gt; And certainly borrowers share responsibility as well. Homebuyers who paid extra fees to avoid documenting their income should have known they were getting in over their heads. Speculators who were busy buying two, three, four houses to sell for a quick buck don't deserve our sympathy.

&amp;gt; But finally, responsibility also belongs to Wall Street, which not only enabled but often encouraged reckless mortgage lending. Mortgage lenders didn't have balance sheets big enough to write millions of loans on their own. So Wall Street originated and packaged the loans that common sense warned might very well have ended in collapse and foreclosure. Some people might say Wall Street only helped to distribute risk. I believe Wall Street shifted risk away from people who knew what was going on onto the people who did not.

&amp;gt; I urge Wall Street and the mortgage industry to voluntarily agree to the following three steps:

&amp;gt; First, we need a moratorium of at least 90 days on foreclosures of subprime, owner-occupied homes. The moratorium will stop foreclosures until lenders and servicers have contacted borrowers and frozen mortgage rates. It will also give financial counselors time to work with families.

&amp;gt; Second, we need to freeze the monthly rate on subprime adjustable rate mortgages, with the freeze lasting at least five years until the mortgages have been converted into affordable, fixed-rate loans.

&amp;gt; Third, the mortgage industry must provide status reports on the number of mortgages it is modifying. Accountability is essential. Despite all the media coverage, despite all the hearings, despite the Secretary of the Treasury, despite all that has gone on in the last 30 to 60 days, the mortgage industry has only modified about 1 percent of at-risk mortgages this year. That' is simply not enough.

&amp;gt; Now, I hope everyone will voluntarily agree to these steps, because we cannot fail at this. The costs are just too high.

&amp;gt; If we cannot reach a voluntary agreement, I will consider legislation to address the problem. Mortgage servicers can work with borrowers to modify their mortgages. In the process, they can save families their homes, save investors from losses down the road, and help the economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580916113.0" user="Joshuages" delta="False">
    <text>You're good. Great work. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580924194.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580958447.0" user="Joshuages" delta="False">
    <text>Addendum: I still wouldn't vote for her if there was a better option. Glad I'm elsewhere in the world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580943499.0" user="msabre7" delta="False">
    <text>Take Trump comments out of your argument and it all falls apart. OP didn't ask you to compare Clinton to Trump. Let Clinton stand on her own when trying to rebuke a CMV. 

Just because Clinton gave a speech in a foreign country on women's rights doesn't mean she's advocating for anything. And Saudi Arabia is arguably the worst place in the world to live if you are a woman, or LGBT. Yet Clinton is happy taking millions of their donation dollars. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580952790.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Let Clinton stand on her own when trying to rebuke a CMV.

I hope my post and other comments are clear that I'm making the case she is as fit as Obama, Bush, original Clinton, and others. I'm not making the case that she's "fit" - I think she's a symbol of much that is wrong in our politics.

&amp;gt; Just because Clinton gave a speech in a foreign country on women's rights doesn't mean she's advocating for anything.

If the speech wasn't advocating for anything, what do you think it was. A summary of efforts to date? Why the hell would that have made the splash her speech did?

Of course Saudi Arabia is a horrible country in many ways; its also a key strategic ally of the US. Should America stop working with Saudi Arabia because of this domestic policies?

However, I can understand people wanting her not to take donations from corrupt regimes like the Sauds. That's fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580960361.0" user="msabre7" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. America should stop working with Saudi Arabia. And any country that shows up on any human rights watch lists. We should condemn every one of them. A lot of people are quick to shout until blue in the face at someone like Trump, while completely ignoring governments that persecute millions of individuals in the world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581002430.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And any country that shows up on any human rights watch lists. We should condemn every one of them.

How does that help the people in those countries or the people in the US? This is like the people at the State Dept that want to escalate with Syria, ignoring that the response of Russia and Iran willl harm our strategic position.

I hope the American President to a higher standard than some foreign partners. (but would hold the UK PM, the French President, and the German Chancellor to a high standard as well)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581569656.0" user="TotesMessenger" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a bot, *bleep*, *bloop*. Someone has linked to this thread from another place on reddit:

- [/r/goodlongposts] [\/u\/falsehood responds to: CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency. \[+777\]](https://np.reddit.com/r/goodlongposts/comments/4pyfn7/ufalsehood_responds_to_cmv_hillary_clinton_is/)

[](#footer)*^(If you follow any of the above links, please respect the rules of reddit and don't vote in the other threads.) ^\([Info](/r/TotesMessenger) ^/ ^[Contact](/message/compose?to=/r/TotesMessenger))*

[](#bot)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581864596.0" user="zdog234" delta="False">
    <text>My only major beef with your post is that Saudi Arabia's policies towards women, sexual minorities and religious minorities are abhorrent enough to merit major pushback. However, taking money for charity is different from taking a personal salary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581927481.0" user="falsehood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Saudi Arabia's policies towards women, sexual minorities and religious minorities are abhorrent enough to merit major pushback. 

Completely agree. Americans should make movement on this. Harder for our government given the strategic situation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
