<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579582757.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>Hillary Clinton does not take money from other countries; The Clinton Foundation does. The Clinton foundation is a charitable organization that has [provided](http://www.nytimes.com/2007/05/09/world/09aidsdrugs.html?_r=1) millions of children around the world with medicine, and that does take money from anyone since no one wants poor children to die. There is no conflict of interest or corruption involved there because the Clinton's don't take money from their foundation, they donate to it: around $25 million. 

Incidentally, your image is wrong when it says Hillary Clinton opposes universal health care. Obamacare is Universal Health Care, although it is been partially blocked by the Republican supreme court and state governments. Under Obamacare, government provides health care to people who cannot afford it making it universal. What Hillary Clinton opposes as unpractical is single-payer healthcare, which involves banning the option for private health insurance.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579594063.0" user="evilpetting-zoo" delta="False">
    <text>[How do you explain this?](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-dY77j6uBHI)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579623090.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>That video was disappointing. Based on the title, I expected 13 minutes of Hillary Clinton lying. Instead I got that Hillary Clinton has changed her position on issues. The Founding Fathers opposed independence from Britain until they supported it, Abraham Lincoln opposed freeing the slaves till they supported it, FDR opposed fighting the Nazis until he supported it, LBJ opposed civil rights until they supported it. If a candidate believes same thing on Wednesday as the believed on Monday, regardless of what happened on Tuesday, history is quite clear that they are not good president material.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579641802.0" user="evilpetting-zoo" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, politicians change their point and I am okay with that sometimes, but she blatantly lies about ever supporting things that she clearly supported and the video shows that. how about the 'landing under sniper fire' clip? That isn't even a political stance. That is just a plain lie caught on video after she repeated it numerous times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579664616.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, stuff like the sniper fire clip is why I supported Obama over her in 08. But that isn't remotely important enough to me for me to contemplate the possibility of allowing Trump to win. You can disagree. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579705023.0" user="evilpetting-zoo" delta="False">
    <text>Would you ever consider a third party option or writing in Sanders over voting for either of them? Honestly curious, and I really appreciate you answering. Personally, I don't agree with you, but I'm glad that there is possibility for a real discussion about issues instead of just name calling and shit-talking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579734598.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>Would I ever consider voting third party? Sure, if I thought it was in the best interests of the country. That said, i'm not going do it in this election. Two reasons:

One, I'm generally take a moderate democratic line on the issues, which puts me closest to Hillary ideologically. For example, I support both keeping nuclear power and regulations to limit climate change. Stein, Sanders, Trump, and Johnson are all pretty far from that view. 

Second of all, I'm not white. No way I want to mess around with anything that risks Trump getting elected.

More generally, until there is 51% of the population that agrees on every single issue, politics is always going to involve compromise. I don't view my vote as a fashion statement so much a civic obligation. I'm happy supporting a candidate I don't 100% agree with so long as I believe they are better for the country that the candidate backed by the next largest coalition. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582213069.0" user="epicirclejerk" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment is negative for point out 100% verifiable facts. This sub is such a joke.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579647704.0" user="KnuteViking" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; single-payer healthcare, which involves banning the option for private health insurance.

Not necessarily true and depends on how strictly you're defining single-payer and what that really means. Take Switzerland as an example. In Switzerland, the government provides payment in the form of vouchers for health care. You bring that to a private medical system. One single public payer, fully private health care that operates on a mostly fixed cost, though you *can* essentially buy a higher grade of service with your own money. What she opposes is the Canadian single-payer system which is nowhere near impractical and is used all over the world very successfully.

Even if it were slightly true, it wouldn't even involve *banning* insurance, most insurance, except those providing premium service, would just go out of business because it would be impossible for for-profit insurance to compete. You *could* ban it, but that hasn't been proposed or implemented very many places and isn't the mainstream view of single-payer in most countries. For example, private insurance is still a thing in Canada (http://www.canadian-healthcare.org/page4.html) which is considered single-payer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579660496.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>My understanding was that single-payer was defined by having a singe-payer, as in one payer, the government. How are you defining it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579953820.0" user="KnuteViking" delta="False">
    <text>By your definition maybe only Cuba has single payer. Single payer generally refers to a basic level of care being paid for by the government. The scope and method range wildly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579991127.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>I was actually thinking of Canada, and the somewhat controversial [ban](http://www.nytimes.com/2006/02/26/international/americas/as-canadas-slowmotion-public-health-system-falters.html?_r=0) that they had on private parties paying for healthcare procedures that are also paid for by their public system. Not sure what the current status; it might vary from province to province. I think Taiwan may have a single-payer system as well, along with socialist countries like Cuba as you mentioned. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580076426.0" user="KnuteViking" delta="False">
    <text>Just trying to say that when people talk about having a "single-payer" option, say for Obamacare, they're not talking about banning private insurance, just providing a basic level of care through the government. Again, there are many flavors of single-payer out there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580367806.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>It's worth pointing out that if you define single-payer as having a government option, Hillary Clinton supports that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579651613.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>I realize that OP asked just not for refutations of attacks against her but for reasons that people actually support the Clintons. Simply put, the reasons that older democratic voters and minorities support the Clinton are things they have done for us. 

-Most importantly, put Ginsberg and Breyer on the Supreme Court. Without that, there is no gay marriage, no right to choose, no a bunch of civil rights law, no Obamacare. Incidentally, Ginsberg and Breyer both voted against the Citizens United Decision, and Hillary Clinton voted for the campaign finance law, McCain-Feingold, that Citizens United struck down. 

-On the economic front, the Clinton Administration saw the minimum wage raised, expanded financial aid for college, and introduced SCHIP to provide health insurance to poor children. Lots of older democrats strongly benefited. 

-Strong Support for science. Bill Clinton, even as he was balancing the budget overall, increased National Science Foundation funding by 30%, the National Institute of Health by 50%, and doubled Department of Energy Office of Science spending. Hillary Clinton has continuously supported science funding when she was in the Senate. The Clintons are pretty much alone of this: Trump claims Vaccines cause autism and China invented global warming. Sanders voted against science funding for things like NASA and the superconducting supercollider. 

-Hillary Clinton's diplomatic achievements: Clinton helped negotiate the sanctions on Iran that lead to the deal, helped negotiate a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas in the Gaza Strip, and helped resolve the diplomatic crisis with China caused when official Wang Lijun took shelter in a U.S. consulate amid infighting. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579671291.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of the Clinton foundation my issue is not where the money goes, but that people who donate get jobs from the Clintons with virtually no experience. You definitely made some great points when it came to health care. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579690250.0" user="SdstcChpmnk" delta="False">
    <text>This OP fundamentally misunderstands universal health care. Look up the insurance rates for the ACA. It ISN'T Universal. It's slightly better than we used to be, but it's not universal. Hillary has specifically stated this election that Universal Healthcare is never going to happen and we should be happy with what we have. 

Also, Single Payer Healthcare doesn't exclude private insurance companies. It's simply ensures that EVERYONE has a baseline coverage. If you want better coverage, you are more than welcome to go buy it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579697636.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>Read my post again. I specifically said that parts of Obamacare were struck down by the Republican supreme court and the Republican controlled states. Of course it's not going to be universal with parts of it struck down.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579709348.0" user="SdstcChpmnk" delta="False">
    <text>It has the OPTION to be struck down. It's not universal health care. Also, it is still an opt in, and privately run, system while only partially subsidized. The ACA is NOTHING like universal Healthcare. It's just a mandate to go buy private insurance or pay a fine. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579737881.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>The ACA originally called for Medicaid to be expanded to provide government paid for health insurance to everyone who couldn't afford private. That is what was struck down by the supreme court. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580542427.0" user="MCRemix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hillary has specifically stated this election that Universal Healthcare is never going to happen and we should be happy with what we have.

Can you source this?  I'd be absolutely shocked if your statement was accurate, as she's explicitly stated that part of her campaign is to seek universal (100%) health care coverage.  

She's not in favor of dumping the ACA to pursue single payer, but that's a tactical decision, not an abandonment of the goal of universal coverage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580595095.0" user="SdstcChpmnk" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.cbsnews.com/news/hillary-clinton-single-payer-health-care-will-never-ever-happen/

Yea, she only fights for things that are politically expedient for HER. This would require her to actually LEAD on something, rather than just adopt a popular position. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580773988.0" user="MCRemix" delta="False">
    <text>Are you familiar with the Hillarycare fight of the 90s?

She was fighting for universal healthcare before Bernie even made it to the Senate and way before he decided to make it a part of his platform.  She also got burned doing so, it was *not* politically expedient for her to do that...

Stop kidding yourself, this is the one issue you really can't say she was behind curve on, she's been leading on this since the early 90s.

Edit: And your link is her talking about single payer, which is different from universal coverage, you don't have to have single payer to cover everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580956789.0" user="TooMuchPants" delta="False">
    <text>She said "single-payer" will never happen.  Not universal healthcare.  The two are not synonymous.

Many countries in Europe have universal healthcare with systems different than single payer (two-tiered, insurance mandates, etc.).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579691234.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>All presidents give positions to donors. Obama has appointed numerous donors to ambassadorships and even to the cabinet, with Penny Pritzker becoming secretary of commerce. Controversy arises when the country is actually harmed in doing so, like when Bush appointed Mike Brown, completely unqualified, to head up disaster response with not good effects after Katrina. The advisory board position is an honor but not one with much damage potential since Obama and Hillary could just and did ignore amateur advice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579981051.0" user="LoveJustHate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; appointed Mike Brown, completely unqualified, to head up disaster response with not good effects after Katrina.

So it's fine as long as they completely mess up? This makes no sense and adds to the narrative that you can buy your way into political power. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579986562.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstand me. I said it was bad when they mess up as Bush did with his appointment of brown, and not bad when they don't mess up as with Obama and Clinton. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580016670.0" user="LoveJustHate" delta="False">
    <text>I understand, it is just a weird way to cover up "buying" political positions. Also using "everyone else did it" to justify one's actions isn't a great defense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582078266.0" user="awa64" delta="False">
    <text>When the context of the conversation is "I believe this makes them unfit for the job," it's a great defense. You'd be functionally arguing every President since Eisenhower was unfit for the job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580534637.0" user="dontrumpreee" delta="False">
    <text>Appointing people because they donated is fucking awful. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579702016.0" user="daftmonkey" delta="False">
    <text>You're describing a very specific situation and I'm not sure that we've gotten the whole story yet. BUT on the balance, I would say her husbands administration was by in large filled with highly qualified people who were distinguished. People like Donna Shalala, Bob Reisch, Madeline Albright... I could go on. It's just a really strange charge. Hillary is a policy wonk. She takes this stuff pretty seriously. Bush, on the other hand, did not. As evidenced by all manner of non-serious appointments from Brownie at FEMA to Harriet Meyers to the Supreme Court. My suspicion is that if one did a thorough analysis of political appointments and their objective qualifications you'd find that Bill Clinton's administration was populated with extremely distinguished people and NOT a high number of political sycophants.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579702020.0" user="daftmonkey" delta="False">
    <text>You're describing a very specific situation and I'm not sure that we've gotten the whole story yet. BUT on the balance, I would say her husbands administration was by in large filled with highly qualified people who were distinguished. People like Donna Shalala, Bob Reisch, Madeline Albright... I could go on. It's just a really strange charge. Hillary is a policy wonk. She takes this stuff pretty seriously. Bush, on the other hand, did not. As evidenced by all manner of non-serious appointments from Brownie at FEMA to Harriet Meyers to the Supreme Court. My suspicion is that if one did a thorough analysis of political appointments and their objective qualifications you'd find that Bill Clinton's administration was populated with extremely distinguished people and NOT a high number of political sycophants.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579714268.0" user="GKrollin" delta="False">
    <text>Obamacare is not even a little bit Universal Health Care.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579715335.0" user="metao" delta="False">
    <text>Single payer doesn't ban private. Single payer means there is a fully funded GP and emergency system, as well as treatment for conditions. Australia has single payer and private working together - private health offers certain treatments (non-hospital such as physiotherapy), private rooms and faster schedules as a premium service. For example, being injured in a car accident will cost you nothing, but private treatment might mean your choice of doctor. If you tore your ACL playing sport, they'll fix it for free - but you might have to wait a few months for surgery. But you can find your own doctor and get surgery next week, if you or your insurer can pay for it.

The quality of care is the same, so it's not really a two-tier system. Health insurance is also much cheaper as a result of the universal system, since that system pays for many kinds of treatment. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579739277.0" user="Mqzp" delta="False">
    <text>Also Hillary Clinton proposed Universal Healthcare in 1992.  It seems weird to suggest that she is opposed to something she worked to hard to do and came up only a few votes short of accomplishing.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579756454.0" user="moration" delta="False">
    <text>Obamacare is not universal healthcare. It's is health insurance reform, Medicare expansion and a health insurance requirement with a penalty for those that don't comply. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579833172.0" user="GeoffreyArnold" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Clinton's don't take money from their foundation,

They are also paid from their foundation.  And the money that they give to the foundation is mostly not theirs.  That's money that was given to them as part of various kickback schemes.  Hillary gets six figures from entities for giving a speech.  What is she saying that's so interesting?  

Plus, they don't need to take money directly from the foundation.  It's a slush fund in order to hand out payola (bribes) to dictators and foreign politicians and jobs to their domestic political allies.  Don't you think it's odd that Bill Clinton's alcoholic brother works for the Clinton Foundation and gets a six figure salary?  Don't you think it's odd that all of Hillary's top campaign people worked for the Clinton Foundation when she was still "deciding" whether or not to run for president again?  They were parking those employees and paying them salaries out of the "foundation" until she was ready to run.  And as soon as the campaign started, they all quit the Foundation and started working for the Campaign at once.  

Don't you think that's strange? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579840535.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to need sources for this stuff. I've seen no evidence that Hillary is paid from the foundation or that her top campaign operatives like Robby Mook and Jennifer Palmieri were foundation employees.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580060988.0" user="GeoffreyArnold" delta="False">
    <text>It's from a Wall Street Journal investigation.  

http://www.wsj.com/articles/the-clinton-charity-begins-at-home-1433459849

It's behind a paywall, but here is part of it.  

&amp;gt;The media’s focus is on Hillary Clinton’s time as secretary of state, and whether she took official actions to benefit her family’s global charity. But the mistake is starting from the premise that the Clinton Foundation is a “charity.” What’s clear by now is that this family enterprise was set up as a global shakedown operation, designed to finance and nurture the Clintons’ continued political ambitions. It’s a Hillary super PAC that throws in the occasional good deed.   

&amp;gt;That much is made obvious by looking at the foundation’s employment rolls. Most charities are staffed by folks who have spent a lifetime in nonprofits, writing grants or doing overseas field work. The Clinton Foundation is staffed by political operatives. It has been basically a parking lot for Clinton campaign workers—a comfy place to draw a big check as they geared up for Hillary’s presidential run.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580108539.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>Your earlier claim was that all Hillary's top people worked for the Foundation. This WSJ opinion piece(not an investigation) only says that there are staffers which have worked for both, which is a very different claim. It's also worth pointing out that a lot of the people that this opinion piece claimed were going to work for campaign any day now (Amitabh Desai, Maura Pally, Craig Minasian etc) are still at the foundation and haven't worked for the campaign.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580050041.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>Those are quite weighty accusations. What payments is the Clinton Foundation accused of making to dictators?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580072222.0" user="GeoffreyArnold" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/foreign-governments-gave-millions-to-foundation-while-clinton-was-at-state-dept/2015/02/25/31937c1e-bc3f-11e4-8668-4e7ba8439ca6_story.html

&amp;gt;The Clinton Foundation accepted millions of dollars from seven foreign governments during Hillary Rodham Clinton’s tenure as secretary of state, including one donation that violated its ethics agreement with the Obama administration, foundation officials disclosed Wednesday.  

&amp;gt;In one instance, foundation officials acknowledged they should have sought approval in 2010 from the State Department ethics office, as required by the agreement for new government donors, before accepting a $500,000 donation from the Algerian government.  

&amp;gt;Foreign governments and individuals are prohibited from giving money to U.S. political candidates, to prevent outside influence over national leaders. But the foundation has given donors a way to potentially gain favor with the Clintons outside the traditional political limits.  

&amp;gt;Besides Algeria, a number of the other countries that donated to the foundation during Clinton’s time at the State Department also lobbied the U.S. government during that time.

&amp;gt;Qatar, for instance, spent more than $5.3 million on registered lobbyists while Clinton was secretary of state, according to the Sunlight Foundation. The country’s lobbyists were reported monitoring anti-terrorism activities and efforts to combat violence in Sudan’s Darfur region. Qatar has also come under criticism from some U.S. allies in the region that have accused it of supporting Hamas and other militant groups. Qatar has denied the allegations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580081228.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>So dictators gave money *to* the foundation, which is the exact opposite of what you previously said:

&amp;gt;It's a slush fund in order to hand out payola (bribes) to dictators and foreign politicians</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580177796.0" user="GeoffreyArnold" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, that's my mistake....the Dictators were paying bribes to the Clintons....not the other way around.  Why would the Clintons be paying dictators?  It's the dictators who need favors and so they're the ones doing the bribing.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580216325.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>Except they're "paying" (donating to) a charity foundation. The Clinton's aren't benefiting from it. What favors are they even getting? The only thing I've seen is the Saudi's getting an arms deal, which they were already getting and had to get much more approval than the SoS, so I don't really see that if they're bribing her that they're getting a return.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580241768.0" user="GeoffreyArnold" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The Clinton's aren't benefiting from it.

You can't be that naive.  Why would the Government of Algeria be donating half a Million dollars to this "charity"?  Algeria doesn't have needy citizens in its own country?  How much did Algeria "donate" to other foreign charities during this time period?

&amp;gt;What favors are they even getting? 

This is how you get access to the Clintons.  The favors come after the dialogue.  If Muammar Gaddafi had given to the Clinton Foundation, he might be alive today.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580259170.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If Muammar Gaddafi had given to the Clinton Foundation, he might be alive today.

See, this is the weird accusations I hear. Where does this even come from? Do you have any examples of people as evil as Gaddafi who were in the US' sights until they donated to the Clinton Foundation? Or do you assert that these things are true because you *feel* they are true, while accusing me of being naive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580263267.0" user="GeoffreyArnold" delta="False">
    <text>The foundation has already admitted taking ~~bribes~~ donations from countries that they shouldn't have WHILE Clinton was Secretary of State.  This is no secret.  Why are these regimes giving their people's money to the Clinton's?  It makes no sense.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580272188.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>So no, no examples then.

Why would despotic leaders want to look like they give a shit about charity? Gee, I wonder.

And yeah, they fucked up on exact donations. Bernie Sanders has gotten half-a-dozen warnings from the FEC for taking foreign donations *to his campaign*, which is *actually* illegal, not "I want it to be illegal" illegal. Guess what, no one cares. Except for people like you who take managerial fuck-ups from one side as excusable and the other side as proof of treason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582218255.0" user="epicirclejerk" delta="False">
    <text>You literally responded to the post where he listed all of the favors they are getting. Can you stop being so dishonest?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580454126.0" user="SearingEnigma" delta="False">
    <text>Obamacare, aka: Romneycare 2.0, isn't universal healthcare. It's a way to tie obsolete establishments to an unregulated "tax" pot that Big Pharma can dip into however deeply they like. 

According to this study on healthcare, we're paying about *twice* as much as most countries with universal healthcare, and our quality of care is pretty much the worst of all of [them.](http://i.imgur.com/Ca5CN5y.jpg)

If we had *actual* universal care, we wouldn't have to refer to our insurance whenever we get treatment. Treatment would be automatic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580868858.0" user="lapone1" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the information on the foundation.  I didn't know that the Clintons donated to the foundation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
