<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579595068.0" user="downvotesanimals" delta="False">
    <text>If the above is your only criteria then literally 95% of all politicians are unfit for their jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579690880.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of politicians being corrupt, Hillary is one of the only politicians that I have noticed where corruption seems to be there. I am sure that every politician has corruption in them, but Hillary's rises to the surface. It is either that Hillary cannot hide her corruption, but will all of her experience she must be great at hiding these things; this is why I think that she has so much that some of it bubbles into the public view. 

Edit: spelling/grammar</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579743005.0" user="20somethinghipster" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen lots of evidence that the wealthy and powerful Clintons have wealthy and powerful friends. I've seen little evidence from Hillary's legislative or administrative history that shows quid pro quo for those wealthy and powerful friends. I mean, there are dozens of posts and lists every day in r/politics about who is friends with Hilary, but none that detail what she does in return to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579743813.0" user="AzazelsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>Where is it that you've found yourself learning about her corruption?  The fact is that you'll learn about the negative aspects of politicians primarily based on what sorts of media you frequent.

For example, the Reddit demographics have been strongly in favor of Bernie Sanders for the past year.  As a result, it has become an echo chamber of anti-Hillary sentiments.  If another politician was running in Hillary's place, you would likely see similar attacks on that politician.

Likewise, if you watch conservative media, you'll now see similar attacks coming from the right.  I'm not sure how long you've been following politics, but the attacks on Obama were just as extreme over the previous 2 election cycles.

My point is that during an election cycle you will always see harsh attacks on politicians based on what media circles you frequent.  Some of those attacks will be founded, because no politician is perfect.  Some of those will be unfounded, because the use of false or exaggerated propaganda is a very common political tactic.

The fact that you think Hillary's corruption is so much worse is probably the result of a few things:

* Hillary has been active in politics for a very long time, and as a result is under a higher amount of scrutiny than figures who haven't been in the public eye for as long.

* It's possible you haven't been following election cycles closely for very long, and are therefore unfamiliar with the level of rhetoric we see every election cycle.

* The political climate has become increasingly more polarized in recent years, and as a result the discourse has gotten significantly more harsh and extreme.  For example, Obama governed as a very moderate president, yet the right continued to make claims that he was a socialist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579828105.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>That is a great point that you make. The reason that I made this post was to get other opinions because I noticed that the news outlets I frequent are quite biased. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579863102.0" user="Hobbes_Novakoff" delta="False">
    <text>Out of curiosity, what exactly would those news outlets be?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579875228.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>Reddit and Google now mostly, some Twitter. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579910296.0" user="blastnabbit" delta="False">
    <text>None of those are news outlets. They're aggregators of news outlets that filter the content you receive based on your behavior (what content you interact with and/or which sources you follow/subscribe to).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579913569.0" user="chaboy" delta="False">
    <text>If those are your only news sources you've been living in an echo chamber. Don't be afraid to branch out and read news from sources you usually disagree with, sometimes the "other side" make good points too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581302949.0" user="Dingleberrydaimo" delta="False">
    <text>I do this quite often for most political opinions, but seeing buzzfeed feminist videos on my news feed just makes me pissed off rather than feeling like i've opened up my information bubble.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580459819.0" user="Delaywaves" delta="False">
    <text>Oh god, please expand your horizons a bit. Literally every one of those sources serves to narrow your perspectives and tailor the news you receive to fit your already-existing interests.

Try to check out the New York Times, NPR, the Washington Post, the Wall Street Journal... any news outlet that at least attempts to be objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580845035.0" user="1_21-gigawatts" delta="False">
    <text>I would hardly call any of these sources objective, they all have biases in not only their POV but also how they gloss over or wave away details that don't fit their desired editorial narrative. Honestly it's a joke that "objective" was used in the same sentence as WashPo and NYT they both have clear Liberal and Democratic biases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580948819.0" user="Hobbes_Novakoff" delta="False">
    <text>It's still less biased than an algorithm that is designed for the express purpose of serving up articles confirming your views.

Frankly, you could do a lot worse than one of the oldest and most respected newspapers. If you want to see a biased news organization, take a look at HuffPo or Breitbart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580955175.0" user="Delaywaves" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, I did throw in the WSJ as a source that's generally considered conservative. I agree that you shouldn't get your news from entirely one side of the political spectrum.

Second, I didn't just "call them objective." My exact words were:

&amp;gt;at least attempts to be objective

You can't reasonably compare reddit/google/twitter—resources which are literally designed to conform to your own personal preferences—to journalistic outlets with real standards, staffed by people who, generally speaking, are trying to report the news accurately and without major bias. Unless you're way off into conspiracy-ville, I think we can agree on all of those points.

Obviously true objectivity is impossible, and luckily, through things like Editorials, those outlets all make no secret of that fact. However, I think it's a joke to pretend that it's just as valid to get your news exclusively from the sources that OP cited as from the ones that I listed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580990855.0" user="niktemadur" delta="False">
    <text>Ever since the early nineties, the barrage of attacks on the Clintons by republicans and a then-nascent right wing media has been absolutely savage, continuous and also extremely hypocritical, such as Gingrich and Livingstone's infidelities while denouncing the same of Bill Clinton during the impeachment fiasco, they turned the American political arena into a worldwide laughingstock by parading a stained blue dress for all to see, all to destroy or humiliate a president, that's when I personally understood that republicans are rotten to the marrow.

In the early 2000s, I saw Hillary treated with profound disrespect on TV, right to her face, by republicans during a congressional hearing, contempt in their eyes and voice, just because she's a Clinton.

Hillary may be no better nor worse than other politicians, but we must ask ourselves if we have been contaminated by three decades of non-stop negative propaganda and attitude bordering on irrational hatred, there is a distinct possibility that many of us have absorbed parts of it on a subconscious level, even if it's just a general vibe it makes us feel, and we are "reverse-engineering" our way from there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579753144.0" user="Mqzp" delta="False">
    <text>Are you sure your opinion isn't shaped by a twenty five year long campaign backed by hundreds of millions of dollars to call her corrupt?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579768313.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>That is the reason that I made this post, to see the other side. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579849620.0" user="Overgoats" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be doing everything possible to *avoid* seeing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579904600.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>I was an adult during the Clinton presidency, and I remember it very well.  

The GOP invented all the scandals that plagued Bill Clinton out of whole cloth.  They had a special prosecutor who went from item to item to item as they didn't pan out or were proven false.  He finally struck pay dirt with Lewinsky, when Clinton foolishly lied in a deposition.  The thing about that one is that it really was manufactured by the GOP, they completely set him up in such a way that he was almost sure to lie.

And it hasn't ever stopped.  Hearing after hearing, lawsuits and artificial indignation.  Did you notice that it all stopped when they found some email irregularities?  Do you think it would have if they had gotten no traction?  Also, where are the charges?

 Of course Hillary lies, she's a politician.  She's good at what she does, and the GOP has gotten good at what they do, too.  The thing is that she's no worse than anyone else and a lot better than some.   All that stuff you list is just shit thrown at a wall, some if it left a trail.

If she were really so corrupt, where are the charges?  The opposition has been claiming they're right around the corner since 1998.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580061149.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580067637.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry historymaking101, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+5+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=historymaking101+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4ntwbh\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580354593.0" user="historymaking101" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry about that, I just meant to say that she has been fending off accusations since 1992.  Some of the bigger ones happened in 1994 for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581287244.0" user="sirius4778" delta="False">
    <text>Just curious, what do you mean he was set up to lie? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581780565.0" user="jcooli09" delta="False">
    <text>He was asked a series of increasingly intimate and explicit questions well beyond legal necessity durring a deposition, especially considering he was not accused of breaking any laws.  I don't remember what the actual mechanism they used to force the deposition, I'm pretty sure it was a civil matter.

He attempted to obfuscate, and was mostly successfull (he famously said 'it depends on tne definition of is...).  They were able to find an answer which was technically incorrect, and the house charged him with purjury.  Republicans, led by Gingrich (a serial adulterer who told one wife he was leaving for her successor while she lay on her cancer bed), were able to impeach, I'm pretty sure a few democrats voted that way for political reasons.

The senate convicted, and sentenced him to censure.  

The whole thing was a terrible joke for several reasons that I remember.

Kenn Star was originall hired to investigate Whitewater, but had to conclude that they were guilty of no impropriety.  He moved on through several "gates", none of which panned out but accomplished to goal of tying the Clinton name to "scandals"   This is a winning strategy for the GOP, which they've adapted over the past several years to work without an independant council (the Watergate era law authorizing Star was repealed very early in the second Bush administration or late in the Clinton administration).

It is telling that, as soon as they had something with traction, Kenn Star quit looking.  It was pretty clear his job was done, he found something to stick to Clinton.

The biggest piece of hypocrisy in the whole pile is, to me, the open and well documented history of infidelity in the white house.  I'm fairly certain Jimmy Carter didn't fool around decause he was the first virtuous man in the white house in a century.  Reagan, who hadn't been elevated to GOP sainthood yet, was likely too old to perform.  Everyone else, and many, many members of the committees that condemned him, had affairs either in the White House itself or at least while in office.  It cost Gingrich his speakership, and Kasich (committee chairman) his seat.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581845702.0" user="sirius4778" delta="False">
    <text>Really interesting stuff, thanks for taking the time! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580053645.0" user="nickpufferfish" delta="False">
    <text>A quick google search of "hillary clinton" shows me that Hillary receives 27% of her campaign funding from "Super PACs and other groups". In comparison, Sanders receives 0.01% and Trump 3%. While this doesn't necessarily indicate corruption, it also doesn't exactly make me trust Hillary and her agenda. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580074827.0" user="Mqzp" delta="False">
    <text>All those terrible groups like:
-labor unions
-environmental organizations
-lgbt groups
-abortion rights groups like Emily's list.

I'm not worried about the corrupting influence of Emily's list.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580612938.0" user="NotFuzz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Hillary cannot hide her corruption

I'd argue that if she is corrupt, she's done a phenomenal job of hiding it. To put it in perspective, there are *scores* of actual, convicted, corrupt politicians: Spiro Agnew was involved in bribery and subsequently resigned; Rod Blagojevich was arrested for selling Obama's vacant senate seat; James Traficant was arrested for bribery, tax evasion, and racketeering. The list goes on and on.

Corruption is something we keep a hawk's eye on in the United States. Personally, I think the fact that she's even standing at this point is a huge indicator of what a solid candidate she is. People have been shouting that Hillary is corrupt for decades, but nothing they've thrown has stuck longer than spaghetti would stick on a wall.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580402031.0" user="lincoln131" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds about right. If you can get elected, you aren't worth voting for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580805278.0" user="hamster_skeletons" delta="False">
    <text>And is the reason Trump has a legitimate shot at the presidency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582780337.0" user="downvotesanimals" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed.  Now, if you're one of those that thinks he's a BETTER choice than the rest, that's where we differ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582799374.0" user="hamster_skeletons" delta="False">
    <text>I personally don't adhere to the Nationalist call.  Under Trump logic not only would I not be in this country, but no one would be besides maybe Native Americans.  That being said, I think outsiders are great for our democracy, I don't believe in voting third party because it's a symbolic vote (i.e. throwing your vote away).  Voting for Trump is not throwing your vote away, it's the first chance in any of our lifetimes to put someone into the White House that truly undermines the establishment and ruling elite.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581324794.0" user="Snaaky" delta="False">
    <text>Come on, you are being generous. I'd put it at least at 99%</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
