<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28580319162.0" user="Kaelaface" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand why people see it as a problem that her views on the issues have changed over the years. I for one am very glad that she's willing to change her views when she learns more about them and keeps an open mind. 20 years ago I thought gay marriage was gross and wrong when I was 14 but now, as I've matured I see it as a right for gay people to get married. It wouldn't make sense for you or I to have the same values as 20 years ago, why should she not have grown and changed?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
