<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579746784.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  She or her husband routinely have taken money from companies

This is not illegal. It isn't even corruption. **FROM YOUR LINK:**

*"Clinton said that at the time of the donation, “We put out the word that if anyone wanted to send me money I would forward it on quickly to Haiti where it would do most good and would take zero overhead.” The sequence of the money and the lobbying, he asserted, “was just an accident. To me it was like a pass-through. I didn’t even think about it.”"*

That's Bill Clinton speaking, not Hilary and what the Clinton Foundation does is good, not bad and not corrupt.

&amp;gt;  One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.

Giving campaign donors government positions like ambassadorships etc. is standard practice, legal and not corrupt.

&amp;gt; She will not release her speech transcripts

Which is again, not corruption, not illegal and not even unethical. No one cares.

&amp;gt; Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. 

All politicians are. Even Bernie Sanders.

&amp;gt; She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. 

No, she actually doesn't say that. She says that she will regulate the financial industry. She may or may not but either way that isn't corrupt.

&amp;gt; She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. 

Yes, there is nothing wrong with that. Nor is it inconsistent to take money from a state that does bad things if that money goes to doing good things. That is in fact morally praiseworthy. The Clinton Foundation takes money from people, NGOs, corporations and governments and then uses that money to help people.

*"Because of our work, more than 31,000 American schools are providing kids with healthy food choices in an effort to eradicate childhood obesity; more than 105,000 farmers in Malawi, Rwanda, and Tanzania are benefiting from climate-smart agronomic training, higher yields, and increased market access; more than 33,500 tons of greenhouse gas emissions are being reduced annually across the United States; over 450,000 people have been impacted through market opportunities created by social enterprises in Latin America, the Caribbean, and Asia; through the independent Clinton Health Access Initiative, 9.9 million people in more than 70 countries have access to CHAI-negotiated prices for HIV/AIDS medications; an estimated 85 million people in the U.S. will be reached through strategic health partnerships developed across industry sectors at both the local and national level; and members of the Clinton Global Initiative community have made more than 3,500 Commitments to Action, which have improved the lives of over 430 million people in more than 180 countries."*

It is not immoral or corrupt to take money and do good works with it. Even if some of those donors are less than honorable it doesn't make one's actions dishonorable, corrupt or immoral.

&amp;gt; I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues

Flip flopping on issues isn't corrupt, immoral or even bad. Politicians *should* change their views when the electorate changes it's views.

&amp;gt; Based on all this, how can people support her?

Because your complaints are baseless, absurd and childish. Because Donald Trump is a fascist authoritarian who would destroy the freedoms I enjoy right now. Because while I object to her close ties to corporations everything else she is for is something that I support.

&amp;gt; The facts are right there

You didn't actually cite any facts. You presented your opinions as if they are facts. Which is a very different thing.

&amp;gt; I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. 

There is no email scandal. You also didn't talk about the other standard wing nut lies about her. Like the lies about Whitewater, the lie that she murdered Vince Foster, The lie that she is a lesbian etc. etc. etc.

You have failed to show that Hilary Clinton is unfit for the presidency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579812034.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>You say that nobody cares about the speech transcripts, but judging by what I see on the news, people *do* care. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579858472.0" user="tokyoro" delta="False">
    <text>Which news sources do you frequent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580002052.0" user="Karmaisforsuckers" delta="False">
    <text>The Blaze, Russian and Venezuelan state propaganda, world net daily, infowars, huffpo, lawnewz </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580083833.0" user="lostvan" delta="False">
    <text>http://rsbn.tv/wp-content/uploads/Hills-Are-Alive-600-nrd-1.jpg

 "News" that are donating to Hillary Clinton:

CNN owned by Time Warner - 7th biggest donor 
[[1]] (http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2015/jul/07/facebook-posts/meme-says-hillary-clintons-top-donors-are-banks-an/)
[[2]](http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brian-hanley/money-talks-why-cnn-wants_b_8313536.html)

Interesting...
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt; The following list includes news media organizations that have donated to the foundation, as well as other media networks, companies, foundations or individuals that have donated. It is organized by the size of the contribution:
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$1,000,000-$5,000,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Carlos Slim
&amp;gt; Chairman &amp;amp; CEO of Telmex, largest **New York Times** shareholder
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; James Murdoch
&amp;gt; Chief Operating Officer of 21st Century Fox (**Fox New**)
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Newsmax Media
&amp;gt; **Florida-based conservative media network**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Thomson Reuters
&amp;gt; **Owner of the Reuters news service**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$500,000-$1,000,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **Google**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; News Corporation Foundation
&amp;gt; Philanthropic arm of former Fox News parent company
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$250,000-$500,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Houghton Mifflin Harcourt
&amp;gt; Publisher
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Richard Mellon Scaife
&amp;gt; Owner of Pittsburgh Tribune-Review
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$100,000-$250,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Abigail Disney
&amp;gt; Documentary filmmaker
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Bloomberg Philanthropies
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Howard Stringer
&amp;gt; Former CBS, CBS News and Sony executive 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Intermountain West Communications Company 
&amp;gt; Local television affiliate owner (formerly Sunbelt Communications)
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$50,000-$100,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Bloomberg L.P.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Discovery Communications Inc.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; George Stephanopoulos
&amp;gt; ABC News chief anchor and chief political correspondent
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Mort Zuckerman
&amp;gt; Owner of New York Daily News and U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Time Warner Inc.
&amp;gt; Owner of CNN parent company Turner Broadcasting
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$25,000-$50,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; AOL
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; HBO
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Hollywood Foreign Press Association
&amp;gt; Presenters of the Golden Globe Awards
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Viacom
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$10,000-$25,000**
&amp;gt; Knight Foundation
&amp;gt; Non-profit foundation dedicated to supporting journalism
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Public Radio International
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Turner Broadcasting
&amp;gt; Parent company of CNN
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Twitter
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$5,000-$10,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Comcast
&amp;gt; Parent copmany of NBCUniversal
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; NBC Universal
&amp;gt; Parent company of NBC News, MSNBC and CNBC
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Public Broadcasting Service
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$1,000-$5,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Robert Allbritton
&amp;gt; Owner of POLITICO
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; **$250-$1,000**
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; AOL Huffington Post Media Group
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Hearst Corporation
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Judy Woodruff
&amp;gt; PBS Newshour co-anchor and managing editor
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; The Washington Post Company

[[3]](http://www.politico.com/blogs/media/2015/05/clinton-foundation-donors-include-dozens-of-media-organizations-individuals-207228)

There are plenty of news that are not mainstream.
So what news do you frequent?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579916038.0" user="gritner91" delta="False">
    <text>Going by you using reddit as a news source. Your view is very skewed about people caring. A group of people on a subreddit upvoting the same anti-Hillary topics is not representative of the American people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580848336.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>Look, most Bernie Sanders supporters care. That's 45% of the democratic party right now. Pretty much 95% to 100% of the Republican party cares, and I'm guessing that large numbers of Libertarians, Green Party members, and Independents care.

Who's left to make up this stunning majority of people who don't care? 

Or is "most" just a figurative term? Maybe we can get the legaleese-fluent Clintons to weigh in on what "care" means?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580878463.0" user="gritner91" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of math are you doing here? 

Who cares...well how many people are educated on it first of all? Just because someone is a Bernie supporter doesn't mean they know about it, and those who do doesn't mean they care. Same with republicans, how many Republicans are just voting R down the line? How many are taking time out of their daily life to research?

You automatically start off your base with people actively interested in politics. There are much more who are passively interested in it, who don't care to follow for a while. They vote, many of which voting along party lines. Go look at a very high primary year even in 2008. 32% about of eligible voter turnout in the primary. Compared to 57.1% of eligible voter turnout for the general. Right off the bat nearly half didn't even care to vote at the time, who would care come general election time. AND that's on a good year. 

So right away nearly most don't care. Then you add in Clinton supporters who don't care because they support her, and everyone else who votes in primaries any way but doesn't follow on the internet. Doesn't go on sites like reddit where you are getting an anti-hillary demographic upvoting anything that is negative towards her. If I didn't go to /r/politics it wouldn't be on my mind ever while voting about her transcripts. When you aren't slammed in the face on a weekly, and really its more so daily basis of the same anti-hillary stances /r/politics holds you forget about them. You stop caring because it isn't on your mind. Not every Bernie supporter comes here, not every republican comes here or other sites that do similar things. So yes most people don't care, because most people aren't getting their news from sources that constantly have an article on their website or in this case front page, that is the same anti hillary articles we see here. They may know it, but they aren't hyper aware about the issue and forget about it easily.

Also don't do this:

&amp;gt;Or is "most" just a figurative term? Maybe we can get the legaleese-fluent Clintons to weigh in on what "care" means?

It just comes off as you being so hard on one side, you look so obviously anti-clinton. To the point where you don't want to be open minded. Even if you're not OP this entire sub is about being open minded to opposing opinions. That last remark shows you aren't.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579989933.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>I think polls are a better measure of what people care about. By those measures people don't care about many of the issues outlined by the OP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580851398.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580870724.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>I said: *"I think polls are a better measure of what people care about."*

You said: *"Source?"*

[California Democratic primary](http://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/election-2016/primary-forecast/california-democratic/) --- *"According to our final polls-plus forecast, Hillary Clinton had an 89% chance of winning the California primary."*

Hillary has a 90% chance of winning the Calif. primary. If people actually cared about this shit she would not be holding such a commanding lead. What is there for me to be "wrong" about? It is my opinion that Hillary's popularity in the polls shows that people do not care about the issues OP raised.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581195157.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>That's a really flawed way to get a feel for public opinion. Polls on a policy would be awesome, but polls for a person skew thing a *ton*. You can't assume that people unanimously support a given platform once you bring name recognition, identity politics, and access to media into the picture. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580915015.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry bonkus, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=bonkus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4oau2u\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581192482.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>Which link now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581193805.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>The big blue text that composes ["message the moderators by clicking this link".](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=bonkus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+%5Bhis/her+post%5D\(https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4oau2u\)) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581203405.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>Not showing up on mobile for some reason. The link above it is though, which is weird. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580069710.0" user="historymaking101" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly nobody cared until the Bernie campaign brought it up.  People have known about those speeches for years.  Bringing this up was a desperation move.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580178415.0" user="saltywings" delta="False">
    <text>It is the same reason Romney wouldn't want that tape of him talking about the 47 percent who are reliant on the government, which was really dumb of him, and spoken out of emotion and not with careful thought to encompass an entire voting audience. Hilary probably says stuff out of her campaign trail that would alienate some people so she wouldn't want that released. I don't see that as a bad thing, I see it as human and honestly playing politics is all about saving face and saying the right things, which Hilary Clinton does pretty damn well and is why people are skeptical of her. Instead of listening to drawn out campaign rhetoric, I look to her record and see that she really is a progressive who fights for a lot of democratic policies and is moderate in her ability to negotiate with both sides of the isle on many issues, just so there can be some progress made. She isn't like Sanders campaign who was all or nothing essentially, when his voting record isn't like that at all, but to get votes he kept with what he really believed in and not the moderate politics that he played through his Congressional career. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580588044.0" user="0mni42" delta="False">
    <text>People cared about Obama's birth certificate too. 

Do you believe that the lack of evidence for an argument is itself evidence that the argument is true? That tends to be the reasoning behind a lot of these conspiracies. It's also an [Argument from Ignorance](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_from_ignorance).

"Of course Obama won't release his birth certificate; if he did it would prove he's not American! The "experts" that looked at it found it to be legitimate, but that just means that Obama paid them off!"

"Of course Hillary won't release her transcripts; if she did it would prove she's corrupt! The investigations that have been conducted against her haven't found her guilty, but that just means that they're in cahoots with Hillary!" 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579830455.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>Not saying you're wrong, but have you got an example of Bernie Sanders being a hypocrite or liar? That would be interesting to see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579987845.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>He voted in favor of the 1999 Kosovo war and had anti war protesters in his office arrested. I personally don't think that's a big deal, I'd still vote for him, but it goes to show you can make a case for any politician being a hypocrite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580064143.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2016/02/09/bernie-sanders-loves-this-1-trillion-war-machine.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580720600.0" user="Dakota66" delta="False">
    <text>Everything else is pretty solid but why do you say there is no email scandal? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580809490.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>What is the scandal? That she kept private emails on her home server? That she did so with the permission of the state Dept? That there was **no law** preventing her from doing so? That the law regulating email for State Dept. heads was passed **after** she left the office? What is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580831515.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580895560.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Dude don't be a douche. 

I asked a series of questions.

&amp;gt; Some experts, officials, and members of Congress have contended that her use of private messaging system software and a private server violated State Department protocols and procedures

Would these be Fox News "experts"? Would these members of Congress be gibbering loons like Louie Gohmert? 

"There was not an explicit, categorical prohibition against federal employees using personal emails when Clinton was in office." -- Daniel Metcalfe, former director of the Department of Justice’s Office of Information Policy.

&amp;gt; Also, one of the first and most important things they brief you in the military is the importance of handling classified information.

Hillary Clinton was the Secretary of State. High-level officials need the flexibility to sometimes use a personal email, such as responding to a national security emergency in the middle of the night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580941205.0" user="Dakota66" delta="False">
    <text>I read your series of questions as pretty condescending but I won't argue that since it's hard to tell tone from text.

However, your assumption that the people who offer evidence must be the bad guys from fox news leads me to believe that you were indeed being arrogant.  I despise fox news, but I simply used a link from a wikipedia page.  

And I whole-heartily agree that "high level officials need the flexibility to sometimes use a personal email" but they need to use the proper methods to do so.  

The issue isn't the emails.  It's the principle that Hillary Clinton is attempting to cover her tracks by deleting emails and hiding other information.  It's discouraging.  I'd like to add that I am by no means a Trump or Sanders supporter.  Hillary Clinton has indeed done some very amazing and great things for this country and her career.  

The fact is that no matter how this situation falls, either in or favor or not, she could have, **and should have** been more transparent through this entire ordeal.  Had any lowly enlisted member of the military done what she did, they would have been reprimanded immediately.  They may not a high level political figure.  But the information is just as sensitive whether it's in their hands or hers.  

I wish I could see your argument.  I really sincerely do.  But the fact that she **is** such a high level political figure means (to me at least) that she should know the difference between Top Secret and unclassified information, despite whether it has been properly classified or not. 

If she needed to respond hastily to a situation dealing with sensitive information, she should be on a 6 ring standby just like uniformed service members, and be required to show up to a place to deal with the information properly.

She also shouldn't have kept such a magnitude of emails.  "Nearly 2100" were retroactively marked as classified, so I'm sure she wasn't keeping all 2100+ (assuming some were unclassified) for day to day use.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580913982.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry Dakota66, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=Dakota66+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4oaeqj\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581235062.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>The scandal is pretty significant, and I find it amusing that you'd just "nothingburger" it away like that. 

The general consensus right now is that what she does [was not strictly legal, nor was it "allowed"](http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2016/may/31/hillary-clinton/fact-checking-hillary-clintons-claim-her-email-pra/)

&amp;gt; she did so with the permission of the state Dept?

You mean, with permission from herself? Because who else would be giving her permission as SoS? Her employees?

And aside from doing something that wasn't strictly "allowed" - the real scandal is in discovering the intent and ramifications of the home server.

It seems extremely likely, based on emails from her employees, that the intent was to (at minimum) keep her shielded from having to comply with the Federal Records Act / FOIA. 

Beyond that, there are questions about the content of the emails in her care, and how secure they were. 

I don't care if Hillary &amp;amp; co. say that the emails she received, sent, and held were "marked classified" - the fact is, she had state secrets in her care, and she did not use appropriate security measures to protect it.

If it's shown that the server was hacked by Putin or Beijing, then what she has essentially done is bcc foreign governments on every email she sent, because they've got them all.

We don't know if our operatives overseas were compromised because of her lax security measures... 

Actually, there's a lot we don't know - which is why it's a really good idea to investigate the issue and see if she should be held accountable in court.

I personally don't believe that any politician who did *exactly* what she's done should just get a free pass.

It's not partisan for me - or for a lot of folks. It's important. We need to know that the officials we elect, and the officials appointed by the president are going to play by the rules and do their job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582671638.0" user="tits-mchenry" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.wsj.com/articles/clinton-emails-in-probe-dealt-with-planned-drone-strikes-1465509863

If it's behind a paywall google the title and click the first result. I don't see anything wrong with their use of the private server for those classified documents. It certainly isn't ideal, but it was their best option at the time. It also says there's little to no chance of indictment and that the investigation was never really about her but a pissing contest between the FBI and CIA.

Also, your point about Russia and China, the whole point of making an email classified is whether or not the government cares about it being intercepted or exposed. I already assume Russia and China have a shitload of unclassified emails to and from the white house, because that's what intelligence agencies are for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583780972.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>I'm glad that you don't personally feel like there isn't anything to be worried about. 

I'm a little surprised that you're so willing to brush off a problem like this. I'm also wondering if the people who are so quick to cry nothingburger about this whole thing would be coming to the defense of another politician if it wasn't Hillary, rather someone more like Paul Ryan or Mitch McConnell who was being investigated.

I personally wish it wasn't happening, and that none of this existed to be uncovered or called into question. I don't *like* HRC, but I wouldn't be concerned too much about her presidency if it wasn't for the investigations into the email server and the Clinton Foundation.

I really don't like the idea that she could have set up a server to circumvent FOIA. I hope it's shown that isn't the case.

I also really don't like the idea that she flaunted security protocols for convenience.

And I'm deeply concerned about the connection between the Clinton Foundation, Sid Blumenthal, Huma, and HRC. There were a whole lot of hats being shared in that little love triangle, and the term "conflict of interest" doesn't seem to do it justice.

The reason I'm concerned is because I really don't know what the FBI knows. Maybe, as you insist, they have nothing. Maybe this is just a game of political grabass.

It should worry everyone though that the FBI *does* have something and *is* conspiring against her. If she gets sworn in, and then the DoJ is forced to indict (or risk massive leaks and an exodus from the FBI) then we're going to have another Clinton impeachment and all the stagnant, partisan bullshit that comes with the territory.

Again - it would be really, really nice if my concerns are unwarranted - but I really haven't seen anything to soothe my jangled nerves here.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28584176361.0" user="tits-mchenry" delta="False">
    <text>If any other politician was in this situation and the FBI had been investigating for a year and found jack shit, then I would also feel like it's a nothing issue.

I think it's also a bit disingenuous to call what was laid out in the article "convenience", as it was literally the only way for her staff to communicate with her on very time sensitive issues.

The Clinton Foundation is a charity. We've seen the returns for it. We've seen that the Clintons don't pocket that money. Why does it matter who is donating to their charity? Are they supposed to refuse donations to their charity from US allies?

As for your nerves, do you think Obama would officially endorse Hillary if he thought there was the slightest chance of her being indicted? He probably knows better than anyone all the details of the situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28584871746.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If any other politician was in this situation and the FBI had been investigating for a year and found jack shit, then I would also feel like it's a nothing issue.

The counter argument here is that the FBI doesn't keep an investigation *open* and well staffed if they don't have anything to build a case on. It may not be an airtight case yet, but it's doubtful that they've "found jack shit".

&amp;gt; It was literally the only way for her staff to communicate with her on very time sensitive issues.

Yeah, except for the secure .gov email that she had, and never used.

&amp;gt; Why does it matter who is donating to their charity?

It's not a legal thing for me, but it's definitely a red-flag. I have a hard time swallowing her assertions that she's for women's rights and education when she's accepting massive sums of money from countries that practically criminalize both vaginas and books. Granted, I do think that taking money from bad guys for a good reason is potentially a good argument, but it still enforces my view of her as a cynic/Machiavellian. It's not the worst thing in the world, but I'd like to see her show a lot more scrutiny.

&amp;gt;  He probably knows better than anyone all the details of the situation.

I'm sure he does - and even if he knows it's all going south in a few months, it's a terrible idea for him to not endorse her unless he's going to throw his full support behind someone else. And since Bernie was all but finished at the time, he used his endorsement the only way he could.

A sitting democratic parent who refuses to endorse the party frontrunner is effectively casting a vote of no-confidence, which would have a massive impact on the general election, including the downticket races.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28585048264.0" user="tits-mchenry" delta="False">
    <text>"It's not a legal thing for me, but it's definitely a red-flag. I have a hard time swallowing her assertions that she's for women's rights and education when she's accepting massive sums of money from countries that practically criminalize both vaginas and books. Granted, I do think that taking money from bad guys for a good reason is potentially a good argument, but it still enforces my view of her as a cynic/Machiavellian. It's not the worst thing in the world, but I'd like to see her show a lot more scrutiny."


Again, this is to her charity organization. She isn't personally accepting massive sums of money. How often do you hear of charity foundations refusing donations? Do you think she should have refused charitable donations from an important ally in the middle east as the secretary of state?



"Yeah, except for the secure .gov email that she had, and never used."

Again, if you read the article I linked, you'll see that her department officials in Pakistan literally didn't have access to the secure email servers. But they were still very time sensitive issues for creating more oversight for drone strikes. And they spoke in coded language. They simply did not have the ability to send secure emails in time for them to matter, but had an agreement with the Pakistani government that they would correspond with Hillary directly about all potential strikes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28585589878.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>On the charity - the thing is that she and Bill have absolutely solicited donations from sketchy places. In some cases it may have been the case that a government just decided one day to send the CF money - in other cases there were trips to talk with heads of state and diplomats preceding large sums being donated. Still not illegal, but not the kind of bedfellows I'd like to see.

And as for the case of Pakistan, sure. It's a tricky situation no doubt. But that ignores the fact that she *never* used her secure .gov email, and chose to sidestep government security and oversight for her whole tenure as SoS.

She had access to secure government servers while she was in DC. She chose to use her own. Why? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580723649.0" user="AnonymoustacheD" delta="False">
    <text>People absolutely do care that she won't release her transcripts. She lied about 225k being what they offered and has repeatedly said that money affects politicians while excluding herself. If she has nothing to hide, she can at least give a peak as to what was said. Her unusual lying on the side gives suspicion as to why she is withholding her transcripts. It's not like she's Tony Robinson and you need to buy the book. Unless it's insider information, which, you know, sounds super sketchy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580811479.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People absolutely do care that she won't release her transcripts.

No, they actually don't. *Some* people do but some people are not everyone.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581215352.0" user="AnonymoustacheD" delta="False">
    <text>That's really interesting but I'm having a hard time finding the part where I said everyone. 
Edit: more importantly, you said "no one cares." 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580845006.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's Bill Clinton speaking, not Hilary and what the Clinton Foundation does is good, not bad and not corrupt.

Which is why it's not currently undergoing an FBI investigation at all.

Just because it's a non-profit on paper (*kinda, technically*, if you look at it from a certain perspective and you can parse all the different entities that comprise it and follow the complicated cash-flow in the right way) we shouldn't just give it a pass. 

Being a "pass though" for funding shouldn't be any kind of excuse. If anything it shows a disturbing lack of oversight. 

Bare minimum, I would expect any non-profit to vet both funds donated and funds dispersed. As it stands, not only the Red Cross but multiple "charities" that were collecting funds for Haiti relief have been shown to either completely mismanage funds, or be downright greedy. 

Hundreds of millions of dollars have been donated by compassionate people and well intentioned corporations, and the bulk of that money never crossed over into Haiti for a second.

Being a pass through into a swamp of shady money fuckery shouldn't be a good thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580882619.0" user="no_en" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Which is why it's not currently undergoing an FBI investigation at all.

There isn't one. There is a political witch hunt, a Stalinesque KGB inquiry based in partisan politics. Nothing more. What crime has Hillary committed? Would it be the law passed after she left office? Her critics can't even answer that simple question.

&amp;gt; Just because it's a non-profit on paper ..... we shouldn't just give it a pass. 

So what.

&amp;gt; Being a "pass though" for funding shouldn't be any kind of excuse.

Excuse for what? What is wrong with a foundation who's purpose is to connect donors with NGOs or other organizations in order to quickly mobilize aid for victims of disasters?

Can you prove fraud has been committed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581197593.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>Never said fraud. But something that's technically legal isn't automatically above reproach. 

And as for the FBI investigations being part of this 'vaaast right wing conspiracy' I can only say ok.gif</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581736920.0" user="TotesMessenger" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a bot, *bleep*, *bloop*. Someone has linked to this thread from another place on reddit:

- [/r/goodlongposts] [\/u\/no\_en responds to: CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency. \[+33\]](https://np.reddit.com/r/goodlongposts/comments/4pyvc5/uno_en_responds_to_cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit/)

[](#footer)*^(If you follow any of the above links, please respect the rules of reddit and don't vote in the other threads.) ^\([Info](/r/TotesMessenger) ^/ ^[Contact](/message/compose?to=/r/TotesMessenger))*

[](#bot)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
