<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579834132.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>Your second point doesn't show "flip flopping". Politicians should be free to change their minds, as should every intelligent person. Changing your mind shows that you have put serious thought into the issue. "Flip flopping" is only an issue if they keep changing their mind whenever it suits them. Changing it once is sensible. A lot of people who initially supported the Iraq war were later against it.

Being able to admit you were wrong is the sign of intellectual maturity, hence this entire subreddit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579844740.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>!Delta 

I still don't think that Hillary is a good candidate, but I now think that her flip flopping is not an issue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579850131.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't think she's a good candidate still, then who would you suggest as an alternative?

Without saying Bernie, because he already lost. Yeah, he'd probably have been a better option, but it's pointless to say that now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579878751.0" user="killfire72" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know that Bernie would've been better, and this coming from someone who voted for him. Over and over he showed himself to be, at the very least, stubborn and difficult to work with, so Dems in Congress (assuming that they could've taken it back) would be hard pressed to really work with him. More than that, economic analysis of his campaign promises often showed them to be unsustainable or unrealistic; not a good sign. Plus, the reason he polled strongly against Trump is because no political ammo has been used against him until now, while Hillary has been getting attacked for almost 25 years now.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579907118.0" user="Uristmcdurr" delta="False">
    <text>Probably would've resulted in a few govt shutdowns. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579952085.0" user="heyheyhey27" delta="False">
    <text>Not to mention he has a fair number of anti-science views, whereas hillary generally respects the scientific consensus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580057620.0" user="Iprefervim" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any examples of this? I'm not a huge Bernie supporter, but my very scientifically conscious friends are and from what they've described of him he seems very scientifically orientated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580076085.0" user="heyheyhey27" delta="False">
    <text>Hes very pro-gmo labeling and anti-nuclear, and has a long history of pushing alternative medicine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580222293.0" user="Iprefervim" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580060059.0" user="ExtraSmooth" delta="False">
    <text>Which among his views are anti-science? This is an argument I have yet to hear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580076991.0" user="heyheyhey27" delta="False">
    <text>Just fyi, another commenter asked me the same thing and I posted my response there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580865150.0" user="lapone1" delta="False">
    <text>Well, as a Hillary supporter, I think Bernie did a lot, particularly on campaign financing.  I think it opens the door to serious reform because Democrats know they can win without corporate money and I'm not sure they knew that before.  Hillary was playing by the standard rules on fundraising; Bernie showed it is might be possible to CHANGE the rules.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580891737.0" user="killfire72" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely, but I don't think he was the guy to do it. His movement of getting tons of his supporters to fill local offices is commendable though </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579929696.0" user="kf7zde" delta="False">
    <text>For anyone know if John Cena is eligible for write-in?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579993415.0" user="glbtrotter2" delta="False">
    <text>Jill Stein
http://www.jill2016.com/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580028809.0" user="Royale_mit_kase" delta="False">
    <text>No. Berners you lost. Don't help Trump to win by voting GP</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580241493.0" user="glbtrotter2" delta="False">
    <text>Defecting Democrats, Trump and bitterness: Why Jill Stein just might turn November upside down.
https://www.salon.com/2016/06/24/defecting_democrats_trump_and_botched_primaries_why_jill_stein_just_might_turn_november_upside_down/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580014109.0" user="Mynotoar" delta="False">
    <text>This seems like a pointless question. From what I understand, your only possible alternatives are Hillary or Trump, right? So who could OP suggest would be a better candidate if you're excluding everyone who can't become a candidate (so everyone besides Hillary/Trump)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580020109.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>I was hoping for more obscure suggestions, i.e. people outside of the major candidates who could have become president if they were more well known</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580058368.0" user="ExtraSmooth" delta="False">
    <text>That's kind of a catch-22. If Bernie has already lost, then everybody that isn't Trump or Clinton has already lost, and the whole exercise is pointless. You're falling back on the "at least she's not Trump" argument, which has nothing to do with Clinton's own legitimacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580073857.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>That's not my point at all. I was wondering if OP had any suggestions for people they preferred, besides Bernie who has already run directly against Clinton and failed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579903377.0" user="LeakyLycanthrope" delta="False">
    <text>~~I think you have to use the symbol, not just the word "delta".~~

Edit: I stand corrected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579921290.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579957272.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry throwthisawayrightnw, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+5+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=throwthisawayrightnw+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4nqwei\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579959402.0" user="LFClaird" delta="False">
    <text>In coding, an exclamation mark generally means "not" (e.g . != means not equal to). I think OP was trying to say they still believe their original opinion and that they aren't giving a delta here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579981624.0" user="LeakyLycanthrope" delta="False">
    <text>Ah! I see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580035770.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>Not true. Using the exclamation mark and then delta is just an alternate way to tell the bot to give a delta, if you aren't able to type the delta symbol, like if you're on mobile for example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580097093.0" user="LFClaird" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, my apologises. I just assumed it was a method for telling them that their view didn't change their mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579997515.0" user="magicpurpledinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>sidebar:

&amp;gt; **How to award a delta:**

&amp;gt; ...

&amp;gt; **!delta** (for mobile users)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580036471.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>Using the exclamation mark and then delta is just an alternate way to tell the bot to give a delta, if you aren't able to type the delta symbol, like if you're on mobile for example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579939114.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno.  It seems like her mind always happens to change when it's politically expedient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579986785.0" user="HeTalksToComputers" delta="False">
    <text>Example?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579989808.0" user="ListenHear" delta="False">
    <text>When she flip flopped in gay marriage then denied that she ever thought differently to save face</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580004786.0" user="HeTalksToComputers" delta="False">
    <text>[This comment answers this way better than I can.](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4nluhs) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580006565.0" user="Lynx_Rufus" delta="False">
    <text>...as did basically every progressive politician in America. If someone is over forty years old, there was probably a time in their life when they were against gay marriage. 

It should be noted that even before she was openly for gay marriage, she was unusually supportive of the LGBT community. I'm on mobile, but look up Barney Frank's comments on her involvement with pride in 2000. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580100596.0" user="Jacksane" delta="False">
    <text>That just means most progressive politicians are dishonest or manipulative, not that Hillary isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580119480.0" user="Breakemoff" delta="False">
    <text>This is such a common defense, "Well everyone else did something similar!" Umm, yeah that makes them all pretty shitty doesn't it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580155345.0" user="Prussian_Spacemarine" delta="False">
    <text>But how does it make her *less* qualified than any other candidate? No ones doubting politics is a shit game, but Clinton is no worse or better than any other candidate that sneaks by without any backlash.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580232181.0" user="Breakemoff" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But how does it make her less qualified

I don't think it does, inherently. 

&amp;gt; Clinton is no worse or better 

Basically most people feel their vote comes down to the lesser of two evils, with that in mind, when selecting among the pool of candidates you should exclude the *least* principled. I mean, wouldn't you say your record is important? And the more principled you are makes you a more trustworthy and thus, qualified candidate? 

Don't get me wrong, I'm voting for her, but there are good arguments to be made that she is less qualified than others. The bar this cycle is set so low, though, that she stands as the only reasonable option. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580349505.0" user="Delaywaves" delta="False">
    <text>Not really, it makes them politicians. You can't change the nature of elective politics, it's inherent to the system itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580715043.0" user="Breakemoff" delta="False">
    <text>If that were a rule, principled politicians wouldn't exist, and they surely do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580961058.0" user="Delaywaves" delta="False">
    <text>Changing some positions and having principles aren't mutually exclusive. I'd argue that Hillary Clinton's guiding principles have [stayed quite consistent over the years](http://fivethirtyeight.com/datalab/hillary-clinton-was-liberal-hillary-clinton-is-liberal/), regardless of various details which may have shifted.

And on the other hand, even politicians like Bernie Sanders, who I'm guessing you'd include in the "principled" category, make many of the same shifts over time that mainstreamers like Hillary do. 

It's a question of what role different politicians choose to play in the political scene. Sanders chose to be, in essence, a fringe member, which gave him a great deal more freedom in the positions he could take but also compromised his influence pretty greatly. Hillary, and others like Obama, Bill Clinton, etc., chose to go for more major, leadership-oriented positions with the knowledge that this stature requires one to be, as I said, a politician in the truest sense of the word. I don't take pleasure in seeing dishonesty from HRC et al., and in fact, it does seem that she sometimes plays it a bit *too* safe in terms of her issue positions. But at the end of the day, I think there's ample evidence that she's a fundamentally trustworthy person, and that those who demonize her tend to lack understanding of context and history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581055833.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Guess that makes 90% of america shitty too, probably your parents and everyone they knew too. Depending on your age, mayhe you too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580130352.0" user="lynn" delta="False">
    <text>Changing one's mind is not dishonest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580253192.0" user="Jacksane" delta="False">
    <text>To deny that one changed their mind is dishonest, though. Above did not address that charge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580336973.0" user="themaincop" delta="False">
    <text>The political reality in American politics is that you can't just be directly honest about certain things because you are giving ammunition to your opponents.  Hillary changed her mind on gay marriage.  She knows she changed her mind on gay marriage.  We know she changed her mind on gay marriage.  But if she says directly in an interview "I changed my mind on gay marriage" then her opponents will hammer her with that soundbite over and over, and certain voters will change their minds because of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580162800.0" user="heretek" delta="False">
    <text>It was a different time. I remember back in the early 90s I was for civil unions rather than gay marriage, although I am a supporter now--is rather us drop the "gay" in that term sooner than later. My argument was that civil union would gain more traction nationwide by distinguishing it from marriage as traditionally between a man and a woman. Before being for civil unions (then gay marriage) in the 80s I was perplexed even by the idea of homosexuality. Holding Hillary, or any long term public servant, up as disingenuous for evolving with the debate will only serve to entrench more public servants and keep them from evolving. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580355582.0" user="PM_ME_YOUR_PM_PHOTOS" delta="False">
    <text>The sentence would also be accurate without the word "progressive"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580183362.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580242789.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry darsynia, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+5+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=darsynia+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4nwima\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580327710.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580381952.0" user="HaveAnotherThe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;...as did basically every progressive politician in America. If someone is over forty years old, there was probably a time in their life when they were against gay marriage. 

TIL Bernie Sanders doesn't exist, and hasn't been supporting gay rights since the the sixties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580466421.0" user="Lynx_Rufus" delta="False">
    <text>I am aware of Senator Sanders' exceptional history on this issue. The point I am making is that he, and to a lesser extent Clinton, have been much better than most politicians of their generation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583452206.0" user="rebel581" delta="False">
    <text>Completely ignoring his lack of support for gay marriage in Vermont in 2006...

Now I don't blame him. It was a very controversial time and he is a politician, but Sanders doesn't have a clean record on this issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580494518.0" user="exit6" delta="False">
    <text>The gay rights movement had to convince politicians to come around to their point of view. Clinton, and many other progressive politicians, are among those who had to be convinced. They should get credit for recognizing the truth in the gay rights argument and embracing it. People who listen to arguments and allow themselves to change, rather than rigidly stick to old positions, are in my mind better fit to hold power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580710225.0" user="Edg-R" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like she came around because she knew she'd need the LGBT community when she ran for president. 

I can't prove it, but based on the way she talks and responds to questions and sucks up to certain minorities... Idk</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580755390.0" user="exit6" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly I don't really think it matters why someone comes around to the right position as long as they do. I feel like she will fight for the LGBT community -- as will pretty much any Democrat at this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581008490.0" user="Edg-R" delta="False">
    <text>What if it becomes popular for politicians not to support LGBT? Do you think she'll stand up for the community?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581042436.0" user="exit6" delta="False">
    <text>It won't happen, ever. LGBT et al has made straight people (like me) realize and accept their civil rights. It's like asking "what if a politician changes her mind and decides that black people aren't equal anymore?" It will never happen. Those rights have been won, and it's permanent. This is the "progress" part of "progressive."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581600911.0" user="Edg-R" delta="False">
    <text>Wait didn't she publicly state that she was a moderate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581054116.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Wow sticking up for minorities is bad now? What, do you aant her to be a white supremacist instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581256480.0" user="Mrknowitall666" delta="False">
    <text>Many people have simply changed their minds on this issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581129050.0" user="srwaddict" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, i agree with you. Except there never was a moment where she said she was convinced. She said recently that she Always was for it and that she had never defending DOMA, which is as blatant a lie on that issue as you could get.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581615643.0" user="exit6" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly I would need to see source material for that before I attempted to defend that, but even that doesn't bother me. One thing about her, she's a true blue democrat. Establishment. Many people feel that's a shot against her but I don't. The LGBT movement has become a key part of the party now. Democrats will fight for gay rights, and the fact that she is so establishment only means she'll fight harder. How she got there, when she got there, that doesn't matter to me. Honestly that's just politics, and we all agree that she's not exactly smooth in that regard. I give her a break on that. Unlike Trump, the thing about Hillary is there's really no doubt where she'll stand on issues, she's pure party line. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581255793.0" user="Mrknowitall666" delta="False">
    <text>The gay rights movement needed to change everyone who wasn't gay, in America, to come around to their point of view. 

As someone else has said many forget how homophobic America was just 20 years ago</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580821056.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>For instance, Bernie Sanders has been against gay marriage since...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580622826.0" user="footnote4" delta="False">
    <text>It is categorically untrue that she denied ever feeling the other way. That's just nonsense. Someone here is just making shit up, but it isn't Hillary Clinton. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580818773.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>In the past 15 years I'm sure many old people changed their views.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580077766.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>Gay marriage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580177520.0" user="HeTalksToComputers" delta="False">
    <text>[I'm not sure many younger people realize that the current "status quo" in terms of how society in general treats LGBT people is very recent, and is really an amazing change from when I was growing up in the 80s and 90s, a time where in most parts of the US two guys or two girls would not walk down the street hand in hand or openly display affection for each other. People still were being prosecuted under state sodomy laws.
It was a big deal when Star Trek: DS9 had two female characters actually kiss each other on screen.
The third season of Real World on MTV in 1993 had a gay house member, Pedro Zamora, who had HIV and was in a relationship with another man. Do you have any idea how unusual it was at the time to show a same-sex relationship \(let alone two men, let alone HIV-positive\)? It was unheard of.
Don't Ask Don't Tell and the Defense of Marriage Act were actually wins for the LGBT community. The fact that they're looked at negatively now is a testament to how far LGBT rights have come in the last twenty years.
And I find it ironic that the 2004 video clip of Hillary Clinton saying that she believes marriage is between a man and a woman \(that has been used to say she was against gay marriage\) is actually from a speech in which she was speaking out against a constitutional amendment defining marriage as between a man and a woman. Had that amendment actually been passed, the recent SCOTUS ruling that in effect legalized same-sex marriage would not have been possible, since the justices rule based on what's in the Constitution. DOMA was a bone thrown to conservatives to keep them away from something that, once done, would be enormously difficult to undo.
People who claim Clinton \(or anyone else on the left\) was "against gay marriage" really don't understand the last twenty or thirty years insofar as LGBT rights are concerned. Focusing on the issue of "gay marriage" pretty much misses the point.](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4nluhs)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580244678.0" user="Dylabaloo" delta="False">
    <text>Most recently with the TPP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580529602.0" user="JCAPS766" delta="False">
    <text>The TPP seems like a very obvious example, and it really disappointed me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580959119.0" user="RexHavoc879" delta="False">
    <text>Are you disappointed she changed her position?

If you are, keep in mind she supported the TPP (1) when it was in very early stages of negotiation and (2) when she was an employee of the Obama administration and Obama, her boss, was pushing HARD in favor. In my opinion, it's rarely a good idea to undermine your own leader and organization in public. Instead, you present a united front in public and settle disputes in private. 

When Hillary was no longer SoS, she said she didn't support or oppose the TPP bc she didn't know what was in it because she had been out of office for some time. Once she knew what was in it, she opposed. That seems reasonable to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581362388.0" user="JCAPS766" delta="False">
    <text>But she's yet to offer much of an explanation as to why she's changed her mind on it.  

What she's said makes it look much more like a hollow populist acquiescence than a change based on updated information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582173085.0" user="RexHavoc879" delta="False">
    <text>She's said she doesn't think it protects American workers. She's also mentioned a few specific provisions here and there. For example she said she didn't like the country of origin rules that would make it impossible to label things made in America if they were assembled here from parts made abroad.  Was Bernie more specific? (I honestly don't know the answer; I'm not trying to make accusations.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580124127.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Would you rather a politician who bows to the inevitable or one who sticks with outmoded opinions for twenty years? In bowing to public pressure they're bowing to the will of the voters- that's how a republic works. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580300863.0" user="this12344" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but I'd rather have neither. I'd rather have someone who's had the right opinions from the start-on basic things like civil rights. Visionaries of their time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580316980.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>And when I was 11 I wanted to go to Hogwarts. Reality ensued. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580643515.0" user="this12344" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying there are no good choices for people that value consistent morality and long held beliefs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580917163.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. sorry. We live in a place called *reality.* Life is not an Aaron Sorkin show (and even Josiah Bartlet compromised when necessary)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581067168.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Huh I guess 90% of americans are immoral because everyone was riding the anti gay bandwagon a mere 15 years ago</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580392432.0" user="wigwam2323" delta="False">
    <text>No, but Hillary's democratic opponent never had outmoded opinions. It would be different if Sanders fit that description. He's an outlier. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580411410.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>He also avoided foreign policy questions like the plague, his economic proposals were unfeasiblle (to say nothing of the fact that they had no chance of passing), and the Clinton campaign never did any real opposition research on him because they didn't want to alienate his supporters. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580440675.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>She seems to change her mind on the surface but few believe she had changed her mind on anything substantive.  

To clarify I doubt she's going to stop supporting gay marriage because there is nothing to gain from it but I'm certain she will still do whatever her donors want on trade deals to bone the middle class.  I'm also pretty sure that if she stated any non interventionist positions she would change her mind instantly.

She's also a damn hypocrite with her email server.  If she was anyone else she would be in prison already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580443217.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Such as?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580468625.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I edited the comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580514313.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>She supports free trade. So do I. Protectionism is a discredited policy that should have died in the 1930s when the Smoot-Hawley Tarriff turned the 1929 Recession into the Great Depression. 

As for the email thing, if you wanted to jail her you'd have to jail the entire Bush Administration, because they did all their business, including things related to national security, on RNC servers. 

I implore you, don't let the perfect become the enemy of the good. She's not ideal, but unless you want to wake up on January 21, 2017 to a President Trump, she's what we've got. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580620341.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I have no issue jailing the whole bush administration.  You want to go hard on whistleblowers then you should get the same treatment.  I think what she did is worse then what Snowden did by quite a bit, but because she is a clinton/poltiician shes not getting shit on for it when she should be.

As for the protectionism shit, I will look it up more since I admit a large degree of ignorance on it.  I remember people going nuts about the TPP deal being secretive and fucked up.

I think clinton is also a war criminal.  There was something released recently in those guccifer papers about how hillary was one of the major people trying to manipulate us into going into syria.

She's a liar, a warmonger, and there is nothing you can trust about her except that she will do anything for her big donors.  You can look at that shit with Elizabeth Warren where Clinton met with her and shot down some bankrupty bill while her husband was president, then as soon as she became a senator she approved it because of big money.  She stands on no principles at all and is going to keep us going down the Obama route.

I'd rather 4 years of trump than 8 years of hillary.  She deserves nothing and the establishment of both parties need to understand that they can't get there way continuing to act against the interest of the people and being bought by corporations.  

To conclude, I know what type of soulless politician clinton is, and I don't know what type trump is.  The republicans are all terrible as well so they won't be able to win in 2020, so I'd rather another chance for bernie or some other sensible person in 4 years.

I currently live in Florida and am either going to vote for Trump, Johnson, or Stein.  I am 100% not voiding for that walking mouthpiece for corporate america.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580851943.0" user="igrekov" delta="False">
    <text>Trump will be a guaranteed war criminal because of his thin skin. He WILL start a war, or at least a deadly international scandal. I implore you to vote third party if you won't vote Clinton. Show the country that swing states hate both parties. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580875057.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I'm probably voting for Johnson.  Only like 20% chance I'd vote for that clown.  Trump might do all those crazy things, but some of it might just be leftovers from the republican primary crazyness that he had to spew off.  But I do think he is thin skinned but I wouldn't say it's an absolute certainty that he will go to war with people over insults.  I also don't think it's possible for him to do that given that he has to go through congress to declare war.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581573269.0" user="igrekov" delta="False">
    <text>I was thinking more like North Korea or something, where Trump provokes an attack with his rhetoric or insults</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581581981.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>Well even nk has not provoked an attack.  Isis was already going to go after us and I don't any legitimate state would go to war over some hurtful words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582486623.0" user="igrekov" delta="False">
    <text>Probably not, but I can see a situation in which words led to trade issues which led to proxy wars. Barring a huge catastrophe, i think the world is done with world wars. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582599636.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>Well aren't we already in a proxy war in Syria?  Russia is backing the Assad regime IIRC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582621615.0" user="igrekov" delta="False">
    <text>Sorta? I don't think the Russian end game was to hurt US interests any more than our entry was to hurt Russian interests. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582637983.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I suppose the context of Syria compared to Afghanistan/Vietnam is quite different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582782245.0" user="igrekov" delta="False">
    <text>I'd totally agree that the two countries have different strategic reasons that are a zero sum game for supporting opposing regimes. But yeah, it's not quite the proxy wars of yore</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580912774.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580913450.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry dpfw, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=dpfw+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/d4oc5fq\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580945801.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I have no issue jailing the whole bush administration.

Not even gonna touch that

&amp;gt;You want to go hard on whistleblowers then you should get the same treatment.

And if pigs flew we'd all carry umbrellas. I oppose the NSA spying thing to, but what the did you *think* was gonna happen? The feds were just gonna say "aww, you got us. We're spying on everyone, but you got us fair and square."

&amp;gt;I think what she did is worse then what Snowden did by quite a bit, but because she is a clinton/poltiician shes not getting shit on for it when she should be.

The email thing was a mistake, sure. A mistake that plenty of other politicians have made as well. The charges are entirely politically motivated and the "investigation" nothing more than a fruitless witch hunt

&amp;gt;I think clinton is also a war criminal. There was something released recently in those guccifer papers about how hillary was one of the major people trying to manipulate us into going into syria.

If you think every president and every member of the executive branch since FDR isn't a war criminal by some stretch, you're in for a world of disappointment.. All wars are crimes.
If we'd intervened in Syria sooner, at the very least we could have cut a deal where the Assad government shares power with a rebel group and Bashar skips town to Moscow or something. Let be be quite clear in saying that there are no good guys in the region, just bad and worse. I trust Hillary to do everything in her power to make sure its not the worse guys.

&amp;gt;She's a liar, a warmonger, and there is nothing you can trust about her except that she will do anything for her big donors.

She adjusts with the times, she plays the game the way the rules are laid out, and she believes in a strong defense- and offense when necessary. Her vote in 2003 was to authorize military force, not go to war immediately. The Senate was promised that the authorization was to be leverage to coerce Saddam into cooperating. Instead, the Bush Administration went all cowboy cop on Iraq. She, just one of 75 senators who voted in favor, cannot be solely blamed.

&amp;gt;You can look at that shit with Elizabeth Warren where Clinton met with her and shot down some bankrupty bill while her husband was president, then as soon as she became a senator she approved it because of big money.

She approved it because it was more lenient than the initial proposal. So lenient, in fact, that between House Republicans that opposed a milquetoast bill and House Democrats who considered it too punitive, it failed to pass the House.
You notice that in 2005 when the bill came up again but passage through the House was assured, she voted against the bill.
I know the Bernie Bros are about as willing to compromise as the Tea Party, but its how Congress works. 

&amp;gt;She stands on no principles at all

And this is based on the wild success of politicians who compete at the national level but never waver on principle. Oh, how difficult it must have been for Bernie to stick to his principles in the most liberal state in the country. You notice the one issue where he bucks the typical liberal orthodoxy is on guns, in a very pro-gun state? Coincidence, I'm sure.

&amp;gt;and is going to keep us going down the Obama route.

Low unemployment, low gas prices, the longest stretch of peacetime economic growth in history, social progress on a number of fronts, increased awareness of racial disparities, the seeds of prison and sentencing reform, growing support for marijuana legalization, the toughest financial regulations since the New Deal, 20 million more insured, etc? that "Obama route,'' do you mean?

&amp;gt;I'd rather 4 years of trump than 8 years of hillary. She deserves nothing and the establishment of both parties need to understand that they can't get there way continuing to act against the interest of the people and being bought by corporations.

You'd rather see the perfect become the enemy of the good. 

&amp;gt;The republicans are all terrible as well so they won't be able to win in 2020, so I'd rather another chance for bernie or some other sensible person in 4 years.

**DON'T. BE. SO. SURE. ABOUT. THAT.** You have no idea how utterly retarded the average voter is
.
&amp;gt;I currently live in Florida and am either going to vote for Trump, Johnson, or Stein. I am 100% not voiding for that walking mouthpiece for corporate america.

My advice is stay home. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580985512.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I shouldn't of even bothered continuing to read after you tried to call the email server a mistake.  You don't mistakenly pay someone to build a private server in your home.  That's a conscious decision.  There were plenty of regulations and rules that made it clear that she shouldn't be doing that.  When you are a multi millionaire lawyer ignorance isn't an excuse because I'm sure someone told her "that's not a good idea" along the way.

By doing that she jeopardized national security as evidenced by Wikileads, Russia, and Guccifer(s) having access to all/most of her emails.  You can say Russia is lying, but I doubt Wikileaks is.  I don't recall them lying about stuff like that.

You can hold someone accountable for there action relating to Iraq if that's what you want.  you say 74 other senators did it too, the issue is that those 74 aren't also running for president therefore they aren't a point of focus.  They would be subject to the same grievance. 

You can trash sanders or whoever for sticking to there positions on principle but I don't know how you can view that as bad.  Just because they aren't generally successful in major elections doesn't mean that trait isn't desirable.  I don't know how you can dismiss someone for being trustworthy.   The 'game' that you speak of is a disgusting joke.  The future of our country and our world shouldn't be viewed as some sort of adversarial game, just like our justice system shouldn't be.  Just because it is doesn't mean I need to accept that at face value.  

Bernie's position on guns could very well stem from his belief about guns and whatever he has read/learned on guns over the years.  I'm not convinced that guns should be fully restricted in our country and I suppose he isn't either.  

Say all the stuff about Obama you want, I've expressed the major issues I had with his administration, namely the complete lack of transparency, the 8 years of war, and his wonderful war on whistleblowers.

He also didn't stop the feds from trying to crack down on legal marijuana and medical was approved in California.  I specifically remember dispensaries being raided and it being a point of contention.

That's a cute quote you got there.  I don't believe in voting for the lessor of two evils.  Evil is evil.  It's like would you rather I stab you to death, or shoot you in the head?  Both are terrible, one is likely more prolonged and painful, but at the end of the day they are both bad.  It's not as though hilldog is 50% good 50% evil and trump is 99% evil.  They are both atrocious human beings.

But hey man, I will certainly take your advice about not voting come November.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581608812.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Oh you sweet summer child. You're what, 18? 19? Politics is dirty. Always has been, always will be. You're gonna spend the rest of your life voting for the shiniest turd because that's how the system works. 

&amp;gt;I shouldn't of even bothered continuing to read after you tried to call the email server a mistake. You don't mistakenly pay someone to build a private server in your home. That's a conscious decision. There were plenty of regulations and rules that made it clear that she shouldn't be doing that. When you are a multi millionaire lawyer ignorance isn't an excuse because I'm sure someone told her "that's not a good idea" along the way.
By doing that she jeopardized national security as evidenced by Wikileads, Russia, and Guccifer(s) having access to all/most of her emails. You can say Russia is lying, but I doubt Wikileaks is. I don't recall them lying about stuff like that.

It was a fuckup. It was a poor decision. That being said, we have *zero evidence* that anything classified or relevant to national security was stolen. In the wild world of politics, this is about the least important thing you could be focusing on

&amp;gt;You can hold someone accountable for there action relating to Iraq if that's what you want. you say 74 other senators did it too, the issue is that those 74 aren't also running for president therefore they aren't a point of focus. They would be subject to the same grievance.

Authorization for military force (which is what the vote was for. The vote was not "to invade or not to invade") was intended to be leverage to coerce iraq into cooperating. If there's anything you can fault her for, its not believing that George Bush could be as retarded enough to invade. 

&amp;gt;You can trash sanders or whoever for sticking to there positions on principle but I don't know how you can view that as bad. *Just because they aren't generally successful in major elections doesn't mean that trait isn't desirable.* I don't know how you can dismiss someone for being trustworthy.

You call it being trustworthy, I call it being rigid. Sticking to your guns doesn't do jack shit to help when it costs you the election. How do you intend to change things when your candidate never wins?

&amp;gt;The 'game' that you speak of is a disgusting joke. The future of our country and our world shouldn't be viewed as some sort of adversarial game, just like our justice system shouldn't be. Just because it is doesn't mean I need to accept that at face value.

Oh spare me the self-righteous indignation- I was speaking metaphorically. 

&amp;gt;Bernie's position on guns could very well stem from his belief about guns and whatever he has read/learned on guns over the years. I'm not convinced that guns should be fully restricted in our country and I suppose he isn't either.

Yes. A Brooklyn native who admitted in 1992 that he only won the Vermont House election with the help of the NRA just so *happens* to express pro-gun views in one of the most pro-gun state in the country. Then when he becomes a national candidate he comes out in favor of an assault weapons ban- something he voted *against* in 1994 and 2005. I'm *sure* it was a coincidence. 

&amp;gt;Say all the stuff about Obama you want, I've expressed the major issues I had with his administration, namely the complete lack of transparency, the 8 years of war, and his wonderful war on whistleblowers.
He also didn't stop the feds from trying to crack down on legal marijuana and medical was approved in California. I specifically remember dispensaries being raided and it being a point of contention.

No, he wasn't the progressive paragon that we all hoped. The Anointed One disappointed you. Why do you expect Bernie would be any different? 

&amp;gt;That's a cute quote you got there. I don't believe in voting for the lessor of two evils. Evil is evil. It's like would you rather I stab you to death, or shoot you in the head? Both are terrible, one is likely more prolonged and painful, but at the end of the day they are both bad. It's not as though hilldog is 50% good 50% evil and trump is 99% evil. They are both atrocious human beings.

You're in for about 60 years of disappointment, then. You're never, and I mean *never*, gonna see a perfect candidate win. Best accept that now. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581735466.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Oh you sweet summer child. You're what, 18? 19? Politics is dirty. Always has been, always will be. You're gonna spend the rest of your life voting for the shiniest turd because that's how the system works.

I'm 26 lol.  That still puts me at 10 when bush was elected.

I suppose this is a value judgement on whether or not you trust/believe Assange, but he says that he has material worthy of indictment and I'm inclined to believe him.  She also tried deleting them all indicating that she felt she had something to hide.  Even if there isn't something seriously fucked up in there, the entire premise of the server to to bypass the transparency granted through FOIA requests which is incredibly unethical at the very least.

I use the Iraq war as one point in a series of being pro military intervention.   That is my issue with the Iraq war, Military action in Syria, etc.  You can say whether Iraq was good or bad decision on her part and you can downplay the importance of that vote but she explicitly was in support of Syria.

You can view it as rigid or trustworthy, the point is you know where they stand, and the only time that is an issue is when it's an objectively bad position to be rigid/trustworthy on.  Our country is shit because we let unprincipled people get in and maintain power.  You want to concede that you have to be unprincipled then you can do that and vote for whoever you want, I won't.

You can say you were speaking metaphorically about the 'game' of politics but plenty of people view the legal and political profession as an adversarial 'game' because they want to win.  The goal should be to do public good, not to claim a personal victory at any cost.  Once again, you can disagree and say you need to work within the system, but a fucked system has no inclination to let you kill it.  So working within it by voting for candidates put forth by it is not going to change anything.

I don't care about Bernie Sanders as an individual.  This is about the merits of Clinton.  But to answer your question, Did he support the NRA because they backed him, or did the NRA back him because of his position on guns?  I don't follow the guys whole career but maybe the mass shootings changed his mind.  Maybe he did it just for political theater, but based off his image I doubt he changed his position just because it was politically expedient.  That has to do with his image which supports that, while Clinton's does not.  

You said all the great things Obama did, I told you what he failed to do.  I weigh the areas he failed higher than I weigh the areas he succeeded in.  That's a personal value judgement.  You an feel free to weigh and value things differently than I do.  We will just disagree on how we view the merits of Obama's 8 years.  I don't think Obama stood on principle and I think the difference on the issues I mentioned is whether you care more about being elected, or more about doing the right thing.  I could be wrong about Sanders, but his 30 years of politics show a consistent trend apart from as you mention, him on guns.

I don't need to see a perfect candidate win.  I need to see someone who is not at least 50% shit win.  I would of been content with sanders as being 80% decent.  There is plenty about Sanders positions that disappoints me but I view him as more good than bad.

You can say I will never see a perfect candidate and that's true.  But someone like Sanders would of been close enough and we almost saw that.  If the democrats treated him fairly we wouldn't even be having this conversation since many polls show that Sanders beats trump by like 15%, while Clinton is statistically tied with that dipshit.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581771915.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>You can't do the right thing is you're don't get elected. Gene McCarthy stood on principle. So did George McGovern. So did Dennis Kucinich, Ralph Nader. Tell me, how much did they change the system? In practical terms, how did their sticking to their guns change government policy? 

I can tell you're young because you seem think legal weed and whistleblower protection are more important than unemployment, economic security, healthcare, gay rights, transgender rights, awareness of racial disparities, the possibility of prison and sentencing reform some time in the near future, etc. Believe me- once you have actual responsibilities and a real job, healthcare, unemployment, the economy, etc, will all matter a lot more than whether you can smoke a joint legally or whether Julian Assange can verbally pleasure himself with the sound of his own voice in public. 

Nothing I can say will convince you that Bernie Sanders isn't the Messsiah. I get it. All of his flip flops were based in deep-seated principle, while all of Hillary's are because she's a corporate shill. 

That being said, I have to ask you: ***what if you're wrong?***

What if Trump *does* get elected. What if the House stays in GOP hands in 2018 because of gerrymandering, and what if the Senate stays in GOP hands because the Democrats overperformed in 2012? ***What if Trump gets reelected?*** You seem so sure that he'd be a one-term president, when you're talking about the electorate that gave George Bush two terms. Are you willing to risk that kind of damage? Are you, *really?*

If Donald Trump wins he'll appoint Antonin Scalia's successor. Clarence Thomas is talking about retiring, so is Anthony Kennedy, and Ruth Bader Ginsburg is basically a walking corpse at this point. Do you really feel safe giving Donald Trump **four** supreme court vacancies to fill? Knowing that he's promised to appoint the most conservative justices he can?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581917577.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>The only one of the things you mentioned that's actually important and attributable to Obama is healthcare, and Obamacare is terrible.

As I said, Sanders came close which shows you that there is hope.  You could argue that Nader changed things by existing since if it wasn't for him we wouldn't have had bush :P

You aren't talking about the same electorate that gave us bush.  That was 12 years ago.  Many old people have died since then and you have a more active youth vote.  He could get reelected.

The SCOTUS nominations are an issue and the prospect of 3-4 new   conservative justices would be pretty terrible.

I'm sure I can be wrong and I like to think I'm open to being wrong.  But they are both terrible candidates hence why they have the highest unfavorabilites among any two candidates in history.  

What do you want from this conversation anyway?  You want me to say I'm going to vote for Clinton in Florida?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581064804.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>You think Clinton is a war criminal? Are you blind? All past presidents are war criminals. The US is an imperialist state that has the most powerful criminal army. The amount of crimes the armed forces committed is countless. And you single Clinton out? Most past presidents have done far worse than what Clinton has done. You need to open your eyes and realize that Clinton is not unique in this regard and definitely not the worst, and then you need to accept the fact that your country has done some of the most despicable things on this planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581457852.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I think for all the terrible things you can say about Trump, you can't say that he is currently a war criminal.  You could argue that he will end up there and you might be right with 90% certainty, but Clinton is already there.

I know my country is shit.  I've never been one to say America is great.  This election is a testimony to how shitty my country is.  

I don't get why people are surprised that at the moment I am singling Clinton out.  Yes I am, you know why?  She's the one who wants to be president with a terrible record on foreign policy assuming you take a non interventionist standpoint.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580934614.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>I'd rather a politician with a consistent philosophy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580940018.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Good luck finding one who is also capable of winning a national election...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580950503.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>The reason we don't is that attitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580958083.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Or maybe it's that most people are mature enough to accept that they are sometimes wrong, and adjust their views accordingly. Best illustrated by a quote from the series finale of MTV's *Daria*:

&amp;gt;Stand firm for what you believe in, **unless or until reason and experience prove you otherwise**

Go ahead and wait for your paragon. Meanwhile, I'll live in the real world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581587638.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>We elect platforms, not people.  If the platform isn't consistent, what is the point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581672234.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>The fuck are you talking about? I vote for people. The platform tells me what they believe in. Reality decide if it gets implemented. 

How old are you? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583013480.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>Old enough to have voted for the last several presidents.  Not that it matters. Philosophy can be taught at any age but misses most people.  Case in point.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581236192.0" user="SuperWalter" delta="False">
    <text>There's a huge difference between changing your mind over the course of twenty years, as the country changes - and changing your mind based on what group of people you're talking to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581450379.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Can you give me an example of when Hillary has done this? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581537243.0" user="SuperWalter" delta="False">
    <text>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/09/10/politics/hillary-clinton-democrat-progressive/

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581564182.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>Something substantive, preferably? It appears that I miscommunicated. I expected you to show me her flip-flopping on something that *mattered.* Labels don't matter</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581392775.0" user="bayernownz1995" delta="False">
    <text>God forbid a politician change their platform support the constituents' opinions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581589333.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>Seems like a very post-hoc way to not feel completely sick about voting for Hillary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581598376.0" user="bayernownz1995" delta="False">
    <text>It's not. Complaining about "flip-flopping" whenever a candidate changes their position on an issue years later always bugs me. Literally any time somebody writes to their senator, calls for change, etc., they want their representative to "flip-flop" on an issue, and it's good that they do. But suddenly, when it's an election year, candidates get shit for doing this.

The one issue I think Hillary legitimate changed just for the sake of it was on the TPP. I would have much preferred her to have stuck with a pro free-trade stance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581605135.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>There's philosophy and then there is practice.

When one writes to their representative, they are arguing why the same philosophy should be practiced in X way.  Usually, they aren't writing to try to change a mind, but to advocate a position without knowledge of their representative's position.

But now Hillary comes along and has held pretty much every position on every issue when it was expedient.  She has voted in favor of war and been a hawkish sec state.  There is literally no way anyone could agree with every position she has had so a lot of post-hoc reasoning is happening.

I'd say it's fun to watch but the future of my country is at stake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581614387.0" user="bayernownz1995" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When one writes to their representative, they are arguing why the same philosophy should be practiced in X way. 

1. I don't see how this doesn't relate to Hillary. Aside from free trade, none of the bills she's changed her stance on were a shift in philosophy, just a realization that things like the crime bills and welfare reforms of the 90s had more negative effects on the people they were trying to help

2. I also don't think this is true. I think the *most effective* attempts to sway one's representative will follow this format, but you can be sure that every pro-gun-control dem in a red district is writing their representative in a way that doesn't fit that format at all

&amp;gt; She has voted in favor of war and been a hawkish sec state

Yeah, so she hasn't really flip-flopped on this then? She said she regrets the Iraq vote but she has never really tried to prevent herself as an anti-intervention candidate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581631132.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>A conveniently-timed shift in philosophy that couldn't possibly represent her actual views.

Just slimy politicking.  I couldn't vote for her, and be calm in my own conscience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581683480.0" user="bayernownz1995" delta="False">
    <text>It happens to be "perfectly timed" because nobody asks when it's not during an election cycle. Do you seriously think she wouldn't have said she regrets some of her votes from the early 2000s if you asked during 2010?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583012292.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen her repeatedly deny ever changing her positions. What do you say to that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583214053.0" user="bayernownz1995" delta="False">
    <text>Since there's a stigma against it it makes sense to deny it. Also pretty sure what you're referring to by "denying" is just her explaining why she's changed a position, but I don't know the incidents you're referring to so I can't say for sure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583673809.0" user="ForTheBacon" delta="False">
    <text>If you believe lying is okay if there's a stigma against telling the truth, Hillary's your candidate.

Edit: here's a piece of an interview where she insists her view happened to change at the most politically opportune time: https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=vgIe2GKudYY

Note: Marriage equality has been on the Libertarian platform since the early 1970s.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579940095.0" user="Gr1pp717" delta="False">
    <text>FYI, I feel like this is a better graphic for her ["changing her mind"](https://prod-static-ngop-pbl.s3.amazonaws.com/media/images/HVH-2_1447531589.png) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579958993.0" user="Enchanted_Bunny" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't flip flopping be changing your mind and then changing it back? I've changed a lot of opinions in the last 10 years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579978961.0" user="ErikLakus" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, yes, from the unbiased, non-partisan GOP.com</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580379849.0" user="HaveAnotherThe" delta="False">
    <text>Is information automatically invalid because the the source is biased? Saying "but they are biased" isn't a valid argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580426556.0" user="DionysusMusic" delta="False">
    <text>Given the short descriptions and lack of nuance in the description, the existence of bias would indicate that the source is not trustworthy. This does not mean the information is false--if a source is unreliable that doesnt mean that the truth is the OPPOSITE of what they say. However, it simply means that the supposed flip-flops need some better evidence one way or the other before we can conclude anything. I would also argue, that in the case of a lack of reliable evidence, clinton gets the benefit of the doubt--the onus is on the accuser, not the accused, to demonstrate a flip-flop with reliable evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580434771.0" user="HaveAnotherThe" delta="False">
    <text>Right. And here you go into *why* the source is not trustworthy, and in doing so you bring of some solid points. This is way different than simply stating that the the source is biased, which brings nothing to an argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580432142.0" user="LiteraryPandaman" delta="False">
    <text>Some of these are pretty absurd. The Cuban one is a good example, the geopolitical situation there completely changed between the year 2000 and 2014. 

The right to enrichment is another great example. They didn't deserve that right until they made a deal.

The debt level bill is something that the opposing party used to take as a formality kind of thing, it was never a serious issue until the Republicans try to shut down the government over it.

Honestly, there is a lot of things you could argue she has flip-flopped over in the past years. But most of the examples from this list are pretty obviously taken out of context and are not the best examples. I work on campaigns, and our job is to make you believe this kind of crap. These infographics are like the new propaganda posters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580438032.0" user="HaveAnotherThe" delta="False">
    <text>Right. I'll copy my reply to the other guy that just left a similar comment.

&amp;gt;Right. And here you go into why the source is not trustworthy, and in doing so you bring of some solid points. This is way different than simply stating that the the source is biased, which brings nothing to an argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580450061.0" user="LiteraryPandaman" delta="False">
    <text>I guess that I think it should. When a group exists purposefully to have its point of view, you should take it 100% with a grain of salt (especially political party communications).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580467459.0" user="HaveAnotherThe" delta="False">
    <text>Really? That's absurd. We are all biased. Every single person on earth is biased. Should Dr. Kings work for black rights have been discredited because he was biased? I mean, as a black man himself, he had a lot to gain by having more rights.

No, I don't think claiming the the source is biased is at all a valid argument whatsoever. If someone tells you "The sky appears blue because of the way light is refracted by Earth's atmosphere.", it remains true, regardless of any personal bias. And if you don't trust the source (and you're fully right not to), question or seek out *their* sources.

&amp;gt;When a group exists purposefully to have its point of view, you should take it 100% with a grain of salt

I kind of agree with you here, but would change it to "*When presented with* ***any*** *information*, you should take it 100% with a grain of salt. Then you should research it and form your own opinion."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579988560.0" user="im_not_afraid" delta="False">
    <text>In order for me to be convinced that her kind of flip-flopping is an issue, you'd need to provide examples of her going from A to B then back to A. Even if it's just one example, that would be a delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579990749.0" user="onca51" delta="False">
    <text>These issues should not be lumped together in an infographic like this one. They are a wide variety of issues, with ranges from a few months to 15 years in between stance changes. In addition, some changes are qualifications rather than flips in position ex. she still supports TPP but now believes that it needs some major improvements before she would consider passing it. I think this chart throws all nuance out the window to create as long of a list as possible and give the impression that she is a liar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580822905.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>I'd really like to see one of these for Bernie.

Why haven't I seen one of those?

Is it because Reddit has such a huge Bernie Bro contingent? Or is it because such an infographic would be like, *maybe* three items long?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580013909.0" user="Abner__Doon" delta="False">
    <text>Whoa, it's almost like there are nuances in these issues that can't be accurately portrayed in 4 words.

It's also weird how certain actions have difference consequences in and out of recession.

The craziest part is that someone could recognize positive consequences and negative consequences of the same action; that's just nuts.  Everything is either 100% good or 100% bad, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580444396.0" user="SearingEnigma" delta="False">
    <text>You would think someone as old as she is with a lifetime in politics would have the capacity to reason about these economic and moral situations a bit sooner before the time her presidential campaign starts(after past failed presidential campaigns, of course.) Seems more like she's finally done enough surveys and opinion testing that she's figured out what people want to hear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580823658.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>Or that people who opposed her the first time made a good arguement and convinced her to switch sides? Anyways this does not show us the whole picture. Sure, she changed sides on these specific issues. But I'm sure she's dealt with so many more issues that she hasn't changed her position on in her political career.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580839218.0" user="SearingEnigma" delta="False">
    <text>I don't necessarily trust most people to pick up on nuance, but I feel like I'm pretty good at it. When someone laughs about defending a rapist of a 12 year old girl and laughs after "we came, we saw, he died" referring to their direct actions to murder someone, ignoring all the deeper factors, that person has a very clear sociopathic appearance about things.

When that person decides to "change their opinion" about moral issues, I believe there's no other possibility than it being a very direct method of exploiting people's likelihood to believe what they hear. It's actually frightening how many excuses people will make for someone that's painted in the right light by media. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580892487.0" user="ohyeah_mamaman" delta="False">
    <text>If you were a little more privy to nuance you'd know she was [not laughing about the outcome of the child rapist case](http://www.snopes.com/hillary-clinton-freed-child-rapist-laughed-about-it/), but rather about how the case had destroyed her faith in polygraphs, being that the defendant had taken one and passed despite being guilty. And "we came, we saw, he died", really? That's the bar for sociopathy? Is everyone who ever joked about the death of a horrible dictator a sociopath too? Moreover, Gaddafi was killed by Libyan rebels. Believe it or not, she is not directly responsible for literally every bad world event that happened while she was SoS (the ouster being the thing in question).

At some point you have to ask yourself whether [the candidate who got the most negative coverage in the past year](http://www.vox.com/2016/4/15/11410160/hillary-clinton-media-bernie-sanders) really is being painted in a light that's duping so many people into voting for her, or whether you're just looking for things to confirm your view that she's a terrible person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580925367.0" user="SearingEnigma" delta="False">
    <text>She "reluctantly" took on the case wherein a rapist male decided it would look best to have a female defendant?

Comparatively, with someone like Sanders in mind, her morals are obscure and entirely open to corporate interests. She worked for Walmart as they gouged their way into more corporate profit. She helped to destabilize the Middle East in different ways because it was a "business opportunity." 

I don't think she has a foot to stand on right now. She's a completely sociopath in her actions. And "the most negative coverage." From where? Fox? The places made to demonize/advertise for oligarchy opponents they prefer over someone genuinely *for the people?*

I'm sorry, but I can't follow your logic. If someone doesn't want to defend child rapists, they wouldn't work to defend child rapists. If someone doesn't want to support corrupt corporations, they wouldn't work for them. 

I'll be voting Trump in Indiana. As will my parents in their disgust at the thought of Hillary winning over Sanders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581013763.0" user="ohyeah_mamaman" delta="False">
    <text>She was recommended to the case by the prosecutor and appointed by the judge. As a member of a legal clinic that helped low-income clients (in part to help alleviate the overburdened public defense system), she was available. She attempted to get out of the request but the judge held firm. Right to representation is a basic bedrock of our legal system, and refusing the judge's appointment would only result in the damaging of her legal career and the shifting of the case back to the public defenders. If every non public defender took such a position on every nasty case, we'd end up with even more crushing case loads for the public defense system.

As for Walmart: In the 80s, the company was under fire for not having a single woman on the board, so they caved to pressure and got Hillary, then First Lady of Arkansas, to do it. She wasn't their first choice and was actually a major outsider, but despite being a sort of symbolic presence she lobbied the board relentlessly about two pet issues: gender equality and environmentalism. She wanted them to hire and promote more women executives, which they mostly failed to do. But she had more success getting Wal-Mart to use cleaner energy and natural light in its stores.

She was mostly silent about Wal-Mart's notorious labor practices. That's regrettable, but the consensus from those on the board at the time was that if she'd been vocal about labor issues it would have further marginalized her position, and probably would have made it harder to advocate for women and the environment.

Mixed record? Sure, but it's also disingenuous to pretend that Wal-Mart and Hillary Clinton are mutually invested in each other. Even when she was on the board, it was hardly the source of her prestige or income she was paid about $15,000 a year for an extremely part-time commitment, much less than she made at her actual job. And I don't think the rest of the Wal-Mart board felt any particular loyalty towards her. In 2005 she refused a $5,000 campaign contribution from Wal-Mart, citing her disagreements with the company. She has received much more substantial donations from various trade unions. As for the Middle East, both the suggestion that she purposely worked to destabilize the region and ascribing "business opportunity" as the definitive motive for such actions are rampant speculation at best (and that's if you're being super charitable with the definition of "speculation").

The methodology of the study on coverage tone is discussed in the article I linked, but since you couldn't be bothered to read it, the analysis encompasses more than 170,000 posts from WaPo, Fox, HuffPo, Politico, and CNN, among others. You can call it free advertisement and believe whatever nonsense about media blackouts, but to suggest they have some sort of love affair with her just because she's more well known than Sanders is nonsense and contrary to the evidence. 

Vote for whomever you want, as is your right. However, you might want to stop pretending you care about nuance when you read causality, motives, and psychological evaluations into people and situations you are clearly have only a passing familiarity with. Especially since you intend to vote for the antithesis of nuance because the people's candidate couldn't get the most people to vote for him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580823685.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>Or that people who opposed her the first time made a good arguement and convinced her to switch sides? Anyways this does not show us the whole picture. Sure, she changed sides on these specific issues. But I'm sure she's dealt with so many more issues that she hasn't changed her position on in her political career.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580031958.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>An uncited graphic from "gop.com"? How do you figure?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580132836.0" user="warmshower" delta="False">
    <text>That's such a crap graphic clearly intended to basically support people's pre-existing notions. Nobody intelligent should be swayed by that shit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580824541.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like infographics like this are the equivalent of Wikipedia pages if you're writing an academic paper. 

It's a good jumping off point for further research, and more likely than not, you're not going to find many bombshells that make you question the original entry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580828166.0" user="warmshower" delta="False">
    <text>You may be right for some but I think a fair amount of the time you'll actually find that they misrepresent the truth or that they gloss over the nuance to try to make a point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580863323.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, and really it's silly for me or anyone to generalize about "infographics" as opposed to any other media. 

Some are Alex Jones level crazy, some are only NPR level crazy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580226917.0" user="grendel-khan" delta="False">
    <text>Some of those merit investigation--is she for or against charter schools, or does she have an opinion that's in some ways supportive and in some ways negative, since both were expressed in 2015?--but supporting "Clean Coal" in 2008 and wanting to regulate coal out of existence in 2015 is reasonable; opposing lifting the Cuba embargo in 2000 and supporting its removal in 2015 is reasonable.

And some of these aren't even contradictions! It's entirely possible for NAFTA to be good for the economy but bad for workers in the non-service sectors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580383067.0" user="schmuckmulligan" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of these are just two separate features of a nuanced view (e.g., gun control). I hate HRC and think she will make a dreadful president, but this is a lot of horseshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580416248.0" user="makemeking706" delta="False">
    <text>Please contextualize that image in terms of things she has not changed her opinion on. Otherwise, this is just selection bias (i.e., highlighting the things that support your argument and ignoring the things that do not.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580446657.0" user="Fredricothealien" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if that's a better graphic.  It's seems kind of misleading and subjective which is sort of reinforced by the fact that is was put together by the GOP.  And some of those issues aren't even flip flops. Like being in opposition to blanket bans of guns in America and being in favor of "stricter" gun regulation aren't necessarily opposites.  It's pretty reasonable to want articulate and thoughtful gun regulation and not lazy "guns are banned" laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581002792.0" user="daynightninja" delta="False">
    <text>Some of those points are fair--on free trade, I see Clinton giving in to the populist/protectionist wave that's going on in the West at the moment (although it's stupid that they separated each trade agreement when it's more or less the same concept.) But most of the rest are stupid:
She voted against raising the debt limit in 2006 because she wanted to decrease the budget because it was military spending, while in 2015 it was for more liberal causes, just like tons of GOP legislators voted for the increase in '06 but not in '15. 

The two Syria points are one in the same--we learned more about Assad, and learned he was shitty. You can't be up in arms that we learned more about a world leader's atrocities and turned our backs on him. 

She opposed lifting the embargo almost two decades ago when the Cold War was less than a decade over and Cuba was committing way more human rights abuses than today. Almost no politicians wanted to lift the embargo in 2000.

The statement about the Iran deal is an unfair representation--she didn't want enrichment without supervision, which we (at least in theory) have now.

I honestly don't know about the Keystone pipeline or ethanol (except that Keystone was viewed more favorably early on when there weren't specifics) but I'd buy that the ethanol is an actual flip flop.

In '03 Mexican immigration to the US was HUGE, now the net flow is from the US to Mexico, so it's logical to be more supportive of illegal immigrants. She has become more liberal on these types of issues, like immigration and gun control though, gradually since the 90s. It's unfair to call that a flip flop if someone just moves in a certain ideological direction through their career.

People already covered the gay marriage issue/DOMA pretty well--she was generally supportive of the LGBT community, but this is an issue where she genuinely recognized she was on the wrong side of it and changed her view. (I assume you consider flip flops to be for political gain/generally disingenuous, not a genuine realization after considering facts/implications of your views)

Criticizing charter schools != being unsupportive of them all together.

There are a ton of more viable options for energy, clean coal is somewhat unnecessary, although I think it's fair to say that Clinton is more supportive of Clean Coal than other types of coal, or at least not as opposed to it.

I do agree it's a prettier image than that one that seems like it was made in MS Paint.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580324542.0" user="wambaowambao" delta="False">
    <text>Then you haven't heard about the coal issue flip flop. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580438271.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that deserved the delta.  The reason she changes her mind is the issue.   She does whatever is politically expedient.  If I believed she changed her mind due to facts then I'd say is fine.   But she seems to change her mind based on what is popular or based on who paid her.

If you look at gay marriage it's ridiculous that she waited until 2012 to 'CHANGE' her mind.  I think she didn't care and just went with whatever the majority was favoring.

She can say she is against the Iraq war but those new leaked documents show she was the one who wanted us to get into Syria.  It seems lime she just changed her mind on Iraq because it's popular to be against it.  She is just as warlike as bush and Obama.

For the trade deals she publicly is against them now but supported them behind the scenes and probably still does.

The issue with her flip flopping is the cause of it.   Changing your mind is fine as long as it is consistent with facts and believable.   She is never consistent and certainly never believable. I don't know what trump will do, but I know Hilary will do what's in the best interest of donors and establishment which is not good for me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580533730.0" user="dontrumpreee" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580655912.0" user="gitarfool" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your points except the last one.  We know what trump will do: whatever serves his own immediate interest. I would rather have a piece of shit for prez than that trust fund egomaniac prick. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580784804.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I also look at it as 4 years of trump vs 8 years of clinton.  Why would he only do whats in his individual immediate interest?  He's already rich, maybe he just wants to do what he think is right/best at this point in his life.  Who knows.  He's said so many things that you don't know exactly what he wants to do.  That's the issue with the republican primary though, you say crazy shit to win that and now its awkward moving back.  The thing is if Cruz won you would know his crazy is authentic but with trump you can't be sure of if he's legitimately crazy or not.

I'm not advocating that he would be great, but 4 years vs 8 years is how I look at it.  The republicans can't possibly put up a good candidate in 4 years.  

I can also understand not agreeing with my position because it does depend on how bad you view trump.  I view him as a semi crazy unknown while hillary seems like a lying warmongering schill/criminal who isn't transparent in the slightest.  She made a server to skirt FOIA requests for fucks sake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580817909.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>Even if you don't think that Hilary will do a good job, do you think the Trump will be anything les than a disaster?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580839363.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure.  It's not that I don't think she will do good.  I think she won't make progress in areas I deem important.  Such as safety for whistle blowers, getting rid of NSA surveillance, stop the overseas warmongering.  She's likely to make negative progress in those areas and not that I think trump will, it's just that I think he's only going to get 4 years so it's less time of no progress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580865231.0" user="FavoriteCentaurMoe" delta="False">
    <text>But think about how much damage he can do in those 4 years? It also means that he gets to pick the Supreme Court Judge. If Hilary is elected then we have a left-leaning Supreme Court.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580869808.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>That supreme court argument is the only decent one I think.  It's the only thing that sways me slightly to possibly vote for clinton.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581235685.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>not the anti vaxxing

not the racism against US born judges

not the complete and utter lack of foreign policy knowledge

not the complete and utter lack of basic economic knowledge

not the saying he will call and the US debt for less than full price

not the loosening of libel laws

not the going to reestablish the "school" while president and profting off of it, said school he is currently under a class action suit for

not the kicking off one of the most respected newspapers on the planet from his campaign

not the racism against innocent teenagers

not the racism against potential tenants? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581252039.0" user="Murky42" delta="False">
    <text>Your not seeing it from his perspective.

Most of those fall under the "he might be pretending to be crazy" banner.

Debunk his argument from that angle and you might be heading somewhere productive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581256870.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>If someone is actually seeing it from that angle then they're beyond helping

I hate to go Godwin but that is literally what the NYT said about Hitler</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581448350.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>That's not really my reason for possibly voting for Trump.  I want a drastic shift in establishment politics and I don't believe that Clinton getting elected would have that effect on the democrats.  I'm 80% voting for third party at this point because I really do not like either of them.

To extrapolate a little more, I think the root of the majority of our countries problems is the monetary corruption of our politicians and unless we change that being normal then nothing is going to change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581941448.0" user="asianbison" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you want a drastic shift in established politics? Why not progressive change instead? 

By voting for Trump you may get a drastic change in a horrible direction, or he may only be acting crazy but is actually sane. But is this really something you should gamble? I get people distrusting Hillary, but somehow not being alarmed by Trumps incostistency is baffling. What if trump sets us back 4 years with regressive policies? At least Hillary will not undermine the Democrats progressive agenda, and she says she'll have reforms. 

By not voting for Hillary you are indirectly increasing that trump will win. A vote for a third party will change nothing and reform is what we all want right? 

Clinton says she wants to reform wall street, is the issue you don't believe her? 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582002526.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think she will do anything to money in politics or reforming wall street because she has taken a stupid amount of money from them.

I will concede that you are right about trump likely being terrible and regressive.  I've never denied that, but she hasn't done anything to earn my vote apart from not be trump, and I'm sorry but that's just not enough for me.

I'm also not confident that progressive change will happen fast enough.  This dying horse is going to hold on to its last breath.  Politicians like being able to get money from big donors and they aren't going to turn on that just because their constituency wants it.  Both sides end up taking big money and therefore you are forced to vote for 2 people who won't do anything about an important issue.

As an aside, I'm happy we were able to have a more or less civil discussion about this even if we don't agree on many levels.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582303620.0" user="waydownLo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think she will do anything to money in politics or reforming wall street because she has taken a stupid amount of money from them.

Obama took a pretty hefty amount of money from Wall St. 

While he definitely made a mistake in prioritizing system stability and credit confidence over minimizing moral hazard, he also did oversee the creation of the first Federal agency specifically tasked with protecting the American people from financial exploitation.

Based on how vehemently the financial industry lobbied to strangle Dodd-Frank in the crib, how they (successfully) made an attempt to prevent Elizabeth Warren from chairing the agency she designed, and now whisper their apprehension of Sen. Warren joining Clinton on the 2016 ticket, I think the chain of events that unfolded in Obama's two terms speak to how Clinton might proceed, with the exception that she has seen how Eric Holder was fricasseed for insufficiently prosecuting the moral fronts of Wall St. regulation.

It's abundantly clear now to Democrats with ambitions of higher office that the valence of base politics has changed significantly from the 1990s, or even the first decade of the 21st century. The issues that now motivate the most vibrant segments of America's party of the Left are now markedly closer to their grandparents' views, minus the ingrained neuralgia of the Cold War era. 

The triangulation policies that arose in the early 90s in the shadow of Reagan are impossible now, simply for the fact that the GOP has moved far enough to the right that pursuit of the marginal GOP voter for a Democrat is expensive enough in terms of ideological distance to warrant that voter be ignored altogether in favor of doing things to activate your base - irrelevant of how unappealing it makes you to the opposition. 

Put another way, progressives who are worried that HRC is a bloodless cipher of the prevailing political winds should rejoice, because the Obama years have provided a framework for an enduring demographic coalition that could assume the dominant role it enjoyed a century ago. Even if the House of Representatives remains in GOP hands, the Senate could quickly approve a large number (hundreds in totality) of HRC's nominees for positions in the executive branch, like regulatory heads (i.e. the BATFE, EPA, BLM, DoJ). Similarly, the Judiciary's large number of vacancies could be filled by a President Clinton with collaboration from a Democratic majority in the Senate.

The upshot is that you need to take as your first premise that nothing good in American politics can be gained without diffuse, diverse effort in unison toward a common goal. Second, that there are only two options on the table to choose from. Third, those choices will ultimately determine who sits in many more seats than the one in the Oval Office. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581446132.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>I don't actually like Trump at all.  The only reason I'd vote for Trump is because I think it would trigger a change in both parties against the status quo of establishment politics.

That's it.  That's the only reason I might vote for him, and as I said elsewhere it's unlikely that I would vote for him anyway, I'd prefer to vote for Johnson or Stein so that if they hit their 5% thresholds in a national poll they can get matching by federal funding.

And who knows, Sanders came out of nowhere and people hate Clinton and Trump to a very large extreme.  It's incredibly unlikely but maybe we will see one of the third parties surge in relation to this.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581439715.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>You are listing negative attributes of Trump, not positive attributes of Clinton.  This thread is about why Hillary is unfit to be president.  I never once said I thought trump was good, nor did I say that I think he's the lessor of the two evils.  I said he's more unknown and I left it at that.  I'm not a trump supporter and I never will be.  The only reason I  might vote for him is I believe that it would shake up establishment politics.  That is the single and only real reason I'd vote for him.  Clinton as president will do nothing to change this shitty dynamic we are currently in and if not change it now, then when?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581216629.0" user="Su15ivan" delta="False">
    <text>They said bush would only get 4 years...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581502897.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>You might be right, I was quite young during the bush/gore election and am not too familiar with the politics of that era.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580931652.0" user="raggedpanda" delta="False">
    <text>If you look at gay marriage almost every single politician was against it until at earliest the late 2000's. I'm a gay person. Gay rights are very, very important to me. But I see figures like Hillary Clinton who have given speeches in defense of gay rights across the world, who have walked in pride parades, who champion those rights today, as having understood that they were wrong and are willing to work toward the betterment of queer people.

The bankruptcy bill quoted above is wrong, too. She supported the bill only while heavily amended. When those amendments were later stripped by the Republican-controlled legislature, she joined her colleagues in filibustering the fuck out of it.

The Iraq war of course is a problem, but our 'hands off' approach in Syria has resulted in a massive destabilization of the region, an ongoing civil war with a huge amount of civil rights violations, and a refugee crisis that is in part a cause of the recent Brexit vote. Syria and Iraq were very different situations.

For trade deals, how on earth do you know what she 'probably still does' behind the scenes? That's not a real point.

Hillary has changed, yes, because she's adjusted her viewpoint between the first time she was in a position of political power 35 years and today Surprise surprise, the world is a very different place than it was 35 years ago. New facts and ideas have come to light since 1990, and she has adjusted her political views accordingly. There is nothing wrong with that. In fact, I'm highly suspect of anyone who can go that long without understanding that things are far more complicated and different than they thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580956461.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>Congrats on being gay.  Some things should be seen by any sensible person as objectively right or wrong.  Gay marriage is one of them.  She can give all the speeches she wants but she only came out directly in support of it in 2012.  

Elizabeth warren apparently didn't feel like the bill was significantly better when she gave that interview trashing hillary clinton for supporting it getting into the senate.

Syria and Iraq are both part of same problem of us getting involved in too much shit.  It sounds callous, but honestly it's not problem.  We need to stop getting involved in shit at some point and it's just a matter of deciding when that point is.  You could argue it is our fault that Syria got to how it was and I'd say you are correct, but you have to choose some point to stop getting involved in other countries issues and if not now, then when?  The when doesn't feel like it exists for people like her.  

She's bought by corporations.  Trade deals that she supports are not going to be in consumer interest.  You can disagree if you want but you can google her shenanigans on trade deals.

I'm not opposed to people changing views.  I'm opposed to them changing them seemingly just to get support and not seeming to authentically believe things that are right.  She has an issue where shes the most untrustworthy politican you can imagine.  The fact that the server exists at all is ridiculous.  It's sole purpose is to dodge FOIA requests.

She's a criminal, she's unethical and she's done a lot of terrible things in her career.  You can pretend she's great if you want, but most people won't agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581232960.0" user="iaglia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if not now, then when

when you dont have dictators who gas their own citizens on one side and terrorists on the other

&amp;gt; She's bought by corporations. Trade deals that she supports are not going to be in consumer interest. You can disagree if you want but you can google her shenanigans on trade deals.

like voting against CAFTA? like opposing the TPP?

&amp;gt; I'm not opposed to people changing views. I'm opposed to them changing them seemingly just to get support and not seeming to authentically believe things that are right.

its a democracy and she continually flips to the left


&amp;gt; She has an issue where shes the most untrustworthy politican you can imagine.


you have no imagination or political education then</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581501889.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>She flips to the left because its a position gaining more supporters.  That's how the majority of people would interpret what she does.  I think its good to authentically change positions on an issue when its in the American interest, but I don't believe she authentically changes her position.  It would also be fair to say that is a very difficult criteria for her to accomplish at this point in her career/life but that's solely because of her track record.

It's going to sound callous, but I don't think its our problem that dicatators are gassing their citizens and terrorists are on the other side.   There is always going to be a 'bad' guy for the US war machine to target.  You can guy back 30 years of presidents and I think you can find some conflict the US was involved in that we shouldn't have been.  Constantly saying we can stop getting involved later results in us never actually stopping.

She's taken 700k from Goldman Sach's and more money from many other people.  She won't release speeches from those events.  I don't believe someone hands you 700k just because they like you.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582578179.0" user="ManBMitt" delta="False">
    <text>Sanders only directly came out in support of gay marriage in 2009. Is he a flip flopper too?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582598124.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.alternet.org/civil-liberties/bernie-sanders-was-full-gay-equality-40-years-ago

Or he supported it 40 years ago.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582705840.0" user="ManBMitt" delta="False">
    <text>Nowhere in there does Sanders explicitly state support for same-sex marriage. It's always been much easier politically to support "equal rights for gays" than legalization of same-sex marriage...the one does not automatically imply the other. For example, during the Prop 8 debate in California, one of the arguments made by prop 8 proponents was that nothing about the law would violate equal rights for gays and lesbians because they have the same right as straight people do to marry someone of the opposite sex. Another argument was that allowing same-sex civil unions counted as equal rights for gays and lesbians because they allow for the same rights under the [state] laws, but it would just be called a different name.



http://time.com/4089946/bernie-sanders-gay-marriage/

"While Sanders generally opposed measures to ban gay marriage, he did not speak out in favor of it until 2009."

"[In 1999] Many prominent Democrats, including Sanders successor as mayor of Burlington and a gubernatorial nominee, spoke out in favor of gay marriage, but Sanders kept mum."

"[In 2006] when Sanders was asked by a reporter whether Vermont should legalize same-sex marriage, he said no. Not right now, not after what we went through, he said."

"It wasnt until 2009 that Sanders publicly voiced support for gay marriage, years after many of his contemporaries in Vermont."



http://m.huffpost.com/us/entry/us_569fcc4de4b0a7026bf9e06f

"Sanders did support civil unions as far back as 15 years ago, but it was for the same reason he opposed the federal Defense of Marriage Act in 1996: his strong belief in states rights. He wasnt advocating for legal marriage for same-sex couples. He actually avoided the subject.

As one Vermont columnist put it in 2000, getting a straight answer from Sanders on gay marriage was like pulling teeth... from a rhinoceros. In 2006, Sanders said he supported civil unions but not same-sex marriage, again deferring to states."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28584472677.0" user="RebirthOfLegend" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough.  I will concede you are correct to a degree. He in fact, did not openly support gay marriage specifically until 2009 and only supported general equality which I think is still noteworthy.  I was reading both of their on the issues pages and it seems that his tone is a fair bit stronger in support of gay rights.  His only comment seemingly against gay marriage was the "Not right now" in relation to the 2006 possible federal amendment against same sex marriage.  To me it seemed like he just meant that it needs some time because emotions are running high, which he confirms in this interview.  

http://www.washingtonblade.com/2015/10/27/sanders-defends-2006-opposition-to-same-sex-marriage/

But you are indeed right he hasn't seemed to say anything directly supporting gay marriage until 2009, which is still way before hilldog, and he also never said anything against gay marriage apart from that one quote, while hilldog directly said she didn't support gay marriage, just unions due to sacred something something nonsense.

The hilldog thing definitely seems like she was trying to fence sit a bit more on her position.  I don't necessarily believe she was ever against gay marriage, but that she voiced it is the problem.

As a caveat, most people who responded to me so far seem to think I'm some sort of die hard bernie support.  I'm not.  I'd support him but I don't think he's the second coming of jesus or anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580944702.0" user="msabre7" delta="False">
    <text>Three words that will never come out of Clinton's mouth, "I was wrong." This delta is undeserved. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581141661.0" user="Mr_Holmes" delta="False">
    <text>Except for all the times she said those exact words? Here's one example of quite a few. https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-politics/wp/2014/06/05/hillary-clinton-on-iraq-vote-i-still-got-it-wrong-plain-and-simple/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581052501.0" user="2k16throwaway" delta="False">
    <text>Dang didnMt know you could use exclamation mark</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581260082.0" user="rjcatani" delta="False">
    <text>Changing your mind after facts are presented is one thing. Changing your mind based on polls and special interests is another. Her change away from Universal Healthcare was not a noble one. 

I don't think that deserved a delta. Flip-Flopping is different than mind-changing. And there's also the dirtiness that comes with it. Like acting as if she has been saying that position all along when we know she hasn't. Like about the minimum wage. Or the fact that she says virtually nothing about stemming corruption. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581278650.0" user="RatioFitness" delta="False">
    <text>In order for some thing to be a flip flop you have to change your mind and then back again. If you only flip but don't flop then you haven't flip flopped.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579901789.0" user="BaxterBeans" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that she flip flops to appeal to the masses and continues to do what she has done before. How much of her flip flopping on corporate policy do you think she will flip flop on if she is elected or not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580020715.0" user="Namika" delta="False">
    <text>I never understood why "appealing to the masses" is a bad thing when it comes to political leaders. 

They are supposed to rule *for the people*. If the people want X, they should work to make X happen, but if the people change their mind and now want Y, every politician should stop working towards X and start working towards Y. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580080142.0" user="cutty2k" delta="False">
    <text>I think that the subtext of "appealing to the masses" when used as a negative is that the politician in question is just giving lip service to the issue. 

To use a Hillary example...is she a progressive, or a moderate? If she's in front of a more conservative big money crowd, then she says "I'm a moderate." When she's talking to a group of young activist voters, then she says "I'm a progressive." She'll say whatever needs to be said to "appeal to the masses."

Contrast this with Bernie Sanders, who never had to change his message to appeal to the masses; the masses happened to agree with his message, which by definition made it appealing to them. 

It all comes down to adjective vs verb. I like it when candidates are appealing(adjective) to me. I don't like it when candidates are appealing(verb) to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580106003.0" user="Jacksane" delta="False">
    <text>Appealing to the masses is fine, if you genuinely share their interests and intend to work to help them. 

Bernie Sanders for example, appeals to the masses, but the implication is that Hillary panders to the masses while never intending to work for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580686568.0" user="JamieHynemanAMA" delta="False">
    <text>The phrase for Bernie is "appeal to utilitarianism".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580218115.0" user="LogicalEmotion7" delta="False">
    <text>Actual behavior versus expected. If a politician is clearly molding their persona to public opinion, then you cannot trust that they will make solid, consistent decisions in private. This becomes especially frightening if said politician is also observed secretly fighting against transparency, like a certain Clinton via a certain home server</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581369780.0" user="postpizza_depression" delta="False">
    <text>Because "the masses" vote as though this is American Idol and don't know anything about issues other than what they heard on the news last night. The masses couldn't  find Syria on a map much less hold a real opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579922487.0" user="Master_apprentice" delta="False">
    <text>Did Hillary ever admit that she was wrong? The only defense of her changing opinions I've seen has been denial. Which does not speak well of her trustworthiness. 

I know it's not to your point, but how can you defend her blatantly defying government restrictions on classified data? How can we trust her with more information if we know she willfully and purposefully exposed that information to the Internet without known good government security in place, to suit her own inability to use technology? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579968528.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Changing your mind shows that you have put serious thought into the issue

changing your mind just proves you didn't put enough thought into your ORIGINAL position.  it shows that you are frequently wrong where others are right and your judgment is completely unreliable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579994252.0" user="teddy-roosevelt" delta="False">
    <text>Exposure to new facts should always allow for updates to your opinion. Hindsight is 20/20, but no one can see all the consequences ahead of time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579995757.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>and what "new facts" changes someone's position on gay marriage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580041591.0" user="ililiilliillliii" delta="False">
    <text>That fact that it's now politically expedient to support it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580177255.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>bingo.  the only reason she changed her position was that there's more people supporting gay marriage NOW and she will get more votes supporting the other side this time, not that she feels morally or ethically compelled in any way</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580064992.0" user="sfcnmone" delta="False">
    <text>Lots of people changed their position on gay marriage in the last 20 years. My husband used to believe that the purpose of marriage is to protect the children born from that marriage. Then he made friends with a lesbian couple with two turkey-baster babies. Now he thinks marriage is (duh!) good for everyone. People change as they are exposed to new ideas and different ways of being.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580113662.0" user="Jacksane" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, everyone needs room to grow, but you don't want someone controlling nuclear launch codes if they can't figure out something as simple as gay marriage. As you say yourself "Duh!" marriage is good for everyone, a leader should be convincing others of obvious things like that. They should be able to change with new information, but they shouldt have to on common-sense issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580174458.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>which means these people who were in positions of power oppressed and ruined people's lives 20 years ago

if someone murders people for fun and sport then 20 years later "learns" that they shouldn't have done so does that mean they weren't wrong and culpable for their actions 20 years ago?

of course not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580086094.0" user="cutty2k" delta="False">
    <text>While that is true, can we agree that it is helpful to contrast the amount of hindsight that a person must employ?

Although hindsight is important and it is admirable to change ones views when presented with new information, it's arguably more admirable to just make the right decision the first time around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580129250.0" user="teddy-roosevelt" delta="False">
    <text>So you prefer lucky people who make semi educated decisions? I could interpret the same data a completely different way and it would usually be about a 50/50 shot of being right </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580295617.0" user="cutty2k" delta="False">
    <text>So every good decision made the first time around is just luck? How incredibly *lucky* of Bernie to have an anti-war stance BEFORE voting for war. And Bernie was just so *lucky* that he championed gay rights decades before Hillary did. I mean, there was a 50/50 chance that he was born a horrible bigot, thankfully we all got lucky and he wasn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580025434.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>No it doesn't. Everyone is wrong sometimes. It's ridiculous to criticise someone for not being perfect and correct 100% of the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580128524.0" user="Jacksane" delta="False">
    <text>It is okay to be wrong, but if you're wrong about seemingly common-sense issues like gay marriage (any human rights issue should be common sense for a democratic candidate), it raises questions about their judgement.

Everyone makes mistakes, but some mistakes will and should disqualify you from certain positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580292295.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>Gay marriage may be common sense now, but it wasn't not too long ago. Hence it only being legalised recently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580177988.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>no one has to be perfect.  they just have to be RIGHT when it matters</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580291166.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody can be right all the time, which is what you seem to want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580314571.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>apparently you aren't even going to read what i JUST wrote</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580188057.0" user="darsynia" delta="False">
    <text>I strongly disagree with this. If this were the case, then any biography written more than 10 years from the death of the subject would have no new information or insight to add. As the years go by we learn more things that can and do change our perspectives of past events. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580202612.0" user="NotHomo" delta="False">
    <text>again, flip-flopping means you held the WRONG position.  it means you lacked the FORESIGHT and INTUITION to correctly predict which side you SHOULD have been on

being CONSISTENTLY on the wrong side and having to flip flop means you have poor judgment, not that you're a good learner</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580054636.0" user="ExtraSmooth" delta="False">
    <text>Changing your mind is one thing, but she often denies that she ever held the previous position. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580074710.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps, but my point is that OP's image alone doesn't show that. The image seems to suggest that just the fact that she ever changed her opinions is a bad thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580390079.0" user="wigwam2323" delta="False">
    <text>It is when it her changing of mind is so blatantly parroting. She has never changed her mind and said, "you know what, I was wrong to think that before". At least not that I can remember or have ever seen, and I've been following her and her husbands shenanigans, good and bad, for years. Anyways, I'd rather have a president who has held morally acceptable civic values before they were popular. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580404306.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>No politician ever admits to being wrong publicly, because the media never fails to accuse them of flip-flopping or being weak willed. I can't think of a single exam of a politician saying "I was wrong." If they do, it's usually phrased as "we were wrong." They'll find a way to shift the blame onto someone else - they'll say that not all of the facts were available, maybe. Or they'll just straight up deny they ever held a different opinion. Because that is what works for the media.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580946955.0" user="RexHavoc879" delta="False">
    <text>They like to say "mistakes were made," as if the mistakes just happened out of nowhere. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581337602.0" user="chalbersma" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty have. Obama did it with gay marriage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581363723.0" user="postpizza_depression" delta="False">
    <text>You're  jumping through a lot of hoops to defend this. First saying she doesn't flip flop, then that she does, but every politician does, then that it's the media's fault she doesn't admit when she's been wrong. This is exactly the type of issue pivoting that is so frustrating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581377992.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First saying she doesn't flip flop

No I didn't, I said that OP's argument doesn't prove that she does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580651164.0" user="gitarfool" delta="False">
    <text>I would just like to say that this is one of my major issues with her. It's like she has no respect for voters. I'd much rather hear that she's changed her position for X and Y than her polished bullshit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580788816.0" user="tuxwonder" delta="False">
    <text>Hillary being as politically savvy as she is would know that denying you ever agreed with a stance is a better move than admitting that she changed her mind. People don't like it when their politicians change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580812280.0" user="ExtraSmooth" delta="False">
    <text>Being politically savvy and being a competent leader are two distinct, often mutually exclusive, things. "People" may not like it when politicians change, but I have no problem with politicians changing and have *every* problem with politicians openly lying about key issues. So if Hillary would like to win over me and voters who share my view, what she has done is in fact the opposite of politically savvy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580846947.0" user="igrekov" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Being politically savvy and being a competent leader are two distinct, often mutually exclusive, things.

See *Reagan, R.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581031894.0" user="tuxwonder" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Being politically savvy and being a competent leader are two distinct, often mutually exclusive, things.

Well that is just definitely not true. Being politically savvy means that you know what it takes to get where you want in politics, what strings to pull when. You won't be any kind of leader, competent or not, without knowing how to play your cards right to get to that position.

&amp;gt;"People" may not like it when politicians change, but I have no problem with politicians changing and have *every* problem with politicians openly lying about key issues

That would be a great mindset if we lived in a perfect world where EVERYONE cared as much about this/politics in general. But it's not a perfect world, and the general population responds better to their politicians being stone slabs with their political positions carved into them than actual people.
I'm not trying to make it sound honorable to lie about positions she took before and now have changed, just that instead of labeling her a liar right off the bat, realize that she probably knows she changed her position and, even if she wanted to, shouldn't admit to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580905607.0" user="heypipiopi" delta="False">
    <text>And here opinion changes depending on who's listening.

ie fracking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581029089.0" user="zistu" delta="False">
    <text>Such as?
Always give examples with your accusations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581127861.0" user="srwaddict" delta="False">
    <text>See - her stance on gay marriage and how she now says she always supported it. That shit is so blatant and enraging. I genuinely do not know why more people aren't mad about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581813525.0" user="Kelsig" delta="False">
    <text>She never has said she always supported it. Do not lie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581814076.0" user="Kelsig" delta="False">
    <text>Provide an example</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580102155.0" user="lloopy" delta="False">
    <text>Changing your mind because of additional evidence is a good thing.  Changing your mind simply because people around you have changed their mind is a very very very bad thing in a leader.  It means you're a follower, not a leader.

There was no additional information with regards to homosexuality and gay marriage.  That was clearly a politically expedient move.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580346037.0" user="RichEO" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds to me like representative democracy might not be your thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580390876.0" user="MCRemix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There was no additional information with regards to homosexuality and gay marriage.

Actually, this is inaccurate. The facts around lgbt issues and gay marriage were *not* clear early on. 

Although in hindsight everything is 20/20 and we know better, back in the 80s and 90s there was a great deal of misinformation and plenty of misunderstandings about the nature of being gay. It was unclear whether it was genetic and therefore normal or a mental illness, whether it had links to pedophilia, whether children of gay couples would turn out normal, etc. 

These all seem like stupid thoughts now, but reasonable, rational people were uncertain on these issues back then. 

So it's inaccurate to suggest that nothing changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580133234.0" user="adidasbdd" delta="False">
    <text>The textbook definition of corruption is dishonesty or fraud for the sake of personal gain. I think her "evolving" on issues is more likely following public opinion polls rather than having ideological epiphanies when it an election rolls around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580134211.0" user="ChuckNorrisWithEbola" delta="False">
    <text>Hillary changes her mind whenever it suits her and denies she ever thought otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580226462.0" user="VladthePimpaler" delta="False">
    <text>That completely depends on the reasons why they voted against, and why they voted for something later. You need to compare these reasons to determine whether or not it was a flip flop. OP caved too quickly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580417288.0" user="boho_lioness" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is she never admits she's wrong.. and it's been shown that she changes her positions on issues based on what the general consensus is with the voters at the time, that's flip flopping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580428455.0" user="Dubstep_squid" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your point about flip flopping and that's alright but the problem is that Hillary changes her view to whatever a majority of the population supports and then pretends and even gets angry when people mention that she changed her mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580600159.0" user="asharwood" delta="False">
    <text>That's not even close to being true. She switches stances based on her audience. Does she change her mind often on extremely important issues? That means she doesn't nor isn't thinking deep enough about important issues. That's flip flopping. She's playing people for votes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581183586.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>That may or may not be true, all I'm saying is that OP's argument alone and they image they use aren't evidence of "flip flopping".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580676046.0" user="Argazm" delta="False">
    <text>Clinton's position always seems to coincide with the most popular opinion according to polls.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581019867.0" user="bowie747" delta="False">
    <text>Refuting one point does not refute an entire argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581182047.0" user="WiseOctopus" delta="False">
    <text>Never said it did.

&amp;gt;Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OPs stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
