<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579872750.0" user="scurius" delta="False">
    <text>Previous presidents have been corrupt (e.g. Grant) and I fail to see how being a liar prevents a person from being competent at the presidency.

Don't get me wrong, I have my own misgivings about her. But I think your criticisms of Secretary Clinton remain valid (perhaps moreso) of Mr. Trump.

Personally, I plan on voting in favor of Clinton primarily to vote *against* Trump. I dislike Clinton, but she has actual experience in politics (12 years spent in the white house, even with primarily tangential exposure to the job of the president (which it doesn't seem like it was) counts as experience in my book) and hasn't been trying hard to emulate Hitler. Would I prefer someone else? Absolutely. But if it's a question of competence and capability (which unfit suggests to me), I think I've made a strong enough case that she passes that measure. If our metric is palatability, then I think it's fair to say she scores pretty low there.

I think a better question than "Is Clinton fit for the presidency" is "out of the two candidates the American electorate has left us to decide between, which is less fit?" To which I believe the answer is Trump. If you feel otherwise, I'd be interested to hear your reasoning. If I honestly thought it was possible to replace one of the nominees with a significantly preferable one (Ted Cruz, from where I'm standing is not significantly preferable) or for a third party candidate to win, then I would say the "Which is preferable" metric becomes less important. But with the endorsement of the sitting president and a sizable portion of voters already voting for her, an option C appears out of the question. That's why I think "of Trump and Clinton, who is less fit?" is the better question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580061209.0" user="iamaravis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 12 years spent in the white house

How does she have 12 years in the White House? She was First Lady for 8 (not President, just First Lady - how does that even count as experience in the White House?). And then Senator (not in the W.H.). And then Sec of State (presumably not living in the White House). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580112529.0" user="scurius" delta="False">
    <text>Not living in the white house as State, but still in the executive branch working within the white house.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580114177.0" user="scurius" delta="False">
    <text>and as experience as FLOTUS, it's not exactly like the POTUS doesn't share things with FLOTUS.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580911611.0" user="rebel2cougar" delta="False">
    <text>Clinton was also one of the more active first ladies in recent history. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
