<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579649384.0" user="georgeisking" delta="False">
    <text>Politicians in general are corrupt, and we are a corrupt nation. To say she is unqualified due to corruption is like saying Tony Soprano shouldn't be boss because he is involved in extortion and racketeering. No kidding, that's the business.

The e-mail scandal is a technicality. Is the risk here that she will do it again? No one is going to let that happen. Everyone makes mistakes; this is faaaar from a disqualifying one, despite what the media and /r/politics will have you believe.

On the positive side, let's look at her resume. 8 years First Lady, 8 years Senator, 4 years Secretary of State. Can you think of someone who has more qualifying experience who has not already been president? Al Gore maybe? Think about what she learned during that time: daily security briefings, White House operations knowledge, first and second-hand experience with the inner workings of the executive branch, relationships with Washington officials and world leaders, expertise in global affairs analysis, experience running successful military campaigns. She knows the intricacies of issues they aren't even telling your average Senator. Not to mention her pre-Washington experience; she has been groomed for this for decades. 

And I voted for Bernie btw

(Edited after fact-checking)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579690399.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking of politicians being corrupt, Hillary is I need of the only politicians that I have noticed where corruption seems to be there. I am sure that every politician has corruption in them, but Hillary's rises to the surface. It is either that Hillary cannot hide her corruption, but will all of her experience she must be great at hiding these things; this is why I think that she has so much that some of it bubbles into the public view. 

I don't believe that the email scandal is something to take lightly. Not only did she put public information into an unsecure server, she was also using it to hide something. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579706481.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>If you think Hillary is the only politician for which the legal kind of corruption is there, you haven't been paying attention. Name nearly any politician and I'll give you an example of similar corruption. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579968153.0" user="grumplstltskn" delta="False">
    <text>Senator Sanders</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580015696.0" user="youraveragehobo" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.dailykos.com/story/2016/4/16/1516075/-Sanders-are-still-profiting-from-Sierra-Blanca-nuclear-waste-dump-per-their-2014-tax-return

http://www.thepeoplesview.net/main/2016/2/17/when-brown-lives-did-not-matter-to-bernie</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580153614.0" user="grumplstltskn" delta="False">
    <text>I'll admit this is disconcerting, I'll have to read more than these sources. I'm not sure this is really about corruption but that doesn't mean it's not troubling nonetheless.

I think it pales in comparison to Clinton but I'm not going to use the "everybody does it so who cares" defense her supporters are fond of</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580166015.0" user="youraveragehobo" delta="False">
    <text>These accusations are about as substantive as anything Clinton has been accused of. If you give Sanders the benefit of the doubt, you should extend the same courtesy to Clinton.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580020128.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>There is his [acceptance](http://www.forbes.com/sites/jaredmeyer/2015/08/25/sanders-rubio-support-costly-sugar-subsidies/#54b03a936403) of money from lobbyists and voting to have taxpayers subsidize those lobbyists industry. 

There is his [support](http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2016/02/09/bernie-sanders-loves-this-1-trillion-war-machine.html) of the f-35 in contradiction to his stated views about the military-industry complex and wasteful spending, and the [donations](http://fortune.com/2016/04/01/defense-industry-campaign-hillary-and-bernie/) he receives as a result. 

There is using campaign contributions to benefit his [family](http://www.vanityfair.com/news/2016/01/bernie-sanders-family-money). Nothing disqualifying, but he's hardly pure. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580100980.0" user="lostvan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; According to an investigation by the right-leaning Washington Free Beacon, Sanders’s spouse of 27 years, Jane O’Meara Sanders, and his stepdaughter, Carina Driscoll, both drew sizable salaries from Sanders’s House campaigns between 2000 and 2004. Public records examined by the online paper reportedly show O’Meara Sanders was paid “more than $90,000 for consulting and ad placement services” between 2002 and 2004, while Driscoll received $65,000 from the campaign over the course of four years.

Doing the math: $90,000/3 years = $30,000. This is very low income.

Vanity Fair ...ok well sure. I am following the links to the 'source' you have just have given. 

[1](http://triblive.com/x/pittsburghtrib/opinion/columnists/datelinedc/s_479239.html#axzz3wOTnaE9C)
&amp;gt; Jane O'Meara Sanders, his second wife for the past 20 years, is president of Burlington College. They have four adult children. Jane Sanders received $91,020 between 2002 and 2004 for "consultation" and to negotiate the purchase of television and radio time-slots for Sanders' advertisements, according to records and interviews.

Again MATH!:  $91,020/3 years = $30,340 . I don't even make this little. 

So Sanders is being accused of paying his wife for working? Please explain why you think this is worng? Is she supposed to work for free?



In the same paper...
[1](http://triblive.com/x/pittsburghtrib/opinion/columnists/datelinedc/s_479239.html#axzz3wOTnaE9C)
&amp;gt; Carina Driscoll, daughter to Jane O'Meara Sanders and Bernie's stepdaughter, who had been a member of Burlington City Council, picked up $65,002 in "wages" between 2000 and 2004, campaign records show. She had been her stepfather's campaign manager in 2000, his fundraiser and office manager in 2003; she was his database manager in 2004.

HUH? wow so he is paying his step-daughter for working...
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580109569.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;HUH? wow so he is paying his step-daughter for working...


Isn't that exactly what people are complaining about with Bill's brother or something like that? Why is it ok for a Sanders to use donated money to pay his family but not a Clinton?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580129934.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>The distinction between bribes which are illegal and campaign contributions which are legal is that bribes are used for personal gain and campaign contributions are to be used strictly for campaign purposes. To it is not technically illegal, paying family members to work on campaigns is frowned upon because it blurs that line. Also worth noting, when you say the payments are low, you are assuming they worked full time. Jane Sanders was a consultant, and in 2004 she had another full-time job as she had been named president of Burlington College. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580137852.0" user="lostvan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The distinction between bribes which are illegal and campaign contributions which are legal is that bribes are used for personal gain and campaign contributions are to be used strictly for campaign purposes. 

Are you saying Sanders bribed his wife by paying her to work minimum wage while holding another job. Is there something wrong with holding two jobs? Is there something wrong to be paid to help your husband? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580151008.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>No. Sanders didn't bribe his wife. The issue is that the special interests funding Sander's campaigns enriched Sanders's household. And Sanders' wife didn't work for minimum wage. Minimum wage is per hour; how many hours did Sander's wife consult for? 

The ethical thing wouldn't be for Sander's wife to work unpaid; it would for Sanders not have family work on his campaign in the firstplace. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580061781.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2016/02/09/bernie-sanders-loves-this-1-trillion-war-machine.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580006511.0" user="lostvan" delta="False">
    <text>Bernie Sanders

~~Tim Canova~~</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580029565.0" user="5555512369874" delta="False">
    <text>I covered Bernie Sanders above. Tim Canova hasn't been elected to anything yet, and you can't really engage in political corruption as a private citizen. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580058563.0" user="Mejari" delta="False">
    <text>Someone already responded about Sanders, and Canova has never held public office</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582209233.0" user="epicirclejerk" delta="False">
    <text>So you dismiss everything negative about her as not being relevant but some how the positives ARE relevant? How does that work? Seems kind of arbitrary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582449715.0" user="georgeisking" delta="False">
    <text>To an extent any opinion will be arbitrary but I explained my reasoning. The characteristics I've regarded as relevant have to do with the job description.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28588921913.0" user="epicirclejerk" delta="False">
    <text>Well she uses her jobs in government as a way to line her own pockets which requires her to:

1. Have to hide and delete State department communications resulting in a an enormous national security issue.

2. Appoint foreign businessmen with no experience and rushed security clearance to highly sensitive intelligence committees. Sure you can say the campaign and Clinton Foundation donations had nothing to do with that but let's not kid ourselves here, we know that's exactly what happened according to the emails.

3. Let Americans die in Benghazi. [(http://www.judicialwatch.org/press-room/press-releases/state-department-hid-key-clinton-benghazi-email-from-judicial-watch/)](http://www.judicialwatch.org/press-room/press-releases/state-department-hid-key-clinton-benghazi-email-from-judicial-watch/) 
And is still actively trying to cover it up [\(http://www.judicialwatch.org/press-room/press-releases/state-department-hid-key-clinton-benghazi-email-from-judicial-watch/\)](http://www.judicialwatch.org/press-room/press-releases/state-department-hid-key-clinton-benghazi-email-from-judicial-watch/)

I could go on but you get the point. Scandal after scandal after scandal. Almost everything relating to her job description has been a complete disaster. Just saying someone was a First Lady, a Senator, and Secretary of State doesn't mean anything. It doesn't mean they had good results and it doesn't mean they aren't completely corrupt. Sure, she has tons of knowledge about the the inner workings of government like you said, but I don't see how that is necessarily a prudent reason to support her considering she uses that knowledge to enrich herself, cause national security emergencies, sell intelligence assets to foreign governments and businessmen, and endanger the lives of thousands of people working in intelligence and the state department.

It would be great to have someone who couldn't be bought for once.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
