<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285192903.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pso93/cmv_hillary_clinton_is_unfit_for_presidency/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton is unfit for presidency.</title>
    <original_poster>Professorjack88</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that Hillary Clinton is unfit for the presidency because she is corrupt, a liar, and a hypocrite.

1. Hillary Clinton is corrupt. She or her husband routinely [have taken money from companies](http://downtrend.com/robertgehl/oops-bill-clinton-says-he-accidentally-took-500000-from-algeria-during-key-arms-negotiation-with-state-department), that they then go on to give government contracts. [One of her largest donors was given a spot on the nuclear advisory board, with no experience at all.](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2016/06/clinton-had-donor-as-nuclear-security-adviser.html) She will not release her speech transcripts, which hints at the fact that Hillary may have told them something that she doesn't want to get out. Whether it be corruption or something else; she is hiding something.



2. Hillary Clinton is a hypocrite and a liar. She takes huge sums of cash from wall street, and then says that she is going to breakup the banks. She says that she is a women's rights activist, and yet takes millions from countries like Saudi Arabia. I haven't even mentioned Hillary's flip flopping on all sorts of her campaign issues, and described in [this](http://imgur.com/Ls3B6n1) image. You can see her whole platform change in response to Bernie Sanders. She seems to say anything to get elected.

Based on all this, how can people support her? The facts are right there, and yet Hillary continues to get many votes. Is there something that I'm missing? It seems as if the second she gets in office she will support the big donors that she has pledged against. Throughout this whole thing, I haven't yet talked about Hillary's email scandal. She held secret government files on a server that was *hacked multiple times.* If someone could show me the reasons to support Hillary that would be great.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28579760797.0" user="moskie" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding her speeches, I think you're buying into right wing hate of Hillary to think that the transcripts will reveal anything along the lines of explicit corruption. These speeches were most likely boiler plate BS, with some platitudes thrown in about her hosts. Are you expecting her to have said "Donate to the Clinton Foundation, and you'll get a committee seat in return!" or something? I don't think you're being reasonable if that's what you're expecting. Ultimately, I don't think it's worth your time to have your opinion of her hinge on whether these speeches are made public.

I think the reality is that there is no upside to her releasing them. People (like you) who assumed the worst about the speeches will mine them for vague out-of-context sound bites to use against her, regardless of any broader truth. And any things she's said in these private speeches that would improve her standing with the general population I'm sure she's already said in public. So what's her motivation? To appease people who make it their lives to take her down? And maybe she will release them one day, just to shut them up, but it'll come at a time that is least advantageous to her opponents.

I find this to be a common theme of criticism against Hillary: it's a fear about the inexhaustible amount of stuff that we don't know about her. I find it absurd to believe that with how much of a public record she has, and with how high profile of a career she's had over the past few decades, that we don't already have an accurate understanding of who she is, and what kind of president she'd be. More so than most presidential candidates in history. Focusing on these remaining things that aren't public yet are FUD tactics, and we can do better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579766403.0" user="Professorjack88" delta="False">
    <text>The big part of the speeches for "people like me" is that she won't release them. I personally think that she is hiding something.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579777351.0" user="moskie" delta="False">
    <text>Do you feel you don't already have enough information about Hillary to accurately judge her capabilities as president? Because I think we do. I think this is a just a hoop you want her to jump through, because you're going out of your way to find reasons to disqualify her ("if she doesn't do unnecessary-thing X, I'm not voting for her!").</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28579999654.0" user="Karmaisforsuckers" delta="False">
    <text>Would you please post your full name, address, SSN, mother's maiden name, bank account number, and phone number?

If no, why are you a corrupt 1% corporate shill?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580022184.0" user="HeTalksToComputers" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think she is hiding something, you FEEL that she is hiding something, [and that is all that is needed to manufacture outrage](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear,_uncertainty_and_doubt). Realistically, what could be contained in those speeches that would change your mind about her qualifications to be president?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580854222.0" user="bonkus" delta="False">
    <text>What she's hiding is most likely just ego-stroking of GS. 

That would be political fodder for Bernie, and if it comes out before the general it'll cost her hundreds of thousands if not millions of votes. 

The other option is that the speeches are ultra-tame or non-existant. Which is proof that she's just accepting huge amounts of money for a completely worthless speech. And that's at least a strong argument for some kind of subtle or not so subtle bribery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28583531636.0" user="tlk742" delta="False">
    <text>I'm late to the party, but I want to hit something historical.  How familiar are you with Joseph McCarthy and the red scare? They had these hearings of people who were suspected of being communists or communist sympathizers. During the McCarthy hearings, while people were testifying, pleading the 5th amendment, out of fear of self-implication, was enough to get you blacklisted for being a communist.  By saying "I legally refuse to testify because I can implicate myself" the committee instantly said "Aha! We were right, you clearly are hiding something, and thus you are a communist".  More often than not, they were wrong.

The speech may contain things that generally are moments of "oh I shouldn't have said that" It could have been a faux pas, a roast, a self-deprecating joke, but to assume the worst is like the McCarthy hearings. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
