<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285265861.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pu8jp/cmv_paytowin_games_are_not_unfair_or_unethical/">
    <title>CMV: Pay-to-win games are not unfair or unethical</title>
    <original_poster>pocketMAD</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pay-to-win games are not unethical.

	After frequenting /r/clashroyale, a subreddit dedicated to Supercell’s new multiplayer strategy game, one notices a vast amount of complaints on the immorality that exists in Supercell’s business model. I agree the game designed to be pay-to-win: purchasing certain options grants one a greater advantage. Regardless, a company offering paid advantages for their video game service is not unethical or evil.
	This method is fair. If one decides their gaming experience is fine as it already stands and that purchasing advantages simply is not worth the cost, then refrain from paying. Heck, go and create your own game with your own business model.
	There’s nothing wrong with complain about a video game. I think complaining is healthy for a community as the company can view the complaints and better their game. I just think complaining about pay-to-win in general is wrong because companies need to make money. 
	Another counter to my argument is pay-to-win games often construct an elitist top-200 filled with players known as “whales.” They put in tons of money to stay at the top, making it impossible for players who pay nothing to ever reach that high. But these people spend most of their day sustaining their high ranks. These people are Youtubers and twitchers. It’s their job to be at the top to sustain their audience. If you wish to be at the top, make your free youtube or twitch account, learn how to gain followers, do it, and then you too can be at the top. This seems perfectly fair to me.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28582549803.0" user="tensor0910" delta="False">
    <text>I'm 5'4 and want to play a basketball game.  I jump into my PS4 and pop in 2K.  Holy crap, now I'm 6'5!  Now I can play without worrying about being too short.


I jump into (insert pay to win game ), but now I'm right back to square 1 b/c player 2 has more money than me.

Conflict of interests, IMO</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
