<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285265861.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pu8jp/cmv_paytowin_games_are_not_unfair_or_unethical/">
    <title>CMV: Pay-to-win games are not unfair or unethical</title>
    <original_poster>pocketMAD</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pay-to-win games are not unethical.

	After frequenting /r/clashroyale, a subreddit dedicated to Supercell’s new multiplayer strategy game, one notices a vast amount of complaints on the immorality that exists in Supercell’s business model. I agree the game designed to be pay-to-win: purchasing certain options grants one a greater advantage. Regardless, a company offering paid advantages for their video game service is not unethical or evil.
	This method is fair. If one decides their gaming experience is fine as it already stands and that purchasing advantages simply is not worth the cost, then refrain from paying. Heck, go and create your own game with your own business model.
	There’s nothing wrong with complain about a video game. I think complaining is healthy for a community as the company can view the complaints and better their game. I just think complaining about pay-to-win in general is wrong because companies need to make money. 
	Another counter to my argument is pay-to-win games often construct an elitist top-200 filled with players known as “whales.” They put in tons of money to stay at the top, making it impossible for players who pay nothing to ever reach that high. But these people spend most of their day sustaining their high ranks. These people are Youtubers and twitchers. It’s their job to be at the top to sustain their audience. If you wish to be at the top, make your free youtube or twitch account, learn how to gain followers, do it, and then you too can be at the top. This seems perfectly fair to me.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28580210092.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>Part of the ethical dimension of free-to-play-pay-to-win games is that they take advantage of people (the "whales") who have addictive personalities or gambling disorders.  The vast majority of these people are not streamers, and aren't making money from these games.

If you have six minutes to spare, I suggest you take a look at [this Extra Credits youtube video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FwI0u9L4R8U).  It gives a good overview of the issues related to free-to-play gaming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580301608.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>No one is forcing these people with addictive personalities or gambling disorders to pay money. I still see nothing unethical with taking advantage of them. It's their fault for giving their money to the company. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580459473.0" user="cmv478" delta="False">
    <text>You don't see anything unethical with exploiting someone's vice for your own gain? Surely you see how this practice goes against many mainstream ethical views. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580491162.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. The reason is the company isn't forcing the person against their will.  They're simply dangling a carrot in front of them. It's the customer's fault that they bought item with their money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580495650.0" user="cmv478" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't answer the second part of my question. Do you or do you not acknowledge that such a practice goes against most mainstream ethical theories?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581823863.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>No. Consider how Supercell, for example, is doing nothing illegal, then I wouldn't consider it unethical against mainstream theories. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581918056.0" user="cmv478" delta="False">
    <text>Ethics and law are not the same thing and very few ethical theories believe that they should have a one to one correspondence rate, so your argument doesn't really make any sense here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580673084.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>What you're essentially saying is that snake oil salesmen are "victimless criminals", and so long as no one has a gun to their head, any sales tactics are legitimate. Most people don't find this to be a case, and want to actively call out exploitative business practices in the hopes of protecting those who are unaware of the situation. 

It's like the Vitamin Water case. Coca Cola, the parent company, was sued over misrepresenting the health benefits of their product in advertising, to which their response was "no consumer could reasonably be misled into thinking vitaminwater was a healthy beverage." For obvious reasons, this attempt to dismiss the case was thrown out as bullshit. Companies are in it for the money, and at times this means actively misleading consumers, manipulating the less informed, and seeing how far they can push people before too many jump ship. That's basically the mobile market in a nutshell right now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582820927.0" user="Mitchiro" delta="False">
    <text>OP, please respond to this; I came in to make this argument as well. Having a product that purposely misleads consumers in order to get their money is unethical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28582849816.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>I'm hoping to get some response from the OP as well. Depending on how it goes, I have this lovely bridge to sell him for a reasonable price. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581188506.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No one is forcing these people with addictive personalities or gambling disorders to pay money.

That's exactly what they are doing, to the dot. Okay biology 101. Human brain responds well to a reward. Under normal circumstances buying brings the reward immediately. When that happens your brain gets nice and big injection of pleasure chemicals than give you this high of happiness.

Normally people buy cosmetic stuff, of other stuff that are not relevant to the gameplay besides a nice hat. Or even XP boosters or some such thing. But P2W games are designed to not be playable for a normal person without the constant purchase.

SO you have simple diagram. In one directions you get no pleasure chemicals through gameplay, in the other you do but only through purchases. If a person isn't dissuaded by the concept immediately and start playing, what do you think they will do. Purchase stuff, as is the design of the game.

This involves small kids who have no idea about the value of the money. And their parents who have no idea about P2W games. You combine those two into one big packet of disaster.

Next we have normal adult people, but who are prone to gambling. And immediate rewards. Those people will pay a lot, just to get that little high.

This is literally what P2W games are. It's fooling of the brain and exploiting mental biases of humans. It's like cigarets. Addicts will buy them no matter what.

"But nobody forces them to try them". Except marketing, peer pressure in school, our society where smokers get free brakes from work, ....... And countless other reasons a normal person get lured into it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581826601.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>That's true however companies aren't holding a gun to the customer and forcing them to purchase their product. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
