<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285265861.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pu8jp/cmv_paytowin_games_are_not_unfair_or_unethical/">
    <title>CMV: Pay-to-win games are not unfair or unethical</title>
    <original_poster>pocketMAD</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pay-to-win games are not unethical.

	After frequenting /r/clashroyale, a subreddit dedicated to Supercell’s new multiplayer strategy game, one notices a vast amount of complaints on the immorality that exists in Supercell’s business model. I agree the game designed to be pay-to-win: purchasing certain options grants one a greater advantage. Regardless, a company offering paid advantages for their video game service is not unethical or evil.
	This method is fair. If one decides their gaming experience is fine as it already stands and that purchasing advantages simply is not worth the cost, then refrain from paying. Heck, go and create your own game with your own business model.
	There’s nothing wrong with complain about a video game. I think complaining is healthy for a community as the company can view the complaints and better their game. I just think complaining about pay-to-win in general is wrong because companies need to make money. 
	Another counter to my argument is pay-to-win games often construct an elitist top-200 filled with players known as “whales.” They put in tons of money to stay at the top, making it impossible for players who pay nothing to ever reach that high. But these people spend most of their day sustaining their high ranks. These people are Youtubers and twitchers. It’s their job to be at the top to sustain their audience. If you wish to be at the top, make your free youtube or twitch account, learn how to gain followers, do it, and then you too can be at the top. This seems perfectly fair to me.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28580216165.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>The trouble with your argument is that it relies on this idea that the companies are making these aspects of their game "optional", and that the companies aren't succumbing to excessive greed. 

Looking at the mobile gaming market, it's clear to see that this isn't the case. Looking at Simpsons Tapped Out, Dungeon Keeper Mobile, etc... you see the same style of game show up over and over. Massively long wait timers, some taking hours, or literally days and weeks to complete, which can be sped up by in game currency which is purchased with real life money. Do you think that at no point in the game design anyone thought "maybe if we make these timers longer, more people will be inclined to just pay to get rid of them?". The incentives of microtransactions do affect game design philosophy, and it does impact the gameplay. What company is going to add paid content without creating any incentive to actually spend on that content? You hear more and more games these days called a "grind" because of this. 

GTA online is a prime example of a AAA game which has succumbed to this greed. They're constantly adding new cars and clothes which cost millions of in-game dollars to buy. A few million in-game dollars can be purchased for real life money... which typically works out that a car and all it's upgrades in the game will cost you $40-60... the alternative is having to grind lower level missions and heists in the hopes to earn enough money, which can take dozens and hundreds of hours. Rockstar knows this- every time they've patched the game and changed the gameplay its clear that the only cheating they care about are money hacks, and the only content they care about adding are gaudy items that you either have to grind for or cough up enough money to just buy another full priced title. It's very obvious in situations like this that the game is only as slow paced as it is because they are trying to make people suffer until they give in and just buy the items with real money. 

I don't mind companies wanting to make money... that is the entire point of their existence as a business. However, exploiting players by dramatically affecting the gameplay isn't the way to do it. Making the game not fun unless you're constantly sinking money is bad game design. You're making players pay to basically skip the gameplay... a good game has some waiting and grinding to it in moderate amounts. Having to earn items you've been waiting for does give you a sense of fulfilment. But mobile gaming and slowly PC gaming has become increasing filled with exceptionally slow progression which is clearly designed with microtransaction circumvention in mind. 

If you want to see microtransactions done right- look at Overwatch. Full priced game, but all the content is open to the player right from the start. All the maps, characters, and abilities are available. None of the gameplay is hidden behind a paywall. The only things you can purchase are cosmetic items which don't affect the gameplay whatsoever, and which you will earn at a steady and fairly reasonable rate without having to spend real money anyway. For players who have more money than time, they can put in a little extra to try and get the cosmetics they want, and for players who have more time than money they can earn the money by playing the game normally. It also helps that the game is actually designed to be fun from the start, not designed to be a grind. Mobile games are the antithesis of this, which is why I gave up on the mobile market years and years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580306375.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>If one doesn't enjoy a company purposely making its game less enjoyable unless a fee is played, then he simply doesn't need to play and instead play another game with a more preferred business model. This would entice companies to use more of these preferred business models. Obviously, the current business model, in clash Royale for example, is preferred, otherwise Supercell wouldn't be making money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580387636.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>Particularly in mobile gaming, however, you have a lot of people who fundamentally don't understand the value proposition being made. Outside of core gamers who are following the news and understand the practices of these companies, I don't think a lot of people really comprehend the exploitation tactics these companies are using. For a lot of people, kids in particular, but also the older generation who didn't grow up with games consoles... their phone is their first contact with games. They've got it with them all the time, there's so many "free" apps... it's easy to pick it up and just try it out. And the fact that so much of the market is saturated with what boils down to watching paint dry or paying to make it dry faster... it leaves a really bad false impression of what gaming is in the minds of people. It's easy for me to say that GTA is too expensive, and mobile gaming is seeing how far they can push people... because I'm a core PC gamer. I try to follow industry news, I have journalists I trust... I have a feeling for what companies are trying to do. For someone who just picks up their phone, or a parent who gives their phone to their child and they see something that looks pretty to play with... and it's asking for little bits of money here and there... it's a whole different experience. I mean, that's why the Apple Store and Google Play have had to put in child prevention and warnings for IAP's because people were getting taken advantage of. To some extent it's the responsibility of the more informed audience to be lobbying against these companies who are just seeing how much shit they can throw at a wall that sticks to help protect those who are less informed and are going to have their wallets taken for a ride. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580411811.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see anything unfair with that. It doesn't take a genius to know that giving your money away is your responsibility. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580434963.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>No, but for someone inexperienced with core gaming the actual understanding of the practices and value proposition isn't there. Dungeon Keeper for example... one of the classics of gaming history. A real time strategy game based on managing minions, mining out underground halls, constructing rooms and traps, and battling with hordes of heroes that came from above. You can buy that on GoG for $6. 

The [mobile version of the game](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GpdoBwezFVA) destroys the entire point of the real-time gameplay. It has blocks which take hours to mine, up to 24 hours for some of them... which can be accelerated with gems. Of course you buy those gems with real world money. To dig out one block in that game could cost you £1.50; the "Best Value" option being £70, or the price of a modern AAA console pre-order. Bearing in mind that the original game was tense and fun because you were digging out hundreds of blocks to build elaborate mazes of dungeons with traps and rooms... to a casual mobile player entering games for the first time who knows nothing about the original and the original gameplay mechanics it gives a totally broken idea of what gaming is. The find a game like that and download it, and instead of getting a tense fun experience in real time, they find a system where you poke a few spots at the screen, and come back to it tomorrow to poke a few more spots, or you pay a little money here and there to speed up the poking at the screen. The entire point of that system and the only reason the game is designed that way on phones is to make money from impressionable and uninformed people. 

Same goes for ["Rollercoaster Tycoon 4 Mobile"](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zck2kMhIS2s). Same goes for ["Simpson's Tapped Out"](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ub9KoUM8yDg). The same goes for these games which are now being ported back to PC, such as ["Frozen Free Fall"](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVhJrFHsGP4).

The mobile market is saturated with these piss poor excuses for games which feature very little gameplay which is gated behind wait timers and limiting mechanics. They're designed to be just flashy enough to get you addicted, but just slow enough to aggravate you into spending as much money as they can get from you. They aren't games, they're social experiments; they're a psychological assault in the attempt to extort money from the casual and ill-informed consumer. 

For the kinds of extortionate prices they're trying to charge for these microtransactions in these husks of games, you could literally go to GoG and buy basically every classic game in existence and actually discover what really makes games enjoyable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580440633.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>They're not social experiments at all..it's a company that wants to make money. If you don't like it, then stop playing and go to some other game. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580458582.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>I have, most core gamers have. But there are kids being given tablets and phones by their parents, and people coming to games for the first time who don't know any better who are still playing. Ignoring that the limited interface of a mobile device makes core gaming nearly impossible, the fact that the market is saturated with these kinds of exploitation... and it is, go to the top grossing list of whatever platform you're on, look at the new releases section and you'll see dozens of rip-offs of rip-offs of rip-offs of these same bullshit excuses of games come up over and over... the fact that these companies are doing this and it's popular shows that there's a uninformed group of people who are being taken advantage of. 

Let's put this in a different context. You're trying to pick theme parks... everyone in town goes to this carnival- it's free to get in, but all the rides cost ludicrous amounts of money to buy tickets for. But it's just around the corner, and people don't realise there's another park, so they keep paying money to get on these short little dinky rides... like a go-cart race that you have to keep paying $5 for a minute long lap over and over... they think they're enjoying themselves but they just don't know any better. Would it not be good for you, and everyone, to let them know, hey... I just heard about this great new theme park. It's got amazing rides, this is what a theme park is really meant to be like, come see! 

That's the difference between mobile gaming and core gaming. For the kinds of prices you rack up trying to actually squeeze an enjoyable experience out of a mobile game, you can pick up core games. Seriously... Humble Bundle, Steam Sales, GoG... if you want to get into gaming, pick up games from like 5-10 years ago, you can find them for $5-10 and they're amazing experiences that will usually run on even the midrange machine you probably own.
For the price of shitty mobile experiences, you don't need a super godly computer to compete... on a laptop you can play Garry's Mod, or Dungeon Keeper, or Civilisation, or Magika, or Rogue Legacy, or Spelunky, or FTL, or Prison Architect, or Limbo, or Isaac, or Portal... but a lot of this audience on mobile (and they are a lot of kids on their parents devices, and the parents don't know any better...) don't know what they're missing and don't realise what the standards of business practice are for the mobile market.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580996644.0" user="NuclearStudent" delta="False">
    <text>The part that's wrong is that these games are deliberately designed to take money from people who are tech illiterate. 

For example, many PTW games are designed so that kids quickly rack up enormous bills on their parents phones. By the time the parents have figured out what's happening, the money's been spent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581827904.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but Apple (or Google) can refund customers when these situations occur. Moreover, I doubt this occurs enough to be a legitimate issue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28581870837.0" user="NuclearStudent" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, but at least some of the time, the bill slips through or the parents aren't tech savvy enough to get the cost voided.


In general, though, the apps are clearly designed so that behavior like that is likely to happen. In general, PTW mobile apps are deliberately cartoony and designed to appeal to a younger/less mentally capable audience. When the player hits a wall where they have to pay to continue to have the same fun, then they pay up the wazoo because they are young or dumb.

 


That's a legitimate business model, I guess. But it results in crappy games and poor dumb people getting poorer and dumber.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
