<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613158661.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Well, in terms of my personal experience:  

I posted on FB about my reaction to the trailer.  Specifically, I posted that I was pretty shocked by the way they have three scientists (white), and one subway worker (black), who seems to be a horrible pastiche of stereotypes.  

It didn't take long for the sexism accusations to roll in, notwithstanding that I hadn't said one word about gender.  

To that end, I propose an experiment.  If you agree, I suggest the following.  I will craft a suitably non-sexist, but negative statement about the movie.  You can vet it to ensure that it meets those criteria.  I'll then make a throwaway account and use it to post to a feminist board.  We can then observe the responses.  Once that is done, we can post a report here.  

Would that be agreeable?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613180453.0" user="corexcore" delta="False">
    <text>I'm curious! Report back even if OP isn't into it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613222909.0" user="PM_ME_BABES_ON_BOATS" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like to see what happens as well</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613239149.0" user="Ensurdagen" delta="False">
    <text>Posting it on a feminist board is baiting. Criticism that has nothing to do with sexism doesn't belong in a feminist board.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613257300.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the CMV here was about feminist backlash.  Seems that feminists would be the appropriate pool to look at.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613288101.0" user="FungalowJoe" delta="False">
    <text>But you'll get negative responses by specifically going to a feminist-focused subreddit and reviewing a movie. Since your review would specifically NOT mention gender, it wouldn't be relevant to that board anyways  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613291469.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have an alternate suggestion for how to conduct the experiment?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613317736.0" user="Ensurdagen" delta="False">
    <text>Post criticism where it belongs. If *anyone* criticizing the movie will be rebranded as a misogynist, you will be branded as such wherever you post it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613326255.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Except that the point was specifically that it was people being branded as misogynist *by feminists*.  So you'd need places that have a large number of self-described feminists, as opposed to just "wherever".  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613353513.0" user="RagingOrangutan" delta="False">
    <text>So post it to Tumblr.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613403601.0" user="Sergnb" delta="False">
    <text>No yeah we get your point but think about it, posting it in a feminism dedicated subreddit would tarnish the results of the experiment as the post would,be seen as baity and inciting hostility when what we are trying to see is if feminists go out of their way to label people as misongynists even for seemingly,inocuous reasons like this.

I'd wager that seeing the natural reviews that I am willing to bet will be widely negative and observing the bscklash or lack thereof by feminists would be more appropiate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613552414.0" user="DualEquinox" delta="False">
    <text>Why not post it in the relevant areas, then when someone calls it sexist, review their post history to see if the take a feminist ideology? I mean its more work but seems the fairest way to do it off the top of my head.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613709208.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Off the top of my head, at that point a lack of criticism could be a lack of the target audience being present, or a lack of them feeling comfortable to trash it.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613419690.0" user="GoodGuyNixon" delta="False">
    <text>There are feminist film review boards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613709917.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Well, we'll see if OP is interested.  Or responds again at all.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613343875.0" user="Eat_The_Muffin" delta="False">
    <text>They don't want you to be instantly proven right</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613957885.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, I'd be up for /u/varsil's experiment, since I think there are some feminist boards that spend a lot of time talking about media. /r/gamerghazi will almost certainly have a thread when the movie is released to the public, so I'd be up for trying it there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613245651.0" user="veggiesama" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't you just post the interactions you had then? And then explain why the random opinions of your FB friends are worth anything. Paraphrasing doesn't really work here, because it's so incredibly easy to misinterpret and misrepresent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613265862.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>For a few reasons:  

1:  Facebook's search feature is fuck-awful.  
2:  Way too easy to identify people even with names/etc blocked out, and I generally take the philosophy that I don't share people's shit off Facebook to other forums.  As much as some of my FB friends can be assholes at times, I'm not willing to subject any of them to any brigading risk.  
3:  Because they're not worth much, it's a non-random sample.  For the little it's worth, you can take my word for it or not, and that's your call.  Anyway, given that you're not likely to get any more convinced by seeing the actual interaction, I'm not terribly inclined to possibly expose my RL and that of those around me.  

What would be worth more is the experiment I proposed.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613285063.0" user="veggiesama" delta="False">
    <text>"Brigading risk" -- there's that persecution complex OP mentioned. Oh well.

Posting a negative statement from an anonymous person to an unfamiliar board is just going to stir up shit. It's like throwing meat to the dogs. There would be confusion and some "don't feed the trolls," but it would mostly go ignored.

It would be much better to find a serious article or op-ed that describes why all criticism of the new Ghostbusters is veiled sexism. Unfortunately that article doesn't really exist, and sexist FB diarrhea shares the same space with baby photos and your weird uncle's flat earth theories, so it's hard to give it any credit or care about it for that matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613306193.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "Brigading risk" -- there's that persecution complex OP mentioned. Oh well.

Not sure how you get that, given that I'm noting equal or greater concern that my friends who made the criticism-is-sexist comments will be brigaded.  

And sure.  Let's find those articles:   

* http://www.huffingtonpost.com/elizabeth-love/is-hating-the-ghostbuster_b_10089570.html

* http://birthmoviesdeath.com/2016/05/18/the-soft-sexism-of-hating-on-the-new-ghostbusters

* https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/arts-and-entertainment/wp/2016/03/04/people-are-hating-the-ghostbusters-trailer-guess-why/   (Comments on some non-sexist reasons people might dislike it, but then goes on to suggest the vast majority is just sexism).  

* http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2016/05/the-sexist-outcry-against-the-ghostbusters-remake-gets-louder/483270/

* http://www.dose.com/hollywood/28823/Is-All-This-Ghostbusters-Backlash-Sexist-Or-Just-Unbridled-Nerd-Rage

* http://www.forbes.com/sites/scottmendelson/2016/05/02/sexism-may-help-turn-ghostbusters-into-a-blockbuster/#50fbddf15970</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614032014.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>Just to make sure you saw it, I'm definitely up for this. I'd suggest /r/gamerghazi as a locale for the post, since they're likely to have a big thread when the movie comes out where the criticism won't seem out of place or shoehorned in, and there's been a lot of discussion there about the controversy already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614228595.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>Awesome, that'll work for me. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
