<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613185005.0" user="NUMBERS2357" delta="False">
    <text>For this I can cite personal experience.  It came up in conversation with someone and I said I thought the movie looked like it was gonna be bad, and they immediately got all hostile and made some wisecrack like "oh yeah because women aren't funny right?" or something.

Anyway, I think it's clear the marketing people *are* drawing that connection to poison the well against criticism and make it into a political act to see the movie.  

But for more concrete examples, take [this](http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2016/05/the-sexist-outcry-against-the-ghostbusters-remake-gets-louder/483270/) article as an example.

&amp;gt; a vocal minority of movie fans have come up with specious reasons to criticize it. Hollywood does too many reboots; the sacred legacy of the original film is under threat; the jokes in the trailer aren’t funny enough. Things reached a fever pitch yesterday when James Rolfe, host of the popular “Cinemassacre” YouTube channel with over 2 million subscribers, announced that he wouldn’t even deign to watch the film. His reasoning dances around the simple fact that has set this innocuous-seeming movie apart from its fellow blockbusters this summer—that it’s a tentpole genre film starring women.

So other criticisms are specious, and Rolfe (who if you Google around, there's a *lot* of stuff out there calling him sexist, and apparently he got death threats for his video) is really just against it because it has all women.

&amp;gt; Its comments thread is filled with fans defending their down-votes as being “on merit alone,” as if a major Hollywood studio film has never had shaky advertising before.

...clearly implying the downvotes aren't "on merit alone."

Here's [Judd Apatow](http://uproxx.com/movies/judd-apatow-popstar-ghostbusters/):

&amp;gt; would assume there’s a very large crossover of people who are doubtful Ghostbusters will be great and people excited about the Donald Trump candidacy. I would assume they are the exact same people.

(for the record I'm doubtful it'll be great, and I'm voting for Hillary, but anyways).  [Octavia Spencer](http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/paul-feig-responds-misogynistic-ghostbusters-899689):

&amp;gt; "The fact that there are people who take any type of umbrage with [the movie] is mind-boggling to me," added fellow Produced By Conference panelist Octavia Spencer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613911123.0" user="peenoid" delta="False">
    <text>You might also mention how a popular _female_ Youtube personality, Comic Book Girl 19, criticized the movie based on the trailers and even told her viewers not to go see it (something even Rolfe didn't do), but her criticism was completely ignored by the same media that went after Rolfe. Funny how that works.

https://youtu.be/lQIuTGfPHvA

There's also compelling evidence that Sony deleted reasonable Youtube comments on the trailers but purposely left sexist and misogynistic ones in order to fuel this controversy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614288060.0" user="Akronite14" delta="False">
    <text>Very good point about the political act seeing the movie has become.

Recently a Facebook friend made a long impassioned post about how movies like these are tests and we need to support it for the sake of women in Hollywood (essentially). It's kinda fucked up since the real problem isn't that we might fail this test but that Hollywood is still not sure if they can make a franchise work with female leads. So many people have made the point while criticizing this film that hate that Hollywood will use it as an excuse to avoid female driven films.

There has absolutely been sexism in response to this film, but it's become such a back and forth bullshit fest at this point that both sides seem to be blowing the whole situation out of proportion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
