<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613178633.0" user="abutthole" delta="False">
    <text>Hm, I think you do have a lot of valid points and I do agree with pretty much everything you're saying.  I'll take a stab at it though and say that time frame is an issue here.  

The people criticizing the film RIGHT NOW (not including actual critics) before the movie has come out and before they've seen it actually are (mostly rightfully) being branded as sexist.  At this point in time, they don't have enough material to actually form an educated opinion about the movie.  So the people who are upset by it aren't mad because the movie's bad, they don't know if it is since they haven't seen it.  They're mad because their childhood favorite is being updated and changed.  There certainly are some people who'd be upset if the Ghostbusters reboot was made starring actors who looked like the originals, and their unwarranted anger has nothing to do with sexism.  But there is a greater number who're upset that their movie is being changed so much by making women the stars and think that it's a result of PC culture going overboard instead of considering that it might just be that these 4 comedians won their roles fair and square.  

Now once the movie is released and people actually see it, I think (should the movie suck) they'll have more reasoning behind their dislike for it.  I think once they can articulate clearly (based on the actual movie) why they don't like it, those accusations of sexism will dry up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613259679.0" user="pm_me_taylorswift" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen this argument and it's never made sense to me. The *entire point* of watching a trailer is to form an early opinion about a movie, to decide whether it's worth your time and/or money, but people who saw the trailer and formed that early opinion are wrong?

Full disclosure - I saw the trailer(s) and decided early on that it looked shitty. Had nothing to do with the actors' genders; I'm not big on McCarthy in general and Leslie Williams' character was grating as shit, but the other two were inoffensive at worst. I thought the jokes fell flat and the CGI ghosts were trying too hard. I'm the kind of guy who laughs at everything vaguely humorous, but I can count on two fingers the number of times I laughed at this trailer for a comedy movie. It looks like a shitty movie *to me*, but maybe I'm just not in the target audience so whatever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613319687.0" user="ZorbaTHut" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The people criticizing the film RIGHT NOW (not including actual critics) before the movie has come out and before they've seen it actually are (mostly rightfully) being branded as sexist. At this point in time, they don't have enough material to actually form an educated opinion about the movie.

Wouldn't that imply that people who are *praising* the film right now are equally sexist? After all, they're working with an identical lack of information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613528029.0" user="abutthole" delta="False">
    <text>Not many people are praising the film. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613820706.0" user="IgnisDomini" delta="False">
    <text>I literally have not seen a single person (aside from a few critics, who have actualy seen it) praise the film. All I've seen is "Wait for it to actually come out before passing judgement."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
