<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28612913039.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any criticism must be rooted in sexism. 

This one group does not say that any criticism is rooted in sexism.

&amp;gt; I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, .... is sexism,

This one group is saying this criticism (ie - all female cast) is sexism.

Am I misunderstanding something in your argument?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612920005.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. The claim being made on parts of reddit is that anyone who criticizes the movie for any reason, no matter how benign, will be labeled a sexist and ostracized. I'm saying that feminists have criticized completely unfounded criticism (eg it's got women now, so it must be pandering to SJWs and shit,) while having no issues with founded criticism (eg the jokes don't play very well to me, and it looks like it's just another McCarthy movie over being a true successor.)

Also, to be clear, "any" in that sentence means "any and all," the phrasing is kind of ambiguous, so I'll update it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612966756.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I'm saying that feminists have criticized completely unfounded criticism (eg it's got women now, so it must be pandering to SJWs and shit,) while having no issues with founded criticism

Isn't this a tautology and therefore doesn't really say anything?  "I have a problem with unfounded criticism but I don't have a problem with founded criticism ".  If you think its unfounded then of course you have a problem with it because you think its unfounded.  If you think its founded then you are ok with it because you think its founded.

Why isn't "I think an all-female cast sucks" not a founded criticism?  Its a personal opinion.  If they made a Ghostbusters remake an CGI all-talking cats as the cast then "I think an all-talking-cats cast sucks" would also be founded criticism since its my personal opinion.  It doesn't mean I hate cats, I personally just don't think its a good idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613004288.0" user="gunnervi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why isn't "I think an all-female cast sucks" not a founded criticism? Its a personal opinion.

"I think all-female casts suck" is an unfounded criticism *because* it is just a personal opinion.  "I don't like it" is not a criticism, it is an opinion.  It's a perfectly valid opinion (who am I to tell you what you do and don't like), but it is not a valid criticism (who are you to tell me that something is bad just because you don't like it)

So "I think an all-female cast sucks *because* [for example] women can't play strong characters as convincingly as men" is a valid criticism.  It's also misogynist.  Now if you were to actually voice this criticism, many would disagree with you.  But it's still a valid criticism, because the conclusion follows logically from the premise.  If women could not convincingly play strong characters, then an all-female cast would certainly result in a bad movie.

Whereas, "I think an all-female cast sucks because it's just pandering to SJWs" is unfounded.  Its an equally valid criticism as "I think Twilight sucks because it's just pandering to preteen girls".  Which is to say, just because a movie is targeting a different audience doesn't mean it will be bad.  It might give you a reason to think you *won't like it*, but again, "I don't like it" isn't a criticism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613851237.0" user="robeph" delta="False">
    <text>The pandering criticism could indeed have much more to it than simply the variable of pandering or not; and typically does.   For example,  Twilight,  pandering to teens means the writing is written for a young adult audience which will not bridge generational gaps well, its representation of romance differs from adult romance seen typically in movies, and the drama plots key in on features teens will recognize which are much less prevalent in adult interactions in the real world.  Simply saying the movie is not good because it panders too teen audiences makes all these statements, while never defining them (which is the fault in the pandering criticism)  such criticism needs to be a preface, perhaps,  but not the final writ, they need to detail what pandering is in this case.  

For the all female cast,  pandering may include a load of things which are not at all misogynistic.   Nostalgia and canon dissonance,  over exaggerating the strength of the characters in comparison to minor and extras involved, and so on.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613020895.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>What you're talking about is different than the opinion I'm seeing on reddit though. The narrative there seems to be that if you criticize the movie in any way, no matter how benignly, if you give it anything resembling a negative score, you'll be branded a misogynist. The fact that some are criticized for specific views that, bluntly, are misogynistic (the female led cast is bad, because it must be pandering) is irrelevant to the idea that critics are terrified to say anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613048795.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The narrative there seems to be that if you criticize the movie in any way, no matter how benignly, if you give it anything resembling a negative score, you'll be branded a misogynist.

There might be a time difference;

A few months ago when the trailer came out and people were saying its sucks, yes they were called sexist.  But there was only the trailer and a few bits of information so "criticize the movie in any way" really meant "criticize one of three/four/five/*insert small number* things we know about the movie".  One of the three/four/five/*insert small number* was the all-female cast issue which did get called sexist.

Now the reviews are trickling out and people haven't yet had a serious time to react.  So people (either side) haven't been said anything yet (sexist/non-sexist, founded/unfounded).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613472272.0" user="Gastte" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The narrative there seems to be that if you criticize the movie in any way, no matter how benignly, if you give it anything resembling a negative score, you'll be branded a misogynist.

People have linked to you what happened to James Rolfe multiple times already in this post so i won't again but it seems to be a clear cut case of exactly that happening. He never mentioned gender or feminism as his reasons for not seeing the movie or really discussed them at all and yet was was labeled a women hater in multiple articles and people flipped their lid on him.

If it happened to him why is it hard for you to believe it has happened or will happen to other people who aren't as famous?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613634943.0" user="orderingrabbits" delta="False">
    <text>Pointing out pandering isn't misogynistic, fam. They ARE pandering by the way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613860364.0" user="uncledrewkrew" delta="False">
    <text>What makes it pandering?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613882155.0" user="orderingrabbits" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's clearly pandering to the feminist "muh stronk women" crowd. Just look at the trailer and tell me it isn't. Note that I'm not saying pandering is necessarily a bad thing (or that even the movie will necessarily be awful), but it's pretty blatantly obvious who their expected audience is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613644570.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614050753.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry woah_dude891, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 3\. "Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view. If you are unsure whether someone is genuine, ask clarifying questions (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting ill behaviour, please message us." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+3+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=woah_dude891+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/d57tpga\))</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
