<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28614124600.0" user="Th3Merchant" delta="False">
    <text>Just to respond to this part:

&amp;gt; I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV

As a bit of context, I've started using reddit pretty frequently over the past month or two. Despite that, I haven't even heard of this movie on this site, having just seen a trailer or two at some point. This wasn't even remotely on my radar. So I don't think that reddit is in a particular uproar about this, just certain small parts of it. In general, my experience in the parts of reddit I hang out in tends to come down fairly solidly on the side of feminism, with the occasional exception. For example, being vocally pro-life will get you stomped on a little bit in most parts of the site.

Now, there are definitely areas of the site that attract the "feminism is cramping my style" types. The funny thing about reddit is that it represents a pretty decent cross-section of the internet as a whole. The proportion of porn to non-porn is maybe a little low to be representative, but most of the communities that exist on the internet are represented on reddit. So if you want to hang out in /r/mensrights or /r/pickupartists or whatever, you're likely to find a fair bit of anti-feminist, anti-PC sentiment. However, that has not been my experience in general, as someone who (though feminist myself) doesn't consciously select for pro-feminist subs.

All that to say - while certain parts of reddit may have a lot of people who live in constant fear of the "feminist PC police", I don't think that's the response of most well-adjusted users of the site. 

On the other hand, certain fans of the show do appear to be automatically on the defensive - it's possible that their gut reaction that it's weird to change the gender of one of their beloved characters makes them a little uncomfortable, because it *feels* a bit sexist. Being constantly expectant of an attack that never comes can make you a little crazy. In reality, it's a somewhat reasonable fan reaction - the characters as they originally existed have been changed. It would be sexist to say that Hermione really should have been played by a man because of her prominent role, but I don't really see anything wrong with wanting the movie to be like the show (as long as the feeling comes from a desire for authenticity and not a discomfort with breaks from gender roles). 

Still, most of the time when one says "that role should have been filled by a man", one is being sexist. So while the fears of feminist retribution are probably not founded in reality, I don't think that the source is purely anti-feminist feeling. Feminists get a bad rap (because some of us do tend to go [a little bit overboard](http://feministing.com/2013/10/03/wow-that-lorde-song-royals-is-racist/) now and again), and a lot of people who don't really care about the issue more or less assume that the stereotype is reality. many people whose views could reasonably be described as feminist would never self-describe as such, because "those feminists are crazy female-supremacists or whatever, right?". 

TL;DR: I think that it's a combination of people wanting the movie to be like the show, but thinking that it must be sexist to want that because the show had mostly just dues on it, and a general misunderstanding of feminism. I don't think there's a rampant anti-women's-rights streak on reddit, just a lot of poor understanding of what the ideology actually is and some rather excitable community members.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
