<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613114086.0" user="my-stereo-heart" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think every criticism against Ghostbusters is misogynist. However, I'm extremely wary when people complain about it because it seems to get SO much more hate than any other crappy remake. Compare the dislikes on the YouTube trailer to any other crappy remake or sequel or prequel trailer. You obviously don't have to like the movie but you have to admit that there's something weird about how strongly everybody seems to hate the movie before they've even seen it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613187976.0" user="jacenat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, I'm extremely wary when people complain about it because it seems to get SO much more hate than any other crappy remake.

Because it tried to create controversy. How is it surprising that it actually succeeded in that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613211382.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, tried to? by doing what, exactly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613239802.0" user="aqouta" delta="False">
    <text>Come off it. You know exactly what he means, you're just asking so he can say:

"They made it all women"

So you can say:

"what's wrong with women?"

Without the addressing the fact that gender bending the entire cast(granted 3/4ths) of a classic is clearly something done purposefully and for what other reason than to stir up political controversy for cheap buzz. It's one thing to do a cash grab with an old IP, it's much worse to try and parade its corpse around for controversies sake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613937016.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>My point is, there's no reason it should be controversial. And if it is controversial, that's not their fault or because they made it so. Is there something wrong with doing something perfectly normal just because someone else doesn't like it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613979013.0" user="aqouta" delta="False">
    <text>It's not perfectly normal to change the sex of the entire cast on a reboot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614006211.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? By perfectly normal I mean entirely without inherent controversy. it's a reboot. Reboot the series, different actors, rewritten characters. It happens. Does the gender matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614086350.0" user="aqouta" delta="False">
    <text>You're literally employing what I said you were doing to dodge the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614099231.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>Not at all. Firstly, if you think you don't have a good answer for why gender matters, maybe it's not because I'm a nefarious trickster, maybe you just don't have a good answer? Secondly, If something is controversial for a meaningless reason, I don't care and don't see any reason to criticize someone for doing it. Someone hiring a male kindergarten teacher might make some people somewhere upset, it might even feel 'controversial', but it doesn't actually matter, so the accusation of 'stirring up controversy' by doing it, as though they shouldn't, is silly. 

You either think they shouldn't hire them, or you think the people making it a 'controversy' are silly. Is there some alternative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614177615.0" user="aqouta" delta="False">
    <text>It matters because it's a large change in the dynamic of the film. If they replaced all the ghosts with walkie talkies because they wanted to do a product placement I would also think it's a bad idea. Reboots are bad enough, I think the intent with the casting was clearly to stir up controversy as a cash grab. The intent is clear and enough to dislike the move, whether the change SHOULD stir up controversy is another subject, it think is reasonable to assume any big change in a reboot is going to stir up a bit and the intent with this one is just so blatant that it comes off really nasty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614188317.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>the dynamic? See, I get that ghost busters is about ghost busting, so if the ghosts weren't ghosts; that would be weird. Like a reboot of Batman except this time he's a Public Defender obsessed with wolves.  And like, two and a half men is about male people, at least ostensibly, so replacing someone with a woman would be weird there. But as long as the women are busting Ghosts in the usual way, that's the ghost busters dynamic, right? Unless you mean specifically how the characters relate to each other, but that's more to do with writing than gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613284638.0" user="jacenat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; by doing what, exactly?

* Nixing the original director who wanted to go mixed-group, and nixing him explicitly for that reason. See Sony leaks. The choice in cast was made a political statement.
* Various media appearances and press releases surrounding the movie, overstating the gender reversal of the Ghostbusters and the secretary (likely tied in with the first point).
* Allegations made by some of the cast (only know it off melissa's twitter so far, but can't be bothered to dig) and the director that critique is largely focused on sexism and not content.

This lead to the movie seens by some of the public and fans as not a reboot of an old franchise but a way to convey a message that is not found in the original movie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613382641.0" user="courtenayplacedrinks" delta="False">
    <text>I think the trailers rely heavily on a particular kind of humour which you could call "women's humour". I'm not saying all humour that women write or enjoy is the same, but there is a kind of humour that relies on experience or social norms that (some) women relate to, but most men don't.

There's a joke about one of the cast being horrified because the slime got "in every crack". There's a joke where one of the cast can't walk past a hat without trying it on. There's a joke where two of the cast are frightened and clasp their bosom dramatically when an experimental trap they're looking at snaps shut suddenly. There's a joke where one of the cast hysterically shouts at everyone to get out of the city as she's dragged from the room, clutching a table.

The repeated underlying joke here is "wouldn't it be silly if women tried to be Ghostbusters?" There's even a joke where a man says "I'm sure you girls can handle it".

Now on the face of it, that's a pretty sexist message, but it's not that simple. Comedy is often about observing people's behaviours and emphasising them for comic effect. If I could relate to not being able to walk past a hat without trying it on, I might find that joke funny.

I can certainly imagine women watching this and being able to relate to the jokes—having a "haha, yeah, that's soooo true" response. As I understand it, the lead writer was a woman so presumably she's drawing on her own experiences and sense of humour. 

So the show is women's humour—it plays on the cast being female. It may or may not be perceived as sexist, or funny, by women who watch it. I know it's possible to play on stereotypes and still be funny. I've enjoyed humour that commented on groups I belong to in a way that I found apt, inoffensive and entertaining.

But there's a problem with in-group humour, if you're not in the in-group it can be hard to enjoy—either because you can't relate to it, or it's something you're not supposed to laugh at, or both.

I contend that many men watch this trailer, pick up on the sexist undertones and experience cultural cringe. Most men have grown up in a world where stereotyping women is highly inappropriate. Humour that plays to these stereotypes induces cultural cringe. I know that was my reaction to the trailers when I watched them. I cringed at every joke that turned on a female stereotype, virtually every joke in the trailer. I didn't think they were funny. I didn't immediately know why I didn't think they were funny, but I knew they made me cringe and that I didn't want to see the movie.

So in a long-winded way I'm arguing that men, in particular, dislike the movie, not because of misogyny or sexism, but because the humour turns on female stereotypes and men have developed an innate aversion to that kind of humour.

Add to that the likelihood that Ghostbusters fans are predominantly male and you get the explanation why it gets so much hate.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613391378.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>I'll level with you, it's in part because it's seen as "politically correct" and it's everything most moderates and conservatives hate. Remaking a movie just to make it PC. Its the worst of everything so it got the most hate: 

- an 80's remake on a budget with no A listers. 

- politically Correct 

- trying to make a buck more than make a film 

- terrible reviews from critics 

it's disliked because it's the perfect storm of things people hate about modern movies </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
