<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28612914626.0" user="RemoveKebabz" delta="False">
    <text>As a marketing major I can tell you that it is absolutely being marketed the way you describe. 

It's a fascinating campaign. Truly revolutionary. The campaign (at least the social media viral part) boils down to, "watch and like this film or you are a woman hater." It's basically identity politics style marketing for a film and I am really interested to see how it works out. 

As to the quality of the movie I have heard it's truly awful and blatant man bashing throughout. I don't know if you have seen this review https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=u-Pvk70Gx6c
 But that guy is pretty fair on his other films as far as I can tell. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612916452.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any sort of citation for that at all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612947712.0" user="RemoveKebabz" delta="False">
    <text>Citation on what? The marketing? No these kinds of campaigns aren't made public. The narrative is plain as day. Just do a search on "new ghost busters" and the terms "man baby" and "misogyny" and "sexist" are the biggest buzz words. We were talking about it at work the other day. You don't always need a website on the Internet to connect the dots for you. I don't need a leaked memo to tell me beer commercials use boobs to sell beer and I don't need one to tell be ghostbusters is using this excellent accusatory extortion as a prong. 

If you are asking about the man bashing my source is that guy in the review. If he is right and the characters are as he describes and the ending is as he describes I don't know what else you could call it. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612959533.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>So, no, you don't have a source, and I'm dumb for asking instead of just taking your word on it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612969300.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613010593.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry RemoveKebabz, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 3\. "Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view. If you are unsure whether someone is genuine, ask clarifying questions (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting ill behaviour, please message us." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+3+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=RemoveKebabz+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/d57f8es\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613703892.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613772661.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>I've removed your comment for violating Rule 3. If you wish to appeal use modmail. If you want to bring the post to the attention of the mods use the **report button** instead of violating the rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613015399.0" user="gunnervi" delta="False">
    <text>/u/RemoveKebabz's premise is that this is a viral marketing campaign, and thus primarily driven by people who are not, in any cpacity, affiliated with the product.

In this case, the very fact that the idea that anyone who criticizes the new Ghostbusters is a misogynist is prevelent is *in of itself* evidence that it is being marketed as such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613034907.0" user="RemoveKebabz" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. A few well placed shills (and well paid. Recruiting shills is a business I am building) seed the meme and it spreads if it's done right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613596088.0" user="luvs2spooge187" delta="False">
    <text>Not even that. This CMV, whether incidental or otherwise, is acting as grassroots marketing. Maybe the producers decided that virtue signalling is a cheaper and more effective marketing strategy than dropping leaflets.

Maybe they took a current topic (3rd wave feminism) and are using that agenda in a vehicle where it has no place (Ghostbusters, a light-hearted comedy) to stay hip. This could be a thinly veiled /r/fellowkids with a /r/Shitredditsays cherry on top.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613208042.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>It's flimsy evidence. The idea is pretty much only prevalent...here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613311519.0" user="Pornfest" delta="False">
    <text>The term you want is *circumstantial* evidence  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613415953.0" user="GoodGuyNixon" delta="False">
    <text>Which is used to prove things in court all the time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613887486.0" user="SmokeyDBear" delta="False">
    <text>I love how when anybody doesn't want to believe something it suddenly requires the same level of evidence as a criminal trial to be plausible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28615501696.0" user="czerilla" delta="False">
    <text>Well, we are on a sub called "change my view", so it's kind of the point to expect a bit more substance to an argument than "my idea is kinda plausible and if you disagree you just don't want to believe it". If you want to only convince people without making a case for it, you're on the wrong sub, to be frank.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613310611.0" user="Pornfest" delta="False">
    <text>No one said you were dumb? Certainly not the commenter... Why the persecution complex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613569500.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613800584.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry atlangutan, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if the rest of it is solid." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+2+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=atlangutan+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/d57s3j0\))

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 3\. "Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view. If you are unsure whether someone is genuine, ask clarifying questions (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting ill behaviour, please message us." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+3+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=atlangutan+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/d57s3j0\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613414201.0" user="Victorhcj" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;these kinds of campaigns aren't made public

Asking for a source for something that can't be sourced is like the new ad hominem. You're just derailing the discussion instead of responding to his argument. Dismissing his entire comment with one little sentence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613485913.0" user="frakkin_farang" delta="False">
    <text>You're right. Everyone pretends they are a great orator because they know a bit about fallacies, but they commit the fallacy of pointing out fallacies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613467559.0" user="Murky42" delta="False">
    <text>Answer his simple and direct question on what it exactly is that you want a source on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613996723.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>That it's an intentional marketing campaign, and not an organic reaction to a lot of people on the internet being sexist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614232478.0" user="TelicAstraeus" delta="False">
    <text>What sort of evidence would be acceptable to you? Where is the bar set for you on this? Commentary from an expert in the field? Secret master plans leaked from the studio's marketing department?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614472018.0" user="Murky42" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The ladies' most impressive talent, however, is their ability to overcome a lazy script that takes forever to get going. Coscreenwriter-director Paul Feig (Bridesmaids, Spy) feels the need to hit every familiar Ghostbusters beat, down to the “look, our business is booming!” montage. Instead of nailing a ghost at a high-profile hotel, they do it at a raucous Ozzfest concert. Jones must literally carry the movie's best sight gag on her shoulders; the rest of the jokes are hit-and-miss one-liners — including a self-referential dig at online fanboy haters.    (After McCarthy uploads a video on YouTube, an anonymous commenter whines,“ain’t no bitches gonna hunt no ghosts." Ouch!)   

http://www.usmagazine.com/entertainm...e-time-w212383

Seems pretty self aware. Could be intended as comedy of course but its suspicious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613676051.0" user="robeph" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly is wrong with you?  

You sure are taking a lot from his comments that went unsaid.  

As for "sources"  a source for what exactly?  That the  marketing effect of misogyny as a baking point for countering negative review and comments and its flip where watching it and "enjoying" it means you're not a misogynist... The source is opening your eyes and looking at pretty much everything about it anywhere?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613894225.0" user="TheDongerNeedsFood" delta="False">
    <text>Where in his post did he call you dumb?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613389560.0" user="filthyridh" delta="False">
    <text>but there literally is a massive, largely misogynistic backlash against the movie. so how does the fact that "sexism" and "misogyny" appear in relation to the movie prove anything about a marketing campaign?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28616028229.0" user="pimpsandpopes" delta="False">
    <text>What evidence do you have that dismissing criticism as mysognostic is a marketing ploy and not just many people who were pissed about the hysterics of the reaction?

The whole movie has been politicised all over the place, but I see no reason it's not organic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613162694.0" user="varsil" delta="False">
    <text>I would suggest that the comments by the director/actors are evidence of this.  It is very, very rare for the marketing/interviews/statements/etc for a movie to be so focused on the negative press a movie is getting.  I'd say it's almost unprecedented, in fact.  I can't think of another movie whose marketing (which includes cast/crew commentary in advance of the film) included so much discussion of the negative commentary, which is usually a topic that will get an interview shut down hard.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613801167.0" user="johnnywatts" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know if the campaign for Ghostbusters specifically targets free publicity generated by feminists, but I do have a citation for a campaign by another book/film: Tucker Max.

There's a great documentary on Netflix right now called Dishonesty, and there is a segment where the marketer behind the Tucker Max campaign (Ryan Holiday) covers basically how he manipulated feminists into generating free PR for the Tucker Max book and film. The segment starts at 20 minutes into the film if you're interested.

So manipulating feminists really isn't a new idea. It's been done, and apparently very successfully.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613924225.0" user="peenoid" delta="False">
    <text>There's evidence that Sony deleted reasonable Youtube comments on the trailers but purposely left sexist and misogynistic ones in order to fuel this controversy.

https://youtu.be/6aQTJw1wlQ8?t=4m15s


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613061468.0" user="ScooterinAB" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "watch and like this film or you are a woman hater."

Which is made all the more ridiculous because people are criticizing it because it looks like a bad movie. If the marketing behind this is intentional, it's certainly an interesting way to approach it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613132307.0" user="RemoveKebabz" delta="False">
    <text>Oh it's more than interesting, it's straight up brilliant. 

It accomplishes several things with an extremely low cost (relatively speaking).

1. Critics will not feel free to express an honest opinion for fear of attacks (see 4). 

2. Consumers are extorted into seeing it and then coerced into liking it if they are asked for fear of attacks. 

3. Draws in a demo not usually interested in sci fi, militants feminists. 

4. 3s will feel obligated to take to social media/rating sites and praise it to the heavens regardless of merit. They will also perpetuate the attacks on any 1s or 2s that don't praise it to the heavens. 

Virtue signaling in consumerism is nothing new but a campaign saying someone is bad for not liking your product, I've never seen it outside of politics and to a very limited extent maternity/infant items (edit also certain prestige foods/coffees use this too. Edit 2 duh of courses religions) and if it works expect a lot more of it. 

We are watching it closely. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613497945.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "watch and like this film or you are a woman hater."

Fascinating theory, honestly, but I can't really make sense of it. If the plan is to alienate viewers on purpose, it wouldn't look like it would bring more ticket sales, quite the contrary. Am I missing something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28630576185.0" user="JurijFedorov" delta="False">
    <text>Their goal is to make you talk about it. Yes, it did alienate viewers but so does all trailers. If it's an romantic movie I won't watch it, or if it's a racist movie I don't want to watch it, if it's an pro-America movie some people won't like it, all movies alienate. I think their goal is to make it such an important movie discussion wise that a lot of people will watch it because they have heard of it. Just like playing Pokémon Go is important to understand what people are doing right now. And they also plan on persuading a few reviewers to give it a really good review just for the marketing alone. It's a brilliant tactic no doubt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613690926.0" user="hashtagwindbag" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As to the quality of the movie I have heard it's truly awful and blatant man bashing throughout.

SPOILER ALERT IF YOU CARE

There would be death threats handed out like candy if the main villain were female and was defeated by being shot in the genitalia. But the main villain is male, so Defeat By Genital Assault is okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28615614312.0" user="lifeonthegrid" delta="False">
    <text>RoboCop. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613743357.0" user="shotpun" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's a fascinating campaign. Truly revolutionary. The campaign (at least the social media viral part) boils down to, "watch and like this film or you are a woman hater." It's basically identity politics style marketing for a film and *I am really interested to see how it works out.*

Being a marketing major looks like it's ruined your worldview. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613828800.0" user="Likewhatevermaaan" delta="False">
    <text>How would alienating your audience like that help your profits? Hollywood puts money first like every other business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613835585.0" user="Randolpho" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, I'm going to need some evidence. The only marketing I've seen is posters and trailers, and talk show appearances, but I'm not aware of any other marketing on the subject, so feel free to provide any additional marketing material that supports your claim. 

The thing is... of what I've seen, *nothing* suggests "watch this or you're a woman hater", *at* ***all***. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28630585016.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28630566598.0" user="JurijFedorov" delta="False">
    <text>People are talking about the movie. But we should be talking about the marketing. It's amazing. Whether you hate or love the movie the marketing have been so good that it is on par with Blair Witch project as the best movie marketing in my lifetime.

Fant4stick did the same thing with "the black guy in the movie and racists" marketing. But it was not really as effective or well thought out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
