<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28612895518.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>Well, check out [this](http://fusion.net/story/276398/ghostbusters-trailer-backlash-sexist-comments/) article.

It's clearly, well, I'll let you decide for yourself.

However, my main point is this - look at the comment section they posted.

"This movie sucks" posts are put right next to comments like "psshht, female scientists yeah right" 

Complaining about a movie being bad isn't the same as hating the movie for being an all female cast, but this website is an example of people who can't seem to differentiate the two. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612901174.0" user="MisandryOMGguize" delta="False">
    <text>I saw two, maybe three comments in that whole list that were complaining about things other than women/SJWs, and one of those was still ridiculously vitriolic. Also, I would point out that the very first line seems to differentiate the "baby men" from those who merely dislike or are neutral on the film.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612903606.0" user="CherrySlurpee" delta="False">
    <text>But my point is those comments are listed right next to complaints about women.

Those complaining aren't able to differentiate "this movie sucks" and "women suck" </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613185033.0" user="jacenat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I would point out that the very first line seems to differentiate the "baby men" from those who merely dislike or are neutral on the film.

I hope you aren't serious in endorsing this stereotyping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613201747.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>stereotyping of whom? Like he said, it's not saying 'everyone who dislikes this is a baby man'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613288479.0" user="jacenat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; stereotyping of whom?

By the author. "Baby men" is toxic stereotyping in the same way as feminazi is, regardless of how small the group the author trying to pin this on is. You are still creating a group who's opinions don't matter. Throwing people arbitrarily in that group is the way it actually becomes dangerous. And since it's such a vague, baseless stereotype, throwing people in is pretty easy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614192137.0" user="CapitanBanhammer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it's not saying 'everyone who dislikes this is a baby man'.

It actually did say just that. It said:

&amp;gt;Some people like. Some people love. Some people whatever. But baby-men, they no like. Baby-men no like at all. 

The article gives no room to dislike the movie without being called baby-men. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613460688.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613802817.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry AlphaBetaOmegaGamma, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 3\. "Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view. If you are unsure whether someone is genuine, ask clarifying questions (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting ill behaviour, please message us." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Removed+Comment+Rule+3+Post+Appeal&amp;amp;message=AlphaBetaOmegaGamma+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/d57prkg\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614134252.0" user="MegaMetal96" delta="False">
    <text>just look at that username.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28612961664.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>Are people actually saying this? If that's the case then there needs to be a clear distinction between the two.

Disliking the movie for trying to push a feminist agenda onto an already established franchise for no real reason other than to push a feminist agenda is a fair argument to me.

Disliking the movie because it's a movie with females/female scientists is not OK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613146613.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by "feminist agenda?" I assure you, there wasn't some group of maniacal, man hating women trying to get this movie made because they believe it will some how further a feminist cause.  I'm just curious what would count as a feminist agenda really.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613164398.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>Trying to insert females into a movie to appeal to feminists for no other reason than for the appeal.

Bonus points when you replace an established male character with a female.

I'm willing to be convinced. Why would you replace the established, iconic Ghostbusters cast with a group of 4 female stereotypes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613182667.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>Because it has the potential to reach a potentially lucrative market that went previously untapped. The way I see it, the movie was most likely made because they thought it would make money. Sure, the movie obviously appeals to more women, but it's like that because women also spend money on movie tickets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613195505.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>They're splitting their fanbase this way though. They're turning an iconic franchise into a cash grab, alienating their previous fanbase, and probably not being a good enough movie to attract any new fans.

If they wanted to make a movie to appeal to women, then make a new franchise to appeal to women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613206789.0" user="Dinaverg" delta="False">
    <text>That seems to be just your personal view of it 'alienating, not good enough', etc. rather than the actual result. Reviews are mixed, it's a perfectly average movie that will probably make some money. That's more than enough reason for a studio to do it, no agenda necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613237756.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>Feminist agenda probably came out a bit worse than what I meant. I meant that by by appealing to women, it has a detrimental effect to the franchise, and alienates the original fans.

I guess what I'm saying is, if you want to make a movie that appeals to women, it should be its own movie. If anything, this means that a female-centric movie needs an established male cast to rely on in order to succeed.

Financially, I know I'm pulling this out of my ass, but I would eat a ghost if this movie made more money than a movie with the original cast.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613219880.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>I don't man, I'm not in the movie production biz or anything, but there are probably people with the sole job of weighing what type of movies will make money. They probably tested it out, and figured out that the influx of women outweighed the loss of die hard fans. If the movie was presented due to some feminist agenda though, I'm sure it would have been canned if they figured that the movie would crash. So maybe, just maybe, someone down the line, maybe a writer or something, could have potentially written the script because he wanted people to realize his or her feminist dream, but that wasn't the reason it got produced and pushed out to the public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613240785.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>And Hollywood gets it wrong more often that they get it right.

Feminist agenda was probably a bit too strong a word than what I meant. But replacing an entire male cast with a female cast has a definite feminist tone to it, you'd be lying if you denied that (which I don't think you are). I just think that should serve as its own movie.

Also Ghostbusters is an iconic movie, it would've made a killing if the original cast returned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613341988.0" user="Jrook" delta="False">
    <text>It would have been lambasted by fans in the same way Indiana Jones and the crystal skull was</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613359071.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>So what? It would've made a killing. We're discussing solely about financial benefits, because everyone seems to agree that this is a cash grab.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613262417.0" user="RagBagUSA" delta="False">
    <text>This is an issue with Hollywood at large. Everything now is a soulless cash-grab, a sequel, a gritty reboot, everything is just shitting on existing IPs and alienating their original fanbase.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613267388.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>See, I'd buy this narrative over the feminist agenda narrative. Hollywood is, I assume, in the business of making money, primarily.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613290132.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you think they aren't tied together? Hollywood is pushing this all female cast to appeal to women, which in turn makes them more money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613323877.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly? Pushing a movie at women is not tantamount to pushing a feminist agenda. Pushing a feminist agenda would need someone pushing the movie to do so with the intent of spreading feminism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613340541.0" user="Jrook" delta="False">
    <text>Uh... was the original movie not supposed to make money? 


"they're turning an iconic cash grab into a cash grab"

If we reword your statement to reflect reality it doesn't make a lot of sense </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613471084.0" user="sassycatty" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what a cash grab movie is though. Reality would be what was stated. This new ghost busters *is a cash grab*. 

Reason why is because the original was a huge risk that ended up making some decent money. Hard to call something a cash grab when so much risk revolves around it. But some movie have much less implied risk because they are simply trying to feed off of the original fanbase. 

Loses meaning if you just apply it to anything that aims to make money..
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613603491.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They're turning an iconic franchise into a cash grab, alienating their previous fanbase, and probably not being a good enough movie to attract any new fans.

Hey now, Ghostbusters 2 came out in 1989.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613255478.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>What untapped market? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613264356.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>Normal ghost busters reboot gets ghost buster fans. Ghost busters reboot with famous cast of women get some ghost busters fans and potentially a lot of women who may or may not have cared about ghost busters in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613266238.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone is a fan of ghostbusters. A lot of ghostbusters fans are not going to see this movie 

The idea is just a stupid gimmick</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613271495.0" user="butt4nice" delta="False">
    <text>A gimmick aimed at making money, no? And not everyone is into ghostbusters. It's an older movie that kind of faded with a lackluster sequel. I enjoy it, but maybe the older fan base wasn't good enough to make enough money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613325352.0" user="fly19" delta="False">
    <text>I've actually heard the argument that just like how the original Ghostbusters were unappreciated in their field before starting the company, women in scientific roles seem to face similar levels of under-representation and ostracization. Creating an underdog parallel between both groups is not a half-bad idea.

The stereotype bit is much less-defensible, though I can't comment much because I haven't seen the movie myself.

EDIT: Got it, don't comment unless you're shitting on a movie you haven't seen yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613528730.0" user="bbraithwaite83" delta="False">
    <text>Re to the stereotype thing. I would say that the original characters were male stereotypes in their own right. Nerdy guy, over confident cocky guy, token cool black guy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28615611198.0" user="lifeonthegrid" delta="False">
    <text>Because Paul Feig likes working with female comedians and has done so to great success. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613231242.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>Is it the fact that it's already an established franchise or is it the feminist agenda? Because I don't really see why encouraging women to be scientists is something people should be angry about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613256023.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>You think this movie is encouraging women to be scientists?

lol </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613279363.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>When somebody says the word scientist, a vast majority of people instantly think of a man. Movies that show women scientists/CEOs/doctors/etc. can help to lessen the effect of that unconscious bias. The comment above said that it is ok to dislike the movie for trying to push this "feminist agenda." I was curious why that would be a bad thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613294521.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, that's ridiculous. Maybe you think that way, but I don't think most people do

More women (*than men) have been graduating with advanced Science degrees for decades. They are well represented </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613341568.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking purely from personal experience, the image that first pops into people's heads when you say the word scientist is that of a man. That may not be the case with you and I applaud you for that, but I don't think it's "ridiculous" to say that it's common.

I didn't know that about the science degrees that's good to hear. However, many other fields are still very male dominated, so a "feminist agenda" should still be pushed. Maybe this specific movie focused on the wrong field, but that doesn't mean that having a feminist message is inherently detrimental to a movie. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613348837.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>What fields are male dominated?

Does every field need to be female dominated?

Women have been earning more college degrees for 30+ years

Naerly 60% of all degrees, that is including every degree type, from associates up to Phd, go to women now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613533840.0" user="bbraithwaite83" delta="False">
    <text>Can you show some facts here. You're spitting out 'stats' with out showing proof. U just can't take your argument seriously</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613582856.0" user="yggdrasils_roots" delta="False">
    <text>Not who you were responding to, but:

From 1999–2000 to 2009–10, the percentage of degrees earned by females remained between approximately 60 and 62 percent for associate's degrees and between 57 and 58 percent for bachelor's degrees. In contrast, the percentages of both master's and doctor's degrees earned by females increased from 1999–2000 to 2009–10. Within each racial/ethnic group, women earned the majority of degrees at all levels in 2009–10. For example, among U.S. residents, Black females earned 68 percent of associate's degrees, 66 percent of bachelor's degrees, 71 percent of master's degrees, and 65 percent of all doctor's degrees awarded to Black students. Hispanic females earned 62 percent of associate's degrees, 61 percent of bachelor's degrees, 64 percent of master's degrees, and 55 percent of all doctor's degrees awarded to Hispanic students.

[Source.](https://nces.ed.gov/fastfacts/display.asp?id=72)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614092846.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.aei.org/publication/stunning-college-degree-gap-women-have-earned-almost-10-million-more-college-degrees-than-men-since-1982/

https://nces.ed.gov/fastfacts/display.asp?id=72

I honestly don't understand how anyone isn't aware of this issue?

I remember discussing this in middle school back in the late 90s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614194888.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>By fields I meant things like members of congress or CEOs where women are still a very small minority. And no ideally there would be no occupations in which one gender dominates unless there's an actual biological reason such as construction workers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614200437.0" user="Theige" delta="False">
    <text>As far as I've been taught that's just going to take time

CEOs, and especially congress people, are pretty old and were born a long time ago when things were different </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613306483.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>For trying to push an agenda to the detriment of an established franchise? Yes. The main point of a film should be to tell a story with interesting characters. You can have feminist undertones, sure. But when it's so heavy handed like this, you can tell it was an explicit direction to pursue this type of movie, it becomes preaching, and no one likes preaching.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613333382.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>Was the agenda a detriment? I haven't seen the movie yet so it is possible that they spend a lot of the movie blatantly preaching. However, from what I've seen of the previews, the only form of agenda pushing was casting women as lead roles. The fact that so many people are equating "women in lead roles" to "movie ruined by feminist agenda" is exactly why the "agenda" needs to be pushed. If they made a shitty movie, then they made a shitty movie. If you think they made a shitty movie because they cast women, then you're proving my point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613357701.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>It's not because they cast women, it's because they prioritised an agenda or idealogy before creating a quality film. For all I know, this movie might be miles better than all of the Ghostbusters and I'll have to eat my words.

But history does say that these sorts of movies that seek to pander to a certain ideology or movement, are usually less than good.

I am not saying that this movie will be bad because the cast are women, I'm saying the movie will be bad because they decided to cast actors solely because they are *women*. The fact that they are women is not the problem, it's that they pushed an agenda before creating a decent film. Again, I may be wrong; this film might be the best of the year for all I know.

&amp;gt; women in lead roles" to "movie ruined by feminist agenda" is exactly why the "agenda" needs to be pushed

I never said this. I'm all for more women in lead roles, as long as it feels organic and the writing is good. What I said was that people are saying that replacing an established male casts with a female cast is primarily because of a feminist agenda. And the problem with that is that it becomes propaganda instead of a narrative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614202092.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>Alright that's reasonable. I didn't see it from that perspective sorry about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613554125.0" user="BrellK" delta="False">
    <text>From both positive and negative reviews, apparently every single male character is either a complete idiot or an asshole. Unlike the original films that had strong female characters, this movie has no male characters with redeeming qualities (apparently).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614204512.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>Oh well that's different then. I agree that that's a problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613708564.0" user="hunkE" delta="False">
    <text>The reason was to make money, not "push a feminist agenda".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613909517.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>Their reason was to make money *by* pushing a feminist agenda</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613917703.0" user="hunkE" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. These execs aren't feminists - they're *pandering* to feminists. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613922563.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>So that makes it even worse? Not only are they pushing a feminist agenda onto an established franchise, they are making a mockery of issue for a quick cash grab?

Your argument doesn't make the fact it was needlessly pushed any worse, you make it better by stating the butcher the movement by putting it up for a quick buck. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613932726.0" user="hunkE" delta="False">
    <text>Kinda?

I wouldn't say they're actually pushing a feminist agenda though. They're pandering to the feminist agenda. If anything they're setting it back by creating backlash for profit. 

And there is no such thing as "needless" in the entertainment industry. You're holding the industry to much too high of a standard. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613973979.0" user="frezz" delta="False">
    <text>Pandering seems to be a better word for what I was trying to say. We both seem to agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613992974.0" user="hunkE" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I think we're on the same page. I just take issue with the idea that these movie execs are "pushing feminism". If anything they're exploiting it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614118674.0" user="redpandaeater" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, so that's what it would look like if a Reddit shitpost became a news article.  The thing I don't understand is even if the movie looked like it would be good, can't we still attack the film for going in a completely different direction with a fully female crew and apparent man hate?  I mean some of the articles I've seen about this movie blast male reviewers because this film clearly targets women.  I wouldn't have a problem with that if it wasn't a Ghostbusters film or if it still tried to include men, but it doesn't.  They've taken a classic series that tended to have a male audience, stripped out everything that made it good, then added in a completely female cast instead of a mixed cast.  It has a completely different target audience than the originals while trying to draw upon its namesake, and that's just completely wrong regardless of how good or shitty of a movie it is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
