<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613305423.0" user="JesusDeSaad" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism.

I've been branded a sexist and misogynist by at least three separate people because:

- They posted on fb how sexists and misogynists should shut the fuck up about Ghostbusters, and they should allow normal people to enjoy the movie.

- All non-sexists and non-misogynists like the movie. Even before it came out.

- I saw this stuff on top of my fb wall because some friend liked this drivel.

- I interjected that "I don't like being called this stuff just because I won't go to see the movie, because I found the trailers bland and i can't afford to pay for mediocre movies. Even though I'm a big fan of McCarthy and the other actresses. Please don't cram everyone up in a pile of horrible names just because they disagree."

- "Yeah that's what you all say. we took your precious guy flick and made it better, enjoy those salty tears you fucking misogynist." and other messages of that caliber.

At least three separate accounts on facebook. One of them even blocked me and then posted shit about me, calling me a "toxic misogynist who just like to sped time raging against the femal sex" (sic)

________________________________________

And that's just personal experience. It's been proven that the trailer mods on Youtube (or whatever they're called) took down comments criticizing the quality of the trailers, and left the misogynist and sexist comments. Why would they do that, to push a specific narrative? I know enough of the media world and the background happenings behind this particular movie to say yes.
__________________________________________

Actual feminists? That just sounds like a No True Scotsman fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613412718.0" user="Sergnb" delta="False">
    <text>On the brightside, you are no longer friends with those psychopaths, so there's that to be happy about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613625473.0" user="DiscoshirtAndTiara" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source on them removing comments from the trailers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613631861.0" user="JesusDeSaad" delta="False">
    <text>Did you even bother googling it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614035493.0" user="DiscoshirtAndTiara" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and I didn't see anything that looked reliable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614084632.0" user="JesusDeSaad" delta="False">
    <text>[Well never let it be said i never served what lazy people expect on a silver platter.](http://imgur.com/S8qFMZ0)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614375225.0" user="DiscoshirtAndTiara" delta="False">
    <text>That looks like pretty much the same results I got. The articles that I read indicated that Sony was focusing on removing the misogynistic comments which is the opposite of what you're saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28614884894.0" user="JesusDeSaad" delta="False">
    <text>source. Unless hearsay is A-OK for you...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
