<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="289297036.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4s8n0s/cmv_the_idea_that_anyone_criticizing_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Idea that Anyone Criticizing the Ghostbusters remake will be branded a misogynist is a fabrication, motivated by people's desire to feel persecuted by feminists.</title>
    <original_poster>MisandryOMGguize</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, as you may be aware, the new remake of Ghostbusters, a movie surrounded by controversy, has been released to critics, and reviews are beginning to come in. The reviews are decidedly mixed, the top critics catalogued by RottenTomatoes.com are split 6 to 7 on whether it's fresh or rotten, with the rest of the critics generally being more positive. 

Reddit of course has an interesting history with this movie, which largely consists of a circlejerk every time it's brought up about feminism, SJWs and political correctness. This has not changed since the movie was released, with people in every review thread talking about how anyone that positively reviews the film must be a feminist, or be terrified of the feminist backlash for being critical of it. [This](http://imgur.com/a/fKRXP) is currently one of the top posts on the ghostbusters sub.

I've not seen any actual feminists claiming any and all criticism must be rooted in sexism. I've seen feminists saying that the immediate backlash to a female cast, dismissing it as political correctness, etc is sexism, but never the idea that any criticism is sexist. In fact, most of the feminists I've seen are fairly mixed, thinking the trailers weren't that funny, and that the black character's position in the crew plays on racial stereotypes.

So, I'm pretty sure that most of this is just reddit being reddit and jerking itself off about how edgy it is to go against the "feminist agenda," but I'd kind of like to believe I'm wrong, and that I ought to have more faith in people, so CMV. Have there been people being slandered just for not liking the film? Is there some vast feminist conspiracy to censor people who don't like the movie, and have any of the people writing the negative reviews faced this? Since I'm sure this topic has been discussed before, I'm also interested if anything has changed since the actual reviews were released.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28613378477.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>Most people know that the "you don't like what I like? Bigot!!" Crowd is small, but it is extremely vocal. There will be people out there (from all political leanings) who will say that anyone who dislikes the new ghostbusters is sexist or racist or whatever. And those few people will attempt to brand "everyone" a racist or sexist. 

This is the Internet age, and unfortunately it gives extremists on all sides a voice. I'm sure there will be people pushing the idea of "you liked that flick? Racist!". 

The motivation on both sides will undoubtably be attention, not persecution. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613812473.0" user="IgnisDomini" delta="False">
    <text>But the problem is that people love to pretend that "if you don't like it you're a misogynist!" is the only thing the movie's supporters (or even just people who don't rabidly hate it) have to say in its defense.

It's the same as always - people on reddit have people who they disagree with, go out of their way to find examples of stupid people among that group, then hold up those few examples as representative of the entire group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28613865533.0" user="robeph" delta="False">
    <text>People mistake the low numbers as less problematic.  The problem is not one solely of quantity,  but of quality.   

When you have a large contingent of contemporary  media outlets (web) with totals well over 100 million views across numerous news organizations,  the saturation and exposure to this type of view in an attempt to push it mainstream is quite a regular.  While even reading such articles (as many published here)  you will be called sexist or racist if you disagree with the article's contents, almost invariably as it is one of the most common elements of the article.   

Now were it just a few no name twitter SJWs,  no one would care,  no one would cry foul.   It isn't.  It's heavily trafficked and followed web news writers and bloggers,  HuffPo,  Vice,  DailtDot,  Jezebel,  and Daily Beast, just to name a few of the worse offenders,  but we can include major outlets like Time and others as many of their writers hold similar lean, albeit much more conservative in their presentation.   .   This is why even if they're a low quantized  number of total people,  their voice carries to millions.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
