<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28637108182.0" user="Pleb-Tier_Basic" delta="False">
    <text>Why not both?

Most BLM movements are intersectionalist; they argue that there is a network of potential identities a person can have that will advantage them or disadvantage them. These identities intersect, interact with each other, or cancel each other out depending on the particular context an individual is in.

For example, a rich black man may be able to leverage his wealth to push poor people out of a neighbourhood, even if it does fuck over poor black people. That same fact, however, wouldn't protect him if he were to come face-to-face with a poor Klansmen. You can see in this example how his wealth is a factor in some situations and gives advatage, while in other situations his race is more important</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637154055.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>You'll have to elaborate as I'm not quite sure I am grasping your point.

I'm not sure how your example relates to what I said originally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637206640.0" user="tit_wrangler" delta="False">
    <text>He's saying it's possible for there to be a class war and for socioeconomic issues to be truly important, while *also* acknowledging systemic racism that compounds the issue for certain demographics as well. In other words, there's no such thing as a single issue that exists in a societal vacuum. Race issues don't need to "distract" from class issues if we can accept that they both exist and, for a significant portion of people, they overlap into more complex issues, such as people of color facing obstacles to upward social mobility. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637237686.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>Okay thanks, that clarifies things a bit.

I apologize if it seems like I am trying to devalue the importance of racial issues. I am not trying to say they don't exist. Only that those issues create a convenient smokescreen for those with a vested interest in quelling the idea that a class war exists. The same reason why we hear more in the news about Islamic extremism than we ever do about corrupt bankers and politicians; It is an easy way to shift the focus from what I see to be the underlying issue onto another issue. It seems to me that a large portion of systemic racial issues are rooted in classism. It isn't about the color of your skin or the beliefs you hold, instead it is about whether or not you have money or assets. If you are poor and an islamic extremist then you are a terrorist and you cannot be negotiated with. If you are rich and an islamic extremist you are a political ally and on the UN human rights council.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637866572.0" user="Outofmyelephant" delta="False">
    <text>I would say what you are saying is becoming more true in modern society. In the past, simply being black would mean you wouldn't be accepted at many of the places rich people gather, nowadays the rich are becoming less shocked by the minorities so there isn't the same racial divide, or rather it's a smaller one. 

So I would agree that it's always be a class war, just in the past the racial issues aligned nicely with the class war to further screw over all minorities, that racial issue is lessening, but is still there.

Definitely still both going on, but the class war is the one that will stick around longer I would bet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28639556393.0" user="Ragark" delta="False">
    <text>If race issues are a smokescreen for class issues, they're a very bad one as race issue movements have also leas to very many becoming class conscious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637795878.0" user="Pleb-Tier_Basic" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that both class and race ultimarely matter, it isn't one or the other and your class position won't necessarily protect you from racism and vice versa</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638543806.0" user="Samuelgin" delta="False">
    <text>what is this, a game of chess? him being rich protects him from poor black people but it won't from a poor klansman? so he's safe from the bishop but the rook can still get him? does the poor klansman automatically arrive somewhere if a rich black guy moves in?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28639044600.0" user="Pleb-Tier_Basic" delta="False">
    <text>I mean you're taking a pretty literal read of what I was getting at. My point was that wealth influences some situations, race others, and they both influence each other. You can be the richest person on the continent, but that can't change the colour of your skin. Look at president Obama: despite releasing his long-form birth certificate *and* getting re-elected *and* winning a Nobel prize *and* having a mostly run-of-the-mill presidency, there is still people out there that are convinced he is a Muslim from Africa hell-bent on destroying the US. Is Obama perfect? No. But he isn't any worse than anyone who came before him and yet (some) people act like he is literally the anti-Christ. Why? Because he is not white. 

&amp;gt;poor klansman automatically arrive...

Also as an aside, yes this has literally happened throughout American history. Prior to the civil rights movement Klansmen would ride out to kill black people. During desegregation middle-class families that moved into white neighbourhoods would often be greeted with burning crosses. Neo-nazis and racists skinheads became huge in the 80s and 90s and many attempted to "police" their neighbourhoods. Etc etc

Maybe it's not like there is a magic force propelling these groups together but plenty of powerful black people have been murdered by racists, and the reality is that being middle class or even rich isn't perfect protection</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
