<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28641609006.0" user="IndianPhDStudent" delta="False">
    <text>The Jews were rich (or at least perceived to be rich). That didn't stop them from being hated, in fact, it increased hatred towards them even more. Jews became "soul-less money-grabbers" and "parasites".

Same thing with Asian and Indian immigration and "stealing our jobs". People keep talking about how rich Chinese and Indians are "very cunning and selfish", or "too controlling/uptight", or "very rude towards servers and workers / too arrogant about money".

Even when some black people came out of the gutters and became rich rappers and actors, people still hated them for "not having class". They were hated for being "noveau rich", "showing off their wealth by wearing gold chains" or taking about "new cars and hoes". 

The dominant group hates immigrants when they're poor. The dominant group hates immigrants EVEN MORE when they are rich.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
