<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28637154689.0" user="18529630741" delta="False">
    <text>What incentive does the media have to make a coordinated attempt to distract the entire US population? Since they're in competition, why doesn't say CNN try to get the scoop first? Why doesn't any independent media source report on the real story? Why don't media sources outside of the US report on this real conspiracy? There are just way too many holes in this theory for it to be plausible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637175208.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What incentive does the media have to make a coordinated attempt to distract the entire US population?

Not necessarily the entire US population. Just enough so that it is easy to control elections and hold legislative power. 

&amp;gt; Since they're in competition, why doesn't say CNN try to get the scoop first?

CNN and other national news sources are owned by large corporations that have a vested interest in drawing attention away from class warfare. All news sources are biased in some way. 

&amp;gt; Why doesn't any independent media source report on the real story?

There are. Noam Chomsky has been talking about it for years. Warren Buffet talked about class warfare. Terence McKenna, Joe Rogan and many others report on the idea of class warfare. The deregulation of financial markets has been happening for decades. It has provided power for the super elite while gouging the livelihoods of millions of average people. It could be used as an example of class warfare.

&amp;gt; Why don't media sources outside of the US report on this real conspiracy?

They do. It isn't even a conspiracy. It is happening in plain site. Banks and corporations are richer than ever because they have systemically rigged the system through lobbying and deregulation so that poor people are at a severe disadvantage economically, despite the infrastructure of the global economy not working without average people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638386527.0" user="jdw1066" delta="False">
    <text>And to add (although I disagree with OP's original post), there are plenty of media sources outside of the US who report on this "conspiracy". Just read RT, or Telesur, or even Al-Jazeera. Of course, we dismiss everything they say as propaganda. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637805651.0" user="DeathDevilize" delta="False">
    <text>Because the media wants money, and most people are going to watch media no matter what they claim, so if they listen to the rich people and get money from them they end up with more than the small gain from being actually comptetent journalists. 

Also, not doing as powerful people say gets you easily killed pretty much everywhere and the US is no exception. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
