<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28639698957.0" user="Trenks" delta="False">
    <text>This is why some prominent black social leaders, like Jim Brown, think black lives matters isn't the right way to go about things. He's not anti, he says if people want to go out and protest, that's fine (though he struggled when asked 'what their end goal' is because it's so poorly defined). But he says the biggest thing that would stop this is blacks getting jobs in inner cities so that they'd stop black on black violence (which we don't like to hear, but is a way higher proportion than police on black violence) which would also stop police violence. Police don't patrol where there ain't violence. 

So we need to clean up drug laws and get people to work in urban communities. That would stop a lot of racial tension.... That and if cops would stop shooting unarmed black dudes. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
