<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28637873371.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>Hypothetically (and I know you won't agree with this but follow with me a minute) what if we lived in a pure meritocracy: the smart and hardworking got rich, the stupid and lazy were poor.  In that society you would expect the poor (being stupid and lazy) to try and settle their disputes violently in the streets, while you would expect the rich to settle their disputes through courts or other means and not risk their lives (and going to jail for life) on some stupid dispute leading to gun play.  

Now the reality of our society is that some poor people are smart and hard-working, and some rich people are stupid and lazy, but there is a correlation between income and intelligence / dedication.  Also even within wealth strata there are different levels and a low income person who is smart and hard working is going to be much better off than one who is not.

And so let me ask you this... when was the last time you heard about anyone smart who resolved their dispute by going into the street with a gun?

Now this isn't to minimize the social problems we have.  If I was a black, inner city, 20 something I would be angry with a lot of things (one of which would be policing).  However you know where I would be marching carrying a sign that says "Black Lives Matter"?  Outside of school board head offices.  The US education system is SYSTEMICALLY failing black children and ruining their lives.  It is absolutely outragious.  It is deliberate (teacher's unions keeping bad teachers in classrooms knowing they are bad and hurting 30 kids every single year).  And it isn't tolerated in white communities (and in part this is because black voters loyally vote democrat who are in the teacher's union's pocket.  It is good to switch up government regularly so no one interest group gets to root too deeply). 

You know what I would be protesting next?  The federal government's war on drugs.  You take a young black man with his whole future ahead of him and you ruin his job prospects, you take away his ordinary social connections and you replace them with criminal associations, you take away years of productive job experience, and you financially cripple him, because he likes to get high occasionally.   There is a black man who's life matters!

So I do agree with you, the BLM movement is attacking the wrong target at the moment.  But this also isn't about rich vs. poor...  This is about a system that is so ineffective at each step that even though it is designed to help people, it ends up manufacturing social problems that finally manifest in a politically captivating way with unarmed black men being shot by police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638028904.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And so let me ask you this... when was the last time you heard about anyone smart who resolved their dispute by going into the street with a gun?

&amp;gt; The US education system is SYSTEMICALLY failing black children and ruining their lives. It is absolutely outragious. It is deliberate

I think those two points go hand in hand. 

&amp;gt; But this also isn't about rich vs. poor... This is about a system that is so ineffective at each step that even though it is designed to help people

A system that is curated by the rich. The people in the upper class who control legislation (there are no "poor" career politicians) do so in favor of those who are already rich while misusing funds that are specifically meant to help the poor. This is seen with education funding to an alarming degree. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638035779.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>So lets protest schools and actually have a competitive two party system vying for reform proposals.  The solution isn't to attack the rich, it is to deal with the one party political monopoly that has allowed this problem to fester within it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638046298.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So lets protest schools

What do you mean lets protest schools?

&amp;gt; The solution isn't to attack the rich, it is to deal with the one party political monopoly that has allowed this problem to fester within it.

How do you "deal" with a political monopoly that is backed by corporations that seem capable of corrupting that vast majority of politicians?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
