<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28639171230.0" user="Torchonium" delta="False">
    <text>I think discrimination lead to class differences. Class differences lead to discrimination.

Let me make a though experiment of two planets:

Planet A has two groups of Aliens. Big Ears and Small Ears.  It happened to be that Big Ears are in the majority. The Big Ears admire their Ears and think very little about Small Ears. Having small ears were viewed as abnormal. 
Big Ears preferred each other in any possible way. Giving them better positions and more money. This causes economic and later social problems for Small Ears. 

Planet B have green Noses and red Noses. Both where seen equal at first, with chances open for everybody. After a time it happened to be that red Noses where statistically richer and a few more red Noses where in powerful position than green Noses. People start to notice that, and this view got widely spread. It is especially popular among red Noses. Group thinking quickly emerged. Red Noses accossiate positive attributes to being a Red Nose. Red Nose chefs starts to prefer people with their own Nose color, expecting better work form them. Even if having the same qualifications, being from the same nose group give some sympathy points. Green Noses get fewer and fewer chances for well paid jobs. Being poorer and marginalized causes more social problems. These problems were  associated with the character of the Green Noses, rather than seeing their economic problems as root of those problems. Red Noses now expect problems when dealing with Green Noses, leading to more open resentments. 

For both planets the cycle of class differences and discrimination perpetuates.

Of course this is immensely simplified.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
