<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28637712526.0" user="mitchyboy" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think class struggle is mutually exclusive with race issues and religious tension?

Also, why are you qualified to say what is/ought to be important to others? Maybe class struggle is what matters to you, but to millions (billions?) it's of lesser importance than other issues

Edit. Deleted a bit because op addressed it somewhat in op</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638038188.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why do you think class struggle is mutually exclusive with race issues and religious tension?

I don't. What I am saying is that race issues and religious tension serve as a convenient way for those on the winning side of the class war to shift potential focus away from it. A lot of racial issues would be lessened if we had a more fiscally responsible government that focused on fixing issues for poor people in the country of all colors.

&amp;gt; Also, why are you qualified to say what is/ought to be important to others?

It is my opinion. What qualifies anybody to have an opinion on anything?

&amp;gt; Maybe class struggle is what matters to you, but to millions (billions?) it's of lesser importance than other issues

My whole point is that I feel that class issues if addressed could help to fix a lot of the issues other people find to be more important.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
