<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="292273408.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4u0fls/cmv_we_are_in_the_midst_of_a_class_war_and_racial/">
    <title>CMV: We are in the midst of a class war and racial issues and extremism are sensationalized in the media to draw attention away from it.</title>
    <original_poster>pandar314</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been reading a lot of people talking about how black lives matter is this or that and things like "if black lives matter so much why do they kill each other" and it is just ridiculous to me. The real issue at hand is rich vs poor. You never hear about two rich people of any color shooting at each other in the streets. It would seem to me that the underlying cause of most racial issues and religious extremism is a lack of money and freedom. Rich people fight this war with militaries and legislation. Poor people fight each other because many of them fail to recognize who their enemy is. Convince me otherwise.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28637149029.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>There is no class war just because people are jealous of rich people and feel entitled to their money. 

Poor aren't attacking rich or vice versa, at worst you can say rich/poor are politically divided </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637179304.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>I would disagree. It isn't about jealousy. It is about things like financial deregulation. The systematic dismantling and heavy opposition to workers unions. It is about the rich super elite using money to pay off politicians that will support their agendas. The poor aren't attacking the rich because they are to busy fighting each other. Meanwhile the super rich have been deregulating the financial sector for decades and using false flag operations to start wars across the world. 

It is far beyond a political division.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637882122.0" user="Wrestlingisgood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;false flag 

That's a heavy claim. Do you have any proof from a reliable source? 

Also the poor outnumber the rich by definition, if people were so opposed to deregulation and unionbusting why haven't they been voted out? (And don't say "they voted against their own interests" because you cannot know what every voter's interest is)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638019062.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's a heavy claim. Do you have any proof from a reliable source?

To be fair most false flag operations aren't confirmed until information has been declassified so it is difficult to prove recent "military operations" are false flag operations. Cuba in the 60s was full of false flag operations. Vietnam has confirmed false flag operations. More recently the whole "WMDs in Iraq" could be seen as a blatant false flag operation as a pretext for invading a country that stopped selling oil in the currency we wanted.

&amp;gt; Also the poor outnumber the rich by definition, if people were so opposed to deregulation and unionbusting why haven't they been voted out?

The chairman of the federal reserve is appointed and cannot be voted out. You can't just vote away deregulation when it is largely created by a person who cannot be removed from their position.  Union busting is an ongoing struggle that has been going on since unions have been a thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28637884074.0" user="Bobberfrank" delta="False">
    <text>A few things: workers unions have become overwhelmingly negative. Their purpose to blindly protect the worker benefits no one but the worker. For example, my high school had a teacher who was horrifically awful. Truly the worst teacher you can imagine. The administration's response to us was "she's been here 8 years, the union won't let us do anything." That response is disgusting. I work part time in a unionized industry. I see no need for a union and I refuse to be apart of one, if I have a problem with my employer I'll take it up with my boss, and if the minuscule chance comes that I am unjustly fired, a simple Google search can show me the correct paths of action. Unions protecting bad employees hurts the consumer and company, I see this firsthand. 

Lastly, the financial sector is the most regulated it's ever been. The stock market even has failsafes built in, if it falls 7% trading is halted, then 13% and 20%. Banks are much more hesitant to loan compared to 10 years ago partially due to more regulation, etc etc. Wall st and the financial sector are more regulated than ever. 

Every war has a cause. Iraq decided to sell its oil in euros right before 9/11 and our invasion of Iraq. This forced us to pay about 15% more for oil. As soon as we invaded, they sold it in dollars again. I'd say this benefited the consumer, no? No one enjoys paying more for gas or a bus ticket. There are many military operations we are involved in around the world but I can't think of any wars.

Honestly you sound like a conspiracy theorist. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638002481.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a union worker myself so don't be surprised that I disagree with your assessment. Workers unions do not "blindly" protect workers. They create a more competitive job scene for all people working in that industry. If it weren't for workers unions every right a worker has would be stripped away by companies in the name of profits. There was a man in my union that was fired unjustly by the company I work for because he had a personal disagreement with a member of the non-union staff. It wasn't even related to the job. The union members paid his wages for a year while fighting to have him reinstated and eventually we succeeded. There are two sides to the anecdotal coin.

&amp;gt; For example, my high school had a teacher who was horrifically awful. Truly the worst teacher you can imagine. The administration's response to us was "she's been here 8 years, the union won't let us do anything." That response is disgusting.

Is that response more disgusting than a group of bankers being responsible for a financial collapse that effected the entire world and yet there is no recourse against them? 

&amp;gt; Lastly, the financial sector is the most regulated it's ever been.

Stock market fail safes aren't the same as the market being regulated. Considering Alan Greenspan was notorious for his belief that deregulating the market was the smart thing to do and he helped cause the biggest financial crisis since the 20s, I would have to disagree the financial sector is the most regulated it's ever been. It is more regulated now than 10 years ago maybe, but 20 years of systematic deregulation didn't get overturned in a few years.

&amp;gt; Every war has a cause. Iraq decided to sell its oil in euros right before 9/11 and our invasion of Iraq. This forced us to pay about 15% more for oil. As soon as we invaded, they sold it in dollars again. I'd say this benefited the consumer, no?

I suppose the question is would there have been an invasion if they hadn't stopped selling oil in dollars?

&amp;gt; here are many military operations we are involved in around the world but I can't think of any wars.

You're sort of right. I guess a war insinuates the other side is actually capable of fighting back. If we drop bombs on people it is just a military operation. If someone were to drop bombs on us it would be an act of war.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638061577.0" user="Bobberfrank" delta="False">
    <text>I do agree that unions often do good, but like many organizations, I believe there is a great deal of harm as well. I was focusing on teachers unions and the harmful protection against strikes such as the Andrew Carnagie steel worker strike back in the day. 

Your response to my high school teacher reference is sort of a straw man, I am not talking about the bankers. I am talking about this specific instance involving the teachers union. Please focus on the addressed issue only. 

Your response on regulation seems to contradict itself. If the market is more regulated now than 10 years ago, wouldn't it be the most regulated it's ever been? There was still less regulation pre Greenspan. 

If Iraq had never stopped selling oil in dollars there would still be a decent chance we would have invaded due to 9/11. Doing nothing following an attack of that magnitude would look laughably weak. I was simply stating that the oil issue was a critical part of our invasion. At the time we got much more of our oil from Iraq than we do now, so it was much more serious at the time. 

You are partially correct about the wars, groups like ISIS are very capable of fighting back, however if someone did attack us on US soil that would be an unprecedented move since 9/11 and would most likely constitute an act of war.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28638077482.0" user="pandar314" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Your response to my high school teacher reference is sort of a straw man, I am not talking about the bankers. I am talking about this specific instance involving the teachers union. Please focus on the addressed issue only.

The whole thread is about rich vs poor. Not validity of unions. I was bringing the topic back to where it started.

&amp;gt; There was still less regulation pre Greenspan

Absolutely untrue. Greenspan spent his entire tenure deregulating the market. Hence the housing collapse. Bernanke did what he could to prevent another financial collapse, but he didn't necessarily institute more regulation. Bailing out the banks and allowing them to continue doing exactly what cause the housing collapse isn't exactly regulating the market.

&amp;gt; You are partially correct about the wars, groups like ISIS are very capable of fighting back, however if someone did attack us on US soil that would be an unprecedented move since 9/11 and would most likely constitute an act of war.

Do you not think that dropping bombs and using drones to kill people is not an act of war? Why is it that it is a military operation when we indiscriminately kill people overseas, yet it would constitute an act of war if there was an attack on our soil?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
