<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="293204231.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4ukdtz/cmv_hillary_clinton_does_not_need_bernie_sanderss/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton does not need Bernie Sanders's supporters to win the general election.</title>
    <original_poster>miscellonymous</original_poster>
    <original_post>So many people seem concerned in Democratic Party unity this election, but I'm not convinced that Clinton ever needed to make any concessions to Sanders's supporters. I supported Sanders's general election campaign, but I think we all have an inflated sense of the importance of Sanders's supporters because they tend to be (1) Redditors, so there's an availability bias, (2) loud, and (3) passionate. But that doesn't necessarily matter in terms of overall votes.

Essentially, the number of Sanders's supporters that Clinton could sway by continuing to make concessions to the left are not enough to justify the effort. Sanders's supporters tended to be young people, who do not turn out in large numbers in a general election. People over 30 are more likely to vote, and they tend to be more moderate, so it made perfect sense for Hillary Clinton to pick Tim Kaine, a more moderate vice president, in the hopes of appealing to centrists who are disillusioned with Donald Trump. Clinton would be better served by spending time making her get-out-the-vote case to the groups of people who already support her and dislike the Donald (i.e., women, minorities, and moderate Democrats), and trying to woo moderate Republicans who have been turned off by Trump, than trying to cater to a group of people who are notoriously fickle on election day.

This is based on my general sense of the importance of these groups to the overall electoral map, but I have never studied political science. Seeing concrete numbers would be more likely to convince me than mere rhetoric.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28644948110.0" user="B0000000BS" delta="False">
    <text>You're right that she doesn't *need* Sanders supporters, in that she can theoretically win without any.  If not a lot of people show up to the polls to vote for Trump, and she gets everyone who voted for her in the primary, a fair number of the republicans who voted for Cruz, Kasich, Rubio, or whoever, and a significant number of people who didn't vote in any primary, obviously that would be enough to win in the general election.

However, it's easier for her to win if she gets Sanders supporters to vote for her, and they seem like they should be easier to convince than people who supported Rubio or Cruz, for example.  Sanders supporters generally have similar positions on the issues to Hillary Clinton, so if they're a large block of people who you haven't yet swung to your side, it makes sense to spend some of your limited resources trying to convince them instead of spending your time and money trying to convince people who didn't care enough to vote at all in the primary election or who are Republicans.

I think you're right that a lot of Sanders supporters on reddit are overestimating their "importance" to Clinton.  Pretty much every survey has shown that at least 2/3 of Sanders supporters are willing to vote for Clinton in the general election, so the "Bernie or Bust" crowd is probably a lot smaller than it may appear to be on here.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
