<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="293204231.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4ukdtz/cmv_hillary_clinton_does_not_need_bernie_sanderss/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton does not need Bernie Sanders's supporters to win the general election.</title>
    <original_poster>miscellonymous</original_poster>
    <original_post>So many people seem concerned in Democratic Party unity this election, but I'm not convinced that Clinton ever needed to make any concessions to Sanders's supporters. I supported Sanders's general election campaign, but I think we all have an inflated sense of the importance of Sanders's supporters because they tend to be (1) Redditors, so there's an availability bias, (2) loud, and (3) passionate. But that doesn't necessarily matter in terms of overall votes.

Essentially, the number of Sanders's supporters that Clinton could sway by continuing to make concessions to the left are not enough to justify the effort. Sanders's supporters tended to be young people, who do not turn out in large numbers in a general election. People over 30 are more likely to vote, and they tend to be more moderate, so it made perfect sense for Hillary Clinton to pick Tim Kaine, a more moderate vice president, in the hopes of appealing to centrists who are disillusioned with Donald Trump. Clinton would be better served by spending time making her get-out-the-vote case to the groups of people who already support her and dislike the Donald (i.e., women, minorities, and moderate Democrats), and trying to woo moderate Republicans who have been turned off by Trump, than trying to cater to a group of people who are notoriously fickle on election day.

This is based on my general sense of the importance of these groups to the overall electoral map, but I have never studied political science. Seeing concrete numbers would be more likely to convince me than mere rhetoric.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28644832420.0" user="NaturalSelectorX" delta="False">
    <text>Just look at the primary, there were MILLIONS of people that voted for Sanders. That's enough people to make a difference in many states. 

&amp;gt; Sanders's supporters tended to be young people, who do not turn out in large numbers in a general election.

Those young people who tend to not turn out for elections turned out in large numbers for PRIMARIES. Speaking personally, this is the first primary I ever felt moved to vote in. You can't go by traditional voter demographics, because this is not a traditional election. Young people, for the first time, became politically active for a candidate in large numbers. Either she converts them into new voters, or they become disenfranchised with the party.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28644871977.0" user="miscellonymous" delta="False">
    <text>But now that Clinton is the Democratic candidate, are these young people really going to turn out in large numbers for her even if she embraces more of Sanders's policies? I haven't seen any evidence of that. Maybe she could wiggle the needle a bit, but I doubt it's worth the effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28644890438.0" user="NaturalSelectorX" delta="False">
    <text>Is your view that she doesn't need the supporters, or that she cannot convert the supporters? If she can convert all of the Bernie supporters, then she has a big advantage. If Bernie supporters stay home or vote for other candidates, it hurts her. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28644924377.0" user="miscellonymous" delta="False">
    <text>My view is that she doesn't need the Sanders supporters who haven't already decided to support Clinton because she's the most liberal candidate who can reasonably win, and that it's not worth the time and effort to try to woo those people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28646178028.0" user="Captain_Stairs" delta="False">
    <text>She had an opportunity to woo sanders supporters with her VP pick. Instead, she continued the blue dog trend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28644939497.0" user="lookuppage7" delta="False">
    <text>presumptive Democratic candidate. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
