<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="293204231.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4ukdtz/cmv_hillary_clinton_does_not_need_bernie_sanderss/">
    <title>CMV: Hillary Clinton does not need Bernie Sanders's supporters to win the general election.</title>
    <original_poster>miscellonymous</original_poster>
    <original_post>So many people seem concerned in Democratic Party unity this election, but I'm not convinced that Clinton ever needed to make any concessions to Sanders's supporters. I supported Sanders's general election campaign, but I think we all have an inflated sense of the importance of Sanders's supporters because they tend to be (1) Redditors, so there's an availability bias, (2) loud, and (3) passionate. But that doesn't necessarily matter in terms of overall votes.

Essentially, the number of Sanders's supporters that Clinton could sway by continuing to make concessions to the left are not enough to justify the effort. Sanders's supporters tended to be young people, who do not turn out in large numbers in a general election. People over 30 are more likely to vote, and they tend to be more moderate, so it made perfect sense for Hillary Clinton to pick Tim Kaine, a more moderate vice president, in the hopes of appealing to centrists who are disillusioned with Donald Trump. Clinton would be better served by spending time making her get-out-the-vote case to the groups of people who already support her and dislike the Donald (i.e., women, minorities, and moderate Democrats), and trying to woo moderate Republicans who have been turned off by Trump, than trying to cater to a group of people who are notoriously fickle on election day.

This is based on my general sense of the importance of these groups to the overall electoral map, but I have never studied political science. Seeing concrete numbers would be more likely to convince me than mere rhetoric.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28644834610.0" user="LappenX" delta="False">
    <text>[Total number of votes in the Democratic primary](http://www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2016/president/democratic_vote_count.html)

So roughly 40% of the total votes in the Democratic primary went to Sanders, 60% to Clinton. If she didn't need Sanders supporters to win the Presidential election she'd have to make up for 2/5 of her *potential* votes vanishing by having an according lead over Trump, even though according to [recent polls](http://www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2016/president/us/general_election_trump_vs_clinton-5491.html) *including the votes of Sanders supporters* she is head-to-head with the Trump campaign.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28644866706.0" user="miscellonymous" delta="False">
    <text>But the real question is how many of those Sanders voters would (1) vote for her in the general election because she's the Democratic candidate, or (2) never vote for her in the general election under any circumstances. Once you remove all of them, the number gets much smaller. I don't know how big that number is, but I contend that it isn't a large enough group to try to woo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28646375346.0" user="notduddeman" delta="False">
    <text>the best number I've seen is 80% are willing to roll over to Clinton, but that was only democrats who voted democrat in the last 2 elections.

The worst I've seen is less than 30%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28644911318.0" user="42696" delta="False">
    <text>So roughly 40% of the total votes in the Democratic primary went to Sanders, 60% to Clinton. If she didn't need Sanders supporters to win the Presidential election she'd have to make up for 2/5 of her potential votes vanishing

What your missing is that roughly 10-15% of Democrats vote in primaries, and about 4% in caucuses. Usually over 50% of the voting eligible population votes in a general election. Additionally most Sanders supporters will automatically vote for Hillary purely out of her being the Democratic nominee</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
