<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="294835640.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vjcmw/cmv_bruce_willis_character_in_the_jackal_is_an/">
    <title>CMV: Bruce Willis' character in "The Jackal" is an overpriced and incompetent assassin.</title>
    <original_poster>SpenceNaz88</original_poster>
    <original_post>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Jackal_(1997_film)

If you haven't seen the movie, Bruce Willis is hired to assassinate a politician. He asks for the absurd sum of 70 million dollars. You'd be surprised how little it actually costs to hire a hitman. 

http://priceonomics.com/how-much-does-a-hitman-cost/

An article I read about an undercover cop who posed as a hitman claims that 200,000 dollars was the most he was ever offered with the average being around 25,000. Granted, a high level politician is a much more high-profile target and would likely fetch a premium on the assassin market but 70 million is just too damn much. 

Nonetheless, The Jackal gets his money and then proceeds to do an incredibly sub-par assassination attempt. He starts by purchasing a "Polish ZSU-33 14.5mm" which is a huge heavy machinegun meant to be mounted on armored vehicles and used for shooting down aircraft. I forget the exact amount he paid for it, but I'm pretty sure it was in the tens of millions. He goes through this elaborate routine involving fake moustaches, accents, and passports to smuggle this massive auto-cannon into the country and hires Jack Black to build a electronically controlled mount for the weapon. After the mount is built, Jack Black's character attempts to extort more money out of The Jackal by vaguely suggesting that the extra money is worth his silence. Now, granted this isn't the most ethical thing to do, but he explains that it ended up being more work than expected and the price of some of the materials had gone up. Bruce Willis then brutally murders Jack Black with his crazy death machine which strikes me as a bit of an overreaction.

The whole concept of this device being used for a simple assassination is rediculous. Why can't he just use a rifle with a scope like a normal assassin? You can get a decent deer rifle and a scope for less than a thousand dollars. A heavy machinegun with depleted uranium bullets would make sense of your target was inside an armored vehicle or something but the target is out in the open, in public, making a speech. There's plenty of tall buildings and other vantage points in the area. The fact that the device is controlled remotely using a laptop is just asking for problems. Let's say the electric mount doesn't work, mission failed. The laptop isn't working? Mission failed. Bad WiFi signal? Mission failed. The more steps you add to the process, the more likely something will go wrong.

So, the day of the assassination comes and The Jackal has his remote controlled machinegun mounted in a minivan, and is sitting on a bench controlling the device via laptop computer. And shockingly, something goes wrong. He can't aim the gun properly and screws the whole thing up.

If there's an assassin's version of Yelp, I hope he got a terrible review.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28660840459.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>On the big gun point, [The Blue Goose](http://deadpresidents.tumblr.com/post/34094644/the-blue-goose-and-other-presidential-perks) which is the iconic lectern from which the President speaks, is bulletproof.  Now I understand we're talking about a candidate here, but it's likely that the Secret Service is also having them use a bulletproof lectern since that's in their list of things to do.

That means if you get spotted by the countersniper team, they're going to have the candidate cover behind the lectern, which is a problem if you have an ordinary rifle, but not if you have the crazy mounted machine gun which can rip armor to shreds.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
