<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="294835640.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vjcmw/cmv_bruce_willis_character_in_the_jackal_is_an/">
    <title>CMV: Bruce Willis' character in "The Jackal" is an overpriced and incompetent assassin.</title>
    <original_poster>SpenceNaz88</original_poster>
    <original_post>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Jackal_(1997_film)

If you haven't seen the movie, Bruce Willis is hired to assassinate a politician. He asks for the absurd sum of 70 million dollars. You'd be surprised how little it actually costs to hire a hitman. 

http://priceonomics.com/how-much-does-a-hitman-cost/

An article I read about an undercover cop who posed as a hitman claims that 200,000 dollars was the most he was ever offered with the average being around 25,000. Granted, a high level politician is a much more high-profile target and would likely fetch a premium on the assassin market but 70 million is just too damn much. 

Nonetheless, The Jackal gets his money and then proceeds to do an incredibly sub-par assassination attempt. He starts by purchasing a "Polish ZSU-33 14.5mm" which is a huge heavy machinegun meant to be mounted on armored vehicles and used for shooting down aircraft. I forget the exact amount he paid for it, but I'm pretty sure it was in the tens of millions. He goes through this elaborate routine involving fake moustaches, accents, and passports to smuggle this massive auto-cannon into the country and hires Jack Black to build a electronically controlled mount for the weapon. After the mount is built, Jack Black's character attempts to extort more money out of The Jackal by vaguely suggesting that the extra money is worth his silence. Now, granted this isn't the most ethical thing to do, but he explains that it ended up being more work than expected and the price of some of the materials had gone up. Bruce Willis then brutally murders Jack Black with his crazy death machine which strikes me as a bit of an overreaction.

The whole concept of this device being used for a simple assassination is rediculous. Why can't he just use a rifle with a scope like a normal assassin? You can get a decent deer rifle and a scope for less than a thousand dollars. A heavy machinegun with depleted uranium bullets would make sense of your target was inside an armored vehicle or something but the target is out in the open, in public, making a speech. There's plenty of tall buildings and other vantage points in the area. The fact that the device is controlled remotely using a laptop is just asking for problems. Let's say the electric mount doesn't work, mission failed. The laptop isn't working? Mission failed. Bad WiFi signal? Mission failed. The more steps you add to the process, the more likely something will go wrong.

So, the day of the assassination comes and The Jackal has his remote controlled machinegun mounted in a minivan, and is sitting on a bench controlling the device via laptop computer. And shockingly, something goes wrong. He can't aim the gun properly and screws the whole thing up.

If there's an assassin's version of Yelp, I hope he got a terrible review.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28660536365.0" user="MrPoochPants" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can get a decent deer rifle and a scope for less than a thousand dollars.

Just, on this particular point... no, not really.

If you want an accurate rifle, which an assassin would, and you want to kill someone from father than 100 yards, which is actually quite close, then you're going to need to invest closer to 2, to maybe even 4, grand. I have a very affordable, but very accurate, rifle that, with quality budget options, cost me around 1.1-1.3k, and that's before ammo. Ammo-wise, you'd also want to invest in manually reloading ammo, which comes with the cost of reloading equipment and supplies, and really tailor your round to your rifle for the best possible accuracy.

&amp;gt;A heavy machinegun with depleted uranium bullets would make sense of your target was inside an armored vehicle or something but the target is out in the open, in public, making a speech.

Well, there's also the fact that it might do better at longer ranges. There's a reason that .50 cal rifles are used for their range compared to, say, .308, specifically since the distance he's likely to be shooting at/from will exceed about 1000yds, which is not easy.

&amp;gt;Let's say the electric mount doesn't work, mission failed. The laptop isn't working? Mission failed. Bad WiFi signal? Mission failed. The more steps you add to the process, the more likely something will go wrong.

I'm actually 100% with you on this point. The added advantage of not being AT the point of firing is good, but then you leave all that evidence, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28660567045.0" user="SpenceNaz88" delta="False">
    <text>Lee Harvey Oswald shot JFK with an old surplus Italian Carcano rifle. Those are only 350 bucks right now and probably only like 60 bucks back then. You can get a Remington 700 for 6 or 7 hundred dollars. But yeah, a good custom rifle will cost quite a bit more. Im actually building my first custom rifle right now from a Mauser action. I don't know anything about hand-loading ammo. Is it more accurate than factory stuff?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28660639334.0" user="MrPoochPants" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Lee Harvey Oswald shot JFK with an old surplus Italian Carcano rifle.

Yea, but when was that? Also, just because its 350 NOW doesn't mean that it was equivalently inexpensive THEN, or that they really had many better options, either.

&amp;gt;You can get a Remington 700 for 6 or 7 hundred dollars.

Sure, but the accuracy you're going to get out of that isn't as good as what you'd get from a much more expensive rifle.

I actually own a Tikka T3 Lite, in .308, and it was only like 600 bucks. The optics is often what'll kill you, unless you go with fixed zoom, and even then you'll be dropping some coin still.

&amp;gt;I don't know anything about hand-loading ammo. Is it more accurate than factory stuff?

Its supposed to be because its tailored to your rifle. Factory ammo is a good alternative, but when you start talking about long ranges and extreme ranges, the general consensus is that you basically have to hand-load to get good performance. Everything from how far in the bullet is seated, to how many grains of powder, to the grain, style, and make of the bullet. It gets pretty in depth just on that aspect.

And then there's me who doesn't have the money for all of that...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
