<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28662245405.0" user="Gomzey" delta="False">
    <text>Just for clarification your view is, we should stuff all unwanted unplanned kids in foster care because I don't like abortions? (Also don't understand the articial womb thing??)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662250614.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>The artificial womb thing is that currently the argument for abortion being legal is that we should do it for woman's bodily autonomy. It's a woman's body issue because the fetus is using her body to grow. If we have proper artificial wombs we would be able to let the fetus grow in the artificial womb and she would lose no amount of bodily autonomy (either procedure ends up with the same result of the fetus no longer using her body).

That's not a very good clarification of my view. Personally I'm pro-choice leaning and really do not care way about abortions. I do truly believe the view however. A better clarification would be, "Parental equality, the rights of the unborn child, and women's bodily autonomy will be better served if instead of abortion we switch to utilizing unborn wombs." Foster care is a related, but secondary issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662259587.0" user="Gomzey" delta="False">
    <text>So you believe artificial wombs would make abortions completely unnecessary? The main reason for abortions has nothing to do with bodily autonomy, it's the fact that for whatever reason the parents do not want or are unable to take care of the child, which leads them to the decision that it's better for the child to not be born over having it and struggling with it and it having not such a great life, or simply just not ready for kids in general. Growing the kid in an artificial womb fails to help any of these problems, it just seems like an extra unneeded step to putting a kid in a foster home</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662262956.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that if this was the main issue then it wouldn't be an argument of woman's bodily autonomy. If the main issue was that the parents do not want or are unable to take care of the child, then men would be able to force women to have abortions and/or force women to NOT have abortions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662267178.0" user="Gomzey" delta="False">
    <text>You can't really "force" anyone to do anything though, if a woman wants to have an abortion she will if she doesn't she won't, how exactly would an articial womb help if one of the parents want/don't want an abortion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662272268.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>If the father doesn't want the abortion and we have artificial wombs transfer instead of abortion then the father gets to keep his child. And you can force someone to do something, have them be legally culpable if they don't do it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662288995.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662291104.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>They wouldn't. It would be the same situation if the child was just born. They'd have to give them up for adoption (or if in this hypothetical financial abortion exists they could do that). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662311760.0" user="AgentEv2" delta="False">
    <text>So you believe depriving a child from ever having a life is better than allowing it to live a life that you believe may be shitty? With this argument alone you could justify killing newborns in bad or poor families or killing children in foster care. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662675413.0" user="Gomzey" delta="False">
    <text>This is a pro-life argument, which I don't believe in, I don't think an unborn fetus is anymore deprived of having life than a sperm cell that didn't fertilize an egg is deprived of having life, how is agreeing with having something removed from you body before it becomes a living breathing human being the same as killing living children that already have a life and how are you saying that's justified? Due to your argument I'm guessing you also aren't in favor of euthanasia, which is letting someone die to end their suffering, you would rather this person be held alive and have his life full of complete pain and suffering than just letting them die? Also you're saying you would rather have a family have a kid with severe health issues be born and have a very low quality of life rather than the parents have an abortion and avoiding putting themselves and the child through that type of life. This argument is equalizes an unborn thing to a living child which is not very practical, I am all for a child that is already born having the best possible life that they can have regardless of their circumstances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28666031711.0" user="AgentEv2" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think an unborn fetus is anymore deprived of having life than a sperm cell that didn't fertilize an egg is deprived of having life,

But a sperm cell will never create a human, a fetus will. If I believe that throwing away pizzas is immoral then throwing away cheese or dough isn't immoral but throwing away a pre-cooked pizza is. I'll concede that this is largely a matter of perspective but nonetheless that's the way I see it. 

&amp;gt; you would rather this person be held alive and have his life full of complete pain and suffering than just letting them die? 

I don't think being in a poor family with irresponsible parents is comparable to having a disease or medical issue that inflicts constant pain. Sorry if I assumed wrongly that you were referring to parents simply not wanting a child for non-medical issues but if that's what you were referring to then I have no argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662590989.0" user="bullevard" delta="False">
    <text>It is true that the main reason for most abortions is a lack of desire to have a kid right then. 

However, it is also true that one of the strongest (and I'd argue most frequently used) legal and emotional arguments in favor of abortion access it is that it is a private medical choice of the woman and her body.

OPs cmv brings up the point that if the "it's a woman's health decision" argument was off the table, would the "inconvenience" justifications be enough to sway public opinion one way or the other.

A more likely scenario in a world of artificial wombs is an ability for a father to sue for a transplant to the womb in the case that the woman wants an abortion but he doesn't. 

This somewhat equalizing (even a transplant would impact the woman's body, so all not equality,  but far closer than carrying a baby to term and birthing it) of the physical burden might open up interesting laws that would allow either parent the option to opt out of parenting rights and responsibilities if the other unilaterally wants to keep the child. 

I think OPs position that therefore every pregnancy should have to come to term if still a moral and ethical position rather than a necessary consequence if such technology. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662897807.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>You did seem to get my main point. I truly believe in my stance, otherwise I wouldn't have posted it on CMV, but there's a large part that is influenced by the fact that I believe the only justifiable argument for abortion in the first place is that "it's a woman's health decision". That argument loses all ground in a world with artificial wombs. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
