<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28662219194.0" user="_SadWalrus_" delta="False">
    <text>There are already over 400,000 children in the foster care system in the US right now.  Over [100,000 of them](http://www.adoptuskids.org/meet-the-children/children-in-foster-care/about-the-children) are eligible for adoption.  Each year, 20,000 kids 'age out' of the system, never having found parents.  And your idea is to compound this problem?  

In 2012, there were [699,202 reported abortions in the US](http://www.cdc.gov/reproductivehealth/data_stats/).  Can you imagine the problem if even a tenth of these unwanted children were dumped into the already-strained foster system?  

What you're proposing would create legions of children we cannot care for and who will never have parents.  Unless you have another idea for warehousing, educating, and guiding these children, you're proposing a nightmare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662221689.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Then that's a problem with our foster care system that should be fixed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662225433.0" user="_SadWalrus_" delta="False">
    <text>Good luck.  The [sheer amount](http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/news/nation/2010-09-23-fostercare23_ST_N.htm) of the [shortage](http://foster-care-newsletter.com/foster-parent-shortages-in-the-united-states/#.V6BI_hUrLIU) of [foster parents](https://www.texastribune.org/2016/03/17/more-kids-sleeping-cps-offices-amid-placement-shor/) is already staggering. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662226540.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. This is a problem for society that we need to figure out how to deal with. I do not agree, however, that abortion is the solution. I personally believe that the solution should be getting as close to 100% effective, incredibly cheap, and easily reversible birth control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662229171.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>You can say that we need something diffent all you want, until we come up with something that is both practical and easy to implement you are doing nothing but whining.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662239201.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Practical and easy to implement are a very good standard to live by, can you expound on what is unpractical about this solution? I understand the problem with foster care but I see it as an unfortunate side effect of a better system. Like I see the death of the unborn fetuses and the parental inequality as an unfortunate side effect of our current system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662242990.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>How is having millions more neglected kids better then having the death of unborn fetuses and slight parental inequality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662253495.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Well I could go with the philosophical answer of, each of those children exist and therefore add an immeasurable amount of good, despite having a relatively poor life, but both of us know that's not actually an acceptable, reasonable, or practical answer to this, so I will give you a less powerful argument.

I believe that equality between everyone is the basis that we need to grow our society from. We can find a way to fix the foster care system. We could even find a way to fix having unwanted pregnancies. Those are issues that can be fixed that are related but not directly connected with the inequality between the unborn fetus and the parents in the current system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662256689.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>Why not give men the option to opt out of parenting instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662264846.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I agree personally that we should have a financial/legal abortion alternative for men, but I do believe that there are legitimate grievances that the opponents to that have that would make this a compromise that would work for both groups (IE the termination of the unborn fetus, the lack of support for the child, and the ability for a man to keep a child who the wife does not want to carry to term, among other things).

That was what I said to someone else. I would agree that allowing men to legally opt out of parenting would be a step in the right direction, but it doesn't actually fix many other issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662267609.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>What issues does it not fix? Also, it carries 0 downsides, where as your plan is a massive drain of tax dollars and leads to millions of neglected kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662274613.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't prevent the termination of the unborn fetus. It doesn't prevent the situation where a man wants to keep a child and the wife does not want to carry to term (and since I figure either way artificial wombs will be a thing, she would also want to not have a biological child in existence). 

It carries the downside of increasing the number of single mothers that don't have the monetary backing of a second breadwinner. Which would equate to a massive drain of tax dollars as they are the ones who tend to utilize various forms of welfare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663355538.0" user="DeviousBluestocking" delta="False">
    <text>Men and women have exactly the same legal ability to "opt out" of child rearing.

Life, liberty, bodily integrity are all rights. Not being a parent if you no longer feel like it, not a right. A desire we can all relate to? Possibly. But it's not a right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662230189.0" user="_SadWalrus_" delta="False">
    <text>Duke already studied this.  It's [precisely](http://econ.duke.edu/uploads/media_items/sutherland-2.original.pdf) the solution.  Abortion restrictions in place = more kids shoved off on the foster system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662234725.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>And would that stay consistent in a world with 100% effective, incredibly cheap, and easily reversible birth control, that feels the same as unprotected sex (I realized I needed to add that part because that's what a lot of people's contention with current birth control is)? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662238105.0" user="_SadWalrus_" delta="False">
    <text>No one can study that, as no such method exists.  I honestly don't think so, because I can't even fathom such a method existing.  Knowing how lax people are about birth control now, though, I doubt it would make much of a dent unless this birth control method were automatically given to every person, male and female, before puberty and only reversed once they wanted to become a parent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662240680.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>That's actually an interesting proposal. It could be a part of the routine vaccinations and/or flu shot culture we already have. I'm sure there are moral/ethical implications there. It would have to be so easy to reverse that there would be next to zero barrier to becoming a parent when one desires before we could even begin to think about how to implement that system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28666191046.0" user="helloshell" delta="False">
    <text>A method does exist for women in the UK (and other countries with an NHS equivalent): the [contraceptive implant](http://www.nhs.uk/conditions/contraception-guide/pages/contraceptive-implant.aspx). &amp;gt;99% effective, free, removable at any time and fertility returns almost immediately. Insertion takes five minutes, forget for three years. There's a reason the NHS encourages it, especially for young women who don't want to have children within three years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28666635300.0" user="_SadWalrus_" delta="False">
    <text>I know about that, but I don't consider it a method that could be used on a wide scale.  I can't tolerate hormones and have never considered myself one of a tiny minority because I've heard it so often from other women.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662814290.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Does that exist? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662847723.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Not yet. That's why I awarded the first delta and put in that second edit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662371415.0" user="FiercelyFuzzy206" delta="False">
    <text>Again, until the foster care system is fixed, it doesn't matter if we have artificial wombs. You HAVE to fix the foster care system first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663327978.0" user="earldbjr" delta="False">
    <text>That's the bottom line. I love this logic of  birthing nearly a million more humans a year first, THEN we'll just have to sort out the implications. Holy hell.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663236383.0" user="Zob_dznts" delta="False">
    <text>People not wanting to be responsible for other's children is not a problem with our society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663265780.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>I believe it is. I personally believe that everyone should be responsible for everyone else. We should all put aside a bit so that everyone can reach a suitable minimum standard of living no matter what happens.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663295045.0" user="Zob_dznts" delta="False">
    <text>That's called communism. Just because you think it sounds nice doesnt make it right. We arent becoming a communist country because of your personal opinion, and when discussing government policy, perhaps you should set your opinions aside and focus on how that policy will effect citizens as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663314374.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>No. That's called socialism. Communism is everyone is equal. Socialism is a minimum standard of living. And it doesn't matter that my personal view won't change policy, isn't this about changing my personal view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663421946.0" user="Zob_dznts" delta="False">
    <text>As I have not replied directly to your OP, consider my replies purely for the sake of discussion (something im sure we both enjoy).  Sociaism means that the government controls the means of production. In socialism, the government is responsible for the well being of its citizens. Communism means that the working class controls the means of production. In communism the people are responsible for the well being of each other, and citizens must be responible enough to produce sufficient goods for their community and to never take more than they need. 

The thoughts I mean to provoke are along the lines of "I know communism(or socialism) is a system of government that would work for me, but would this system work equally well for different types of people? Is it practical to do so?"

As it relates to your OP, perhaps consider "It would make me happier for my own unwanted child (abortion candidate) to be born and taken care for by another, but is it correct to believe government policy should change to relfect these feelings (your OP)? Is it practical to do so?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663442172.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"It would make me happier for my own unwanted child (abortion candidate) to be born and taken care for by another, but is it correct to believe government policy should change to relfect these feelings (your OP)? Is it practical to do so?"

I understand now what you're getting at and I actually would love to have this discussion. I personally think a society where we value existence and helping others is highly important. It wouldn't necessarily make me happier to have my own unwanted child to be taken care for by another, it would be more apt to say that I would be happier to know that no unwanted children are robbed of the chance to live and that collectively as a society we are making sure that all people meet a minimum standard of living. They just overlapping to be "It would make me happier for an unwanted child to be born and taken care for by another". 

And to follow that, I do personally believe that government policy should be set up to make it so that no one can fall through the cracks. A safety net of some kind to ensure that everyone has enough to survive. The net good of functionally eliminating poverty surpasses any of the tax burdens that would be imposed on people. 

I also believe that government policy should respect the sanctity of life above all else. Every other right stems from the individual's right to live, and I believe no one has the right to supersede another's right to life (besides your own right to live). So I do believe others should not legally have the ability to make the choice to bring a life into this world and then choose to end it. At any point in time. And I believe that without respecting the right to live we're effectively shitting on every other human right. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662313993.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>It is a massive problem and no it won't just get fixed. 

You are going to create thousands of more children with no network to support them. 

You can't just wipe that under the rug with an IT should be fixed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662317980.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>If you saw the rest of the comments you will see I already conceded that point. It's something that should be fixed but that doesn't change the fact that this is also something that needs to be fixed. We can do both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662329058.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>Until you fix it, the rest of this idea is useless. 

In fact, it only makes the current system crushingly worse. 

You are taking an already strained system and then added millions of more children to it. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662330144.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>In this hypothetical, we have enough time to fix the current system before hand. Artificial wombs aren't going to show up tomorrow. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662334750.0" user="forestfly1234" delta="False">
    <text>Your entire premise makes zero sense if the idea is just to say oh we fixed a major problem that made this idea really bad. 

That's all you're doing.

Anything else impossible that you want to create to make this idea of yours work? Because if you have to "fix" impossible to fix things then you might just have a bad idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662338411.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>1. I don't consider it a bigger problem than the problem that is being fixed. I believe it's a net good even without addressing the issue of foster care. I'm only addressing the problem because others have brought it up.
2. I already addressed how the failing foster care system isn't the fault of the abortions it's the fault of the unintended pregnancies. Which can be decreased drastically by efficient, universally applied, easily reversible birth control. You just haven't read through the rest of the thread to see me address this.
3. I already gave a delta out for the first person who brought this up and meaningfully challenged my idea. You can see the edit to my main post in regards to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662628354.0" user="AlwaysABride" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What you're proposing would create legions of children 

No.  Those children are already created (going with the OP's thought process).  It is just that right now we, as a society, have decided that it is ok to ~~kill them~~ let them die because a woman's bodily autonomy is more important that the life of that child that requires the woman's body.

Once the artificial womb exists and the woman's body is no longer needed, then the fetus in the artificial womb is no different than a 2 year old child.  And when a 2 year old child is unwanted, we as a society are uncomfortable with killing it.  So we have the foster care system in place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28664322546.0" user="qi1" delta="False">
    <text>Then why not just round up every one of these unadopted children and kill each of them, one at a time, to help alleviate this problem?

Can't do that because you can't kill human beings?

Then if the unborn are also human beings, you can't justify abortion as a part of caring for unwanted children.

Advocating for the right to life doesn't mean opposing quality of life, and outside of the abortion context, nobody argues that it does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28673838857.0" user="MisanthropeX" delta="False">
    <text>We could just draft them into the military. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
