<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28662802464.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What would be done with all the extra kids? Child family services where I am from are already way beyond capacity. Living in foster care is awful. Just awful. I know lots of people raised in the system and none of them are better for their experiences. Maybe I'd agree with you if we could actually take care of the kids who already exist,  nevermind adding a huge number more. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662878739.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. This is a major problem. I addressed it in a lot of other places, but I'll reiterate. 

1. I consider it a net good to fix this inequality even with the thousands of new extra kids that would be born (Partially because I believe a shitty existence trumps non existence).
2. I consider them separate, if related problems. Focus on one doesn't cause detriment to fixing the problems inherent to the other (although I can admit that if we do it in one order it would temporarily cause the problem to be exacerbated).
3. I did concede, earlier, that we would have to work on creating a more effective and universally applied contraceptive that would, in the end, cause the net number of unwanted children born post this policy to equalize with the net number of unwanted children that we can sustain in our foster care system. We'd also need to fix our foster care system, but I don't actually consider that a problem in any way related to abortion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663037682.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I consider it a net good to fix this inequality even with the thousands of new extra kids that would be born (Partially because I believe a shitty existence trumps non existence).

Is it though? Non existence doesnt come with pain, or suffering. Just the extinguishing of something that could be. Its not really a net good because kids who go through the system have a much higher chance of burning out. They miss out on a ton of school, and are raised in a system with no role models or stable parental figures. They get moved around a lot so they cant set down roots. They're set up to fail by the system set to protect them. Not to mention lots of these kids come from horrific homes and already come with their own scars.

&amp;gt; I consider them separate, if related problems. Focus on one doesn't cause detriment to fixing the problems inherent to the other (although I can admit that if we do it in one order it would temporarily cause the problem to be exacerbated).

But your proposal would make an already broken system even worse, without actually fixing a problem. 

&amp;gt; I did concede, earlier, that we would have to work on creating a more effective and universally applied contraceptive that would, in the end, cause the net number of unwanted children born post this policy to equalize with the net number of unwanted children that we can sustain in our foster care system. We'd also need to fix our foster care system, but I don't actually consider that a problem in any way related to abortion.

But these things dont exist. And fixing the foster care system isnt something you can just do. There are a million reasons why the CFS system is in such trouble. It would take a restructuring of society to fix everything. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663141792.0" user="Coollogin" delta="False">
    <text>"I believe a shitty existence trumps non existence."

Really? Why?  How in the world could the worst possible existence be preferable to no existence?

"We would have to work on creating more effective and universally applied contraceptive..."

THAT is the real solution.  Prevent the unwanted pregnancy, and you have no need for the sci fi stuff. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663190442.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; THAT is the real solution. Prevent the unwanted pregnancy, and you have no need for the sci fi stuff.

Artificial wombs aren't sci fi stuff. It's something that's actually coming down the line. It's just a more advanced neonatal incubator. 

&amp;gt;How in the world could the worst possible existence be preferable to no existence?

Because I believe that being alive and able to think is the most amazing thing possible. You can't think if you're dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28666118931.0" user="kayemm36" delta="False">
    <text>Even without abortion, the world has an infinite amount of people that could have existed, but never get the chance to.  Every time a man ejaculates in the shower, millions of cells that each could have become a person go down the drain instead.  Every time a woman has a period, that egg could have become an existing person.  Even pregnancy means that for the nine months the woman is pregnant, the rest of her eggs don't get a chance to become existing people.  Having sex on Thursday instead of Monday means that the person that would have existed, had the sex happened on Monday, doesn't ever get to exist.

Every method of birth control, including abstinence, creates a mass graveyard of people that 'could have existed' but don't.  A couple that never has children is responsible for the non-existence of potentially dozens of grandchildren and great grandchildren, people that would have existed if the couple had decided to have children.  Go down a few generations, and you have the non-existence of thousands.  Is the non-existence of them and their descendants any less tragic or significant than the potentially existing person that has sperm meet ova but is aborted?

For that matter, you could fill any number of artificial wombs with artificially inseminated ova, without involving the transfer from real wombs to artificial ones.  These people would be no less real and existing.  Why is one set of potentially existing people more deserving of that chance than another?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28666135322.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Because they did exist. They were conceived. The others never existed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663208295.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I believe a shitty existence trumps non existence

If that were a universal truth suicide wouldn't be a problem. There are lots of lives and modes of living that can be worse than non-existence. 

What about children who are likely to die shortly after birth because of severe birth defects? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663273450.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>I think suicide is a product of failure in their cognitive process that causes them to not see the inherent value in continuing to live. But that's a philosophical thing. 

&amp;gt;What about children who are likely to die shortly after birth because of severe birth defects?

A chance at life is better than no chance at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663364601.0" user="DeviousBluestocking" delta="False">
    <text>This whole argument kind of misses the point for me. Most people who talk about abortion forget that at 12 weeks, by which 88% of abortions have occurred, a fetus is the size of a lime. A fetus is not human with all of the human capacity for thought, feeling, or sensation. To limit this medical procedure on the basis of sentimentality or religious dogma would infringe on the human rights of women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663368625.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>I've got concerns that fetuses that *should* be aborted would be forced to live a horrible and short existence.. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663413899.0" user="DeviousBluestocking" delta="False">
    <text>I agree on principle, but as a humanist I think there could and should be far fewer suicides. I don't think we need to sacrifice a value for life to justify abortion. For instance, many degenerative disease justify abortion, but many children raised in foster care *would* rather be alive than not alive. I understand that what you said isn't mutually exclusive with what I said.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
