<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28663446337.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>You've said frequently in this thread that you believe that the birth of a child, regardless of circumstances, is a net good. How are you defining "good" in this sentence? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663455293.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Essentially it boils down to an increase in sentience. The more sentient life, the more thinking life, the better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663474668.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you feel that way? What makes sentient life so important and special that there is no limit to how much of it we should strive to bring in to the world?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663529929.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Because sentience is the only form of existence that is fully aware of itself. It's the only form of existence that can philosophize, and the more thoughts and thinking, the closer we can come to true understanding. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663718908.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Let me pose a hypothetical for you. If a country was unable to feed its population resulting in famine, would it have been better if they had a smaller population and avoided that famine, or is it better that more people were born and then doomed to die?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663732521.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>More people. Average Utilitarianism is a horrible concept. Because with that same logic you would say if we had to pick between 1 person living an absolutely perfect life and 1000 people living a shitty life we should pick the 1. I'd rather the 1000.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28664108207.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Would you say your belief in the net positive impact of all sentient life is more spiritually rooted? I'd suggest something more nuanced. In the real world we have finite resources, and some people have very negative impacts on themselves and those around them. We don't have an infinite amount of resources available to raise an unbound number of unwanted children. 

If I understand you, your caveats for your view are as follows:

1. Your belief is restricted to a hypothetical future in which we have completely fixed how we care for unwanted children disproportionately likely to have severe medical problems
2. The use of artificial wombs is as non invasive as medical abortion
3. Birth control is free and perfectly effective

I would suggest that even if the technology for an artificial womb is possible the world which conforms to your caveats is impossible for the foreseeable future. 

In order to so perfectly care for so many unwanted and unhealthy children we would need to spend a vast amount of money, and have profound changes on a societal level to increase the number of people willing to care for them. Alternatively we could care for them in orphanages, which would take a massive amount of money and resources. Maybe there will one day be a society with those sorts of resources available, but I don't expect to see it.

Medical abortion (which is just a pill) will always be less invasive than the use of an artificial womb for a fetus transplant unless we come up with some type of teleporter

We're actually getting close on the birth control thing. Male birth control options similar to what you describe are in the testing phase right now. The problems for now is it's not free, there are lots of people who object on religious grounds, and we're not going to know the long term risks for decades.

While the world you suggest might be possible at some point in the future, we're much further away from it than we are from artificial wombs.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28664170123.0" user="annoyinglongusername" delta="False">
    <text>The 1000 starving people would be too busy struggling for survival to worry about philosophy or coming closer to "true understanding." At least the one person living an absolutely perfect life would have the resources necessary to pursue further knowledge. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
