<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28662233706.0" user="AwesomeAim" delta="False">
    <text>What if a girl gets raped though? I think that's kind of unfair in her situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662236624.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>If she is raped she would put the fetus in the artificial womb and wash her hands of it. She would be no more forced to raise it than she would be now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662239920.0" user="AwesomeAim" delta="False">
    <text>Where does the baby then go once it's born?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662241778.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Where do any unwanted children go when they are born? Someone else pointed out the foster care situation and I understand that it's a horrible situation currently that would only get worse, but I see it as a secondary, if related, issue that we would need to address along side this one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662247526.0" user="AwesomeAim" delta="False">
    <text>Well, see, we'll probably have around 10 billion people when this comes (or nearing that).

At that point, it makes more sense to have an abortion than to put it into an artificial womb. Thus, the unwanted children is dealt with, and the problem is solved, and the mother can then go to later have some babies she does want, and raise them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662258750.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Is that not using abortion as a band-aid for two related, but not necessarily completely connected problems (Unintended pregnancies and our shitty foster care system, which wouldn't even be an issue if the first wasn't a problem)? Would it not make more sense to figure out how to prevent unintended pregnancies and then figure out how to, in the worst case scenario, take care of the unwanted child than to perpetuate this inequality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662261926.0" user="AwesomeAim" delta="False">
    <text>How is this inequality?

If a girl gets raped then gets pregnant, I think it's anything but unequal to give her the rights to the child.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662263561.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>It's in equal because if a man is raped and the woman gets pregnant then he has no right to force an abortion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662370156.0" user="FiercelyFuzzy206" delta="False">
    <text>Foster Care reform would HAVE to happen first. 

639,807 babies have been aborted this year. Around 1.2 million babies are aborted each year in America. Do you really think that we could handle 1 million new kids in foster care every year? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662686031.0" user="Zeiramsy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If she is raped she would put the fetus in the artificial womb and wash her hands of it. She would be no more forced to raise it than she would be now.

Psychologically it´s not that simple, it´s still traumatic knowing you´ve created life, knowing that there is a child born of rape with your genes.

Also to me it doesn´t really solve, the definition of an abortion. What about the morning-after pill. Would I be forbidden from using that? Some of these pills work days later, scientific progress may prolong that period. Would they still be allowed, what would be the point in time, you aren´t allowed anymore to use them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662855255.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Well the Morning-after pill isn't an abortion pill. It does nothing if you're already pregnant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662729945.0" user="Cantaloupe_Frost" delta="False">
    <text>But, as you stated earlier, would she have to cover the costs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662851267.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Does she not have to cover the costs of an abortion now? If not then I would be find letting her not pay for the costs of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663216798.0" user="CunninghamsLawmaker" delta="False">
    <text>Abortion can be conducted in an outpatient setting and is on a sliding price scale if you go to a clinic. Also, in the first trimester it can be done with a pill. Short of Star Trek level technology, it transferring a fetus into an artificial womb will always be far more complicated and difficult. Not to mention the cost of maintaining and eventually somehow birthing the child.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
