<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28663564341.0" user="SchiferlED" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, but then who pays for the (undoubtedly expensive) artificial womb procedure, and who will care for the child? All I see from this is an unnecessary increase in healthcare costs and a much greater number of children up for adoption. Just a net negative for society overall. Why enforce such a policy when it just makes the situation worse?

No one is morally responsible for the natural conclusion of a fetus separated from the mother who does not want it, which is the death of said fetus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663581856.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;artificial womb procedure

The same person who'd pay for the abortion. 

&amp;gt;who will care for the child

The parents if they keep it, the state if it goes into foster care. Just like any other unwanted child.

&amp;gt;No one is morally responsible for the natural conclusion of a fetus separated from the mother who does not want it

I disagree with that, but I'm more interested in why you hold that position. Because I can think of a few choices that a person can make that just naturally lead to a death that people would find morally reprehensible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663642375.0" user="SchiferlED" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The same person who'd pay for the abortion. 

What if abortion is a better option for them? Why force them to pick the option they don't want to deal with? Why is abortion okay now, but suddenly not okay when this new option exists?

&amp;gt;The parents if they keep it, the state if it goes into foster care. Just like any other unwanted child.

Ok. That's what I suspected.

&amp;gt;I disagree with that, but I'm more interested in why you hold that position. Because I can think of a few choices that a person can make that just naturally lead to a death that people would find morally reprehensible.

The way I see it, the mother is actively keeping the fetus alive with her body (often against her will). Getting an abortion is the mother's decision to stop actively keeping the fetus alive. Deciding to stop keeping something else alive when you did not formally agree to keep it alive is not a morally reprehensible act. When something dies, it does not mean that everyone who could have potentially kept it alive is now a killer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663689198.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What if abortion is a better option for them? Why force them to pick the option they don't want to deal with? Why is abortion okay now, but suddenly not okay when this new option exists?

Because it's only okay because it's the only option that allows bodily autonomy. That's the main argument for it and the only one that has significant moral and legal weight. In this situation it's no longer the only option that allows bodily autonomy therefore it loses it's most valid argument for being allowed.
&amp;gt;formally agree to keep it alive

You did when you had sex. Consent to sex is a consent to all of the likely outcomes of sex. So you did consent to giving it life. It was your choice that brought it to life. 

&amp;gt;When something dies, it does not mean that everyone who could have potentially kept it alive is now a killer.

And when you set up a situation where someone's life is now in your hands and you decide to NOT keep them alive you have killed them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28664074930.0" user="SchiferlED" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You did when you had sex.

And that's where we fundamentally disagree. Sex is sex, not an agreement to birth and raise a child. And it's most certainly not a formal agreement.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
