<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295379811.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vv0ir/cmv_the_economic_and_social_conditions_that/">
    <title>CMV: the economic and social conditions that created the so-called stability of the 1950s are unique, thus it's foolish to try to recreate that time period.</title>
    <original_poster>dpfw</original_poster>
    <original_post>The 1950s in popular imagination are a time of prosperity and stability. Whether this is or is not the case, a great many people, particularly on the right, particularly repeatedly-bankrupt millionaires who's eyes look like their mouths, seem to think of this time period as something to emulate. 
The fact of the matter is that this is patently absurd. The economy of the 1950s was so strong and America so dominant because every other country that could possibly compete with us was rebuilding from World War II. Short of Europe and East Asia destroying themselves in a nuclear holocaust or us halting all trade into this country, that is a condition that is nevergoing to happen again. 
The 1950s are also known for a level of social homogenity that is largely a product of low immigration. The 1965 Immigration Act repealed many of the limits on immigration put in place in the 1920s. 
The fact of the matter is that what the Baby Boomers consider to be America's decline is actually America returning to the conditions that had persisted for the 170 years preceding the 1950s. Present conditions- that is, an unstable economy, lots of immigrants, and a religious minority that many people are mistrustful of- is the normal state of affairs in this country. A more achievable goal is a return to the conditions (both economically and socially) of the 1990s- a decade which will undoubtedly in 20-30 years be as idealized by Millennials as the 1950s was by Baby Boomers
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28663679448.0" user="ayyy__1mao" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The economy of the 1950s was so strong and America so dominant because every other country that could possibly compete with us was rebuilding from World War II. 

Not really. At least not the economic bit.

Other countries doing well economically doesn't bring our economy down. In fact, a lot of our prosperity *depends* on trading with other countries, which in turn depends on their ability to produce surplus economic output.

Living standards have actually increased substantially in the US since the 1950s. The 1950s are remembered as being unusually prosperous relative to the Depression, not today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663767150.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In fact, a lot of our prosperity depends on trading with other countries, which in turn depends on their ability to produce surplus economic output.

In the 50s it depended on trade as well. At that point we could produce more for cheaper and thus American-made goods were easier to get. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663770260.0" user="ayyy__1mao" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;At that point we could produce more for cheaper

By what measure? Consumer goods are generally cheaper now than they were back then. Which is one reason why living standards are higher.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
