<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295379811.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vv0ir/cmv_the_economic_and_social_conditions_that/">
    <title>CMV: the economic and social conditions that created the so-called stability of the 1950s are unique, thus it's foolish to try to recreate that time period.</title>
    <original_poster>dpfw</original_poster>
    <original_post>The 1950s in popular imagination are a time of prosperity and stability. Whether this is or is not the case, a great many people, particularly on the right, particularly repeatedly-bankrupt millionaires who's eyes look like their mouths, seem to think of this time period as something to emulate. 
The fact of the matter is that this is patently absurd. The economy of the 1950s was so strong and America so dominant because every other country that could possibly compete with us was rebuilding from World War II. Short of Europe and East Asia destroying themselves in a nuclear holocaust or us halting all trade into this country, that is a condition that is nevergoing to happen again. 
The 1950s are also known for a level of social homogenity that is largely a product of low immigration. The 1965 Immigration Act repealed many of the limits on immigration put in place in the 1920s. 
The fact of the matter is that what the Baby Boomers consider to be America's decline is actually America returning to the conditions that had persisted for the 170 years preceding the 1950s. Present conditions- that is, an unstable economy, lots of immigrants, and a religious minority that many people are mistrustful of- is the normal state of affairs in this country. A more achievable goal is a return to the conditions (both economically and socially) of the 1990s- a decade which will undoubtedly in 20-30 years be as idealized by Millennials as the 1950s was by Baby Boomers
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28663703334.0" user="GenderNeutralLanguag" delta="False">
    <text>The primary driver of the economic boom was unions.  The stability was the result of getting along.

We can have the strong economy of the 50's again if we rebuild the unions and reduce income inequality.

We can all get along.  This is much harder with a diverse population like we have today, but it is possible and worth pursuing.

These are very achiveable goals and will return us to a state similar to the 50's (only better)

The economy of the late 90's isn't something we should pursue.  That was a bubble created by booming internet markets.  In the late 90's thousands of internet startups popped up.  Every one wanting to get in on the ground floor of the next NetScape or Geocities threw money at these projects.  This vastly increased the velocity of money, but then most of them failed causing the .com bust of early 2000's.

We can, and should, look to return to the economy of the 50's.  The biggest hurdle is that the people advocating a return to the 50's are against the steps needed to do so.  We would need to raise the top marginal tax rate up to 90%.  We would need to promote Unions.  We would need to socialize services like health care and expand welfare a great deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663765083.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>The reason why the unions could command that level of control is because we had no real competitors. It just doesn't make economic sense to have that many blue collar jobs pay that well anymore, not when automation and cheap foreign labor exist. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28664142892.0" user="GenderNeutralLanguag" delta="False">
    <text>You don't seem to understand how STRONG unions work.

Should a company attempt to by-pass unions this way, all unions would work to stop them.  Ford decides to ship it's last US factory to Mexico?  Nope, not only is there a strike at the Ford plant that would be kinda pointless, but the Teamsters refuse to haul any Ford parts or cars.  Every one from Bus Drivers to FireFighters to Nurses and Teachers all join in on the strike.

You get a viable threat of a national strike of 80%+ of the workforce, and the bad press against the company alone would make such wage reductions unworkable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28663766500.0" user="mr_fallacy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We can have the strong economy of the 50's again if we rebuild the unions and reduce income inequality.

* Even if we introduce unions, whose to say it wouldn't be a unionized workforce in a third world country?

* If we listen to Reddit futurists, automation will replace many of the manual jobs anyways. A higher wage will likely only accelerate that process.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
