<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="297873535.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/">
    <title>CMV: Describing someone as "the female Michael Phelps" is not insulting, and saying so is being ridiculous and hyper-sensitive.</title>
    <original_poster>Siiimo</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just saw an article calling out announcers for referring to Katie Ledecky as "the female Michael Phelps." The suggestion being that that was sexist, and why not refer to Michael Phelps as "the male Katie Ledecky?"

This seems pretty clearly ridiculous. Phelps is the most decorated Olympian of all time, one of the most recognizable names in the world, and has shattered many olympic and world records. Ledecky has four medals. A laudable achievement for sure, but nowhere even close to Phelps'. Famous people are compared all the time to others. "The Michael Jordan of _____" "The George Washington of ______" "The male Rosa Parks"

This is a common turn of phrase. To claim that it is sexist and not a compliment is insanity. Am I missing something?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28685029407.0" user="n_5" delta="False">
    <text>The articles I've seen which complain about this don't complain about Ledecky being called "the male Michael Phelps" - they complain about Ledecky being described as a swimmer who ["swims like a man."](http://www.slate.com/blogs/xx_factor/2016/08/08/are_the_olympics_sexist_on_wives_broadcast_delays_and_swimming_like_a_man.html) This is an entirely different issue, and I think it's a fair one to bring up - it implies that Ledecky is dominant in large part because she (uniquely, somehow) swims like the other 50% of our population. It's not sexist to compare Ledecky's dominance to Phelps' dominance, but it is sexist to imply that Ledecky's dominance should be even in part ascribed to a "non-female" form or mindset.

As a potential comparison point: it wouldn't be homophobic to praise a gay athlete by comparing them to a straight one, but it would be homophobic to say they "play like a straight person." Does that make sense in terms of your original CMV?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685094989.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>Is that homophobic though? If there was an established difference in common traits between gay and straight sportsmen?

Let's take dancing, if I said a straight guy danced like a gay guy, is that offensive?

Why is it so offensive to say that someone displays traits usually associated with another gender or sexuality?

I'm a guy who likes to sit down and pee like a woman, I'm usually too lazy to stand up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685101058.0" user="n_5" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why is it so offensive to say that someone displays traits usually associated with another gender or sexuality?

Because in the case of Ledecky, people are praising the most dominant swimmer in a very long time by comparing her to male swimmers. Not dominant male swimmers - just male swimmers in general. The implication here is that excellence is, in your words, a trait associated with men, which I'd say is absolutely offensive. Certain things - like complimenting a straight guy for dancing like a gay guy - are arguably less problematic (though I can't think of what a "stereotypical gay guy" would dance like, so I'm having trouble thinking of an example of when you'd use that). Other things, like complimenting an excellent Black orator by talking about how he "speaks like a White guy" or complimenting a gay football player for "showing the machismo of a straight man," absolutely cross the line into offensive territory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685110898.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>I'm still not seeing why this would cause offense. Bear with me.

So men are generally faster swimmers than women, they hold faster records etc. When a woman is a strong enough swimmer that she starts getting compared to male swimmers that logically is a compliment right? It's like saying "this 11 year old is top of her class in maths, she is as good at maths as some of my 15 year old students!" good for the 11 year old, and good for Ledecky. Right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685195710.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>The idea is that her accomplishments can stand on their own, they don't need to be spoken about in a way that also brings up the accomplishments of men.

Most people aren't really "offended" like they're upset and crying about it. They think we should develop a better way to talk about women athletes. If all we can think to do is go, "well how does she compare to men?" then they don't think we're doing a great job.

Edit: I also think it's important to point out that just because something is positive it doesn't mean it isn't offensive or wrong. You might think you're saying something nice about someone else but they could take it differently depending on how you say it. Couching praise for a woman in terms of how she compares to men doesn't mean it isn't praise, it just means it's more backhanded than I imagine many people wanted it to be. It isn't hard to interpret such statements as being closer to, "oh you're so good at this thing...*for a woman*."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685241931.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The idea is that her accomplishments can stand on their own

As far as I'm aware the entire point of the Olympics is to see how one's accomplishments stack up against *other* sportsmen/women. This is why there are medals, it's a competition.

Camparison helps people people judge the significance of something.

Someone tells me: "The Burg Khalifa is 828 m high."

Me: "Oh, that sounds pretty big."

Person: "Yeah it's almost as big as Mount Snowdon in Wales!"

Me: "~~Why do we have to compare it to a mountain, why can't it's accomplishments just stand on their own.~~ Oh wow cool that is fuckin big! And *people built that?* holy shit."

Whatever helps people understand the significance of how good at swimming she is. Would it be better to compare her to a type of fish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685250907.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As far as I'm aware the entire point of the Olympics is to see how one's accomplishments stack up against other sportsmen/women. This is why there are medals, it's a competition.

Not between the genders there isn't. That's why the competitions are segregated by gender. It's unnecessary. I also can't help but notice that the comparison's don't usually go the other way.

&amp;gt; Camparison helps people people judge the significance of something.

Thank you, I am aware of how the concept of comparison works.

Do you seriously need to know how Ledecky compares to Michael Phelps to know that she's a top notch athlete? You couldn't look at her three gold medals and one silver and say, "yep she's a top notch athlete."?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685262981.0" user="dfountain62" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I also can't help but notice that the comparison's don't usually go the other way.

Don't you think that this is the *real* sexism? I mean as far as I can see it's sexist to not acknowledge womens comparative advantage (flexibility, "grace", agility) in the same way we acknowledge mens.

Edit: come to think of it the only time I ever hear the male having female traits is when men are described as inheriting things from their mother.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685336899.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Thank you, I am aware of how the concept of comparison works.

Ok good.

&amp;gt;Do you seriously need to know how Ledecky compares to Michael Phelps to know that she's a top notch athlete?

Hang on... It seems like you might not actually understand.
Do I need to know? No, but more points of reference means a more accurate understanding. I don't think running around telling people they can't use a point of reference just because it happens to be male is a very progressive way of thinking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685341483.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No, but more points of reference means a more accurate understanding.

What new understanding have you gained here?

And why stop there? Why not compare her to fish? Or cheetahs on land? She's surely a better swimmer than a rock - shouldn't we bring that up?

After all, apparently there is no end to comparisons if you want the most accurate understanding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685359722.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What new understanding have you gained here?

That she is not as fast as Michael Phelps, and some other male swimmers? In the same way that she is faster than other female swimmers. I can place her on a scale.

&amp;gt;And why stop there? Why not compare her to fish?

I don't have a good mental idea of how fast a fish can swim the length of a pool. Plus I don't care, fish have evolved to swim.

&amp;gt;Or cheetahs on land?

They're way faster, and the comparison does little to help me visualise her speed as the method and medium of movement are completely different.

&amp;gt;a rock

This is just childish.

Comparing her to other swimmers is a fair and sensible thing to do. I'm not going to omit a comparison based on sex.

In my eyes it's a compliment to be on nodding terms with athletes who hold a physiological advantage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685361987.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>"You're really good at having sex, for someone who isn't my ex-boyfriend."

How do you feel about that compliment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685402818.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>Like I would have come in 2nd (pun intended) place. I know very clearly that I'm better than most of her sexual partners but not her most recent ex.

Duh?

If you were actually trying to come up with a relevant metaphor you should've compared either me or the ex to a vibrator or something. Both doing the same thing, but not in direct competition, like Phelps and Ledecky. Something like:

"You're really good at having sex, but my super turbo-charged V8 rabbit jizz-master gets me off quicker"

Course it does, It's 14" long and vibrates. Doesn't mean I'm not proud of making you quiver. ;)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685417180.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>The point I'm making here is that not all compliments come across the same. And essentially saying, "you're pretty good I guess *for a girl*" is maybe how we shouldn't go about talking about women athletes.

People are trying to raise the level of discourse here. Some compliments can seem really backhanded when the comparison is made.

Like Jesus Christ, even the "new understanding" you said you gained:

&amp;gt; That she is not as fast as Michael Phelps, and some other male swimmers? In the same way that she is faster than other female swimmers. I can place her on a scale.

Is ridiculous. You seriously didn't know that women aren't as strong swimmers as men *until they compared the top athletes*? Are you serious?

Edit: And you're not in direct competition with her ex. My analogy was just fine. I do like how you managed to turn it into an actual compliment. Why yes, if you reword the whole thing and change what you're comparing yourself to it changes the nature of the compliment. Go figure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685481719.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>What's ridiculous is the social blowback for just wanting to know. It would be if we could talk about the genders in the same breath instead of pretending men don't exist in case we hurt someones feelings. I don't care about their feelings, I don't care about female athlete's feelings or men's. I'll compare anyone to anyone if I want to.

Heh, you know. I bet people would be singing a different song if she had swum faster than Phelps. I bet they would be all for comparisons then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685486564.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Who is pretending men don't exist? Are you suggesting that now every time Michael Phelps *isn't* compared to women that they're implicitly pretending that women don't exist?

And sure, do whatever you want. I'm allowed to think it's a lame way to talk about women athletes like that. Turns out, we're both allowed to do whatever we want.

The social blow-back is an attempt to elevate how we talk about a whole group of people. If you don't like it, get over it. I don't care about *your* feelings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685553321.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Are you suggesting that now every time Michael Phelps isn't compared to women that they're implicitly pretending that women don't exist?

No there are just better points of reference, like other male swimmers. When you are the fastest woman where do you look? Faster. Guess what? Men.

This is the funny thing, in your fervoured desperation to make sure nobody blemishes her achievements by being faster you are driving a wedge between the genders. 

"OOooooh no you mustn't talk about how fast men can swim while talking about how fast women can swim."

Perhaps that's the way you want it I guess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685215425.0" user="CireArodum" delta="False">
    <text>Is it appropriate to be comparing them at all? That takes the assumption that men and women are on the same scale of excellence and that women are further behind then men and therefore inferior.

However, we know that men and women are built differently. You don't really compare boxers of different weight classes. Yes, a heavyweight boxer will have more absolute strength than a middleweight, but what does that matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685234051.0" user="foomits" delta="False">
    <text>But it would be a compliment for a middleweight boxer to be praised as being able to compete with heavyweights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685257555.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That takes the assumption that men and women are on the same scale of excellence and that women are further behind then men and therefore inferior.

Well yeah they are. Swimming speed is an objective thing, and men are faster. That's not an assumption, it's proven fact.

&amp;gt;However, we know that men and women are built differently.

Of course, this is why they show no interest in competing with one another professionally, why would they? It would be like rowers racing sailors, it would prove nothing.

&amp;gt;a heavyweight boxer will have more absolute strength than a middleweight, but what does that matter?

If the middleweight could punch as hard as an average heavyweight, you wouldn't find that significant? You wouldn't think that was a useful piece of information on gauging how hard he could punch? "he weighs 5 stone less but still hits as hard as Tyson". That's a significant, useful and apt comparison to help people understand sporting prowess.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685253697.0" user="tanacobus" delta="False">
    <text>But her abilities alone aren't being praised, she's being praised in the context of how she compares to men in the same sport. This raises an interesting question as to how we as a society view people based on gender. People are automatically making that comparison when men are almost never compared to women in that way, except as an insult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685112709.0" user="profheg_II" delta="False">
    <text>I'm by no means an expert in sports science, but my understanding is that men and women are biologically built differently and have different peak levels of strength etc. (it's the reason why men and women compete separately in most events). It surely then stands to reason that men and women may adopt slightly different styles of doing things like competitive swimming that most take advantage of their sexes biology. I don't know what the motivation behind that "she swims like a man" comment was, but bearing in mind we're talking about the absolute best people in the world here who will have refined their technique to perfection, I feel like that could be a general observation about that rather than a sexist comment. (Or it could have been sexist, but part of "hypersensitivity" often seems to be people jumping to making accusations in situations which are ambiguous).

On this general topic I do think people are getting hypersensitive in these olympics. I saw another article about sexism in the olympics which was complaining about one commentator who said of a female acrobat "she's jumping off the bars almost as high as the men". This surely is a fair point to make as men will have more strength so be able to lift-off more when they're swinging around?

Edit: as a quick test Ive done a little research. Take the 400m freestyle, which Katie Ledecky has the womens world record in at 3:56:46. I then looked at all the timings for the men's 400m freestyle initial heats from these olympics. Out of 50 competitors, only 5 of the men got a slower time than that. When you've got a disparity like that, I think it can be a fair way of hyping up someone's performance. Essentially, I suppose I don't think it should be sexist if it's based on a real effect like this (and also making no judgement on the value of a person either).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685187905.0" user="xm0067" delta="False">
    <text>Except for men are unequivocally the faster swimmers. Look at the Olympic records. Look at their times. Men and women compete in separate events for a reason, ya know? 

Katie is characterized in many ways through her pure dedication to the practice and execution of her sport, even above that of other olympic level athletes. It's worth considering that at a certain point her strength and biomechanics allowed her to be overall faster if she modified her swimming stroke to, you guessed it, swim like a man. Not characterized by male traits, but literally in the same way a man does. Like a man. In an entirely non sexist way. 

Partial Source: I've been talking about this whole thing with my female  best friend who was a D-1 college swimmer at a big name college. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685271808.0" user="tanacobus" delta="False">
    <text>You're not wrong, but the argument isn't really about the biology or technique of it. As much as the comment of her swimming like a man may have been meant as a compliment, or may even be true, it's raising the question of "is this the best we have when we refer to female athletic ability?" Praising her abilities is great, but it becomes relatively meaningless when it's only in the context of how she compares to men.

I get that her technique is unorthodox for women in general but there is an underlying social context here as well. A woman being compared to a man is seen as a compliment but generally if a man is being compared to a woman it is an insult. That's a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685381478.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A woman being compared to a man is seen as a compliment but generally if a man is being compared to a woman it is an insult. That's a problem.

Surely it depends on the topic of comparison. Comparing GenderA to GenderB where GenderB is typically worse at the given activity is seen as an insult to GenderA. But we don't know which way round that is until we know the activity. It's not sexist, it's just a way of saying this person is good/bad by referencing the usual gender disparity.

You throw like a girl.

You smell like a man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685430093.0" user="tanacobus" delta="False">
    <text>I was generalizing; I'm sure there are man-based insults. But the only time I've heard anyone say "you smell like a man" is in Old Spice commercials, and even then it's a compliment. I've honestly never heard someone being insulted that way, but maybe that's a regional thing. My guess is if we made a list, there would be a lot more "you X like a girl" insults.

But it is sexist either way, no matter which gender you're comparing. You aren't giving merit to a person and their skills, you're giving them merit *based on how they live up to gender stereotypes.* 

It isn't sexist in a way that is making people furiously offended and combative. But if we step back and look at why we think the way we think, it's pretty clear that the only way we know how to refer to female athletes is in gender stereotypes. And maybe that's worth looking into?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685533888.0" user="spazmatazffs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;there would be a lot more "you X like a girl" insults.

Yeah I think you are right. At least in terms of sports, but then men just happen to have a physical advantage, it makes sense that "you 'sport' like a girl" because men generally outperform in physical sports.

Incidentally, I don't believe the "she swims like a man" thing was meant as anything other than an objective observation. Quite literally: "Her technique is that usually seen among male swimmers". A neutral descriptive statement. But I have no evidence for that, just my hunch.

&amp;gt;You aren't giving merit to a person and their skills, you're giving them merit based on how they live up to gender stereotypes.

I think it would be more insulting *not* to compare women to men in sports. Insulating people from the comparison is belittling.

&amp;gt;the only way we know how to refer to female athletes is in gender stereotypes

This, I think, may be the crux of the issue. The gender comparison isn't the *only* way we can gauge her prowess; it is just *one* way. Female swimmers don't win smaller medals than men, they are recognised independently. They set their own records, they have all the same competitive possibilities as men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685478659.0" user="xm0067" delta="False">
    <text>How does it not make sense to compare her to the only other people that compare to her in speed: men. Kaitie could have swam in the men's finals for the event and gotten 6th, which is essentially absurd and, you guessed it, makes her comparable to men.

Its like how they don't compare the new BMW M3 to a Honda Accord. They're not in the same class. In the same sense, Katie has in many ways transcended her cohort of women athletes and is now in a higher class of swimmers: men, who are unequivocally faster in every Olympic swimming event. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685661660.0" user="tanacobus" delta="False">
    <text>Right, as stated in this thread already, the issue isn't that she was compared to another great swimmer (Phelps). Saying something like "She rivals Phelps in skill" is a measurement of her abilities independent of gender, she would just be incidentally compared to a man. But saying "She swims like a man" or saying "She's a female Phelps" is viewing her skills in the context of how a woman *should* swim or how much better a man *should* be than her. It can be interpreted as speaking only to her technique but they were most certainly talking about her medals and skill set, not the length of her stroke. 

I don't mean to be word police or anything because I am 99. 9% positive that whoever first said that meant absolutely nothing by it. But from a de-tribalization standpoint, where we get into why we view the world in the way we do, it's an interesting thought, and maybe one worth making an effort to change. Seems like those gender expectations, however innocuous, are pretty ingrained in even the turn of phrases we use. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685203349.0" user="CireArodum" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I saw another article about sexism in the olympics which was complaining about one commentator who said of a female acrobat "she's jumping off the bars almost as high as the men". This surely is a fair point to make as men will have more strength so be able to lift-off more when they're swinging around?

So, thinking about that it doesn't seem off. The man jump higher. She almost jumped as high as the men. It's factual. I wonder though, if you'd find a commentator saying about a male gymnast or something "he's almost as flexible as the women," or "he's almost as well balanced add the women."

There is a somewhat underlying tendency in or society to have a male = physically superior mentality, rather than a male = differently physically superior than women. For women, it seems that comparing them to men is supposed to be a complement. But for men you don't really hear them complementarily compared to women. "He throws like a girl" doesn't mean he throws in a differently good way. It means he throws poorly.

So, the comment definitely wasn't intended sexism, but it might be a window into our ingrained societal bias. We always praise women for doing things that fit the male version of excellence. But we don't praise men for doing the female version of excellence. And if we do, we certainly don't refer to the person as being female-like.

And at the end of the day we as a society seem to place higher value on the things men tend to excel at versus the things that women tend to excel at, and we've created our sports around the things that men tend to excel at.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685244589.0" user="profheg_II" delta="False">
    <text>But comparing one gender to the performance of the other, when the other is better on average, is quite complimentary. The flexibility example you give is a good point though; while that would be complimentary to a male gymnast in the same way as we're talking about Katie Ledecky it does feel like that sort of thing wouldn't be said. So even if the comments themselves aren't sexist maybe there is a bit of a bias in which ones get said more.

I do believe a lot of things which get blasted as sexist shouldn't though. There seems to be a fundamental difficulty that people have in first going "men are on average stronger than women" (true), but then NOT jumping from that to an opinion that men are somehow then worth more than women. Men and women are generally better at different things, but none of that should make one sex more valuable as a people than the other. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685184778.0" user="YourKneesAreWeird" delta="False">
    <text>When people have said she swims like a man, they are not talking about her speed or ability, they are talking about her technique. She has a long, galloping stroke that is almost never seen in females, while it is very common in males. It is a comment on her style of swimming, and is not sexist. It is just pointing out that she is using a technique most commonly used by men</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685745930.0" user="Siiimo" delta="False">
    <text>I understand what you're saying, but men swim better. The women winning gold would be ranked around 800th to 1000th with their times. If there was something biological about being gay that objectively lowered your performance, then that wouldn't be a homophobic phrase. The phrase "she swims like a man" is obviously saying she swims like an olympic man, or she swims like those that are ranked hundreds of spots above her.

I think the only way you can perceive this as sexism is if you don't acknowledge significant biological differences between men and women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28689150882.0" user="my-stereo-heart" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point but I think the frustrating thing is having to be compared to a man in order to establish some kind of reputability, as if she couldn't be an accomplished athlete as a woman.

Male gymnasts and volleyball players don't get described as "the male ___" or "performs like a girl". Probably because men are generally seen as more desirable in sports overall and being compared to a woman in any fashion is seen as degrading, as opposed to being compared to a man. Women's sports overall are less appreciated and revered than men's sports (look at the discrepancy outside the Olympics between men and women's soccer, and how much attention either side gets).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28689200038.0" user="Siiimo" delta="False">
    <text>But it's not sexism that makes men seem more desirable in sports, it's biology. Sports is about being the best, and men are simply better. So saying he "performs like a girl" would, objectively, be an insult to any top level male athlete. Saying "she performs like a man" is complimentary, because the top level men are much, much better than her.

Regardless of all that, if in 2008 a woman had swept every single medal, and kept it up, and now coming into these olympics was the most decorated athlete of all time, and Phelps was starting out now, he would absolutely be described as "the male Mary Jane." It's just using a point of reference, the turn of phrase doesn't even have to do with sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28689769802.0" user="my-stereo-heart" delta="False">
    <text>Men are not objectively the best at every sport. Women have the edge in many fields such as gymnastics, yet even with female-dominated activities men would never be compared to a female athlete. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
