<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="297873535.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/">
    <title>CMV: Describing someone as "the female Michael Phelps" is not insulting, and saying so is being ridiculous and hyper-sensitive.</title>
    <original_poster>Siiimo</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just saw an article calling out announcers for referring to Katie Ledecky as "the female Michael Phelps." The suggestion being that that was sexist, and why not refer to Michael Phelps as "the male Katie Ledecky?"

This seems pretty clearly ridiculous. Phelps is the most decorated Olympian of all time, one of the most recognizable names in the world, and has shattered many olympic and world records. Ledecky has four medals. A laudable achievement for sure, but nowhere even close to Phelps'. Famous people are compared all the time to others. "The Michael Jordan of _____" "The George Washington of ______" "The male Rosa Parks"

This is a common turn of phrase. To claim that it is sexist and not a compliment is insanity. Am I missing something?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28685187474.0" user="dave_881" delta="False">
    <text>I think what many find offensive about phrases like "the female X," is that they draw attention directly to the person's gender ahead of their achievements. 

This can feel as though their achievement is inherently inferior because of gender.  I think it is seen in the same vein as "she's an amazing swimmer, for a girl" 

As others here have said, it would be more inclusive to say "she's the next Michael Phelps."  I think this does a better job of capturing her perceived potential to dominate in her sport in the same way that he has over a long and impressive career. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685252169.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As others here have said, it would be more inclusive to say "she's the next Michael Phelps."  I think this does a better job of capturing her perceived potential to dominate in her sport in the same way that he has over a long and impressive career. 

I generally agree that it must suck to be constantly compared to someone in this way. The problem in this case is that their performances are directly comparable and she will never hold a candle against Phelps in any event they have in common.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685303362.0" user="dave_881" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not trying to say that they should compete against each other, rather that different phrasing downplays gender as an important qualifier while highlighting her potential to build a similarly impressive reign at the top of her sport. 

Something more in the vein of celebrated boxers who would never fight each other because they are in drastically different weight classes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685329784.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>People love talking about who's better between differently sized boxers. Pound for pound lists are always hotly debated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28689122168.0" user="rafabulsing" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, it would be kinda weird calling her "the next Michael Phelps" considering we still have, you know... The current Michael Phelps. He will continue to be the most accomplished Olympian ever for some time, still. The only way the comparison to Phelps works, is exactly when you consider the female and male divisions as being separated from each other. Which makes her, indeed, "the female Phelps".

The other way of phrasing it would be "she is almost as good as Phelps", which in my opinion sound so much more belittling, because it brings to attention the fact of her not objectively not as good as Phelps, while the other phrasing at least puts them as equals, aside from gender. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
