<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="297873535.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/">
    <title>CMV: Describing someone as "the female Michael Phelps" is not insulting, and saying so is being ridiculous and hyper-sensitive.</title>
    <original_poster>Siiimo</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just saw an article calling out announcers for referring to Katie Ledecky as "the female Michael Phelps." The suggestion being that that was sexist, and why not refer to Michael Phelps as "the male Katie Ledecky?"

This seems pretty clearly ridiculous. Phelps is the most decorated Olympian of all time, one of the most recognizable names in the world, and has shattered many olympic and world records. Ledecky has four medals. A laudable achievement for sure, but nowhere even close to Phelps'. Famous people are compared all the time to others. "The Michael Jordan of _____" "The George Washington of ______" "The male Rosa Parks"

This is a common turn of phrase. To claim that it is sexist and not a compliment is insanity. Am I missing something?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28684992254.0" user="DBerwick" delta="False">
    <text>There are simply better alternatives, and failure to use them highlights an implication of sexual discrimination.

If it was a man, they might say "this year's Michael Phelps", or else not make the comparison at all. And that could fit just as well for a woman. But saying "Female Michael Phelps" is promoting the notion that athletes should be classified by gender.

Of course, I can't say that I find anything terribly wrong with this, since the Olympic sports are divided by gender anyway. Just saying she's the American Woman team's answer to Michael Phelps, highlighting that she'll likely become an icon for American sports as he has. But I think that's a bit more subtle than the initial description really provided. So I guess this is just my two cents, and not a conclusive argument for or against.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685024333.0" user="tigerhawkvok" delta="False">
    <text>It's unfortunately muddled by this year being... Well, this year. There is a male Michael Phelps, it's Michael Phelps. Nor can you say "American", since so is he.

The least gendered thing I can think of is "may be another Phelps", or, "an up and coming MP", but that minimizes this year's accomplishments in favor of a decade from now, so that's still poor.

While a gendered statement, I think it's the most laudatory thing to say for her current achievements without being speculatory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685025905.0" user="skrill_talk" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't athletes already classified by their gender? Men and women typically don't compete. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685171367.0" user="agoddamnlegend" delta="False">
    <text>What's wrong with promoting the notion that athletes should be divided by gender?   They **do** have to be divided by gender.  That's not sexist, that's a biological fact.  If there was no gender separation, then no woman would ever qualify for the Olympics in anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28696716024.0" user="Stevey854" delta="False">
    <text>Possibly in shooting, gymnastics and diving. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28696975996.0" user="agoddamnlegend" delta="False">
    <text>You should watch the difference between women and men in gymnastics.  Simone Biles is the GOAT female gymnast and she can't do anything the guys are doing.  Don't know anything about the other sports though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697000014.0" user="Stevey854" delta="False">
    <text>But there is still the fact that men do not train for a bunch of events that the women do, men do high bar where women do high and low bars. Men do rings and pommel horse, women do beam. 

This specialization would (only initially, I admit) mean that women would still medal in the current games even if men and women could compete in all events. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685238333.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But saying "Female Michael Phelps" is promoting the notion that athletes should be classified by gender.

Aren't the Olympics designed to do this anyway?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685251740.0" user="UrbanZenMonk" delta="False">
    <text>They are classified by gender. Do you see men and women competing against one another? No, because they aren't equal.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
