<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="297873535.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/">
    <title>CMV: Describing someone as "the female Michael Phelps" is not insulting, and saying so is being ridiculous and hyper-sensitive.</title>
    <original_poster>Siiimo</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just saw an article calling out announcers for referring to Katie Ledecky as "the female Michael Phelps." The suggestion being that that was sexist, and why not refer to Michael Phelps as "the male Katie Ledecky?"

This seems pretty clearly ridiculous. Phelps is the most decorated Olympian of all time, one of the most recognizable names in the world, and has shattered many olympic and world records. Ledecky has four medals. A laudable achievement for sure, but nowhere even close to Phelps'. Famous people are compared all the time to others. "The Michael Jordan of _____" "The George Washington of ______" "The male Rosa Parks"

This is a common turn of phrase. To claim that it is sexist and not a compliment is insanity. Am I missing something?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28685106629.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>It's a question of context. On it's own, it might sound fairly innocuous, but it comes in the context of a lot of rather sexist coverage of sportswomen. Things like where male coaches are given absurd levels of credit for the work of female athletes, the level of commentary on female athlete's appearance, and the overcategorization of women as "female athletes" while men are just "athletes". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685140413.0" user="scouseking90" delta="False">
    <text>I think that coaches allways get alot of attention. An example is  Andy Murray  ( current Olympic got for mens tennis) where it made mainstream news when he changed coach's.  The fact that the coach is male is historical as men have been professional athletes for longer and will then retreat and become coaches. 

This is complete over hype. If you said the British Mike Phelps would that be anti-British ?  If you said this runner runs like they are 4 inches taller is this anti hight. 

Comparsents are fine imo. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685181943.0" user="agoddamnlegend" delta="False">
    <text>Coaches always get a lot of credit for athlete success.  There are people who legitimately think that even Tom Brady is just a product of Bill Belichick's system.  So don't act like this is something unique with women's sports.  

And I think it does make sense to clarify that somebody is a great *female* athlete.  Just due to biology, there has never and will never be a woman that can compete with the best men in any sport that requires any bit strength.  So Ledecky is a great swimmer, *for a woman*, because there are literally thousands and thousands of *people* on earth that are much faster than her.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685240327.0" user="foomits" delta="False">
    <text>this is my feeling.  it only becomes sexist when there is even playing ground between men and woman.  "that's a pretty good book, for a woman" that's sexist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685269881.0" user="agoddamnlegend" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely agree.  Saying that would be sexist because women and men are equally capable of writing books.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685583887.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>There's nothing wrong with coaches getting credit. There's something wrong with coaches getting all the credit

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/early-lead/wp/2016/08/07/the-man-responsible-nbc-broadcaster-draws-ire-after-crediting-world-record-to-swimmers-husband/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685247459.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Things like where male coaches are given absurd levels of credit for the work of female athletes

I watch mma and I can name you half a dozen coaches who get praised regularly during fight commentary for improving specific (male) fighters' techniques. Examples off the top of my head: Freddy Roach, Rafael Cordeiro, Mike Winklejohn and Greg Jackson, Duane Ludwig, etc. And coaches who get a lot if shit when their athletes don't perform well. This only seems to be a problem from the perspective of people who don't watch individual sports.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685582291.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>Coaches can and should get praise, but they should not be described as being solely responsible for an athlete's achievements.

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/early-lead/wp/2016/08/07/the-man-responsible-nbc-broadcaster-draws-ire-after-crediting-world-record-to-swimmers-husband/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685637626.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm..."solely". I don't see that part.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
