<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="297873535.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/">
    <title>CMV: Describing someone as "the female Michael Phelps" is not insulting, and saying so is being ridiculous and hyper-sensitive.</title>
    <original_poster>Siiimo</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just saw an article calling out announcers for referring to Katie Ledecky as "the female Michael Phelps." The suggestion being that that was sexist, and why not refer to Michael Phelps as "the male Katie Ledecky?"

This seems pretty clearly ridiculous. Phelps is the most decorated Olympian of all time, one of the most recognizable names in the world, and has shattered many olympic and world records. Ledecky has four medals. A laudable achievement for sure, but nowhere even close to Phelps'. Famous people are compared all the time to others. "The Michael Jordan of _____" "The George Washington of ______" "The male Rosa Parks"

This is a common turn of phrase. To claim that it is sexist and not a compliment is insanity. Am I missing something?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28685224825.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>How often do you hear a man being compared to a woman? Using your Rosa Parks example, how many men have been called that?  

Now flip it around. How many women are compared to men? A lot. An awful lot. 

Men are still the standard, and this is another instance, thus it is an example of sexism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685250216.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>In athletics, men are the standard because their performance is better. Women's divisions are created so women can compete. Without that distinction, there would be no women in the Olympics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685263403.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>Their performance might be better, but these comparisons are not about performances, they are about accomplishments. Steffi Graf and Serena Williams have won more singles tennis majors than anyone, male or female, but when is a man referred to as the "next Steffi Graf"? Never. Women can and do accomplish more but are not the standard for medals, wins, contribution to society, whatever, because of sexism. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685332273.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>Because any high level man could've beaten all of That 's opponents without trying. It's like saying a bad golfer is better than a pro when you include their handicap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685648296.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>I addressed that here:

https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/d6eoyx7</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685688694.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>But winning as an achievement is not as impressive at a lower level of competition. Plain and simple. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685906071.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>You are not giving any consideration  to my posts, you are just parroting yourself. I'm out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28686029513.0" user="crustalmighty" delta="False">
    <text>I considered your post and how it was not addressing our conversation and tried to continue our conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685271166.0" user="foomits" delta="False">
    <text>sexism implies there is prejudice or discrimination involved.  the greatest female athletes in any given sport wouldn't make a division 3 men's team in most cases... and it wouldnt be because they are women, they just aren't as good.  I don't see how facts are sexist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685294830.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>I addressed that here:

https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/4xcgov/cmv_describing_someone_as_the_female_michael/d6egqwb</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685310549.0" user="foomits" delta="False">
    <text>They dont get the same recognition because they aren't playing against the best competition.  if a 10 year old peewee football players runs for 600 yards in a game, we wouldn't be comparing him to an nfl player.  if a premiere mens tennis player was called the next Serena williams, it wouldnt make any sense because he would already be significantly better than serena ever was.

we do it all the time with men in other ways.  Tim tebow is widely considered one of the best college athletes of all time, but he didn't do shit at the highest level so noone cares.  female athletes are no different, their accomplishments are only impressive in relation to other women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685647051.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>You make it sound as if the only times women and men are compared is based on superior athletic talent. That is NOT the only time. You also make it sound as though people are only compared to those who are the best in their sport. That is not true either. To use your own example, other athletes are most definitely compared to Tim Tebow. People- not just athletes- are compared for other reasons. They are compared for failure. They are compared for contributing to a cause. They are compared for being clutch. Being clutch, for example, is something that can be compared regardless of the level of competition. So does being Bill Buckner. But women are never used as the standard for comparison. Ever. 

This is not just true in athletics, it's true in anything. It's true in business, in social activism (see Rosa Parks in the OP). Women are held up against men for almost everything, while women are the standard for very little, if anything. 

Thus, my original point stands: this is one example of many of society systemically ignoring women's contributions, and thus it is sexism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28686365076.0" user="foomits" delta="False">
    <text>who's the female equilevant of  bill gates, albert Einstein, Michael jordan?  we can't help that until 20 or 30 years ago women were not afforded the same opportunities as men.

edit: though athletics was the original cmv topic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28686373868.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>This is a valid point. I'm not sure where the tipping point should be, but the fact that no woman has been used as the comparison for men at all, ever, says to me that it's likely more than simply a lack of candidates. And it is possible that such women do not exist because for years society has chosen not to elevate the successful women as much as men. But I will concede that your question is valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28689021256.0" user="UCISee" delta="False">
    <text>I'm obviously coming in late here, but I can't let it stand. You're talking in theoreticals. 'No woman has been used as the comparison for men, at all, ever" there is literally no way you can know this. However, as the poster before you mentions, until (and this is generous) 20-30 years ago women weren't afforded those opportunities. The OP was about Michael Phelps. He's literally the greatest Olympian/athelete in history. He is the yardstick. The next MALE Olympian of such stature will be regarded as the 'new MP' or 'MP 2.0'. Furthermore they were directly comparing swimmers and Michael Phelps simply came before Ledecky. So in a number of metrics the sexist argument goes out the window. We're Ledecky 31 and MP 19 and she had the most Olympic medals ever I am literally certain they would have said he was the male Ledecky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28689449322.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>You had me until the last sentence.

I understand the point that Phelps is the greatest. I will concede that in his case, it's not sexist. But your last sentence will not happen as things stand today.  Give me an example. Prove me wrong. I bet you can't, whereas I can give you several examples of women with greater accomplishments failing to be the yardstick. Steffi Graf is one, and she has held her tennis records for twenty years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685738621.0" user="Siiimo" delta="False">
    <text>In this case the standard is the best olympian of all time. If it had been a female who had won as many medals as Phelps, the comparison would be reversed. But he's the biggest, most well known, most accomplished olympian. the comparison in and of itself is not sexist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685903674.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>I wish OP had not deleted the post, but I can go along with that in this case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28685922942.0" user="Siiimo" delta="False">
    <text>...OP? Of what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28694381478.0" user="Awisemanoncsaid" delta="False">
    <text>Is it the same for me to call one male athlete beating on another male athlete "The male Tonya Harding."?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28694471226.0" user="NewYorkerinGeorgia" delta="False">
    <text>I would consider that an example of a woman being the standard, and would change my view that women are not used as the standard for men. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
