<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697427469.0" user="Br0metheus" delta="False">
    <text>I'm having a real tough time understanding your conclusion here. For the sake of argument, let's say I accept your assertions regarding a difference in mean IQ, and that IQ is the *cause* and not the *effect* of education, social class, etc. Then, you go on to say:

&amp;gt; If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.

You've just made an argument to *not* change our standards based upon race. If a smaller proportion of the black population is capable of these kind of feats, it would be *expected* that they'd be underrepresented in schools and jobs. 

Are you implying that we should grant an exception to a specific group simply because they can't reliably meet the same standards applied to everybody else? Why the hell should schools and employers willingly lower their standards to accommodate an under-performing group, *especially* if the difference in performance is due to lack of inherent ability, as opposed to opportunity/discrimination/whatnot?

Standards are set where they are because *ability actually matters.* If you're hiring somebody to be an engineer, then it's because they can *perform the necessary tasks.* If you can't do the job, then you can't do the job, and I shouldn't have to pay you for your non-performance.

Also, think of it this scenario: two people of different race both have an IQ of 100 and apply for the same opening. Should institutions have an obligation to one over the other, just because of their race? What matters more; performance relative to *our own group*, or performance *in the absolute*? Clearly the latter, because the universe at large isn't going to go easy on you because you got dealt a rough genetic hand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697438596.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstood.  If black people are say 10% of the pop. and they only represent 3% of a colleges pop. That's okay, and explainable by the difference in IQ.  I don't think we should lower our standards so that those numbers are equal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697676348.0" user="Br0metheus" delta="False">
    <text>Then the statement in your post title doesn't accurately or clearly represent your thesis. You explicitly stated that we *should not* try to hold black people to the same standards as others.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
