<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697169915.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>Race is a social construct. The scientific community is in agreement that race the only significant differences between races are phenotypical. The American Anthropological Association states "human populations are not unambiguous, clearly demarcated, biologically distinct groups"  Because of this any differences in IQ between races can't be caused by race. It is more likely that the bell curves differ due to environmental and sociological factors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697243883.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>Yes humans exist on a spectrum, but there are definite differences between races, for instance:

* Cystic fibrosis, the most common life-limiting autosomal recessive disease among people of Northern European heritage

* Sickle-cell anemia, most prevalent in populations with sub-Saharan African ancestry but also common among Latin-American, Indian, and Saudi Arab populations, as well as those people of South European regions such as Turkey, Greece, and Italy

* Lactose intolerance affects (over their lifetime) as many as 25% of Europeans but up to 50-80% of Hispanics, along with people from southern India and Ashkenazi Jews, but nearly 100% of Native Americans.

Regardless of what you believe about race, there ARE genetic differences between races, so much so that some races are much more likely to develop certain diseases.  Then is it a stretch to say that intelligence is just one of the many things that make one race different from another?

You can say race is a social construct, but the fact is that there exist significant genetic differences within the human species across the planet, many of these differences are aligned with what part of the world you or your ancestors came from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697370228.0" user="hurf_mcdurf" delta="False">
    <text>Intelligence is phenotype.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697381450.0" user="Br0metheus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  The scientific community is in agreement that race the only significant differences between races are phenotypical.

Your argument is incoherent. I'll agree that it's very difficult to draw clear boundaries around racial groups, but that's not the point. Phenotype *is directly influenced* by the genotype, and it's patently obvious that there are *general* differences between populations on a genetic level. It is *literally impossible* that we'd see this much physical variation if the gene pool was homogenous. Why is it that Africans populations have a much higher incidence of sickle-cell anemia? Why do Ashkenazi Jews have a higher incidence of Tay-Sachs? 

And how, exactly, can you ignore the relationship between phenotype and cognition? Unless you believe in some fantastic, otherworldly explanation for intelligence, you can't possibly hold this position. Intelligence originates in the brain, and isn't the brain a physical organ? Are you trying to say that the neurological organization of the brain, which is *hugely* dependent on a complex machinery of cells, proteins, and neurotransmitters, is not *strongly* influenced by genetics? If genes don't matter, then why are people with Down's Syndrome reliably mentally disabled? Why can't dogs and cats learn to understand speech the way humans do? If you say it's because their *brains* are different than ours, the only reason for that is because their *genes* are different than ours.

You literally *cannot have* phenotypical differences without genetic ones, and you can't draw a line in the sand between physical and mental characteristics. You're essentially taking the "100% nurture" position in the nature-nurture debate, which is both theoretically and empirically unsound.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
