<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697324911.0" user="virtuallyvirtuous" delta="False">
    <text>Three points.

(1.) Dismissing people on factors they have no control over is bad, regardless of whether they bear any statistical meaning. If I were a lazy asshole, I could dismiss everyone in a wheelchair as potentially retarded, since people in wheelchairs are significantly more likely to be retarded than other people. Thus, it makes sense to just avoid having to deal with wheelchair users altogether. Of course this would be a horrible, and senseless thing to do.

The same applies to race. Say on average black people score 20 points lower on an IQ test. This means the blacks I'll have to deal with will probably be pretty stupid. However, **we should think of the few black people who do have an high IQ.** They shouldn't be disadvantaged. 

(2.) Yet this doesn't seem to be what you're getting at. **You are not talking about opportunity, but outcome.** On this point, **I agree with you.** If a certain demographic can be shown to get less out of something, we shouldn't expect them to take part in it as much as any other demographic. For instance, if it's actually true most women will enjoy an engineering job less, then we shouldn't expect men and women to become engineers in equal numbers.

However, **the statistics you refer to are questionable to say the least.** Sub-Saharan Africa has to deal with severe malnutrition, disease, warfare, and lower levels of education. There is no reason to believe anything you've cited indicates anything about black people as a race. In the United States, there are also factors outside of genetics, that will impact the IQ of the black population significantly. **When you look at countries where black people are a tiny minority, you'll find they aren't less intelligent.**

(3.) A large part of the reason African-Americans are less intelligent than European-Americans is their learned behavior. **Learned behavior can be tackled effectively by changing your expectations.** If you expect a child to whine and cry, it will whine and cry, but if you treat them as if they're reasonable human beings, you'll find they will often act responsibly. By the same principle, **expecting black people to be smart will cause them to be smart.** The inverse is also true.

Also, **when you expect black people to do more difficult jobs**, they may at first be ill-fit, but **gradually their culture will shift**, and they will become very good. Think of how Jews became such successful bankers. They were forced to be, since no one allowed them to take any other job. Nothing in their nature makes them good bankers, it's purely circumstance and how they adapted to it.

As a TL;DR I boldfaced the most significant stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697369378.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>1. I don't think that analogy really fits because being in a wheelchair isn't a naturally occurring thing, the correlation between being in a wheel chair and being retarded is entirely explainable through causation, nobody is retarded because they sat in a wheelchair.  I'm not arguing that we should treat individuals differently I'm arguing that if black people make up 10% of the population, it's understandable that they're less than 10% of a college population.

2. The Sub-Saharan statistic is admittedly not directly applicable to The United States, but my other statistic concerning black people in the US is. "When you look at countries where black people are a tiny minority, you'll find they aren't less intelligent."  I'd like to see a study on this, but that sounds like further evidence for IQ being genetic and not learned.
3. IQ is 75% inherited according to the American Psychiatric Association.

EDIT: I a word</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697514037.0" user="virtuallyvirtuous" delta="False">
    <text>(1.) There _is_ a direct causal connection between the race and the social position of blacks in the US. 

(2.) [Here's an article on it in the UK.](http://www.unz.com/article/the-iq-gap-is-no-longer-a-black-and-white-issue/) Very few studies have been done on the topic, it seems.

(3.) Inheritance isn't the same as genetics, and genetics aren't the same as racial differences. You may have large differences due to genetics _within_ a certain race, while on average these differences make no difference.

My main point still stands. If there is a cultural component to this (there is), and it disadvantages individuals (it does), raising your standards seems like a good way to tackle it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697395315.0" user="hurf_mcdurf" delta="False">
    <text>It's pretty obvious that OP is talking about a supposed genetic predisposition to traits that would equate to general intelligence, not whether or not we should expect every black person to have low IQ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697565109.0" user="virtuallyvirtuous" delta="False">
    <text>_Holding black people to an intellectual standard_ certainly means expecting something of them, OP was ambiguous as to how this works. Like I said, he's probably talking about statistical outcome for the entire population, but it could also mean having prejudices on an individual level. 

I also wanted to make the point that whatever the conclusion here might be, racism is never justified, something a lot of people on the internet don't seem to get.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
