<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697200588.0" user="Oliver5366" delta="False">
    <text>[There is a fairly strong possibility that IQ tests and the like contain various forms of racial bias.](http://www.education.com/reference/article/cultural-bias-in-testing/)

&amp;gt;If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115)

It doesn't, necessarily. Those things are largely about specific forms of intelligence and hard work. Someone with an IQ of 70 might not be capable of it, but someone with a 100 certainly could be with hard work.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
