<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697235991.0" user="overthrow23" delta="False">
    <text>I've worked for several large corporations and the upper managers did not appear to be that intelligent to me - are you sure it's really a requirement?

Seriously, though, I argue as a devil's advocate, meaning I don't necessarily buy the premise but will treat it as true for discussion's sake.

The existence of a low IQ trend among Black people in certain populations is not indicative of every Black (not African American, because I'm speaking internationally) in *that population* let alone the entire world.

To assume less of a population because of traits shared by some of even most of the population cannot be fair when the two are indistinguishable visually.  To use the sub-saharan example you raised, statistically some of those Africans will be geniuses.   But since they look like everyone else, they would have crappy lives because of everyone always assuming they were like everyone else.  That's not fair.  And since they are likely to become leaders in their community, by tagging them  with the low IQ generalization, we are in effect hobbling what development we can expect out of that community.

Have you heard of the soft bigotry of low expectations?  Or the principle of people rising to meet the expectations of others?  When we place such limiting language on people, it really matters.  Not only to them, by impacting their collective self image, but by others around them.  Tagging them as as a race of dullards cannot bode well for future race relations, even if true.

Sorry for any tangents.  I know when constructing logical arguments, one isn't supposed to let emotion get in the way, but I really feel for folks judged based upon factors they can't help.  For example, I'm white but my ancestors never owned slaves or even lived in the US during that era.  Yet I am, in some quarters, deemed to be the recipient of some kind of "privilege", an oppressor, an angry white male, uptight, out of touch, based upon *a reputation* of what *other whites did?*  So I can't in good conscience allow the same to be done to others, or I'd be a hypocrite.

For this reason, please change your view from "unreasonable" to "reasonable".  It doesn't mean that you're suddenly going to be out supporting affirmative action and BLM.  It just means that you recognize that Black people aren't going anywhere, and they deserve to be treated as individuals, rather than data on an IQ printout.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697270044.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you in that when it comes to job applications and the like you should be judged entirely on ability.  On the same note as a doctor you should diagnose a disease based on the symptoms and if you know that a certain race is more prone to a certain disease, should you not take that into consideration?

On a side note, I don't consider myself racist and I really did come here to have my view changed, but I don't like that this is such a touchy topic. If you make a joke about Asians being more intelligen than white people (they statistically are) nobody cares, but if you make the same joke about white people and black people it's a no-go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697296471.0" user="overthrow23" delta="False">
    <text>*know that a certain race is more prone to a certain disease, should you not take that into consideration*

Possibly, but you should not vaccinate everyone willy-nilly - you have to make sure the patient is even "sick".  


Plus, IQ can be changed en masse.  As an example, something as simple as lead paint in an area could lower them, to be corrected after a generation or two of lead-free living.  If the IQ issue one is real, we cannot rule out other factors, biological or cultural, that may change in only a generation, altering the premises upon which this argument is based.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697355423.0" user="virtuallyvirtuous" delta="False">
    <text>"Playing devil's advocate" means you're advocating a position contrary to your own. What you're doing is arguing "ad hominem," but in its original meaning, which isn't a fallacy, but a very respectable thing to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697423724.0" user="overthrow23" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the correction!  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
