<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697223302.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever taken an IQ test?

A major portion of it (the part I personally do very well on, as an aside) is literally a vocabulary test.  Another part of it is basically trivia: they ask you about historical figures.  Some of the scoring is seeing if you can answer concisely but with nuance.... but if you never learned the words or the facts, you can't get points.

Other things relate to categorization, "What do these four things have in common?"  It's 100% whether you've learned the categories; it's not stuff you can puzzle out. "Oh, those are all amphibians."

The things these tests measure ARE indeed useful.  They don't have nothing at all to do with innate ability.  But the lion's share of the variance is clearly explained by schooling: quality but also kind.  You should NOT take IQ score as some kind of universal, pure mark of ability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697254571.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>There isn't one IQ test.  Raven's Progressive Matrices has no words at all, but still there exist differences in scores across race.  Across many different IQ tests people of African descent score lower than average.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
