<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697196873.0" user="orygunmane" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.

Except it doesn't.  Stupid people, regardless of race, have started successful businesses and achievements throughout history.  Google the history of Kinkos.  It was started by a guy who basically failed out of high school and was written off as an idiot.

Furthermore, IQ is a metric that is not scientific, unreliable and generally invoked by those who use the number to prove to themselves they are smart, rather than an actual measure of how smart you are.  General intelligence does not take into account someone's creative abilities, social skills or drive to work hard, all of which contribute to school performance, ability to complete educational programs and job performance.  

No college application asks you what your IQ is.  No employer makes you take an IQ test.  No bank requires you to provide proof of your IQ for a loan if you have a good business plan.  

IQ may measure some specific aspects of intelligence, but it in no way determines the capability of anyone.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697221697.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>IQ is very much a scientific measure, that is unless you don't consider psychology to be a science. And of course no college application asks for IQ.

But this doesn't mean IQ doesn't matter, IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance as I mentioned in my OP.  Saying IQ doesn't matter is like saying the horsepower of a vehicle has no affect on it's maximum speed, sure there are other factors but you can't ignore a major factor just because it's not the only factor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28699362863.0" user="super-commenting" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And of course no college application asks for IQ.

Colleges don't need to know your IQ because they know your SAT score and the correlation between the two is around .8</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697243296.0" user="virtuallyvirtuous" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; IQ may measure some specific aspects of intelligence, but it in no way determines the capability of anyone.

Not on an individual level, but that doesn't imply it's meaningless on a demographic. Take one person, and based on his IQ you won't be able to make any meaningful predictions. Take a hundred people, or a million people, and you'll see that IQ is a scientifically reliable indicator of all sorts of things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697412099.0" user="hurf_mcdurf" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No employer makes you take an IQ test.

Don't many police forces require officers to be under a certain IQ?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
