<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="307605532.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5351y4/cmv_major_corporate_failings_such_as_deceptive/">
    <title>CMV: Major corporate failings (such as deceptive subprime lending) should result in punishments at all levels of individual responsibility.</title>
    <original_poster>luminarium</original_poster>
    <original_post>The process would be as follows: 

1. Society should find out who is directly responsible / performed the action
2. Did he report it to his superior and at least one other person in his chain of command (ie. superior's superior)?
3. If no, then he's fired, fined for the full amount of his past year's salary, and banned from the industry for three years.
4. For all the people he reported the issue to, or who knew about the issue, and who should have done something about this, but didn't, or who should have reported it up further, but didn't: repeat steps 2, 3, and 4.

As a corollary, all corporations should be required to educate employees that they are to report anything that could potentially be seen as immoral or illegal, to not just their supervisor but someone further up the chain of command, and to educate them of the consequences should they fail to do so. Supervisors are to be educated that if they become aware of the issue and take no action to fix or escalate the issue, that they will be held responsible as well. 
This policy wouldn't be retroactive.

The idea is that if the underlings had duly reported the issue and the supervisors hadn't, the supervisors would be punished. Every single individual who should have reported or done something to fix the issue but didn't would simultaneously be held liable. If the issue had been reported all the way up to the executive level, then the fines would be massive (since executives make far more). This way there would be incentive for issues to be escalated all the way up, and an incentive for those with the decision making power to do something about it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28765311570.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>You can't legislate morality.

Look at what is happening with Wells Fargo right now.  http://www.wsj.com/articles/how-wells-fargos-high-pressure-sales-culture-spiraled-out-of-control-1474053044 

You report problems to your supervisor - you aren't a "team player", get fired and something token happens to appears to address the problem.  No supervisor wants to know about "problems" that actually keeps them employed by allowing them to meet their goals.

&amp;gt; If the issue had been reported all the way up to the executive level, then the fines would be massive (since executives make far more).

With Wells Fargo it did go up to the senior level.  The results was investigations and reports, some firings and some easing of goals.  The problem was still there yet the senior managers could say "Hey, we did something about it.  Its not our fault employees don't follow our code of ethics.".  Finger pointing and "miscommunication" all around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28765342101.0" user="luminarium" delta="False">
    <text>Getting fired for reporting problems is already illegal, isn't it? That ought also be treated per the above proposal ie the manager doing the firing would be fired and banned from the industry.

If after some firings/easing of goals the problem is still there then the senior managers haven't solved the problem, time to fire and ban them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28765365398.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Getting fired for reporting problems is already illegal, isn't it? 

They get fired for "not being a team player", which is legal.  

&amp;gt; If after some firings/easing of goals the problem is still there then the senior managers haven't solved the problem, time to fire and ban them.

"The problems are getting solved, just look at all we are doing, it just takes time so don't fire us."  This is exactly what Wells Fargo is saying how they are addressing their problems.   

There are so many ways around your rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28767033135.0" user="luminarium" delta="False">
    <text>There's such a thing as whistleblower protections. I understand those are pretty crappy but the solution would be to improve those protections.

The "we are working on it" excuse is fine, but the people who started off doing it wrong can still be kicked out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
