<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="307605532.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5351y4/cmv_major_corporate_failings_such_as_deceptive/">
    <title>CMV: Major corporate failings (such as deceptive subprime lending) should result in punishments at all levels of individual responsibility.</title>
    <original_poster>luminarium</original_poster>
    <original_post>The process would be as follows: 

1. Society should find out who is directly responsible / performed the action
2. Did he report it to his superior and at least one other person in his chain of command (ie. superior's superior)?
3. If no, then he's fired, fined for the full amount of his past year's salary, and banned from the industry for three years.
4. For all the people he reported the issue to, or who knew about the issue, and who should have done something about this, but didn't, or who should have reported it up further, but didn't: repeat steps 2, 3, and 4.

As a corollary, all corporations should be required to educate employees that they are to report anything that could potentially be seen as immoral or illegal, to not just their supervisor but someone further up the chain of command, and to educate them of the consequences should they fail to do so. Supervisors are to be educated that if they become aware of the issue and take no action to fix or escalate the issue, that they will be held responsible as well. 
This policy wouldn't be retroactive.

The idea is that if the underlings had duly reported the issue and the supervisors hadn't, the supervisors would be punished. Every single individual who should have reported or done something to fix the issue but didn't would simultaneously be held liable. If the issue had been reported all the way up to the executive level, then the fines would be massive (since executives make far more). This way there would be incentive for issues to be escalated all the way up, and an incentive for those with the decision making power to do something about it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28765190887.0" user="TheRealHouseLives" delta="False">
    <text>The problem comes in finding who lied, who was lied to, who was mistaken, who was ignorant, and who was used as a straight up patsy. 
If the CEO tells his underling to maximize profits from this sector. The underling looks at several companies doing well in that sector, identifies several with similar structures to his company, and tell HIS underling to research those companies, find out what they are doing right, and copy them. She sends her team out to research, they come back with a series of suggestions, several of which make .... creative use of "technically-legal" endeavors. She brings those up to her boss, who sends them over to legal to check. Legal informs them that they CAN do this within the law if they follow strict guidelines, and are very careful with their reporting. This gets handed back down to a different underling, and told to impliment, that person hires people from the other companies researched, and they set out to make big money skirting the law. At various points lower downs make mistakes or cut corners, and in doing so gain an edge. Often-times those mistakes are overlooked or ignored, because they are minor. Over time the culture shifts, and now everyone is somewhat slipshod with the rules. A different boss is brought in and briefed, somewhat briefly, on the legal situation, and the goals (make lots of money), then that boss is given a SECOND education by all the people "in the trenches" on how it really works. A balance is struck, they report things like they're supposed to, but give their team some leaway. If they come in and report every mistake, they'll be fired for being a bad culture fit, if they crack down on every mistake they'll be fired for dropping numbers, and the whole culture of the company is telling them it's no big deal, all the other firms do it, this is how the sausage is made. So now everyone is in on it, and no one decided to do it. Who's to blame?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28765345690.0" user="luminarium" delta="False">
    <text>The proposal would only be applicable where there is potential for culpability, ie. something illegal had been done. In your example it sounds like the activity wasn't illegal, so no penalties. But if say legal got it wrong, and it actually was illegal, then legal ought to see some firing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28765365060.0" user="TheRealHouseLives" delta="False">
    <text>Oh no, there was illegality. Something that skirts the law, and has to be done in a very careful way to avoid breaking the law, then stops being done in a careful way, so various laws are broken, but only at the margins, but in aggregate it results in wholesale law-breaking and big problems. That's more or less what happened in the 2008 crash. Some straight up crime, and people got charged for it, but mostly it was just a culture of lax internal rules, which led lots of people to step over the line a bit here an there. Like a restaurant that doesn't keep on it's employees to make them stick to health codes. They aren't just letting literal shit go everwhere, but they cut corners here and there, to make things go faster, and so long as nothing catastrophic goes wrong, everything seems good, fast service, happy customers. Then it goes wrong and EVERYTHING comes out, who's to blame? That's the problem with assigning individual blame for what amounts to a cultural or institutional problem, it's all too diffuse (this argument can and HAS been applied to pretty much ALL crime, but that's a different CMV). 

edit- Specifically on legal, they correctly and honestly informed their bosses of the precise measures that would have to be taken, the forms filled out, the definitions to be abided by, the words that had to be spoken even for the process to meet legal standards. Along the chain from lawyer to say, mortgage broker at a local branch, the specifics broke down, and in practice, laws were broken. Legal told them what to do, they didn't do it. So it's on the brokers? But they're half trained and incentivised to sell and it's what everyone around them is doing and it's really only minor stuff, hinting that the person applying for a loan might include income they wouldn't usually consider "theirs" when applying for a loan, so they can get the big house they want, and the broker can get his big cut. It's against the rules, but who wants to nail the old guy who spent 3 years making 100 grand and blowing it up his nose then lost it all when he got fired? Is that justice? But that's who, in most cases, actually broke rules. The lowest on the rungs, and maybe their supervisors. It's about incentives and DADT. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28767045600.0" user="luminarium" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; then stops being done in a careful way, so various laws are broken, but only at the margins

Then whomever started to not do it in a careful way, would be punished. If he was an underling that the supervisor told to do it thus, and the underling didn't report it, underling gets booted. If the underling reported it to the superior and the superior didn't do anything and didn't report it, then the superior gets booted. If everyone in the firm starts skirting the law then they're all to be booted.

&amp;gt; Along the chain from lawyer to say, mortgage broker at a local branch, the specifics broke down, and in practice, laws were broken.

Did the local branch people get the full memo and didn't abide by it? If so the local branch people get booted. If the lawyer didn't send the memo / missed out on the crucial details then the lawyer gets booted.

&amp;gt; who wants to nail the old guy who spent 3 years making 100 grand and blowing it up his nose then lost it all when he got fired? Is that justice?

Yes. He's the one who broke the rules despite knowing that he's breaking the rules, so why wouldn't punishing him be justice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28767129312.0" user="TheRealHouseLives" delta="False">
    <text>"knowingly broke the rules" can become murky. It also makes it really easy for powerful people to use underlings as pawns, there's always someone out there willing to take the job, and there's lots of ways to encourage them to do something illegal while explicitly telling them not to (CYA), and if they get busted, no biggie, hire a new pawn. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28768109974.0" user="luminarium" delta="False">
    <text>The proposal also involves mandatory training of all employees in what is legal/illegal in their field and the need to report anything they suspect of being illegal to supervisors. And once they do so, liability would be transferred to these "powerful people" you mentioned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28766847468.0" user="poloport" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Who's to blame?

All of them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
