<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="307605532.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5351y4/cmv_major_corporate_failings_such_as_deceptive/">
    <title>CMV: Major corporate failings (such as deceptive subprime lending) should result in punishments at all levels of individual responsibility.</title>
    <original_poster>luminarium</original_poster>
    <original_post>The process would be as follows: 

1. Society should find out who is directly responsible / performed the action
2. Did he report it to his superior and at least one other person in his chain of command (ie. superior's superior)?
3. If no, then he's fired, fined for the full amount of his past year's salary, and banned from the industry for three years.
4. For all the people he reported the issue to, or who knew about the issue, and who should have done something about this, but didn't, or who should have reported it up further, but didn't: repeat steps 2, 3, and 4.

As a corollary, all corporations should be required to educate employees that they are to report anything that could potentially be seen as immoral or illegal, to not just their supervisor but someone further up the chain of command, and to educate them of the consequences should they fail to do so. Supervisors are to be educated that if they become aware of the issue and take no action to fix or escalate the issue, that they will be held responsible as well. 
This policy wouldn't be retroactive.

The idea is that if the underlings had duly reported the issue and the supervisors hadn't, the supervisors would be punished. Every single individual who should have reported or done something to fix the issue but didn't would simultaneously be held liable. If the issue had been reported all the way up to the executive level, then the fines would be massive (since executives make far more). This way there would be incentive for issues to be escalated all the way up, and an incentive for those with the decision making power to do something about it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28765588681.0" user="Dreamer-of-Dreams" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know anything about how laws and company policies usually operate, but consider the following just as a thought experiment:

Suppose a trustworthy employee makes a small legal error while devising a process which makes the company $100 on a customer over a year. Then employee tells their superior about the process and the superior - on the evidence of the employee's past reliability - assumes the process is legal. Suppose that employee then leaves the company. Suppose the replacement employee is told by the superior that the process is legal. Suppose the superior then leaves the company. The employee then builds upon the process and it now makes the company $10,000 per customer per year. Suppose the entire process relies upon the small legal error but is now so complex that the error is almost impossible to find. Now suppose the replacement superior carefully checks the process, fails to find the error, and recommends it be used for all 100,000 customers. An illegal process is now making the company $10,000,000 per year, and after ten years the company makes a hundred million dollars illegally.

Who should be punished and by how much?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28767036662.0" user="luminarium" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the superior - on the evidence of the employee's past reliability - assumes the process is legal

The first superior, for not having conducted due diligence. Fired, fined the full amount of a year's wages and banned from the industry for three years.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
