<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="310572070.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/54wmxy/cmv_every_straight_girl_out_there_secretly_wants/">
    <title>CMV: Every straight girl out there secretly wants to date a rich guy</title>
    <original_poster>windmill230</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let's be honest here. Some girls say that they have no desire to date rich guys as they are looking for true love but really they are just lying. And as for girls who don't pursue rich guys, they secretly want to do this and the only reason why they did not do this is because they know that rich guys are out of their league.

Some people say that money is not a priority but really it is. Who doesn't want a rich husband who treats you nicely? "Money cannot buy happiness" is just a myth propagated by not-so-well-off people with a sour grapes mindset. The truth is deep down, everyone values money and secretly desires to be rich. I don't believe it when a girl says that she has no particular desire to date rich guys.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28792597331.0" user="clever-fool" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe they don't necessarily want a rich guy, they just want someone who is comfortable to be with. When the stress of money isn't a factor in staying togather, it helps. But I think maybe you can take a step back and redefine what rich is. If I live within my means, and have the ability to do things that I want responsibly, along with the discipline of aligning my interests according to what I can afford. I'm rich. Also I bet lots of rich guys are highly passionate about something and found a way to make money off of it, and that's an admirable trait in itself. It's not about money really, I think it's way more related to comfort, responsibility, and passion. That's what I tend to believe anyways. Rich is such a relative term, just live with the comfort and confidence of a financially independent person. I think that's what they're looking for, and "rich people" tend to have these qualities more often. Sorry, also note that money gives opportunity, but if one has the wit to create opportunity from more than just money, I bet they are even more desirable. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
