<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="320213946.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ananu/cmv_if_you_think_abortion_is_murder_you_can_only/">
    <title>CMV: If you think abortion is murder, you can only have 1 specific opinion on it.</title>
    <original_poster>Send_Me_Trump_Nudes</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let's start this by saying I don't want to have any arguments about whether abortion is murder or not. I really feel like someone is going to think I am pro-life, I am not. However, my argument is basically saying that IF and only IF you do believe abortion is murder, you can only have the following specific opinion on it:

Abortion is wrong in all cases, INCLUDING rape, except for cases where the mother's health is at risk. 

So basically the main argument is that even rape shouldn't be aborted if abortion really is murder to someone. Here is why. 

If abortion is murder, then it isn't OK. Pretty simple right?
But then you have to get down to the different nuances. Rape is absolutely horrible, but if we assume abortion is murder; murdering because you were raped still doesn't make sense.

Murdering because you might die and you don't want to take a gamble makes sense, as horrible as it is, which is why mothers health is the one exception.

Would like to also include that I am not simply talking about pro-lifers, as there are many variances and AFAIK not all pro-lifers necessarily think abortion is literally murder. 

Thank you, now change my view. :)

Edit: Thank you for the replies, my view has been changed. 

 Just to clarify the murder thing I was only using because I see a lot of pro-lifers use it. I don't really care about the specific wording that should be used, point is that you are killing someone. or someone is dying. Whatever word you would like, imagine I used it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28872234908.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>Clarifying question. By "murder," do you actually mean killing. Murder is a legal definition. It means the unlawful killing of someone. There are lots of lawful ways to kill someone, which are not traditionally or technically considered murder. Abortion is legal, so unless the laws change, it can't be murder, even if it is killing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872244072.0" user="Send_Me_Trump_Nudes" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't really think about this, I am just using the term that pro-lifers often use. If it isn't the right term, I think you understand what I mean if you have listened to pro-lifers. If you believe abortion is killing, I guess. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872259001.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I won't waste your time because some of the other commenters have addressed the points I was going to raise. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
