<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="320213946.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ananu/cmv_if_you_think_abortion_is_murder_you_can_only/">
    <title>CMV: If you think abortion is murder, you can only have 1 specific opinion on it.</title>
    <original_poster>Send_Me_Trump_Nudes</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let's start this by saying I don't want to have any arguments about whether abortion is murder or not. I really feel like someone is going to think I am pro-life, I am not. However, my argument is basically saying that IF and only IF you do believe abortion is murder, you can only have the following specific opinion on it:

Abortion is wrong in all cases, INCLUDING rape, except for cases where the mother's health is at risk. 

So basically the main argument is that even rape shouldn't be aborted if abortion really is murder to someone. Here is why. 

If abortion is murder, then it isn't OK. Pretty simple right?
But then you have to get down to the different nuances. Rape is absolutely horrible, but if we assume abortion is murder; murdering because you were raped still doesn't make sense.

Murdering because you might die and you don't want to take a gamble makes sense, as horrible as it is, which is why mothers health is the one exception.

Would like to also include that I am not simply talking about pro-lifers, as there are many variances and AFAIK not all pro-lifers necessarily think abortion is literally murder. 

Thank you, now change my view. :)

Edit: Thank you for the replies, my view has been changed. 

 Just to clarify the murder thing I was only using because I see a lot of pro-lifers use it. I don't really care about the specific wording that should be used, point is that you are killing someone. or someone is dying. Whatever word you would like, imagine I used it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28872249243.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If abortion is murder, then it isn't OK.

Shooting a guy in the head is murder, but sometimes it is okay.

For example the law recognizes self-defense as a legitimate affirmative defense to murder.  Basically saying, "Yes, your honor, I did murder him, but this was a legal murder because it was me or him."  Likewise defense of others is recognized as an affirmative defense to murder - "I had to kill him to make him stop raping her" is allowed.

Likewise we allow murder when the death warrant is properly executed - eg. in the case of the death penalty, even if the person is later found to be innocent, no one is jailed for that.  Or when we are at war.  Or in some active shooter situations.  Or under duress.  Or ... well you get the point.  Lots of murder is just fine.

Why shouldn't murder be okay in the case of aborting the child of a rapist?  It's not enough to point to it and say "murder", there has to be a reason that kind of murder is different from all the other kinds of murder that the law does allow and that most folks seem fine with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872264682.0" user="Send_Me_Trump_Nudes" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I worded that poorly. I said this not as a abortion can never happen, but to set up my point that abortion IS acceptable when the mothers health is at great risk. 

You did reply to my point in your last paragraph though. Why punish the child for the rape, though? I know it's a horrible situation all around for everyone, but why not give the mother financial help and other government assistance, free counseling, etc and work through the pregnancy so that the baby doesn't have to die in order for the women to feel better for less than a year. 

Yes the baby dying can sometimes be for the greater good, like when the mothers health is at risk, but even rape shouldn't justify murder. You wouldn't even murder the rapist for raping( like death penalty, obviously you could murder him if it was during the rape) , why would it be worth it to murder the child whose life would be completely scrapped for less than a year worth of less discomfort for the mother? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872319224.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You wouldn't even murder the rapist for raping( like death penalty, obviously you could murder him if it was during the rape) ,

That's not clearly the case.  It's probably unconstitutional to do so, now.  But plenty of states still have it on the books, and we certantly used to. More importnatly, lots of people seem very moraly comfortable with it.

But assume that's true.

&amp;gt;abortion IS acceptable when the mothers health is at great risk. 

Define great risk.  

Right now the maternal mortality rate in the US is 28 in 100,000, about triple Canada, and that marks a substantial increase over a decade ago.  A mother giving birth in the US is more likely to die as a result than she would in any other industrialized country.

How much danger should a woman be forced to endure for the sake of a human being placed inside of her against her will?  

Does that calculation change if she chose to put that person there?

Does it change if she took actions that lead to that person being there, but it wasn't intentional?

&amp;gt;why would it be worth it to murder the child whose life would be completely scrapped for less than a year worth of less discomfort for the mother? 

Why shoot a man who is raping a woman?  Why not just provide her with therapy when he is done?  Why should his life end for less than a year worth of discomfort for the woman?  



Think of it this way:  We all agree that in some cases killing people is okay.  And in some cases killing people is not.  If abortion is killing a person, we can still decide it is the okay kind of killing or that it is not the okay kind of killing. Knowing that it is killing doesn't answer the question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872349165.0" user="Send_Me_Trump_Nudes" delta="False">
    <text>For your second point, I shouldn't have said great risk but I just mean a mother's health as a reason for an abortion is perfectly fine. 

&amp;gt;Why shoot a man who is raping a woman? Why not just provide her with therapy when he is done? Why should his life end for less than a year worth of discomfort for the woman?

My argument is that the baby isn't responsible for the woman's pregnancy, but it is about to enter this world. The man who is raping her is choosing to do so, the baby didn't choose to be a product of rape but it is and it will exist. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872484490.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;For your second point, I shouldn't have said great risk but I just mean a mother's health as a reason for an abortion is perfectly fine. 

So any abortion is okay becasue any pregnancy is a risk to the mother's health?

&amp;gt;    My argument is that the baby isn't responsible for the woman's pregnancy, but it is about to enter this world. The man who is raping her is choosing to do so, the baby didn't choose to be a product of rape but it is and it will exist. 

That's a whole different argument from where you were before. Now we are at a question of guilt and moral culpability.  You've already agreed that it's okay to kill an innocent person if that person is causing a risk to another's health.  So, it seems that moral culpability isn't the issue - it's okay to kill person A to save person B whether or not person A is morally responsible for the threat to person B's life - why then shouldn't it be okay to kill person A for violating the bodily integrity of person B without permission even if person A isn't morally responsible for the violation of person B. Wouldn't it, in fact seem that it is more okay the longer the violation of bodily integrity is likely to last?  If A is going to be violating B's bodily integrity for the next 5 seconds it seems almost worse to kill A than if A is going to be doing so for the next 5 months.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872498496.0" user="Send_Me_Trump_Nudes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it's okay to kill person A to save person B whether or not person A is morally responsible for the **threat** to person B's life - why then shouldn't it be okay to kill person A for violating the bodily integrity of person B without permission even if person A isn't morally responsible for the violation of person B. Wouldn't it, in fact seem that it is more okay the longer the violation of bodily integrity is likely to last? If A is going to be violating B's bodily integrity for the next 5 seconds it seems almost worse to kill A than if A is going to be doing so for the next 5 months.


Emphasis on THREAT. I am not saying any abortion is ok, im saying if there is a THREAT. if the threat is not there, then it shouldn't be aborted.

I'm not totally sure if I even believe this, I don't have an opinion on abortion yet, but I feel like both sides have decent arguments. probably leaning choice. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872528565.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Emphasis on THREAT. I am not saying any abortion is ok, im saying if there is a THREAT. if the threat is not there, then it shouldn't be aborted.

But, as I've already said, 28 in 100,000 pregnancies that are carried to term in the US result in the death of the mother.  Every pregnancy is a THREAT to the life of the mother (that number only goes up if you start to include non-fatal, but permanently damaging impacts).

Also, don't confuse defense of self or others in the case of murder with defense of self or others in the case of rape - they are two very different things.  In the case of rape we allow people to kill to stop a violation of bodily autonomy, the rapist need not pose a threat to the life of the victim we allow killing to stop it independent of the threat it poses.  That plus your established lack of concern about moral culpability, should lead you to conclude that it's okay to have an abortion to end a violation of bodily autonomy, despite the fact that, as you pointed out, it isn't the fetus' fault that it is violating the bodily autonomy of the mother.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872528568.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Emphasis on THREAT. I am not saying any abortion is ok, im saying if there is a THREAT. if the threat is not there, then it shouldn't be aborted.

But, as I've already said, 28 in 100,000 pregnancies that are carried to term in the US result in the death of the mother.  Every pregnancy is a THREAT to the life of the mother (that number only goes up if you start to include non-fatal, but permanently damaging impacts).

Also, don't confuse defense of self or others in the case of murder with defense of self or others in the case of rape - they are two very different things.  In the case of rape we allow people to kill to stop a violation of bodily autonomy, the rapist need not pose a threat to the life of the victim we allow killing to stop it independent of the threat it poses.  That plus your established lack of concern about moral culpability, should lead you to conclude that it's okay to have an abortion to end a violation of bodily autonomy, despite the fact that, as you pointed out, it isn't the fetus' fault that it is violating the bodily autonomy of the mother.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28875670876.0" user="Wojciehehe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why punish the child for the rape, though?

Why punish the woman? Especially since she's fully capable of emotional and physical pain, which the unborn child is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28876960751.0" user="Send_Me_Trump_Nudes" delta="False">
    <text>I have already mostly changed my view BUT

I realize that. I really do. The argument is that 80+ years a child can live is worth more than the 9 months of emotional and physical pain. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28877995169.0" user="Wojciehehe" delta="False">
    <text>Okay. 

&amp;gt;more than the 9 months of emotional and physical pain.

But it's so much more than that. I'd say the pregnancy itself is the least shitty factor. If you're a women who would otherwise get an abortion, you do not want the kid for some reason. That means having it usually ruins your life. 

It means the women drops out of collage. It means she loses her boyfriend and is pretty much damaged goods on the dating market, or her relationship goes really sour. She loses her job, and her career will not recover in her lifetime. It's literally life-wrecking. 

Now, let's consider the baby.

&amp;gt;80+ years a child can live is worth more than

It will not have 80+ years of a nice life. Once again, these are unwanted babies. They will not get a lot of love, a proper parental figure, and so on. They will likely go to an orphanage if the woman has no desire or means to raise the baby, which will very likely be the case.

Now I was a volunteer in an orphanage for some time, teaching elementary school kids (I can't claim moral high road, I was forced to do community service for a minor drug infraction). The level of fucked up was simply astonishing. The kids were ignored and unloved. They literally chain smoked cigarettes, at elementary school age! I can only imagine what becomes of them, but it's not 80+ years of a nice life. 

Even if they do find a foster family, they will not find it right off the bat. And then, the family will likely not be perfect. It's likely the kid will switch the families, perhaps multiple times. There's a lot of problems even with the perfect solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872271246.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Murder is defined as the unlawful killing of one human being by another human being with malice aforethought. It needs all of those elements:    

* Unlawful
* Killing
* Of a human being
* By another human being  
* with malice aforethought  
    
If the only information we have is that a human being shot another human being in the head and the person died, that is insufficient information to know if the act constitutes murder. The term you are looking for is *homicide*- the killing of a human being by another human being. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872293882.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, yes.  But the OP meant abortion is homicide.  Since it isn't unlawful.  (And since it would be circular to say it's unlawful, therefore it should be unlawful.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872466041.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>You have your terms messed up. There is not defense to murder, it is always a crime. But there is defense to killing someone. Homicide is not always murder, murder is a very specific term that means the unjustified killing of another human. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872514352.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>There are plenty of (affirmative) defenses to murder - like self-defense, necessity, duress, insanity, and defense of others.  (There are, of course, far more defenses - like I didn't pull the trigger, I didn't mean to kill him, etc. but in context I assume you are suggesting there are no affirmative defenses.)

For easy example, see [18 U.S. Code ยง 17](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/17) - making insanity an affirmative defense to prosecution under any federal statute, which would include the federal statute agaisnt murder.

This legal dictionary entry on [affirmative defenses](http://legaldictionary.net/affirmative-defense/) might clear up some of your confusion.  "When an affirmative defense is used, the defendant is basically admitting he committed the crime of which he is accused, but is offering an explanation or justification for the incident."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28872629159.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text> Self defense renders the killing not murder. Necessity renders the killing not murder, defense of another renders the killing not murder. The killing was not a crime in these situations. 

In the case of insanity you are still guilty of murder but your punishment is held in a mental health facility rather than a prison. 

Murder is specifically the unjustified and unlawful killing (homicide) of another human. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873111497.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Self-defense, if proven, renders the murder not criminal.  

Insanity, as an affirmative defense, does not necessarily result in institutionalization.  If temporary, the defendant can walk free.  If the illness poses an ongoing threat to the safety of others or the defendant, they can be hospitalized agaisnt their will.  You are thinking of the more common situation in which insanity prevents trial at all, as the defendant can't participate in their own defense, and the defendant is hospitalized until such time as they are able to participate in their own defense.

I understand the elements of murder - what you are failing to grasp is how affirmative defenses work.  In an affirmative defense the defendant argues that the elements of the crime are all present, but that an additional set of elements are also present so as to negate criminal liability.  This is why the burden of proof is on the defendant with an affirmative defense.  If self-defense negated an eliment of the crime, it would be on the state to prove beyond a reasonable doubt that self-defense didn't happen.  But, self-defense is an affirmative defense, the defendant must prove that it did.  It only comes into play at all once the prosecution has shown, beyond a reasonable doubt, that all the elements of the crime were present.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873113707.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Murder, once again, is by definition the criminal act of killing another human. Not all killings are murder. If a killing is determined to not be criminal then it is not a murder. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873143821.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Once again, you are failing to understand how affirmative defenses work.

Step one: Prosecution proves all the elements of the crime (in the case of murder this includes the unlawful killing).

Step two: Defense proves an additional set of facts that make it not a crime after all.

Step two does not make it so step one never happened.  By the time a defendant is arguing self-defense in a murder case the prosecution has already shown that they was an unlawful killing of another human (with malice aforethought - and note unlawful, not criminal).  If the defense can show that the unlawful killing of another human was [insert elements of any affirmative defense here], then that unlawful killing is not something the defendant can be convicted of.  The unlawful killing of the other human still happened, but it isn't punishable.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873152495.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>It can be treated as a murder for the entirety of the trial and the lead up to that. The moment it is ruled that it there is no guilt of a crime it means no crime has been committed. The action still occurred, and it is still a homicide (killing) but it was not unlawful and was therefore not murder. 

Self defense is fully justified and legal. It fully negates the accusation of calling it a crime. It is not a crime. 

Killing someone without malice in an unlawful manner is manslaughter. It is still a crime and still punishable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873241165.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Step one: Prosecution proves all the elements of the crime (in the case of murder this includes the unlawful killing).
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Step two: Defense proves an additional set of facts that make it not a crime after all.

Self-defense doesn't mean the elements were not present - it means additional elements were also present.  (A defendant doesn't need to advance an affirmative defense if all the elements of the crime are not present.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873242821.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>And those additional elements render it a non-crime. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28873284177.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly!

But those elements don't mean that the elements of the crime were not there.

An affirmative defense is a "Yes, but" while a traditional defense is a "No, that's not true".  

All the elements of the crime exist, some extra stuff also exists that makes it non-criminal - but all the elements of the crime exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28874459583.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The moment it is determined to be non-criminal there is no longer a crime that has been committed. The pre-existing evidence that pointed toward a crime is fully negated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28874587957.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>That's not at all how the law works.

"I'm terribly sorry Ms. Smith, but it turns out you weren't raped at all - it was just person who lacked the ability to tell right from wrong due to some mental disease or defect penetrating you without your consent."

"Sorry, Mr. Jones it turns out your renters insurance won't pay for that laptop you reported stolen. The person you claimed stole it had a valid affirmative defense, also you're under arrest for attempted insurance fraud."

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28874605962.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>You will note that I very clearly stated that insanity or mental disability does not negate it. It also does not negate punishment, it only moves location of punishment. Self defense on the other hand does fully negate it in US law. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28874645978.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I thought you'd left behind that false distinction (and I'll reiterate that it is a false distinction and inaccurate understanding of the law) but that's an easily avoided debate: 

&amp;gt; "I'm terribly sorry Ms. Smith, but it turns out you weren't raped at all - it was just ~~person who lacked the ability to tell right from wrong due to some mental disease or defect~~ a person acting out of necessity, in the legally relevant sense, penetrating you without your consent."

Problem solved.  

Also please direct your attention to the second example I suggested.  You claim "The moment it is determined to be non-criminal there is no longer a crime that has been committed. The pre-existing evidence that pointed toward a crime is fully negated. " it wold follow that if someone reported a robbery and the robber was later found not guilty due to some affirmative defense or another, the person reporting the robbery would have filed a false report as a crime was no longer committed and any evidence that may have lead him to think one was has been negated.  And that if he reported it to his insurance company to be reimbursed he should be arrested for insurance fraud, as he reported that he was robbed, when in fact he was never robbed and any evidence that suggested he was has been fully negated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28877020415.0" user="phoenixrawr" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why shouldn't murder be okay in the case of aborting the child of a rapist? It's not enough to point to it and say "murder", there has to be a reason that kind of murder is different from all the other kinds of murder that the law does allow and that most folks seem fine with.

This argument seems backwards. Murder isn't an exception to a general rule that it's okay to kill people, justifiable murder is an exception to a general rule that it's not okay to kill people. If we're granting the premise that abortion is murder then it's not enough to say it's justified because someone can't prove it isn't justified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28877060623.0" user="law-talkin-guy" delta="False">
    <text>I may have expressed that poorly.

Let me try again.  We distinguish socially/legally/ethically between a number of kinds of killing.  Some are good, some are okay, some are not great but legal, some are criminal, and some are really really bad.  It isn't enough to say that you are killing a person, you have to explain why it's the bad kind of killing.

OP's position is that once we know it is killing the inquiery stops, once we know that we have to accept that it's the bad kind of killing in all cases (except self-defense).  My contention is that once we identify it as killing there are still lots of reasonable views to have, it could be the good kind of killing or the legal but uncomfortable making kind of killing.  My point is not that it is any of those, just that OP is mistaken that saying it is killing ends the discussion. (It's the "you can have only 1 specific opinion" I object to - I don't think that follows.)
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
