<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884437518.0" user="Ramblingmac" delta="False">
    <text>Comey was widely seen to be on the side of Clinton when the investigation concluded. He (an Obama Appointee) received an enormous amount of flak from the conservative side (and from FBI agents) made all the worse by an unrelated private tarmac meeting between Bill Clinton and the US Attorney General just days before the announcement that set conspiracy theorists nuts.

Comey is decidedly trying /not/ to influence the election. Doing so would be career suicide, but he's been put between a rock and a hard place as he does his job.

The conservatives already want his head because they think he covered for Clinton, then he's told new information comes out, with hardly any time left to go till the election.

He can:
1) Say nothing despite an investigation, in order to not influence the election, and by his inaction do exactly that, 2) Inform congress that more information came up, and that they're hard at work to clear it.

A) If he does not inform congress, and it turns out something actionable is in the emails, he just 'proved' everyone right who thought he was covering for Clinton

B) If he does not inform congress, and it turns out there's nothing actionable, but the investigation is leaked, he sets the stage for allegations of a cover up, accusations of FBI complacency, and an immediate congressional investigation that will derail everything.

C) If he tells congress, and there is nothing actionable, then he did his job and hopefully the fallout clears up before the election. The Clinton camp will join in the previous republican calls for his head.

D) If he tells congress, and there is something actionable, Then he avoided having to charge a president-elect or sweep it under the rug when he didn't mention it before. He's vindicated and just has to weather the storm of, "He made it up!"

TLDR;

Comey didn't want to influence the election. He's probably cursing Clinton's "Extremely Careless" email behavior that's predicated this entire ruckus as he watches his career and reputation go up in smoke, no matter what he does.  He made a calculated gamble on how to react, and it was the best of many bad options.

*edited - because it's impossible to not find typos and rewording after first posting.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885322811.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Comey was widely seen to be on the side of Clinton when the investigation concluded. He (an Obama Appointee) received an enormous amount of flak from the conservative side (and from FBI agents)

He may have been seen this way, but his only action which deviated from policy/instructions to that point was to publicly scold HRC.

&amp;gt;Say nothing despite an investigation, in order to not influence the election, and by his inaction do exactly that

How would saying nothing be influencing an election?  He had no new material information about HRC's conduct.  He had information that indicated there might or might not be some new evidence to be found which might or might not reflect her conduct.  As it turns out, there was no new evidence.  Saying nothing when you don't actually know anything new about HRC's conduct seems to be not influencing an election.

I get he was in a tough spot because of his decision to scold her in July which meant he could no longer take the normal road of just "no commenting" a case where no charges are filed.  But that was his bed he made, and if he put himself in a jam and couldn't extricate himself without violating DoJ policy and the Hatch Act, then he should be fired for letting his self righteousness get him in that jam to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28888748046.0" user="stiljo24" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;He may have been seen this way, but his only action which deviated from policy/instructions to that point was to publicly scold HRC.

I may have genuinely missed a scolding, all I saw was him summarizing the findings of his investigation where he found her to be "extremely careless."  But regardless, do you know the play-by-play of his career?  How can you possibly claim any one thing was his only deviation from policy?

&amp;gt;How would saying nothing be influencing an election?  

It leaks and his silence becomes the story.

&amp;gt;He had no new material information about HRC's conduct.  He had information that indicated there might or might not be some new evidence to be found which might or might not reflect her conduct.  

How does a person obtain material information prior to investigating?  All he did was truthfully say they were looking into some things again.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
