<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884224365.0" user="KungFuDabu" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it's a good idea to fire someone for doing their job, even if their job makes you sad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884227571.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that he did not do his job inasmuch as he violated the law and DoJ instructions in his conduct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884607948.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>Did he violate the law? The DoJ certainly did instruct him not to do it, but to my knowledge you have not supported the argument that Comey *actually did* violate the Hatch Act. Indeed I believe you have *retracted* that argument elsewhere in this thread, arguing that although he may not have violated the law, his insubordination is sufficient to warrant a dismissal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884274538.0" user="GhastliestPayload" delta="False">
    <text>But he violated DoJ policy of not interfering or causing undue influence on the political process within a certain time of an election.

If you read into DoJ testimonies regarding this policy, even if investigators have very strong cases that could lead to an indictment and possible prosecution, it is expected that they sit on the evidence and not bring up the case in an election year due to the skewed perception it could give to the candidate in the eyes of the public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884281746.0" user="KungFuDabu" delta="False">
    <text>I'm certain that every election the government skews the perception of every candidate they do not like in order to dismiss them in the eyes of the public. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884285896.0" user="GhastliestPayload" delta="False">
    <text>[Hatch Act](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hatch_Act_of_1939)

Read up. Doing what you're saying could be a federal offense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884308782.0" user="KungFuDabu" delta="False">
    <text>I bet the politicians respect that law as much as they respect the bill of rights :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884610891.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, "sit on the evidence"? You're saying that DoJ policy is *not to pursue cases* against candidates for election? To *actively cover up criminal behavior* simply because the suspects are running for office?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884615757.0" user="GhastliestPayload" delta="False">
    <text>They resume the investigation or proceedings following the election. Sorry, next time I will immediately suffix my comments by stating something completely obvious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884617263.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>How in your mind would that work for a candidate for President, who would then have the ability to quash any investigation or even pardon herself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884621482.0" user="GhastliestPayload" delta="False">
    <text>Kind of irrelevant since the appended investigation yielded nothing. If there was something of substance, there is something written into the Constitution known as an "impeachment."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884626018.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Kind of irrelevant since the appended investigation yielded nothing. 

You're the one arguing that it *isn't* irrelevant and that, in fact, even if the investigation yields nothing, the DoJ should still have sat on that ambiguity and covered it up lest they be accused by idiots of trying to influence the election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884646217.0" user="GhastliestPayload" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Covered it up

They're not covering it up. You're confusing what I'm saying. They halt an investigation when an election comes near (DoJ policy typically is quoted at 60 days before an election) and resume it after the election.

&amp;gt;Accused by idiots of trying to influence the election

Whether Comey was trying to or not, his letter was poorly timed and did have a negative impact on Hillary's image with the voting public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884632304.0" user="lahddax" delta="False">
    <text>The FBI would have 2 months to do an investigation before the next president took office. Then at that point they could present the evidence to congress which could impeach the newly inaugurated president. The president could not pardon themselves from a congressional impeachment. 

That to me sounds more appropriate than convicting someone in the court of public opinion before the warrants even been acted upon. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885408253.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't you trying to have your cake and eat it here? If impeachment is a sufficient remedy for the criminality of a Presidential candidate, then why does it *matter* if Comey talks about evidence of criminality? Either it doesn't affect the election or it does.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
