<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884207635.0" user="SueZbell" delta="False">
    <text>You're wrong.  Comey's announcement that his recommendation has not changed should have been accompanied by his resignation and his leaving town w/his tail between his legs, leaving no need for removing him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884218428.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this is an argument aimed at changing my view.  Comey has not resigned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884232192.0" user="SueZbell" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure he can be fired -- something about 6 year term overlapping presidents and not serving at the pleasure of the president and all that jazz.  The GOP controlled Congress is certainly not going to impeach him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884238715.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>[He can be fired by the President unilaterally.](http://www.fas.org/sgp/crs/misc/R41850.pdf)  The last FBI director to be fired was in 1993.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884262988.0" user="SueZbell" delta="False">
    <text>Read that in another response.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884244657.0" user="we_are_compromised" delta="False">
    <text>He doesn't need to be impeached to be dismissed by the POTUS and his term is 10 years long, not 6. [source](http://heavy.com/news/2016/10/james-comey-fired-fbi-director-hillary-clinton-email-private-server-influence-election/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884246367.0" user="SueZbell" delta="False">
    <text>It appears I've been misinformed about his term -- that's for senators only, it appears.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
