<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884335714.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>It was not in violation of the Hatch Act unless it can be proven that his actions were done with an intended purpose of affecting the election.

If I plan to use dynamite to blow up a tree stump, and the explosion sends a shard of wood flying into the chest of a jogger on the road, I can't be found guilty of murder because I did not intend to murder someone.

Even if I knew that there could be bystanders, it would be negligent homicide/manslaughter because I didn't have the intention of killing anyone just to remove the stump.

James Comey's actions while against DoJ protocol, have not been proven to have been done with the intention of violating the Hatch Act and therefore are not illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884344157.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Even if I knew that there could be bystanders, it would be negligent homicide/manslaughter because I didn't have the intention of killing anyone just to remove the stump.

If you definitely knew there was a bystander and that your actions would cause that person to die, I think that'd still be murder.

Comey knew, without any doubt, that his official actions would negatively impact the campaign of Hillary Clinton and positively impact the campaign of Donald Trump.  He therefore I believe had the requisite intent for a Hatch act violation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884361155.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Comey knew, without any doubt, that his official actions would negatively impact the campaign of Hillary Clinton and positively impact the campaign of Donald Trump. He therefore I believe had the requisite intent for a Hatch act violation.

Couldn't the same be said of the reverse action?  Had Comey chosen to sit on the information until after the election and said nothing to Congress, it would have positively impacted Clinton, and negatively impacted Trump.  Isn't he in a "damned if you, damned if you don't" situation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884366308.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Inaction is not a Hatch Act violation, especially when inaction is the proper protocol to follow for the situation he was in.  In a typical investigation, you would never make a public announcement on such thin information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884375490.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>In a typical investigation, he never would have given a press conference in July, or been called to testify in front of Congress.  According to his own words, "here I feel an obligation to do so given that I testified repeatedly in recent months that our investigation was completed"

Do you think no such obligation existed?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884390402.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Legally such an obligation did not exist.  His testimony was truthful at the time it was given and there was no obligation to update it.

I think the July press conference (which was as you say not typical of a normal investigation) was in error.  I think that compounding a first violation of protocol with further violations of protocol is not the right way to go.  If he did box himself in with his first violation of protocol, then he would still seem to be responsible for letting himself get boxed in like that in the first place.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884393168.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Right, what I am addressing is your point.  You say he should be fired for his actions this week.

I'd argue that if that if your argument holds, he should be fired for the actions in July, since they meet the same criteria, and they preceded the current action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884397122.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Quite possibly!  Two wrongs don't make a right after all.  But the July statement was given at the direction of the DoJ (at least, he was directed to make some sort of statement), whereas the Oct. 28 letter was made against the advice of his superiors at the DoJ.  If you're told to do something by your boss and you do it badly, that's not as fireable an offense as being told not to do something and doing it anyway, and doing it badly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884403598.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>I thought you were arguing he should be fired for violating the law.  Whether his bosses told him to or not shouldn't be relevant, should it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884404760.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>I just said he should be fired.  Insubordination is a very good reason to fire someone.  Insubordination that possibly breaks the law is even worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884412950.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I just said he should be fired.

Actually, you said more than that.  You said 

&amp;gt; Jim Comey's letter last week [...] and his subsequent letter today [...] have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

It's a minor quibble, but I'm saying if you want him fired for violations of the Hatch Act, it should be the primary action, not the subsequent ones that are the cause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884433586.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>The act of insubordination was to violate the Hatch Act though.  The reason he was told not to send the Oct 28 letter was:

&amp;gt;Justice officials reminded the FBI of the department’s position “that we don’t comment on an ongoing investigation. And we don’t take steps that will be viewed as influencing an election,”

So the DoJ said "don't do this.  It violates the Hatch Act."  And then he did it.  In the July action he wasn't told he was about to violate the Hatch Act, and therefore it's not as clear he knew he might be stepping over the line.  In this case, he knew he was violating the Hatch Act, and had been warned not to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884605736.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So the DoJ said "don't do this. It violates the Hatch Act." 

Well, no, they didn't. "Steps that will be viewed as influencing an election" is not the same as "Steps that influence an election." If the DoJ instructed him not to report to Congress because it could be *perceived* as unduly influencing an election, then the Hatch Act was not the primary motivation but instead simply a desire to cover their ass and have nice PR.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884401224.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Legally such an obligation did not exist. His testimony was truthful at the time it was given and there was no obligation to update it.
&amp;gt; 

According to [most of the articles I've read](http://www.newsweek.com/fbi-reviewing-more-clinton-emails-514825), this obligation comes from "Department of Justice rules to keep the relevant committees apprised."

If Comey is supposed to follow DOJ protocol, and that protocol requires keeping relevant committess apprised, what should he do?

Or can you say affirmatively that no such DoJ rule/regulation exists?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884403362.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>He should go to the DoJ's leadership and ask what to do.  He did that.  They said "do nothing and wait until after the election."  He then did not do what he was told to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884421690.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; He should go to the DoJ's leadership and ask what to do

In that case, if the DOJ chose to break protocol and not release the information, knowing it was relevant to the election, wouldn't the DOJ leadership be guilty of the same Hatch Act violations?  And Comey still be complicit?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884438795.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if the DOJ chose to break protocol and not release the information, knowing it was relevant to the election

Releasing information was breaking protocol, not releasing information would be following protocol.  Standard protocol in a criminal case is to release nothing at all until and unless charges are filed.  

Releasing information is not protocol at all.  Releasing it relevant to an election is double not protocol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884446669.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying is that he appeared to be in a damned if you do/damned if you don't situation. 

* Disclosure - Violate protocol about not commenting on ongoing investigation, and influence the election
* No Disclosure - Violate protocol about keeping Congress apprised, and influence the election

Both choices violate protocol, and both influence the election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884456946.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>He was a bit, but he went with that situation to his superiors, and they said "take the 'damned if you don't'" and then he defied them and took 'damned if you do.'

I don't accept that not sending the Oct 28 letter would have been influencing the election though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884462259.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't accept that not sending the Oct 28 letter would have been influencing the election though.

If the action influences the election, then the absence of the action is also an influence on the election.  If the release caused Clinton's numbers to dip, then any withholding would have been seen as artificially inflating her numbers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884473835.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>"Artificially" is the key word here.  Comey was not withholding information which would change the FBI's decision to recommend charges.  Indeed, the "new" emails were nothing new at all.  The pre-Oct 28 baseline integrated all of the relevant information we know today, because we learned absolutely nothing of any probative value from either letter.  The pre-first-letter baseline was therefore not artificial, but reflected the information the FBI knew then and the information the FBI knows now, because the FBI learned no new information at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884659197.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Comey was not withholding information which would change the FBI's decision to recommend charges. Indeed, the "new" emails were nothing new at all

He didn't know that when he wrote the first letter.  That's 20/20 hindsight.  

Had he sat on that information, and released a letter either immediately before, or the day after the election stating that he suddenly had new information that *was* extremely relevant, that would be equally problematic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884371457.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>If I knew there was a bystander who would be hit, then yes.

But if I only knew there is a chance that the bystander will be hit, then no.

Comey didn't know if it was going to negatively affect Clinton because as you said, he did not know if there was any information.

At the same time if Clinton was involved and it came out later that they had suspicions before the election it could be argued that their inaction and suppression of such information was beneficial to Clinton and therefore in violation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
