<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884226457.0" user="Cyberhwk" delta="False">
    <text>~~Comey is out of a job in two months anyway.  Why go through the hassle of firing somebody if he's a lame duck anyway?~~  Hillary will not re-appoint him and if Trump tries he'd be utterly eviscerated by Democrats in his appointment hearing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884230445.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Comey's term runs until 2023 unless he resigns or is fired.  He does not automatically get removed when the next President is inaugurated, and would not need to be reappointed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884238431.0" user="Cyberhwk" delta="False">
    <text>Well I'll be damned...

&amp;gt;In theory, they serve ten-year terms unless they resign, die, or are removed, but in reality, since J. Edgar Hoover, none have served a full ten years, except Robert Mueller, who served twelve years.

Still, I'd imagine there would be HUGE pressure for Comey to resign should Hillary win.  While these positions are supposed to be independent, I still don't see how the FBI and a Clinton administration could have a functional relationship the way this has turned out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884240730.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>If he resigned that'd be fine.  But if not I think Barack Obama should fire him on Wednesday regardless of the outcome of the election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884279520.0" user="GhastliestPayload" delta="False">
    <text>If you [watch Obama talking on the recent Comey letter](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NH3ke4bEecw), I think Obama is setting the stage to fire Comey.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884286623.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>That may be.  Though I'd still like for someone to give me a meaty reply as to why I might be wrong here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28886612266.0" user="hijh" delta="False">
    <text>Are higher-up government officials ever actually fired or is it more a case of a strongly requested resignation? I've never heard of this happening, but I'm not sure I would have heard about it either. Do you know? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28886624212.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>They usually resign when asked, but they can be fired if they won't resign.  WJC fired the FBI director in 1993.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
