<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884313128.0" user="iauwefhh" delta="False">
    <text>I can't believe the amount of people who don't understand that the INVESTIGATION WAS NEVER CLOSED and Comey was under a written agreement to INFORM WITH *ANY* RELEVANT INFORMATION. Given that the Weiner leaks can be viewed, you yourself can confirm it's relevance.

You have have no argument whatsoever therefore, as you didn't even understand this basic premise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884316065.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Comey was under a written agreement to INFORM WITH ANY RELEVANT INFORMATION. 

Was he? Could you link to the specific document?

&amp;gt;Given that the Weiner leaks can be viewed

I don't think any of the contents of Weiner's laptop has been disclosed publicly to my knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884390481.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Was he? Could you link to the specific document?
&amp;gt; 

According to most of the articles I've read, they contain some form of the following argument ([this from Newsweek](http://www.newsweek.com/fbi-reviewing-more-clinton-emails-514825))

&amp;gt; Under oath Comey had stated that the bureau had completed its review. Once he learned that there were new emails that required examination, Comey had to notify Congress that he had to amend his testimony because it was no longer true.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884905506.0" user="chinpokomon" delta="False">
    <text>This was my understanding too. If it were leaked that Weiner's laptop's content might potentially reopen the Clinton investigation, this would have looked more like the FBI was trying to obstruct. So to prevent the appearance of misconduct, he was trying to be transparent about potential new evidence. Of course the timing was awful, but it was handled quickly. It wasn't a new investigation as the public already knew there was an investigation. This just delt with new potential evidence.

In an alternate universe where new evidence caused the FBI to change course and recommend indictment, do you announce that before or after the election?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
