<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="321704697.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5bj8xl/cmv_jim_comey_should_be_fired_for_his_recent/">
    <title>CMV: Jim Comey should be fired for his recent conduct.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jim Comey's letter last week which strongly insinuated new information about Secy. Clinton, and his subsequent letter today indicating that there was no new actionable information have been egregious violations of the Hatch Act for which Comey should be fired.

I have three principal reasons for this

* Comey acted with almost no information.

When Comey sent his first letter, all he knew was that Weiner's laptop had been scanned and metadata had indicated there were emails on it that went to or were from Clinton's email server.

He did not know what if anything they said, whether the FBI had seen them before, or whether they were in any way relevant to Secretary Clinton herself.  

This was woefully insufficient information for any responsible FBI director to make a public statement about any case whatsoever.

* Comey acted contrary to the advice and instructions of his department.

[Comey was warned that his actions would violate DoJ policy before he undertook them.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/justice-officials-warned-fbi-that-comeys-decision-to-update-congress-was-not-consistent-with-department-policy/2016/10/29/cb179254-9de7-11e6-b3c9-f662adaa0048_story.html)  You are not allowed to act contrary to your policy and specific instructions from your department and keep your job.

* Comey revealed absolutely no new information of public value.

Comey might be forgiven for the above if he had revealed substantial information of public value before an election so that voters could decide.  But in fact Comey's letters revealed no new information of any public value.  If you're gonna break the rules for public benefit, you'd better have some public benefit.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28884327856.0" user="ShittyShittyNameName" delta="False">
    <text>Since no one has pointed this out, I would like to say that many, many, MANY people would have felt cheated if Comey's investigation HAD found something and it was only announced AFTER the election (and assuming Clinton won). I think that this is the primary reason he made that announcement before the election and not after. It was a gamble on his part that he lost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884636966.0" user="lahddax" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is as of this point Comey hasn't found anything. It'd have been one thing if he had indicted her 11 days before the election, but rather all he did was issue a warrant for emails related to her. 

Also, if those people felt cheated then they should be alleviated by the embarrassment Clinton and the DNC would suffer by the impeachment and removal of Clinton on the day of her inauguration. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28884897086.0" user="GreatCornolio" delta="False">
    <text>the wikileaks emails have shown the original investigation had plenty of evidence to indict, but they didn't. most of the FBI saw this and felt that their agency had been taken on a ride for political gain. Inside sources say Comey had resignation letters piling up on his desk from disaffected agents across the organization, and acted to reopen the investigation (also because of the reasons above). 

Another important thing to note is the FBI felt it had an overwhelming amount of evidence in their investigation of the Clinton Foundation in 2015 but the DOJ shut it down. And the agents in the email case recommended a grand jury but that was ignored as well. And the person overseeing this new investigation from the DOJ is a personal friend of John Podesta and whose daughter works for the Clintons, so it was very highly unlikely that this new investigation would go anywhere anyway, even though the proof has been out for a while of various felonies and possibly arguably treasonous acts by Clinton and her team. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885051419.0" user="ShittyShittyNameName" delta="False">
    <text>There's a highly informative podcast called Open Arguments that discusses law issues. Episode OA13 - Hillary Clinton's Damn Emails! explains the laws that could have been used to prosecute her and why she was not charged with anything. They even discuss the provision in the law that Rudy Giuliani claimed could be used to prosecute her.

As for the rest of the FBI thinking that was enough evidence or any investigation stuff into the Clinton Foundation, that's all news to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885383435.0" user="Korwinga" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source for any of that? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885046527.0" user="ShittyShittyNameName" delta="False">
    <text>If she had been impeached and removed, her VP would become president, not Trump. The cheated people would include all the people that also voted for Trump, not just those that voted for Clinton.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885180369.0" user="lahddax" delta="False">
    <text>I think those that voted/are voting for Clinton would prefer Kaine to Trump any day. Trump supporters can't have it both ways. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885405071.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't it *you* who can't have it both ways? Would people change their votes tomorrow from Clinton to Trump if Clinton was brought under indictment today? If so, then impeachment seems like an insufficient remedy for them. If not, then no action Comey could take would affect the election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28885777919.0" user="ShittyShittyNameName" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but I think you misunderstood what I was saying. IF Clinton had been found guilty of something and IF Comey had waited to announce this finding after the election (because he wouldn't have had this finding before the election) then:
1) Trump supporters would have felt cheated that the investigation wasn't announced before the election because this could've help bring swing voters to Trump (and now Kaine would become president)
2) Clinton swing voters would have felt cheated because they would have wanted to know before they voted for Clinton

TBH I'm not sure if Clinton voters would care because people have been vilifying her for so long, this seems like sexism (at worst) or like nothing new (at best).

Also, Comey should've waited. But again, I see why he didn't. It was a gamble that did not pay off.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
