<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="322703900.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5c4nx8/cmv_i_just_dont_think_i_will_be_able_to_vote_3rd/">
    <title>CMV: I just don't think I will be able to vote 3rd party anymore, if they have no real chance of winning.</title>
    <original_poster>BoozeoisPig</original_poster>
    <original_post>I entered the election, knowing full well that I would vote for the candidate I could best hypothesize would generate the most utility. I planned on voting for Hillary Clinton because, to me, she seemed to be the best possible thing my vote could have accomplished. But then I heard the argument that there is precedent for a party absorbing a smaller party and its positions when it gets big enough, via the dixiecrats. And thus, it is good for a 3rd party get to a level of funding where they can build more power. So if you live in a state that is probably going to vote for the greater of two evils, you should salvage your vote to use on Jill Stein to get to 5%.

And I put that number at if Hillary Clinton had a &amp;gt;20% chance of losing and a &amp;gt;80% chance of winning as calculated by 538, because he seemed to have better models of prediction, and even had the best mainstream prediction based on the only methods we know work for determining these probabilities. But there is clearly not enough information to trust to those polls, because Wisconsin was a safe state on the last poll aggregate, and michigan probably was when I voted because I voted early.

I voted for Stein in Utah, and while the polls came more true here, I can't commit to something I don't know has properly correlated with what it is studying. The range between the Donald and Hillary voters in those states is lower than the vote for Stein in those state. By definition, Jill Stein was a spoiler candidate. And if every Stein voter/liberal thought like me when casting their vote, then the results would have been even worse. I, in good conscience, cannot vote for a candidate who is more unlikely to win in a first past the post voting system, because the lesser of two evils is always so much better than the greater of two evils, regarding something like the presidency, that it cannot be jeopardized by misinforming probability calculations.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28892581215.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I entered the election, knowing full well that I would vote for the candidate I could best hypothesize would generate the most utility. I planned on voting for Hillary Clinton because, to me, she seemed to be the best possible thing my vote could have accomplished.

Let us grant that a vote should be based on the utility that it provides. To be more precise, we should look at the *expected* utility. There are two ways that your vote can produce utility: (a) by improving the nation by determining who becomes president, and (b) by benefiting you personally, by causing you to you feel an intrinsic sense of pride for voting for the candidate. 

Now, the chances of your vote deciding the election is essentially zero, so the expected utility from (a) is essentially zero. Whoever is going to be president is going to be independent of who you vote for. Therefore, none of the utility of your vote will come from any benefit to the country (since your vote will almost definitely not influence the country). 

So the only *realistic* utility that your vote provides comes solely from (b) the intrinsic joy of voting for your chosen candidate. If you approve of your favorite candidate significantly more than your 2nd favorite candidate, then voting for your favorite candidate will provide you with significantly more intrinsic joy than voting for your 2nd favorite candidate. Therefore, if you wish to maximize utility, then should vote for your favorite candidate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28893400320.0" user="BoozeoisPig" delta="False">
    <text>The value of a vote changes based on where you vote, and it goes up if you live in a smaller, closer state. A vote in this election was very powerful in various states. Wisconsin, Michigan, Pennsylvania, North Carolina, Florida, Virginia. All of those states were very close and thus your vote mattered much more there. And for some of those states, polling indicated otherwise.

Consequently, my personal pride is massively outweighed by the difference between what 2 presidential candidates want to accomplish. Presidential candidates probably cause a range of difference in generating utility that is billions of times greater than my own, because their policies or lack there of will effect millions of people, every moment that they are underway. If there is only a 1 - 10,000,000 chance that my vote will effect an election result that will cause something that will generate 10,000,000 times greater than my personal utility I might feel by voting for a person, then that vote is worth it. Also, a rational person should always seek to feel the most pleasure in maximising utility. And while many selfish activities provide a personal utility that is hard to ignore, a vote is simply a decision to get someone to make decisions on your behalf, and thus it makes more sense to feel the need to vote for a person who will maximise utility with those decisions, because that person would be the most likely to maximise YOUR utility in their process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28893738087.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The value of a vote changes based on where you vote, and it goes up if you live in a smaller, closer state. A vote in this election was very powerful in various states. Wisconsin, Michigan, Pennsylvania, North Carolina, Florida, Virginia. All of those states were very close and thus your vote mattered much more there. And for some of those states, polling indicated otherwise.

If you want to talk about how much a single vote *actually* mattered (as opposed to what polling what *predict*), then the value of a single vote on the rest of the country would be zero regardless of the state, since there was no state where a single vote impacted the outcome.

&amp;gt; If there is only a 1 - 10,000,000 chance that my vote will effect an election result that will cause something that will generate 10,000,000 times greater than my personal utility I might feel by voting for a person, then that vote is worth it.

If you think that's rational (I don't), then go ahead. Just realize that if you vote like that for your entire life, then it's essentially a certainty that your vote won't influence anything about the country. 

I mean, a similar argument of yours could be used to make it rational to vote for your 2nd best candidate in a non-swing state, but you clearly think it would be acceptable to vote for your favorite 3rd party candidate in that situation. So the intuitions for my position are already present in your mind, it seems. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
