<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="323449689.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ckndl/cmv_i_should_give_up_trying_to_stop_climate_change/">
    <title>CMV: I should give up trying to stop Climate Change</title>
    <original_poster>FifthDragon</original_poster>
    <original_post>We made some small progress here in America during the last presidential term, but despite that, we've already passed the point of no return with regards to Climate Change. No matter how hard we try, we can't fully reverse it. Now we (will shortly) have Donald Trump in the Oval Office, a man who has promised to repeal all Climate Changes acts, while the House and Senate are filled with a majority who likely agrees with him. The way I see it, the only way we can even stop Climate Change, not to mention reverse it, is to have someone in office as radical as Bernie Sanders with a House/Senate majority on his side. And that's just *my* country, don't get me started on China. I don't want to drown, please CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28898827303.0" user="kanzenryu" delta="False">
    <text>Here's a real fact for you. Almost nothing you do has any effect on climate change. Turn that light off? Buy an electric car? Replace meat with vegetables in your diet. Nothing. There's one thing in your life that dwarfs all the other things, and that is the number of children you have. The impact of another person's entire life on the planet will or won't happen, based on your decision. So maybe get some birth control organised and relax about everything else.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
