<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="323449689.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ckndl/cmv_i_should_give_up_trying_to_stop_climate_change/">
    <title>CMV: I should give up trying to stop Climate Change</title>
    <original_poster>FifthDragon</original_poster>
    <original_post>We made some small progress here in America during the last presidential term, but despite that, we've already passed the point of no return with regards to Climate Change. No matter how hard we try, we can't fully reverse it. Now we (will shortly) have Donald Trump in the Oval Office, a man who has promised to repeal all Climate Changes acts, while the House and Senate are filled with a majority who likely agrees with him. The way I see it, the only way we can even stop Climate Change, not to mention reverse it, is to have someone in office as radical as Bernie Sanders with a House/Senate majority on his side. And that's just *my* country, don't get me started on China. I don't want to drown, please CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28899423850.0" user="iwantmynickffs" delta="False">
    <text>It's extremely unlikely that anything you do as a single human could change anything about climate change. No amount of feel good token efforts like recycling will change anything in the grand scheme of things. Even if everyone in US was wiped out and the land magically returned to pre industrial levels the rest of the developing world would cause enough pollution to continue global warming. It's just a matter of economics, they want what you have, and what you have requires a lot of energy.

You won't be able to convince any population to regress in terms of energy usage once they've gotten used to a higher standard. This is something that environmentalists don't really seem to understand. We need a truly monstruous amount of increased energy production world over to cover their future development. If coal is the cheapest then that's what they're going to use.

We have a stop-gap right now, nuclear, but the scare mongering is too great so we're stuck with coal until we can figure out fusion or some other futuretech.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
