<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="323449689.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ckndl/cmv_i_should_give_up_trying_to_stop_climate_change/">
    <title>CMV: I should give up trying to stop Climate Change</title>
    <original_poster>FifthDragon</original_poster>
    <original_post>We made some small progress here in America during the last presidential term, but despite that, we've already passed the point of no return with regards to Climate Change. No matter how hard we try, we can't fully reverse it. Now we (will shortly) have Donald Trump in the Oval Office, a man who has promised to repeal all Climate Changes acts, while the House and Senate are filled with a majority who likely agrees with him. The way I see it, the only way we can even stop Climate Change, not to mention reverse it, is to have someone in office as radical as Bernie Sanders with a House/Senate majority on his side. And that's just *my* country, don't get me started on China. I don't want to drown, please CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28898134736.0" user="JustAGuyCMV" delta="False">
    <text>He also promised to build a wall across the Mexican border and has already reversed part of that plan.

He played into exactly what people wanted to hear. I guarantee his positions in private are much different than the public ones he has expressed on many issues, maybe not climate change, who knows for sure.

The problem is that it even if the US stops all emissions of harmful substances into the atmosphere it wouldn't change a thing. We got to our point in the world by using industry to build our power. Other countries see that and want to do the same.

However, that doesn't mean it is unimportant to oppose the measures, or lack thereof, of politicians. 

It would be unimportant historically to oppose the Nazis as a single German infantry soldier, but it is amazing to be able to say that in the face of tremendous odds people were still principled.

And guess what? You can use that passion to get other principled people to form a coalition that rivals the one you don't like.

However, the issue of climate change has continuously been passed on to the next administration or the next guy in line. What Trump can do is deregulate businesses to make products that we want, with a majority of Americans wanting to own a car or power their house in a way that doesn't kill the environment. 

The way is not to legislate the technology into existence and make us suffer until technology catches up. We need to build safe technology that makes current tech obsolete, cheap, and worth it, all while saving the environment.

I'll pay $35,000 for an electric car over $30,000 for a gas powered car. But I will not pay $45,000 for an electric car that goes 200 miles before needing a recharge when I can buy a gas powered car that can go 400 miles for cheaper, that lasts longer, and has better technology. 

The civilian population will not revert, they will change. They won't go backwards, but they will move from an equal car to a safe and equal car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898217390.0" user="FifthDragon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It would be unimportant historically to oppose the Nazis as a single German infantry soldier, but it is amazing to be able to say that in the face of tremendous odds people were still principled.

∆ for that. That is a really inspiring point, at least for me. I'll definitely stay strong on that front. Thank you.

&amp;gt; The way is not to legislate the technology into existence and make us suffer until technology catches up. We need to build safe technology that makes current tech obsolete, cheap, and worth it, all while saving the environment.

&amp;gt; The civilian population will not revert, they will change. They won't go backwards, but they will move from an equal car to a safe and equal car.

Another very good point. So what you're saying is that I'm approaching the issue of Climate Change from the wrong angle? Instead of a legislative approach, I should focus on the technological approach? That makes a lot of sense, and honestly sounds easier. As normal citizen do you know of anything I can do on that front?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898270798.0" user="JustAGuyCMV" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So what you're saying is that I'm approaching the issue of Climate Change from the wrong angle?

Yes. The bureaucratic red tape that surrounds these things doesn't matter if we can't change anything. People saying "Stop driving your car!" when they live within walking distance of all their needs is disingenuous.

Coming from middle America, I can tell you that the people use oil and gas products for many things. Many are farmers who see the regulation of the oil making it obsolete and expensive, but no replacement coming in. And they are rightfully scared.

&amp;gt;I should focus on the technological approach?

Definitely. Or you could at least combine the two. Push for legislation into giving tax breaks for people using renewable forms of normally destructive things, such as cars. Push for legislation that not only develops new ways to get renewable energy, but makes it practical and affordable for everyday Americans.

A lot of Americans are living paycheck to paycheck. If saving money in the short term results in a little more environmental damage in the long-term, it is seen as fine because they need the money right now. 

&amp;gt;As normal citizen do you know of anything I can do on that front?

1. Don't demonize the people that disagree with you on pushing for this technology. Just make the technology so good that they are stupid for disagreeing.

2. Get the information together and make it easily explainable to people that might not necessarily understand the "scientific mumbo-jumbo."

3. Vote in legislators that believe in climate change and heavily flood areas that don't with new information they may not know.

One of the reasons Trump won is because he speaks in visuals. A big wall. "Bombing the shit out them." Putting Hillary in jail. It was brilliant from an outside perspective, even though I didn't vote for him.

The Democrats problem, and a future Republican one, is that they focused on the long ball. What do you care about more, realistically. Someone saying you might get blown up driving down the street tomorrow by a terrorist, or someone saying the world will be 3.6 degrees hotter in 100 years? You have to make it stick to people without acting like a lunatic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898305250.0" user="FifthDragon" delta="False">
    <text>That's a really good idea, making environmentally friendly technology desireable regardless of the perspective. I never thought of the people who depend on the current, harmful technology for their livelihoods. 

&amp;gt; Someone saying you might get blown up driving down the street tomorrow by a terrorist, or someone saying the world will be 3.6 degrees hotter in 100 years? You have to make it stick to people without acting like a lunatic.

So should I present it by emphasizing the impending Californian Super Drought, the football field's worth of land that Louisiana looses every day, and the eventuality of flooding?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898334359.0" user="JustAGuyCMV" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's a really good idea, making environmentally friendly technology desireable regardless of the perspective.

Remember, some people won't believe regardless of the truth of climate change. So you just have to ask them why not fund it, especially when gas or diesel will just continue to climb in price and eventually be unaffordable. 

The current technology is like a minor league baseball player that needs development to get to the majors. You can't talk about change until it can step onto the field and compete. But you can say how vital that player will one day be to the organization because he is the proven player that will save the franchise.

&amp;gt;So should I present it by emphasizing the impending Californian Super Drought, the football field's worth of land that Louisiana looses every day, and the eventuality of flooding?

I would say you need to focus on everything that is current. You also need to have some handy facts to say why their help matters. I would imagine many people also ideologically opposed the Nazi's, but couldn't see a way to oppose them. Give those people a way to oppose them and win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898705937.0" user="FifthDragon" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, looking at it that way, I'm surprised big oil companies haven't started founding branches of their companies dedicated to preparing for the renewable energy future. They could make a lot of money on that.

Ok, so my big point would be the following? Oil, coal, and natural gas are rising in price as the resources are being used up, but renewable energy won't rise in price since, by definition, it's renewable. Funding research on it will lower the price and resources taken to set it up initially.

By the way, I really like your baseball analogy, it's really creative. Mind if I use it in the future?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898763295.0" user="JustAGuyCMV" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They could make a lot of money on that

It is the same thing as big tobacco companies. I don't understand why they aren't advocating for legal pot that they would already have the infrastructure to support and get money.

&amp;gt;Funding research on it will lower the price and resources taken to set it up initially.

All you really have to point out is that the cost may be higher initially to get the tech, but you have negligible costs after that. You would be stupid to not do it.

&amp;gt;Mind if I use it in the future?

Go for it. The greater amount of people that stop being stupid would benefit all of us.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
