<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28904191250.0" user="almostjay" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). 

I suppose my main disagreement is that I don't know that keeping developing countries down is a requirement for allowing developing countries to continue to thrive. Is the West systematically keeping Africa impoverished and stealing their abundant, survival essential resources to keep themselves at the top? 

I think the real problem is that the countries that have historically been, and mostly still are, at the top, are there because they were located in resource rich environments and/or in geography that is conducive to trade and the reverse is also true. 

Are you proposing that we move the resources to where the people that don't have them are? Why not vice versa? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904873002.0" user="lizard-state" delta="False">
    <text>We rely mostly on other countries that are typically developing countries for their rich abundance of resources. We are more so stripping resources from countries that already have so little as in return they gain some profit, but still barely enough to have access to all survival necessities. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904918879.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We rely mostly on other countries that are typically developing countries for their rich abundance of resources.

And those countries often rely on us for our agriculture, or for our petroleum refining capabilities or for our [insert X here].

It's a complex system and the majority of the issues aren't because first world countries are abusing third world countries, it's because the wealthy (or those with the guns) in the third world countries are abusing the poor in the third world countries.  When we pay the DRC for their cobalt exports, we aren't exploiting them, we're paying market prices, but the majority of those profits aren't getting funneled down to the workers.  We could not buy from the DRC, but that won't do much to help the workers as then they won't have a job, so we're stuck letting internal forces sort themselves out.  For the majority of cases, not intervening is the best option as intervening only leads to more issues (see ISIS).

I would agree that Cold War policies did cause a lot of strife in the third world, but that had less to do with economic exploitation and more to do with the desire to prevent the spread of communism.  When the US supported Mobutu in Zaire in the 60s it wasn't because we wanted their resources, it's because we didn't want the USSR to gain another ally.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
