<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28906026345.0" user="ZeusThunder369" delta="False">
    <text>You mention that you're an atheist and that existence is a cosmic accident.

I wonder then, why do you think it matters what people's lives are like? Regardless of how we live our lives, the cosmos will carry on normally; We have no way of affecting it.

Everyone is going to live, and then die in an extremely short period of time (relatively speaking), so why does it matter what their life was like? Do you feel sadness for the millions of people living pre-1800s or so that went through hardship in their lives? If you do not, then why care for people going through hardship now?

Why are just human lives the ones that matter anyway? Animals of every type suffer in nature, and have their lives cut short. Cosmically speaking, what makes human life more valuable than other animal life?

Since you're an atheist, I'm not sure why you see some kind of deeper meaning in this context, or why you care what we're doing in this life. You don't believe in objective morality either, so I don't know why you feel obligated to worry about persons in other areas of the world you're not likely to ever visit.

At the end of the day, nothing we're doing right now really matters. The universe will just carry on, with or without us.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
