<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28904355342.0" user="Smudge777" delta="False">
    <text>1. By using the word 'should', you're either appealing to a moral system or a pragmatic reason to do it.  Perhaps you could explain why it **should** be anyone's prerogative to give up our luxury for the benefit of others.  If life is precious, short and one-chance-only, why would it make sense to purposely limit our own happiness in the one and only life we get?

2. How would you suggest this resource sharing is carried out?  
If we just rounded up 80% of the money, food, clothing, etc. from the rich countries and sent it to the poor countries, that wouldn't markedly improve the lives of those in the poor countries.  The resources would be quickly snapped up by the political/military powers in those countries, and kept to make them even richer, while the average citizen remains poor and downtrodden.  

The problem of poverty is not a resource scarcity problem.  It is a political one.  It's actually not possible (with the current global political situation) to redistribute resources to those who need them the most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904992220.0" user="lizard-state" delta="False">
    <text>Should is appealing to a moral system, however, the system we have in placed is based in many ways on our morals and ethics. It is under the belief that we deserve to live a decent quality life with high access to food, water, proper sanitation, and even things above survival needs like transportation and consumer goods. The West clearly does not extract the majority of its resources locally and relies heavily upon developing countries to sustain our system. What makes us think it is okay to exploit other countries for our good, with less importance placed on the lives of those in developing countries that is seen through the low wages and poor living conditions they receive through capitalism. 


To round up our resources and send them to poor countries wouldn't be an effective solution. It would much more worthwhile if we learnt how to properly manage our resources better. This would not only be beneficial to others, but developing countries as well. If we changed our political system to improve resource management, I do believe things would change for the better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28906937280.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>Almost all interaction we have with poor countries helps them. We are taking nothing from them. We give them jobs that normally wouldn't exist working in factories to make our stuff. I refuse to purchase from Nike but if you ask any of their sweatshop employees, they are just happy to be able to feed their families. Most of the actual working conditions are enforced by the people in those countries while US companies usually try to improve them to keep a good image. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
