<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28904364610.0" user="AlextheYounguh" delta="False">
    <text>This is called socialism. It's been done before. 

It's killed over 100 million people over the last century, mostly due to starvation. This is all that really needs to be said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904724760.0" user="OMG_ISTHIS_REAL_LIFE" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a bit confused. How has socialism starved people? socialism distributes food to all of the community, not for the select few who work. Example: let's say there are 100 apples and 100 people of which 70 are working people. in capitalism, the 70 each would get 1.4 apples and the rest starve, but in socialism everyone would get 1 apple. please help me understand?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904906007.0" user="lizard-state" delta="False">
    <text>I am curious to know too. Could you please elaborate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905162662.0" user="Quancreate" delta="False">
    <text>Socialism disincentivizes workers. It kills the human spirit. There will always be a divide between the makers and the takers.

 People get up and go to work every day not because they love being electricians, policemen, barbers ect, but because they need to provide for themselves and their families. Where socialism has been applied people just stop carring, they become disincentivized to do things they don't want to. The pride in building something on their own is killed, the government just takes it away killing the motivation people need to drive themselves into success. 

No where has socialism been implemented has it succeeded. It kills itself through a lack of incentives and while it may seem moral at first, what you're arguing for is for men with guns to take something away from someone something they earned because you think someone elses deserves thwt thing. How is that any different than what your criticism of capitalism? Poverty worldwide has been decreasing, and it is being done, not due to centralized planning and forced redistribution. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905201883.0" user="wolfram184" delta="False">
    <text>[It reduces incentives to work, and the central planning required is often incompetent and inefficient.   Read up on collectivisation](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collectivization_in_the_Soviet_Union) 

For small communities there isn't  much of a problem, that's how humanity survived for hundreds of thousands of years.  However, that sort of society quickly breaks down once you move beyond tribe-size communities. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905328228.0" user="OMG_ISTHIS_REAL_LIFE" delta="False">
    <text>Makes sense. But in your opinion wouldn't socialism be the ideal economical model when artificial intelligence does the work for us? Capitalism can't work in a fully automated society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905375232.0" user="wolfram184" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely.   There's actually a scifi series that touches on this,  called "The Culture" series. 

It essentially describes an anarcho-socialist post scarcity society run by hyper-intelligent, benevolent AIs.  You get all of the benefits of socialism with most of the benefits of libertarianism.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905568223.0" user="AlextheYounguh" delta="False">
    <text>Robots would solve many problems inherent to socialism, but they could not solve the [Economic Calculation Problem of Socialism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economic_calculation_problem), which would inevitably bring down the system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905688544.0" user="wolfram184" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed, it's a need for both extremely advanced AI and a post-scarcity economy.  But that's just a fantasy for now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905559866.0" user="AlextheYounguh" delta="False">
    <text>Look up Mao's China and The Great Leap Forward. This was the greatest attempt at Socialism ever conducted.

Roughly 44 million people died, again, mostly due to starvation. People were literally eating each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905696735.0" user="OMG_ISTHIS_REAL_LIFE" delta="False">
    <text>What was the reason? Surely working is better than eating each other. the problem should've been lack of food itself. which then the economic model wouldn't matter because someone would have to starve even if it was capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905832254.0" user="AlextheYounguh" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you're correct in concluding that people were not eating each other simply for the fun of it. 

The greatest problem with socialism is what's called the [Economic Calculation Problem](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economic_calculation_problem), a problem to which there is no earthly solution to.

Under socialist economics, it becomes impossible to accurately determine how much of each good should be produced. In a Capitalist economy, prices determine how much should be produced. There are no prices, or no accurate prices, in a socialist economy. 

This usually leads to massive shortages in most goods. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905980393.0" user="thebedshow" delta="False">
    <text>Because when you have a central authority managing everything, they fuck up and don't manage things appropriately or give favors to connected people. You are describing some utopian socialist system that literally will never exist. In reality they try to manage food supply and realize they aren't producing near enough or it is being siphoned off by the politically connected and in turn the people waiting to be handed food just die of starvation instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28907126857.0" user="OMG_ISTHIS_REAL_LIFE" delta="False">
    <text>So, government corruption and greed? I don't know.  I read several articles that says we can feed the world right now and we're wasting %40 of our food supplies. But we're not helping others because their government is corrupt so, The biggest obstacle seems to be government corruption, right?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
