<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28904137782.0" user="insipid_comment" delta="False">
    <text>Consider water.

In Canada, we have got a lot. Nestlé is busy bottling it up like crazy even in areas of drought to sell it to other places far and wide (for a profit, of course—why shouldn't they be able to make a living being so helpful?*)

But when it comes to resource management, it really should be left to the locals to manage the local extraction or production of resources, and only a federal/global enterprise to look out for sustainability in the long term which *individuals* acting freely are likely not to account for.

The reason I say this is because Nestlé is flat-out a bad judge of how much water to take from Canadian soil. The rain falls here for a reason, and speaking ecologically it can be pretty important. Beyond that, Nestlé has also been insensitive to the water needs of residents here.

It needn't be a villain like Nestlé. Even a federal/global government could just as easily bungle a resource transfer and jeopardize the livelihoods of people who have otherwise lived a long time peacefully in a place. It's crap because it is top-down resource management.

I am all for sharing and providing equality of opportunity and pay equity the world over. I do think the West enjoys a lot of privilege unfairly on the backs of people in other lands. But I do not think global top-down resource management is a responsible way to secure that.

-----

\*half sarcastic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904904767.0" user="lizard-state" delta="False">
    <text>On a global scale though, is Canada really as affected by Nestle's poor management and over-extraction of Canada's resources compared to other countries with no access to clean water? 


I do agree with your second paragraph to a point. But look at how resources are managed in other countries where locals are being exploited and stripped of their right to manage local resources. Sustainability is something hardly considered when it conflicts with the profit being gained from extracted resources. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905149563.0" user="insipid_comment" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;On a global scale though, is Canada really as affected by Nestle's poor management and over-extraction of Canada's resources compared to other countries with no access to clean water? 

Probably not, but that is barely relevant. If we had considered a different resource (say, bitumen extraction), then yeah, every bit you dredge up affects many thousands of Canadians, local and all over, sometimes positively and sometimes negatively.

&amp;gt;
I do agree with your second paragraph to a point. But look at how resources are managed in other countries where locals are being exploited and stripped of their right to manage local resources. Sustainability is something hardly considered when it conflicts with the profit being gained from extracted resources. 

My only point is that top-down resource management leaves the door wiiiiide open for bureaucrats to overlook the needs of locals from where they're extracting resources.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
