<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28904118646.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again.

Well that's called living. We each are going to experience it in different ways, implying they would be the same isn't true, and that all the experiences would be good isn't true. So what are you wanting? Everyone to be happy? How would they know it without sadness? Everyone to be fulfilled? That is each persons choice and understanding given their life circumstances.

&amp;gt;In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through.

What makes you think you have the right to judge their lives? What makes you think their hope is false? Even if it is how does that diminish their lives in any way. You claim your knowledge of Atheism changed you, yet what did you gain from it other than your understanding that life is brief and short. Any religion teaches that as well. We all deal with the world differently, so assuming your way has given you more or better fulfillment is foolhardy. You came to it through your choices, that's what gave it power.

&amp;gt;Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.

That number is growing every day. and anyways the value of a good life isnt in dollars, but how its lived. I know tribesmen in "primitive" tribes who lead more fulfilling lives than most modern educated people I know. If you want happiness it can be found in any circumstances, same with fulfillment. But you have to work for it.


&amp;gt;Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever.

Well we are still prone to competing against nature. That hasn't changed despite our technology, we are still evolving, and like it or not we are a part of nature. No matter what we do nothing is going to change that, those struggles are still ongoing.

&amp;gt;The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world.

I would suggest reading a bit of Montaigne. Our intelligence is cool and all, but don't let it go to your head. Despite it all we still all seated on our asses. Don't fall into the trap of intellectual self love. It does nothing for you. Remain a life long student remembering you are just an idiot no matter how much you know.

&amp;gt;It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do.

Dont underestimate our shit, its awesome!

&amp;gt;If we are intellectual beings,

We aren't. We are funny little apes that can make really cool sharp things and smash things together. Now that may have improved quite a bit, but that's still what we are.

&amp;gt;why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?

You seem to have a hatred for capitalism, yet what are you suggesting? Capitalism despite its flaws has brought more people out of poverty than any other system. Yes there are problems, but you are ascribing beliefs to it that no simple economic system has. What would you want instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904968912.0" user="lizard-state" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We each are going to experience it in different ways, implying they would be the same isn't true, and that all the experiences would be good isn't true.


I didn't mean to imply we will all experience living in the same way. What I mean is how are people capable of experiencing life when they subjected to poor living conditions and low wages that make the base of their needs, survival necessities, hard to achieve. 


&amp;gt;We all deal with the world differently, so assuming your way has given you more or better fulfillment is foolhardy.


I understand many of us deal with the world differently and have the freedom to do so, however, it is shown statistically that does with higher levels of education tend to be less religious. I think if developing countries had enough economic resources to put towards other sectors of society like education, more would rely on critical and scientific thinking instead of relying upon other coping mechanisms like relying upon religious beliefs. 


&amp;gt; If you want happiness it can be found in any circumstances, same with fulfillment. But you have to work for it.


Sure, we have the power of our minds to find happiness, however, it's being limited by being human, it is hard to reach self-fulfillment when your survival needs haven't even been fully met. (Referring to Abraham Maslow's classic and simple hierarchy of needs).


&amp;gt;Well we are still prone to competing against nature. That hasn't changed despite our technology, we are still evolving, and like it or not we are a part of nature. No matter what we do nothing is going to change that, those struggles are still ongoing.


Meant to say we can't compete against natural laws forever. What will happen when we over stripped the planet of its resources? The planet won't suffer, but we for fuck sure will. And if the results in human extinction, the planet will only rebound. 


&amp;gt;Don't fall into the trap of intellectual self love. It does nothing for you. Remain a life long student remembering you are just an idiot no matter how much you know.


What I mean by this is that with our intellectual capability to alter the natural world around us, shouldn't we be capable of properly managing resources. I mean, people are always proposing solutions of how to fix the shit we're in, but the issue is we don't manage our economic resources properly where sustainability is a concern.


&amp;gt;We aren't. We are funny little apes that can make really cool sharp things and smash things together. Now that may have improved quite a bit, but that's still what we are.


Again, I mean this in terms of how we are able to alter the natural world and our environment in a way that is beneficial for us.


&amp;gt; Capitalism despite its flaws has brought more people out of poverty than any other system. Yes there are problems, but you are ascribing beliefs to it that no simple economic system has. What would you want instead?


I feel like capitalism only keeps the absolutely poor out of poverty, but continues to keep the poor poor. And as for what I would want, it is hard to say, which is why I am on this subreddit, however, I do feel like better resource management would be beneficial globally. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28905075914.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;y. What I mean is how are people capable of experiencing life when they subjected to poor living conditions and low wages that make the base of their needs, survival necessities, hard to achieve.

Well people have been living productive happy lives for centuries without wages even being a thing. I lived with a group of pastoralists for the last year who live in what we would consider primitive conditions yet are happier than many people in the west I know. Before that I was with some horticulturists who I would say are in similar conditions. And they still use stone tools. The necessities to actually live a fulfilling life are fewer than you would think. But as for the poor in capital systems increase safety nets and make sure social mobility up and down isn't stagnant. But at the same time give them the dignity of assuming they have fulfilling good lives. Believe it or not dignity is important.

&amp;gt;I understand many of us deal with the world differently and have the freedom to do so, however, it is shown statistically that does with higher levels of education tend to be less religious.  I think if developing countries had enough economic resources to put towards other sectors of society like education, more would rely on critical and scientific thinking instead of relying upon other coping mechanisms like relying upon religious beliefs.

Chicken or the egg. Education isn't a silver bullet, nor is lack of religion. For some atheistic people I know it would have been better off if they kept their religion, they would have been happier people with less problems.  Being an atheist doesn't mean you are a critical thinker either. Many atheists don't come to their choices through critical thought and many religious people do. Some of the best thought out systems we have were come up with by religious people. We all have our crutches we lean on don't assume that they block us from achieving.  Only when they are should they be put to blame. The "third worlds" problems are many but religion isnt the worst. If anything its lack of transportation, and tons of parasites, and political instability that are real issues atm. Education is on the rise, but so is religion. They actually tend to go hand in hand. Both help keep social order in different ways.

&amp;gt;Sure, we have the power of our minds to find happiness, however, it's being limited by being human, it is hard to reach self-fulfillment when your survival needs haven't even been fully met. (Referring to Abraham Maslow's classic and simple hierarchy of needs).

Try living with a Hunter Gatherer tribe for a while. You will understand how little those needs truly are. There are hang ups we have in more modern cultures that are totally artificial.

&amp;gt;Meant to say we can't compete against natural laws forever. What will happen when we over stripped the planet of its resources? The planet won't suffer, but we for fuck sure will. And if the results in human extinction, the planet will only rebound.

Well we technically will always struggle against nature. As long as we exist we will struggle against nature. Even if we come up with ways to live more "in tune" with it, we will still be a part of it. We are evolving as we speak. There is change, but that doesn't mean it has a set direction. We have to learn how to live well, and maybe strive for more or better. But that doesn't mean everyone is going to view it the same. Yes resources are limited. We are going to compete for them. That's good. It helps us grow. There is no guarantee of extinction, just of change. You know what will happen before scarcity becomes a real problem? War. and deals will be made to stop it. Populations will rise and fall and solutions will come, but creating a falsely equal system would more likely result in problems across the board. Look at the times historically that has been attempted. They are disasters on epic scales. Yet treating people liberally and with dignity and respect for differences and needs has always given better solutions.

&amp;gt;What I mean by this is that with our intellectual capability to alter the natural world around us, shouldn't we be capable of properly managing resources. I mean, people are always proposing solutions of how to fix the shit we're in, but the issue is we don't manage our economic resources properly where sustainability is a concern.

Well yes people do sugest things all the time. And honestly they are often really bad ideas. Often artificial changes and adaptations are insanely destructive. So is artificial stagnation. Our intelligence can do some things but not everything. SO I'm saying work within the limits you have and don't just self aggrandize our abilities, but rather understand them better. Wisdom is far better than hubris.

&amp;gt;Again, I mean this in terms of how we are able to alter the natural world and our environment in a way that is beneficial for us.

Look at many of the changes we make. In the short term they have benefit, long term they don't. Understanding it has to play to both short and long term and weighing consequence against benefits is the important lesson. Once again its about understanding what tools and methods we have, and what we don't.

&amp;gt;I feel like capitalism only keeps the absolutely poor out of poverty, but continues to keep the poor poor.

Is that capitalism or bad actors within the system? Because capitalism is simply trade of goods within a system of barter and currency exchange with individuals rather than state entities making the choices. There may be variations, but its actually not that complex. Now it appears some state regulation actually tends to be better for the overall economy, and better for people, but capitalism is simply about personal choice.

&amp;gt; I do feel like better resource management would be beneficial globally.

What sort of management? Equal distribution of all resources? Each's needs being fulfilled as fully as possible without being told what their needs are? Individual monitoring of needs by a state or computer entity? I mean I need to know what your talking before I can agree or disagree. Because though I do agree there are problems, I'm not sure just plain capitalism is to blame. There are other factors at play.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
