<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="324174479.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5d06mn/cmv_we_should_share_resources_equally_globally/">
    <title>CMV: We should share resources equally globally</title>
    <original_poster>lizard-state</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like we people living in the Western world have such a good life, an almost too good life. It just seems like everything, access to resources and services, in some way or another are gained through keeping developing countries at the bottom of the latter (capitalism). I don't want to live a life that is only achieved by keeping others in a low position.
I think when I became an atheist, my viewpoint on life and the lives of others changed significantly. I realized how precious, short, and lucky we are to be apart of this thing called existence due to a cosmic accident. We should all be able to experience it before it's gone to never be experienced again. In the world we live in, people in developing countries seem to either die miserable and depressed or have to rely on a false sense of hope in a faulty religion to get through. Meanwhile, the smile amount of us actual have access to what is needed to live a decent life and again, it is seem that this is only achieved by keeping the poor poor in order to allow the rich to stay rich and become richer.
Competition for survival is a normal thing among many other species, but we have competed against natural laws forever. The Age of Enlightenment/ Reason led to this idea that God's hand wasn't the only thing that determines the state of the natural world. It reflected importance on intellect, something that makes human beings a remarkable species, despite all the shit we may do. If we are intellectual beings, why can't we initiate mitigation instead of living under this capitalist belief that other nations are the ones who should adapt and be kept under our thumbs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28904418412.0" user="KungFuDabu" delta="False">
    <text>Sharing kills competition. Without competition, things will never get better. 

The American dream is not achievable with socialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904853194.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>If there are enough resources, then competition isn't needed, since sharing is a better solution.

Also, in cases where certain resources are fixed and finite, competition won't create more of that resource.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904921290.0" user="lizard-state" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly what I was going to point out. The case in where many resources are fixed and finite is right here on Earth. We are over exploiting resources to the point where I think it has become less about having what we need to survive, but what we need to fuel to profit-based and consumerist society. How long will we be able to compete over the amount this planet can naturally produce before not only will developing countries be suffering, but we will be as well. Isn't it silly to wait until things come crashing down? What if there is no reversal on our damage? If active change was done, we have the high potential of sustaining proper resource management. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28904949239.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>I agree... but it's also important to realize that a lot of the resources we use are "human resources" (labour, creativity, invention, engineering development, etc), and those are not fixed or finite. Competition would actually increase the amount of those resources generated. As such, it's important to draw a distinction between the two.

Many of our Western luxury items are more a product of human resources than limited physical/planetary resources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28906300611.0" user="KungFuDabu" delta="False">
    <text>Competition is always needed to decide who gets the finite resources. If your dad didn't compete for your mom then she would have been shared with everyone who wanted her :) Sharing is bad for economics and its unnatural. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28906337264.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>When there is enough resources for everyone - you don't need to decide.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
