<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28926496675.0" user="AlphaGoGoDancer" delta="False">
    <text>If I come from a very unique background, say I'm the last of my kind, how much extra weight do you think my vote should have relative to that of a African American?

How far down the gene pool are you willing to split people? You seem to be grouping all African Americans together, but is it fair to split African Americans off from the rest of Americans, while still giving the same voting weight to Moroccan African Americans as you do Kenyan African Americans?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926872187.0" user="Arthur_Edens" delta="False">
    <text>I think this was probably OP's point, but I think you're making a pretty good argument against the EC. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927780433.0" user="AlphaGoGoDancer" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, but with states its easy: states get equal representation. No need to subdivide more because States can decide their vote however they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28928203021.0" user="Arthur_Edens" delta="False">
    <text>States are easy because we made it easy, not because of something inherent with them. We could make it more complicated; we could go down to the county or square mile. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28928414140.0" user="AlphaGoGoDancer" delta="False">
    <text>In theory yes but in practice it would make very little sense, because states determine counties not the fed. So the fed really shouldn't give counties any special treatment as states could just arbitrary make more of them as they see fit.

Square mile is more reasonable,   but in both cases states could still choose to allocate their EV votes based on these things -- so its not really a change that needs to come from the fed, if you really want to advocate for this you could get your state to start the trend and see if other states take off.

IMO thats better than having the fed force a rule change which is always controversial.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
