<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28926515104.0" user="ZerexTheCool" delta="False">
    <text>How do you believe we should "cut up the pie" of votes? Should it be that blacks get 50% whites get 50%? well, what about Asians? So 33% for blacks, 33% for whites and 33% for Asians? Who gets to decide a person's race? I have a Chinese grandmother, which puts me at something like 25% Asian, but the rest of the 75% is all mixed up. Basically no clue what the rest is. Should my votes be waited as if I was an Asain? 

Where I am going with this: There is NO practical method of giving extra votes to people without trouncing human rights. You either get labeled a race by the government at birth and assigned a value based on that label. Or you are allowed to choose whichever race gives you the best advantage.

The reason some people can say the Electoral College is not a bad idea is that it gives STATES extra votes. Because the Federal government needs to work very closely with the states it makes sense to try and even the playing field and prevent single states from owning the Federal government with to many votes. But that is an entirely different discussion.

**Disclaimer:** Remember to only do a CMV on subjects that **you** personally hold. That means if you don't *personally* believe that minorities should have extra voting power, then you should avoid doing a CMV on the subject. That being said, I replied with the assumption that you personally believe minorities should get extra voting power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926528782.0" user="Cadfan17" delta="False">
    <text>Whether or not OP believes this, I can say for a fact that there are people who believe we should have an ethnic and gender based electoral college.  I read them in undergraduate.  They literally just cut and paste all of the arguments in favor of and defenses of the existing electoral college and change them to be about race and gender.  And they argue that race and gender separates us more meaningfully than state of residence.

I think they're right that race and gender separate us more meaningfully than state of residence.  And I was forced to acknowledge that IF you accept that the electoral college is a good idea, THEN that implies that a race and gender based electoral college is a better idea.

But I think the electoral college is kinda dumb to begin with, so I was never actually convinced by them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926540816.0" user="ZerexTheCool" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Whether or not OP believes this, I can say for a fact that there are people who believe we should have an ethnic and gender-based electoral college


I need to know the specifics of what causes a person hold this view in order to create a useful counterargument. 

If the person does not hold the view, then all I am doing is objecting to an idea to a crowd of people who already agree. I don't mind devil's advocate, but this subreddit specifically requests that we don't create a post as a devil's advocate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926640902.0" user="Deus_Priores" delta="False">
    <text>But the USA is built on a federal system where STATES hold power and sovereignty and individual minority groups do not hold this same type of power and they definitely do not hold sovereignty</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926717476.0" user="Cadfan17" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but, those are made up words that don't actually refer to anything real.  They reflect decisions about how things ought to be that could have been made, and could be made, differently in the future.  Your response amounts to "we can't have that because its not how the law is."  Everyone knows that and the argument is about whether the law should change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926547569.0" user="Generic_On_Reddit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; **Disclaimer:** Remember to only do a CMV on subjects that **you** personally hold. That means if you don't *personally* believe that minorities should have extra voting power, then you should avoid doing a CMV on the subject. That being said, I will continue with the assumption that you personally believe minorities should get extra voting power.

His belief isn't that minorities should have extra voting power, it's that the reason given for rural voters having extra representation through the electoral college is inconsistent and hypocritical unless applied to other marginalized groups as well, such as minorities. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926573766.0" user="ZerexTheCool" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, you are probably right. Thank you.

Then my answer to that view is:

Implementation IS possible for allowing low population states to have a higher percentage of the votes.

Implementation is extremely messy and (I would argue) disastrous when attempting to apply it to metrics that are hard to define such as race. 

Unless you can find a way to implement it, we can't even begin the discussion on whether it SHOULD be or shouldn't be. We have to know the costs in order to determine if the benefits are worth it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926682872.0" user="HarryPotter5777" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Unless you can find a way to implement it, we can't even begin the discussion on whether it SHOULD be or shouldn't be.

I'm not sure this should be accepted as an axiom - lots of things are difficult to implement but are still worth discussing (legislative measures to combat climate change, for instance). Certainly determining the optimal way to carry out such a policy would be very difficult, but one could still ask "is this proposal which doesn't do everything possible better than the current system?" or similar questions to get at the issue at hand without a concrete plan for implementing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926649459.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927189682.0" user="Gamer36" delta="False">
    <text>If you allow people to select their race, you run into the problem that you quoted. People would choose whichever race gave them the most voting power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926743626.0" user="ChaoticVegan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Remember to only do a CMV on subjects that you personally hold. That means if you don't personally believe that minorities should have extra voting power, then you should avoid doing a CMV on the subject. That being said, I replied with the assumption that you personally believe minorities should get extra voting power

I am not arguing that minorities should get more of a vote. I am arguing that under our current system, it would be equally fair for minorities to get more of a vote (I specifically said "on the basis that"). Just like a libertarian might think taxes are bad. But as long as we are going to have taxes, they might think certain taxes are particularly unfair. I think the electoral college is bad, and choosing to give people a benefit for something that they choose is particularly unfair. It would seem more fair to do it for things people have no choice in. I can move to Wyoming for the specific purpose of making my vote be worth more.

I will agree from a practical standpoint though. I suppose I should have addressed that, I am arguing purely from a "what would be fair" standpoint. I think very few people think minority votes should be worth more. Personally I think both items in my title would be unfair, but that giving minorities more of a vote would be less unfair than giving rural states more of a vote. But you're completely right that it's not practical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927140121.0" user="Zaeron" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I am not arguing that minorities should get more of a vote. I am arguing that under our current system, it would be equally fair for minorities to get more of a vote

Except that this is a fundamental misunderstanding of why the EC exists.

The EC doesn't exist to make sure that rural voters are worth more than city voters.

The EC exists to make sure that each state has a more balanced say in who becomes president. The reason is that the *United States* wouldn't be united if the union was bullshit for some states. For example, how are you gonna convince Vermont, w/ 500k people, to join a union of states when it's voting against New York, with over 10mil in the biggest city alone.

You'd be saying "hey Vermont, come join our cool club where all the cool kids hang out and vote, only your vote is FUCKING WORTHLESS LOL".

You're looking at this from a completely absurd perspective because you fundamentally misunderstand why it was created the way it is.

EDIT - from another perspective, the EC *is* minority protection. It's just a minority protection at the state level, not the individual voter level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927450905.0" user="TheOctazone" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The EC doesn't exist to make sure that rural voters are worth more than city voters.

Whether or not it is designed to, it DOES do this though.

&amp;gt;You'd be saying "hey Vermont, come join our cool club where all the cool kids hang out and vote, only your vote is FUCKING WORTHLESS LOL".

Except Vermont doesn't go to the voting booth, the citizens in Vermont do, where their votes are NOT worthless, they are worth exactly the same amount as 500K people from New York.

States don't want the government to build roads, fund schools, or enforce laws. People in those states do, and those people are not treated fairly under our current system. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927517400.0" user="Zaeron" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Except Vermont doesn't go to the voting booth, the citizens in Vermont do, where their votes are NOT worthless, they are worth exactly the same amount as 500K people from New York.

Uhhhh. Actually, yes, yes it does. The only reason there's a popular vote at all for President is that states have agreed it's binding on their electors. Their electors (members of the electoral college, chosen by the states) will hold the actual vote for president in a month or so.

The election we just had is actually just an elaborate dog and pony show that is in no way actually binding on the people who actually vote for president.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927563018.0" user="TheOctazone" delta="False">
    <text>Vermont does not physically go to the voting booth. It is a landmass. I understand exactly what you are saying- Yes, our system does consider "Vermont" to be a valid voting entity, rather than the individual citizen. I used the metaphor to illustrate that since the actual citizens are the ones asking for government to do specific things, and the ones actually going to a booth and casting a vote, they are the ones the system should count, not the landmasses they live on that have been (unwisely) chosen to be considered the basis of our system.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927536147.0" user="THE_LAST_HIPPO" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with all the facts that you stated but one could still think that the EC is unfair or could be made more fair even though they understand what the EC's intent was</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
