<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28928379460.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>I think the basis of your argument is flawed but I'll try to explain it in three sections.

* The electoral college is not to protect rural areas. It is to protect small states. While small states are often rural they aren't always. Deleware has the 6th highest poulation density but is one of the smallest states. Rhode Island has the 2nd highest density and is also one of the 7 smallest staes. 

* Rural areas are most certainly not helped by the electoral college. In many, if not all Democratic states, the urban areas control the electoral college. Illinois is blue because Chicago is blue. The rural areas in Illinois are red yet they get no say in the electoral college. Washington state hasn't voted for a Republican since 1988 yet the rural areas of Washington vote consistently Republican. The electoral college hurts these rural areas it doesn't help them at all.

* Why are you choosing to help minority voters? Who gets to decide which group gets a boost and which doesn't? Do Catholics or Mormons get a boost? Do homosexuals get a boost? Do geniuses get a boost? Are you just deciding based on the color of skin? And why would we do that? Are you really proposing that white people only count as 3/5 of a person? Because an idea like that was used once and it was a pretty terrible idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29119428323.0" user="unak78" delta="False">
    <text>He isn't advocating giving minorities extra weighted votes.  He's using it as an example of why urban voters feel disenfranchised by the EC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29119626530.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>That's fine but he's doing it by falsely stating rural voters are disproportionally represented when like I showed it was small states not rural states that have disproportional representation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29151242771.0" user="unak78" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, however it is somewhat true that the states in which urban voters have more influence tend to be larger states. But this does not discount the fact that there are mid-sized states with large metro areas like Miami, Cleveland, etc.  So, yes, it isn't entirely true.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
