<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28926506175.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>Rural voters get a disproportionate amount of power because there are few people that live there. Every state gets three representatives guaranteed. This means that states without many people are over represented, not necessarily rural people as a whole. Both California and Texas have many rural areas where few people live, but they don't get over represented. They get vastly under represented because the state they live in has a ton of people. Someone in a big city in North Dakota is in an urban area but is still over represented because they live in a state with few people. If minorities wanted to become over represented they could move to a state with fewer people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926512227.0" user="lahddax" delta="False">
    <text>The OP is saying that they "should" not that they do. Nothing in your argument speaks to the justness of the current arrangement and thus you're completely off topic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926553044.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>If minorities want to be over represented they can do what everyone else who's over represented does and move to a small state. Minorities in those states are over represented. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926657431.0" user="HarryPotter5777" delta="False">
    <text>You're correct, but you're also not replying to OP's post. The stated view is about the justifications of more weight given to rural votes vs more weight given to minority votes, not about why these weights are currently the case or how minority voters could indirectly gain representation in the current system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926691445.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that the premise that rural votes get more of a say is wrong. It's small states that are over represented. That's way different than singling out a group based on a characteristic. The fact that he argument is based on a faulty premise is the issue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926694974.0" user="HarryPotter5777" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I misunderstood you then. Fair point!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926977291.0" user="Ducks_have_heads" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you here. But I think the justification for the electoral college is often that it allows a "fair" representation of the rural, less populous states who would otherwise be under represented. I don't think OP buys into this premise, just that it's the argument used to justify the electoral college. And then by the same logic, OP is trying to argue that these people must also grant a higher weight to minority votes because they're under represented. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28928389106.0" user="gaviidae" delta="False">
    <text>Small states are not all rural voters. Deleware and Rhode Island are 2 of the 7 smallest states yet are 2 of the 6 with the highest population density. Calling Deleware and Rhode Island rural areas is absurd. The electoral college favors them as much as it does South Dakota and Montana.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
