<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28926554468.0" user="rsaunders21" delta="False">
    <text>Minorities are the new majority. More than 50% of Americans are not white</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926675249.0" user="HarryPotter5777" delta="False">
    <text>It's impressive how wrong you can be in so few words!

First off, your demographic claim is completely false. White americans made up 63.7% of the population in 2010, a proportion which is estimated to be around 2% lower now. This is well over half of the population. White non-Hispanic people make up less than half of the population in just 4 of the 50 states.

Also, Jesus Christ how biased can you possibly get? "White Americans are clearly the group to compare against, because they're the normal ones, but all those minorities, why, *they* should be lumped together because they're all basically the same anyway." Is that really how you categorize people? More underrepresented groups put together does not equal one group with adequate representation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926675910.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; More than 50% of Americans are not white

That's [not correct](https://www.statista.com/statistics/270272/percentage-of-us-population-by-ethnicities/).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926722335.0" user="ChaoticVegan" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source that that backs that up? A quick search of the census seems to indicate that white people make up 77% of the population.

https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/table/PST045215/00</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927161630.0" user="therapy" delta="False">
    <text>The tricky thing is what is "white". Some Hispanic people look "white", for example, so you start getting into issues of ethnicity vs race. The same happens with Jewish people, many of whom look "white" but white supremacists certainly don't think so. Likewise, some Hispanic people are "black" and some of them identify more as Hispanic than black.

Anyhow, depending on how you define "white", the percentage of such people in the US is [between 72% and 63%](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demography_of_the_United_States#Race_and_ethnicity). So still a majority, although at 63% not a big one, and a decreasing one as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28930952875.0" user="grandoz039" delta="False">
    <text>I think white is defined race. There are many white ethnicities, but white is too wide to be considered ethnicity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
