<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28926647417.0" user="-Kryptic-" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose of boosting the rural vote isn't for the rural people, per se. There are whole industries, farming, mining, and logging being the big examples, that just don't exist in cities. If rural votes were equal to urban or suburban votes, these industries vital to the American economy and therefore American wellbeing, would not be as represented. Could you trust a government made up of those from Americas biggest cities, New Yorkers, Angelinos, etc. to even learn about these industries representatives from rural areas, much less represent them when they aren't a part of their constituency?


Another point is that weighting votes based on race would be racist, by even the most narrow definitions. All it would do is encourage racial based voting blocs, which could only make racial tensions worse. While a boosted rural vote is biased, and might even be biased towards certain cultural groups, it is fair in the way that it is purely geographic. Anyone can take advantage of this weight by moving there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926672772.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926695671.0" user="HarryPotter5777" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;While a boosted rural vote is biased, and might even be biased towards certain cultural groups, it is fair in the way that it is purely geographic. Anyone can take advantage of this weight by moving there.

One could make the same argument about weighting votes by wealth, though:

&amp;gt;While a boosted rich vote is biased, and might even be biased towards certain cultural groups, it is fair in the way that it is purely economic. Anyone can take advantage of this weight by working harder and getting a better job.

The objection to this sort of argument is more clear here: factors like this aren't so voluntary as we might like to think. While not intrinsically predetermined, one's location and ability to move from it, or wealth and ability to increase it, are relatively difficult to alter from that of their parents for most people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927702196.0" user="-Kryptic-" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that those are not even comparable examples, poverty requires hard work across generations to escape from or insane luck, while the only "hard" cost about moving to a new state is just that, the transportation. Assuming you're not going to Alaska or Hawaii, its relatively cheap to rent a uhaul and find yourself across the country in short order, cheaper if you get a ride from a friend or a greyhound. I would agree that there are a lot of soft costs in moving, you don't know as many people to help support you, and by moving you might be severing some ties in your home state, but it's not insurmountable, and everyone who moves experiences these problems. It's not perfect, but its a far cry from wealth voting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29119411377.0" user="unak78" delta="False">
    <text>Finding employment in your newly chosen locale is not easy unless you're either really poor or very wealthy.  A Walmart employee can probably go to another state and find another equal-paying minimum-wage job fairly quickly, but he/she would find a difficult time putting their lives back together afterwards.  A middle-income employee might have more savings with which to move, but they might also spend up to a year finding employment in their skilled profession.  Only the wealthy and upper middle class have fairly unlimited mobility</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28926797566.0" user="Darkwind85" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Mining, farming and logging

You just mentioned 3 industries that are extremely destructive to the environment. Rural areas also tend to be the least educated and most religious regions. Reducing their influence and power to affect policy in USA would be a step in the right direction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28927694141.0" user="-Kryptic-" delta="False">
    <text>Typically its not the people involved on site, engineers and miners, that are malicious, their experience and education has shown them the impact of their actions. Its the people that they rely on for their living, the corporate people that want to cut corners and costs, that are to blame for environmental damage. 


Riddle me this: If mining, logging, and farming, are all integral to our economy and standard of life, would you rather have power vested in the states that are experienced in the given field, the ones with the experience and who would face the consequences of mistakes, or would you rather that the power is vested in some fortune 500 company in a big city, like the dickweeds trying to build the standing rock pipeline?


Look, I'm saying this as a very blue guy in a very red state, its like I'm glad that Republicans keep winning elections despite the popular vote, but I also know the reason why we have the system in the first place. If you could kindly get off your high fucking horse, and stop trying to disenfranchise people because of their religion and level of education, that would be nice. Its funny how we liberals want to protect and help those of religious and poor socionomic background, until its a white guy from Appalachia. Its a double standard, and one of the things I hate about our current political culture.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
