<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28926852456.0" user="thereasonableman_" delta="False">
    <text>This policy would be like putting an atomic bomb at the top of a very slippery slope.  It's a future disaster waiting to happen once you establish different groups get different voting power.

Also, what is a minority?  Atheists are far more underrepresented than black people, should they get more votes?  There are very few Jews but they have substantial political representation and influence, do they get more votes?  Wealthy black men have their interests better represented than poor whites and need less political protection, do they get extra votes?  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
