<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="327010324.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5eoys4/cmv_on_the_basis_that_rural_votes_count_for_more/">
    <title>CMV: On the basis that rural votes count for more in US politics, minorities should also get disproportionate voting power.</title>
    <original_poster>ChaoticVegan</original_poster>
    <original_post>People in favor of the electoral college always say that rural areas would get ignored if we did the popular vote, that their voice isn't heard. I would think this effect would be even stronger with minority groups. According to the 2010 census 19.3% of people live in rural areas. But African Americans make up only 13% of the population and Latino's make up 17% of the population, and that's just looking at the two biggest groups. So I would think that if rural voters get a disproportionate portion of the vote, and that's fair because they are underrepresented, then it should only be fair for minorities also get a disproportionate amount of the vote.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28927588932.0" user="PuffyPanda200" delta="False">
    <text>The reason that the US has he electoral collage and a winner take all system for each state is that the US States were created to be highly independent, semi sovereign governments. The original constitution only allowed the Federal government to regulate interstate commerce. Looking at the US as a collection of sovereign states is more appropriate. 

The smaller states also get a slightly inflated weight as part of the Great Compromise. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29119436821.0" user="unak78" delta="False">
    <text>And if the powers of the Federal government remained comparatively restricted, then the weighted disproportion would draw no issue.  The problem now is that our voting system recognizes the sovereign will of states but it is anything but in practical day-to-day governance.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29119771663.0" user="PuffyPanda200" delta="False">
    <text>There are many checks on federal power in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29279646233.0" user="unak78" delta="False">
    <text>Hopefully this is still true when one party controls both houses of congress, the executive and the SCOTUS.  Federal Courts have shown initiative, and to their credit, SCOTUS appointees on both sides have often gone against the grain on many big cases if only to reinforce their political independence. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
