<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="337612532.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5l07hw/cmv_nicotine_is_not_alone_more_addictive_than/">
    <title>CMV: Nicotine is not, alone, more addictive than caffeine.</title>
    <original_poster>blubugeye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Nicotine is widely claimed to be highly addictive, but it is quite difficult to find studies of nicotine in isolation.  Studies found through web searches address nicotine in cigarette smoke.  Cigarette smoke is known to include many chemicals that may significantly influence the effects of nicotine.  In fact, it is difficult to determine whether elements of cigarette smoke make nicotine more addictive, as opposed to nicotine enhancing the effects of other chemicals and therefore appearing to be addictive while actually enhancing in a different experience.

Meanwhile, nicotine is available "over the counter" (albeit with restrictions) in the form of nicotine gum or nicotine in "vape juice."  Addiction to nicotine gum (in non-smokers) does not appear to be an issue.

I have never smoked, but I have taken up vaping.  After months of exposure, I find that I miss my vaping no more than I miss my morning coffee.

**EDIT**

I have found [an article that is pertinent](http://discovermagazine.com/2014/march/13-nicotine-fix), published by Discover Magazine.  To my point: "Perhaps most surprising is that, in studies by Boyd and others, nicotine has not caused addiction or withdrawal when used to treat disease," and "it’s almost impossible to get laboratory animals hooked on pure nicotine, though it has a mildly pleasant effect."

I now have leads that I can follow through the researchers named in the article.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29010369647.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>The evidence is _overwhelming_ that nicotine is the source of cigarette addiction.  Gum statistics are pointless since that is an audience that _almost by definition_ is attempting to quit and using gum as a method of weening.  It also provides a slower binding affect with receptors due to the method of intake (e.g. it satisfies less).  Further, the physiologic connection between nicotine and addiction is well understood (look for studies on tolerance in the nicotinic cholinergic receptors if you really want to dig in).

However, since caffeine is not thought to be _harmful_ the motivation of cessation is relatively low comparatively making it hard to measure a comparative level of addiction.  However, symptoms of withdrawal last about a week for caffeine but much longer for nictotine - so...at least some measures of addiction (withdrawal) are more sustained for nicotine than caffeine.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010546758.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>You'll have to cite sources that consider nicotine in isolation.  Thanks, though.

Also, I would like to see your sources for the claims about "symptoms of withdrawal."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010591147.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>I gave you a google search.  You're the one going contrary to conventional wisdom....where are the sources that convinced you?  Im not in a place where i can ppint you to anything, but will be happy to point you when i can.  Also, look for the Jarvis and Stolman piece.  Perhaps the most compelling fact is that nicotine immediately stops withdrawal from cigarette smoking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010698002.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; nicotinic cholinergic receptors

A "Google search" of "nicotinic cholinergic receptors" is wonderful for learning about the behavior of a specific class of receptors, but I'm struggling to translate the chemistry into an understanding of why I should believe that nicotine is more addictive than caffeine.

Once I came to understand that tobacco smoke includes MAO inhibitors (or, at the least, "produces inhibition of brain MAO activity in humans" https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3685473/), I realized that tobacco addiction can have causes un-related to nicotine.  Finally, upon searching for research on nicotine alone, I was disappointed that there appears to be very little.  I find it hard to understand how any scientist can draw conclusions about an easily isolated chemical while studying it in the midst of a stew like cigarette smoke.  My skepticism feels natural, albeit not "conventional."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010732324.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I'd be compelled by the impact of nicotine on tabacco withdrawal - that alone should be compelling.  That said, i doubt you'll find anything that shows it to be _more_ addictive - they are both highly addictive, just one has a delivery system that kills you.  

Did you find the jarvis study?  it should convince you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29011582895.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Jarvis

I have found an article by Jarvis and *Stolerman*, entitled "[The scientific case that nicotine is addictive](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/7724697)."  The abstract is less direct than the title, including this: "Studies in both animal and human subjects have shown that nicotine can function as reinforcer, albeit under a more limited range of conditions than with some other drugs of abuse."  As far as I can tell, access to the full article will cost me $40.  I'll put it on my list of things to go after when I am ready to part with the cash.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29012770725.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>I have the study given my access.  The highlights:

1. take away cigarettes and compulsion to smoke is alleviated by nicotine replacement.

2. take away cigarettes and physical withdrawal symptoms - both subjective and measured / biological - are alleviated by nicotine replacement.

3. nicotine enhanced tobacco products (long illegal) showed stronger addiction than non-nicotine enhanced.

(lots of other things as well)

4. The conclusion of the study is also in the summary that you cherry picked from - "In total, the evidence clearly identifies nicotine as a powerful drug of addiction, comparable to heroin, cocaine and alcohol."

5. The prior studies I point to detail the _chemical mechanisms_ that lead to addiction.  Not understanding them shouldn't lessen their validity since you're looking for 'scientific evidence' it seems a bit disingenuous to have lack of scientific knowledge and background be the reason that you choose to take the contrarian and strongly minority position with regards to the addictiveness of nicotine.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29012826840.0" user="Deadlymonkey" delta="False">
    <text>Nicotine has a different metabolic pathway than caffeine. It's like if you went to mcdonalds to get food and your brother went to a steakhouse. You both went out, got food, and are now full, but your brother is happier because he got a steak. You both are probably going to go get food again, but it's harder to stop getting steak than it  is mcdonalds.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
