<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="337612532.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5l07hw/cmv_nicotine_is_not_alone_more_addictive_than/">
    <title>CMV: Nicotine is not, alone, more addictive than caffeine.</title>
    <original_poster>blubugeye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Nicotine is widely claimed to be highly addictive, but it is quite difficult to find studies of nicotine in isolation.  Studies found through web searches address nicotine in cigarette smoke.  Cigarette smoke is known to include many chemicals that may significantly influence the effects of nicotine.  In fact, it is difficult to determine whether elements of cigarette smoke make nicotine more addictive, as opposed to nicotine enhancing the effects of other chemicals and therefore appearing to be addictive while actually enhancing in a different experience.

Meanwhile, nicotine is available "over the counter" (albeit with restrictions) in the form of nicotine gum or nicotine in "vape juice."  Addiction to nicotine gum (in non-smokers) does not appear to be an issue.

I have never smoked, but I have taken up vaping.  After months of exposure, I find that I miss my vaping no more than I miss my morning coffee.

**EDIT**

I have found [an article that is pertinent](http://discovermagazine.com/2014/march/13-nicotine-fix), published by Discover Magazine.  To my point: "Perhaps most surprising is that, in studies by Boyd and others, nicotine has not caused addiction or withdrawal when used to treat disease," and "it’s almost impossible to get laboratory animals hooked on pure nicotine, though it has a mildly pleasant effect."

I now have leads that I can follow through the researchers named in the article.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29010552775.0" user="WhenSnowDies" delta="False">
    <text>I think your view is making a false comparison. Caffeine is actually *extremely* addictive and part of the same family of drugs as nicotine. The reason caffeine doesn't get a bad reputation is because its delivery method is completely safe. If you had to smoke coffee then that'd be a different story. Aerosols can be extremely damaging to complex and sensitive lung tissue, which is deep in the body, and frankly if your lungs begin to fail you don't last long. Smoking is a gamble adding complex chemicals to a complex  device you absolutely need, with a history of very bad results, for pleasure.

And that pleasure is where nictone stands out from caffeine: It's both a stimulant and depressant, releases dopamine, and has complex effects on your mood. Because of that, nicotine *is* both physically and psychologically addictive in a far more complex way than caffeine, or else you wouldn't use it. You'd be collecting and sampling complex coffees and keeping a thermos with you, not a vape. You're not vaping for the risks you're downplaying, but the effects, and if they were similar and as addictive as caffeine then you'd just drink coffee.

You should change your view.

On a personal note, I know there's a secondary sneaky view within your view: That vaping isn't *really* that addictive or dangerous. It's like coffee.

I smoke a tobacco pipe privately and drink coffee like everybody else. I'm sure to smoke only a couple times a week so I don't form a chemical addiction, and tobacco pipes have a long history of not killing people, probably because it's very little tobacco over a long period of time, delivered to superficial and physically sensitive tissue you can look at and identity problems fast and fix cheap without risking your life. Still there's a risk, and it's certainly addictive, requiring monitoring and moderating properly to minimize exposure.

In my experience, lots of guys new to these hobby drugs will downplay their ill effects because it's not worth it to them, because it's a fad or pleasure to them, and they're unwilling to commit to actual risk but are willing to lie to themselves and ask others to lie to them. If you love to vape then vape and accept the risks and be honest and real with yourself and others. If you're vaping for other reasons like addiction, hobby, pleasure, image or whatever, then there are better and safer things out there that do all that. Find those things. Leave these things to the folks who accept and take responsibility for the risks, including addiction.

However if you're smoking under the pretense that it's safe and non-addictive, then you don't know what you're doing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010571365.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>None of this addresses my original premise.  Further, "You should change your view" is not true to the spirit of this exercise.  Please supply some reason, other than your personal opinion, that would lead me to reconsider my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010786836.0" user="MainStreetExile" delta="False">
    <text>He gave several reasons that were not his personal opinion. You just ignored them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29012611656.0" user="WhenSnowDies" delta="False">
    <text>Personal opinion and reason is an aspect of /r/ChangeMyView, and my post contained both. It's disingenuous to portray it like that and write me off in three lines because you disagree.

You should be responding to my response to your post, not analyzing if it's worthy of CMV. That's complete bullshit.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
