<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="337612532.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5l07hw/cmv_nicotine_is_not_alone_more_addictive_than/">
    <title>CMV: Nicotine is not, alone, more addictive than caffeine.</title>
    <original_poster>blubugeye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Nicotine is widely claimed to be highly addictive, but it is quite difficult to find studies of nicotine in isolation.  Studies found through web searches address nicotine in cigarette smoke.  Cigarette smoke is known to include many chemicals that may significantly influence the effects of nicotine.  In fact, it is difficult to determine whether elements of cigarette smoke make nicotine more addictive, as opposed to nicotine enhancing the effects of other chemicals and therefore appearing to be addictive while actually enhancing in a different experience.

Meanwhile, nicotine is available "over the counter" (albeit with restrictions) in the form of nicotine gum or nicotine in "vape juice."  Addiction to nicotine gum (in non-smokers) does not appear to be an issue.

I have never smoked, but I have taken up vaping.  After months of exposure, I find that I miss my vaping no more than I miss my morning coffee.

**EDIT**

I have found [an article that is pertinent](http://discovermagazine.com/2014/march/13-nicotine-fix), published by Discover Magazine.  To my point: "Perhaps most surprising is that, in studies by Boyd and others, nicotine has not caused addiction or withdrawal when used to treat disease," and "it’s almost impossible to get laboratory animals hooked on pure nicotine, though it has a mildly pleasant effect."

I now have leads that I can follow through the researchers named in the article.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29010410936.0" user="Omega037" delta="False">
    <text>They have done plenty of studies on this, and here are the basic results according to the National Institute of Drug Abuse:

http://www.drugwarfacts.org/comparecht.gif

Basically, Nicotine has the worse dependence of any drug, including Heroin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010550712.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>I need evidence that these studies considered nicotine isolated from tobacco smoke.  A .gif is not convincing.

BTW, who is "drugwarfacts.org"?  Why should I respect them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010644883.0" user="Omega037" delta="False">
    <text>The graph was produced by the NY Times based on rankings given to them by [Jack E. Henningfield](http://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/psychiatry/expert_team/faculty/h/henningfield.html) who at the time was at the National Institute on Drug Abuse (now at John Hopkins) and [Dr. Neal L. Benowitz](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neal_Benowitz), a Professor at the University of California at San Francisco.

Both are considered experts in the field, with Benowitz often being called "one of the country's preeminent experts on nicotine", according to his Wikipedia page.

I found the [original NY Times article](http://www.nytimes.com/1994/08/02/science/is-nicotine-addictive-it-depends-on-whose-criteria-you-use.html?pagewanted=2) online, but while it references the chart by title, they didn't include it in the online version.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29010730028.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>Following references in your reply, I get further re-enforcement that research regarding nicotine is bound tightly to tobacco.

I did find a quote from Dr. Benowitz that ["Nicotine may have some adverse health effects, but they are relatively minor."](https://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/23/health/a-hot-debate-over-e-cigarettes-as-a-path-to-tobacco-or-from-it.html?_r=0)  Also, I found a NIH paper entitled "[Nicotine Addiction](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2928221/)" that is really about tobacco addiction (from the abstract, "This article focuses on nicotine as a determinant of addiction to tobacco....").

So far, I'm more frustrated by the lack of science addressing nicotine alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29011014701.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I did find a quote from Dr. Benowitz that "Nicotine may have some adverse health effects, but they are relatively minor."

Okay, but who cares? Why would you tell us this? It's totally irrelevant to any point that anyone is discussing. Your CMV isn't about whether nicotine is *healthier* than caffeine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29011614483.0" user="blubugeye" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed.  Addiction is, I suppose, not an adverse health effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29011345841.0" user="plaid_tartan" delta="False">
    <text>Nida is an anti drug wing of the us government. Because they are explicitly anti drugs, they are not objective and you shouldn't trust any of their findings. They may sometimes put out true information, but only if it aligns with their goals. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
