<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="337612532.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5l07hw/cmv_nicotine_is_not_alone_more_addictive_than/">
    <title>CMV: Nicotine is not, alone, more addictive than caffeine.</title>
    <original_poster>blubugeye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Nicotine is widely claimed to be highly addictive, but it is quite difficult to find studies of nicotine in isolation.  Studies found through web searches address nicotine in cigarette smoke.  Cigarette smoke is known to include many chemicals that may significantly influence the effects of nicotine.  In fact, it is difficult to determine whether elements of cigarette smoke make nicotine more addictive, as opposed to nicotine enhancing the effects of other chemicals and therefore appearing to be addictive while actually enhancing in a different experience.

Meanwhile, nicotine is available "over the counter" (albeit with restrictions) in the form of nicotine gum or nicotine in "vape juice."  Addiction to nicotine gum (in non-smokers) does not appear to be an issue.

I have never smoked, but I have taken up vaping.  After months of exposure, I find that I miss my vaping no more than I miss my morning coffee.

**EDIT**

I have found [an article that is pertinent](http://discovermagazine.com/2014/march/13-nicotine-fix), published by Discover Magazine.  To my point: "Perhaps most surprising is that, in studies by Boyd and others, nicotine has not caused addiction or withdrawal when used to treat disease," and "it’s almost impossible to get laboratory animals hooked on pure nicotine, though it has a mildly pleasant effect."

I now have leads that I can follow through the researchers named in the article.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29011359712.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nicotine is widely claimed to be highly addictive, but it is quite difficult to find studies of nicotine in isolation.

It's because it is impossible.

Caffeine has some mild dependence-forming, and in some individuals strongly. And one can and will experience a desire to consume caffeine in whatever form available.

Nicotine however has no dependece whatsoever without it's delivery mechanism (tobacco). A test were done where a pure nicotine was administered to smokers and non-smokers. And in every case the individual didn't form pure nicotine dependence regardless of the dose administered.

Nicotine has much stronger dependence with it's delivery mechanism, the tobacco. One must first be addicted to tobacco, and then the nicotine dependency manifests.

Generally according to many articles, studies and experiments. If 100 people tries to quit smoking and 100 people tries to quit drinking. Less than 2% of smokers will manage sucessfully without an assistance quit smoking and still test abstinent after 1 year.

So technically yes. Nicotine alone by itself has no potential for dependency and hence addiction. But with combination with the tobacco and/or other effective vehicles it is much, much stronger than caffeine alone, or in any other vehicle.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
