<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="340675377.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5mtusx/cmv_modern_office_jobs_makes_you_a_robot_and/">
    <title>CMV: Modern office jobs makes you a Robot. And there's nothing you can do about it.</title>
    <original_poster>turbo_runner</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello.  I'd like to say that I work in an programming job, so I've experienced beforehand what I'm about to describe.

First of all, I know there's nothing new about it, people were doing monotonous tasks in the past, typing all day long or filling forms by hand. It hasn't changed at all, maybe the difference is that most things are done by a computer now.

However after working for more than a year in the same place, doing the same thing for 5 or 6 days, sometimes working extra-hours so the company can have a report that no one is going to read but they "need it". Can create in the individual a sense of emptiness, Some might cope with it by staying with their family, or going out with friends, but in the end, it's going to be the same thing after the weekend or vacations are over. 

The individual then, needs to go back to work, and continue with the same routine, year after year, until they either retire, or die. 

So in a sense, those working in a cubicle are robots, we're all robots, because we do the same thing until we break down and they replace us. 

Of course one might get this sense of "meaningless" in any job, white or blue collar, but working in a corporate job gives you that feeling sooner. 

That being said, I believe there's nothing we can do, so we can only work until we die. Please CMV.





_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29034385657.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't you just do something you enjoy instead? I'm about to turn 29 and I've had all kinds of different jobs and just in the last 2 years started working trades. It's amazing. So much more satisfying than any other kind of work. You go home feeling like you accomplished something. I actually look forward to working now. Everyone I know who does corporate/office type stuff is miserable. I think humans have a psychological need to see the results of their labor and an office job simply can't satisfy that. I never thought I'd be doing the type of work I do now. If I can do it, anyone can. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29034404821.0" user="turbo_runner" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I know that working in what you enjoy is the key. But I feel I've lost that when I started working in software development and Programming. Suddenly working in what you like, everyday. Can kill that passion.

However I agree that trying something different might be a solution!.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
