<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="340675377.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5mtusx/cmv_modern_office_jobs_makes_you_a_robot_and/">
    <title>CMV: Modern office jobs makes you a Robot. And there's nothing you can do about it.</title>
    <original_poster>turbo_runner</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello.  I'd like to say that I work in an programming job, so I've experienced beforehand what I'm about to describe.

First of all, I know there's nothing new about it, people were doing monotonous tasks in the past, typing all day long or filling forms by hand. It hasn't changed at all, maybe the difference is that most things are done by a computer now.

However after working for more than a year in the same place, doing the same thing for 5 or 6 days, sometimes working extra-hours so the company can have a report that no one is going to read but they "need it". Can create in the individual a sense of emptiness, Some might cope with it by staying with their family, or going out with friends, but in the end, it's going to be the same thing after the weekend or vacations are over. 

The individual then, needs to go back to work, and continue with the same routine, year after year, until they either retire, or die. 

So in a sense, those working in a cubicle are robots, we're all robots, because we do the same thing until we break down and they replace us. 

Of course one might get this sense of "meaningless" in any job, white or blue collar, but working in a corporate job gives you that feeling sooner. 

That being said, I believe there's nothing we can do, so we can only work until we die. Please CMV.





_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29034376045.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text> I believe there's nothing we can do

Get a different job which offers more freedom and creativity. 

There are a few things here. 

Certain  jobs do suck. That's why they give you money to do them. 

But if your job does suck you can try to find a job that is a better fit for you. There are jobs that require different skills. There are companies that want different things. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29034400049.0" user="turbo_runner" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with getting a different job, but some jobs are utterly similar in the end, for instance software development, so it doesn't matter really in which company you work for. Everything ends with developing or maintaining a system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29034661900.0" user="Tuokaerf10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Everything ends with developing or maintaining a system.

Well I mean if you think of it in a different way your entire life is developing or maintaining a system (getting up, eating 3 times a day, paying bills, doing your taxes, walking your dog, jerking off, sleeping, changing the cat litter, and so on). The key is to make your time enjoyable while doing all those things. 

Even though you're doing "similar" things from job to job, the time there makes all the difference. I've worked on teams where everyone is micromanaged and told what exactly to do, and it sucked ass. Other places have encouraged a lot of freedom and creativity, and going to work was a lot of fun even when I had to do some menial shit I generally didn't want to do. If you like to be creative, go there and have some fun while you're unit testing your code. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29037016301.0" user="ramd1000" delta="False">
    <text>I really think you chose a job that you dont enjoy. You could also see your job only as a source of money and then work on something that you like on your free time, this would probably help with the feeling of boredom</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
