<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="340675377.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5mtusx/cmv_modern_office_jobs_makes_you_a_robot_and/">
    <title>CMV: Modern office jobs makes you a Robot. And there's nothing you can do about it.</title>
    <original_poster>turbo_runner</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello.  I'd like to say that I work in an programming job, so I've experienced beforehand what I'm about to describe.

First of all, I know there's nothing new about it, people were doing monotonous tasks in the past, typing all day long or filling forms by hand. It hasn't changed at all, maybe the difference is that most things are done by a computer now.

However after working for more than a year in the same place, doing the same thing for 5 or 6 days, sometimes working extra-hours so the company can have a report that no one is going to read but they "need it". Can create in the individual a sense of emptiness, Some might cope with it by staying with their family, or going out with friends, but in the end, it's going to be the same thing after the weekend or vacations are over. 

The individual then, needs to go back to work, and continue with the same routine, year after year, until they either retire, or die. 

So in a sense, those working in a cubicle are robots, we're all robots, because we do the same thing until we break down and they replace us. 

Of course one might get this sense of "meaningless" in any job, white or blue collar, but working in a corporate job gives you that feeling sooner. 

That being said, I believe there's nothing we can do, so we can only work until we die. Please CMV.





_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29034516549.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds to me like you're making a rationale argument for how _you feel_.  Since there are at least some people who feel that their office jobs are great and that they are passionate about their work, the people they work, their customers and so on that you should at least considering looking at both yourself _and_ the job.

Perhaps most importantly - and a bit preachy, for which I'm sorry - is that the "attitude" you're presenting here is incredibly toxic in a work environment is a defining characteristic of the employee who doesn't "live up to their potential".  People around you are very, very sensitive to people feeling and acting like victims and people are very bad at hiding those feelings.  

Since you can't change the job, as you say...then look at what you can change.  Since there are people who don't feel like you do who have jobs that by your measures are no better, or maybe even worse than yours, then there is _absolutely_ something you can do about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29034560547.0" user="turbo_runner" delta="False">
    <text>Well, maybe you're right, I guess I will have to change of attitude given that I can't change of work (Unless I want to do something completely different from what I've studied). However my views may be shared with a lot of others who are in a similar position. Even Disney [made a short film about it](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XhEf0DRAVDE) and in the end I guess is the persuit of  happiness, in whatever form suits each one. 

Thanks for the advice though!.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
