<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="343657035.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5olrgr/cmv_us_expenditures_on_defense_is_why_there_is_so/">
    <title>CMV: U.S. Expenditures on defense is why there is so few terrorist attacks</title>
    <original_poster>KS1867</original_poster>
    <original_post>On Reddit the U.S. gets a lot of flak for spending so much on its defense budget. People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities. Another hot button issue on Reddit seems to be the use of drones and many will argue that our drone program makes more enemies than it kills. Although I do recognize the flaws with our drone program I believe stopping is not a solution and the drone program weakens the capabilities of terrorists networks to effectively plan attacks. I subscribe to the "peace means carrying a big stick" philosophy. Change my view on American defense spending and drones.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29057935405.0" user="tesla123456" delta="False">
    <text>US spends money on heavy weapons, tanks, submarines, nuclear, carriers, stealth planes, etc... To what... to fight ISIS teenagers with AK47s and a 20 year old Toyota pickup? Or bomb a single guy on the run in Paris? You must be joking. The US military is nothing but appeasement of the military-industrial complex and global posturing. Terrorism exits not only in spite of this, but in many ways BECAUSE of it.

Our intelligence is massive in the same way the TSA is massive, massively ineffective. They literally had the last two terrorists on FBI watch lists and they still committed attacks, right in the US. This is because you cannot use the military to fight terrorism as it isn't a military problem, it's a civilian problem.

In terms of Drones, drones are just a tool, and probably one of the cheapest ones we have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29057986963.0" user="JustAGuyCMV" delta="False">
    <text>Ha! I see you have never seen how the intelligence community has worked.

Hell, they had spied on us for years before a guy who worked there told us about it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
