<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="343657035.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5olrgr/cmv_us_expenditures_on_defense_is_why_there_is_so/">
    <title>CMV: U.S. Expenditures on defense is why there is so few terrorist attacks</title>
    <original_poster>KS1867</original_poster>
    <original_post>On Reddit the U.S. gets a lot of flak for spending so much on its defense budget. People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities. Another hot button issue on Reddit seems to be the use of drones and many will argue that our drone program makes more enemies than it kills. Although I do recognize the flaws with our drone program I believe stopping is not a solution and the drone program weakens the capabilities of terrorists networks to effectively plan attacks. I subscribe to the "peace means carrying a big stick" philosophy. Change my view on American defense spending and drones.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29057829319.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Except a good portion of the defense budget isn't spent on those things.

It is spent on soldiers, whose actions are often used as recruiting tools for terrorist organizations.

It is spent on hardware, which is then sold domestically, sold internationally, or just stored in such excess that it becomes illogical. security.blogs.cnn.com

The USA could still cut it's defense budget and perform all those duties you list.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29057863936.0" user="KS1867" delta="False">
    <text>Again the whole philosophy of "peace means carrying a big stick." Population wise we are not nearly the largest country. China alone has a billion more people than we do. Not saying war with China is probable, but the U.S. has plenty of world interests to protect in the event of a war. We've got the benefit of bordering two oceans, but when a country has a billion more people than you it's reasonable to want to have more firepower in the event of a shortage of resources (drinking water, oil, etc.) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29058779794.0" user="Tinie_Snipah" delta="False">
    <text>But these are not the same as terrorism. You're right that China couldn't beat the US in a war because of U.S. military spending, but that doesn't stop lone crazy people making chemical bombs and targeting civilians. If you so wanted you could do this on a very short amount of time essentially by yourself. The reason it doesn't happen all the time is because there aren't that many people in the U.S. that truly wish civilians harm. Far less than media would have you believe.

Why not? Well mainly because home grown terrorism in the US is very rare, and almost always consists of a lone gunman in a single shootout. So they have to come from abroad. Where? Well as you say there is two big oceans either side, which helps protect from terrorism as well as foreign invasion. They would either have to cross your land borders or fly in as migrants. Canada and Mexico are simply not hotbeds of terrorism, and any non U.S. national will get some pretty bad checks before entering. I drove in from Canada as a Brit travelling with a U.S. state representative, and it took me 4 or 5 hours of waiting at the checkpoint to be allowed in. God knows what they were doing with our passports.

So it relies on people flying in. There is simply no amount of attack helicopters, aircraft carriers, strategic bombers or ICBMs that could stop someone that has a legal right to fly to the U.S. from doing so. What stops people entering your country is background checks on people from areas of terrorist groups (central Africa, middle east, etc) and stopping these people getting visas or other entry requirements. I have heard that U.S. entry visas can be pretty extensive for many countries but haven't had experience personally so I couldn't say

So yeah, your military certainly protects your country from invasion, but it is your border force and immigration controls that stop terrorists from entering. Whether you class them as military is up to you. You could certainly make an argument that they are a civilian wing of your defence forces, but I personally wouldn't class them as military or military spending.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
