<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="343657035.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5olrgr/cmv_us_expenditures_on_defense_is_why_there_is_so/">
    <title>CMV: U.S. Expenditures on defense is why there is so few terrorist attacks</title>
    <original_poster>KS1867</original_poster>
    <original_post>On Reddit the U.S. gets a lot of flak for spending so much on its defense budget. People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities. Another hot button issue on Reddit seems to be the use of drones and many will argue that our drone program makes more enemies than it kills. Although I do recognize the flaws with our drone program I believe stopping is not a solution and the drone program weakens the capabilities of terrorists networks to effectively plan attacks. I subscribe to the "peace means carrying a big stick" philosophy. Change my view on American defense spending and drones.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29057843380.0" user="wugglesthemule" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities.

The main point of this argument is that it's a massive amount of spending to fight a trivial risk. The chance of an average American getting killed by a terrorist is close to zero, but terrorism gets a disproportionate amount of our attention, and hogs resources that could be used elsewhere. (It has also expanded the government's authority and eroded civil liberties, but that's another story.)

Secondly, there's no strong evidence that they've actually *stopped* a terrorist plot. If the TSA ever prevented an attack, they would have bragged about it. No matter what we do, the number of attacks will still be pretty small. One can easily argue that the benefit isn't worth the costs.

Regarding the drone program, most people agree that it's a useful tool, but the way we're using it is counter productive. There is always collateral damage, and that (understandably) pisses people off more. Also, it makes us less likely to go and gather intelligence or try and capture someone because it's way easier to take them out with a drone. It provides an incentive to over-do it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
