<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="343657035.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5olrgr/cmv_us_expenditures_on_defense_is_why_there_is_so/">
    <title>CMV: U.S. Expenditures on defense is why there is so few terrorist attacks</title>
    <original_poster>KS1867</original_poster>
    <original_post>On Reddit the U.S. gets a lot of flak for spending so much on its defense budget. People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities. Another hot button issue on Reddit seems to be the use of drones and many will argue that our drone program makes more enemies than it kills. Although I do recognize the flaws with our drone program I believe stopping is not a solution and the drone program weakens the capabilities of terrorists networks to effectively plan attacks. I subscribe to the "peace means carrying a big stick" philosophy. Change my view on American defense spending and drones.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29064419793.0" user="Bucanan" delta="False">
    <text>US Expenditure on Defence and more accurately war does actually create more terrorists than it kills. 

Think of it like this:

You are a un-educated, young man living in the backwater of Afghanistan. Since America , through its drone program, considers every man above the age of 15 to be a terrorist ( in the "warzone" ), they bomb the area where they think some terrorist dude is hiding. This results in various deaths, potentially that young man's friends, family etc. 

Now, to that young guy, he saw America fly this weird monstrosity that rained down death upon them. He saw it as if it was the devil in person. He now automatically hates America and in relation the West. He goes to some fucked up Mullah and that dude tells him that you will get 72 virgins or some bullshit, live like kings, be the greatest of greatest etc etc. Now, you have potentially another terrorists hating America. 

Now, when America bombed the terrorist, they didn't just kill the terrorist, they killed like 10 more people around him. Assuming they all had 2 children ( which might not be case but this is hypothetical scenario ) there are now 20 more terrorist. 


Also, the fact that the Iraq War directly produced ISIS and the mujahadeen in Afghanistan was the CIA training militants to fight against the Soviets. I reckon the whole "War on Terror" was probably the greatest failure in recent history.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
