<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="343657035.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5olrgr/cmv_us_expenditures_on_defense_is_why_there_is_so/">
    <title>CMV: U.S. Expenditures on defense is why there is so few terrorist attacks</title>
    <original_poster>KS1867</original_poster>
    <original_post>On Reddit the U.S. gets a lot of flak for spending so much on its defense budget. People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities. Another hot button issue on Reddit seems to be the use of drones and many will argue that our drone program makes more enemies than it kills. Although I do recognize the flaws with our drone program I believe stopping is not a solution and the drone program weakens the capabilities of terrorists networks to effectively plan attacks. I subscribe to the "peace means carrying a big stick" philosophy. Change my view on American defense spending and drones.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29058111014.0" user="BeatriceBernardo" delta="False">
    <text>* USA military spending as percentage of GDP: 4.4%

* USA Global Terrorism Index 4.613

Compare with

* Mongolia military spending as percentage of GDP: 0.9%

* Mongolia Global Terrorism Index 0

Looking at military spending as percentage of GDP and terrorism index alone, we could make these conclusions:

1. Military spending increase terrorism.

2. If Military spending actually decrease terrorism, then USA should learn from Mongolia as they are doing a more effective job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29058498059.0" user="plague006" delta="False">
    <text>Can you provide your source please? Choosing Mongolia seems like cherry picking an outlier and I'm also curious what the "terrorism index" is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29058753688.0" user="BeatriceBernardo" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly:

http://militarybudget.org/mongolia/

Don't look at the graph, look at the numbers in the table

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Terrorism_Index

&amp;gt;Choosing Mongolia seems like cherry picking an outlier 

Maybe I am. The data was separated, so I haven't done my math to suggest a correlation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29058862813.0" user="plague006" delta="False">
    <text>I appreciate that.

I threw together a quick table that I think better represents western nations.

Nation | Terrorism Index | Military %GDP
---|---|----
Austalia | 3.114 | 1.8%
Canada | 2.297 | 1.3%
France | 4.553 | 2.4%
Germany | 3.442 | 1.5%
Poland | 0 | 1.8%
United Kingdom | 5.613 | 2.5%
United States | 4.613 | 4.4%

And also some statistical outliers for fun:

Nation | Terrorism Index | Military %GDP
---|---|----
Iraq | 9.96 | 2.7%
Kuwait | 0.019 | 3.3%
Saudi Arabia | 4.006 | 8.9%</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29060730280.0" user="BeatriceBernardo" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you. Looks fun. I'm going to do a full analysis</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
