<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="343657035.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5olrgr/cmv_us_expenditures_on_defense_is_why_there_is_so/">
    <title>CMV: U.S. Expenditures on defense is why there is so few terrorist attacks</title>
    <original_poster>KS1867</original_poster>
    <original_post>On Reddit the U.S. gets a lot of flak for spending so much on its defense budget. People often use the argument "[some uncommon event] kills more people a year than terrorists." I argue that this is because of our massive intelligence and military capabilities. Another hot button issue on Reddit seems to be the use of drones and many will argue that our drone program makes more enemies than it kills. Although I do recognize the flaws with our drone program I believe stopping is not a solution and the drone program weakens the capabilities of terrorists networks to effectively plan attacks. I subscribe to the "peace means carrying a big stick" philosophy. Change my view on American defense spending and drones.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29060836166.0" user="gnualmafuerte" delta="False">
    <text>Any individual can pick a fight with another one. A thin, short, weak, untrained girl can pick a fight with a muscular, tall, powerful trained man. She might not have many chances, but she can start the fight and throw a few punches. Two equally powerful individuals can also pick a fight and go at it for a long time. Guns change this. If one of this individuals carries a gun, and they start the fight, say, 50 meters away; there is no possible fight. The gun ends the fight before it starts regardless of how powerful the fighter holding it is. [Basically this](https://i.makeagif.com/media/5-16-2014/ReFspj.gif). 

Before WWII, any army could pick a fight with any other army. You might have superiority, but you still have to deploy your military and have a fight. The Nazis and the US where both trying to change this. The US worked on the payload: The Atomic bomb. The Nazis worked on the delivery: Their V-weapons. 

After WWII ended, Nazi technology met US technology, and the equivalent of taking a gun to a a knife fight was born in the form of ICBMs. Meanwhile, the US and Russia (that had not really seen WWII action in their territory) spent several times the PBI of most other countries in military development, while Europe focused on rebuilding. The US and Russia, both equipped with this this "guns" couldn't really get into a good'ol fistfight without killing each other, and so the Cold War and proxy wars were born. Meanwhile, other major countries knew they couldn't take on neither the US nor Russia (nor wanted to even try), so they focused on other things, and the military power disparity grew larger. After the fall of the Soviet Union, the US was left towering over everybody else in terms of military power. 

Right now, countries with the actual technical possibility to enter into an actual conflict with the US (with the actual US, not its "we'll send some marines and choppers to your sand shithole" division, the actual full power of the US) don't really want to. They know they can't win, and even if they did, the price either of them would pay would be absolutely massive. Meanwhile, nobody really wants to defeat the US. Why do that? Somebody needs to and will be in the US's position, and if you defeat them it'll be because you want to be there. What countries have the capabilities to be there? It's not enough to be rich and powerful. So, what countries have the large population and territory, alongside being rich and powerful enough to try and take the US's place? China? Impossible, as their riches come mostly from selling shit to the US. Every single country that could even tickle the US is more than happy with US-driven consumerism and doesn't really want to challenge them. 

Add all of that up, and you get a world where the people that want to start a war with the US aren't capable of starting a war with the US. So you get terrorism, guerrilla tactics, etc. Basically, a poor man's war. 

So, I don't think the US expenditure in defense actually prevents terror attacks, it actually creates them, but that is the price to pay for avoiding larger conflicts with even larger loss of life. We haven't had any major conflicts since WWII ended (certainly none involving two powerful nations), and the price we pay for that is terrorism. Seems like a bargain to me. 

Now, this doesn't mean that I entirely approve of the US's huge military expenditure or the political reasons behind it, but the balance of power it creates has (albeint unintentionally) given the world the longest period of lasting peace we've ever seen, so I'll take it. A few people dying here and there because some religious asshole decides to blow himself up inside a cafe certainly beats the damage created by major wars fought between professional armies. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
