<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="352222222.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5tpcem/cmv_privacy_is_actually_a_bad_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Privacy is actually a bad thing</title>
    <original_poster>Wagawaga2401</original_poster>
    <original_post>Around the XIX century, the concept of privacy was very different than the current one. Your personal data and identity would travel with great difficulty to a different state, and someone in a different country would find nearly impossible to know personal details about you, much less interact with you in a threatening enough way. That does not mean information was safe either; gossiping and the such were as rampant then as they are now; but thanks to how slow information travels, they were much less dangerous. You could start a new life by traveling in horse with enough money to a different part of the country, where nobody knows you.

Right now, thanks to the modernization of identity documents and such, that's nearly impossible; but I don't think that's a problem.

In the modern age, there are many problems where a person of public interest and/or hate has their privacy breached; death threats, harassment, violence and all sorts of things can happen. The usual approach is to try to disappear; to go back to a state of privacy; change names, appearance, address, and online identities. But all of this could be avoided if the assailants didn't have privacy either. 

It would probably be impossible to implement, but I think that if law enforcement agencies had the ability to minutely track people's activity, both online and in real life, many, many instances of harassment, crime, rape and similar things could be prosecuted, if not prevented. It would certainly be much more difficult to effectively plan a terrorist attack or mass shooting.

And to most of the citizens who (I assume) will see this, whose worst crime will probably be online piracy or drug possession/use, this won't be as much of a problem as it will be an increase in safety, not only from terror attacks but from common everyday thefts.

This argument seems so obvious and intuitive to me that I find it hard to believe that it's not the mainstream opinion. What is it about privacy that people fight so hard to defend? Is there a basic principle of social relationships that is passing right above my head, or is everybody else in the world a dirty criminal with horrible things to hide? Occam's razor points to the first one, and that's why I'm here. Please change my view.




EDIT: what I've learned so far:
&amp;gt;the government isn't flawless and unbiased, and privacy allows you to retaliate with much more strength than information about it. also people suck.

I'm going to sleep, so see you in a couple of hours, pals. ^I ^stayed ^here ^for ^the ^first ^4 ^hours ^so ^I ^think ^I'm ^good ^to ^go

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29124901195.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/Wagawaga2401 (OP) has awarded at least one delta in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [**here**](/r/DeltaLog/comments/5tqcff), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view [doesn't necessarily mean a reversal](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/index#wiki_what_is_a_.27view.27.3F), or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
