<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="361709424.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5zcos0/cmv_i_dont_think_guns_can_be_effectively_used_for/">
    <title>CMV: I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence</title>
    <original_poster>CDWEBI</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence.

First of something about me, maybe it'll be useful somehow. I live in Germany and I'm not that opposed to gun possession. And as the USA is the only major western country I know of which has these major gun issues I'm interested in the reasons why the USA doesn't impose stricter gun laws.

One of the major reasons I heard of, as to why a great amount of US-Americans want to have loose gun laws, is for self-defence and also for the fact that otherwise the "bad guys" would just have all the guns, as they can just get it from the black market. It may be true, but I don't really see how the possession of guns can help you with self-defence. The only way I see a gun can help someone is if this someone carries it all the time and even then it may most likely be contraproductive.

I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you? Most criminals use a weapon, be it a knife or a gun, for intimidation, so that they are more convincing convincing you to give them what they want (usually money or other valuables). Unless the criminal is a complete idiot, he will try to surprise the victim. 

So, he surprised you and now holds a knife or a gun at you and demands your money or other valubles. How can a gun help you? If you take out the gun, the criminal may panic, as he sees a risk to his life, and may kill or harm you severely in the process, even if he didn't want it. You may be lucky and the criminal freezes, because of the panic,  however most criminals are more or less mentally prepared for these situations, at least better than the victims which are mostly caught off-guard. And is it really worth it risking that he'll freeze? And in the end it could be you who'll freeze, as again criminals are usually more mentally prepared for this then the victims. In the end you either exchanged or almost exchanged your life for some valubles.

If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

Or did I got it wrong as to how a gun can be used for self-defence? If yes how else can a gun be used for self-defence?

In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time. I'm not saying that there aren't situations where having a gun is good for self-defence, but most of the time it won't help or might even be contraproductive.

If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

Thx in advance.

PS: In this post with "criminal" I mean somewhat between the line of "someone who attacks or intimidates people with a weapon (usually knife or gun)".

EDIT: It may be somewhat relevant, though I might have added it earlier. I'm doing self-defence (Krav Maga) for several years already. I'm by no means a professional, but I have enough self-defence knowledge to have some say. And most facts I said are the stuff we were taught. 
Here's me giving some insight: Most people don't know how easy and how hard self-defence can be. E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally. Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely. Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be. At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

EDIT2: It maybe somewhat too late, but I noticed I accidentally  misformulated my view quite heavilyt. I don't think "I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence", but rather "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence". I know it's somewhat late to "change" my view, but if somebody still answers this post that's what I meant. I maybe repost it with a better formulated view some time later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29204136492.0" user="Electric_Dirt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time.

Texas's (and many other states') self defense laws do not sanction the use of a firearm in a "psuedo-dangerous situation," so a person who is carrying a defensive firearm would not be justified in drawing their weapon in such a situation.  The only time you are justified in drawing your weapon in self defense is if you are facing the threat of imminent death or severe bodily injury (e.g. someone is threatening you with a knife).  

Where the threat of death or severe bodily injury is real, drawing a defensive handgun will not "escalate" what is already a potentially deadly situation.  Meeting the threat of deadly force with deadly force is the option of last resort under most states' laws in the U.S.

I have carried a concealed defensive handgun nearly every day of my life for the past 15 years.  In that time, I have never once needed to draw my weapon in self defense, and I fully expect to live out the rest of my days without breaking that trend.  So why bother carrying at all if the chances I'll need it are very small?  Because "very small" is not zero.  I carry because I do not know if, when, or where I will be confronted with the threat of deadly force.  If I knew those things, there would be no need to carry at all because I'd simply avoid that place at that time.  But my crystal ball is broken, unfortunately, so my only recourse is to ensure that I'm equipped with the tools, training, and mindset to have the best chance of stopping a threat if and when one presents itself.

I leave you with the words of the late Col. Jeff Cooper, founder of Gunsite Academy and the father of the modern handgun technique:

"The press, academe, and the law enforcement establishment preach: Do not fight back! On the street, in your home, on the airplane, on the high seas, anywhere, anytime. Do not fight back! You may be hurt.  Of course you may be hurt. You may be killed. As my daughter put it just last week: 'Big deal. You expect to live forever?'  The only honorable response to violence is counter-violence. To surrender to extortion is a greater sin than extortion, in that it breeds and feeds the very act it seeks to avoid."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29209453497.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>First off, as /u/Fizzy_T pointed out, I unfortunately misformulated my view quiet heavily. I meant "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence" not that "I don't think guns can be used effectiveley against self-defence".

&amp;gt;Texas's (and many other states') self defense laws do not sanction the use of a firearm in a "psuedo-dangerous situation," so a person who is carrying a defensive firearm would not be justified in drawing their weapon in such a situation. The only time you are justified in drawing your weapon in self defense is if you are facing the threat of imminent death or severe bodily injury (e.g. someone is threatening you with a knife). 

&amp;gt;Where the threat of death or severe bodily injury is real, drawing a defensive handgun will not "escalate" what is already a potentially deadly situation. Meeting the threat of deadly force with deadly force is the option of last resort under most states' laws in the U.S.

That's good on paper, but in reality self-defence is much more chaotic. In the moment of perceived danger, you won't think "but is it legally justified by the state?". Whether the law considers it "dangerous" or not, it is "dangerous" for you at the moment. And IMO it's better to not think about it, because if it is in fact dangerous, the thinking about the law might steal your time. 

Now the problem is what is "dangerous" and what is not. E.g. if a criminal came to you with a knife or gun demanding money, IMO objectively speaking it's "pseudo-dangerous"/ not dangerous. Of course, he might kill you nontheless, even if you cooperate, but then it wouldn't make sense asking for money in the first place. However you may panic and start thinking irrationally and think it's really dangerous. You see a gun/knife pointed at you and you think he can kill me every moment. So you pull out the gun to defend yourself, after all you carry your gun all the time to defend yourself. Personally I wouldn't judge one who'd do that, as in that situation one doesn't think clearly and wants only to survive. 

However now you have three probable outcomes, you might kill him out of panic, you convince him to let you alone or he shoots/kills you. IMO opinion if he has a gun he'll hit you first no matter what, as it's already out, except you are some sort of Lucky Look. If he has a knife instead, you might hit him first if he approached you from a far, but such criminals attack victim usually from up close. And even if you might have hit him first, the chance that they hit you afterwards is nontheless high.

&amp;gt;I have carried a concealed defensive handgun nearly every day of my life for the past 15 years. In that time, I have never once needed to draw my weapon in self defense, and I fully expect to live out the rest of my days without breaking that trend. So why bother carrying at all if the chances I'll need it are very small? Because "very small" is not zero. I carry because I do not know if, when, or where I will be confronted with the threat of deadly force. If I knew those things, there would be no need to carry at all because I'd simply avoid that place at that time. But my crystal ball is broken, unfortunately, so my only recourse is to ensure that I'm equipped with the tools, training, and mindset to have the best chance of stopping a threat if and when one presents itself.

You're right, you have a point. Since it's legal, it's you're right to have it. I'm not against gun ownership per se and using a gun to defend oneself. I'm more about the fact that in a stressful situation like above, one can easily miscalculate the real danger. In the end we don't react to real danger, but to perceived danger. And, as I already said,  it's comepletely alright to react to the "perceived" danger, as one shouldn't lose time thinking about it if it's real danger or not. However, having a gun changes the dynamics a bit. In a scenario like above most people wouldn't counterattack, if they don't have a weapon, as any action of the criminal is more deadlier than the own. If person has a weapon, like a gun, this person may get more courageous to do something against it, even if the danger is the same. Of course it might work, but at the same time could kill you or severely harm you. And if it was a "pseudo-dangerous" situation, you were severely harmed or lost your life for nothing. 

I guess what I'm basically trying to say is that IMO most people with weapons will react to a situation which wasn't life threatening to begin with in a way which will lead to the situation being life threatening, thus defeating the purpose of using a gun for self-defence. Of course one might come out of it alive, but

&amp;gt; I leave you with the words of the late Col. Jeff Cooper, founder of Gunsite Academy and the father of the modern handgun technique:

&amp;gt;"The press, academe, and the law enforcement establishment preach: Do not fight back! On the street, in your home, on the airplane, on the high seas, anywhere, anytime. Do not fight back! You may be hurt. Of course you may be hurt. You may be killed. As my daughter put it just last week: 'Big deal. You expect to live forever?' The only honorable response to violence is counter-violence. To surrender to extortion is a greater sin than extortion, in that it breeds and feeds the very act it seeks to avoid."

Is honor really that much more important than life? Idk I'd rather live unhonorable, than be dead honorable. Idk this statement sounds a big too heroic to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215921670.0" user="Electric_Dirt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In the moment of perceived danger, you won't think "but is it legally justified by the state?". Whether the law considers it "dangerous" or not, it is "dangerous" for you at the moment.

At least in Texas, the classroom instruction for a concealed handgun license teaches you how to evaluate situations you may find yourself in.  Skills such as non-violent dispute resolution are taught, and the emphasis is on de-escalation and trying to avoid a violent encounter if possible.  You are taught that drawing your weapon is an act of last resort, and only justifiable if you are in genuine fear for your life.  Harsh words are not enough... the other person has to be doing something that puts you in imminent threat of death or serious bodily injury.  So yes, if a person is going to undertake the responsibility of going armed for self defense, they're going to have to evaluate the appropriate response to a given situation.  With that said, if you have time for an internal debate on "should I draw my gun?" then you are probably not facing an imminent threat of death or serious bodily harm.  Which brings me to my next point...

&amp;gt; Now the problem is what is "dangerous" and what is not. E.g. if a criminal came to you with a knife or gun demanding money, IMO objectively speaking it's "pseudo-dangerous"/ not dangerous. Of course, he might kill you nontheless, even if you cooperate, but then it wouldn't make sense asking for money in the first place. However you may panic and start thinking irrationally and think it's really dangerous. You see a gun/knife pointed at you and you think he can kill me every moment. So you pull out the gun to defend yourself, after all you carry your gun all the time to defend yourself. Personally I wouldn't judge one who'd do that, as in that situation one doesn't think clearly and wants only to survive. 

And therein lies part of the problem with your viewpoint, in my opinion.  If someone is confronting you with a deadly weapon, it is a dangerous situation and you would be legally justified in defending yourself with deadly force in every state in the nation.  The whole point of self defense is that you don't HAVE to surrender your safety to the whim of the criminal.  Sure, they might not have any intention of killing you. They may only want to scare you into giving over your wallet.  But they may also be out for blood...  The point is you don't have to make that call before defending yourself.  You see a deadly weapon, it's justification for drawing and firing without waiting to ascertain the criminal's intentions.

&amp;gt;IMO most people with weapons will react to a situation which wasn't life threatening to begin with in a way which will lead to the situation being life threatening

And those people will likely be indicted by a grand jury of their peers for homicide, because they were not justified in using deadly force to defend themselves.  Carrying a gun comes with certain responsibilities, one of which is knowing when you are and are not justified in using said gun for self defense.  If you draw and shoot in a situation that is not life threatening, then you are not justified.  Going armed for self defense is not something to be taken lightly, and anyone who does so is, IMHO, foolish.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
