<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="361709424.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5zcos0/cmv_i_dont_think_guns_can_be_effectively_used_for/">
    <title>CMV: I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence</title>
    <original_poster>CDWEBI</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence.

First of something about me, maybe it'll be useful somehow. I live in Germany and I'm not that opposed to gun possession. And as the USA is the only major western country I know of which has these major gun issues I'm interested in the reasons why the USA doesn't impose stricter gun laws.

One of the major reasons I heard of, as to why a great amount of US-Americans want to have loose gun laws, is for self-defence and also for the fact that otherwise the "bad guys" would just have all the guns, as they can just get it from the black market. It may be true, but I don't really see how the possession of guns can help you with self-defence. The only way I see a gun can help someone is if this someone carries it all the time and even then it may most likely be contraproductive.

I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you? Most criminals use a weapon, be it a knife or a gun, for intimidation, so that they are more convincing convincing you to give them what they want (usually money or other valuables). Unless the criminal is a complete idiot, he will try to surprise the victim. 

So, he surprised you and now holds a knife or a gun at you and demands your money or other valubles. How can a gun help you? If you take out the gun, the criminal may panic, as he sees a risk to his life, and may kill or harm you severely in the process, even if he didn't want it. You may be lucky and the criminal freezes, because of the panic,  however most criminals are more or less mentally prepared for these situations, at least better than the victims which are mostly caught off-guard. And is it really worth it risking that he'll freeze? And in the end it could be you who'll freeze, as again criminals are usually more mentally prepared for this then the victims. In the end you either exchanged or almost exchanged your life for some valubles.

If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

Or did I got it wrong as to how a gun can be used for self-defence? If yes how else can a gun be used for self-defence?

In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time. I'm not saying that there aren't situations where having a gun is good for self-defence, but most of the time it won't help or might even be contraproductive.

If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

Thx in advance.

PS: In this post with "criminal" I mean somewhat between the line of "someone who attacks or intimidates people with a weapon (usually knife or gun)".

EDIT: It may be somewhat relevant, though I might have added it earlier. I'm doing self-defence (Krav Maga) for several years already. I'm by no means a professional, but I have enough self-defence knowledge to have some say. And most facts I said are the stuff we were taught. 
Here's me giving some insight: Most people don't know how easy and how hard self-defence can be. E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally. Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely. Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be. At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

EDIT2: It maybe somewhat too late, but I noticed I accidentally  misformulated my view quite heavilyt. I don't think "I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence", but rather "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence". I know it's somewhat late to "change" my view, but if somebody still answers this post that's what I meant. I maybe repost it with a better formulated view some time later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29200661295.0" user="Fizzy_T" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you?

[I feel like it's impossible to explain to you how a gun could help, so here's a youtube channel that posts videos of self protection.](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsE_m2z1NrvF2ImeNWh84mw/videos) Here's a few in particular that show how a gun helps, but very graphic but you see people get shot on from distance so NSFW?

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ji4GxrYruJ8

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hTq8fGKL_jI

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JOzWdGc0ne0

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kodNfvkqY8s
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29202804869.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not denying guns do provide self-protection, I'm saying that IMO generally it makes more harm than good to self-protect with a gun. I mean of course there are many situation were guns saved the lives of innocents, and it's good that they were saved, but in general it's more probable that it can end negatively. Just having a gun doesn't equate to being able to use it properly. Of course, I don't know the statistics, but I doubt that a high percentage has regular training or just training.

The videos show however how guns can be used for self-defence. I looked at the channel. It's interesting and there are in general good examples, but one can often see gun self-defence were it was more safe to just let them go. Most of such videos, at least the ones I saw, had (off-duty) policemen in them, so it may be justified as they are trained not only in fire gun usage but also in physical combat. But IMO showing these videos as examples may lead people to misjudge their capabilities and the situation. It's somehow compareable to showing unarmed self-defence or street fight videos where a trained and/or strong fighter decides to fight back and than someone explains what he has done right like in these videos. IMO it encourages people to not back down, but rather get into fights, as they believe they now know how to fight, without having any combat training.

For example the third video is IMO a bad example. The only good thing is that they are said to be off-duty policemen, and thus may have received formal training. However, the whole situation is very risky, as it's a rather highly populated area. That makes it dangerous since failing at aiming can lead to more harm than the robbing itself. I can't say how populated the whole area was, but since it was evening it could have been that the policeman could have shot somebody accidentaly. It also could have happened that he shot somebody from the innocents from the video accidentally. As the man shooting was a policemen, I suppose his aim is good enough, though. However it could have easily happen that the robber could have accidentally fired when he was hit, and thus possible harmed innocents.

This [video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=akmK2SqNJoQ) from the same channel shows how easily self-defence with a gun can get wrong. [TL;DW: While going out after robbing an animal hospital, the guy is attacked by an off-duty cop. The robber attacks the cop, trying to get the weapon while taking the cop to the ground. As the robber got tired and wanted to leave the scene, the cop gives him a leg hoop (?).] One can easily see that just having a gun doesn't determine the outcome. Even though he is an officer and is probably trained in gun usage and physical combat, he could have easily lost this fight. Though I don't really think the robber would have shot the cop, if he got the gun, it would have been a very bad situation nontheless. However if you are not trained or only trained in gun use, such gun use may be risky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29203179523.0" user="Fizzy_T" delta="False">
    <text>Would you say that guns cannot be effectively used for self defense or most humans are cannot effectively use a gun for self defense? It seems to me that the OP says the former but this reply says the latter. Regarding the video you linked to, the cop would've been in a better situation by just unloading on the robber. As the commentator said, the cop shouldn't have placed the gun in reach of the robber.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29205164476.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Would you say that guns cannot be effectively used for self defense or most humans are cannot effectively use a gun for self defense? It seems to me that the OP says the former but this reply says the latter. 

Oh wow, thanks, you're right, I totally didn't mention that in my OP. I make it seem as if I mean guns can't be used effectively than rather that most humans cannot effectively use a gun for self-defence.

&amp;gt; Regarding the video you linked to, the cop would've been in a better situation by just unloading on the robber. 

I don't know the laws of France (IIRC that that was the country), but I'm not sure whether firing would have been lawful in this situation.

&amp;gt;As the commentator said, the cop shouldn't have placed the gun in reach of the robber.

That's mostly my point. Policemen should be the ones that should know better and nontheless that happened. Of course, there may be a bunch of reasons why he did that. Maybe he is just the exception of the policemen and another would have handled it better. But that shows even people, whose job is to be able to use a gun, can make major mistakes. Now imagine how easily a person, who doesn't train gun usage and physical combat regularly, can make mistakes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29205478416.0" user="FuckTripleH" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but in general it's more probable that it can end negatively. 

You keep saying this, but what data do you have to back it up? You can't just say something is "in general more probable" without data suggesting it is in fact more probable</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
