<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="361709424.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5zcos0/cmv_i_dont_think_guns_can_be_effectively_used_for/">
    <title>CMV: I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence</title>
    <original_poster>CDWEBI</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence.

First of something about me, maybe it'll be useful somehow. I live in Germany and I'm not that opposed to gun possession. And as the USA is the only major western country I know of which has these major gun issues I'm interested in the reasons why the USA doesn't impose stricter gun laws.

One of the major reasons I heard of, as to why a great amount of US-Americans want to have loose gun laws, is for self-defence and also for the fact that otherwise the "bad guys" would just have all the guns, as they can just get it from the black market. It may be true, but I don't really see how the possession of guns can help you with self-defence. The only way I see a gun can help someone is if this someone carries it all the time and even then it may most likely be contraproductive.

I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you? Most criminals use a weapon, be it a knife or a gun, for intimidation, so that they are more convincing convincing you to give them what they want (usually money or other valuables). Unless the criminal is a complete idiot, he will try to surprise the victim. 

So, he surprised you and now holds a knife or a gun at you and demands your money or other valubles. How can a gun help you? If you take out the gun, the criminal may panic, as he sees a risk to his life, and may kill or harm you severely in the process, even if he didn't want it. You may be lucky and the criminal freezes, because of the panic,  however most criminals are more or less mentally prepared for these situations, at least better than the victims which are mostly caught off-guard. And is it really worth it risking that he'll freeze? And in the end it could be you who'll freeze, as again criminals are usually more mentally prepared for this then the victims. In the end you either exchanged or almost exchanged your life for some valubles.

If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

Or did I got it wrong as to how a gun can be used for self-defence? If yes how else can a gun be used for self-defence?

In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time. I'm not saying that there aren't situations where having a gun is good for self-defence, but most of the time it won't help or might even be contraproductive.

If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

Thx in advance.

PS: In this post with "criminal" I mean somewhat between the line of "someone who attacks or intimidates people with a weapon (usually knife or gun)".

EDIT: It may be somewhat relevant, though I might have added it earlier. I'm doing self-defence (Krav Maga) for several years already. I'm by no means a professional, but I have enough self-defence knowledge to have some say. And most facts I said are the stuff we were taught. 
Here's me giving some insight: Most people don't know how easy and how hard self-defence can be. E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally. Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely. Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be. At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

EDIT2: It maybe somewhat too late, but I noticed I accidentally  misformulated my view quite heavilyt. I don't think "I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence", but rather "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence". I know it's somewhat late to "change" my view, but if somebody still answers this post that's what I meant. I maybe repost it with a better formulated view some time later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29200887527.0" user="ManRAh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds.

Criminals don't just leap out of empty dumpsters and attack people from surprise. They often follow people and isolate them. Yes, people can be surprised, but I think you're setting an unrealistic precedent to argue from. Your argument is built on the tenuous notion that "the bad guy always wins".

If I'm carrying a weapon, and someone suspicious is following me, I have an option beyond "run and pray". If someone approaches me, and my attempts to avoid them fail, I still have a firearm.

&amp;gt;E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally.

A gun is a massive psychological deterrent. Unless the criminal is mentally unstable, there is a good chance the threat of severe injury or death may turn them around.

&amp;gt;Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely.

Your argument seems hinged on the notion that "anyone who wants to hurt you will, and there's nothing you can do about it." This just seems incredibly flawed to me. Not all attackers are high on PCP and will literally eat your face off while you pump 12 rounds into their chest.

&amp;gt;Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be.

And I doubt most criminals are "knowledgeable" with knives. Muggers and your average burglar aren't skilled assassins. A firearm immediately turns a victim into a threat in almost any circumstance.

&amp;gt;At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

Which is why you train with any firearm you purchase, and you don't wait until the last second to ready it. Again, criminals aren't hiding around corners in camouflage. If you're alone at night, and you've got a gun in your purse, you keep your purse open and make sure your gun is accessible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29209777912.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Criminals don't just leap out of empty dumpsters and attack people from surprise. They often follow people and isolate them. Yes, people can be surprised, but I think you're setting an unrealistic precedent to argue from. Your argument is built on the tenuous notion that "the bad guy always wins".

I wasn't saying that there are many criminals who just kill for the sake of it. I'm just saying if there are criminals who are like that, they usually won't go to you and demand your money, so it doesn't really makes sense to self-defend against a muggler who only wants money.

Hm, I don't think "the bad guy always wins" is the notion of my argument, it's rather "the guy pointing a weapon at you wins if you want to stay alive". If you are reffering to the "criminals can kill you if they really want", it's just how it is. If I really want to kill somebody, I just shoot him or go behind him and slice his throat open. But this again was refering to the fact that that if a muggler with a knife or a gun didn't do the already mentioned, there is a high chance in him not doing it after you gave it to him. If you refer to "just give the muggler what he wants if he has a weapon", I mean you can also risk your life, though I'm not sure whether it'll benefit you very much.

&amp;gt;If I'm carrying a weapon, and someone suspicious is following me, I have an option beyond "run and pray". If someone approaches me, and my attempts to avoid them fail, I still have a firearm.

In those cases it does make sense. Though I was taught, that criminals choose their target semi-random. Other than choosing a rather weak looking person (physically and mentally), they usually don't care who it is. Thus there is really not so much following. However you're right about the bigger options a gun provides.

&amp;gt; A gun is a massive psychological deterrent. Unless the criminal is mentally unstable, there is a good chance the threat of severe injury or death may turn them around.

It depends. If you carry it openly (whcih I didn't know was allowed in the US at the time of posting OP) it is very deterrent, though there will still be people who won't care about it. However if you pull it out during the action something like [this](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=akmK2SqNJoQ) can easily happen. Of course, he may be mentally unstable, however in a high stress situation we act rather quickly than logically. There was a gun that didn't turn the criminal around.

&amp;gt; Your argument seems hinged on the notion that "anyone who wants to hurt you will, and there's nothing you can do about it." This just seems incredibly flawed to me. Not all attackers are high on PCP and will literally eat your face off while you pump 12 rounds into their chest.

No, I think you misinterpreted it. It means that "in any self-defence against most weapons, one will get usually harmed. E.g. if you fight against someone with a knife, there is usually now way going out of the situation without some kind of damage. Thus the sentence you quoted "Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely" doesn't mean don't do anything, because you'll be harmed no matter what. The sentence was based opon the fact that the self-defence in the first place is unneccesary as he wanted just the money. Thus it meant that you put yourself in danger just because of money.

And no, but they will have enough time to either shot some times at you or do some stabs at you.

&amp;gt; And I doubt most criminals are "knowledgeable" with knives. Muggers and your average burglar aren't skilled assassins. A firearm immediately turns a victim into a threat in almost any circumstance.

Knowledgeable doesn't mean master, it just means knowing which places to hit. And one of the best places is usually directly in front you him, it's the neck.

&amp;gt; Which is why you train with any firearm you purchase, and you don't wait until the last second to ready it. Again, criminals aren't hiding around corners in camouflage. If you're alone at night, and you've got a gun in your purse, you keep your purse open and make sure your gun is accessible.

How many do of the gun owners train and how regular? Is it required?

Though I already commented on the criminals are easily visible because they follow you suspiciously, here again. You suppose one can just see them because they'll be following you suspiciously. Of course that might be the case, but you say they all do it. Muggers generally don't care about who they rob, thus if you go by them and you look somehow weak enough they'll attack you. Here in Germany, I also heard several time about muggers who work in teams. Either one distracts, the other attacks or one sees someone suitable, they inform the other to attack directly.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
