<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="361709424.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5zcos0/cmv_i_dont_think_guns_can_be_effectively_used_for/">
    <title>CMV: I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence</title>
    <original_poster>CDWEBI</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence.

First of something about me, maybe it'll be useful somehow. I live in Germany and I'm not that opposed to gun possession. And as the USA is the only major western country I know of which has these major gun issues I'm interested in the reasons why the USA doesn't impose stricter gun laws.

One of the major reasons I heard of, as to why a great amount of US-Americans want to have loose gun laws, is for self-defence and also for the fact that otherwise the "bad guys" would just have all the guns, as they can just get it from the black market. It may be true, but I don't really see how the possession of guns can help you with self-defence. The only way I see a gun can help someone is if this someone carries it all the time and even then it may most likely be contraproductive.

I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you? Most criminals use a weapon, be it a knife or a gun, for intimidation, so that they are more convincing convincing you to give them what they want (usually money or other valuables). Unless the criminal is a complete idiot, he will try to surprise the victim. 

So, he surprised you and now holds a knife or a gun at you and demands your money or other valubles. How can a gun help you? If you take out the gun, the criminal may panic, as he sees a risk to his life, and may kill or harm you severely in the process, even if he didn't want it. You may be lucky and the criminal freezes, because of the panic,  however most criminals are more or less mentally prepared for these situations, at least better than the victims which are mostly caught off-guard. And is it really worth it risking that he'll freeze? And in the end it could be you who'll freeze, as again criminals are usually more mentally prepared for this then the victims. In the end you either exchanged or almost exchanged your life for some valubles.

If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

Or did I got it wrong as to how a gun can be used for self-defence? If yes how else can a gun be used for self-defence?

In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time. I'm not saying that there aren't situations where having a gun is good for self-defence, but most of the time it won't help or might even be contraproductive.

If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

Thx in advance.

PS: In this post with "criminal" I mean somewhat between the line of "someone who attacks or intimidates people with a weapon (usually knife or gun)".

EDIT: It may be somewhat relevant, though I might have added it earlier. I'm doing self-defence (Krav Maga) for several years already. I'm by no means a professional, but I have enough self-defence knowledge to have some say. And most facts I said are the stuff we were taught. 
Here's me giving some insight: Most people don't know how easy and how hard self-defence can be. E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally. Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely. Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be. At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

EDIT2: It maybe somewhat too late, but I noticed I accidentally  misformulated my view quite heavilyt. I don't think "I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence", but rather "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence". I know it's somewhat late to "change" my view, but if somebody still answers this post that's what I meant. I maybe repost it with a better formulated view some time later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29200221180.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If you try to kill me and I shoot you in the gut until you can no longer threaten my person I have defended myself.

Most criminals being biologically inferior subhumans in the majority of cases are incapable of higher level thought.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200312313.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure whether it should be somehow ironic, but that's the main reason why defending oneself in this way is very dangerous.

As I already wrote there is a high chance to be attacked by such actions. It's better to coorparate with them, if that keeps you unharmed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200363663.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As I already wrote there is a high chance to be attacked by such actions. It's better to coorparate with them, if that keeps you unharmed.

According the CDC study I cited in my own response to your OP, this is false. Self-defense actions with guns have a lower incidence of injury to the victim than other strategies, including complying with demands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200524304.0" user="Big_Pete_" delta="False">
    <text>[Not quite as open-and-shut as all that.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2015/01/16/the-study-that-gun-rights-activists-keep-citing-but-completely-misunderstand/?utm_term=.4564a28fe6a1)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200543781.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing in that debunks my claim.

The study wasn't isolated to the point I brought up, but it does include it.

At best, the article you linked argues that facets separate from defensive use *may* outweigh the benefits from defensive use. It doesn't contest the benefits of defensive use.    </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200614303.0" user="Big_Pete_" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that the CDC study's only purpose was to identify priorities for further study.  The numbers for defensive use are particularly squishy, which implies a need for further study and standardized methodology.

Not debunking your claim, just stating that your evidence isn't as ironclad as it was presented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200666200.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>It's more substantial than OP and your claim that not resisting is statistically safer.

Based on the available statistics, using a gun is safest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200735578.0" user="Big_Pete_" delta="False">
    <text>[CDC isn't the only study out there.](https://www.thetrace.org/2015/07/defensive-gun-use-armed-with-reason-hemenway/)

But I'll grant that it warrants further study, and that no current stats close the debate.  I'm particularly interested in a standard definition of DGUs, which may help those numbers settle:

*Surveys conducted by Hemenway in 1996 and 1999, in which respondents were asked to describe DGUs in their own words, found that the majority of defensive gun uses were both illegal and provided no social benefit. Across these two large national samples of randomly selected telephone numbers, the conclusion was overwhelming: “Guns are used to threaten and intimidate far more often than they are used in self-defense. Most self-reported self-defense gun uses may well be illegal and against the interests of society.”*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200466599.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Why if you kill him you drop the amount the state pays on welfare dramatically with each cartridge fired. Theft is dangerous business when the cost is summary execution

Sure if they get the drop on you no amount of ammo is gonna help, but if they come rather equal to you or you get a gleaming chance you can blow the fucker away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200567721.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>I also wanted to add that unless you hit certain point in the body, the criminal won't die directly. Meaning that if he was about to threaten you with a knife, there is a high possibily that he will attack you with it, as pain during an adrenaline-rush is reduced. Basically, taking you with him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200595289.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>It's possible that the gunshot won't result in an immediate stop, yes.

The chances of causing the perpetrator to either be disabled (inclusive of dead) or run away is greater with a gun than without.

Noone is claiming that a gun is a cureall, and a gun simply isn't effective as self-defense in *absolutely all* situations.

It is demonstrably true that guns can be and are used effectively for self-defense and the defense of others in some situations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201624462.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Keep shooting, I'll chance getting stabbed and if you stab me after a bunch of shots from about six inches away well I tried my best.

Getting shot hurts, it hurts a lot you stabbing through having your guts torn up is very hard</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29212149594.0" user="Jaxonsrazor" delta="False">
    <text>This is a very good point. There is no guarantee that anyone anytime will survive a violent encounter, but if I am going to die anyways I would rather die standing up in the middle of the street defending myself like a man, than cowered on my hands and knees, executed like a dog. At least that F****r would know he had been in a fight when he left.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
