<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="361709424.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5zcos0/cmv_i_dont_think_guns_can_be_effectively_used_for/">
    <title>CMV: I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence</title>
    <original_poster>CDWEBI</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence.

First of something about me, maybe it'll be useful somehow. I live in Germany and I'm not that opposed to gun possession. And as the USA is the only major western country I know of which has these major gun issues I'm interested in the reasons why the USA doesn't impose stricter gun laws.

One of the major reasons I heard of, as to why a great amount of US-Americans want to have loose gun laws, is for self-defence and also for the fact that otherwise the "bad guys" would just have all the guns, as they can just get it from the black market. It may be true, but I don't really see how the possession of guns can help you with self-defence. The only way I see a gun can help someone is if this someone carries it all the time and even then it may most likely be contraproductive.

I mean let's say a criminal approaches you, how could a gun help you? Most criminals use a weapon, be it a knife or a gun, for intimidation, so that they are more convincing convincing you to give them what they want (usually money or other valuables). Unless the criminal is a complete idiot, he will try to surprise the victim. 

So, he surprised you and now holds a knife or a gun at you and demands your money or other valubles. How can a gun help you? If you take out the gun, the criminal may panic, as he sees a risk to his life, and may kill or harm you severely in the process, even if he didn't want it. You may be lucky and the criminal freezes, because of the panic,  however most criminals are more or less mentally prepared for these situations, at least better than the victims which are mostly caught off-guard. And is it really worth it risking that he'll freeze? And in the end it could be you who'll freeze, as again criminals are usually more mentally prepared for this then the victims. In the end you either exchanged or almost exchanged your life for some valubles.

If a criminal really wants to kill you, usually you won't even have a chance to defend yourself, as sad as it sounds. I mean if the criminal wanted your death, he would just shoot you in case of a gun or just cut open your throat from behind. He could even just take a big stone and smash it into your head. Of course there are also those who will "bully" (?) you and only than kill you, but if I'm correctly informed, it's relatively seldom.

Or did I got it wrong as to how a gun can be used for self-defence? If yes how else can a gun be used for self-defence?

In short, I think a gun would only escalate a pseudo-dangerous situation to a real dangerous situation most of the time. I'm not saying that there aren't situations where having a gun is good for self-defence, but most of the time it won't help or might even be contraproductive.

If I got the fact wrong, that people want guns for self-defence, than why are people worrying about "the bad guys" having all the guns?

Thx in advance.

PS: In this post with "criminal" I mean somewhat between the line of "someone who attacks or intimidates people with a weapon (usually knife or gun)".

EDIT: It may be somewhat relevant, though I might have added it earlier. I'm doing self-defence (Krav Maga) for several years already. I'm by no means a professional, but I have enough self-defence knowledge to have some say. And most facts I said are the stuff we were taught. 
Here's me giving some insight: Most people don't know how easy and how hard self-defence can be. E.g. even if you hit the criminal, he won't die directly, except you hit certain keyspots and because of adrenaline he won't feel as much pain as normally. Thus if he got a knife or a gun at you, and you shoot him, there is nontheless a high percentage that you will be harmed severely. Also, so many don't realize how lethal a person who has at least some knowledge with knives can be. At the time you are getting your gun out, he might have hit you already several times.

EDIT2: It maybe somewhat too late, but I noticed I accidentally  misformulated my view quite heavilyt. I don't think "I don't think guns can be effectively used for self-defence", but rather "I don't think most humans can effectively use a gun for self-defence". I know it's somewhat late to "change" my view, but if somebody still answers this post that's what I meant. I maybe repost it with a better formulated view some time later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29200174688.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>Gun owner here, i have an open carry permit, so I carry my gun everywhere in my hip holster openly for everyone to see, this in itself makes people think twice before starting anything. if you had to choose between the guy carrying the Smith and Wesson revolver on his hip or the guy who is walking along sipping his latte listening to his ipod, who would you attack? It's a deterrent all by itself.

I also keep a gun next to my bed at night in a thumb lock safe. if anyone were to break in to my house, i would have the gun pointed in front of me as i searched the house, they would never have the chance to draw on me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200276180.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>Ah good point, I didn't know one could carry guns openly in the USA. I somehow assumed that the only way to carry guns would be concealed, as here in Germany there would be a public outcry if somebody would ever be seen with a gun. After googling, to my surprise, many states allow to openly carry weapons even without a permit.

However, can you elaborate how often it is to see people carrying their guns openly, at least in your area? And does it mean there are also licenses where one is only allowed to carry firearms only concealed?

Also is there a specific reason for you to carry a gun openly, like high crime rates in your area, or is it more of a cultural thing?

EDIT: As I said, I didn't know carrying a gun openly is allowed, and after googling many states allow it even without liscences. This doesn't change my view completely, but because I assumed that most gun carriers have their guns concealed, criminals wouldn't have a way to distinguish between the ones with where there is "escalation potential". Here is your Delta ∆</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200331835.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not who you replied to, but in my state (Texas), we passed licensed open carry of handguns (previously only licensed concealed carry of handguns and unlicensed open carry of longguns was legally permissible) in 2015. I have seen someone (other than police and gun store employees) open carry a handgun exactly once.

I know for a fact than many of my friends, family, and coworkers concealed carry.

Concealed carry is arguably at least as effective because A) it doesn't make you stand out and thus potentially make you a target, and B) it makes *every* person potentially armed in the eyes of a criminal, thus increasing the percieved risk involved with violent crime and adding to any deterrent effect C) allows you to surprise a robber who targetted you under the expectation that you were not armed.

Imagine this scenario: someone theatens you and your significant other with a knife and demands your wallet. You reach your hand behind your back, similar to pulling out your wallet from uour back pocket, but also where your cocealed gun is. By the time the robber realizes that you pulled your gun instead of your wallet, it is already pointed at him. You now have control of the situation and can either shoot immediately or hesitate to wait for the robber's reaction as the situation dictates.

As for why carry a gun, it's a mentality similar to owning a fire-extinguisher (of which I have one in my car and one in my bedroom), where you keep it around not because you expect to need it for anythig in particular, but there is little risk in having it when you don't need it, but significant advantage to having it when you do need it.

If you are going into a situation *expecting* to need a gun, you should just avoid that situation. Therefore, if you are doing things correctly, you statistically will not likely ever need your gun, but by correlary, if you ever *do* need your gun, it will almost by necessity mean you weren't expecting it.

Noone really *expects* their house or car to catch fire, but that doesn't mean it doesn't happen or that fire extinguishers aren-t useful.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29209809547.0" user="CDWEBI" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imagine this scenario: someone theatens you and your significant other with a knife and demands your wallet. You reach your hand behind your back, similar to pulling out your wallet from uour back pocket, but also where your cocealed gun is. By the time the robber realizes that you pulled your gun instead of your wallet, it is already pointed at him. You now have control of the situation and can either shoot immediately or hesitate to wait for the robber's reaction as the situation dictates.

IMO it's a very bad decision if you are with your significant other. If he sees it he might turn onto SO with the knife on the throat. I think only psychopaths are not at all by the situation and will remain calm. Even if he is a criminal and threatens you he will most probably have a adrenaline rush, increasing his attention, at least IIRC. In the end you put more lives on risk with your gun than by just giving the money, especially with SO around</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29210067701.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In the end you put more lives on risk with your gun than by just giving the money, especially with SO around

[No, it won't, based on the statistical data we have.](http://www.cnsnews.com/news/article/cdc-study-use-firearms-self-defense-important-crime-deterrent) I've provided you the data. Please consider the data rather than assumption.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200425102.0" user="tirdg" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also is there a specific reason for you to carry a gun openly, like high crime rates in your area, or is it more of a cultural thing?

I think this is mostly cultural. I live in an area that isn't particularly high in crime and never really has been and people love carrying guns here. We've recently passed an open carry, actually. 

I have several friends who are very into guns and the best way I can describe it is childishness mixed with some paranoia. I remember carrying toy guns as a child and I thought it made me feel/look cooler. From what I can tell, that's about it. No one ever uses them but when you ask them why they carry, you get elaborate scenarios the likes of which you only see in movies where they always turn out to be the hero because they had their gun. Many of them have several different guns "for protection", because some guns are better in certain scenarios, I guess. I think the primary reason people own so many is because the gun companies know their market and can play pretty easily on this type of thinking. I literally know people who live in fancy houses with security systems, but to talk to them, you'd think they live in a war zone. It's hilarious.

To be clear, I'm not against guns. I have one that I keep at the house. It's not for hunting, it's for protection in the event of a break in or some such garbage. I'm almost certain I'll never need it and if I ever do, I'll probably be too incompetent to use it. But I already have it and doesn't do any harm just laying there so I'm not going through the process of selling it. If I didn't have one, I probably wouldn't buy one unless there was some immediate threat or local scare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200506555.0" user="cp5184" delta="False">
    <text>Guns give people a lot of confidence.

But it's mostly an illusion.

Take an improvised weapon.  A baseball sized rock, or a pointy stick, or a dull stick, or something called a "milwall brick", which is a newspaper folded over into a brick.

https://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;site=imghp&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;q=milwall+brick&amp;amp;oq=milwall+brick

A lot of gun people are surprisingly unaware of several key weaknesses of guns.

Let's say you're a weak woman.  A rapist stands ~30 yards in front of her in the daylight, yells at her "I am going to rape you" then starts running towards her.

She gets her gun out of her holster or out of her purse or whatever and gets off a shot or two...

And then he beats her up and possibly kills her.

Because he's much stronger than she is, and she just shot him, and because guns and bullets don't work like they do in the movies.

But, obviously, this is a ridiculously contrived situation.  A "best case" situation.  And even then, it's not really a win.

As people who have taken serious self defense courses that teach self defense, and don't just tell people what they want to hear or just do the minimum required by law know, criminals aren't stupid.

One advanced criminal tactic, for instance, is walking behind someone, picking up a loose brick, and hitting them over the head with it.

Another popular tactic, as anyone who knows the first thing about self defense knows, is probably the "classic" mugging technique.  It's like the first one, but there's another element.  Someone will approach you from the front and distract you, then the mugger will hit you from behind.

Other things that people who know anything at all about self defense know, are that if someone rapes or murders you, it's probably someone you know, unless you live in violent slums.

If someone who knows you tries to rape or murder you, for one, your defenses will be down, and for another, they'll probably know about your gun.  And they could very well murder or rape you with it.

If you're in a violent relationship, just about the worst thing you can do is bring more weapons into it.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201291909.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>Depending on the bullets you are using,  say .38 snake shot, you will not kill them but you will stop then in their tracks if you fire in their general direction.  If you are using 7 point plastic tip flechette rounds, anything that hits a body mass will cause death 90% of the time, even if you hit a limb as said limb will basically explode.  FMJ will just go straight through them and not do much unless you hit a major organ. So knowing your weapons possible loadouts helps.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201333842.0" user="cp5184" delta="False">
    <text>There's no bullet that that I know of that guarantees an attacker will stop in their tracks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201340410.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing guarantees it period.  But it sure as heck helps.  It's one of those better to have it and not need it,  then to need it and not have it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201558984.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>Who practices drawing under duress. 

Who practices drawing, aiming and firing in the 2.3 seconds someone can close on you with a knife from 20 feet away. 

Some people do. Most don't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201576955.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>I do. I practice my draw almost daily , mostly because I find it relaxing and its good exercise.  But I do main hand draws and off hand draws at minimum 3 times a week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201593650.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>Under duress? Or in controlled environments?

Because those aren't the same. 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201614823.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>Do time trials count? Because no I don't 
Practice with someone else shooting at me unless it's paintball or softair</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200791975.0" user="Pivan1" delta="False">
    <text>Not only is open carry allowed, but it is allowed without any kind of permit (in some states) whereas you usually need a permit to carry guns in a concealed way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201258064.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>I see people open carry every day.  I am a business owner so I carry to protect my business. And here our it's very much a cultural thing.  But we have had no robberies in our town in quite a while.  And some guy from another state tried to rape a girl who was carrying.  Let's just say he will never rape anyone again ever without massive reconstructive surgery. 

As for licenses a concealed permit allows you to open carry and vice versa.  You only need one kind. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201548885.0" user="JimMarch" delta="False">
    <text>You don't yet realize how incredibly common carry rights are in the US.

These maps on this next link are for concealed carry laws - green means "no permit required", blue means "permit is readily available if you're not a crook", yellow means "probably have to bribe a sheriff or high ranking police" (how Trump likely scored his very rare permit in New York City!) and red used to mean "no legal carry rights available" (now extinct):

http://www.gun-nuttery.com/rtc.php

Notice that no state went backwards from 1987 forward.  1987 was an important year - it's when Florida added a training requirement which made the concept politically viable.  A lot of states copied the FL model.

ALL of the green states also allow open carry and a fair amount of the blue states allow open carry with either no permit needed or a carry permit needed (Texas and Connecticut are in that latter category now).

None of the remaining yellow states allow open carry.  These are big, populous "politically leftist" states.  Proposed national laws would turn all of them effectively blue; passage of such bills is fairly likely right now inside of the next year.  If that doesn't work there's efforts to do the same thing in the courts.

So does it work?  Reddit has a great collection of "Defensive Gun Use" media reports:

https://www.reddit.com/r/dgu/

Some are possible "bad shoots" - guy shoots assailant after he's running away, stuff like that.  It does happen, but it's not common.

What does NOT get a lot of media attention are "chase-offs" - cases where no weapon is used, the bad guys get scared and run off when confronted.  We have statistics for this happening when bad guys are confronted with guns held by cops (because reports are still made) but we don't have the same data for legally armed citizens.  In police hands the rate of "threaten versus shoot" runs 10:1 in favor of "no shots fired" cases and there's reason to believe the numbers are even higher for non-cops.  After all, if a bad guy is looking down the barrel of a gun held by their intended victim they know that if they run away screaming with wet pants the regular folk are under no duty to chase them :).

To understand the psychology of all this in more detail see also:

https://www.amazon.com/Killing-Psychological-Cost-Learning-Society/dp/0316040932 - his main thesis is that humans are naturally wired to bluff much more than we're wired to kill.  This in turn explains why people with no criminal background can fundamentally be trusted with personal artillery, which in turn is why the states allowing widespread carry aren't seeing "blood in the streets" as a result.

I was personally the cause of a "chase-off" situation where I had a gun on me but never needed to make a move for it as it was carried illegally in California.  (I had recently come across evidence of corruption in carry permit access and was pretty pissed off over it.)

https://www.reddit.com/r/guns/comments/afw2z/if_you_see_someone_being_assaulted_can_you/c0hdx6n/

I also have a collection of news stories regarding the effects of allowing widespread carry that quote many of the same officials "before and after" - in other words before carry rights are established they predict "blood in the streets" while after they are forced to admit they were wrong:

http://www.ninehundred.net/~equalccw/ccweffects.html

*Grossman's research shows why legal carry by people able to pass background checks doesn't cause societal chaos.*

With the rise of Islamic terrorism there's a pretty good chance the US concept of legal defense is going to spread.  The Czech Republic's leadership is making noises like this now, and if they were a US state they'd be classed as "blue" on those maps already.  I think some of the Baltic states are the same way, and there's a credible movement towards this in Brazil.

It's also worth considering that some time in the next 15 to 30 years, one 3D printer will be able to print all the components to make another 3D printer, and will also be able to print guns.  At that point the entire concept of gun control goes flying out the window with it's ass on fire.  In a nation like Germany this won't be too big a deal.  In the US, hardly a ripple.  In China?  North Korea?  Etc?  National policies will have to confront the fact that they can either have a culture of lawful self defense, or a culture of complete criminality where it comes to guns.  They need to pick which one it'll be, ASAP.

Full disclosure: I'm a member of the most radical group of American "gun nuts" - the "amateur gun modder" community.  Even other gun nuts think I'm a weirdo :).  My "Maurice" has a feed cycle completely unique to personal arms.

http://www.thefirearmblog.com/blog/2014/03/03/maurice-frankenruger-magazine-fed-revolver/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29212097415.0" user="Jaxonsrazor" delta="False">
    <text>You make an excellent point that really made me think. As an aside may I say your Maurice is both scary AF! and mind boggling, but in a very good way!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29212238840.0" user="JimMarch" delta="False">
    <text>Three things to remember about Maurice:

1) From the factory, the gun started life as a reproduction 1873 Colt except made out of better metal and had a distinctly 20th century "drop safe" mechanism grafted in.  This "transfer bar safety" makes it a lot less likely to go "boom" if dropped **and I've left it in place, fully functional**.  Ruger "cowboy guns" with this safety (made since 1973) have a very low rate of accidental discharge and are recommended as a beginner's trainer handgun.

2) From the factory the gun was a 357Magnum, capable of 800ft/lbs of bullet energy.  It's now converted to 9mmPara, with a max energy level (in +p extra pressure) of about 450ft/lbs of energy, so I'm running it at lower energy levels than factory.

3) If that wasn't enough, the cylinder (the main part that "contains the boom") was made by Hamilton Bowen, one of the best gunsmiths of all time.  It is oversize in every dimension, made of forged chromoly.  It is rated for 41magnum and over 1,000ft/lbs of energy!  And again, I'm running it as a 9mmPara.

Upshot: this sucker ain't gonna blow up on me.  *It may be one of the strongest 9mmPara guns ever made.* It should be able to eat loads that would grenade a full size Glock. Even if my admittedly massive modifications weakened the frame a little, I've got tons of room for error by running a milder caliber than stock and using a seriously overbuilt cylinder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29202546685.0" user="temporarycreature" delta="False">
    <text>I used to live in Utah, a western state here in the US. I could carry my M4 carbine on my back, and often I did when I went target shooting because I only have a motorcycle, and couldn't carry the large case I store it in. Strapped it to my backpack, and off I went on the public roads. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200385671.0" user="stoicsmile" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;if you had to choose between the guy carrying the Smith and Wesson revolver on his hip or the guy who is walking along sipping his latte listening to his ipod, who would you attack?

That would depend.  Considering a lot of handguns used in crimes are stolen, it might actually make you a target in some situations.  There are plenty of people out there who wouldn't be afraid of your tough-guy-with-a-gun appearance.

I think that a safer solution would be to carry neither an ipod nor a gun openly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201269712.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>Most of them are not stolen from people carrying them, they are stolen mostly from pawn shops and residences. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29200785725.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>How often do you practice with your weapon in a situation similar to being attacked (adrenaline pumping, surprise, etc). And how much time do you spend at the range in general. What kind of training did you do so to get your open carry. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201265798.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>I practice every weekend , weather permitting.  I use timed pop-out targets at least every other month.  And you have to have an 80% hit rating to renew your permit every year (unless you are a veteran of military or law enforcement)

And before you ask, yes I have drawn on someone. They backed down and I never fired a shot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201302479.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>That's good. I don't think you're the norm though. There are repeated incidents where guns drawn by bystanders have not hit their intended targets. 

Re: I've drawn a gun on someone 

How common do you think that is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201337915.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>I've only had to do it once,  I've been carrying 20+ years</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201357039.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that. But nation wide. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201363632.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>i can't speak for the nation, i would have to do a lot more research. i can only speak for me personally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201386759.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>The reality is not very much and in most cases guns escalate a situation 

https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/hicrc/firearms-research/gun-threats-and-self-defense-gun-use-2/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29201537084.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>Wow.  That is one screwed up study.  Very skewed in the direction they want it.  Yes guns are used for intimidation.  I would rather intimidate someone then kill them any day! That doesn't make it any less effective at protecting me, and that's exactly what it did when I drew on the would be robber.  I scared him with a gun, he ran off, end of story. That's the point. The point isn't to use deadly force,  It's to have it.  

As I said I can only speak for myself,  But I personally know quite a few people who have used their guns for various forms of protection whether it be shooting a snake or a coyote, intimidating a robber,  or shooting a rapist. And yes I personally know people who have done all of the above, some multiple times. So those studies can not be that accurate, i'm just one person and my experience is that guns help more often then not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29202702671.0" user="mysongranhills" delta="False">
    <text>
 &amp;gt; listening to his ipod... 

This makes you sound soo old lol. While you are correct, that the gun being on display is a deterrent, wouldn't a fake gun in a holster accomplish the same thing? If I walk up behind you as you're getting into your vehicle and jam a pistol in your spine, how does your holster gun help you at all? In fact at that point I might get nervous if I see it and then any movement by you would just cause me (not really me but hypothetical bad guy me) to just blow your spine out your stomach. So it might deter people from trying ,but once they try (weather they saw and didn't care or didn't see) element of surprise makes your gun more of a hazard then a defence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29202864558.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>I am old! Lol. I hope it happens to you some day!

Situational awareness will always be better then a sidearm,  But I carry it at my place of work more then "out and about" . Because you never know what will walk in. And I'm rarely "out and about" I am old after all,  we don't do much. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29203030560.0" user="mysongranhills" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I am old! Lol. I hope it happens to you some day!

Well I'm 30 so already closer than I'd like.

&amp;gt; I carry it at my place of work more than "out and about" . Because you never know what will walk in.

This makes good sense.

Personally I think the best self defence case is for at home, stopping a burglar/home invader. Open/concealed carry in public can defend others very well (store clerk gets stuck up but guy behind robber is carrying), but I  tend to agree with OP that carrying in public doesn't offer much self defence b/c most times the element of surprise renders it useless. Even if you are aware of someone they might not present as a threat until it is too late.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29203064574.0" user="Ahshalon_Tenisk" delta="False">
    <text>You are not wrong (or old)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
