<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="363480636.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/60engc/cmv_the_war_on_drugs_failed_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: The War On Drugs failed due to the punishments not being severe enough</title>
    <original_poster>Blood_tree</original_poster>
    <original_post>The War on Drugs could have went significantly better had the DEA been able to request harsher sentences for distribution. Specifically corporal punishment and public executions for distribution would have made the drug problem in the United States negligible had they been enforced. Prison sentences cause people to disassociate the punishment from the crime due to their lengthly and impersonal nature and by contrast caning can be done in full very soon after the crime has been commited and is very personal and intense despite being on a whole less severe than a prison sentence. Public execution within a year of the crime is also a good measure since it will save money (we will be reducing the amount of appeals to one) and it will serve as a vivid denunciation of drug distribution and prevent perpetrators from reoffending. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29215086210.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/Blood_tree (OP) has awarded at least one delta in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [**here**](/r/DeltaLog/comments/60f4sb), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view [doesn't necessarily mean a reversal](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/index#wiki_what_is_a_.27view.27.3F), or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
