<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="363480636.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/60engc/cmv_the_war_on_drugs_failed_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: The War On Drugs failed due to the punishments not being severe enough</title>
    <original_poster>Blood_tree</original_poster>
    <original_post>The War on Drugs could have went significantly better had the DEA been able to request harsher sentences for distribution. Specifically corporal punishment and public executions for distribution would have made the drug problem in the United States negligible had they been enforced. Prison sentences cause people to disassociate the punishment from the crime due to their lengthly and impersonal nature and by contrast caning can be done in full very soon after the crime has been commited and is very personal and intense despite being on a whole less severe than a prison sentence. Public execution within a year of the crime is also a good measure since it will save money (we will be reducing the amount of appeals to one) and it will serve as a vivid denunciation of drug distribution and prevent perpetrators from reoffending. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29214959301.0" user="njwillforever" delta="False">
    <text>Let's look at an example of a prohibition from history: Alcohol.

The harsh punishments and criminalization of alcohol production, sale, and transportation that was established under the 18th Amendment ended in disaster with rising crime and the perpetuation of gangs. No amount of enforcement changed this, only the federal decriminalization of the 21st Amendment did this.

Stricter enforcement of the law will not lead toward solving the problems.

I will not, however, state that the War on Drugs was a success. The reason for it's failure has been due to the way it's been approached. We have approached the War on Drugs treating drug use and abuse as a crime rather than what it actually is—a health problem.

If you want to win the War on Drugs, you stop putting people in jail for minor drug offenses. You stop putting people into prisons that lock them in cycles of poverty and being in and out of jail and drug abuse (as the current model encourages). If you want to win the War on Drugs, you give people rehabilitation services rather than treating them as criminals.

A seventeen-year-old girl is hooked on heroin? We put her in rehab and help her put her life back on track instead of throwing her in county lockup. We treat it as a health problem rather than as a pure crime and we'll actually be able to see change.

It's not that we don't have severe enough punishments, it's that we're approaching the entire situation wrong and need to engage in a paradigm shift.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214974706.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you want to win the War on Drugs, you stop putting people in jail for minor drug offenses. You stop putting people into prisons that lock them in cycles of poverty and being in and out of jail and drug abuse (as the current model encourages). If you want to win the War on Drugs, you give people rehabilitation services rather than treating them as criminals.

Reread the OP where I argue that lengthly prison sentences do not work.

&amp;gt;A seventeen-year-old girl is hooked on heroin? We put her in rehab and help her put her life back on track instead of throwing her in county lockup. We treat it as a health problem rather than as a pure crime and we'll actually be able to see change.

I was purely talking about distribution and never even mentioned usage in the OP</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29221771928.0" user="SolaireDeSun" delta="False">
    <text>It is tough to talk about the War on Drugs without mentioning the main bulk of its money and effort: punishing drug users and minor cogs in the machine. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29222576511.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>I think that distribution of resources also contributed to its failure. They prioritized numbers over real results.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
