<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="363480636.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/60engc/cmv_the_war_on_drugs_failed_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: The War On Drugs failed due to the punishments not being severe enough</title>
    <original_poster>Blood_tree</original_poster>
    <original_post>The War on Drugs could have went significantly better had the DEA been able to request harsher sentences for distribution. Specifically corporal punishment and public executions for distribution would have made the drug problem in the United States negligible had they been enforced. Prison sentences cause people to disassociate the punishment from the crime due to their lengthly and impersonal nature and by contrast caning can be done in full very soon after the crime has been commited and is very personal and intense despite being on a whole less severe than a prison sentence. Public execution within a year of the crime is also a good measure since it will save money (we will be reducing the amount of appeals to one) and it will serve as a vivid denunciation of drug distribution and prevent perpetrators from reoffending. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29214933342.0" user="LtFred" delta="False">
    <text>That's true. Al McCoy makes your argument in most of his books, including Politics of Heroin in SE Asia. You can effectively eliminate drug sale if you're a fascist government. Just shoot anyone you even half suspect of involvement without a trial, and people will pretty quickly stop selling smack. We can't do that though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214934891.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Why can't we do that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214937450.0" user="LtFred" delta="False">
    <text>The US is a democracy. People have the right to a trial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214941954.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>They have trials in Singapore and Saudi Arabia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214970841.0" user="LtFred" delta="False">
    <text>There is a thriving drug market in Saudi, and Singapore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214972425.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>[citation needed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214986694.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/drug-dealing-in-saudi-arabia-sounds-like-a-very-stressful-business</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215001193.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>I want statistics, I don't want a vice article. By vice's articles I could conclude that feederism is a common fetish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215021887.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>The study referenced in the article states that roughly 25% of people had abused alcohol. As such we can extrapolate there is some substantial market for alcohol, a drug. 

Marginalization results in people operating in the margins. Colorado has seen a marked decrease in heroin abuse and a whole other host of positive things after legalizing weed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215030621.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>86% of Americans use alcohol so that means that the laws caused a decrease to almost a quarter of what it would be at otherwise.

&amp;gt;Marginalization results in people operating in the margins. Colorado has seen a marked decrease in heroin abuse and a whole other host of positive things after legalizing weed.

Weed is not the same thing as hard drugs and it is unclear whether a bad policy is better than no policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215045961.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>You're moving the goalposts now. Weed is the main arrest made in the war on drugs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215054351.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know what moving the goalposts means? I think that weed should be still punished harshly but not as much as worse drugs just like the war on drugs currently does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215642444.0" user="PM_For_Soros_Money" delta="False">
    <text>The war on drugs IS harshest on weed right now when you look at what it is in the grand scheme </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215120751.0" user="mr_indigo" delta="False">
    <text>Except he's demonstrably wrong.

Source: Duterte's Phillipines still has a drug problem despite extrajudicial murder of suspected drug traffickers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
