<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="365307341.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/61hsy5/cmv_a_society_run_via_a_libertarian_meritocracy/">
    <title>CMV a society run via a libertarian meritocracy has the same outcome as a strict class (or caste) system.</title>
    <original_poster>that-other-username</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the purposes of this question, I define libertarian meritocracy as one where the government has almost 0 effect on day to day life, and people advance in society purely on the strength of their own skill or luck.

I believe this has the effect of creating and reinforcing a class system because of the fundamental inequality of birth. A poor person born into this society would have few chances for learning and advancement of their skills, while a rich person would have access to high quality teachers and resources that would help them get ahead.

After several generations, you would have rich families far more power and influence than any poor family, and they could easily conspire to keep it that way via nepotism and corruption. 

Once societal mobility is taken away, there's nothing effectively different about this society and strictly class based society.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29229808351.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Brahmins are the highest caste in India, but they aren't the wealthiest. The merchant castes have far more money, but they are considered beneath the Brahmins despite that. [It's kind of like how racism works because poor white people think they are better than rich educated black people.](http://www.snopes.com/lbj-convince-the-lowest-white-man/) 

The same applies to social class as well. People think that someone who is born into an old money family is better than a self-made man or "new money." The plot of Titanic was about a woman who was from an old money family that went broke and needed to leverage their social status to marry into a richer family. 

The British style class system relies on the concept of nobility too. The richest class has hereditary titles that go to their children regardless of personal wealth, education, or talent.

In those systems the outcome is that some people are considered inherently better than other people, regardless of how rich or successful they are (or aren't.) In the libertarian meritocracy model, the same outcome will happen where some people are richer and more important than others, but it's based on something they actually have. That might be money, education, talent, or whatever, but not some inherent thing. People might still use nepotism and corruption, but it would be less effective than it is today.

There will always be some level of inequality in this world. Kids in high school are always going to be nicer to the pretty cheerleaders and the football stars. But in the libertarian meritocracy model is better at making it based on something that individual has, rather than some inherent magic trait from birth like race, religious status, or a hereditary title. Rich people can still game the system with nepotism and corruption like you said, but it's much harder to do in a libertarian meritocracy compared to other systems.

As a final point, don't forget that the cost of obtaining education is far lower than it used to be. A hardworking poor kid can learn a lot of stuff for free on Wikipedia, Khan Academy, Youtube, and many other websites. Rich parents can still buy their kids a good education, but free education is much better today than anytime in the past, and I expect that trend to continue. Most of the billionaires who have signed the [Giving Pledge](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Giving_Pledge) have focused on education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229851672.0" user="that-other-username" delta="False">
    <text>(For this paragraph, I'm assuming my conclusions about libertarian meritocracy are true. I'll be arguing for whether or not they are actually try in the subsequent paragraphs)

Just because it's based in reality rather than something imaginary (e.g. 'race' or 'birth') doesn't mean that it's different. In both examples, people of one class are *better* than people of another class and there's  nothing the lower class can do about it.

(Assumption over)

Khan academy is pretty great, but I don't think it's nearly as effective as, say, having private tutors in math while having a set time when you don't have to worry about other things. Remember that the poor have a lot of worries, food, safety, internet and free time are a lot less available than they are for the rich. That would make it a lot harder for a poor person to find a (low stress, optimal) hour to spend watching khan academy and doing practice problem.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
