<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="365307341.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/61hsy5/cmv_a_society_run_via_a_libertarian_meritocracy/">
    <title>CMV a society run via a libertarian meritocracy has the same outcome as a strict class (or caste) system.</title>
    <original_poster>that-other-username</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the purposes of this question, I define libertarian meritocracy as one where the government has almost 0 effect on day to day life, and people advance in society purely on the strength of their own skill or luck.

I believe this has the effect of creating and reinforcing a class system because of the fundamental inequality of birth. A poor person born into this society would have few chances for learning and advancement of their skills, while a rich person would have access to high quality teachers and resources that would help them get ahead.

After several generations, you would have rich families far more power and influence than any poor family, and they could easily conspire to keep it that way via nepotism and corruption. 

Once societal mobility is taken away, there's nothing effectively different about this society and strictly class based society.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29229685353.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>One thing you're missing in your analysis is that people and organisations currently gain power and influence by lobbying the government to institute laws that favour them. Take away the government and you take away that power. All you are left with is people being successful because they have products or services that the consumer wishes to purchase. What you don't have is people using the coercive power of the state to protect their positions and influence, because you have no coercive power of the state. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229695267.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>You're making the assumption that only the government is capable of affecting the market.

That seems like a completely unjustified.

What is stopping !Big_Evil_Corp from roughing up it's competitors, instead of paying of the governement to make them illegal.

Historical evidence shows us that this is no mere speculation, but simple fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229708469.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm not making that assumption. My point is that the coercive powers of the state are stronger than those of a corporation providing goods and services in a consumer society. One relies on free transactions, the other relies on force. 

A lot of this relies on what sort of libertarian state the OP is envisioning. Is it a minarchist one where your suggestion doesn't really apply, or an ancap one, where your suggestion has more force? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229723772.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One relies on free transactions, the other relies on force.

One relies on free transaction because the state controls the force. If the state is gone, there's nothing prevent the corporations from using force.

If the state is not gone, then it can be bribed. In your supposed minarchist system, what you claim to be failures of the state would not be solved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229730535.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes it would - in a minarchist state the power of the government doesn't extend into the business realm. You could bribe them all you want, but they can't pass laws in that respect. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229736905.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>You don't need to pass laws to bribe the cops in roughing up your competitors, or stuff like that.

Any governement that has sufficient power to stop the use of force has sufficient power to apply force. It's a basic neccesity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229743511.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>On the contrary. You can carve out limits to government power (Constitutions in the western world already do that, just not to a great enough of an extent). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229752400.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and people will magically never do anything illegal or against the constitution. 

You're assuming that stuff is incorruptible just because you want it to be.

Let's go with a practical example. Compagny A is using armed goons to threaten company B. What now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229758914.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You keep using the word 'magical'. Go read up on the minarchist model and come back to me. Until then it's a bit of a waste of my time, and you aren't the OP. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229773032.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>That's a nice copout. 

Every time people say it doesn't work, simply assert that it does and that if they knew better, they'd know it too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229792610.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, you keep using the word 'magical'. No one who is educated on the topic (on either side of the debate) would do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29230658937.0" user="Sheexthro" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes it would - in a minarchist state the power of the government doesn't extend into the business realm

I don't think this claim is very coherent. Even if the government doesn't *legislate* about businesses, surely it has *power*. The government - I presume - collects taxes and spends money. It - I presume - operates court systems that render enforceable verdicts. It - I presume - has soldiers who can fire guns at people or objects. It seems pretty obvious that whether or not it has 'regulations' on business, even a minarchist government has *power* over business.

And in fact this parallels the actual historical development *of* markets. Did you know that markets are government creations? It's true. The process is simple: the government wants to create a market for a service, so it announces that it will pay for that service with money, oh and by the way the tax man will be coming at the end of the year, so I hope you have some money to pay him with. Then people apply their own ingenuity under that constraint and hey presto, a market is formed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229705138.0" user="verpa" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't that just replace 'the state' with a state controlled on an individual level by the dominant business oligarchy for the region? Every time I hear libertarianism and a truely free market, I think of company towns where you're in life-debt before you're born (thanks for the term, Continuum).  
  
The only way to fight the power of the oligarchy providing workers their basic needs would be to form unions to enforce contracts between the workers and their employers. At which point you're basically recreating a government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229711643.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, because one relies on free transactions and competition, the other on force. 

And libertarians are all for unions - note that wouldn't be a government, that would just be two competing groups in competition. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229730332.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>But why would those corporations magically compete properly in the free market, something which history has shown does never happen.

If the corporation sees the opportunity, they will seize power.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229738403.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>There's nothing magical about it - it's the basis of the market. As for your 'history', government has always granted favours - you can't accept that and say 'well, businesses won't compete properly', because the coercive power of the state hasn't been separated from those markets. You're making the mistake of transposing assumptions that are valid in the current system with an entirely new one proposed by the OP. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229747662.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>You're assuming a magical system were the governement is at the same time powerfull enough to prevent any abuse of power while having insufficient power to abuse any of it's own.

I see no reason why the assumptions would be invalid, except that you want them to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229757488.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'd suggest you read up on the minarchist model and you'll see that there is still a defence force, courts and the police to protect private property and individual life. 

Until you are informed, I suppose it would seem 'magical' to you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229762822.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, why is your police force magically incorruptible. Why can the courts not be bribed, why can the defense force not be abused?

You're not getting away with "Trust me, there's an answer but I won't tell you". Usually, that means there isn't and you're trying to hide that lack.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229766794.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You keep using the word ''magical' which just seeems to denote that you've put little thought into the topic. In any event, you seem to assume that government departments are corruptible - I largely agree. You seem to want to then give them more power, which is confusing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229781780.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>No, minarchism denotes you've put little thought in explaining it.

You assert system is supposed to work, but give no reasons for why it should. Hence it's magical.

My point is that everything is corruptible, and hence your free market system is sn impossible utopia. Better the current system, where the governement is largely "corrupted" by it's major voting blocks, than a corporate anarchy only beholden to the wealthy.

It's not oerfect, but perfect does not exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229797861.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Except any corruptibility of government is limited to the functions of government, which are minimised in a minarchist system. 

You got this cognitive dissonance going where you say 'governments are corruptible. Don't take their power and reach away.' 

An interesting dichotomy, I'm sure you'd agree. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229808637.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>You're delusional if you think only governement is corruptible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229830449.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I don't - I merely suggest we decrease the power of government so that the corruptibility isn't such an issue. In any event, this isn't going anywhere. You aren't the OP - if you wish to continue discussing this, I suggest you do your own CMV. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229757350.0" user="verpa" delta="False">
    <text>Large groups of people coming together to make decisions on what people in those groups can do is literally what a government is. And without an overriding 'state' to threaten both sides with force, the threat of force from either side is always implicit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229761829.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>On the brighter side, you at least seem to accept that the state is an entity of force, primarily. It's just that you agree with that force to project your will... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229773226.0" user="verpa" delta="False">
    <text>I've yet to see a stable society that didn't have the implicit threat of force.  http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Minarchism seems like an unstable equilibrium if I've ever heard one ... there's always going to be someone who pisses in the well, both literally and figuratively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229706731.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  What you don't have is people using the coercive power of the state to protect their positions and influence, because you have no coercive power of the state. 

And we all know there's *no* coercive power besides the state. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229712734.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>One has power derived by force, the other by the freedom to contract and consume. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229719944.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>*Or force*. You do not remove force because you remove the government. Guns still exist and the power to buy and use them remains intact. Somehow, I feel like the Waltons of this world can buy more guns than you and I. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229723698.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, which come back to my other point in another reply about what kind of libertarian state the OP is envisioning. A minarchist or ancap one? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229746010.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>Both of which face the same issue: money litteraly becomes power. Either because the state exist as a legitimate source of force and you buy it or because there's no legitimate source of force except the one you can buy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229755034.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No, transactions become the source of power. If Yu don't have a good or service that other people are willing to purchase, you have no power. As opposed to now, where power is derived from governmental largesse and force. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229765182.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>Or, just as it always did, power comes from force, which you can either buy from the state of build for yourself. I see no reason to believe coercion will disapear because the state ceases to exist. Aside from you simply saying it will, I mean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229768314.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Coercion doesn't disappear, but you don't have the power of the state at the back of it. It's derived from voluntary transactions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229795576.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>And after a few voluntary transactions to buy force, those voluntary transactions will become deals no one can refuse.

"Derived from voluntary transactions " is not a magical spell that will mske everything work out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229802405.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, if you're going to keep using the word 'magical', I have little time for this. There are good arguments both for and against this, so if you aren't willing to have that in good faith, move on. I'll wait for the OP. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29230261949.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  There are good arguments both for and against this

You are yet to present any of these arguments. You just state the problem will dissolve and get mad when people aren't convinced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29230277710.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I'm not mad at all. And the arguments are all their in the replies. 

Have a good day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229766579.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>But why would that happen.

What is stopping Corporation A from simply shooting up Corporation B's stores instead of properly competing.

Even in the minanarchism system, everything is still enforced by force, you just don't want to admit it and instead shove it under the carpet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229771066.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Again, go and read about this and come back to me. A lot of your questions are premised upon an ancap construction, rather than a minarchist construction. Hence my query earlier about which one the OP was talking about. You remain not the OP, so it's a little pointless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229778126.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Clearly, if you had read more about it, you'd know it wouldn't work. Read up and come back later.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229794112.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You're the one that keeps using the word 'magical'. Which is the problem on reddit, I suppose. People spout off based on feelings rather than facts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229776724.0" user="StanguardRL" delta="False">
    <text>I can't just put a gun to your head and force you to buy my product in a Libertarian society. The entire point is to preserve your individual free will to do as you please, so long as you don't tread on the rights of others.

There is still a state, the state still has teeth, and the state still uses or threatens to use those teeth in order to protect individuals.

Libertarianism != Anarcho-Capitalism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229790366.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, and what then prevents said state from doing all the stuff you blame it for now?

You seem to rely on a hopelessly idealistic vision of  a state which never interferes incorrectly, which simply won't happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29229807664.0" user="StanguardRL" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You seem to rely on a hopelessly idealistic vision of a state which never interferes incorrectly

The state only interferes when someone's rights have been infringed upon (such as putting a gun to your head and forcing you to buy something)

The way things are now, the state preemptively interferes in everything, because the state thinks it knows whats best (whether it actually is or not)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
