<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="367694912.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/62wz7k/cmv_rng_can_be_a_good_mechanic_even_in/">
    <title>CMV: RNG can be a good mechanic, even in competitive gaming</title>
    <original_poster>alfredo094</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, I'm not completely sold out on RNG mechanics, but playing the Game of Thrones board game made me consider RNG mechanics (for those that don't know, the GoT board game has an optional RNG mechanic that adds up to +3 in combat strenght, where numbers don't usually go above 10. This is the only random mechanic in the game).

I think there are some cases where RNG hides over the fact that the game is not deep at all (like RISK, Monopoly and to some extent Fire Emblem, although I fucking love FE), but I think in a well-designed game it adds a layer of depth to it.

1) In games where snowballing is a thing (so many of them), it prevents snowballing since there is a chance for the losing team to make a comeback - the winner thus has to keep plan B in case plan A gets fucked by the RNG, thus he has to stratigize further in order to keep his advantage instead of just pushing a single plan.

2) It forces adaptation on a completely new level and makes risk-taking much more prevalent, since there is a chance of something going wrong without your control. In Smash Bros. games, for example, people would have to work around items randomly appearing, and this could open a huge amount of possibilities in the game.

3) It makes capitalizing on advantages much more important - in the aforementioned GoT example, you can get in very rare cases a +3 in combat strenght, but it's not going to matter much if you have the possibility to go in with 10 strenght while your opponent has 4.

4) It makes it more exciting for the audience, and this is really important for games that are pushing for a big competitive scene (like League of Legends).

I don't advocate for abuse of RNG, it doesn't even have to be true RNG (like LoL's crit chance) but I think it does have a place in competitive gaming.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29248379016.0" user="teerre" delta="False">
    <text>RNG is much, much more common than you're giving it credit. E.g most, if not all, RPGs don't have a set value for dmg, but instead a small interval, which is ultimately decided by RNG

In competitive it isn't super rare either. DOTA2, which is extremely competitive, has a lot of RNG in it. Including the very base dmg which is not a discrete number but instead it's a interval and the dmg done is ultimately decided by RNG

It's completely unreasonable to say RNG has no place in competitive games and even more in gaming in general 

Just to clarify, I'm challenging your view by saying it's not that RNG "can be" a good mechanic, it demonstrably is already in large scale 
 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29248622893.0" user="alfredo094" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't know that DOTA had RNG for damage, that's interesting.

In my case, I'm talking about mechanics that impact the game - colors and aesthetics wouldn't count.

Indisagree on the extent of the RNG - I think it has to be on a very small scale and its results need to ne predictable. Critting for 15x regular damage wouldn't be fair, and you need to have some control over your crit chance.

I think some items in some instances of Smash Bros. should be a thing, for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29249042690.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Indisagree on the extent of the RNG - I think it has to be on a very small scale and its results need to ne predictable. Critting for 15x regular damage wouldn't be fair, and you need to have some control over your crit chance.

Does it depend on the game in question?  Certainly that wouldn't be great in a tournament-style game, but what about a role-playing game that strives for realism?  Sometimes when you get stabbed or shot, you just die.  A fair fight is something to be avoided, in many games.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29249188591.0" user="teerre" delta="False">
    <text>Did you read what I wrote? I didn't say anything about "color and aesthetics" 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
