<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="367694912.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/62wz7k/cmv_rng_can_be_a_good_mechanic_even_in/">
    <title>CMV: RNG can be a good mechanic, even in competitive gaming</title>
    <original_poster>alfredo094</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, I'm not completely sold out on RNG mechanics, but playing the Game of Thrones board game made me consider RNG mechanics (for those that don't know, the GoT board game has an optional RNG mechanic that adds up to +3 in combat strenght, where numbers don't usually go above 10. This is the only random mechanic in the game).

I think there are some cases where RNG hides over the fact that the game is not deep at all (like RISK, Monopoly and to some extent Fire Emblem, although I fucking love FE), but I think in a well-designed game it adds a layer of depth to it.

1) In games where snowballing is a thing (so many of them), it prevents snowballing since there is a chance for the losing team to make a comeback - the winner thus has to keep plan B in case plan A gets fucked by the RNG, thus he has to stratigize further in order to keep his advantage instead of just pushing a single plan.

2) It forces adaptation on a completely new level and makes risk-taking much more prevalent, since there is a chance of something going wrong without your control. In Smash Bros. games, for example, people would have to work around items randomly appearing, and this could open a huge amount of possibilities in the game.

3) It makes capitalizing on advantages much more important - in the aforementioned GoT example, you can get in very rare cases a +3 in combat strenght, but it's not going to matter much if you have the possibility to go in with 10 strenght while your opponent has 4.

4) It makes it more exciting for the audience, and this is really important for games that are pushing for a big competitive scene (like League of Legends).

I don't advocate for abuse of RNG, it doesn't even have to be true RNG (like LoL's crit chance) but I think it does have a place in competitive gaming.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29248439968.0" user="r_vigorous" delta="False">
    <text>At the core of this argument is the question of what a competitive game is meant to accomplish. Within your four points, you mention that RNG has the ability to create complexity (points one and two), require players to play more skillfully (point three), and make the game more exciting for the audience (point four). 

In regards to complexity, the complexity that RNG offers often leads to a meta game that is undesirable. In the games that people enjoy the most, winning is a combination of effectively executing a strategy and predicting your your opponent's actions. In games where there is a significant RNG component, a meta game emerges where players build strategies intended to capitalize on this mechanic. However, because RNG is static strategies that incorporate it are inherently less complex than the dynamic strategies intended to capitalize on your opponent's actions. 

You argue that an RNG mechanic forces players to capitalize on opportunities, but if the mechanic is this significant then the gameplay  favors the less skilled player to an undesirable extent. If the better player makes more correct decisions but does not capitalize perfectly, and the worse player makes fewer correct decisions but wins because of an RNG mechanic, it becomes difficult to argue that the game is skill based. This will limit the game's longevity and prevent it from developing a significant tournament presence. 

I do think that you're correct in that comebacks are very exciting for the audience, but many games implement comeback mechanics that are not dependent on RNG. Consider two different situations:

1. A competitive Pokemon battle takes place in which P1 has acted more skillfully and is significantly favored to win, but P2 wins as a result of multiple RNG based critical hits. 

2. A Street Fighter match takes place in which P1 has a significant life advantage, but P2 is able to make a comeback as a result of making a correct read and landing a high damage super combo.

These examples are meant to show that there are different ways to implement a comeback mechanic, with one based on RNG being much less desirable. In situation 1, the more skilled player lost and the less skilled player won due to random chance. In situation 2, the player who is at a disadvantage was able to make a comeback based on correctly guessing their opponent's actions and capitalizing on them. There certainly is value in a comeback mechanic, but it's much better for both audiences and players for that mechanic to have a skill component. 

However, as another commenter has mentioned, RNG in some form is essential to almost every game we play. From color assignment in chess, to daily double placement in Jeopardy, to attack values in RPG's, some form of RNG appears almost everywhere. Your title argument that RNG can be a good mechanic is certainly impossible to dispute. However, in the body of your post you argue in favor of examples of RNG mechanics that severely limit the quality of gameplay. Having items enabled in Smash Bros. would significantly lower the skill differential necessary for a worse player to beat a better player. I would encourage you to specify your view so that it does not stand in opposition to a strawman ("no game should ever have any kind of RNG"), or change your original position and acknowledge that many of the examples you gave make for an inferior competitive game. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
