<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="368037533.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/634bkt/cmv_in_the_future_when_the_average_age_of_death/">
    <title>CMV: In the future when the average age of death is significantly higher than today, the age of adulthood will also be significantly higher.</title>
    <original_poster>synergistali</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is just something that popped into my head and I thought about it for a few minutes. 

The reason I think that if the average age of death is higher that the age that a person is considered an adult will be higher is because that is how our society has functioned so far. Long ago children were considered adults at maybe 13 or so. Now it's 18. I think this is because the age of death being greater now then long ago. So I'm just extending this reasoning to the future. 

Really I made this post so that I can hear some better reasoning as to why this would happen or why it wouldn't. 

Cheers!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29250940260.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>1 - i - Kids weren't seen as adults at 13 in the past. That is a myth supported by the fact that 13 year olds got married.

ii - 13 year olds didn't get married in the past. 13 was a good age to create betrothals, but marriage still occurred later at 16-20 like in the modern age. 13 year olds only got married when mass inheritance was at stake, such as a kingdom. It just so happens that kings are the people who typically had their marriages recorded, hence the misconception.

2 - On to your main post. What we see as the age of adulthood largely depends on what we consider to be an adult.

The age of majority in Medieval Britain was seen to be 16 for Commonfolk as it was the age you began planning a family, and 21 for nobility as that was the age you could be knighted and take on responsibilities of your own.

We see adulthood as 18 because the majority of Western society is descended from commonfolk, so we use the same standard. In the last century as we began to place more emphasis on education, adulthood ended when education ended which was typically at 18.

In the future the age of adulthood will likely only increase if we as a society believe it should increase. The most likely candidate is 25 as that is the age that the brain begins to finish development. Because of this learning slows down and the brain is less likely to be damaged by exposure to things like alcohol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29250975248.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>"1 - i - Kids weren't seen as adults at 13 in the past. That is a myth supported by the fact that 13 year olds got married."

In a legal sense they were adults. They worked, joined the military, got married, etc. 

"ii - 13 year olds didn't get married in the past. 13 was a good age to create betrothals, but marriage still occurred later at 16-20 like in the modern age. 13 year olds only got married when mass inheritance was at stake, such as a kingdom. It just so happens that kings are the people who typically had their marriages recorded, hence the misconception."

Hmmm, I'm not sure this is accurate. Would like to see a source. 

Basically, why wouldn't our future society extend the age at which children start to plan for families and finish education? I feel like this would happen just based on my intuition (could be wrong haha). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251023446.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.medievaltimes.com/teachers-students/materials/medieval-era/marriage.html

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_European_marriage_pattern?wprov=sfla1

Perhaps it is wrong to say that the average age was 16-20.

Girls could be younger, but men were often older.

They could get married at 12, but this is like saying you can get married at 16, most people don't get married as soon as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251030254.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.medievaltimes.com/teachers-students/materials/medieval-era/marriage.html

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_European_marriage_pattern?wprov=sfla1

Perhaps it is wrong to say that the average age was 16-20.

Girls could be younger, but men were often older.

They could get married at 12, but this is like saying you can get married at 16, most people don't get married as soon as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251268891.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>When humans went through puberty was the sign of adulthood for many societies for most of human history. Cultural traditions like Jewish Bar Mitzvah, Spanish Quinceanera, English/American Sweet 16, Catholic Confirmation, and many others were the coming of age ceremonies that marked entering adulthood. 

Age 13 was not common true, but age 15-16 was. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
