<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="368037533.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/634bkt/cmv_in_the_future_when_the_average_age_of_death/">
    <title>CMV: In the future when the average age of death is significantly higher than today, the age of adulthood will also be significantly higher.</title>
    <original_poster>synergistali</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is just something that popped into my head and I thought about it for a few minutes. 

The reason I think that if the average age of death is higher that the age that a person is considered an adult will be higher is because that is how our society has functioned so far. Long ago children were considered adults at maybe 13 or so. Now it's 18. I think this is because the age of death being greater now then long ago. So I'm just extending this reasoning to the future. 

Really I made this post so that I can hear some better reasoning as to why this would happen or why it wouldn't. 

Cheers!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29250939751.0" user="Ghost_of_John_Galt" delta="False">
    <text>I think the flaw in your reasoning is assuming that adulthood is related to people's lifespans. I'd argue they are more closely related to when an individual can usefully contribute to society. 

Back in preceding centuries, a 13 year old could do some manual labour, fight in wars etc. As society has developed, it's taken people longer to get to that stage - people go to school, university etc. write really contributing. Accordingly, it makes sense to set the line for adulthood at a higher age (it doesn't make sense for a 13 year old who is in school, living at home, and not contributing taxes to be considered an adult). 

So, you may be correct, in the sense that if people are spending longer getting qualified and aren't working until later then legal recognition of adulthood may not occur until later - but that's unrelated to the average age that people live to .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29250964910.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>"So, you may be correct, in the sense that if people are spending longer getting qualified and aren't working until later then legal recognition of adulthood may not occur until later - but that's unrelated to the average age that people live to ."

The first part of this statement is something that I had in mind. Getting qualified is a major part of our lives and it takes until you are in your early to mid twenties on average to start making an income you can have a comfortable life with. The last part of the statement is where I have an issue. I would argue that if we can live until we are 200, we won't starting working until we are say 50. I'm not exactly sure why I think this, I guess it's just what I would think would intuitively happen. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29250968699.0" user="Ghost_of_John_Galt" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't it more likely that the average working life increases, rather than starting later? I mean, what does the average person work now? 40 years? It used to be the case that people died before they got to 30. People haven't delayed starting work so that they only work the amount of years that they used to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29250988729.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't think so. We would extend our "getting qualified" period no doubt. People will have more flexibility to change education goals and to have more proper and less rushed educations. It would be easier to take a few years off and see the world, seeing as you have so many years ahead of you. 

You see the range of expected settling age is something like mid twenties to early thirties, right? This range would expand greatly if we could live to 200 yoa. The range might look something like early 50's to late 80's or something like that. I would think that every other aspect of society would follow the same rule. Our "getting qualified" age range would be something like 40's to 60's. I'm just throwing semi-random numbers but you see my point I hope. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29250993545.0" user="Ghost_of_John_Galt" delta="False">
    <text>But that's not related to lifespan. That's just related to how long it takes to get qualified. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251003054.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>I'm arguing that how long it takes to get qualified is related to lifespan. We as a society will find ways to extend the getting qualified period. Or we will have larger breaks in between school years or we will encourage taking years off between high school and college to explore, etc. etc. I don't see society keeping the same strict rules of finishing college when you are 22 if we can live until 200. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251019467.0" user="Ghost_of_John_Galt" delta="False">
    <text>How long it takes to get qualified depends (on part) on the complicated matter that is before us. Neurosurgery in 2017 requires longer to get your head around (pun intended) than sowing some fields. The fact that we live longer is a corollary of that, but isn't related to how long it takes to learn neurosurgery. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251029429.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying is that our society will become more relaxed with how and when you finish educating yourself. Does that not seem reasonable to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251033375.0" user="Ghost_of_John_Galt" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that's necessarily reasonable - until then you are a burden on society. I can't see people becoming comfortable with that. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
