<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29272133378.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>So is your claim *merely* that it's not "necessary"?

Or are you making some kind of stronger claim?

Because I would argue that, regardless of whether it's "necessary" or not, it's *useful*, because so many people in the world think this way about things that are inborn vs. a choice. 

Politically, one is much more likely to be successful using that tactic.

I.e., while it's not "necessary", it's "sufficient", because it's generally considered to be unfair to blame people for things that they had no choice in. 

On the other hand, it's neither necessary nor sufficient to demonstrate that it's a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272166937.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>I hold the position that it's counterproductive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29273014069.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>You don't really explain *why* it's counterproductive.

Let me ask: if it were *useful*, and it were *successful* in getting people to allow gays to enjoy more rights, would you *still* consider it "counterproductive"?

Because the evidence certainly seems to point to this tactic being effective. Human beings, especially the kind that are dumb enough to argue against gay rights in the first place, are quite prone to Appeals to Nature. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29274989334.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>I think my position is best summed up by user ReOslr10: 
&amp;gt;Not only is it not necessary to prove that gay people are "born this way", but it's actually detrimental. Not only does this argument imply (not logically, but in the casual sense of the word) that being gay is wrong, and that society should only tolerate it because we can't help it, but it also marginalizes individuals who claim to have chosen their sexuality.

Moreover, the immediate utility of something is not incompatible with it's ultimate counter-productivity. Allow me to elaborate on this. Several years ago I had a criminology ethics class in which a professor, who no doubt had the best of intentions, was going to have a guest speaker who was not only a diversity trainer for law enforcement but also gay. This was a Tuesday/Thursday class and on Tuesday he said, sarcastically, "Oh and by the way, he's a *flaaaming* homosexual." On Thursday we met him and he was a guy who defied the gay male stereotype. Now, to a lot of people, this seems sensible (and no doubt effective, if it indeed changes minds) because they often feel stereotypical gay men "hurt" the cause and that we should instead assimilate to heterosexual male demeanor. But imagine if we changed some of the variables. Suppose he had instead said, "Next class we'll be having a diversity trainer come talk to us. Oh and by the way, she's *suuuper* dark. I mean, dark as the night sky." And then we find out that Thursday that she's very light skin like Beyoncé. Now, suppose this were effective and successful in changing racists' minds. Can you see why this would still be seen as counterproductive? This is giving people bad reasons to disavow their prejudices and still leaves open the door to arbitrary prejudice anyway (which, to relate it back to the topic in question, can be applied to those whose sexuality is more fluid than fixed). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
