<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269198356.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy.

Well it depends do you want people treating homosexuality as a mental disorder that can be "cured" or not?  Once you take the religious side out of the equation, the whole homosexuality debate has been a nature vs nurture debate. If it is nurture, then there is something being nurtured that has created a maladaptive trait that has not only taken people out of the gene pool, but also gotten people killed. If that is the case then something should be done about the nurturing. If its natural then culture itself should adapt in accordance with that information. Without that evidence for the nature argument, much of the progress made by the gay community since the 90s falls apart.

Also people tend to pull out fallacies like they are a win card, they aren't, they are a caution sign to show areas of logic where there may be trouble, not that the logic is wrong or that the argument is bunk. (On top of that you are probably thinking "appeal to nature" rather than naturalistic fallacy, they actually are two different things. Both tend to rely on is-ought problem, but even is-ought is pretty debated, and tends to fall apart in a non moral realist setting and in scientific discussion since then you would have to define a moral ought, when the "is" is actually still being defined or discussed.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269213474.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If it is nurture, then there is something being nurtured that has created a maladaptive trait that has not only taken people out of the gene pool, but also gotten people killed.

How so?

&amp;gt;If its natural then culture itself should adapt in accordance with that information.

That is, of course, until someone discovers a way to, say, genetically modify baby humans. Then we're back to square one. 

&amp;gt;On top of that you are probably thinking "appeal to nature" rather than naturalistic fallacy, they actually are two different things.

I don't disagree, though I'm not convinced I've made that error.

&amp;gt;but even is-ought is pretty debated, and tends to fall apart in a non moral realist setting and in scientific discussion since then you would have to define a moral ought, when the "is" is actually still being defined or discussed.

Reminds me a bit of Sam Harris' argument on the issue. In any event, I'd rather not derail the main claim with an esoteric discussion on a Humean is-ought debate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269265521.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How so?

Well the taking out of the gene pool is pretty obvious, but then (discounting hate crimes) you have the suicde rate that is still pretty high. In most ways it would seem like a pretty maladaptive trait if it is something that is being nurtured. 

&amp;gt;That is, of course, until someone discovers a way to, say, genetically modify baby humans. Then we're back to square one.

Yeah, but the morality of eugenics is a totally different problem. Plus if it is proven that homosexuality is actually an evolved trait (gay uncle theory, though it has its problems still seems like its on the right track) then you can prove it evolutionarily is actually a beneficial trait.

&amp;gt;I don't disagree, though I'm not convinced I've made that error.

Well naturalistic fallacy describes to explain that which is good reductively in terms of natural properties such as "pleasant" or "desirable". It specifically is about the description being reductive and only works in moral arguments If one is not making a moral argument on the matter then naturalistic fallacy does not apply. In a nature vs nurture argument one is making no moral claims, that's why I was clarifying the depth of the actual problem to nature vs nurture.

Appeal to nature instead instead can be used to describe the argument "This property is unnatural; therefore, this property is undesirable." It doesn't rely on a moral argument but rather shows the problem that morals cannot be derived from nature in its base state, and instead are a human invention.

&amp;gt;Reminds me a bit of Sam Harris' argument on the issue. In any event, I'd rather not derail the main claim with an esoteric discussion on a Humean is-ought debate.

Though I take the Harris statement as a complement, you were the one who brought the naturalistic fallacy into it. The naturalistic fallacy literally is an is-ought problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269300763.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well the taking out of the gene pool is pretty obvious, but then (discounting hate crimes) you have the suicde rate that is still pretty high. In most ways it would seem like a pretty maladaptive trait if it is something that is being nurtured.

I've come across this argument in years past and I have not found it at all convincing. From an evolutionary standpoint, it isn't enough to merely point to a trait that might have a disadvantage to claim it as "maladaptive." Take for instance the sickle cell gene. If you get one copy of it it can make a person immune to malaria, which is beneficial for someone living certain parts of the world where it is epidemic. If you get two copies, you get sickle cell anemia, which can be fatal. Is this maladaptive? Not if the benefits outweigh the costs. In the case of homosexuality, homosexuals are not sterile, but their same-sex pairings certainly function in this way, at least if exclusively kept this way. But studies seem to indicate that females who have gay offspring tend to be more fecund. It is possibly the case that, from an evolutionary standpoint, the cost of having one child not produce offspring because he is gay is offset by the benefit of making you more fertile. These things are not so cut-and-dry.

Now, all this science is really interesting, but I don't see it being of much relevance when furthering gay rights causes. We don't claim that because certain human races have certain genetic predispositions to disorders and whatnot relative to others that interracial relationships are wrong. And most people (thankfully) don't accept the notion that, say, white girls should be discouraged from dating black guys simply because they'll suffer as a result of affiliating with persons who are marginalized in society. Perhaps it will make their life harder, but that's not the fault of their black boyfriend or the notion of interracial dating.

As to the hate crimes and suicide claims, ask yourself who causes this? Would you blame a woman who wears a hijab if she got stabbed by an anti-Muslim bigot? If gay lives are subpar relative to straight ones, it isn't because of something inherent to their sexual orientation. It's because others make life hell. As a side note, have you considered at all that maybe the "nurture" part of your argument should be directed at society at large and not to gays?

&amp;gt;Yeah, but the morality of eugenics is a totally different problem. Plus if it is proven that homosexuality is actually an evolved trait (gay uncle theory, though it has its problems still seems like its on the right track) then you can prove it evolutionarily is actually a beneficial trait.

Whether something is beneficial to evolution is kind of mute at this point. It is simply the case that we have flown the perch to our evolutionary destiny. Is it adaptive to have children who are dwarfs? Probably not, but a lot of people who know their children will be born with defects and the like often choose to have them instead of aborting them. We tend to leave that choice to people and go out of our way to use technological advancements to make their lives livable if they are indeed brought into this world. 

Again, this is all unnecessarily complicating a very straightforward matter. 

&amp;gt;In a nature vs nurture argument one is making no moral claims

I don't know that that is true. It depends on what is being discussed. If I'm debating a suburbanite soccer mom who is making the claim that kale is a superfood and is good for your because it is "natural," she is likely not making a moralistic claim (though sometimes these debates resemble them). If we're talking about homosexuality, the claim is often made that it is with respect to ethics. Think of, for instance, the conservative Catholic stance about "natural" sexualities being defined as the "complementarity of the sexes" as opposed to just "occurs in nature." 

&amp;gt;Though I take the Harris statement as a complement, you were the one who brought the naturalistic fallacy into it. The naturalistic fallacy literally is an is-ought problem.

Sure, I referenced it in the topic, and I generally agree with Harris, but there is a distinction to be made between the claim that an "ought" can never be derived from an "is" (which I don't challenge and virtually agree) versus the claim that *any* "is" leads to a particular "ought" (which I quarrel with).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269403223.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've come across this argument in years past and I have not found it at all convincing.

Well it's partially because it seem that you are misunderstanding a few things about what a "maladaptive trait" means within the context of a nature nurture argument. A trait within the nature argument can only be maladaptive in an evolutionary sense if it does not persist, and only in that sense. If it persists then it is obviously not maladaptive. But in the nurture sense a trait can be maladaptive and persist outside evolutionary bias (the whole you cant kill an idea thing). If being gay is natural, it is obviously not maladaptive in an evolutionary sense. If it is nurture then it IS maladaptive because it is forcing people not only out of the gene pool but causing all the cultural conflict that forces other problems. can you see the difference in the two arguments? That difference is why the whole being gay is natural argument is SO important to the movement.

&amp;gt; But studies seem to indicate that females who have gay offspring tend to be more fecund. It is possibly the case that, from an evolutionary standpoint, the cost of having one child not produce offspring because he is gay is offset by the benefit of making you more fertile. These things are not so cut-and-dry.

That's not what those studies point out. In fact it's the exact reverse of what you are saying. Rather it than the female being more fertile and that somehow being the trait. It is the accumulation of androgen and testosterone within the womb after having multiple male children that is thought to partially be the cause of homosexuality. If that is the case homosexuality has little to do with genetics of the female.

&amp;gt;Whether something is beneficial to evolution is kind of mute at this point.

Well once again you miss the point completely of what the differences in the argument ACTUALLY are.

&amp;gt;We don't claim that because certain human races have certain genetic predispositions to disorders and whatnot relative to others that interracial relationships are wrong.

That's not the argument in hand... AT ALL. In fact before most racial differences were scientifically debunked that was an argument that a lot of people were having... When in that case it was shown it was more a problem of nurture over nature the conversation changed to how to help people overcome the disadvantages of nurture. If one were to do the same thing with homosexuality then people would be trying to find what social programs could "fix" the nurture problems leading to homosexuality...

&amp;gt; As a side note, have you considered at all that maybe the "nurture" part of your argument should be directed at society at large and not to gays?

THAT IS THE ARGUMENT. If being gay is natural, then it is the society that is causing these social differences and problems rather than the biology. If being gay is nurture then you cannot separate the society from the equation so it becomes a maladaptive socialized trait...

&amp;gt; It is simply the case that we have flown the perch to our evolutionary destiny.

I tend to disagree with Harris on that argument. We do not live outside of an evolutionary context.

&amp;gt;Again, this is all unnecessarily complicating a very straightforward matter.

No shit. You seem to be going out of your way to make it far more confusing than it actually is.

&amp;gt;Think of, for instance, the conservative Catholic stance about "natural" sexualities being defined as the "complementarity of the sexes" as opposed to just "occurs in nature."

Why do you think I said "once you take religion out of it"...

&amp;gt;an "ought" can never be derived from an "is" (which I don't challenge and virtually agree) versus the claim that any "is" leads to a particular "ought" (which I quarrel with)

You see I disagree on this. Oughts can often be derived from Is; often that is the only logical route. Not all the time, but much of the time it shows that you actually understand what the IS actually means and entails. But then again i'm not a moral realist, and I don't tend to agree with Humes on just about anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269429836.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It is the accumulation of androgen and testosterone within the womb after having multiple male children that is thought to partially be the cause of homosexuality. If that is the case homosexuality has little to do with genetics of the female.

It's a moot point. It's merely be a side-effect of a good trait. It's also irrelevant to the discussion.

&amp;gt; If it is nurture then it IS maladaptive because it is forcing people not only out of the gene pool but causing all the cultural conflict that forces other problems.
&amp;gt;THAT IS THE ARGUMENT. If being gay is natural, then it is the society that is causing these social differences and problems rather than the biology. If being gay is nurture then you cannot separate the society from the equation so it becomes a maladaptive socialized trait...

Gays are not causing the cultural conflict. People's biases toward gays are. In other words, the nurture should be directed at people's implicit and explicit biases, not as to whether gays are raised to be gay.

Also, that gays are forcing people out of the gene pool is of little relevance. There's a claim that if it turns out that homosexuality is genetic then because gays do not naturally produce offspring with their same-sexed partner, this trait will die off. That may or may not be true, given what we've discussed above could play a role. Again, what is the relevance to this as to gay rights? None. It almost reminds me of the silly argument people make that if everyone were gay in society there would be no society. You could say that about anything, of course. If everyone were like couples who have no kids, there would be no society. Therefore, having no kids is immoral or unworthy of rights or dignity? Please.

&amp;gt;No shit. You seem to be going out of your way to make it far more confusing than it actually is.

No, the confusion is in bringing up irrelevancies in the pursuit of gay rights.

&amp;gt;Why do you think I said "once you take religion out of it"...

It was but one example.

&amp;gt;You see I disagree on this. Oughts can often be derived from Is

I might have worded it incorrectly. I meant to say that there's a claim other people make that one cannot derive an ought from an is. I agree with Harris, not with these other people. There is a difference, however, between that and making the claim that *any* is statement leads to a particular ought. That's how it can be compatible with a naturalistic fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269529078.0" user="PineappleSlices" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It almost reminds me of the silly argument people make that if everyone were gay in society there would be no society. You could say that about anything, of course. If everyone were like couples who have no kids, there would be no society. Therefore, having no kids is immoral or unworthy of rights or dignity? Please.

Heck, not only is this argument silly, but it's also outright false. Plenty of gay people want to have children. If through some bizarre act of god everyone on Earth suddenly became gay, then there would be a sudden push to advance artificial insemination technology. If anything, society might be better off, since only people who legitimately really want children would be having them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269685268.0" user="cardboard_dinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's a moot point. It's merely be a side-effect of a good trait. It's also irrelevant to the discussion.

Just to reassure you that you didn't get this wrong (if it's the study I'm thinking of) - work on insects shows that the genetic variation underlying fecundity in females can influence rates of same-sex behaviour in males. So the genome that produces more fecund females also produces more male-fancying males.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269704245.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's a moot point. It's merely be a side-effect of a good trait. It's also irrelevant to the discussion.

Well you  are misinterpreting what the science said. You made it the point by doing such. Well fertility isn't exactly a genetic trat, more a situational factor so no it isn't a the side effect of a desirable trait, nor is it always something that is always desirable. More babies =/= better. Not really irrelavent to the discussion since you brought it into it. If you want to drop it cool, but misinterpreting the science within a discussion of the topic makes it a topic of discussion.

&amp;gt;Gays are not causing the cultural conflict. People's biases toward gays are.

Well then its more that gays are the subject of the cultural conflict... So in otherwords like it or not they are involved.

&amp;gt;In other words, the nurture should be directed at people's implicit and explicit biases, not as to whether gays are raised to be gay.

So in other words you agree that we should have different socialization, but you still don't want to separate the false "gays are raised gay" thing out of it... Honestly despite the science being on the side of the born gay side, you aren't willing to take that win for the team?

&amp;gt;Also, that gays are forcing people out of the gene pool is of little relevance. 

Well except for you know the natural desire to reproduce being a little thing.

&amp;gt;. There's a claim that if it turns out that homosexuality is genetic then because gays do not naturally produce offspring with their same-sexed partner, this trait will die off.

Absolutely 0 evidence to support that.

&amp;gt; Again, what is the relevance to this as to gay rights? None.

Well if you are wanting recognition as group with real claims and a legitimate struggle its been incredibly important.

&amp;gt; It almost reminds me of the silly argument people make that if everyone were gay in society there would be no society.

Human society requires reproduction. Without it it wouldn't exist. So though I agree its a dumb argument, it also contains a nugget of truth.

&amp;gt;Therefore, having no kids is immoral or unworthy of rights or dignity? Please.

Who said that? In fact the nurture side and proponents of it would say attempts at conversion therapy would be returning dignity to them (they make that claim now).

The fact is the gay rights movement has relied on the scientific evidence to show it is not a mental illness or even a choice to help justify their call for rights and dignity. You drop that out and many of the grounds of current progress drop with you.

&amp;gt;No, the confusion is in bringing up irrelevancies in the pursuit of gay rights.

Scientific facts are irrelevancies? Ummmmm okay.

&amp;gt;It was but one example.

One that I specifically left out, mainly because its rarely a position that can be reasoned with.

&amp;gt;There is a difference, however, between that and making the claim that any is statement leads to a particular ought. That's how it can be compatible with a naturalistic fallacy.

I understand that, which is why I'm saying you may want to use appeal to nature, it fits your argument slightly better. I mean most people confuse them anyways, but if you want to use the proper phrase for the argument you now have it.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270032986.0" user="busawa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The fact is the gay rights movement has relied on the scientific evidence to show it is not a mental illness or even a choice to help justify their call for rights and dignity. You drop that out and many of the grounds of current progress drop with you.

That it isn't a mental illness or a choice does not necessitate that it's something one is born with.

The conclusion that there are gay babies and straight babies ignores the complicated science behind sexual development. Innate factors that predispose individuals to a particular manifestation of sexuality are not deterministic. Nurture plays a role in all complex human behaviors. This *does not* mean that homosexuality is unnatural, that it can or should be prevented on an individual or widespread basis, or that acceptance of gay people lacks a scientific grounding.

It just means that sexual development is more complex than we are capable of understanding in detail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270101170.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The conclusion that there are gay babies and straight babies ignores the complicated science behind sexual development.

Actually it kinda IS the complicated science. In fact its pretty much been one of the most successful branches of research letting us understand how sexuality develops and if people do have innate sexual tendencies.

&amp;gt;Innate factors that predispose individuals to a particular manifestation of sexuality are not deterministic. 

Of course its not 100% deterministic. Culture plays a huge part in sexuality. For example the homosexual actions preformed by hetrosexual people is often cultural. But when it comes down to preferred mate preferences it seems to be around an 80-20 split weighed heavily towards innate sexual preferences, and the more research being done the more it weighs in towards preferred mate preferences being biologically determined.

&amp;gt;Nurture plays a role in all complex human behaviors.

Of course. Anyone who says otherwise is fooling themselves. But they play differing degrees of influence on different aspects. Mate preference seems to be more biologically determined than culturally determined, where as "what makes a good mate" appears far more influenced by culture than by biology (with some key exceptions including MCH).

&amp;gt;This does not mean that homosexuality is unnatural, that it can or should be prevented on an individual or widespread basis, or that acceptance of gay people lacks a scientific grounding.

Well I never said it did... I noted that the acceptance movement has heavily relied on the scientific backing and understanding to prove its need for equal treatment. As have pretty much every rights movement.

&amp;gt;It just means that sexual development is more complex than we are capable of understanding in detail.

Well we may not fully understand it yet. That's kinda what science does is try to narrow down and get closer and closer to the truth. But the fact is that we DO have a pretty damn good understanding of some of the key features of how homosexiality developes, and the cultural biological interplay. Not 100% of course, but we do actually understand quite a bit of it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270193420.0" user="busawa" delta="False">
    <text>If you're actually going to argue that there are gay babies and straight babies then please provide the sources that support that claim. I used that phrase to highlight that it sounds ridiculous. In any case, thank you for clarifying your view a bit more. I guess we don't fundamentally disagree, but do disagree when it comes to degree. 

You agree that culture plays a huge part in sexuality. And yet you seem to be asserting that homosexual and heterosexual are biological categories. If heterosexual people engage in homosexual behavior, how are they heterosexual by a biological standard? The difference between behavior and identity is key here, so this framing is already glossing over a huge amount of the complexity that is inherent to this issue.

Again, I'd love to see a source for your 80-20 figure because I'm quite wary of arguments that seem to have as their goal explaining something in a way that makes intuitive sense or that validates a preexisting view. Numbers should always have sources anyway. Bringing up pair bonding and mate preference only serves to highlight further the shaky ground all this is on. Not all people are inclined towards monogamy or pair bonding to begin with.

If this scientific understanding of how adult sexuality arises is as well developed and clear as you claim, please point us to the materials that make it so clear. I am not an expert authority on this so I'm open to the idea of being taught something new, but I am also not inexperienced in this area and even with years of studying it and related issues I feel that your level of certitude is unwarranted, so if there's something I'm really missing I'd like to know. Until then I can only regard this statement as an opinion and not a fact:

&amp;gt;But the fact is that we DO have a pretty damn good understanding of some of the key features of how homosexiality developes, and the cultural biological interplay. Not 100% of course, but we do actually understand quite a bit of it. 

And let's not resort to preachy platitudes about science. I'm sure you understand that in reality human beings disagree about what science is, what its goals are, and how to interpret it. You seem to know a fair bit of philosophy so I imagine you know even better than I that the relationship between science and truth is a hotly debated ideological issue about which there are a few schools of thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270539602.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you're actually going to argue that there are gay babies and straight babies then please provide the sources that support that claim.

Okay if you want to start looking into the scientific data we can. Lets start out with twin studies. [This 1991](http://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/article-abstract/495588) study was one of the first of its kind on MZ DZ twins as well as looking at adopted siblings of the same age to try and understand levels of influence. It found that when one sibling was gay around 52% of MZ twins shared sexual preferences while 
22% of DZ twins shared preference, and only 11% of adopted siblings share the preference. Now this study did have some problems with sample sizes, but later studies such as [genetic](http://www.nature.com/ng/journal/v11/n3/abs/ng1195-248.html) and [epigenetic](http://escholarship.org/uc/item/863841tx) studies have shown that particularly in men there is strong genetic linkage between specific mutations of the x chromosome and specific epigenitic modifications that there is an Incredibly strong bias towards homosexuality. Now it should be noted that most estimates put the influence of genetics at around 31-39%, but there are other factors at play outside genetics. In particular prenatal environment is seen as incredibly important. In studies of [fraternal birth order](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S002251939690315X?via%3Dihub) show that each male son born increases the prospect of the next son being born's being gay by 33%. Now this is in particular caused by [HY antigens](http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0091302211000227) produced by the mother treating the infant as an infection and crossing the BBB and skew the develpment of sexually dimorphic brain structures towards female structures (Some studies show this may have particular effect on the hypothalymus.  Now this is by far the most robust of the biological linkages and linkages and when stacked with heritable genetic. Then there are the womb hormonal studies which thoug linked with the birth order hypothesis do show slightly different resuts when sudied indepentently of the hy antigents. Partuicularly [androgen](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951011/) exposure has shows effects, but also prenatal stress shows a [signifigant impact](https://dx.doi.org/10.1016%2FS0031-9384%2801%2900564-9). Now there are a few more less signifigant biological factors, that show far less consistant results, but if you stack these biological factors to try and get a percent influance with variance you tend to get around 83%. Given that there is till a lot of inconclusive data I rounded to the closest 10 becase its a rough estimate and 10s are easy (so yes I admit the estimate is rough but I did factor in multiple variables with proven influance).

&amp;gt;You agree that culture plays a huge part in sexuality. And yet you seem to be asserting that homosexual and heterosexual are biological categories.

I think biologically influenced behavior or proclivities would be a better choice of terms. Nature doesn't really tend to draw as easy of lines as culture does between behaviors.

&amp;gt;. If heterosexual people engage in homosexual behavior, how are they heterosexual by a biological standard? 

Well this is where mate preference comes into play. If a male tends to sleep and sexualy behave towards women he has a hetrosexual mate preference, if the same is done towards men its a homosexual preference. If its around the same its bisexual mate preference. Now you can measure that in percentages if you have the full sexual histories, but that is rarely the case, so for most of that you have to rely on survey data and self reporting.

&amp;gt; Numbers should always have sources anyway. 

It's a rough estimates off of different biological studies such as those I listed earlier and discussion with other anthropologists on the topic. Most everyone concludes that with mate preference biology is key.

&amp;gt;Bringing up pair bonding and mate preference only serves to highlight further the shaky ground all this is on.

I never mentioned pair bonding at all. I mentioned mate preference. Those are two totally different things. Bonding practices are defined far more heavily by ecology than biology anyways.

&amp;gt; I am not an expert authority on this so I'm open to the idea of being taught something new, but I am also not inexperienced in this area and even with years of studying it and related issues I feel that your level of certitude is unwarranted, so if there's something I'm really missing I'd like to know. 

I cant claim to be an expert in this field. My research mostly deals in evolution of brain structures, violent behaviors, and human behavioral ecology. But I can point you towards some of the experts in the field. I would first suggest The Biology of Homosexuality by Jacques Balthazart, hes one of the most accomplished researchers in the genetic and neurological aspects of sexuality. Then I would also suggest The Science of Desire by Dean H Hammer whose team did some of the first genetic research on the subject and one of the first genetic twin studies.

&amp;gt;You seem to know a fair bit of philosophy so I imagine you know even better than I that the relationship between science and truth is a hotly debated ideological issue about which there are a few schools of thought.

Its debated less than some think but more than others like depending of the field of origin. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270471646.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271556790.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry KriosDaNarwal, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 3\. "Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view or of arguing in bad faith. If you are unsure whether someone is genuine, ask clarifying questions (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting ill behaviour, please message us." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+KriosDaNarwal&amp;amp;message=KriosDaNarwal+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/dg2vsgu/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271647416.0" user="KriosDaNarwal" delta="False">
    <text>My bad</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269737624.0" user="Revengecertainly" delta="False">
    <text>The high suicide rate doesn't come from being gay but not being accepted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269766136.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>That's kinda the point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269855005.0" user="Revengecertainly" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be implying that the cause of it is being gay rather than not being accepted. In that saying being gay is what caused people to be killed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269898708.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>No, I was noting that in a nature mindset that the solution would be to change the cultural outlook to reduce the suicides. 

In a nurture mindset the solution would be to change the enculturation and socialization so that people wouldn't be gay...

In one mindset the biology is what defines it so it can't be changed and has to be worked with; so in turn the socialization has to change.

In the other mindset the socialization is the root cause of both the issues and the discrimination so the easiest solution would be to get rid of the socialization that is causing the issue in the first place...

That's why the fact that sexuality is heavily defined by biology is important to the problem solving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269356022.0" user="shinkouhyou" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; maladaptive trait

There are quite a lot of [biological reasons why homosexuality may be positive or at least neutral on a population level](http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26089486).

The "gay uncle hypothesis"suggests that while gay people may not pass on their *own* genes, they actually increase the likelihood that the children of their closely related relatives will survive.  So having a certain percentage of an animal community be gay is actually beneficial for the community.  You've got extra adults who are able to bring in food and care for children.

It's also possible that the genes that cause homosexuality are actually beneficial to *heterosexuals*.  Women tend to prefer men with somewhat feminine behavior and appearance over extremely masculine men, so these "femininizing" genes are preserved in the population's gene pool.  Some men end up with a little extra feminization and end up gay, while others get a *lot* of feminization and end up transgender.  I don't really like the idea of conflating gayness with femininity, though, since many gay men aren't feminine at all.  

It's also possible that homosexuality isn't actually genetic - instead it could be caused by fetal exposure to maternal hormones.  The more male children a woman has, the more likely her younger sons are to be gay.  That woman is still producing a lot of kids and passing on her genetic material, so it doesn't matter if a couple of them are gay.

And it's quite possible that being gay *is* a choice for some people... in that they're born with a tendency towards bisexuality but they choose to exclusively have relationships with the same gender.  Sexuality is a spectrum and there are probably a *lot* more people in the middle than we currently believe.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269416094.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There are quite a lot of biological reasons why homosexuality may be positive or at least neutral on a population level.

I agree with this, and agree that there are biological causes for homosexuality. I am ONLY stating that if it WAS social causes (nurture) then it is a maladaptive social trait. That's the whole point of the distinction and why the biological reasoning is important. I even brought up the gay uncle hypothesis to show why.

&amp;gt;I don't really like the idea of conflating gayness with femininity, though, since many gay men aren't feminine at all.

Never argued they were.

&amp;gt;It's also possible that homosexuality isn't actually genetic - instead it could be caused by fetal exposure to maternal hormones.

Most likely is a little of both since it does seem to run in families but it seems more associated with hormones than genetics.

&amp;gt;And it's quite possible that being gay is a choice for some people... in that they're born with a tendency towards bisexuality but they choose to exclusively have relationships with the same gender

Possibly in some cases it is. But it tends to fit the reverse bell curve a lot nicer numbers wise and better describes a spectrum of sexual behaviors with a biological root as the primary cause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269593139.0" user="1000ancestors" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; do you want people treating homosexuality as a mental disorder that can be "cured" or not?

Whether it is a mental disorder or not should be a question that can be determined scientifically (which it was in the US in 1973). There is no scientific evidence that such a disorder exists.

https://www.psychiatry.org/news-room/apa-blogs/apa-blog/2016/03/homosexuality-as-a-mental-disorder-simply-not-backed-up-by-science</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269678823.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>Well thats specifically due to the definitions that were changing at the time. The scientific community had already been leaning towards the biological causation of homosexuality in the 70s the first such studies were being produced. Because of that the APA changed its definitions such that it didn't fit within the DSM. I mean I agree, but if you were to stop making sure the biological  nature of it was hammered home you would most likely see a rise in phoney conversion therapy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270206909.0" user="obliviious" delta="False">
    <text>Just because it's nurtured doesn't mean it needs to change. It doesn't harm people, unless you are saying the victim caused others to persecute them...? Let's not go there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270546604.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Just because it's nurtured doesn't mean it needs to change.

Not really saying it does, but I am saying with nurtured behaviors it tends to be far easier than biological behaviors to influence</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270749376.0" user="obliviious" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't really come across that it's what you meant, but I do agree that it generally would be easier.

&amp;gt; Without that evidence for the nature argument, much of the progress made by the gay community since the 90s falls apart.

In some peoples eyes it may fall apart, but logically as there are no determinantal affects to themselves or others, they should be allowed to do what they wish. As the saying goes, your right to swing your fists ends at my nose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270769677.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It doesn't really come across that it's what you meant, but I do agree that it generally would be easier.

I get that, as a note I don't agree with that position at all. But I understand that people often go for the easiest solution, not the best one.

&amp;gt;In some peoples eyes it may fall apart, but logically as there are no determinantal affects to themselves or others, they should be allowed to do what they wish.

Personally I agree, but that won't be the logical outcome. The outcome would be a reinvigoration of things like conversion therapy. Which I think we can both agree is fairly harmful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272264970.0" user="alfredo094" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, we know today that sexual orientation isn't 100% genetic, there are ambient factors here.

Second, if you admit that homosexuality is a "maladaptive trait that has not only taken people out of the gene pool, but also gotten people killed", you're hereby proving OP's point by saying that gays should be seen as sick. There is a lot of stuff that is influenced by genetics and we still call it a disorder.

I don't believe homosexuality is something that needs to be cured (although I do find it gross, but hey, they probably think the same about me), but my reasoning isn't that "they don't choose it".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272478390.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First of all, we know today that sexual orientation isn't 100% genetic, there are ambient factors here.

True, its about an 80/20 split to be generous to ambient factors.

&amp;gt;Second, if you admit that homosexuality is a "maladaptive trait that has not only taken people out of the gene pool, but also gotten people killed", you're hereby proving OP's point by saying that gays should be seen as sick.

Only in a certain mindset and only if it is a nurtured trait which we know its not really. Maladaptive only really is a thing if the trait does not continue in the genetic sense, so that's why we can only talk about the nurtured sense being maladaptive, and if it were proven there is no evolutionary advantage, which kinda is yet to be proven, and probably never will be on that.

&amp;gt;I don't believe homosexuality is something that needs to be cured (although I do find it gross, but hey, they probably think the same about me), but my reasoning isn't that "they don't choose it".

Cool cool, I dont think it needs to be cured either, but that's because I think its purely natural and mostly biological. Its a trait seen in just about every other mammalian species (especially goats and giraffes).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
