<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29277631025.0" user="ddeese" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a gay male. I'm not a liberal. I don't have the answer to what the root cause of homosexuality is. Perhaps there was some hormonal or chemical processes that happened in the womb during maturation. Perhaps there are some environmental issues at play. It is also possible that there are some genetic factors that make a person susceptible when added to environmental and/or hormonal chemical stimuli is an additional factor. 

What I can say is that making the premise that being gay is an inherently in-born trait, a truism, isn't necessary to advance the cause of allowing people to having the maximum possible amount of liberty possible. It is a tactic of those on the political left and typically those who consider themselves liberal. I'll explain. 

Being gay, black, transgendered, muslim, female, pick your non-majority minority; its about victimhood status. With the possible exception of the gay and transgendered (I didn't consciously choose to be gay) all of these groups have traits of physicality that are in-born and unchangeable. If you say that they are at a disadvantage and it is because of a trait that cannot be changed, then they are a victim. Even worse yet, they are a victim that cannot change the nature of their reality and are therefore a perpetual victim.

Victimhood is a political tool of the left. Once us gays are having surrogate babies at a rate of 3:4 and live as a family unit on one in every twenty five homes and seeing gays holding hands and kissing each other goodbye at airports and work becomes ubiquitous; we'll be left behind for the transgendered and the muslims. Because we won't be victims anymore. There is no clout, no power to shut up the majority without a argument that shows one party as David and the other as Goliath. Where the majority would use their power and privilege and numbers to go out of their way, not just to disagree with gays or their premise that they were born this way, but to say the majority goes out of their way to harm the gay; to discriminate, to promote HATE.

When or if, I'm born gay, I can't change it. A woman, I can't change it (unless I'm a man who thinks I can put on a dress and become a woman) a muslim, black, etc. 

Consider the Black Lives Matter movement and the whole, "hands up, don't shoot." BLM doesn't care about the value and the quality of living for black lives. Their protests and involvement has driven down the number of police in high crime areas in black urban communities. In these neighborhoods violent crime and the mortality rate for black victims has risen. The movement created a crime vacuum that the average black person in the urban community is paying for with their lives. But on college campuses we now have segregated dormitories for the first time since the civil rights era. Because of the political power to claim that things are horrible because, in the case of BLM, you're born black, you can't change being black and you're a target because you're black. Therefore its institutional racism and white privilege that makes black lives more difficult. 

The reality is that if you replaced being black with black culture, then you would see something that can be changed. That would mean that black persons in America would be responsible for their culture and having to stand up and do something about their culture of violence.

If gays said well perhaps our attractions are inherent, but the gay culture has issues that make gays off-putting to straights. Then we would have to acknowledge as gay people that we are responsible and we have a duty to fix it. We'd no longer get to claim victim and use it in movies, academia and government to beat (politically) people over the head with. If we had to acknowledge that gay culture is responsible for the fact that HIV infection rates are down everywhere in the modernized world, accept amongst gays, where it is up 22%. Then we'd have to acknowledge our faulty lifestyle choices and own up to them. If black citizens acknowledged that black culture is a culture of violence, that they represent 13% of the American population, but make up 53% of violent crimes, 95% of that against other blacks. Then blacks would have to take responsibility and then they wouldn't be victims because they would have to go out and change their communities. If transgendered persons admitted and accepted that the 40% suicide rate of transgendered persons was just as high after hormone replacement therapy and gender reassignment surgery, then they might have to acknowledge that transgender feelings might be caused by an underlying mental imbalance and then they would have to seek mental health treatment which would seek the underlying causes of that disorder and try to bring them back to health. But that would mean admitting they aren't victims. Admitting that their position might be flawed. Admitting that there are things that must be cleaned up in our own home before we demand more laws and protections. But as long as we're born this way, what can we do? Nothing. After all who can change how they were born? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
