<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29270703243.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>In as much as the universe is deterministic and there's no such thing as "free will", and as a consequence no such thing as "choice", how would it be possible for it to be anything *other* than "born that way"?

EDIT: a more interesting point is that this works *at all* in the U.S. Don't Christians think homosexuality is a sin? And don't they think that we're all born with "Original Sin", and yet we're still supposed to struggle against it (but that everything is part of God's Plan)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271751431.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In as much as the universe is deterministic and there's no such thing as "free will", and as a consequence no such thing as "choice", how would it be possible for it to be anything other than "born that way"?

It is still rational to speak about choice in a deterministic world. Read Sam Harris' book *Free Will*. Let's not further derail this thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271780660.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Did *you* read the book? 

Of course it still makes sense to talk about choice even though every action you take and everything you will ever believe is determined at birth. That's not the point.

My point is that this means that it *only* makes sense to say that gays were "born that way", scientifically speaking. There's nothing else useful to say about them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271822527.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Did you read the book?

I have. I own it.

&amp;gt;My point is that this means that it only makes sense to say that gays were "born that way", scientifically speaking. There's nothing else useful to say about them.

That is a complete irrelevance to what's being discussed here. Those who bring up the statement "born this way" do so out of a response to those who claim that "it's a choice." Those who assert that it's a choice are advancing an unstated assumption that that is somehow relevant to the conclusion that we should therefore not afford people dignity, respect, tolerance, rights, etc. My position is not to entertain their non sequitur but instead force them to justify how their premise leads to their conclusion. It's a way of shifting back the burden of proof.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
