<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29270184167.0" user="Vicvic38" delta="False">
    <text>What is stopping the advancement of gay rights?

People who stand against it on moral grounds, the "it just isn't right crowd." People are in the way of this, not matter how idealistic you wish to be about it. 

For the reason that you cannot ignore/silence/kill those who oppose these things, the only thing you can do is prove that it is natural. Sadly, a lot of the opposition is from religious sources (no, I am not painting all people of faith as bigots), and thus by proving it is a natural thing, one can argue that God made them that way.

Your argument hinges on the fact that people will live and let live. Who cares if it's a lifestyle choice? It's not our choice to make. 

This is fatalistically idealistic. People can and will care what others do behind closed doors, even when it does not affect them. Again, religious fanatics fall foul of this quite a lot. 

Once it is proved that it is not a choice, these people will just have to put up with it, or in other words, live and let live. On the whole society is coming around to LGBTQ+ rights, but there is still that loud minority who are a demographic with votes to be won.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271792600.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People are in the way of this, not matter how idealistic you wish to be about it.

I'm not being idealistic. This isn't about idealism; it's about improving our way of engaging the other side. I see the "born this way" response to the "it's a choice" crowd as simply playing their game. If a large group of the population start to claim that we shouldn't allow dwarfs and the blind to own homes because they choose to be disabled, our response shouldn't try to be to prove that they are indeed disabled. Our response should be, "How the hell is this even relevant?" *That* is my point. We're wasting time playing their game. And worse, we are validating their non sequitur assumptions.

&amp;gt;Your argument hinges on the fact that people will live and let live.

What part of my argument hinges on that, exactly? I feel like you're just projecting your own impressions on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272399761.0" user="Vicvic38" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;dwarfs and the blind

Swings and roundabouts. This is different to standard disability. This falls closer to the invisible disability side of the argument. Proving it's existence in this case, as something that cannot be helped is incredibly important.

Misophonia might be an imperfect analogy, but it's better than dwarves. Up until recently, no one had proved misophonia existed. This lead to a lot of secrecy from sufferers, a lot of damaged social relationships, and when it was explained, people would get defensive and assume you were choosing to be that way. However, it has been shown to be a result of a miswired pathway in the brain, causing a fight or flight response to innocuous sounds. Now, when you are explaining it to people you can bring up this research and go, look it's natural I can't help it. People are far more accepting of things they mayn't like if they know it is no ones fault. 

This can be repeated on many mental illnesses throughout history which have eventually come around to a more caring world with a better understanding. Homosexuality was lumped in there, but hasn't quite made the full circle, because of people standing in the way.

&amp;gt;What part of my argument hinges on that, exactly? I feel like you're just projecting your own impressions on it.

Well, you don't actually explain why you hold this view in the slightest in the original post, contravening rule 1 of this sub, but I'm not gonna be that guy.

To explain my reasoning as to why I chose this avenue of argument, 

&amp;gt; this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. 

I then thought, well gee, what's stopping us? Bigots. Why are bigots stopping us? They don't think it's natural.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29274959020.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is different to standard disability.

I see this as a distinction without a difference. The whole point is that the deprivation of someone's liberty is occurring for an irrelevant reason. Suppose instead of making a false claim I make a true claim. Suppose I say that no one who has a pinky shorter than two inches should be allowed to purchase a home. Should such people and their supporters spend time measuring their fingers seeing if they can pass the test or should they confront me about what on Earth this has to do with anything? That's kind of my point.

&amp;gt;They don't think it's natural.

And then when you respond that it is natural they come back and say that this doesn't absolve one of moral responsibility. It's a wasted effort. That they don't think it's natural doesn't address the fact that they were operating on a non-sequitur fallacy to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29275075429.0" user="Vicvic38" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I see this as a distinction without a difference.

So you can see people's gay can you? The difference is that we can see that someone is missing a leg, is a dwarf, or is blind. You cannot deny that someone who has dwarfism, has it. You keep regressing back into discussion of physical disability, and it is irrelevant.

Denying the right to exist for these people is a lot harder than for someone with an invisible disability. The depressed, for instance. A common complaint is people telling them "to snap out of it, just be happy." This is a marginalisation resulting from a misunderstanding of how the condition works. This is solved by learning the nature of the condition.

I think this may come down to semantics. The naturalism fallacy stipulates that because something is natural, does not make it morally good. I don't think arguing moralities is useful given the lack of objectivity inherent in the subject matter.

Therefore, I posit a slightly different definition. *Natural = normal.* The human race thrives on normalcy, and to prove that being gay is natural, thus normal will swing a lot of younger, more impressionable minds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29287185841.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So you can see people's gay can you?

Huh? This is irrelevant. I can give you what you want or just simply have a bracket that reads "[insert conspicuous or inconspicuous trait here]" and my point would be the same. It simply doesn't matter whether we're talking about a conspicuous trait or not. The fact that I can see a dwarf from a mile away but I can't see if someone is left-handed just by looking at them is irrelevant to the point that we're talking about irrational and arbitrary discrimination. 

&amp;gt;Natural = normal. The human race thrives on normalcy

I can see that potentially backfiring. There are many traits that are not normal (as in, they are a deviation from the norm), like being a redhead for instance, that are not problematic whereas there are things that are normal, like violence, which are or can be.

&amp;gt;thus normal will swing a lot of younger, more impressionable minds

I would direct you to the response I gave [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/dg5kmc6/) about why I'm not keen on using non sequiturs to sway a person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29288570802.0" user="Vicvic38" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to make one question here. 

Let us say that "gay is ok, whether it is naturally caused or not."

That's great. We've all changed the tune we are singing to. How exactly will furthering Gay rights go with all of the people who believe that it is nurture and the "water is turning them gay" or something like that. The people who believe it is a mental disorder that can be cured, and prevented, we just say: oh yeah it's a nurture thing now.

There is a lot of lobbying to be made on that front. If we concede that is is something that happens to the child as they grow up, many pieces of dubious research could be made that "prove" that x, y or z causes "the gay." Some may even lobby against teaching about LGBT issues because they fear it will turn their children.

This gets back to the core of my argument. People can, and will, stand in the way of progress in this area. The "bigoted" crowd still exists, and they are still a demographic with votes to cast.

Sure, these people will be weeded out in the next 20-30 years or so, but do we want to wait that long?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272266458.0" user="alfredo094" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the only thing you can do is prove that it is natural.

There are a lot of things that are "natural" and we still don't find them acceptable. This reasoning is fallacious and we shouldn't be using it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
