<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29271530709.0" user="iongantas" delta="False">
    <text>Broadly speaking, you can only make moral judgements about choices.  Things that are an inherent part of one's nature aren't a matter of choice and aren't subject to moral judgement (by rational people, anyway).  It is even arguably immoral to dramatically contravene your essential nature (like using a screwdriver as a hammer).

Apart from this, it is also manifestly true that homosexuality is a natural phenomena, so even making hypothetical claims about it not being are counterproductive to public discourse.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271739256.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Apart from this, it is also manifestly true that homosexuality is a natural phenomena, so even making hypothetical claims about it not being are counterproductive to public discourse.

Except I'm not making hypothetical claims about it not being this way. I'm saying it's rather irrelevant what my opinion or anyone else's is on the matter. Many of these same people who assert that it's a choice often aren't defining homosexuality they way that you are. They define it as an act that people choose or choose not to do. They often concede that there can be a predisposition or inclination toward the same sex but that ultimately one chooses to be immoral or not, akin to alcoholism. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271747191.0" user="iongantas" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I'm aware of that argument, but the people making it probably unanimously lack any kind of perspective.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
