<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269143848.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>It is necessary, it's a fundamental component of how we build all of our rights for individuals. Genetics are a very important component of the law, and proving anything is genetically related reflects upon the law as a component of merit.


For example, if there was a certain type of person more genetically predisposed to being a criminal, and they do in fact end up being a criminal it's clearly not something they can nessecerily help, it's hardwired into them. So then we have a new question. If someone is born with something they cannot select or choose, do they deserve to be punished as harshly as someone for whom it's 100% a choice? Or do they even deserve to be punished for being born a certain way. Most people would say no.


As this relates to advancing rights for Gay people, choices are not looked upon so fondly under the law, because for most of the first world determinism is a core philosophy. We believe that everything that is a choice, should carry the appropriate consequences. If being gay is a choice, then people do not have an innate basis to respect it. It's just a choice, and it being a choice means it is just as undeserving of political protection as any other choice. Such as cheating, overeating, theft, stealing etc.

Think about other legal protections, they are all in general built around the idea that the things they protect aren't choices. Race, Age, Sex. We understand as a byproduct of genetics (people are born that way) that those components are beyond a person's control and to punish them as such is nessecerily wrong. Homosexuality, is still up in the air in regards to this. It could be genetic or it could be a choice, but the minute it's definitively genetic the federal law, is immediately put into a position where it must offer a protection to a minority. That's why being born a certain way is important for advancing protections for homosexuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269157181.0" user="chris2315" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's just a choice, and it being a choice means it is just as undeserving of political protection as any other choice. Such as cheating, overeating, theft, stealing etc.

That's kind of a bullshit argument. If you live in a country that values freedom, it is illogical to oppose something on the basis of it being a choice. We don't ban or look down on things because they're choices, we do it because these things hurt other people. The only thing we need to prove regarding homosexuality is that it doesn't cause harm to anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269180400.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;That's kind of a bullshit argument. If you live in a country that values freedom, it is illogical to oppose something on the basis of it being a choice. 

I value freedom, and I oppose murder on the basis of it being a choice. If someone suffered from a condition that caused them to murder people or bleed internally causing them inconceivable pain I treat that 100% differently than someone rationalizing that someone else has to die.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;We don't ban or look down on things because they're choices, we do it because these things hurt other people. 

Then you're not actually valuing freedom are you? You are valuing convenience. It's convenient for you that people don't hurt one another, it adds value to currency and the stability of your economy that allows you to feed and water yourself and purchase goods you enjoy.

Things being a choice matters. If it doesn't matter in your own philosophical paradigm then it matters because you need to achieve outcomes pragmatically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269196804.0" user="chris2315" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I value freedom, and I oppose murder on the basis of it being a choice. If someone suffered from a condition that caused them to murder people or bleed internally causing them inconceivable pain I treat that 100% differently than someone rationalizing that someone else has to die.

From a moral perspective, sure, we might not regard this person as evil in the same way we would someone who chooses to commit murder. But are we just going to say "sure, go ahead and murder some people"? Are we going to offer sacrifices so this one person can live? Of course not. It's sad that you have this wildly implausible condition, but you're gonna have to die, because you are literally incapable of coexisting with other people.

That's how we decide what is allowed and what is not. It has nothing with choice, it has to do with morality. Being forced to kill someone does not make it okay to kill someone. Having sex with people of the same gender remains unharmful regardless of whether or not it's a choice.

&amp;gt; Then you're not actually valuing freedom are you? You are valuing convenience. It's convenient for you that people don't hurt one another, it adds value to currency and the stability of your economy that allows you to feed and water yourself and purchase goods you enjoy.

What kind of ancap bullshit did I just stumble onto? I value freedom, I just perceive freedom as focused on the individual rather than collective. Or, simply put, freedom for slave owners is not freedom. It is not conducive to freedom to give people the right to infringe on other people's freedom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269165882.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If someone is born with something they cannot select or choose, do they deserve to be punished as harshly as someone for whom it's 100% a choice?

It depends. Does this inborn trait deprive them entirely of free will? If the condition resembles something like duress or coercion, then perhaps you could make this case, but this is rare. The better analogy would be to alcoholism, not in the way anti-gay people bring it up which is usually to make homosexuality out to be some condition that will lead to misery, but in the sense that one still has choices to make. That one is born with a predisposition to alcoholism does not in any way absolve that person of, say, a conviction for a DUI. Likewise, a gay person could also be said to have a choice in their relationships and sexual encounters. The response to this shouldn't be to assert that we're born this way as though we're some helpless creatures that are deprived entirely of our free will. Rather, it is that the options that society pushes are often unsatisfying and harmful.

&amp;gt; Think about other legal protections

Okay, how about one from the First Amendment to the U.S Constitution: the free exercise [of religion] clause. People are not born Catholic, Episcopalian, or Baptist and yet they enjoy First Amendment protections on this front. This is because it is unimportant to us whether it is an inborn trait. While religious belief may not be completely arbitrarily chosen, given that you have to be convinced of certain claims, it is nevertheless a choice to persist in associating with this or that church or denomination -- and being rationally (or irrationally) convinced of certain beliefs is separate from being born with them. We recognize that while religious affiliation is not innate, it is still a deep and meaningful aspect of people's identity and makes inroads in various areas of their life. So too is the case with sexual orientation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269202039.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;It depends. Does this inborn trait deprive them entirely of free will? If the condition resembles something like duress or coercion, then perhaps you could make this case, but this is rare. The better analogy would be to alcoholism, not in the way anti-gay people bring it up which is usually to make homosexuality out to be some condition that will lead to misery, but in the sense that one still has choices to make. That one is born with a predisposition to alcoholism does not in any way absolve that person in, say, a conviction for a DUI. Likewise, a gay person could also be said to have a choice in their relationships and sexual encounters. The response to this shouldn't be that we're born this way as some helpless creature that we are deprived entirely of free will. Rather, it is that the options that society pushes are often unsatisfying and harmful.

Reddit in general has this weird relationship with determinism you put on display. We like to believe we determine everything about ourselves, but we really don't, and on that talking point alone. We are helpless creatures at the mercy of the functions of society and our own births and our environments and to say that we have 100% deterministic qualities is a farce. If you walk the line back far enough, there was a choice we made that wasn't in reality a  choice.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Okay, how about one from the First Amendment to the U.S Constitution: the free exercise [of religion] clause. People are not born Catholic, Episcopalian, or Baptist and yet they enjoy First Amendment protections on this front. This is because it is unimportant to us whether it is an inborn trait. While religious belief may not be completely arbitrarily chosen, given that you have to be convinced of certain claims, it is nevertheless a choice to persist in associating with this or that church or denomination -- and being rationally (or irrationally) convinced of certain beliefs is separate from being born with them. We recognize that while religious affiliation is not innate, it is still a deep and meaningful aspect of people's identity and makes inroads in various areas of their life. So too is the case with sexual orientation.

You are arguing for a law written over 200 years ago in a society built on piety. Do you know how many problems this particular protection causes relative to what it protects? This specific protection is not modern, and frankly ought to be evaluated. Setting that aside, as it relates to my first paragraph, you have to wonder how much of a choice religion is for some people in the first place. Imagine being indoctrinated your entire life with the threat of being removed from your home or never seeing your loved ones again because you don't share their values. That's not a choice that is a very dark social blackmail. 





</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269225075.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Reddit in general has this weird relationship with determinism you put on display.

I would hope that gay rights and a pursuit of our dignity is not contingent upon convincing the general population that determinism is true.

&amp;gt;Do you know how many problems this particular protection causes relative to what it protects?

Whether it does or it doesn't is quite irrelevant to my point which is that we have long recognized rights to be separate from inborn characteristics. There's also a difference between a law being antiquated and our modern interpretation of it. The Supreme Court does this all the time -- much to the chagrin of so-called Originalists. 

&amp;gt;Imagine being indoctrinated your entire life with the threat of being removed from your home or never seeing your loved ones again because you don't share their values. That's not a choice that is a very dark social blackmail.

I have no doubt that many (perhaps most?) religious folks are indoctrinated into the faith at an early age. What does this have to do with being "born this way?" I wasn't born knowing English. I learned it from a very early age (so early in fact, that I can't recall my first encounter with it). That I wasn't born with it does not change the fact that I can't unlearn it, absent some freak accident that makes me lose my memory.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
