<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29270421754.0" user="One_Winged_Rook" delta="False">
    <text>To point directly, your argument included Title VII, which of course is EEO based on protected classes.

If sexual orientation was included in the list of protected classes (which, judging from your reference to Title VII, I can only assume that's what you mean by LGBT rights, is to include it as a protected class), it would have the sole distinction among them as being something entirely by choice (if that is how you regarded sexual orientation).

I could see the argument for religion being a choice as well, but I can see it as not being one too (in this context, as you are often regarded as the religion of your parents regardless of your own view, while young. It also happens to be specifically listed as a freedom in the constitution, so maybe that would be a good argument to include it as well.)

So, in that way, if you were to somehow try to justify it to include it in the list of protected classes, you would need some additional justification (and a change to the laws thereof). However, if you regard it using the same justification as the rest of the protected classes (that it is not a choice), then no additional justification is needed.

Whichever the truth, it is simpler/beneficial from the legal perspective to regard it as not a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271775196.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>My reference was only to bring up Posner and his concurrence as an example of someone who is referencing the "born this way" argument. His concurrence included a broad defense of homosexuality, not merely a restricted application to Title VII. (He also included a jab at Scalia and Fox News, because that's how he rolls.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
