<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269192841.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>I want to change your view, but in the opposite direction than you probably expected. Not only is it not necessary to prove that gay people are "born this way", but it's actually detrimental. Not only does this argument imply (not logically, but in the casual sense of the word) that being gay is wrong, and that society should only tolerate it because we can't help it, but it also marginalizes individuals who claim to have chosen their sexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269199502.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you can't really change a view that I didn't hold in the first place. I pretty much already agreed with what you said prior to making this thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269204223.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, fair enough. From my perspective, saying something was "not necessary" didn't lead me to believe you would think it was detrimental.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270494721.0" user="almightySapling" delta="False">
    <text>Why on earth would you want your view changed? Why would you *desire* thinking that gay people only deserve rights if it could be proved that they had no choice but to be gay?

Please remember that CMV is *not* a debate forum or a soapbox.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271761490.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why would you desire thinking that gay people only deserve rights if it could be proved that they had no choice but to be gay?

Who said anything about only? And I want to see if it's necessary to proceed in this way because I honestly believe it's actually a hindrance to the cause and ultimately counterproductive.

&amp;gt;Please remember that CMV is not a debate forum or a soapbox.

Your insinuation isn't applicable here. I am coming in here with an open mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270086327.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>What? People who defend gay rights almost universally don't see anything wrong with being gay. They are forced to point out that it's natural *in response to* religious arguments that claim it is an unnatural conscious choice people make.

When someone is saying "just stop being gay, then we won't hurt you!", you kinda have to point out that people *can't* just stop being gay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270157690.0" user="hydrospanner" delta="False">
    <text>I think the point is that the better response would be, instead of arguing that it can't be helped, to point out that *it doesn't matter*. 

Arguing the point of whether it's a choice not only gives legitimacy to the notion that it's only okay because it can't be helped, but it also implicitly suggests that, for those who say they *did* chose to be gay, that not only is it not okay, but that the rights and protections that the gay community has fought to earn should somehow not apply to them.

I see it as a long term stumbling block in return for short term gains for the community, and I hope it doesn't come back to bite them in the ass. In essence, qualifying and limiting the scope of their movement to sidestep a moral objection from their opponents. The problem being that every time you sidestep, you're diverting your course...and it shows the opposition that your course can, in fact, be diverted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270179760.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying is that it's *not* the core argument of people who support gay rights. It's just the one they *have to use* against the most prevalent arguments against gay rights.

"These people choose to sin!"

"They can be gay if they want."

"Aha, you agree it's sin! They should burn!"

Vs:

"These people choose to sin!"

"Actually, they're not choosing anything. If you believe that God cares about this stuff, then why did he make them this way?"

"Uh, um..."

You believe that "they're born this way" is used as the core reason why gay rights should exist. It's *not*. It's just the argument that is currently needed against the people who are currently attacking gay rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270219114.0" user="TheVineyard00" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"These people choose to sin!"

&amp;gt;"It's not a sin!"

&amp;gt;"Uh, um..."

&amp;gt;Vs:

&amp;gt;"These people choose to sin!"

&amp;gt;"Actually, they're not choosing anything. If you believe that God cares about this stuff, then why did he make them this way?"

&amp;gt;"God works in mysterious ways!"

FTFY

They make two claims, he's arguing to counter the second one (it's a sin) while you're arguing to counter the first (it's a choice). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270244922.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>Hey, I'm not saying it's a simple argument to win. I'm just saying that people have been forced to argue about the natural, built-in occurrence of homosexuality *because* the opposition to gay rights has used "it's a choice" as the bedrock of their argument.

You have to fight the enemy where they are, not where it's most convenient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270645399.0" user="hydrospanner" delta="False">
    <text>In this case I just think you're wrong.

To change the perceived "sin", let's substitute "is gay" for "occasionally kills people", there's no rational person who would respond to "they killed some people!" with "*it's okay because* they're just wired to kill people".

Now there *may indeed* be people that'd suggest that maybe they do have a mental condition that has led them to kill people, but *nobody* would argue that, welp, that's just how they are, can't do anything about it, so we just live with it. 

Rather, the discussion then becomes one of "okay, so they are biologically/mentally/psychologically predisposed toward this behavior...what do we do about it?" It's a subtle but very important shift in the scope of the discussion because it comes with the implication of a consensus that, were it not for the agreed-upon conditional, that it wouldn't be okay (even if it's not stated outright).

So for our hypothetical murderer, we start to discuss whether they should be imprisoned, rehabilitated, confined, whether they're a risk to themselves or others...we're in agreement that we need to take possession of their personal agency since they have less/no control over it themselves, or that their agency is being used in a manner at odds with society.

Similarly, if you skip making it a point that homosexuality being hardwired or decided upon *makes no difference* you leave the door open to all sorts of "well then what are we, as a society, going to do to address this?" Since those who are anti-gay very much see a need to do something about it. 

You've implicitly told these people that their argument that being gay isn't okay, but the issue needs to be approached differently because it isn't a voluntary conscious decision.

I think that it's important for the community to pick their battlefield since they can't pick their battle, and that they not make concessions for the sake of winning a lesser argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270695611.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>That's a bad analogy because we can all agree that murdering people is bad, but not that homosexuality is bad. One is a clear pragmatic issue and the other relies on philosophy and worldview. That's why you can't address them in the same way.

&amp;gt; You've implicitly told these people that their argument that being gay isn't okay

That's preposterous.

"We can do whatever we want to the planet because it's only 6,000 years old so we should ignore everything scientists say."

Any argument against that that focuses on the resulting issues will be ignored because it is the person's philosophy that the planet is here for our exploitation and any threat we perceive is based on incorrect reasoning.

You can throw yourself against a wall a million times. As long as they have that belief, they'll be secure in their position and can deflect any argument you have about what we *should* do.

The only solution is to try to get them to understand the scientific method and realize their premise is wrong. That is the only way there is hope.

Likewise, you can argue moral positions on homosexuality for ages, but if a person's position comes from "the bible says so", you're going to make zero progress. Because you're arguing against an authority that will always be favored above you when it comes to moral reasoning, to that person.

The only way to change the view is to work around it, to unseat it in a way that involves demonstrable facts and mechanisms, rather than mere philosophical argument. Because they're already solidly in a camp for that one.

So if their unassailable *moral* argument rests upon a *factual* premise that you can disprove, suddenly you've got a way in. It's your trench run. Blow it up from the inside.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271213030.0" user="hydrospanner" delta="False">
    <text>You clearly don't understand analogy, and are incapable of (or unwilling to entertain the thought of) considering anything that doesn't already fit your narrative, so I'll leave you to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271237609.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I tried. But I guess you'd rather not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270314673.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>I know that people who defend gay rights don't believe that "being gay is only ok because we can't help it". But that's what the implication is. The correct response to "just stop being gay, then we won't hurt you!" is "you shouldn't be hurting people either way".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270322235.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know how much clearer I can make this. We *know it's wrong anyway*. The point is that that's not the debate the opposition is having. You have to counteract the points they're actually making, not the more basic ones you'd wish they were making because it lets you establish your position better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270348173.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>The opposition is making two points in their argument:

1. Being gay is a choice  
2. If being gay is a choice, then it's ok to hurt gay people

My point is that it is the second point which is the one that matters, not the first. The second point is the morally outrageous position; the first is just some statement which may or may not be entirely false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270358828.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but you're not going to make progress on the latter when dealing with religious hatred. So if you can convince them that their *premise* is flawed, that's more likely than them giving up their tightly held religious convictions about what is right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270374324.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>Sure it may be a harder argument, but convincing people that there's nothing wrong with being gay is the goal. Otherwise, you have a bunch of people thinking being gay is wrong, and while we shouldn't hurt gay people, we should ban them from doing gay actions, which are a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270404723.0" user="arcosapphire" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you have to fight then where they are.

If someone says "I can't support gay people because it's unnatural, I can't agree with that choice", you can't just say "being gay is fine!" It doesn't address their argument. It's just a different opinion that they'll ignore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270294345.0" user="SoMuchMoreEagle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it also marginalizes individuals who claim to have chosen their sexuality

I have heard of people who have claimed to have somehow rid themselves of their gayness, but never heard of someone who said they chose to be gay.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270333894.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>There is a thing called political lesbianism, where a lot of women chose to be lesbian as a political statement, for example. Now I'm sure a lot of people would say they aren't "true" lesbians, but I'd rather take them at their word rather than try to dictate what they feel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270304157.0" user="_manoftheyear_" delta="False">
    <text>I hold the same opinion. You should be free to choose your sexuality without the feeling of harm or discrimination from the government. Whether you were born that way or not, gay rights can and should exist separate from the "born this way" argument. Arguing you were born this way sort of creates your own unnecessary straw man for the other person to attack. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270392913.0" user="porkchop_d_clown" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. I'm old enough to remember when gay people pushed the idea that it was a "lifestyle choice" in response to people claiming they were genetically defective. When they flip-flopped to saying "we were born this way" I was utterly bewildered.

My personal belief has always been that you don't see very many binary choices in nature - everything is always a spectrum. You might be closer to one end of that spectrum or to the other, but it's still a continuous gradient, not a yes/no check box.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
