<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269486247.0" user="withmymindsheruns" delta="False">
    <text>It's necessary because otherwise you have to prove that homosexuality is inherently positive/beneficial to justify actively conditioning society to have a positive view of it (through gay marriage laws etc.). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269494202.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't people have to do that anyway? The fact that someone is, say, born a psychopath doesn't make it obvious for the rest of us to just accept it. Much of our endeavor as a society is often to rise above our instincts and nature and "civilize" ourselves. This doesn't have to be done always.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269504327.0" user="withmymindsheruns" delta="False">
    <text>Your psychopath example is obvious in a liberal society though. They breach the fundamental rationale of 'don't hurt others'. Even so, the 'born this way' part of it slightly mitigates the judgement we have of the way the psychopath impacts others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269513016.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Your psychopath example is obvious in a liberal society though. They breach the fundamental rationale of 'don't hurt others'.

Well, often people who are anti-gay aren't just that way because they have some visceral revulsion to it. They often make the argument that it's bad for society, etc. My point is that you'd have to tackle this whether or not "born this way" is true.

&amp;gt;Even so, the 'born this way' part of it slightly mitigates the judgement we have of the way the psychopath impacts others.

It might make us be less antagonistic, but we'd still want to lock them up (at least those who follow through and kill someone). On the flip side, people who are often sexually abused end up abusing others. Does this mitigate our judgment? Probably not. Should it? Maybe, I don't know. They certainly weren't "born" abused, but I feel it can be a similar issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269547047.0" user="withmymindsheruns" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree about the sexual abuse one, from what I see it does seem to mitigate judgement, the same with addiction, as with the 'born like that' causation, it's all the same, the person isn't (as) culpable for the act. Even the criminal system operates on this basis, two materially similar crimes will be treated differently according to intent.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
