<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269591717.0" user="zornathan" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say that your position is based on a fallacy.  There is no such thing as gay rights.  You deserve no special rights because you are gay.

Everyone deserves the same basic rights of free association, making contracts (or marrying) with others, and freedom from spying and prying into their personal affairs.  This should be independent of gender.

In effect, It's nobody's business if you prefer men or women, as someone of relatively sound mind can choose to do whatever they want as long as they don't directly harm others.  It shouldn't matter if this is a personal choice or if you were born this way.  That is irrelevant as far as your rights are concerned.

Long story short, I believe you're approaching this from the wrong avenue.  I'd agree there's no need to prove gay people are born that way, but not because of the technical/biological arguments you allude to, but because it should not matter when determining someone's day to day life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269740926.0" user="Revengecertainly" delta="False">
    <text>It's semantics, but there are definitely gay rights, as those rights were previously denied and only applied to gay people. Gay rights aren't special rights and no one who ever advocates claimed they were, they are equal rights but still rights that apply to gay people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269860591.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>Who said anything about special rights?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
