<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269832163.0" user="Hint227" delta="False">
    <text>Essentially, determining whether gay people are born gay or become gay because of external reasons serves two purposes:

* 1: If it isn't caused by external forces, and happens during conception/pregnancy, we can't avoid it, and therefore we can't treat it. If it truly is innate, we can't force someone to go to therapy for it. 

* 2: If it isn't innate, then we must determine what external forces or patterns cause someone to be gay, and what actions, if any, should be taken to avoid it happening. Like, if it's nurture, corn syrup, or exposure to the moon, if we know what it is, we can take measures about it, or actively not.

DISCLAIMER: I'm not saying gays are sick and need treatment, what I'm saying is that if it isn't innate, we can't stop someone who wants to be treated to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271813666.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>This hasn't stopped people from responding that while gays may be born that way, just as we don't use an excuse for psychopaths that their condition is innate as a way of absolving their responsibility in murdering others, so too is it the case that gays can be held accountable for their choices (which are often framed moralistically). It doesn't solve the problem people think it does and it wastes time by entertaining their non sequitur arguments. The question should be, how is the claim "it's a choice" relevant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271866578.0" user="Hint227" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; just as we don't use an excuse for psychopaths that their condition is innate as a way of absolving their responsibility in murdering others

The obvious: psychopathy =/= homossexuality. A murderer choosing to kill and a man choosing to kiss another man isn't the same.

&amp;gt; The question should be, how is the claim "it's a choice" relevant?

If it's a choice, and you want to treat it so as you can not choose it anymore, you can. 

If it isn't a choice, and you want to treat it so as to accept your life and future with that genetic code, you can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271897890.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The obvious: psychopathy =/= homossexuality. A murderer choosing to kill and a man choosing to kiss another man isn't the same.

You seem to be misunderstanding how analogies work. Analogies are not meant to compare two or more things as though they're similar in every respect. Otherwise they wouldn't be analogies; they'd be identities. They're meant to compare two or more things that are similar in some relevant respect(s). Here I wasn't making the claim that homosexuality is just like psychopathy. Rather, it is that psychopathy can be illustrative of the flaw in the argument that the "born this way" claim can absolve someone of moral responsibility. We would, of course, not say that simply because someone is born psychopathic that this absolves the person from any moral responsibility, such as if he or she were to kill someone. 

&amp;gt;If it's a choice, and you want to treat it so as you can not choose it anymore, you can.
If it isn't a choice, and you want to treat it so as to accept your life and future with that genetic code, you can.

No, that doesn't follow at all. Now you're making the assumption that all choices can be treated as though they're some condition. But it's also irrelevant because suppose you could choose otherwise. So what? Any religious person could theoretically choose a different religion. People could theoretically choose not to raise their biological children. People could choose a lot of things. That doesn't mean that said choice isn't deep, important and immutable. None of these three characteristics depend on whether it's a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272458528.0" user="Hint227" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You seem to be misunderstanding how analogies work

I said it more as a disclaimer than a counterpoint. I understood what you meant.

&amp;gt; Now you're making the assumption that all choices can be treated as though they're some condition.

You could, theoretically, make someone *choose* to do/say/be whatever you wanted them to. If it's a *choice*, it's not immutable, because it's something you actively (or unconciously) favor partaking into. If it is indeed a choice, and there is a homossexual man somewhere that wants to *not choose to be gay anymore*, it would be terribly immoral of us not to give him the chance to treat himself, if he so desires. Not that being gay *needs* treatment, but if someone *wants* to be treated, who am I to deny it?

Same way the opposite. If it *isn't a choice*, and a gay man wants treatment, not to *change*, but to *accept*, we must comply, and make sure he has a life that's happy and meaningful, to the best of his capacities, without being impaired by something he sees as bad, but that actually can be quite good if he just switches his view.

TL;DR: Knowing if it's born or chosen changes the psychological treatment offered to those who want to be treated.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29274978753.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If it's a choice, it's not immutable, because it's something you actively (or unconciously) favor partaking into.

Fixating on this is misdirected. How we came to have our orientation is a different question from whether we can change it. Sexual orientation in most males seems relatively fixed from an early age (which doesn't necessarily mean "birth"). For women, it's somewhat more fluid but not arbitrarily so. Whether or not we are "born this way," most of us are going to stay this way. Moreover, whether or not I can change doesn't address whether I should, anyway. I can, after all, convert to being a part of the alt-right, but I shouldn't and won't. My position is that we should emphasize that there isn't anything wrong with us. Focusing on this distracts us from that important message and plays into their fallacious thinking. 

As a minor note, it's also a false dichotomy to insist that the options are either that homosexuality is choice or an inborn trait. In some cases it could be neither. The truth of the matter is that we don't have a fully developed understanding of sexual orientation and, because of this, it is entirely possibly that even when empirically finding a genetic component to homosexuality, it doesn't follow that this is the only way someone could end up being gay. After all, a discovery that diabetes has a genetic origin and that many people develop it entirely due to genetics doesn't foreclose on the possibility that others could develop it through external factors like their diet. It's at least a possibility that homosexuality could operate this way wherein some are genetically born gay while others were influenced by their environment. Harping on the "born this way" dogma in such a case would backfire and leave us vulnerable, ultimately having to argue what I've been arguing in the first place, which is that it was a fact that had no relevance to begin. It has no relevance in terms of whether our orientation is deep, immortant and immutable nor any relevance as to whether we should afford dignity to others or recognize rights others should enjoy.

&amp;gt;If it isn't a choice, and a gay man wants treatment, not to change, but to accept, we must comply

I think this line of reasoning comes from not having actual experience engaging with people who have made this argument. I have. I can tell you from personal experience it matters little. This is because there is often a fundamental misunderstanding about what they mean when they say "it's a choice." See, when we say we're born this way, we are coming at the issue by first (correctly) defining homosexuality as an orientation. By contrast, they are often beginning with an odd definition of homosexuality focusing on the behavioral aspects of it. They're reducing homosexuality to the choices one does indeed make -- homosexuality does, after all, involve making choices, such as who to marry or have sex with. When we do manage to convince people that we are "born this way" as to our orientation, this doesn't really satisfy them because they feel that their claim isn't being addressed head on. This is why they often draw the analogy to alcoholism wherein they concede there is a genetic predisposition but this doesn't morally absolve the person of making the decision not to pick up the bottle. Your emphasis on homosexuals leading happy and meaningful lives is effort best spent rather than entertaining their non sequiturs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29275279618.0" user="Hint227" delta="False">
    <text>Full on wall of text mode, man. I'm at work right now, will answer later.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272269316.0" user="alfredo094" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; we can't avoid it, and therefore we can't treat it. If it truly is innate, we can't force someone to go to therapy for it.
&amp;gt; 

Schizophrenics always had a "chip" that could get triggered. We can reduce its probabilities of happening even if you had the "chip", but that doesn't mean there isn't a degree of innateness in it or that we shouldn't make everything to stop it.

IMO it's condescending to say that it's innate and therefore accept it, it's like saying "well, they can't help it, might as well", making the implication that it isn't desirable at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272463678.0" user="Hint227" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "well, they can't help it, might as well", making the implication that it isn't desirable at all.

This next sentence might surprise you:

Not everyone wants to be gay.

(Gasps! Shouts! Angry mobs throwing tomatoes!)

Some people, for religious reasons, or for sociological ones, or because they don't like to like what they like (what?), already want to change. Tune into the latest church talk-show and the likelihood of a "former gay" appearing is biiiig. I'm not trying to imply it isn't desirable (IMO as a man, a woman is the most desirable being on Earth, but if you like men, mate, go for it), I'm just saying that if you **want to**, we can help you either treat it, or cope with it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
