<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269336489.0" user="WarrenDemocrat" delta="False">
    <text>Tactically speaking, the presentation of homosexuality as an involuntary condition is crucial to neutralizing homophobia in the Christian community, which being 70% of the US and a characterizing force of western civilization, is valuable to advancing LGBT rights. 

If orientation is successfully presented as involuntary, it works to torpedo the narrative of it being a freely committed sin like that of Adam and Eve. They could go on the back foot and call it a mental illness, but at this point even zealous homophobes are hesitant to be seen as advocating conversion therapy.

It also distinguishes it from the homosexuality that LGBT affirming Christians claim homophobic verses in the Bible are really referring to: totally voluntary and perverted acts of homosexuality as part of pagan rituals and/or classical pederasty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269407771.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Tactically speaking, the presentation of homosexuality as an involuntary condition

Well it isn't a condition, for one. For another, it's involuntariness isn't as important as it's mutability. Whether or not we're born this way, most of us are going to stay this way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29269499794.0" user="WarrenDemocrat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well it isn't a condition, for one.

i don't mean medical condition, just "the circumstances affecting the way in which people live or work", but point taken.

&amp;gt;For another, it's involuntariness isn't as important as it's mutability. Whether or not we're born this way, most of us are going to stay this way.

what difference does that make to my case? are you making a distinction between the two, ceding that mutability is an important factor but whether the person was LGBT when they were born is not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270016164.0" user="TanithArmoured" delta="False">
    <text>The point is it's incredibly valuable to the movement as it gives the Christian majority a way to think about and accept it (because God made them that way in their eyes) instead of it being a purposeful sin. 

For this reason it has done a great deal to advance the movement, because of that idea didn't exist we would see a lot more institutional attempts to 'fix' these people because it would only be by their choice eg pray away the gay or conversion therapy. Once they claimed it to be an inborn trait it gains a certain amount of defensibility because otherwise the choice is seen as sin much like Eve eating the apple in Christians eyes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270069081.0" user="Open_Eye_Signal" delta="False">
    <text>Try reading the comment next time. He's not arguing that homosexuality truly is a "condition", but that framing it as a "condition" legally has helped to further the movement more than framing it as a choice would have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271805651.0" user="poolerboy0077" delta="False">
    <text>It's still irrelevant. Many people, for instance, frame homosexuality as a sin and use this to bolster their position that we should not give rights or dignity to homosexuals. Many go through great pains to try to prove that it isn't a sin. Is this really how we should be spending our time -- to answer their irrelevancies? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270080298.0" user="theblackraven996" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really understand why it would affect the way christians view it when it is explicitly stated that homosexual relations are a sin, the same way having sex with someone who is not your wife is.  It is a commandment for men to only have relations with their wives, for example.  Does that mean christians should accept heterosexuals sleeping with other women just because they were born that way and have the desire to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270150118.0" user="WarrenDemocrat" delta="False">
    <text>It's the view of most mainliners and some catholic dissenters that homosexuality as a monogamous practice was absent from the societies in which the scripture was written, that the homosexuals Moses and Paul condemned were doing something wrong apart from homosexuality, such as engaging in it as a ritual for Moloch (in the case of Leviticus), rape (in the case of Sodom), spontaneous orgies and pederasty (in the case of the Pauline epistles). Christians see heterosexual attraction as natural but the act of adultery and prolonged entertainment of adulterous thoughts as a voluntary sins.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
