<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="372786470.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/65y3vq/cmv_kids_today_are_losing_the_ability_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Kids today are losing the ability to express themselves effectively</title>
    <original_poster>rewdd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Since writing is an important tool of communication it is important to learn the process without the help of paraphrasing from the writings of others and arriving at ideas naturally. most kids don't write using their own ideas, they search the internet and arrange the writings of other people into an essay. The effect of this method of writing papers is harmful because if they don't arrive at ideas naturally and write them in their own words they will not be able to write or know proper grammar without the help of technology. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29290562457.0" user="eydryan" delta="False">
    <text>Human achievement is a result of adaptation of previous knowledge. We build on the foundation laid by the ones before us. Therefore, it is generally more useful to know how to mix and remix what we have than it is to explore new territory without any guarantee of success. 

Effectively, both things are useful, and what is lost by not having kids write things themselves is not that important. Grammar, and the language itself, is fluid and ever changing, which is why lol and googling are in the dictionary, and it will belong to the future generations. 

You mention the use of technology. Why not rely on it? Do you expect the spellchecker will become banned or something? Or, to make a parallel, do you think we should all learn cartography just in case Google Maps no longer works? There are many redundant solutions and the integration of technology into the process allows us to focus less on details like grammar and calligraphy and more on the message we want to send.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
