<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="372786470.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/65y3vq/cmv_kids_today_are_losing_the_ability_to_express/">
    <title>CMV: Kids today are losing the ability to express themselves effectively</title>
    <original_poster>rewdd</original_poster>
    <original_post>Since writing is an important tool of communication it is important to learn the process without the help of paraphrasing from the writings of others and arriving at ideas naturally. most kids don't write using their own ideas, they search the internet and arrange the writings of other people into an essay. The effect of this method of writing papers is harmful because if they don't arrive at ideas naturally and write them in their own words they will not be able to write or know proper grammar without the help of technology. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29289509242.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>Give me a time frame. 

A majority of kids were illiterate in the 1920s. 

Sputnik and forward white males had the best time. It started to look up for minorities by the end of the '70s. 

But literacy rates have been stagnant for many groups. 

But you need to give a grade level. Literacy rates are set to the 8th grade. 

Also, what is the threshold for 'effectively'. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289525805.0" user="rewdd" delta="False">
    <text>By effectively I mean, being able to express thoughts without having to resort to slang. The issue I come across when talking to younger people is that they use slang words constantly, making it hard to understand the points they are trying to deliver. When I ask them to elaborate on their statement they sort of just give up mid sentence, and some don't even try, saying "forget about it". It's something I've noticed more recently so I would say the time period  of the last 10 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289541610.0" user="renoops" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; By effectively I mean, being able to express thoughts without having to resort to slang.

There's nothing at all ineffective about slang (at least not any more than any other word or phrase—plus, people of all ages have been using slang forever). 

&amp;gt;The issue I come across when talking to younger people is that they use slang words constantly, making it hard to understand the points they are trying to deliver.

Why is this their shortcoming, and not yours?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289558486.0" user="rewdd" delta="False">
    <text>There's nothing at all ineffective about slang (at least not any more than any other word or phrase—plus, people of all ages have been using slang forever).

I think it's important to to have the ability to speak English in a way most people can understand, and if you have to rely on slang to communicate it limits the amount of people you can have a productive exchange of ideas with. 
Why is this their shortcoming, and not yours?

Slang is certainly effective between groups of people that understand it, however no person can be expected to learn the colloquialisms of every region or subculture. Therefore, it is important to be able to communicate ideas without the use of slang.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289560686.0" user="rewdd" delta="False">
    <text>also how do I quote someone so my responses are more legible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289574665.0" user="renoops" delta="False">
    <text>To format them as block quotes, put a greater-than symbol in front of what you're quoting, then press enter/return twice to begin a new paragraph and end formatting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289979412.0" user="rewdd" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To format them as block quotes, put a greater-than symbol in front of what you're quoting, then press enter/return twice to begin a new paragraph and end formatting. 

Like this? Edit: ah ok ty!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29289776276.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>Slang in writing or speech. Because we use informal language by default. 

Educational studies show that students do better if the write - speak</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
