<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="376661722.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68961m/cmvfreedom_of_speech_should_not_be_limited/">
    <title>CMV:Freedom of speech should not be limited</title>
    <original_poster>shad0w-fax</original_poster>
    <original_post>I strongly believe that freedom of speech and expression must have no limits. Even in case if the speech is offensive to people. One can choose not to listen but not to take away my right to say it. Before someone suggest the "fire in a theatre",I recently came across with this speech of Christopher Hitchens and would recommend you to watch it (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Z2uzEM0ugY)
One big question is-who will be the one deciding that what is and isn't right to say? Who would you give authority to decide for you what is and isn't right to think and say?
Obviously, it is not an ideal case. Of course the best way is to have a perfect individual to make these decisions but, have we not seen that at last it always ends badly. That kind of authority would be tyrannical.
I would like to give analogy of democracy being imperfect as compared to a benevolent dictator BUT we know dictatorship always end badly. No one person should be given so much power. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29320806728.0" user="77mx77" delta="False">
    <text>Personally I think the best argument in favour of restricting freedom of speech is the same argument used to restrict other behaviours. I think most people agree that you should be able to do whatever you want as long as it doesn't significantly affect other people in a negative way, so while I think political speech should be free, if you insult other people/incite hatred etc to such an extent that it causes harm to someone then it doesn't seem unreasonable to limit that sort of speech. I think the idea that someone can choose not to listen only applies in a minority of scenarios so I don't think it's fair to place that burden on someone just trying to go about their business.

And I would argue that the loose restrictions place on free speech in the US are in many ways worse than those in the UK. From what I've seen they give the people the right to insult and harass other people, but doesn't protect their political speech when it matters. For example, when you look at the situation during the cold war there were many people being arrested for their political views, but relatively little is done about the KKK. It just seems like the worse of both worlds. The fact that the government could just shut down opposing political views in this way just goes to show how little legislation means, and I don't think its realistic to think that completely free speech will prevent an authoritarian regime sprouting up. Resistance needs to come from people voting for what they want and being politically active, which is also relevant to one of your points because you say that one person will be in charge, but in theory, as a democratic society, surely we are all in charge of what is and isn't acceptable? In the same way that racists etc are excluded socially and occasionally fired from their jobs, legislation supported by the majority is surely just a more direct and efficient way of discouraging this behaviour?

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
