<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="376661722.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68961m/cmvfreedom_of_speech_should_not_be_limited/">
    <title>CMV:Freedom of speech should not be limited</title>
    <original_poster>shad0w-fax</original_poster>
    <original_post>I strongly believe that freedom of speech and expression must have no limits. Even in case if the speech is offensive to people. One can choose not to listen but not to take away my right to say it. Before someone suggest the "fire in a theatre",I recently came across with this speech of Christopher Hitchens and would recommend you to watch it (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Z2uzEM0ugY)
One big question is-who will be the one deciding that what is and isn't right to say? Who would you give authority to decide for you what is and isn't right to think and say?
Obviously, it is not an ideal case. Of course the best way is to have a perfect individual to make these decisions but, have we not seen that at last it always ends badly. That kind of authority would be tyrannical.
I would like to give analogy of democracy being imperfect as compared to a benevolent dictator BUT we know dictatorship always end badly. No one person should be given so much power. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29320727555.0" user="fullchorter" delta="False">
    <text>What about child porn? That technically falls under free expression so are you advocating for it to become legal? The first amendment is not the end all be all of law and sometimes it conflicts with other areas of law such as in my example child endangerment or in other examples  the incitation of violence. While ideally you would be right we do not live in a world that allows for total free speech.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
