<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="376661722.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68961m/cmvfreedom_of_speech_should_not_be_limited/">
    <title>CMV:Freedom of speech should not be limited</title>
    <original_poster>shad0w-fax</original_poster>
    <original_post>I strongly believe that freedom of speech and expression must have no limits. Even in case if the speech is offensive to people. One can choose not to listen but not to take away my right to say it. Before someone suggest the "fire in a theatre",I recently came across with this speech of Christopher Hitchens and would recommend you to watch it (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Z2uzEM0ugY)
One big question is-who will be the one deciding that what is and isn't right to say? Who would you give authority to decide for you what is and isn't right to think and say?
Obviously, it is not an ideal case. Of course the best way is to have a perfect individual to make these decisions but, have we not seen that at last it always ends badly. That kind of authority would be tyrannical.
I would like to give analogy of democracy being imperfect as compared to a benevolent dictator BUT we know dictatorship always end badly. No one person should be given so much power. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29320486207.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>What about a speaker telling listeners to engage in violence. Anything from 'kill all jews' to a private 'it would be better for us if John were dead' are technically speech. Should it be protected?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320524416.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>I dont think banning this kind of speech will somehow protect people from the one who are incited against them,on the contrary listening and debating it openly is more helpful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320547783.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>You are advocating for what is essentially contract killing. Notice I had two examples. One of them was quite blatantly asking another person to kill someone. Are you really okay with not punishing that person?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320578738.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>Banning such ideas only drives the thoughts underground, not away. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320610558.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstand me. I'm saying that the type of free speech you are advocating for legalizes hiring a hitman to kill someone. Your response is that banning that only drives the thoughts underground? You think we should legalize it?

If that is your ultimate response, then I seriously wonder whether you think anything is wrong with murder. If you think murder is wrong, but hiring/asking/ordering someone to commit murder is right, where is the punishment for the person inciting the murder? Is there one? If not, do we just allow people to hire hitmen indiscriminately? Clearly this would allow a rich person of low morals to just kill whoever stands in his way without legal repercussions. I just see so many issues with your stance if murder is still illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320627044.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>I must concede that the limits are needed on speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320636255.0" user="nathan98000" delta="False">
    <text>This seems like it should be a delta...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320737519.0" user="consummate_erection" delta="False">
    <text>I think murder is wrong, but asking somebody else to commit murder is just words. If the murder is actually committed then the person who asked should face conspiracy charges, but in the event nothing happens I don't believe either of those incitements should be considered illegal a priori.

i.e. talking to my friends about how I'm planning to kill a certain high-ranking member of the U.S. government shouldn't be illegal. I just have a dark sense of humor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320803880.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>While I understand the idea behind not punishing individuals until they commit crimes, there has to be a point at which law enforcement can step in. According to [this](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/1117), one of the conspirators must commit an overt act for it to be considered conspiracy (NOTE: this is federal law, state laws may differ). I'm not familiar with the application of this law, but I would guess that merely discussing it in private is not illegal. However, I would think something like buying a gun or paying the hitman could fall under the overt act. You seem to think we have to wait for the conspirators to commit the murder to arrest them. I think that's too late.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29329540042.0" user="consummate_erection" delta="False">
    <text>No, I think that the overt act definition is pretty reasonable. It gets to the heart of my concern: words are just words and nobody should have the power to curtail them. If there exists other evidence beyond people just talking about it then that's something else entirely.

It gets a bit messier when words lead directly to a crime, for example in the case of somebody asking somebody else to commit murder and then the murder occurs. Say the only evidence we have is a recording of this request and no evidence of an overt act. In this case I think it should fall to the court to examine extenuating circumstances such as leverage and status and determine whether the instigator should be held responsible. But only after the fact. Basically I submit that no wrongdoing has taken place until the crime that was verbally instigated transpired. At this point both the criminal and the instigator become liable, whether they were joking or performing satire or whatever. I guess that's all covered by the statute though.

But because nearly any sentence can be said sarcastically, it just infringes on people's rights too much to curtail any form of speech beyond maybe racial slurs and other language who's primary purpose is to degrade. But even then I don't support this because it ends up creating different rights for different races or classes of people (think of the n-word used innocently by working class black people), which is bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29321934996.0" user="princessbynature" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm saying that the type of free speech you are advocating for legalizes hiring a hitman to kill someone

No it doesn't.  The act of hiring a hitman is not an example of speech - it is an act of hiring someone to do something.  Saying, "I wish John were dead" is not the same thing as hiring someone to kill someone else.  Just like telling someone you hope they get fucked is not the same thing as fucking them.  Speech and action are not the same thing.  And we have laws against inciting violence and against fighting words and threats already.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320611052.0" user="DocCannery84" delta="False">
    <text>So, as /u/Znyper has intimated, you have no issue with conspiracy to murder, as it is only speech, not action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320862222.0" user="elbeanodeldino" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain where exactly shad0w-fax advocates this? Seems like a bit of a leap there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320997307.0" user="stratys3" delta="False">
    <text>That's already a crime, outside of speech laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29321027949.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>If you read the replies of OP, he does (or rather did) believe that this sort of speech should be protected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29322766768.0" user="InfinitelyThirsting" delta="False">
    <text>How is it more helpful? Violence against oppressed minorities has always gone down after people started calling out hate speech and shaming it out of use. You don't think that leaders have ever incited violence that would not have otherwise occurred? The Stanford Prison Experiment, flawed though it may be, shows that at least some people are very susceptible to authoritative pressure and will do terrible things to other humans just because they were told to.

So yes, while too many limits on freedom of speech can absolutely be misused by a government, and you need a vigilant legal system to keep it in check, there still should be some legal repercussions for *inciting violence* with speech (with a trial to help distinguish between someone's empty hyperbole and someone actually trying to incite violence). 

And there certainly can be plenty of social ways to get that hate out of the air. Which matters. You worry about what happens when it gets driven underground, but why? There was a burst of hate crimes after the election because people thought it would be okay to not hide their hate anymore--violence that only happened because talking about things makes people more likely to think it's okay. In a positive example, how there are "more" gay people now because it's not seen as something shameful to be afraid of. Millenials are twice as likely to identify as LGBT than previous generations. Obviously there are no objective standards for what is good or bad, but most people would agree that hatred is bad. Do you really think the world has just coincidentally become less racist, and that most people consider black people to be humans instead of property just out of nowhere? You don't think the fact that they aren't being taught blatant racism everyday matters?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
