<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="376661722.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68961m/cmvfreedom_of_speech_should_not_be_limited/">
    <title>CMV:Freedom of speech should not be limited</title>
    <original_poster>shad0w-fax</original_poster>
    <original_post>I strongly believe that freedom of speech and expression must have no limits. Even in case if the speech is offensive to people. One can choose not to listen but not to take away my right to say it. Before someone suggest the "fire in a theatre",I recently came across with this speech of Christopher Hitchens and would recommend you to watch it (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Z2uzEM0ugY)
One big question is-who will be the one deciding that what is and isn't right to say? Who would you give authority to decide for you what is and isn't right to think and say?
Obviously, it is not an ideal case. Of course the best way is to have a perfect individual to make these decisions but, have we not seen that at last it always ends badly. That kind of authority would be tyrannical.
I would like to give analogy of democracy being imperfect as compared to a benevolent dictator BUT we know dictatorship always end badly. No one person should be given so much power. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29320460597.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Before someone suggest the "fire in a theatre",I recently came across with this speech of Christopher Hitchens and would recommend you to watch it

Its a 21 minute video - no one is going to watch it.  Could you summarize the point you agree with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320477744.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>It asks the question that who would you give the authority to decide citing different examples of incompetence of the person in power to make right decisions. Suggesting that it's a slippery slope. The fire in a theatre case was given by a judge in case when there was indeed a big fire and he sent to prison those who were shouting,showing that at the other end we have a tyrannical censorship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320492907.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>You are talking about extremes - the extremes should not be the rule for all situations.  Eliminating freedom of speech would allow one situation that should be allowed for every 100 situations that should not be allowed.  It is obviously more beneficial to society to not allow total freedom of speech.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320512804.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>As soon as we try to limit freedom of speech and banning some form of it,the power to do it will always be abused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320527110.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>But you can equally say that once there is no limit on freedom of speech the power will always be abused.  (e.g. You then have 100s of people yelling fire in a crowded theater)

There are more people/situations who will abuse total freedom of speech than powers who will abuse limits on speech so it is better for society to not have total freedom of speech.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320631884.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>I think i need to research and spend more time on this topic,but i do believe very strongly that main source of hatred is also the main caller for censorship</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29321065173.0" user="Shino_Ayashi" delta="False">
    <text>From what standpoint are you saying this from? That the *real* oppressors are not the alt-right, but actually the Jews and the liberals for *daring* to infringe on the rights of the alt-right's freedom of speech? That the real hatred doesn't come from Neonazis, but the people of color who voice opinions of dissent against them? The refusal of the general public to give neonazis a public platform? I don't understand how hate speech would ever be considered productive, especially since it brings harm to minorities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29321928898.0" user="princessbynature" delta="False">
    <text>You can't possibly believe that the "alt-right" are oppressing anyone.  Please tell me who is being oppressed by the alt-right.  It was Richard Spencer, the supposed founder of the alt-right, who was sucker punched and I have yet to find anyone to provide any example of Spencer doing anything remotely close to assaulting anyone.  And yeah, liberal are absolutely trying to silence Spencer, literally infringing on his rights of speech.  Anne Coulter was silence by violent leftists at Berkeley as was Milo Yionoppolis.  

Hatred can come from anyone - why would you think otherwise?  Just as there are white supremicists who hate black people there are black people who hate white people.  Hatred doesn't have a political ideology.

Speech doesn't harm anyone.  Hate speech is a vague term that could apply to just about anything that anyone finds to be offensive but offense is not the same thing as physical harm.  We live in a society that allows for holding someone accountable if they cause physical harm to a person or their property.  Words cannot hurt you and if you think that offense is the same thing as harm I would recommend watching that Hitchens video - when you find yourself in the moral majority it may seem to be a good idea to put limits on speech - but the moral majority changes and you will find yourself at some point holding a minority opinion that others will want to suppress and allowing for limits on speech now against those who disagree with you will come back to bite you in the ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29320529106.0" user="DirtCrystal" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The fire in a theatre case was given by a judge in case when there was indeed a big fire 

I think this is mostly irrelevant to the point, because there are indeed "procured alarm" issues, and false advertisement, and vilifying, and verbal contracts. Now, i think these are issues that fall into legitimate limitation of what you can say.
Would you **not** restrict speech during a lecture or conference, so that a single person could legitimately destroy an entire event?

Is a fine balance, not a slippery slope, a society of rules is made of many such balances between personal freedoms and collective good.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
