<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="377703481.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68vhvd/cmvstalin_was_a_bad_leader/">
    <title>CMV:Stalin was a bad leader</title>
    <original_poster>BRINGITSISTA</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I have recently become a communist, or more specific a marxist leninist. But that is not what you will be changing today.

I hear many leftists and communists proclaim that Stalin was actually a really good leader and his negatives are exaggerated or fake....

Despite this, I still seem to have a somewhat negative view of Stalin

Yes, my image of Stalin has been improved by some communists I have encountered, but int quite there yet...

Instead of small one liners, I would like someone to write me a good, well rounded summary of why I should like Stalin

I know this might be controversial, so lets keep it to just communists and pro-Stalin people to answer this one...

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29328838721.0" user="Best_Pants" delta="False">
    <text>Stalin defeated Hitler.  We all like to think that it was America who beat Germany, but the vast majority of the work was done by Russia.  Operation Barbarossa was the largest invasion in human history; carried out by a skilled and technologically advanced military that was then undefeated on the field.  Stalin's sweeping, swift, and extreme measures to modernize and galvanize the Russian Army and throw the entirety of Russian economic capacity against the Wehrmacht were unprecedented and ultimately successful.  Stalin did not simply hold off the juggernaut; he completely turned the tables.

Now, that doesn't necessarily mean you should become a fan, but he definitely had the qualities of a leader.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29328885195.0" user="BRINGITSISTA" delta="False">
    <text>I referring more or less to the politics of Stalin, not his war victory.... Though you do bring up a great point where people mistakenly think USA tool out Germany which annoys me so much lmao</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29328949091.0" user="Sand_Trout" delta="False">
    <text>Part of the reason the Red Army got their shit pushed in early on is largely credited to the purges Stalin conducted of the upper echelons of the soviet military, leaving the officer corps lacking in competent leaders, so the the *need* to rapidly unfuck the army was directly attributable to Stalin's leadership. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29329022497.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>I'm surprised you didn't mention the British contribution. I think most of us are aware America joined the war at the last second to help with a final push that would have worked without them, but the UK deserves as much credit as Russia for toppling Hitler. 

As for Stalin being a brilliant military commander, I don't really see how wearing down your enemy by throwing hordes of underarmed and under-trained peasants at your enemy until they finally buckle constitutes brilliant military strategy. Russia had like 4x the population of Germany, and lost a higher % of them in combat compared to Germany. Operation Barbaroussa being the largest invasion in the war isn't impressive when you have a country with 4x the population of your enemy. Maintaining lower casualty counts would have been impressive, but they didn't accomplish that at all. And, as with much of Russian past military success, their climate did a lot of their fighting for them. 

And where are you getting this idea that the "total war" economy was "unprecidented?" In scale, maybe, but again that's just due to population. Every other major power in WW2 did the exact same thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29329196498.0" user="Best_Pants" delta="False">
    <text>The UK was barely hanging on mid-1941 and the US was still technically neutral.  The western allies were little more than harassers until 1943, when bombing campaigns actually started being effective.  By then, the eastern front was in its 2nd year.  They certainly helped seal the deal by creating a 2nd front after D-Day, but Stalin had already defeated most of Hitler's army by then and outpaced his production.

The feat should not be understated: the depth of transformation accomplished in the Russian military and economy over a relatively brief period while fending off a numerically, technologically, and expertly superior army.  Simply having a greater population isn't by any means an indication of victory.  China was vastly more populated than Japan, and fell easily.  Under a different leader, Russia would like likely fallen.  Few would have taken the severe measures needed.  The UK and US economies did not see nearly as dramatic a shift to war production, and they did not have to do it while huge swaths of their homeland were being seized and purged.  They could not have accomplished the same without abandoning some of their free principles.  It took them a year just to build up enough forces to invade North Africa; a costly campaign that taught the western allies how to fight a modern war.  France had, numerically and in many respects a superior army to Germany and fell in a mere 46 days.  Superior tactics and leadership had allowed an inferior German force to capture France and drive out the British Expeditionary Force.  Yes, the winter of '41 slowed the Wehrmacht, but it wasn't nearly devastating enough to credit for the reversal in fortunes.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29329398474.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>In terms of killing Germans, Stalin takes the cake. In terms of neutralizing germans, other allies come out on top. If you look at numbers for killed *or captured,* non-Russian allied states come out ahead by about 3,000,000, so I don't agree that Stalin was responsible for handling "most" of Hitler's army. 

In regards to size of population, saying that China had a particularly bad leadership doesn't mean Russian leadership was good. Before saying numbers don't matter you remark that taking on a numerically superior force is impressive. Which is it? 

Regardless, a lot of my prior post was critiquing the idea that Russia mounting the largest offensive of the war was impressive just because in terms of sheer numbers non of their enemies or allies could possibly hope to match up. Even if Germany sent every man woman and child to the Frontline they still wouldn't have the numbers Russia had at its disposal. 

And sorry, when you talk of Stalin's extreme measures contributing to his success a large part of his extreme measures were him murdering his own population and starving many more. Are you suggesting that other allies would have preformed better in WW2 by following this example? 

Finally, the US played a huge part in Russia success long before formally entering the war. Russian historian Boris Vadimovich Sokolov, a Russian commissar who worked closely with Stalin named Nikita Khrushchev, and Soviet Marshal G.K. Zhukov all admit (and admit that Stalin said) that Soviet victory would have been impossible without the $50,000,000,000 of goods and tens of thousands of vehicles and airplanes the US *gave* them. Your admiration for the military successes of the USSR is like lauding the military victories of modern day Isreal; they seem impossibly impressive on their face, but when you look at who was funding them it makes sense why they won..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331187297.0" user="Best_Pants" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pointing out the numbers so you understand that WW2 wasn't a numbers game.  Germany didn't utilize numbers to beat France - they won through effective leadership.  The feat of victory Stalin accomplished was in leadership; in effectively utilizing the particular strengths of his people/resources/geography, galvanizing a military and population, and not simply relying on the conventional strategies/policies of past wars.  I never implied his decisions were particularly brilliant; just effective in circumstances where other nations' leadership had failed.  Any WW2 historian will acknowledge the leadership required to accomplish what the USSR did.  Nations flush with supplies, tanks and men had fallen easily to the German juggernaut.  

&amp;gt;In terms of neutralizing germans, other allies come out on top. If you look at numbers for killed or captured, non-Russian allied states come out ahead by about 3,000,000, so I don't agree that Stalin was responsible for handling "most" of Hitler's army.

You asserted the UK deserves as much credit for defeating Hitler as the USSR, without qualifying the assertion, so I pointed out that the UK did not have a major impact on Hitler until 1943, by which time his military capacity had already become dramatically diminished by the Soviets.  75% of all German casualties in the war occurred on the Eastern front.  Those battles were massive and if we're arguing which nation deserves the most credit, that is relevant.  When you look at "captured" figures for the allies, you are looking at men who surrendered, not necessarily men who were defeated in battle.  During the final months of the war, many German soldiers fled westward and actively sought out American and British divisions to surrender to, rather than risk getting shot on sight or starved in a camp by bitter Soviets. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29332004096.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>So if numbers are irrelevant then you'd feel comfortable saying that Russia would have still won their war if they'd only had 4 million troops rather than the 20-30 million they actually had? Seems silly to me, given they lost over 8 million. Could Hitler have conquered France with 1000 men? No, because he lost 27x that in the battle. Numbers are absolutely a factor in every conflict. They might not be the deciding factor, but they are unquestionably *a* factor, and they might be one deciding factor of many. 

Okay, so the other allied powers only came out ahead in terms of enemies neutralized because they were more humane to POWS than the Russians were. What if it was just Russia and no allies on the western front to flee to? What if germans were caught between Germany and the Russians on the eastern front, who they knew would shoot them on sight or put them in internment camps to slave for the soviets until they starved to death? If that was the case we likely would've ended up with a situation like with the Japanese refusing to surrender even when it was clear they had lost. If your options are death by Russians or going back to your own country to be executed or sent back to death by Russians, you'd stand your ground till the last man. If you can't save your own life you can at least take some of the enemy with you. The other allies offering up a humane treatment of POWs is in itself an effective war strategy. I'm not sure if you've read ASOIAF, but in the books the most successful military commander has a policy of letting enemies who "bend the knee" live on, because if you take no prisoners nobody has any reason to surrender. That's like the brits and Americans on the western front. 

Speaking of, brushing up on this a bit im reminded of the impact the US had on WW2 through basically funding all the allied powers war efforts. They funded the soviets less than other allies, but still provided like 20-90% of all Soviet war material by the end of the war (the wild % range isn't total, it varies from material offered, like a third of their trucks, 90% of their rail system, etc). Stalin himself was quoted as saying the USSR couldn't have won the war without US intervention. Is it too late to change my position that the US deserves a fuck ton of credit here, as well? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
