<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="377703481.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68vhvd/cmvstalin_was_a_bad_leader/">
    <title>CMV:Stalin was a bad leader</title>
    <original_poster>BRINGITSISTA</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I have recently become a communist, or more specific a marxist leninist. But that is not what you will be changing today.

I hear many leftists and communists proclaim that Stalin was actually a really good leader and his negatives are exaggerated or fake....

Despite this, I still seem to have a somewhat negative view of Stalin

Yes, my image of Stalin has been improved by some communists I have encountered, but int quite there yet...

Instead of small one liners, I would like someone to write me a good, well rounded summary of why I should like Stalin

I know this might be controversial, so lets keep it to just communists and pro-Stalin people to answer this one...

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29328811929.0" user="Drunken_Frenchman" delta="False">
    <text>I find it difficult to argue that on the aggregate he was a good leader but he certainly did do certain things right.

For example, throughout the Second World War, the Soviet Unions industrial production continued to grow while Germany's consistently shrunk. Stalin had concentrated the majority of industrial development projects behind the Ural mountains which made them out of reach of German bombers. This meant that although Russia suffered heavy casualties, their War infrastructure remained sound and allowed them to continue producing armored vehicles. 

Also, rather than focus resources into more advanced and expensive tanks, they kept T-34 and did not actively try to change their main battle tank. Instead, they refused any alterations for combat effectiveness that increased the cost of production or lowered efficiency. As a result, the Soviets were able to build a stupid amount of T-34s which to this day remains the most mass produced armor in history.

Apart from that, I can't really make a great argument for the guy :/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29328940595.0" user="BattleBoltZ" delta="False">
    <text>Actually German production rose every year until 1945 and Soviet production was on the back of American material and grain.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
