<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="377703481.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68vhvd/cmvstalin_was_a_bad_leader/">
    <title>CMV:Stalin was a bad leader</title>
    <original_poster>BRINGITSISTA</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hello! I have recently become a communist, or more specific a marxist leninist. But that is not what you will be changing today.

I hear many leftists and communists proclaim that Stalin was actually a really good leader and his negatives are exaggerated or fake....

Despite this, I still seem to have a somewhat negative view of Stalin

Yes, my image of Stalin has been improved by some communists I have encountered, but int quite there yet...

Instead of small one liners, I would like someone to write me a good, well rounded summary of why I should like Stalin

I know this might be controversial, so lets keep it to just communists and pro-Stalin people to answer this one...

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29329012175.0" user="jacobspartan1992" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I'll admit that I am not a Stalinist by any measure and do not condone the horrific loss of life at his hands. However I do welcome taking such a challenging position, so here it goes. 

Joseph Stalin, despite what many Western partisan historians like to assert, is to be heavily credited with leading the Soviet Union in it's decisive role during WW2. Simply put the USSR's sacrifice and effective all be it ruthless combat doctrine was ultimately the downfall of Nazi Germany. The Allies for all their efforts would have at the very least found fighting alone against the Nazi's a much more costly endeavour and may well have lost. It was Hitler's the Wehrmacht's errors in the East and Stain and the Red Army taking ripe advantage of those errors that set the war on it's conclusive course. 

In Asia, Stalin's decision to invade Manchuria and open up another front against Japan successfully took thousands of Axis units out of the war, including most of Japan's armour and it's main supplies of raw materials. After this Japan's war effort was truly crippled. This thus helped force Japan's hand and avoided a US invasion of the Home Islands which would have been an absolute bloodbath. The alternative of more nuclear strikes against the country could have been another catastrophe that was avoided. 

The Soviet Red Army also had a key role in putting to an end the horrific humanitarian abuses perpetrated by the Axis as result of their worldview. Fascists believed that some people were sub-human and could be displaced, enslaved, experimented on and exterminated because they are Jewish, Black, Russian, Chinese etc. Most Nazi concentration camps were liberated by the Red Army and much of the evidence during the Nuremberg Trails was provided by the Soviets. The Soviets also shutdown the Japanese [Unit 731](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unit_731) in Manchuria. Many survivors owned their lives to the Red Army.

Also Stalin successfully moved Soviet industry over the Urals and kept it out of German hands and the range of their bombers. This had the effect of escalating Soviet war production and industrialising backwater regions and creating thousands of new jobs and livelihoods. After the war Stalin oversaw the reconstruction not just of the USSR but of Eastern Europe. 

He also encouraged the advancement of science in the USSR and begun the groundwork towards achieving manned spaceflight in 1961 and arguably helping the USSR win the space race. Though he presided over the early years of the Cold War, Stalin's foreign policy and intelligence networks effectively spread Soviet influence to the far corners of the globe and he established the roots of a network of alliances that would one day stop only 90 miles off the coast of Florida. His successful testing of nuclear weapon's could have prevented the Cold War going Hot due to MAD.  

So recap: 

Decisive victory over Hitler's Germany impossible without USSR.

Decisive in pressuring Japan to surrender and preventing a bloody invasion. 

Put an end to the Holocaust and Unit 731 among other horrors. Saved individual lives. 

Industrialised backwater regions of USSR and rapidly rebuilt Eastern Europe.

Advanced science, set course for manned space flight and projected Soviet influence around the world.

Kept the Cold War cold.

DISCLAIMER: I am not a Stalinist or even a committed Communist, just being the Devil's advocate (literally, some might say). 

Apologies for any spelling errors and offence caused.  

     

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
