<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="377961507.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6910yr/cmv_a_computer_could_do_90_of_a_doctors_job/">
    <title>CMV: A computer could do 90% of a doctor's job (general practitioner in particular).</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyOnceThreetimes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have numerous medical conditions throughout my life and I have many friends who are doctors.  All the doctors I have visited have been terrible at their jobs.  Whether it is complete disinterest, misdiagnosis, unknowledgeable of symptoms indicating problems, misreading x-rays/cat scans, etc.  Any condition that has been solved has been me fighting the medical system with information i've researched on the internet.

If we started a database that tracked symptom of patients, eventually we'd see what percentage of particular symptoms indicate a particular disease/condition/disorder/etc.

I understand people do their own research on Web MD and often go to a doctor and a doctor laughs and tells them what they read is incorrect, but this is because WebMD is not considering everything else about the patient.  

For instance low blood pressure in a 24 year old athlete is not an indicator of a problem as it would be for say an old sedentary and obese 65 year old male. 

Doctors should be detectives, puzzle solvers or scientists, but often I find they are quick to get you in and out of your office for that paycheck.  They see too many patience to devote enough time to solve your obscure case.  And let's say it is indeed an obscure case.  Imagine only 100 people have had your condition, no doctor could ever be expected to piece together the puzzle.  But if those 100 people were logged,  the computer could compare against that.

At best we could train individuals to be intermediaries between the patient and the computer system, so training for general practitioners could be lowered considerably.   And in doing so, their pay would be much lower which would allow money to be used for other things.  more testing labs, more MRI machines, etc.

Imagine going into the automated medical facility and getting your blood work and cat-scan done all in one place.  It would seem to me that your chance of a correct diagnosis would be MUCH higher than dealing with a human.  Most of medical school is just learning IMMENSE text book knowledge and analysis skills, both of which are best handled by a computer.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29331798738.0" user="Geralt_of_Rivia1" delta="False">
    <text>Is your CMV that a computer can do 90% of that job, or that computers can replace doctors for basic functions?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
