<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="377961507.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6910yr/cmv_a_computer_could_do_90_of_a_doctors_job/">
    <title>CMV: A computer could do 90% of a doctor's job (general practitioner in particular).</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyOnceThreetimes</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have numerous medical conditions throughout my life and I have many friends who are doctors.  All the doctors I have visited have been terrible at their jobs.  Whether it is complete disinterest, misdiagnosis, unknowledgeable of symptoms indicating problems, misreading x-rays/cat scans, etc.  Any condition that has been solved has been me fighting the medical system with information i've researched on the internet.

If we started a database that tracked symptom of patients, eventually we'd see what percentage of particular symptoms indicate a particular disease/condition/disorder/etc.

I understand people do their own research on Web MD and often go to a doctor and a doctor laughs and tells them what they read is incorrect, but this is because WebMD is not considering everything else about the patient.  

For instance low blood pressure in a 24 year old athlete is not an indicator of a problem as it would be for say an old sedentary and obese 65 year old male. 

Doctors should be detectives, puzzle solvers or scientists, but often I find they are quick to get you in and out of your office for that paycheck.  They see too many patience to devote enough time to solve your obscure case.  And let's say it is indeed an obscure case.  Imagine only 100 people have had your condition, no doctor could ever be expected to piece together the puzzle.  But if those 100 people were logged,  the computer could compare against that.

At best we could train individuals to be intermediaries between the patient and the computer system, so training for general practitioners could be lowered considerably.   And in doing so, their pay would be much lower which would allow money to be used for other things.  more testing labs, more MRI machines, etc.

Imagine going into the automated medical facility and getting your blood work and cat-scan done all in one place.  It would seem to me that your chance of a correct diagnosis would be MUCH higher than dealing with a human.  Most of medical school is just learning IMMENSE text book knowledge and analysis skills, both of which are best handled by a computer.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29330858678.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>There is actually a lot of research on this. The most recent high impact paper I've seem corroborated past research that physicians continue to outperform computers at diagnostic accuracy:

http://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamainternalmedicine/article-abstract/2565684

If you can't access that article, a copy is also available on the AHRQ website. 

I'm certain that there will be a time when computers outperform humans consistently in this regard. We just aren't there yet. The reality is that the key to diagnosis isn't the symptoms you input but the follow-up interview that is conducted by the provider to rule out what could literally be dozens of competing diagnoses. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29330937766.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>IT seems the conclusion of this paper is:

"The diagnostic accuracy of computers vs physicians remains unknown."

Also, this paper focuses on "performance for reading electrocardiograms."  And in my argument, I'm not saying a computer could yet read that better, this might still require specialists.  But rather I am saying diagnosis is better performed by a computer.  And yes, this is mostly theory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29330955105.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;IT seems the conclusion of this paper is:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;"The diagnostic accuracy of computers vs physicians remains unknown."
&amp;gt;

Are you being serious here? That statement was the reason they ran the study. They actual conclusion of the study was that humans outperformed computers across a variety of scenarios. If you can't access the article the AHRQ website at least summarizes the conclusion better. 

https://psnet.ahrq.gov/resources/resource/30510/comparison-of-physician-and-computer-diagnostic-accuracy

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29330977014.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I didn't know that was the entry spot for the paper, rather than the conclusion as I was unable to read the paper (just the first page).  

I still can't read the article so i'm unable to read the statistical analysis of the study.  There is a conclusion there, but I can't conclude for myself if there is any flaws in their study.  Many studies are done to conclude many things and often are incorrect.  If there had been numerous studies to suggest the same thing, then I'd say I'd be forced to change my view.

I'd love to read it though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29330989586.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>This was published in JAMA which is the most respected and difficult to get into medical journal along with New England Journal of Medicine. Also, while studies can have weaknesses this isn't a lone study. As I pointed out this corroborates previous evidence finding similar conclusions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29330999225.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Hmmmmmm, I guess we are getting down to the wire in awarding you with a delta haha because I'm close to being forced.

But it rests more on the believing of the study.  My knowledge of JAMA is absent and knowledge of publication of journals is minute.  Many journals may publish a well conducted study, yes.  But how much peer review does it require?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331056246.0" user="inspired2apathy" delta="False">
    <text>It's the Journal of the American Medical Association and basically a gold standard in terms of academic journals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331133642.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, I am willing to accept that and thanks for the information.  So I will assume the study is peer reviewed etc.  Nonetheless. my view has not changed for the reasons of this [comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6910yr/cmv_a_computer_could_do_90_of_a_doctors_job/dh2ziik/):

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331059075.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>If you are unconvinced by well respected medical journals, what type of evidence is going to be required to change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331111548.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>It is the limitations of the study (as listed by the study):

The main one -&amp;gt; 

1) Symptom checkers are only 1 form of computer diagnostic tools and other tools may have superior performance.

2) Use of clinical vignettes don't reflect the complexity of real-world patients and did not include physical examination or test results.

3) Physicians who chose to use Human Dx may not be representative sample of US physicians and therefore may differ in diagnostic accuracy.  


This study is non-exhaustive.  It was not using, in full, current technology that we have available to us today, I firmly believe a computer could still do a better job. 

I wrote a thesis in A.I and bioinformatics so am aware of cutting edge tech out there as well as a software engineer.  The only thing standing between accurate diagnosis of problems surpassing a doctor's ability is infrastructure (as I have sort of painted through explanations in this thread).

Yes the doctors outperformed again this particular software, but I'd say further studies are required to hammer the conclusion home.  I'd still argue that a highly advanced software and massive amounts of compiled patient data paired with a nurse would do a better job than a doctor and in the long term, cost less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331395288.0" user="DaraelDraconis" delta="False">
    <text>Your position is a strong claim and requires evidence to back it up; "other tools may have superior performance" is always going to be true, but unless you have specific reason to believe that there are tools which already exist which *do* have superior performance it's a little much to say with confidence that "A computer could do 90% of a GP's job".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331754550.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Your position is a strong claim and requires evidence to back it up; "other tools may have superior performance" is always going to be true.

No, it most certainly is NOT true there will always be superior tools to produce a job.  For example, there is not sufficient computing power nor information to predict the future.

&amp;gt; but unless you have specific reason to believe that there are tools which already exist which do have superior performance it's a little much to say with confidence that "A computer could do 90% of a GP's job".

There most certainly is a tonne of evidence supporting my claim that there is sufficient tech to do a doctor's job.  

Basic stock market analysis algorithms are FAR more complicated.

[AlphaGO](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AlphaGo) is the most sophisticated AI program in the world.  The problems they have solved with this are mind blowingly complicated.

[Simulations Plus](http://www.simulations-plus.com/software/overview/) predicting how chemicals will behave in the human body.

These problems are vastly more complicated than a simple symptom checker.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331786732.0" user="DaraelDraconis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it most certainly is NOT true there will always be superior tools to produce a job

I didn't say that there would always be perfect tools for any job.  I said that it will always be the case that there (theoretically) *may* be tools that do a *better* job - which is to say, "other tools may have superior performance".

&amp;gt; There most certainly is a tonne of evidence supporting my claim that there is sufficient tech to do a doctor's job. 

There's evidence that we can do computational problems of greater complexity than running a symptom checker.  That much is true.  It's not the same thing, though: it seems reasonable to assume that people designing a study that checks computers against doctors are going to choose the best available computer-tools.  If you have a suggestion for a *specific* tool that would be better, go find out whether it really *is*!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331825910.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  didn't say that there would always be perfect tools for any job. I said that it will always be the case that there (theoretically) may be tools that do a better job - which is to say, "other tools may have superior performance".

Fair, but my CMV is not based in theory, I am asserting that the tech is available to us today.  I'm asserting that a doctor's job is trivial and an easy one to solve compared to the REALLY difficult problems we solve already with sophisticated AI.

&amp;gt; If you have a suggestion for a specific tool that would be better, go find out whether it really is!

This is my first post to CMV.  The key word being view, I would assume there is a large amount of subjectivity involved.  It wouldn't be a view if I said "This algorthim and this machine can do a better job than a doctor" that would be a hypothosis and the owness (scientificaly) would be on me to prove my hypothesis. 

I'd assume view is still in the 'forming hypothesis' stage.  Like, is this hypothesis worth investigating.

For instance, people don't say "I'm going to build a time machine" and work backwards from there, rather they would say, "If I use all these scientific principles, I could build a time machine".  People could argue technologies used to see if it's worth exploring. 

This is how I understand it.  Does that make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331838886.0" user="DaraelDraconis" delta="False">
    <text>If the tech is available to us today, you should be able to present the tech in question.  Things of a seemingly-comparable complexity are a great way to conclude it's not impossible, but not strong evidence that a computer definitely *could* do 90% of a GP's job.  Absence of computers that *do* do a GP's job is only weak evidence that it can't be done yet, at best - this I acknowledge freely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331706082.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>I have to wonder what current technology we are missing in the healthcare field? I'm a pharmacist and studying clinical decision support tools. As far as I know, these are still relatively crude databases and are not particularly user friendly. On the flipside you can say they are cutting edge technology since health informatics is a relatively new field but my experience is that it's hardly overwhelming. 

I use drug-interaction checkers in my work and they still require my input. The computers I have do not have a sophisticated AI to evaluate the appropriateness of drug therapy for patients. I guarantee if there was such a system available, I'd be out of a job because pharmacists do not come cheap. 

So I must wonder if peer-reviewed data on systems that actually exist won't change your view, what will? You seem to be talking about potential technology that has not coalesced into a tangible product to be used. If you are so sure of your thesis, why have you not developed and monetized such a product? Why has no one else? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331726224.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Well written.  

My background is in artificial intelligence and large data analysis in the medical field.  My frequent visits to Doctors has forced me to come to the conclusion that what computers can do today, are far more complex then the decisions doctors make.  Most of their clinical work can be done on autopilot.

I want to stick to the thrust of my view.  I didn't say that there is sufficient money to build such an infrastructure, nor are the correct politics and resources in place to implement.  My view is that there is nothing a doctor does that technology today cannot solve.  

Aside from the human interaction, bedside manner, etc. The problems they solve are incredibly linear.  Googles search engine is INCREDIBLY complex and solves problems 1000 times more complicated than what I am talking about and their search engine pales in comparison to other AI or machine learning software out there.

What I'm looking for is a counter example. Computing power, computing storage, computing AI is all there to do a better job than a doctor at locating symptoms.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331766208.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>That's such a reductive and facile view though. There's nothing anyone does that can't be replaced by technology now or eventually. The human aspect of medicine is to help navigate gray areas since a lot of medicine doesn't exist on a strict binary. 

Let's take a simple example from my profession. I get a hard stop every time someone is on mutiple psychoactive medicines either due to concerns of duplication of therapy or serotonin syndrome. Now I use my professional judgement based off what I know to be max doses for medicines but there's no equation for determining serotonin syndrome. Sometimes I judge based off how long the patient has been on that combination of meds and if they're stabilized. Those are really soft measures and I don't have a great way of explaining why I'll question a psychiatrist's order over another besides what I know to be somewhat standard medicine. In fact, with psychiatry, there are hardly any set standards to judge other than the DSM-V which is more a diagnostic tool than treatment based. There's no JNC-8, ADA, or GOLD guidelines like there are for blood pressure, diabetes, and asthma/COPD when it comes to that field. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331812730.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Let's pick apart your example to get to the root whether a computer could do your human decision tree:

&amp;gt; I use my professional judgement based off what I know to be max doses for medicines

Call this procedure ProfessionalJudgement().  I'm having a hard time this cannot be deduced with raw data alone.

&amp;gt; no equation for determining serotonin syndrome.

Okay.  Let's call this variable X which by your assertion is 'non-equitable'.  But how would you, as a human, determine X.  And what about it is so unique that an extremely complex decision tree could not figure out?

&amp;gt; Sometimes I judge based off how long the patient has been on that combination of meds 

Call this variable Y obtained from a database of patient drug history.  I'm sure we can agree this could be determined.

&amp;gt; and if they're stabilized.

Call this variable Z it can be obtained from a database of patient medical history.  I'd assume we could agree?

&amp;gt; Those are really soft measures and I don't have a great way of explaining why I'll question a psychiatrist's order over another besides what I know to be somewhat standard medicine.

I assume you are talking about a specific intuition?  Are you saying your intuition cannot be replicated?  Because intuition is probably replicated with google's AlphGo.  

The computer 'watched' 1 billion games of the game 'Go' and over time, it formed an intuition.  The game of 'Go' cannot be solved with traditional combinatorial arc-consistency algorithms, like  the game chess can.  The possible combinations are FAR too great.  Intuition was indeed a requirement.  When we FEEL we are choosing the right thing, this is usually because of experience.  While you might have 5 years of experience dealing with these things, the amount a computer would have would equate to 80000 years.

There might be so much data that the emergent property could surface in that while you 'feel' you are being intuitive, you aren't at all.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29332243727.0" user="videoninja" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see the point in answering your questions since it's leading back to my original point about your view being reductive. You could say the same many other fields that an AI can replace people but if these products are so easy to create, why haven't you or anyone else seized on that opportunity? Not just medicine but in any analytical field? 

I'm simply saying that if current technology were where you believe it to be then I see no reason why your belief is not reality. Personally, I think you're putting the horse before the cart here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331064983.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a clinical researcher. JAMA is the most prestigious medical journal along with New England Journal of Medicine. It is peer reviewed and has a research acceptance rate of approximately 3.5%.  Personally I don't believe you should put too much weight on one study but like I said this is the general finding in the field right now with very few exceptions. I guess I would say that you don't have to determine that physicians are definitely better at diagnosing than computers, but at the very least you should back off from your assertion that computers are superior unless you have some other data that I'm not aware of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331136956.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the info, I'm glad I learned that.  However, I don't think I can back off my assertion just yet and my reasoning is in [comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6910yr/cmv_a_computer_could_do_90_of_a_doctors_job/dh2ziik/).

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331522616.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>Very strange that you came in so strong on the point of the paper prior to reading the whole thing. You should probably re-evaluate your level of confidence when arguing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331733663.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Is it so strange though?  Considering the vast amount of mis-information there is on the internet, there is always a way to show a study to support one's view, even if incorrect.

I'd say the tone of my comment was certainly not a strong conclusion as I acknowledged the possibility.  I'd say the skepticism I insinuated was justified, I stated that I was unable to read the paper, however I did later manage to and I responded in this [comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6910yr/cmv_a_computer_could_do_90_of_a_doctors_job/dh2ziik/).
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331827964.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>You made a pretty declarative statement about the content and conclusion of the study. However, you didn't read the entire study. That suggests to me that just from reading the abstract and intro to the paper, you thought you could infer the conclusions. You clearly could not. That gap between perceived comprehension and actual comprehension can be explained in part by over-confidence on your part. 

Grammar and punctuation aside, you seem like a pretty smart guy (or gal). IMO, that makes you one of the good guys on issues like this. All I'm asking is that you please use that intelligence to temper your words until you actual understand things. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29331888153.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your input and advice.  But I'd ask you take into consideration the resources of the OP before making conclusions on his grammar, intelligence, etc. (This isn't me getting defensive about your 'ask' of me, i'm asking for empathy)

You have to understand that the OP (which happens to be me) has several conversations going on at once and not just one with you.  I'd say your standards are too strict to expect everything I say to be as well thought out and ask you re-evaluate your expectations.

Had it been a conversation between just me and you, I'd read the paper, pay more attention to grammar, adhere to the scientific method, really consider my conclusions.  

But this subreddit has a great deal of theory and subjectivity involved (as inherent to the word 'view'), it isn't a dissertation defense or peer review, nor is it scientific where the onus is solely on me to prove my hypothesis, if that were the case, no philosophizing would be required as it is blatantly obvious that I cannot provide a proof of my view and no conversation would need to be had.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29332540070.0" user="pfinny22" delta="False">
    <text>If you can't take the time to deliver a well-thought-out post I'd say it would probably be better not to post. If you're not able to then you're wasting other people's time who are genuinely interested in understanding the issue at hand and would like to see well-formed, meaningful arguments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29332623569.0" user="OnlyOnceThreetimes" delta="False">
    <text>You are being a little harsh frankly.  Read all my responses; I spent a good 7 hours debating with people as intellectually as I could.  I cant devote my entire day to it. Come on. I displayed interest but it is tiring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29333197902.0" user="pfinny22" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry If I sounded harsh. If you were tired, just let them know instead of giving a reduced effort.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
