<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="386479431.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6e3lfr/cmv13_reasons_why_is_a_terrible_show/">
    <title>CMV:13 Reasons Why is a terrible show</title>
    <original_poster>Schnippernyc</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite all its acclaim, 13 reasons why is absolutely awful. Here is why I think so. 

1. Everyone praises the TV Show for its originality,  how original can it be if it's based on a book?

2. Far to many of the characters are two-dimensional. Hannah's the stereotypical drama queen, Bryce, Zac, Marcus... are the stereotypical popular boys. Tyler's the weird outcast. Justin's the troubled kid, and Jessica is the bad influence that drinks, smokes, and has underage sex that is perceived as an angel. They only tried to give depth to 6 characters. This sounds like a lot, but a show with such complicated social webs and so many characters should have them with more depth. That said here is a list of the characters they tried to  make dynamic.
   
  
     A. Tyler. Like I mentioned before, they failed at Tyler. They tried to make him troubled and worthy of sympathy. Instead, they made him a creep.
    
 
     B Courtney. When Courtney breaks down into tears in the cemetery, we are supposed to feel sorry for her. However, her insistence of acting like an asshole causes the viewer to think of her as a mean girl in sheep's clothing, not someone with complex emotions.
    
 
     C. Sherri, Alex, Clay, and Tony. This is an odd group but I am putting them together because they actually did have emotions. You may think that 4 characters with complex emotions is enough. It isn't for one interesting reason. Although the 4 character arcs are complex, they are all virtually identical. They all have human characteristics shown based on one thing, regret because of Hannah. They are all shown as human by this one trait. Their responses to regret are also similar. Two commit suicide or try to. As much as I try, I can not relate to the show's human-looking robots.
3. The entire plot is revolved around sympathizing with an asshole hungry for revenge. I know what I said before about Hannah being a drama queen, but she is also a terrible human being. Not only does she commit suicide, leaving all the people who care about her feeling guilty, she makes sure everyone who contributed knows about it. This is supposed to haunt everybody for the rest of their lives. Worst of all, this was done for no reason other than revenge. She clearly did not want anyone to know what happened to them, and for god-knows-how-long, they had to go to school with this over their heads, unable to tell anyone, "I helped kill Hannah Baker". 
     
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29399149279.0" user="AlveolarFricatives" delta="False">
    <text>My response here might be skewed because I read the book first (and prefer it to the series), but here's my take. 

1.) The book and show portray complex characters, not one-dimensional villains and heroes. Tyler is a creep, 100%. But he's also a human, and has some redeeming qualities. Same with Courtney. She's very selfish, but she's also scared of coming out and worried about what others think about her, which is understandable, though her actions suck.

2.) I think Alex and Clay were well-realized and distinct characters on the show, as in the book. Sherri and Tony were indeed pretty one-dimensional. 

3.) I don't think Hannah's a bitch. I do think she's certainly externalizing her pain. I see that externalization as part of her depression though. If she had an internal locus of control and saw herself as being able to create change in her life and improve things for herself, then she wouldn't be suicidal. Instead, she sees everything as happening *to* her, as though she were a passive audience member in her own life. That's the depression talking. The people she talks about on the tapes are not to blame for her death. The depression is to blame, but she isn't able to see that (because of the depression). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29399180066.0" user="Schnippernyc" delta="False">
    <text>My answer wasn't formulated properly. I do think that Alex is complex. Clay is somewhat complex but not enough for a lead role you need to sympathize with when he becomes Machiavellian.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
