<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390098992.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6g96b4/cmv_i_believe_in_death_of_the_author_but_only_for/">
    <title>CMV: I believe in Death of the Author, but only for some forms of art</title>
    <original_poster>PeptideBond007</original_poster>
    <original_post>If you're not familiar with the Death of the Author concept, [here](http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/DeathOfTheAuthor) is a link that explains it (warning: TVTropes).

I have had many discussions with people about this theory in the past, and although none of them have convinced me to change my mind I am still open to the possibility. 

_____


**Where I believe Death of the Author applies:** physical art (sculpture/painting/drawing) and literature (poetry/prose). Since these forms of art are inherently more subjective, I think it makes a lot of sense to argue that the creator may be unconsciously channeling things outside of their original intention. Since all of these forms of art rely entirely on the creative vision of one person, any number of things in that person's personal history or life experiences can influence their work in ways they don't realize. I also think that works of art like these are distanced from their creators in ways that other art is not, and this distance allows for greater freedom of interpretation.

To give an example, Mary Shelley's *Frankenstein* is often analyzed using the context of Shelley's own issues with her father. Shelley probably did not intend for this to influence her work and might not have agreed with some interpretations of the main character's oedipal tendencies. In my opinion, this does not make those interpretations wrong.

**Where I believe Death of the Author does not apply:** performance art (films/TV/theater). These forms of art are less subjective. They also function by a creative consensus between performers, directors, producers, etc., meaning that their vision and motivation has to be much more clearly defined. Performance art even comes with *documentation* of these motivations in the way of stage or script direction. In a book, if a character says "I'm sorry," it is up to the reader to interpret that character's motivations based on the rest of the text. In a performance, the line "I'm sorry" is often accompanied by directions in the script to indicate those motivations for the performers' benefit. Performance art is also much "closer" to the artist than physical art or literature is, so it cannot be decontextualized in the same way that those art forms can.

To give an example, television followings in the modern era of internet fandom are very eager to "ship" characters outside of the intentions of the director/screenwriter/performers. This sometimes goes as far as fans arguing that a character's sexuality is actually different than the creators say it is (e.g. that a straight character is actually gay or bisexual based on their own interpretation of the show). In my opinion, these interpretations are objectively wrong.

_____

I suppose this CMV has two potential deltas – either convince me that Death of the author applies to performance art or that it doesn't apply to physical art/literature. Change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29428043364.0" user="Br0metheus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; To give an example, Mary Shelley's Frankenstein is often analyzed using the context of Shelley's own issues with her father. Shelley probably did not intend for this to influence her work and might not have agreed with some interpretations of the main character's oedipal tendencies. In my opinion, this does not make those interpretations wrong.

Maybe I'm misunderstanding your post, but you seem to be applying DoA haphazardly here. For Shelley to "die", you must ignore her intentions *and* her biographical information. Any oedipal tones of *Frankenstein* need to be apparent if you were reading the work in a vacuum, without knowledge that she had a weird relationship with her father.

Anyway, onto my main response, which primarily addresses the literature aspect of your CMV, but could be applied to any form of art almost as easily.

**Let's talk about speech and language.** Human beings evolved the ability of language for a singular purpose: to share information from one person to another with as much detail and integrity as possible. While all social animals have some level of ability to communicate with one another, humans are far and away the strongest communicators on Earth. No other species has the same ability to take an individual's thoughts about abstract concepts like time, space and emotion and convey them with clarity to another individual. When one human speaks to another, the speaker has information that he wants the listener to have. The speaker creates the message with some sort of purpose.

Poetry and prose are undeniably forms of speech; they are merely encoded in text instead of sound. And much like the spoken word, literature serves the same purpose: to convey the thoughts of the author to the reader as best as possible.

Authors have *something to say* to you. For instance, in *1984*, Orwell had a message of warning about the surveillance state and retroactive alterations of history. In *The Lord of the Rings*, Tolkien wanted to immerse the reader into an alternate world, rich with it's own history. In the *Iliad*, Homer wanted to relate the course of the Trojan War and the larger-than-life personas who were involved. You get the idea, I think.

However, Death of the Author purposefully ignores all of the above, and pretends that there was never any point to the text, that it wasn't crafted with a deliberate purpose. It pretends that the text simply appeared out of some void, and forcibly strips it of any context which would help interpretation.

Personally, I find this particularly ironic, given how the lit-crit crowd usually has a *huge* fetish for contextual interpretations, even going so far as to say that communication without context is literally impossible. But then again, the lit-crit world hasn't bothered to make sense in decades, so we shouldn't be surprised that they can't keep their story straight.

&amp;gt; I think it makes a lot of sense to argue that the creator may be unconsciously channeling things outside of their original intention.

It only makes sense if you believe that psychoanalysis is totally reliable, which it isn't. Sure, maybe you can read between the lines of text and infer parts of the author's psyche. But maybe what you're seeing is actually *your own* psychological quirks, not the author's. Or maybe you're just completely off-base, but there's no way to falsify your conclusions. Whatever the case, analyzing a text in this way opens the door for a *huge* wank-session that allows the reader to corrupt the information originally meant to be conveyed. I mean, can you imagine trying to apply DoA with spoken language, with a speaker who was present and with whom you could speak directly? The results would be *insane*. You could take a story that your friend just told you about a hot dog stand in Chicago and interpret it as "an expression of his repressed homosexuality, signified by the presence of phallic imagery." Nonsense, that is. Much like cigars, sometimes a hot dog is just a hot dog.

I'm not going to say that analysis using DoA is *useless*; it can still be a fun exercise, and it can test how well an author conveyed their message (since ideally, a work should stand on it's own). But the problem is that it is often misused or overapplied, when other analytical tools would be more appropriate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
