<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390098992.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6g96b4/cmv_i_believe_in_death_of_the_author_but_only_for/">
    <title>CMV: I believe in Death of the Author, but only for some forms of art</title>
    <original_poster>PeptideBond007</original_poster>
    <original_post>If you're not familiar with the Death of the Author concept, [here](http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/DeathOfTheAuthor) is a link that explains it (warning: TVTropes).

I have had many discussions with people about this theory in the past, and although none of them have convinced me to change my mind I am still open to the possibility. 

_____


**Where I believe Death of the Author applies:** physical art (sculpture/painting/drawing) and literature (poetry/prose). Since these forms of art are inherently more subjective, I think it makes a lot of sense to argue that the creator may be unconsciously channeling things outside of their original intention. Since all of these forms of art rely entirely on the creative vision of one person, any number of things in that person's personal history or life experiences can influence their work in ways they don't realize. I also think that works of art like these are distanced from their creators in ways that other art is not, and this distance allows for greater freedom of interpretation.

To give an example, Mary Shelley's *Frankenstein* is often analyzed using the context of Shelley's own issues with her father. Shelley probably did not intend for this to influence her work and might not have agreed with some interpretations of the main character's oedipal tendencies. In my opinion, this does not make those interpretations wrong.

**Where I believe Death of the Author does not apply:** performance art (films/TV/theater). These forms of art are less subjective. They also function by a creative consensus between performers, directors, producers, etc., meaning that their vision and motivation has to be much more clearly defined. Performance art even comes with *documentation* of these motivations in the way of stage or script direction. In a book, if a character says "I'm sorry," it is up to the reader to interpret that character's motivations based on the rest of the text. In a performance, the line "I'm sorry" is often accompanied by directions in the script to indicate those motivations for the performers' benefit. Performance art is also much "closer" to the artist than physical art or literature is, so it cannot be decontextualized in the same way that those art forms can.

To give an example, television followings in the modern era of internet fandom are very eager to "ship" characters outside of the intentions of the director/screenwriter/performers. This sometimes goes as far as fans arguing that a character's sexuality is actually different than the creators say it is (e.g. that a straight character is actually gay or bisexual based on their own interpretation of the show). In my opinion, these interpretations are objectively wrong.

_____

I suppose this CMV has two potential deltas – either convince me that Death of the author applies to performance art or that it doesn't apply to physical art/literature. Change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29427819451.0" user="SKazoroski" delta="False">
    <text>Things like "fan theories" and "head canons" generally regard questions about stuff that happens off-screen. Whatever happens on-screen are objective facts about the story's universe that can't be debated. What can be debated are details about stuff we do not get to see on-screen. These can be abstract things like what is going on in a character's head during any particular scene, or it can be more concrete things like what events occurred at places and/or times we were not shown.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
