<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29433083235.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

Why would that necessity asserting that there is no god? It's perfectly sufficient not to have an official position, and only prevent all public endorsements of theism and religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433100393.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>If you make no statement about the existence of god you end up implicitly supporting the belif in god. in the usa we have many mentions of gods existence even though we have a "secular state"
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433146531.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you make no statement about the existence of god you end up implicitly supporting the belif in god

How would that work?

&amp;gt; in the usa we have many mentions of gods existence even though we have a "secular state"

Isn't that merely a failure of not sufficiently preventing endorsements, rather than a failure in asserting that no gods exist? 

For instance, I'd agree with the point that "In God we trust" should have never been added to your money as a reaction to communism in the 50s.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433186153.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>people don't just leave theyre religion on the side in the day to day life. If they aren't flat out told that they can't bring it with them they will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433755425.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>But how does telling them that they can't bring their religion into state business require asserting that no gods exist? You can do that without the added claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433485924.0" user="AristotleTwaddle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you make no statement about the existence of god you end up implicitly supporting the belif in god.

How do you figure?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433660516.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; people don't just leave theyre religion on the side in the day to day life. If they aren't flat out told that they can't bring it with them they will.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29434073666.0" user="AristotleTwaddle" delta="False">
    <text>The same is true of any code of ethics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29434713453.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>We ask  that nudists leave theyre ideas to the side . why not religion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29434740372.0" user="AristotleTwaddle" delta="False">
    <text>How did you jump to nudists? We cause geopolitical terror without the need to invoke a deity. I think health care is a tragedy because of chasing capitalist ideals. You can't escape bias by banning one type of it. If you're upset about homosexuals, consider that most senators/congressmen are religious and yet gay marriage is now federally legal in the US. If you want to ban religion you may as well ban lobbyists in general as well. Nobody can "leave their ideas aside" or nothing would get done because nobody would care about anything. That's the idea behind the populace electing people *to represent* their own ideals. If the majority of people are Christian, it's no surprise most elected officials are as well.

Also, you frequently use they're in the place of their. I don't know if you're a non native speaker so I would watch out for that. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
