<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29433088351.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Why can't we expect religious people to act in accordance to secular cultural values?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433110361.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>because whether we know it or not our belifs always taint our actions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433176770.0" user="verfmeer" delta="False">
    <text>Can't we make laws that forbids religious government employees to do so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433198811.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>that would amount to massive discrimination against a religion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433209853.0" user="verfmeer" delta="False">
    <text>Why would that be discrimination? Is it discrimination to only hire people who want to work on friday/saterday/sunday? Many religions forbid working on one of those days.

I would say only hiring civil servants who want to service LGBT isn't different. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433222167.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>oh! i misread your comment I thought you said forbid religous employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433233645.0" user="verfmeer" delta="False">
    <text>No problem. Could give a reaction to my original comment? Why couldn't you simply only hire people who are willing to serve LGTB or other religiously sensitive tasks when that's neccesary in their job?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433247834.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>How would you enforce this? It feels easier to just fire those who do discriminate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433186726.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't this imply no one can ever be fair to any member of any other group?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433201165.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>no, just that we need to counteract the damage our beliefs can have</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433263215.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so my original question is back: Why can't we just trust religious people to do that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433300758.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>Because they don't want to. After everything with the discrimination against gays in the US bureaucracy are we really going to trust the religious right to police themselves? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29437264560.0" user="Palidane7" delta="False">
    <text>Is this about all religious people, or the just the ones you don't like?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29438195760.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>neither. Its about making sure the government remains secular</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
