<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29445185806.0" user="anLandaT" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like you're assuming that there are no secular institutions in non-atheist states.  The constitutions and bodies of laws of (many) modern liberal democracies specifically prohibit any actions or considerations based on religion in the legal system or government services, rendering them in theory and practice atheist.

You mention as an example fundamentalist Christians withholding or refusing services from people whom they view as being in opposition to their beliefs but that is not an official policy of the government, and in some countries it would result in prosecution or a lawsuit.  That is to say nothing that those are a-few-in-hundreds-of-millions occurrences.

Put simply, we need to see a trend of religion overtaking secular institutions to accept your point.

I would suggest to you that practical atheism is already entrenched in societies with clauses like this:

&amp;gt;Every individual is equal before and under the law and has the right to
the equal protection and equal benefit of the law without discrimination and, in
particular, without discrimination based on race, national or ethnic origin,
colour, religion, sex, age or mental or physical disability.

And this:

&amp;gt;Any discrimination based on any ground such as sex, race, colour, ethnic or social origin,
genetic features, language, religion or belief, political or any other opinion, membership of a national
minority, property, birth, disability, age or sexual orientation shall be prohibited.

And this:

&amp;gt;Everyone is entitled to all the rights and freedoms set forth in this Declaration, without distinction of any kind, such as race, colour, sex, language, religion, political or other opinion, national or social origin, property, birth or other status.

Modern states already have laws in place to ensure that people are free to believe what they want but are not allowed to infringe on the rights of others because of it.  The institutions are already as secular as they can be without infringing on the rights of religious people to be employed or to have access to government services.

Again, we'd need to see some numbers about religious discrimination being a rampant and/or invasive problem to accept that we need a secular state.

Prohibiting religion at the state level wouldn't make "religious discrimination [...] far easier to deal with", it would simply turn the table around to discrimination from the other, atheist, side.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
