<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29434097172.0" user="Veronica_Wang" delta="False">
    <text>I'm curious about the execution.

You can't go door to door and force ideas down people's throat. I mean what you like, a marxist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29434710106.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>It is not forcing everyone to be atheist but just the government saying there is no god</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29435389371.0" user="LeighmurBJJ" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but just the government saying there is no god

Dude, this is directly taking a stance on religion. Here's something from your original statement

&amp;gt;If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

Atheism is a religious belief system, and from what you're saying you're showing a bias for a certain belief system. Your statements are directly contradicting themselves.

I think what you're trying to say is the government should be areligious or secular. Secular does not equal atheistic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29436651847.0" user="Veronica_Wang" delta="False">
    <text>That's incredibly stupid because you pretty much would just seal the deal for a lot people about there being most certainly a god, and lizard  people, and the illuminatis are in control.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
