<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29433033266.0" user="NoodlerOf88s" delta="False">
    <text>Secular is defined as "denoting attitudes, activities, or other things that have no religious or spiritual basis".

I think the problem with your view is that you are ignoring that atheism *is technically a religious stance*. So by having state atheism, you aren't living in a secular nation - you are living in an atheist nation.

Plus the problem with having any sort of governmental religious stance is that it becomes *much* easier to accuse the government of religious discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433059230.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>Atheism is the absence of a religious stance. The government saying there is no god does not mean that the nation atheist, it just means the government is atheist. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433081444.0" user="NoodlerOf88s" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Atheism is the absence of a religious stance. The government saying there is no god does not mean that the nation atheist, it just means the government is atheist

* Atheism is a religious stance - the stance being that you lack belief in a god.

* State atheism means that policy will be made from an atheist perspective - regardless of what the general populace believe - so in that respect, it would be nonsecular (according to my first point) and open up the government to religious discrimination lawsuits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433082912.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>atheism is not the absence of religion, it is the denial of it, i think it would be better to be "state agnostic" with the state holding no belief on weather or not god does or does not exist.

theist = god exists 

agnostic = i don't know 

atheist = god does not exist </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433156997.0" user="jm0112358" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; atheism is not the absence of religion, it is the denial of it

Although the exact definition will change depending on who you ask, atheism is simply not believing in a god. Atheism/theism refer to _belief_, whereas agnosticism/gnosticism refer to _knowledge_. You can be an atheist and agnostic (you don't believe in a god, but don't claim to know that a god doesn't exist) or you can be a gnostic atheist (you don't believe in a god, and you claim to know that no god exists).

Also, you can be an atheist and have religious beliefs that don't include a god. For instance, some Buddhists are atheists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433186218.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>i realize that the terms i used are not universally agreed upon, but i still believe they illustrate a point, the state should not get involved maters of religion, they should not believe or disbelieve in god, being an atheist would strongly imply you have a belief.

unrelated; your statement that some Buddhist see themselves as atheists is accurate, to a point. the "atheist Buddhist" is almost exclusively a western interpretation of traditional Buddhism. i have a lot of Buddhist friends and they corrected me when i said something similar. This western version of Buddhism is mostly (but not entirely) based on 1960s hippies.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433202160.0" user="jm0112358" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; i realize that the terms i used are not universally agreed upon, but i still believe they illustrate a point, the state should not get involved maters of religion, they should not believe or disbelieve in god, being an atheist would strongly imply you have a belief.

I agree that the government should remain neutral^1 when it comes to religion, and being officially atheistic isn't neutral.

^1 Or at least as neutral as possible. Certain types of religion infringe on the rights of others, such as parents not taking their sick child to a doctor because of their religion, in which the government should intervene.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433220127.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>it seems like we where in agreement from the begging but used different terms. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433288573.0" user="PenisMcScrotumFace" delta="False">
    <text>It is when participating in certain official debates and chatting on the internet. While it is technically the correct definition it certainly isn't true or relevant in these circumstances.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29437317751.0" user="auryn0151" delta="False">
    <text>Despite being fiction, I'd highly recommend you watch the old Twilight Zone episode "The Obsolete Man." It's incredibly relevant to your CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433066457.0" user="th4tfilmguy" delta="False">
    <text>This seems to be from the common linguistic misunderstanding. Atheism does not mean a disbelief in the existence in a god, it means a *lack* of a belief. Just as the prefix "a-" in atypical means not typical, the prefix put into theist means not theist. Is someone making a stance against golfers by not playing golf? No, they just don't golf. There is no need for a word to describe non-golfers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433074831.0" user="NoodlerOf88s" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This seems to be from the common linguistic misunderstanding. Atheism does not mean a disbelief in the existence in a god, it means a lack of a belief. Just as the prefix "a-" in atypical means not typical, the prefix put into theist means not theist

I agree. But while it isn't a religion, it is a *stance on religion*. Secularism *by definition* precludes any stance on religion, even if that stance is "I lack belief in religion".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
