<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29435492916.0" user="RedditTruthPolice" delta="False">
    <text>this is just...a historically horrible idea.

the only countries with atheist governments are places like China, North Korea, and other places, where they forbid religion because they want people to worship the state instead.

the kind of states that have the most secular institutions are actually ones who have official state religions, such as some nordic countries, and places like england. basically many parts of western europe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29435589286.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>state atheism is not banning religion. Its just the state saying god doesn't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29435705500.0" user="RedditTruthPolice" delta="False">
    <text>that's in theory. in practice it's different, always. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
