<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469292113.0" user="Heycanwenot" delta="False">
    <text>[Here's](http://i.imgur.com/5nXpDox.jpg) what I got for the defintion of "homophobic".

This may be a difference in definiton, but isn't discouraging homosexuality by calling it a sin showing prejudice against them? Of course everyone sins under their teachings, but you would also say that they discourage premaritial sex and similar "sins".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469313207.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Did you not read the CMV? There is a reasoned argument for it being a sin. You don't have to accept it, but the point is we don't believe homosexual acts are wrong 'just because' they're wrong. We have reason behind it. It's not bigotry. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469319880.0" user="Heycanwenot" delta="False">
    <text>What's the reason why it's wrong exactly? Because it's written in a religious text? That's not something you wrote in your post.

Just because it's written down and it's believed by a group of people doesn't make it immune to being bigoted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469327044.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Read the CMV ..... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469329571.0" user="Heycanwenot" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, didn't see the first part.

I'd still like to see your response to my second point though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469334568.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>What was your second point? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469355709.0" user="Heycanwenot" delta="False">
    <text>That following a set of rules that is lined out does not make them immune to being bigoted.

You're saying (from what I've read in this thread) that it's not just senselessly based off of nothing because it's based on these rules. But how does following these rules make you not bigoted?

At that point... where do you draw the line? Discouraging someone else's lifestyle because you believe in one set of rules that contradicts theirs seems senseless to me, especially when they've done nothing to directly impact you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469364475.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>The rules are derived from a belief in the sacredness of sexual relations which we are able to justify, if you'd like to go into it further. I don't think that's bigotry. 

I don't know many Catholics who go up to gay people and tell them not to have sex. Perhaps you do. We simply hold a view that it is wrong, and this view does not derive from a hatred of gays. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469903324.0" user="z3r0shade" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The rules are derived from a belief in the sacredness of sexual relations which we are able to justify,

You are able to justify this to judge your own behavior, there's no justification for imposing these judgements on others who do not believe what you do and attempting to discourage and outlaw that which you see as sin. The attitude towards others and society regarding homosexuality is what is bigoted.

&amp;gt; We simply hold a view that it is wrong, and this view does not derive from a hatred of gays.

Then why so much fervor over same sex marriage? Why so many boycotts and outcry over organizations and media that support gay people? If you only held a view that it is wrong *for you* and did not try to prevent others from believing differently, no one would have a problem with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469949335.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The rules are derived from a belief in the sacredness of sexual relations which we are able to justify, if you'd like to go into it further. I don't think that's bigotry.

It seems like you hold the premise that if something is justified based on a religious belief, it cannot be bigotry. Why is that? If you take most things that are commonly accepted as bigotry, do you think they would be alright if someone is able to come up with a religious reason for supporting their beliefs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470029427.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>If we took the distinction you're making to its logical conclusion, we could simply take any hateful belief or action and swap in some alternate religious motive to make it no longer hateful.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
