<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469709506.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you and don't believe most people would consider what you've outlined in the OP as homophobic (though some, of course, do). When people use this belief to justify discrimination of any sort (e.g. excluding homosexuals from participating in communion, advocating for laws against homosexuality), it becomes homophobic. Would you agree?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
