<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469682646.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Do you believe that sterile persons should be allowed to marry? E.g. a woman who has lost her uterus due to cancer?

&amp;gt; But everybody is a sinner.

This view is incredibly condescending. It makes it sound like gays and lesbians, and straight people are on equal footing when it comes to sin, but if you look more closely, they're really not. Stating it this way allows them to make criticism sound more reasonable because of the believer's humble admittance of their own sinful nature. It's basically like saying: let me lower myself to your level, so that I may more legitimately criticize your actions", or "I admit that we are both sinners, but I repent for my sins, so I'm allowed to criticize you."

Then there's the inherent unfairness: heterosexuals have been given a way out. The sinning nature of heterosexuals is often portrayed as some kind of constant "noble struggle" against evil. This struggle allows them to commit sins, as long as they repent and show remorse.

For gays and lesbians to achieve that same status before God would mean to entirely forgo the experience of romantic love in their lives. It denies them something wonderful, that only heterosexuals are allowed to experience, as they have been given marriage as a "legitimate" way to satisfy both their needs for romantic relationships as well as sex.

The fact that heterosexuals have been given a legitimate way to satisfy their sexual urges and the need for romantic love without sinning (through marriage), makes this distinction inherently unfair.

The fact that it specifically targets gays and lesbians, means that it's homophobic.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
