<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469783656.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend

So essentially, you're saying that the Catholic view on homosexuality is motivated by love, or at least a desire for a better world, right?  That makes sense, and i think that's probably at least partly true for most Catholics  (I would wager that the issue of homosexuality is not actually all that important on a day-to-day basis for most Catholics, but that's a separate discussion really).

The issue is that this view on homosexuality is still somewhat homophobic.  Not in that it is hateful, but in that it fails to treat homosexuality as a part of a person's identity and instead puts homosexuals in the same category as drug addicts or adulterers by viewing them more or less as people making a series of bad choices about their lifestyle. This is largely due, at least from what I understand, to the fact that Catholics tend to view homosexuality as a choice rather than an orientation.  This is a pretty paternalistic view of homosexuality and people in general, which isn't bad by itself but ignores the fact that sexual orientation is entirely determined by factors outside ones own control.  

Unlike drug addicts, adulterers, or other sinners, there isn't generally a specific choice to be homosexual.  The choice is only whether or not to engage in homosexual relations, which as many others have alluded to isn't really much of a choice. Either refrain from ever having sexual contact despite the strong natural inborn urges all humans feel (a rather torturous experience as one might imagine, not to mention a lifestyle that is also not open to reproduction), have sexual contact with a group of people one is not interested in (committing deception, another sin), or giving in to urges outside of one's control and being branded a horrible sinner in exchange.

The above is the life that the Catholic church has forced upon homosexuals (even putting aside very real hatred espoused by the church in the past and continued by some members to this day).  While you might believe that this is still not homophobia,  and you have the right to believe what you want,  hopefully this gives you a glimpse of why many people consider the Catholic church to be a bit homophobic. 
 </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
