<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469349621.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Homosexual acts are by definition NOT open to life

Where are you getting that homosexual acts are not open to life?  A homosexual act can result in new life if, and only if, God wills it to be so.  This is exactly the same as a heterosexual act.

And certainly many homosexuals _intend_ to be open to life when having sex, and would be overjoyed if they would become pregnant by doing so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469377324.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Because two men cannot make a baby? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469395349.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that if God willed it, it would be impossible? That would be denying the omnipotence of God.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469410793.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>If He willed it it would happen, but He has obviously never willed it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469423940.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>So given that you admit that it is possible for the action to result in a baby, how is this action not open to life?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470547959.0" user="bluespartans" delta="False">
    <text>We also know that it is 100%, completely impossible for an embryo to form without a sperm fertilizing an egg. Yet obviously, the Gospels tell us that's exactly how Jesus was born. I'd say /u/yyzjertl was on the money with his point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29482831193.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of self-respecting God would have been conceived on Earth the usual way? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483084107.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483306727.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>YojimboSlice5000, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostility extremely seriously. Repeated violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+YojimboSlice5000&amp;amp;message=YojimboSlice5000+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/djlgtaj/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483082657.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>Which was apparently decided by your god. So was the fact that gays are gay. After all, it is proven in the DNA and DNA is what God wrote to design us right? So he gave gays free will, a desire for a family and to be accepted, then he made it impossible for them to have kids and told his followers to shun them for impulses he created. If God is real, that's how I view him. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469485013.0" user="TopekaScienceGirl" delta="False">
    <text>Wait this is literally the best argument I have ever seen, wtf.  Like how God will Mary to have a baby.  Your argument also bases on so many Christian arguments which makes it genious.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
