<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29470378868.0" user="randy_buttcheese" delta="False">
    <text>The most important part of your argument is the aspect of being able to create life, deeming it natural and good. If a heterosexual married couple is unable to conceive, do you consider it a sin if they continue to have sex knowing they will never have a child from their union? Is it then considered legitimate if the woman is artificially inseminated? Or adoption? A surrogate mother? 

If these are acceptable without being seen as a sinful relationship then can't it be said that gay relationships are capable of life? 

Let's pause on that for a moment. Consider the story of Abram and his wife Sarai. She was unable to conceive. The solution that God accepted was for Abram to sleep with their slave. This did produce children for the married couple, Abram however was not married to their slave. He had sex with another woman to create life. This idea of using a surrogate mother is in the Bible and approved by god. So if a married gay couple uses a surrogate mother or artificial insemination this fulfills a way to make open to life, in a fashion that god himself approved of for heterosexual couples. This modern method is even better because neither partner is having sex outside of their marriage. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
