<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29470144126.0" user="chaoticathebutterfly" delta="False">
    <text>By the strictest sense of that definition, there is TECHNICALLY no bias towards LGBT+ people. However, the result of that stance still causes disproportionate harm to the LGBT+ community, because while the same rules apply to gay and straight couples (no sex that can't potentially create kids), you are effectively telling a certain kind of person that they are allowed to experience a perfectly natural and joyful part of life, and another group that they aren't allowed to do so.

There are several examples of rules like this if it helps put it into context. For example, mandatory minimum sentences for offences relating to the drug crack cocaine in the U.S. Technically these laws applied to everyone, but since crack cocaine is a "black drug" and powder cocaine (which carried lesser sentences) is a "white drug," the laws were extremely racist in how they disproportionately damaged African-American communities. Similarly, banning same-sex marriage technically doesn't discriminate against gays, since if for some reason (for example, financial reasons) two heterosexuals of the same gender wanted to get married, they can't either. Technically heteros are no more privileged than gays under these laws, but realistically it still only hurts the gay community.

Even if you were to take the position that this kind of rule is fair because it doesn't TECHNICALLY discriminate, you and the Catholic Church would still be ignoring the wider consequences of this stance. Religious rules like these ones contribute to general hatred towards LGBTQ+s, because when homophobes hear about them they feel that their hatred is legitimised by an institution with a lot of authority in the world. They wouldn't even have to be a Catholic homophobe for this to work, just someone who acknowledges the Church as any kind of legitimate authority. You could argue that this isn't the Church's fault, but unless they're really stupid (which I don't believe they are), they know that this is one of the results of their decisions. This stance from the Catholic Church and similar institutions directly and indirectly causes bullying, hatred, discrimination and suicide which disproportionately affects the LGBTQ+ community, especially our precious youths :(

Also, I and many other queers really can't stand that "love the sinner, hate the sin" line. It doesn't apply in the same way as it does your hypothetical friend who is selfish and swears too much, because we were born this way baby :) and even if we could change we shouldn't have to because we're not hurting anyone. It feels patronising and passive-aggressive when people say it, and while I'm not accusing you personally of hating me (you seem nice), most people who say it really act like they do. The message it sends is that we can be loved in spite of our queerness, but there is nothing wrong with queerness and everyone should be loved!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
