<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469352784.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>I don't like to eat fish. I'm fishphobic. Because I dislike fish, I dislike salmon, which is a type of fish. I'm salmonphobic. Just because my rule is opposed to fish in general doesn't mean I'm not also salmonphobic as well.

The Catholic Church is sexnotopentolifephobic. Homosexual acts are by definition not open to life. So the Catholic Church is homosexualactphobic. 

Fishphobia is really called ichthyophobia, salmonphobia is really called salmosalarphobia, and homosexualactphobia is really called homophobia. (I'm not good enough at Greek to figure out that third one.)

Phobic doesn't necessarily mean you hate something. It doesn't necessarily mean you are afraid of something. Oil is hydrophobic because it has an aversion to water. Just because the word homophobia has a negative connotation these days doesn't mean it's not true. The Catholic Church is homophobic by definition. It might really care for the lives and souls of every LGBTQ person, but it doesn't change the definition of a word (phobia) that has existed for at least 1000 years longer than the Catholic Church.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469365892.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Then what is being 'phobic' ? People tend to say that it's being hateful towards a certain group. If there's another definition I'd like to hear about it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469440315.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>It all depends on what discipline you are talking about. Here are a handful of -phobia words. I coped and pasted the first paragraph from each Wikipedia page on the specific world. 

 &amp;gt; * Islamophobia is defined as "Intense dislike or fear of Islam, esp. as a political force; hostility or prejudice towards Muslims".

&amp;gt; * Acrophobia (from the Greek: ἄκρον, ákron, meaning "peak, summit, edge" and φόβος, phóbos, "fear") is an extreme or irrational fear or phobia of heights, especially when one is not particularly high up. It belongs to a category of specific phobias, called space and motion discomfort, that share both similar causes and options for treatment.

&amp;gt; * Photophobia is a symptom of abnormal intolerance to visual perception of light."


&amp;gt; * In chemistry, hydrophobicity is the physical property of a molecule (known as a hydrophobe) that is seemingly repelled from a mass of water. (Strictly speaking, there is no repulsive force involved; it is an absence of attraction.) In contrast, hydrophiles are attracted to water.



So various definitions of phobia include being hateful of something (Islam), being prejudiced towards something or someone (Muslims), being extremely or irrationally afraid of something (heights), avoiding something (light), an aversion/lack of attraction (water).

Interestingly, the definition of homophobia includes all of these definitions:

&amp;gt; * Homophobia encompasses a range of negative attitudes and feelings toward homosexuality or people who are identified or perceived as being lesbian, gay, bisexual or transgender (LGBT). It has been defined as contempt, prejudice, aversion, hatred or antipathy, may be based on irrational fear, and is often related to religious beliefs.

If you don't want to say that the Catholic Church has contempt, prejudice, hatred, or antipathy for homosexuality that's fine. But I think the Catholic Church itself would be the first to say they have an aversion (defined as "a strong dislike or disinclination") to homosexuality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470152199.0" user="KingMelray" delta="False">
    <text>While we're here; the word Islamophobia describes too many things to be useful and it makes it harder to talk about issues related to Islam.

It involves 4 very different things: 

Fear of ideas.  

Fear of people.

Dislike of ideas. 

Dislike of people.

Being this vague makes discussion more difficult than it needs to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470171117.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but that's the definition of Islamophobia. The definition and connotation of the word isn't going to change just because someone wants a more politically correct way to say they have a negative view of Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470183541.0" user="KingMelray" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying is people should make their intentions and thought process clear.

Saying:  "I disagree with the doctrine of martyrdom" is more helpful.

If someone says:  "ISIS scares me" and you call them Islamophobic you would be technically correct, but so unhelpful you risk derailing the conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470223694.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "ISIS scares me" and you call them Islamophobic you would be technically correct, but so unhelpful you risk derailing the conversation.

Sure, but the original post was "Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic." That's not true. They are homophobic by definition. You can say that people should make their intentions and thought processes clear. You can say that it's technically correct, but misses the broader picture. You can say many things about the subject. But once you distill it down to the final point, the Catholic views of sexual morality are homophobic. They aren't neutral, and they aren't in favor of it. That only leaves phobic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470289143.0" user="KingMelray" delta="False">
    <text>I'll admit we got off the rails.

"Islamophobic" encompasses more things than "homophobic."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470326120.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, then I'll try one last definition of homophobic. If you are opposed to homosexuals having non-procreative sex, you are homophobic. That is the most widely accepted definition. Every single homosexual person and most of the rest of society uses that as the definition. You can say that social justice warriors and immoral gay activists created that definition to make the Catholic Church look bad, but for better or worse, they did and that's what it means now. If you go to the Wikipedia page on homophobia here is what it says about the Catholic Church:

&amp;gt; The official teaching of the Catholic Church regarding homosexuality is that same-sex behavior should not be expressed. The Catechism of the Catholic Church States that, "'homosexual acts are intrinsically disordered.'...They are contrary to the natural law.... Under no circumstances can they be approved."

Maybe a bunch of liberal, secular Wikipedia writers wrote that definition, but there it is. One of the main examples of homophobia in the world's most popular encyclopedia is the Catholic Church's views of sexual morality. You have to actively change the definition of homophobia if you don't want the Catholic Church to be part of it (or change the Catholic Church's position.)

As a final point: http://imgur.com/gallery/HEZ1eJY</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29471405834.0" user="jm0112358" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Ok, then I'll try one last definition of homophobic. If you are opposed to homosexuals having non-procreative sex, you are homophobic.

I think very straightforward because homophobia is very clearly defined by society. However, Islamophobia is usually a lot less clear when people use it. Does it mean you are very fearful of Islam (ideas) or Muslims (people) or both? It makes a big difference, and I've seen it used both ways.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
