<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469305865.0" user="bryry" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the OP.

Let's start with a generally accepted definition of homophobia from Merriam-webster:

irrational fear of, aversion to, or discrimination against homosexuality or homosexuals (source: https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/homophobia).

Let's add a generally accepted definition of homosexuality from Merriam-Webster's:

sexual attraction or the tendency to direct sexual desire toward another of the same sex (source: https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/homosexuality).

So, you don't need to think homosexuals are "evil" or "sinners" or "hate them". You just need to be averse to the idea of someone else having the tendency to direct sexual desire to a person of the same sex. 

It sounds like the catholic view of moral sexuality would qualify as aversion in this context. Thoughts?

On a tangent - do catholics believe that sexual activity after menopause is also not moral? Because I think that would also not be "open to life".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469324721.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>There is no aversion towards people who have this tendency. All of us hold some kind of proclivity to commit sin. If we had to be averse to everybody with a proclivity, we'd be guilty of being 'phobic' towards most things, but that's simply not the case. 

Yes it would not be moral. The reason being open to life is important is because without that, sexual relations become lustful. To make oneself into an object for pleasure, and to objectify one's partner for pleasure is immoral, according to our beliefs. Yours may be different, but I hope you can see the rationale behind the Catholic belief. It's never been 'gay sex is wrong because it's wrong'. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469340886.0" user="bryry" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the reply.

Again, from Merriam-Webster's for aversion:

a tendency to extinguish a behavior or to avoid a thing or situation and especially a usually pleasurable one because it is or has been associated with a noxious stimulus.

If you have a friend who is going to hell because of his behavior - would you try to change him a save him? Thereby extinguishing the behavior? If so, can't this be considered aversion?

&amp;gt;Yes it would not be moral...I hope you can see the rationale

Thank you for the information and catholic perspective. Yikes, you guys have a harsh god. No, I cannot see the rationale. I don't hold these types of superstitions and have difficulty understanding people that do (I understand it's one of my failures of empathy). 

But, it helps to get to discuss these issues with religious people. On another tangent - Do you think it's possible that you are both emotionally tied to catholicism and also accepting of homosexuals and therefore must engage in a bit of rationalizing in order to feel ok about the catholic church's sometimes less than total acceptance of gays?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469357059.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Well, tell me what the flaw in the logic is and I'll happily answer it. Nope, I both accept homosexual people and the Church's teachings. I just don't think the acts are right, in the same way I don't think lying is right.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469367156.0" user="bryry" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the response. 

Could you please reply to the point regarding the definition of aversion? I'm concerned your idea of homophobia may be a bit too narrow.

&amp;gt;tell me what the flaw in the logic...

From my perspective your sexual morality is based on on an iron-age ideology that is in turn based on an imaginary god. I do not believe there is a god(s) judging me, watching me have sex, or ensuring that I have the correct motivation for having sex. So to me, it's a bit irrational.

&amp;gt;Nope, I both accept homosexual people and the Church's teachings

Do you thinks it's possible to engage in cognitive dissonance and not know it? If you're not concerned about this topic on some level, then why post a CMV and want your view changed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469373790.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>My belief in God is as substantiated as your belief that the universe is a purposeless place that will ultimately end and leave nothing behind. Even if you say you are agnostic about the world, you live practically as an atheist, and you derive your ideas of sexual morality from this assumption that the world has no natural law. 

As far as I know, aversion is a strong disinclination or dislike of something. I don't think Catholics hold this kind of feeling towards homosexuals. Only the acts. 

I think it's an interesting topic, and I want to get people thinking about their views, which is why I've started this CMV. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469394931.0" user="bryry" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you again for your response.

You've made some less than accurate assumptions about my beliefs. I recommend in the future asking people about their beliefs - as opposed to telling them about them. Questions are always more likely to result in a better understanding of others. But this isn't my CMV, it's yours, so we should stick to your beliefs.

Aversion has many related accepted definitions including the one I pasted above from Merriam-Webster's. 

Particularly from a practical perspective of accepting homosexuals, the way they live their lives, and how they express love and affection for their partners - conservative religions such as catholicism certainly are not fully accepting of all those aspects of homosexuals and homosexuality. 

Saying you don't hate someone and that they should suppress their need to express sexual love to another consenting adult - does not really count as acceptance.

Thank you for your OP. I'm afraid I do not have the ability to change your view (per your CMV request). I hope someone else will have more success. Thank you again for the interesting discussion.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469399797.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>By all means, tell me what you believe and how it is more valid than a belief in God. I would be interested to know. 

I suppose it might not count as acceptance from a humanist worldview, but I can't do anything about that.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469907913.0" user="z3r0shade" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't count as acceptance from any point of view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469998834.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>Since you acknowledge that it might not count as acceptance from a humanist worldview, let me ask you this. If 
there were either no God or a God who made no moral proclamations on the subject of sex and sexuality, would the same view of homosexuality become hateful?

Also, when you say you can't do anything about that, you're denying your own moral agency as if you have no accountability for the content of your beliefs as long as you defer to some external moral authority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469444511.0" user="SultanofShit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I want to get people thinking about their views, which is why I've started this CMV.

So you admit that you are unwilling to change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470478325.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>"My belief in God is as substantiated as your belief that the universe is a purposeless place" thing is it actually isn't. It just isn't. That is scientifically incorrect. Just because we haven't PROVEN that there is no god, does not mean there is an equal likelihood of him existing or not existing. The fact that there is horrid pain and suffering and that the word of a god was written down by men more than implies there's a good chance this whole thing is not quite true! MEN! 

And the fact that miracles are actually not scientifically possible (or repeatable if they ever did happen in the first place) also indicates an extreme likelihood of no god. To this you are likely responding "but I BELIEVE in miracles." But that does not matter one bit. There are literally billions of things that prove gravity every minute, but not once has someone proved you can walk on water. The evidence is unbelievably stacked to him note existing. 

The point is, you can argue that you believe in a god because.. you just do and it feels right. That's ok. I wont judge you for that. But for you to argue that "God is as substantiated as your belief that the universe is a purposeless place" because your religion is based on a load of unsubstantiated happenings and rule-breaking physics, whereas there is so, so much evidence to back evolution, the big bang, and the fact there is pain and suffering EVERYWHERE. Science also doesn't want your money every Sunday, nor to guilt trip you about whom you love. Science has made life immeasurably better for people. The agents of your benevolent god spread aids through Africa by demonising birth control. 

Let's say your god exists in the form you describe him as, why would we follow him? There is no evidence for heaven but there is evidence for suffering. Essentially, even if you accept he exists and analyse his intentions as if he were a powerful being, you'd soon conclude he was a space dictator. 

Your claim of "God is as substantiated as your belief that the universe is a purposeless place" proves you don't look at the situation objectively. 

Honestly the idea that it is logically a coin toss to whether god exists or not in the form you guys imagine him is absolutely ludicrous and honestly leaves me questioning your analytical abilities. 

Also, I was raised in a Roman Catholic school and came to this conclusion of my own volition, so I've lived both sides of the coin. Unfortunately, the stories told to me by crinkly old demagogues in robes didn't line up with logic or the world at all so I abandoned that nice fluffy feeling for reality. 

Edit: Linky here that explains it pretty well
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mkgYgJEH-e4</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29482828805.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>For you to have any point, you need to tell me why your choice to live as though there is definitely no God is more scientifically supported than the way I live my life. You haven't done that at all. Evolution and the Big Bang do nothing to make God's existence less likely. There are many eloquent philosophical and moral arguments for the existence of God which you ignore. The evidence for the resurrection of Jesus Christ is also formidable. You may have been raised Catholic but it's clear you never understood or thought about the faith. 

Science does not belong to atheism, nor religion. You like to pretend that it does, but it doesn't. Do try to think. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483072040.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, watch the video I linked and address it. It is a few minutes and very concisely answers every question you ask. Science is not philosophical, it is not moral. It looks at what we can see and prove in front of us and asks "if we have literally no solid proof of this phenomena apart from people saying he's cool over thousands of years, it's likely he may not exist, or if he does exist, has no will to communicate with us."

"is more scientifically supported than the way I live my life" I'm not listing off arguments again. I already did. You just ignored them. For you to have a point maybe you should address the following? 

I understand I was raised to believe God was fact. Upon logical examination, I can't believe he exists. What I'm asking you is where is any shred of evidence he exists beyond some feeling you have?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29485609779.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Science doesn't belong to atheists. I'm asking you to justify atheism, not science. Atheism is the choice to live as if there is definitely no God. It's the assumption that once you die, that's it, despite the fact that we have no idea how consciousness works or how the universe began - that makes it a bold assumption that needs justification. Get it?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29485742529.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>I never said we owned it. No one owns science. I simply that when applying a scientific approach you'd be mad to arrive at a 50/50 god exists based on physical scientific evidence because there just isn't any. What is so hard to understand about that? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29487676799.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Stop dodging the question. Justify your definite position as an atheist, or I will mute you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29488133852.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>I already said otherwise I didn't thin I'll convince you so I'm done with the conversation so mute away :) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29488133885.0" user="doggobotlovesyou" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;:)

I am happy that you are happy. Spread the happiness around.

[This doggo demands it.](https://i.redd.it/hutykqppzrhx.jpg)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493102263.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493135139.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>forgivememia, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostility extremely seriously. Repeated violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+forgivememia&amp;amp;message=forgivememia+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/djrfjcn/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470466159.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>That kind of is phobic really in my book, by the very definition quoted above. 

Let's look at your liar example. 

I am phobic towards liars. If someone lies to me it hurts my feelings. If I know someone lies a lot, even if it has not directly influenced me, I won't want to be friends with them. 

The difference here is that sometimes people occasionally tell a little "white lie" and you can forgive this. But people who are gay are gay full-time, everywhere they go. It is not a slip-up. If you view being gay as a sin, you must view them in the same way as people who go around lying all the time. 

 They don't go home afterwards and think "whoops, there I go being gay again, gotta stop that!" like a liar might think "Ah damn, I'm a compulsive liar, gotta stop." It isn't a fair comparison and kind of implies there is some level of phobia there. 

Now, I am honestly fairly opposed to religion so maybe I'm not the best person to change your mind. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29482835597.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>It's not being gay that is the issue, it's committing gay acts. Gay people generally have other defining qualities besides who they choose to have sex with and how. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483074043.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>You've not even tried to think or address this point. No one is changing your mind so I give up because you wont engage. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
