<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469320247.0" user="bad__hombres" delta="False">
    <text>Catholics are against gay couples period - whether or not they're engaging in sexual acts or not. That's homophobic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469326539.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Well, some might be, and shame on them. The Catholic position I've outlined in this CMV is the one you have to argue against. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469332735.0" user="bad__hombres" delta="False">
    <text>Really? Do you actually think that Catholics only insert themselves into the gay debate when they have proof that same-sex individuals are having sex? Because that's not realistic in the slightest. There's always been a huge pushback against romantic relationships, not only sexual. I'm not going to argue something that I don't think is accurate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469338434.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>There is no gay debate. There's just a misrepresentation of Catholic views as being homophobic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469349435.0" user="bad__hombres" delta="False">
    <text>Of course there is, especially considering Pope Francis and his views on gay people and its deviation from traditional catholic beliefs.

Besides, why would they block same-sex marriage then? There's no reason to believe that marriage automatically results in sexual acts. If two members of the same sex were able to become married while still abstaining from sex, wouldn't that be moral? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469360675.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>There's no gay debate because what would it achieve? It's not going to stop homosexuals from sinning. There's a gay marriage debate. 

That's a good observation, until I tell you that the Catholic view of marriage is that people have a duty to give themselves to their partners. Gays obviously cannot do this in a moral fashion according to our view, so we have to oppose gay marriage. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469365736.0" user="bad__hombres" delta="False">
    <text>Gay debate, gay marriage debate, purely semantics. 

&amp;gt; people have a duty to give themselves to their partners. 

In what way? Sexually? Catholics don't ban marriage for infertile individuals, and I thought that sexual acts were only to be committed for procreation. Why have restrictions on gay people while straight people in similar situations don't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469368219.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>There's a huge difference between opposing gay people and opposing gay marriage. It's not semantics at all. 

Sexually, yes. Catholics would not approve of the marriage of a couple that is infertile. Such a couple can still be together. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469379481.0" user="bad__hombres" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think so, because they're both rooted in homophobia. You can't say that you're perfectly accepting of gay people while also placing restrictions on them, such as marriage. 

[That's not true.](http://www.vatican.va/archive/ENG1104/__P3Y.HTM) Check out Canon 1084.3, which states "Sterility neither prohibits nor nullifies marriage". Why can sterile people get married but gay people can't? I can't think of a good reason, can you? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469418484.0" user="bad__hombres" delta="False">
    <text>/u/forgivememia will you be addressing this obviously hypocritical stance that the Catholic church holds? This seems like evidence for homophobia to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483088849.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>OP wont address any well-developed points because they aren't here to change clearly. I hate to admit it, but I understand the logic behind gay marriage. I don't like it or agree with it but I understand how thye can feel that way without it being hate driven. I kind of get it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469913460.0" user="z3r0shade" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sexually, yes. Catholics would not approve of the marriage of a couple that is infertile. Such a couple can still be together.

So why can't a gay couple still be together?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470557911.0" user="bluespartans" delta="False">
    <text>The Church is most definitely averse to homosexual inclinations. From the [Catechism, paragraph 2358](http://www.vatican.va/archive/ccc_css/archive/catechism/p3s2c2a6.htm):

&amp;gt; The number of men and women who have deep-seated homosexual tendencies is not negligible. This inclination, which is ***objectively disordered***, constitutes for most of them a trial.

The official stance of the Church clearly indicates that homosexual inclinations are inherently "bad" (for lack of a better term) and antithetical to human nature. I'd say that is a phobic point of view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469413573.0" user="SultanofShit" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, they're just against sex outside of marriage, but same sex couples are permanently forbidden marriage.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
