<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469295843.0" user="Cadfan17" delta="False">
    <text>So sometimes people will call a piece of media sexist, because it features something they think is sexist.  Like seemingly gratuitous nudity.  And fans of that movie will insist that this can't possibly be sexist, because there's a really good in-universe justification for why that female character had to run around topless during that particular scene.

Lets leave aside whether that's actually sexist.  I'm inclined to view media, purchased for the literal purpose of entertainment, charitably with respect to whether or not it depicts entertaining nudity.  That seems a reasonable time and place for it.

But lets just analyze excuses that come in the form of, "that nudity wasn't sexist, there's a really good reason why that character is nude!"

Its a terrible excuse.  Because the author knew what they were doing when they thought up the in universe justification for the nude scene.  It probably wasn't "oh, I'm just writing this for no particular reason, and it seems like I'm in a position where nudity is what makes the most sense."  It was probably more like, "female nudity sells, so what's a good reason I can use to have some in my movie... ok, lets use that."  A critic is free to recognize this, AND to recognize that the enjoyment of the audience isn't just some dry enjoyment of the narrative impact of the scene- they're getting off to the nudity, and everyone knows it.

What you've offered here is an in-universe explanation for why Catholicism is critical of homosexual acts.

But a critic is justified in asking, "why is that actually convincing to these people"  Or, "what are they actually getting out of this?"  Or, "why the focus on this issue, and not others that seem like they could justifiably be criticized under this rubric?"

Just to run down the list.

Marital is a moot point because Catholicism opposes gay marriage.

Unitive is a moot point because if you're going to claim that gay sex is uniquely not unitive then you're outing yourself as a bigot and ruining your CMV.  And of course a critic is free to note other Catholic thinkers who have done exactly that...

So that leaves "open to life."  But of course Catholicism doesn't oppose other forms of sex that have no capacity to lead to pregnancy, like elderly sex, or sex between infertile partners.  The usual excuse is that these may not be EXPECTED to lead to pregnancy, but the participants are at least OPEN to it.  But it boggles the mind to imagine a way in which a post menopausal woman could be "open" to pregnancy in spite of knowing its literally impossible, but to which a gay couple couldn't also avail.  

Further, the phrase "open to life" becomes kind of... laughable, and worthy of mockery, when Catholics use it.  Someone who is using the rhythm method is literally putting actual effort into *avoiding* pregnancy.  This would normally be considered NOT being open to something.  The fact that they're using a method with a failure rate seems irrelevant to what they are or are not "open to."  If a straight couple uses birth control, but agrees that if the birth control fails they will keep the resulting pregnancy, that's psychologically similar to any rational outside observer.

The result is that the exclusion of gay couples from "open to life" seems arbitrary once paired with the inclusion of couples that are taking affirmative steps to avoid pregnancy, and couples who are literally incapable of pregnancy.

And a critic can observe all of this, and draw conclusions about the character of the people involved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469310314.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>That's way too long for me to respond to but I'll point out some flaws in your logic anyway.
Catholics oppose sex between infertile partners and the elderly if it is truly not open to life. Catholicism opposes gay marriage because in marriage partners have a duty to give themselves to their partners, but homosexuals cannot do this morally, by definition. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469391428.0" user="LeopoldTheLlama" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Catholics oppose sex between infertile partners and the elderly if it is truly not open to life. 

I'd ask to see support for this claim, as I've never heard any catholic I know truly espouse it and a quick search of the internet found a lot of explanations for why its okay for infertile couples to have sex. There may be some, but I think we can agree that even if some catholics do hold this view, the number is far lower (and with much less fervency) than those who oppose homosexual sex. For one, I have yet to see a single catholic group speaking out to ban marriage among the elderly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469394071.0" user="InfinitelyThirsting" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Catholics oppose sex between infertile partners and the elderly if it is truly not open to life. 

Ha, where are you getting this idea? That is absolutely not true.

According to the Code of Canon Law in section 1084:

 ยง1. Antecedent and perpetual impotence to have intercourse, whether on the part of the man or the woman, whether absolute or relative, nullifies marriage by its very nature.

ยง2. If the impediment of impotence is doubtful, whether by a doubt about the law or a doubt about a fact, a marriage must not be impeded nor, while the doubt remains, declared null.

ยง3. **Sterility neither prohibits nor nullifies marriage,** without prejudice to the prescript of canon 1098.

Emphasis added. Complete impotence (inability to have sex at all) can prevent a marriage from happening, but sterility (or age) does not, nor are they ever supposed to stop having sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469870013.0" user="Cadfan17" delta="False">
    <text>If what you're saying is that Catholicism opposes sex between the elderly or infertile, you're wrong. 

If what you're saying is that Catholicism opposes that sex if it's not "open to life" in spite of life being an impossible outcome, I already addressed that. 

In what sense are gay couples unable to "morally" "give themselves to their partner?"

And of course the TLDR still applies. You are back engineering "in universe" explanations for talking down gay people and thinking poorly of them, but your in universe explanations are still patently contrived excuses for what you already wanted to do, as evidenced by how they don't actually make sense when investigated, and as evidenced by the empirical fact of who they appeal to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469904821.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Catholicism opposes gay marriage because in marriage partners have a duty to give themselves to their partners, but homosexuals cannot do this morally, by definition.  

What part of the definition of homosexuality prevents gay partners from morally giving themselves to each other?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483095089.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>But then surely elderly couples shouldn't be allowed to marry either? IE poor old misses piss buckets who's a widow at 75.. Sorry gal ya can't marry that nice bloke Roger despite being really lonely beacuse ya junk don't work no more. Nice.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
