<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469645894.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm with you, but let's both wander over to the other side for a second.

&amp;gt;Homosexual acts are by definition NOT open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are equally immoral, and also considered a sin. 

Yes. I've taken this as granted.

&amp;gt;But everybody is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

Can I interject here though?

There is a chance for a straight person to not be a sinner in this realm. Like they could marry, only have sex while married, and only while fulfilling the conditions you laid down.

For a homosexual, this opportunity is not there. They can never, by definition, meet your standard for sexual morality.

Now, I get that you said "everyone is a sinner" but do you not look down at people when they commit a sin in front of you? Do you at least try to deter them from that sin? If a friend of yours was about to hit someone in an argument, wouldn't you stop them and tell them not to commit that sin? If a friend confided that he was interested in cheating on his spouse, wouldn't you advise them not to do it, as it is a sin?

Back to homosexuals, if you knew a homosexual and knew they were committing sin by engaging in that lifestyle, wouldn't you want to steer them away from it? To keep them from sin?

But homosexuals (according to many) cannot be steered away from this path or perhaps do not want to be. They wish to have their religion and their sexuality, and an attitude which always puts them in perpetual sin makes it difficult to do so. Furthermore, they have to deal with people (if they're religious) trying to sway them from their course of sin, and it may not be what they desire and it may feel belittling of their lifestyle choice or as if their lifestyle choice is abnormal, wrong and something to be ashamed / guilty of.

Do you see why, for this reason it is a bit homophobic in that it treats homosexuality as something to be ashamed / guilty of? You disapprove of your friends' swearing for example. Won't you tell them to stop it as well? But if you tell a person to stop being who they are, or stop having the identity they have, that's something harder and has more lasting consequences for that person psychologically.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
