<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="395295873.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6jck8x/cmv_catholic_views_of_sexual_morality_are_not/">
    <title>CMV: Catholic views of sexual morality are not homophobic</title>
    <original_poster>forgivememia</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Catholic position is this: in order to be moral, sexual acts must be (1) marital, (2) unitive and (3) open to life. 

Homosexual acts are by definition *NOT* open to life, and therefore they are seen as immoral. They are a sin. All heterosexual acts outside of marriage (which most people are guilty of) are *equally* immoral, and also considered a sin. 

This means that the people who engage in these acts are sinners. But *everybody* is a sinner. There's no belief that sinners are by definition 'evil'. Catholics think that homosexual acts are immoral, but we do not hate the people who commit them, and we do not think that homosexuals are evil. 

If you believe that your friend swears too much, or behaves selfishly, you disapprove of these behaviours, but you don't have to hate your friend. 


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29469308375.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>It's telling gay people they have to be alone their whole lives or have a sham relationship with someone they *can't* be attracted to or romantically involved with, and that any time they *do* feel romantic love or sexual attraction, they need to feel ashamed and suppress it. 

Imagine if the shoe was on the other foot, if the Evil Gay Agenda took control and outlawed heterosexuality, forcing you personally to choose between homosexual relationships or none whatsoever, for your whole life. Would you feel oppressed and hard-done by?

And it's cute to say that you bear a group no ill-will, while enforcing a rule that selectively screws them over. 

Look for instance at the Stolen Generation here in Australia; the government took *an entire generation* of aboriginal babies away from their mothers and raised them 'like decent white people'. For their own good, you see. It wasn't that they had anything against them, oh no, not at all. They *wanted the best for them*, you see, and so took it upon themselves to be *evil fucking bastards*.

Catholics want to take the opportunity for love, affection and sex away from 15% of the population. You can call it not-hate all you want, but that sure feels pretty fucking hateful to me. You wouldn't like it, so why should they?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469330572.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not telling gay people anything. They are free to be together and to have sex, it doesn't affect me. I'm saying that I think homosexual sex is immoral for the reasons I've outlined above, and that my view has clear logic and reason behind it, and therefore I'm not homophobic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469384528.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>"I think it's wrong and bad and shameful for you to be happy and loved, but I totally don't hate you" 

Think about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469387450.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>Think about what I've said. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469393561.0" user="InfinitelyThirsting" delta="False">
    <text>We have. Thinking someone is wrong, bad, immoral, and shameful is hateful. You may not think it is, but it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469407074.0" user="forgivememia" delta="False">
    <text>No, try again. The act is wrong, not the person. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469412373.0" user="SultanofShit" delta="False">
    <text>Saying that an act is wrong when that act is necessary for a person's well-being, and an equivalent act is just fine for everyone else, is hateful and cruel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469712720.0" user="PenisMcScrotumFace" delta="False">
    <text>Sex is more than just an act. You're suppressing someone's entire identity when you're saying they can't have sex with who they want. Why does God care anyway? Doesn't he want people to feel pleasure?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29469713274.0" user="tellahater" delta="False">
    <text>Let me try and bring a different perspective so that you can see it as other people see it.

There is a religious movement known as [Kinism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinism). Their position is that all 'races' were created by God, but to be completely separate. They disapprove of any position that is 'race' mixing, such as 'interracial' marriage, people of different 'races' living under the same roof, etc. Notice that they don't believe any 'race' is inherently evil, only that certain acts are. They believe all 'races' are equal and will all go to heaven, as long as they avoid mixing.

Now, would you call a Kinist racist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29470528952.0" user="jmdg007" delta="False">
    <text>But they are acting upon the same feelings that a straight person would, does this make both sides immoral as both get pleasure from sex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29483077937.0" user="YojimboSlice5000" delta="False">
    <text>That's like me saying "just so you know, I think you're ignorant because you believe in religion, but it doesn't affect me, so I'm just going to silently judge you here and make you feel shitty. I hope you feel shitty, because I believe an entire defining part of your life is just shit-house wrong." 

That's the impression your attitude gives to gays apart from religion is a choice and being gay is not. Essentially, if you don't understand how your views hurt them without you acting directly on them you are a fool and deliberately shielding yourself from the damage your views do to great people trying to get on with their lives who get persecuted enough. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
