<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397288315.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kj9mj/cmv_the_esrb_rating_system_is_frivolous_and/">
    <title>CMV: The ESRB rating system is frivolous and inaccurate</title>
    <original_poster>Aid2Fade</original_poster>
    <original_post>My parents prevented me from playing games rated above the ESRB required age. I don't think this was helpful or necessary, and in fact I experienced a short period afterwards where I specifically sought out games like CoD for the novelty of it. I understand that people may find the concept of violence grotesque, but video game violence is incredibly cartoonish. Not many people, or children I'd think, would belabor under the illusion that the silly video game blood on-screen has anything to do with what a realistic analogue would entail. I've even heard from people that it helps get aggression out of their system. Additionally, things like innuendo, violence, and 'bad language' are lumped together without any real way to differentiate. Even if I accept that there's benefit in controlling content, there doesn't seem to be a way for a parent that would want to pick one or two factors to actually choose. But beyond the value to isolated households, even if you tell your kids to not play M games, someone else's parent isn't going to care and will probably just let your kid play one at their house. Plus, if the concern is language and innuendo, they run into those at school anyway. And instagram is hardly sparing either. I just feel like the ESRB wasn't that useful at first and is now even more of a dinosaur.

_

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29485088759.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>The ESRB is just a tool like a screwdriver. It's not meant to solve the world's problems with it's circumvention, it's supposed to be an idiot proof way for retailers to protect themselves from angry parents and it's a mechanism for parents to choose what they want to buy for their children. 


&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Even if I accept that there's benefit in controlling content, there doesn't seem to be a way for a parent that would want to pick one or two factors to actually choose. But beyond the value to isolated households, even if you tell your kids to not play M games, someone else's parent isn't going to care and will probably just let your kid play one at their house. Plus, if the concern is language and innuendo, they run into those at school anyway. And instagram is hardly sparing either. I just feel like the ESRB wasn't that useful at first and is now even more of a dinosaur.

This is just conflating the issue. You wouldn't get upset at a screwdriver for being a flat head when you need a phillips. You are attributing problems to issues the ESRB never tried to solve. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
