<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29486163650.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere.

Im going to suggest reading Sam Huntington's [Clash of Civilizations](https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/united-states/1993-06-01/clash-civilizations). Its an interesting foreign policy piece that predicted a rise of political views based on "culture" or "civilization" rather than policy. Its important to realize that the Alt Right is a manifestation of this. Its not per say patriotism. Its a new form of political belief.

&amp;gt;Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism CAN but does not always lead to these things. You can really say ANY emotion or feeling CAN lead down a path to these things, but it's not a guarantee.

&amp;gt;Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Hardly. I think the quote of my favorite president Teddy Roosevelt comes into play here: 

"Patriotism means to stand by the country. It does not mean to stand by the president or any other public official, save exactly to the degree in which he himself stands by the country. It is patriotic to support him insofar as he efficiently serves the country. It is unpatriotic not to oppose him to the exact extent that by inefficiency or otherwise he fails in his duty to stand by the country. In either event, it is unpatriotic not to tell the truth, whether about the president or anyone else."

True patriotism will lead to debate and open conversation because that is what is needed for the nation to be its best. It encourages people to seek out and solve the problems in their society. Patriotism is about creating a better society, not particularly preserving some imagined good of the past of it.

The fact is people will shroud their ideas in mantles of patriotism to make people think they are standing up for their society, but you can often see  real patriotism when someone is willing to set their ideas aside for a greater good. When they are willing to work for their nation over their interests. But the fact is people can be blinded by shitty ideologies and put that first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486163680.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486166135.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486178987.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree this Roosevelt's quote I don't think it illuminates this discussion much.

The quote is interesting for two reasons. First, it simply assumes there is some inherent value to "stand by the country" but does not explain what that value is. Second, it speaks of a patriotism that I simply don't think exists anymore. Patriotism is not used in this sense today is it? When was the last time you heard people talk about patriotism as something that is malleable and ever changing based on the direction of a nation? It's use today is normally similar to the idea of faith; something that must persist no matter the evidence counter to it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486214521.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First, it simply assumes there is some inherent value to "stand by the country" but does not explain what that value is.

Well I think you have to ask two questions from this response. Do you see value in a government, and do you see value in a working government? If your answer to either one is no then you see no value in patriotism. If your answer is yes then you understand the value. The value of true patriotism is to support the working of that system.

&amp;gt;Second, it speaks of a patriotism that I simply don't think exists anymore.

As someone who works with a lot of govenment folks and grew up around it I would disagree. You talk to most people in government and you will understand most people are there to make a difference. They could be making much more in the private sector. They are there because they legitimately want to do public service.

&amp;gt;Patriotism is not used in this sense today is it?

When you see politicians argue and make deals that's a patriotism. When you see people support their politicians that patriotism. When they protest that's patriotism. They are doing it because they want their country to be a better place to live in.

&amp;gt;When was the last time you heard people talk about patriotism as something that is malleable and ever changing based on the direction of a nation?  It's use today is normally similar to the idea of faith; something that must persist no matter the evidence counter to it.

All the time. But as always this speech is [salient](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DMbBuEoEYnk).  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486374003.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You talk to most people in government and you will understand most people are there to make a difference. They could be making much more in the private sector. They are there because they legitimately want to do public service.

I agree however these people don't do their job out of a sense of patriotism even if they say they do. They do it out of a sense of community which is nearly always defined at a much more local level than country. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486391387.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>A sense of local community, a sense of whole country, its all the same thing when it comes down to it. Segregating it by degree of full separation from the whole doesn't change what it is. People working for the betterment of the system they believe in out of a sense of duty to the community of people it in turn serves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486415778.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>I think this conflation is dangerous and cuts at the core of the debate. It is very different to feel a sense of community to those you interact with on a regular basis than it is to some abstract notion of a nation. The latter is what leads to all the problems I listed in my OP because it is not based on real human connection but rather abstract political badges of honour. 

National borders of accidents of history. It makes no sense they should define who we are. Doing so doesn't help us address issues in a global world where nearly all the major issues are externalities which cant be addressed by one county (e.g., climate change, macroeconomics).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486559266.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think this conflation is dangerous and cuts at the core of the debate. It is very different to feel a sense of community to those you interact with on a regular basis than it is to some abstract notion of a nation.

Yet if you work on anything at a national level you are forming a community that is based on other communities. Representatives to the government are all from their individual communities, but that in turn forms a larger community. Its all degrees of separation but if you can see how people take pride in their local community that is the same sense of pride people feel about their nations, its just a question of scale. 

You see one of the largest differences between us is that I don't view a nation as some abstract concept. Nation states are incredibly well defined realities based not on accidents of history but by force and convention. 

While yes those decisions were made in a past they were made for a reason. Though you may not see the reason today you can see the force that enforces it.

&amp;gt;It makes no sense they should define who we are.

It makes sense because we are talking about nations being the largest units of governance that we have any control or influence over. Like it or not there is no global government that can deal with problems such as climate change. You can influence your country because you have ties to it. BUT you cannot influence another because you don't have ties to it. Taking pride in and working to better your particular unit of influence, in turn expands the unit of influences power and scope to effect said externalities. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486285456.0" user="TheManWhoWasNotShort" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Im going to suggest reading Sam Huntington's Clash of Civilizations

This is a very bad book. Feel free to read it, but it is one filled with American prejudices of the outside world, many of which do not stand up credibly to any comparison of these regions.  Most particularly striking is his utter lack of knowledge about Africa and Latin America and his insistence that Latin America is culturally different than what he defines as the West.  It's ultimately White Supremacist, as he divides nations not on real geopolitically accurate lines, but on American-defined racial lines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486319288.0" user="Ardonpitt" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I'm talking the original paper he wrote in Foreign Affairs (which I linked to). Not the book. I agree that his later theories fall far short due to his limitations of knowledge. I also would say his book hasn't aged well at all. The thing is he was working with geopolitical lines of the day (still that of the cold war, the paper was written 2 years after its end), ones that are far from accurate today. But that doesn't mean his original theory of the "idea" of culture as a dividing line of post cold war conflicts is bun, if anything its being proven correct. Look at the stances taken by modern nonstate actors as a prime example. Hell even Russia's actions are following the plan laid out in Foundations of Geopolitics which is a prime example of this post cold war thought. 

I would highly disagree with it being white supremacist, realize the author wasn't happy about these conflicts nor happy about them being a thing. Rather he was writing this as a predictive piece to what he thought further conflicts would be. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
