<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29486120073.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're confusing patriotism with nationalism, the latter being the more aggressive form.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486121014.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that just a difference in degree and not kind?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486123911.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>I would say patriotism is supporting your country's ideals and nationalism is more the thinking that everyone should follow those ideals all over the world. 

We can take this either way, I see value in both.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486135400.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>That's a fair point but I do think they exist on a continuum. I guess I would argue patriotism too often is nationalistic and we only hear about it when it is. My basic argument is that the minor benefits of patriotism are far less significant that the serious harm caused when it becomes nationalistic. Also, the latter is far more common than the former. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486153492.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>The minor benefits are not minor at all. Historically the strongest and most peaceful empires have been highly imperialistic and patriotic.  With these ideals comes unification and with unification there's peace.  Read about the periods of peace like the Pax Romana and the Pax Mongolica.  The peaceful period that began post WWII in America follows the same model.

This idea that they are anti progress and anti intellectual is nonsense.  Imperialism is literally the reason we have progressed so quickly.  I don't know where you get anti globalism since nationalism is the exact opposite.

I'm not going to touch the racism/sexism point.

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486191609.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>I really wanted to avoid a discussion of Trump in this thread but it is hard to do. His ideas on trade are a classic example of how patriotism is anti-progress. He thinks free trade is somehow a bad deal for America based nearly entirely on silly patriotic ideas which leads him to propose tariffs which will harm his economy and slow its growth. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486232200.0" user="sittinginabaralone" delta="False">
    <text>Donald Trump being a bad leader doesn't make nationalism bad.  Good systems have always been abused by bad leaders.  I'd rather discuss the ideals than the people who don't understand them.  Just like I don't like people using the USSR and Stalin to denounce communism as an ideal.

You raise a fair point regarding the *dangers* of applying nationalism, but nationalism itself doesn't include anti free trade.  If anything, it encourages it and is why global trade even exists.  

 </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
