<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29486258092.0" user="TheManWhoWasNotShort" delta="False">
    <text>Patriotism, if properly channeled, can lead to countries doing great things.  It was Patriotism that JFK used to sell the idea of going to the moon to the American people, and it was Patriotism that the USSR used to sell space exploration to its people.  There sheer amount of technology invented in the Cold War dickwaving contest between the US and Russia has advanced society forward by leaps and bounds. 

Patriotism also led to the end of colonialism.  From the US rebelling against the UK to eventually everyone's foreign territories, it led to the self-determination of many nations and an ability to determine their own futures instead of being held back by their colonial masters raiding them of resources.

You are right, patriotism can be dangerous. But you are wrong that it can't also be powerful and good.  Patriotism is whatever those trying to channel it make of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486388671.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This is my first attempt at CMV so I am trying to reply to the main opinion on Patriotism. I agree with the OP on many points regarding patriotism as not a useful value except one. The OP states:
"Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas."
I have always argued that America is a hyper-individualistic society and a hyper-stoic one. I think that there is really little sense of community and families are barely nuclear at that. Patriotism is needed to provide some sense of coherence for American families lost in meaningless consumerism that they believe is something of value. As a result, you have a society that openly values individualism and looks down on asking for help. As a result you have consumerism that does nothing to bring together communities. The end result is the "mother" value of patriotism which gives people something to cling to. I hope I addressed the main argument in the correct format for CMV and responded to the correct person. Thank you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486410406.0" user="Bukhahan" delta="False">
    <text>First attempt on CMV. I am trying to reply to the main opinion on Patriotism. I agree with the OP on many points regarding patriotism as not a useful value except one. The OP states: "Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas." I have always argued that America is a hyper-individualistic society and a hyper-stoic one. I think that there is really little sense of community and families are barely nuclear at that. Patriotism is needed to provide some sense of coherence for American families lost in meaningless consumerism that they believe is something of value. As a result, you have a society that openly values individualism and looks down on asking for help. As a result you have consumerism that does nothing to bring together communities. The end result is the "mother" value of patriotism which gives people something to cling to. I hope I addressed the main argument in the correct format for CMV and responded to the correct person. Thank you</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
