<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29487171397.0" user="nate_rausch" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. 

Patriotism has many redeeming values in its own. There's an element of loyalty there. There's an element of being consistent, reliable and therefore truthworthy across time. 

What you will find very unpatriotic people often feel like is that it can border on a sort of betrayal. A most extreme case would be if a Canadian joined a foreign force in a war as a spy. That would be very unpatriotic, and simultanously disloyal to the community he was a part of. 

Another thing patriotism does well is to err on the side of caution. Things are changing quickly now. So how quickly should Canada change? 
As we have seen before in both Russia, China, Cambodia, Nazi Germany - rapid change isn't always progress. Sometimes caring about the principles and taking care of that which is worth preserving is a valuable thing. 

Furthermore, I assume that you like me are temperementally on the left. But remember that we need both the right and the left, we just need to talk more. We need to left to rejuvenate us and solve new problems. But we also need the right to maintain order in society. The times we dispense with either always lead to catastrophe. 

I am from Norway myself, perhaps the healthiest society in the world. And also, you might be surprised to hear, a very patriotic one. We celebrate the national holiday and are very proud of our values, results from our good governance and many do their best to preserve that motivated by patriotism. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
