<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29486129737.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're assuming that in the absence of nationalism people would adopt a generous love for all mankind a globalism that benefits all.

That's generally not true. In the absence of nationalism political religious and tribal ideologies dominate and you tend to get violent thuggery towards most country people.

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truth_and_Reconciliation_Commission_(Canada)

That said, Canada has its own brutal past of rape, murder and child abduction to help achieve its globalistic agenda, with extreme brutality directed at natives to help them get in line with their politics.

http://ipolitics.ca/2017/03/13/guess-what-canada-were-racists/

And the Canadian dislike of Muslims who don't tend to fit in with globalistic agendas is well known.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486157033.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>I don't want to derail this into a debate over Canada. My point was not Canada is better than other nations. In fact, that would be a patriotic which is counter to my central theme. Of course, we have our own issue and past. 

This is not a discussion of which country is better than the other one.

I don't think your point holds that in the absence of patriotism people don't act in a more holistic sense. "Generous love for all" is a bit of stretch, but as I mentioned it appears to me that the more patriotic a country they less its political system functions well and the more likely it is to act in its own interest rather than global interest. Granted, I cannot cite data for this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486261355.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't want to derail this into a debate over Canada. My point was not Canada is better than other nations. In fact, that would be a patriotic which is counter to my central theme. Of course, we have our own issue and past.

My point wasn't that Canada is the worst, it was more that globalism often includes as a goal homogenizing natives and immigrants with murder, rape, and abduction. It's often not a great value. Respecting people's nations often leads to better results.


&amp;gt;I don't think your point holds that in the absence of patriotism people don't act in a more holistic sense. "Generous love for all" is a bit of stretch, but as I mentioned it appears to me that the more patriotic a country they less its political system functions well and the more likely it is to act in its own interest rather than global interest. Granted, I cannot cite data for this.

Look at somewhere like Afghanistan. Very weak nationalistic sense, people are generally warring tribes joined together by religion. Do you think that's a better place to live than a nationalistic nation?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
