<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29486127929.0" user="absolutefuckwit" delta="False">
    <text>I think the main benefit comes from the exporting of your values to the wider world. Of course introspective, jingoistic, "my-country-is-better-than-yours" will be bad, but what if you take what you learnt from your country and try and bring it into the wider world?

I'm British and I've only been to the USA once, but I've met a fair few Americans in London. I can never big up the NHS enough when I meet them, because Britain has universal healthcare and the USA doesn't. To me that's patriotism, using the examples you find in your own country to try and improve the lives of humanity across the globe.

Another example was a quote that made the rounds recently where a German described his patriotism as paying high taxes knowing it was making his country able to give free university, schooling and healthcare to those most in need.

I think pride in one's country can be good or bad, because you can be proud of things that are good or bad. I don't think the pride itself is a bad thing, it's the thing your proud of that is good or bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486143371.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>I agree being proud of a specific thing or feature of ones country is not a bad thing but that doesn't strike me as the typical use of the word patriotism. As you mention, that is not pride in ones country. My premise is that its the pride in ones country that is nearly always a bad thing because its smooths over the problems and pretends only the good things are true. 

Am I being patriotic when I say I am proud Canada has universal healthcare but being unpatriotic when I say we treat our First Nations terribly? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486151879.0" user="absolutefuckwit" delta="False">
    <text>So I'm proud of the NHS, which is a system made by British people. That mean's I'm proud of what British people did and still do. That also makes me proud to be British. Isn't that patriotism?

I think you have a problem with too much patriotism, because loving your country so much you can't see the problems is obviously not good. Patriotism in moderation does give you a lens through which to view all other countries and compare them to the country you're from. You can look at countries different to yours and see why they fall short of the one you are a part of. Does that make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486146674.0" user="Prupple" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I can never big up the NHS enough when I meet them, because Britain has universal healthcare and the USA doesn't. To me that's patriotism

That's not necessarily patriotism. You just have the opinion that the UK has better healthcare than the USA. If the healthcare systems were reversed, would you claim at that point that the UK's private health insurance was now better than the USA's universal publicly funded system?

When people make patriotic claims, they are generally saying that "my country's X is better than your X". *That can be a objectively true fact*. Being right wouldn't make the statement any less patriotic, and your statement of the NHS being better is both patriotic and (in my opinion) true. 

The danger of patriotism comes when a statement is patriotic and *wrong*. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486161273.0" user="absolutefuckwit" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say that it would make me less patriotic if the country moved away from what I believed in - I would feel like a stranger in my own neighbourhood. Patriotism cannot be exempt from how you feel about what is going on right now in your country. If we deported all immigrants Britain would become 'more British' but I would feel less patriotic, because I would love my country less for that decision.

As for 'my country is objectively better than your country' debate - personally I think the difference of opinion on what makes a good country is the reason why it can't be an objective fact. A German can say Germany is better than Greece because it has a higher GDP, less debt etc. but a Greek can say that Greece's national history is to them what makes Greece a better country than Germany, while Germany's past tarnishes its present. Both these people are right, they just disagree on what it means to be a  good country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486228356.0" user="Prupple" delta="False">
    <text>I think my reply wasn't worded very well, as I'm not completely following your comment. I wasn't intending to talk about subjective statements like "Germany is better than Greece", but about objectively provable facts. 

Let's take healthcare again as an example. It is an objectively provable (or disprovable) fact that UK's healthcare system, if implemented into the US, would result in less people going without treatment for curable diseases or declaring bankruptcy due to medical bills. For the sake of argument, lets assume this fact *has* been proved. And we can also assume that going without treatment and declaring bankruptcy are bad. 

A patriotic American and a patriotic Brit would meet to discuss healthcare and quickly reach an impasse, as neither would admit that their system was worse, and so the amount of Americans suffering needlessly wouldn't change. 

A non patriotic American and a non patriotic Brit would meet and realise that the British system was better, make attempts to implement it into the States and therefore save lives.

In these situations, it doesn't matter whether the Brit is patriotic or not, because coincidently his country is better in respect to healthcare. But in a reverse situation, his patriotism could cause similar harm.

Of course, these are hugely simplified examples, but hopefully they get the point across. Patriotism is simply a reason to hold an opinion. If that opinion is correct, no harm done. If that opinion is incorrect, then harm can be done. It's simply better to not take patriotism into account when deciding anything of substance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486271797.0" user="absolutefuckwit" delta="False">
    <text>ah I get what you mean - there's no benefit to being patriotic in any reasoned debate, that facts should win not where you're from.

Maybe you're right, but I think even the definition of better healthcare or, frankly, better 'anything' is almost impossible. An american could say his health system is more 'free' (you can chose your doctors) , has a higher standard if you can afford it etc. while the NHS is more egalitarian or whatever. 

I guess we'll have to agree to disagree, even if it's just on the topic of defining the best country but I do understand why patriotism doesn't add any value to an argument.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486340998.0" user="Prupple" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that's my only point really. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486367073.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; there's no benefit to being patriotic in any reasoned debate

This nicely cuts to the core of my position. Patriotism only clouds reason, it never enhances it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486835266.0" user="Inelukie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Patriotism is simply a reason to hold an opinion. If that opinion is correct, no harm done. If that opinion is incorrect, then harm can be done. It's simply better to not take patriotism into account when deciding anything of substance. 

I would strongly disagree with that definition. 

Another user posted a Churchill quotation on the word, which essentially boils down to: A person wanting and working for "the best" for "his country".

In your example the non patriotic American could simply say: "Who cares? I got my healthcare, the rest can die for all I care."

Not caring about the people around you is very normal in cases where others remain anonymous and far removed from your personal life. Patriotism gives people a common and shared identity. Soldiers don't have to know each other but still will be loyal to each other, just by the fact, that they are soldiers in the same army. That kind of feeling is patriotism for me. Loyality towards "your group".

A patriotic person could never let others die for stupid reasons. His fellow citizens are of utter importance for him and he can not shy away from his resonsibility to achieve the best solution for everyone else.

One might argue this clouds reasoning and maybe it does. Not giving a fuck about others most certainly doesn't produce good results, either. And why would I care about my fellow citizens who live far away from me or are in direct competition with me, when there is no connection between us at all?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
