<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29486576615.0" user="AskMeIfOPIsRelated" delta="False">
    <text>OP, do you agree with the following statement: People don't choose to be born in their country, so it is foolish to be proud of it."?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486601238.0" user="THHUXLEY" delta="False">
    <text>Sort of yes. Better stated would be people don't choose which country to be born into so it is foolish to think theirs is better than another based only on this accident. 

That is the core of patriotism, as I am using the term. It's a belief that their nation is great based on nothing but the fact that they are members of it. This is how it is commonly used today, in my opinion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29486653763.0" user="AskMeIfOPIsRelated" delta="False">
    <text>Then, do we as people have reason to have self-esteem, even though we didn't choose to be born? Some people "own" their hardships and want to improve themselves. Patriotism/Nationalism is self-esteem for nations. Saying nationalism makes one blind to a nation's flaws is akin to saying self-esteem makes you narcissistic. *You* didn't choose to put a man on the moon, but *they* did. When you do something good, you own it. Patriotism/Nationalism is just a container to hold your "good things". Same with self-esteem.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
