<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397464917.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kn1w5/cmvpatriotism_is_the_worst_emotion_and_has/">
    <title>CMV:Patriotism is the worst emotion and has basically no redeeming value</title>
    <original_poster>THHUXLEY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm Canadian and today is our 150th anniversary. It got me thinking about patriotism as did a recent episode of One the Media which can be found here;

http://www.wnyc.org/story/on-the-media-2017-06-30

Canadians are not very patriotic, at least compared to our American neighbours. I think a strong argument can be made that this is a huge benefit to Canadian culture and democracy. 

On the surface patriotism seems somewhat benign or even good. How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism. Our world is increasingly global yet patriotism only reinforces sectarian and tribal ideas. It can be argued it is largely responsible for the rise of the alt-right and the anti-globalism in America and elsewhere. 

It is also nearly always factually inaccurate. In nearly every case, people who think their country is the best in some way are just wrong about the facts.

Patriotism also reinforces otherness which leads to racism, sexism, anti-intellectualism and xenophobia.

Patriotism is always used as a political weapon with the sole purpose of stifling critical thinking or open debate. One is not to question any idea that can be wrapped in the guise of patriotism.

Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

I'd be curious to see data but I would hypothesize there is an inverse correlation between the levels of patriotism in a country and the health of its political system.

I honesty cannot think of a redeeming quality to patriotism. 

Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29487395991.0" user="GingerJack76" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How can it be bad to feel good about ones country? However, little good actually comes from patriotism.

The soldiers that die for you want the country to do well. The politicians in your congress and senate want the country to do well. In order for your country to succeed, you, and your fellow citizens have to actually want it to succeed. You need to want things to be better, and to do that you can't hold spite in your heart. Good change comes from people with good intentions, not from people who are constantly thinking they're country isn't important, or are spiteful to those who actually care about it.

Also, being agaisnt globalism isn't bad or wrong. I know you think it is, but it's not.

&amp;gt;Finally, patriotism nearly always blinds people to the problems in their own society and allows those problems to persist far longer than they should.

Trump. Seriously, everyone wanted their country to do well, got together, and voted someone to change the way it was run.

Maybe consider that there might be moderation. Being sad isn't all that great if it's keeping you from doing what you need to do to improve your situation, but being a little bit sad will help motivate you to make your situation better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
