<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397999908.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kyip0/cmv_students_who_excel_in_sports_should_not_have/">
    <title>CMV: Students who excel in sports should not have their sporting achievements weighed the same as someone with strong academic achievements in terms of being admitted into high-schools and universities.</title>
    <original_poster>sourmilky</original_poster>
    <original_post>Firstly, let me start by setting some context for my CMV.

The universities I know have specific criteria in which they can admit for points for someone who is trying to get into a degree. Hypothetically speaking, if Person A and Person B got the same final mark and is both trying to get into a degree - Person A would have an numerical advantage as they would be awarded with additional points/marks on their total mark due to their excellence in sports in an university, but does not have any relevance to their degree.

While I understand there maybe benefit in increasing notable alumni or their yearning for well-rounded students, I believe if they want to admit people for their strengths in extra-curriculars - they much either admit everybody that excels in acting/dance/music/acting, or none at all. It's incredibly unfair that certain students get an advantage over others because they know how to kick a ball, especially since it's irrelevant to the degree they pursue. In saying this, the odds of having sporting alumni 'making it' onto a team is very small. While it's nice to have an athletic person represent to school and dominate every game - it doesn't seem like a wise long-term investment for some short-term gain. Unlike disciplines which have a high employment rate, I don't understand how there are aspects like sporting scholarships which is on par with academic scholarships, when there doesn't seem to be a lot of jobs. 

The purpose of academia scholarships is to provide a financial cushion to bright students in hopes for their long-term contribution into society. I don't see how sports provide the same effect (and when I talk about long-term contribution into society, I mean the ability to provide essential help as a community). The purpose of sports I see is collectively as a form of entertainment which helps bind society and enjoying together - but isn't this concept also applicable to other extra-curriculars?

Due to this, I presume schools do this in order to increase school's image and gambling on the hopes for famous sporting alumni. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29490309730.0" user="maverickLI" delta="False">
    <text>Athletics can bring in millions of dollars for the university. TV rights, ticket sales, jersey sales, ect. This money is used to fund other aspects of the University, since the athletes bringing in those millions of dollars are not allowed to make any money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29490322213.0" user="sourmilky" delta="False">
    <text>This is probably true, however I don't see how it's fairs our in the long run. I don't think it's fair how you are being able to do sports prioritises you over someone mainly due to you being a source of income at the school - rather than the long-term goal of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29490348656.0" user="ReX-24" delta="False">
    <text>/u/maverickLI is 100% correct, those students that kick a ball in major sports are recruited by most universities with medium or large sports programs as immediate revenue generators. Those schools also have to balance their NCAA participation - NCAA female lacrosse teams get funding as the result of their NCAA men's basketball counterparts. 

How it's fair is that you as *only* a tuition-bringing student offer only a little bit in terms of immediate or short term revenue to the university at a scale that allows for capital investment. Is there a brand new dorm on campus? That dorm might have cost $15 million to build, but only houses 200 students paying $50,000 in tuition a year, only 10% of which would go to that kind of thing and not teacher salaries, landscape maintenance, sewage servings, etc. In rough terms, that means based on students alone, it would take 150 years for the school to pay off that dorm. That's a bit longer than the usefulness of a dorm building. But with a constant revenue stream backed by sports teams, they can get a loan and pay that off in a decade or less. 

How do you, as an academic-only student bring return on investment to the school? Being a good alumnus. Sending them good students to apply for admission 5, 10, 20 years later. Being a PhD researcher that discovers a cure for cancer in a lab at the school. Being elected president of a country or something and telling everyone your alma mater was ____ university. Driving around with a license plate frame that says "______ Alumni" or whatever. Will any of those bring the school $1 million a year from your actions alone? No. Maybe if you work at the U.S. News and World Report University rankings office and can change the survey results to bump them up to top 5 status, but realistically, once you finish paying tuition, you're probably not worth a whole lot to the university. So on a long timeline, it's a maybe at best that you'll be worth, over your lifetime, as much as a top-recruit NCAA sportball player is for one year. 

But so what for you? First, accept this as what it is. Those kids that kick a ball are doing *you* a favor by providing revenue to your school. And honestly, their chances of making it a career are very, very low. I'm not saying that you need to pity them, as they get special treatment the whole time at university, but that ball-kicker is working for you indirectly. You don't need to treat them like some sport deity either, but just know how the system works enough to know where everyone falls.  It's a shitty system, and there's a ton of lawsuits and issues related to this - like the fact that NCAA players can have their faces used in Xbox games but can't get any pay for that. But for now, that's what it is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29490594881.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You appear to have it backwards:

&amp;gt;On the other hand, it’s perhaps worth asking:  Is the fact that football isn’t profitable—or only for a rare and nearly unchanging few—necessarily a bad thing?  Large portions of the student body love football, right?  Even if this whole “student body” argument were true—and it’s probably not—Benedict and Keteyian put the problem in the following stark terms: Football Bowl Subdivision (FBS) schools spent more than $91,000 per athlete compared with just over $13,000 per student.  Yet students across the country faced steep tuition hikes and increased fees.(http://www.ethosreview.org/intellectual-spaces/is-college-football-profitable/)

The vast majority of college sports programs don't generate a profit, those that do only do so under the strictest definition of the word, and college athletes apparently cost universities 7 times as much as a regular student. The people making millions off of university sports are the ones who are getting favors, and ain't none of those people at universities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29491107170.0" user="ReX-24" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have it backwards, I have specifics in mind: 
http://www.ocregister.com/2015/10/16/ucla-athletics-reports-10-million-revenue-increase-for-2014-15/

I'm pretty sure that UCLA Making $44 million per year on football alone is enough to float every other team. 

Your article even backs up my point with another example: 

&amp;gt;The information recorded by the U.S. Department of Education shows that Alabama football did indeed subsidize almost all other sports at the university. 

So if I'm at one of the 120 top tier universities in the country, then yes, everything I said is perfectly valid. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29491235209.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I have specifics in mind: http://www.ocregister.com/2015/10/16/ucla-athletics-reports-10-million-revenue-increase-for-2014-15/

That article only talks about *revenue* and not the *profit* that would be necessary in order for sports programs to come anywhere close to subsidizing non sports students as you claim college sports teams do. All the article say is that the athletic department has reported a balanced budget of $96.91 million meaning they brought in that much revenue, and spent that much money in the process.

&amp;gt;I'm pretty sure that UCLA Making $44 million per year on football alone is enough to float every other team.

Your post wasn't about football subsidizing other teams. It was about athletic departments subsidizing non sports students. Please don't attempt to move goal posts.

Even at top tier universities, athletics **in no way shape or form, by any possible measure** subsidize or provided significant financial revenue for universities. Take your own advice and accept this for what it is.

To put it in context, sure, the UCLA athletics dept. **spent** and brought in $96 million dollars. The UCLA yearly budget is $6.7 billion. So the *total revenue* of the athletic dept, every penny they spent and made back makes up about 1.4% of the total budget. The payout for the UCLA endowment alone rival the athletic dept revenue (again **not profit** just money in after money out) at $83.2 million (https://www.uclafoundation.org/finances.aspx?content=highlights). And that 83.2 million is straight return on investments, profit, cash money available to spend on stuff. Not revenue.

&amp;gt;So if I'm at one of the 120 top tier universities in the country, then yes, everything I said is perfectly valid.

Absolutely not. Not even close. If you're at one of the top **25 football schools** in the country, there's a good chance that the athletic dept. is breaking even or making an incredibly modest profit ($10 million after $150 million in expenditures) and that profit, 9 times out of 10, goes back into the athletics dept. And even then you have to ignore the myriad ways that the dept. is subsidized by the school.

Also, if your point requires that we ignore the *vast* majority of cases and only look at the few in which you are correct, you have no point.

There is not one school in this country whose regular student body is in anyway subsidized by the sports program as you have stated. Not one. 

Edit:http://projects.huffingtonpost.com/ncaa/sports-at-any-cost

https://www.forbes.com/sites/ccap/2014/12/12/who-actually-funds-intercollegiate-athletic-programs/#5aca14c117af

https://thinkprogress.org/why-students-and-taxpayers-are-subsidizing-college-sports-and-how-we-might-fix-it-b9d94723e4a1

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/grade-point/wp/2015/11/18/college-students-are-bankrolling-the-athletic-ambitions-of-universities/?utm_term=.a76004df018a</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29492894939.0" user="ReX-24" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I went to one of those top 25 football schools, so this was a common topic for discussion. Times change I guess. I recall seeing a Frontline about NCAA basketball that was the majority of where I got my information about this, but I'm happy to admit that I'm wrong and that OP should hold nothing but vile and contempt in his heart for sportball players of any sort. I'm fine with that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493382787.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but I'm happy to admit that I'm wrong and that OP should hold nothing but vile and contempt in his heart for sportball players of any sort. I'm fine with that.

Why it gotta be that way? Who, besides you, has said a fucking thing about "vile contempt"?

Why can't ya just admit that you're wrong without qualifying it and trying to cast OP as some sort of villain?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29495130541.0" user="ReX-24" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't being sarcastic and I did admit I'm wrong - why do you need more? I wanted to suggest vile contempt first as it seems appropriate. When the athletes were funding my education, I was happy to have them around. Now I learn that most people are funding the athletes with crushing student loan debt? No way in hell I'm going to look at the chunk of my paycheck I send off every month, say "go Bruins" and wish that upon other people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29495193621.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I wanted to suggest vile contempt first as it seems appropriate

How on earth was it appropriate? Literally no one mentioned it, or exhibited it until you brought it up?

&amp;gt;When the athletes were funding my education, I was happy to have them around. Now I learn that most people are funding the athletes with crushing student loan debt? No way in hell I'm going to look at the chunk of my paycheck I send off every month, say "go Bruins" and wish that upon other people.

What the fuck are you going on about? Athletes were never funding your education. Theres no need for vile contempt. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29496402638.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29496429455.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>ReX-24, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostility extremely seriously. Repeated violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+ReX-24&amp;amp;message=ReX-24+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6kyip0/cmv_students_who_excel_in_sports_should_not_have/djte9xq/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29490580223.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This is a lie that needs to be taken out behind the shed and shot.

At *absolute best* it could be said that *some* of the top ten most popular college football teams generate a lot of revenue but spend most of that revenue on themselves. In terms of profit, the margins for even the highest earning teams are thin or vanish completely when the perks/subsidies of being associated with an established university are taken into account (Tax exempt status, public subsidies, student tuition, etc.).

To put it into fantastic perspective:

&amp;gt;The standard narrative about the profitability of football for non-athletic arenas of the university is also a series of half-truths.  Back to Alabama football.  Of the $110 million of football revenue, less than $6.5 million went to the university to pay for scholarships, faculty support, and the Acts of Kindness fund.  In other words, 5.9% of the football program’s revenue goes toward “academic programming.” However, even that percentage of the revenue given to academics isn’t entirely divorced from athletics, because universities often fold a portion of those funds back into athletic scholarships.  The football program at the University of Florida, for example, contributed $7.2 million to academic programing, while only $1.5 million of that revenue was earmarked for non-athletic scholarships. The muddled—perhaps diluted—contribution of revenue from football is particularly dubious when athletics received a $2 million dollar increase in their budget at the same time as the University eliminated its Computer Science Department in 2012 to save $1.4 million.  Furthermore, when the University’s “education and general” expenditures amount to $524.6 million, the $7.2 million of revenue generated by the football team is far from a critical source of funds. While there’s certainly truth to the idea of non-athletic “profitability” among certain top-tier football schools, it’s a slim and muddied percentage of the program’s actual revenue.  In fact, the real money to be made by big-time college football is actually found outside the university. (But that’s an issue for another post…)

(http://www.ethosreview.org/intellectual-spaces/is-college-football-profitable/)

For a bit more perspective The University of Florida endowment is 1.8ish *billion* dollars. They would not be hurting in the least if their football team disappeared tomorrow.


As that author said: There's shit loads of money to be made in college sports, but almost none of it goes to the colleges.

More articles that come to the same conclusion:

http://www.ncaa.org/about/resources/media-center/news/athletics-departments-make-more-they-spend-still-minority

http://www.washingtonpost.com/sf/sports/wp/2015/11/23/running-up-the-bills/?utm_term=.cd64f0a116fc




</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
