<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397999908.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kyip0/cmv_students_who_excel_in_sports_should_not_have/">
    <title>CMV: Students who excel in sports should not have their sporting achievements weighed the same as someone with strong academic achievements in terms of being admitted into high-schools and universities.</title>
    <original_poster>sourmilky</original_poster>
    <original_post>Firstly, let me start by setting some context for my CMV.

The universities I know have specific criteria in which they can admit for points for someone who is trying to get into a degree. Hypothetically speaking, if Person A and Person B got the same final mark and is both trying to get into a degree - Person A would have an numerical advantage as they would be awarded with additional points/marks on their total mark due to their excellence in sports in an university, but does not have any relevance to their degree.

While I understand there maybe benefit in increasing notable alumni or their yearning for well-rounded students, I believe if they want to admit people for their strengths in extra-curriculars - they much either admit everybody that excels in acting/dance/music/acting, or none at all. It's incredibly unfair that certain students get an advantage over others because they know how to kick a ball, especially since it's irrelevant to the degree they pursue. In saying this, the odds of having sporting alumni 'making it' onto a team is very small. While it's nice to have an athletic person represent to school and dominate every game - it doesn't seem like a wise long-term investment for some short-term gain. Unlike disciplines which have a high employment rate, I don't understand how there are aspects like sporting scholarships which is on par with academic scholarships, when there doesn't seem to be a lot of jobs. 

The purpose of academia scholarships is to provide a financial cushion to bright students in hopes for their long-term contribution into society. I don't see how sports provide the same effect (and when I talk about long-term contribution into society, I mean the ability to provide essential help as a community). The purpose of sports I see is collectively as a form of entertainment which helps bind society and enjoying together - but isn't this concept also applicable to other extra-curriculars?

Due to this, I presume schools do this in order to increase school's image and gambling on the hopes for famous sporting alumni. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29490593486.0" user="lordusan" delta="False">
    <text>I plan to pursue law as my career. Why should my achievements/grades in physics, chemistry, earth science, algebra, calculus, etc. be relevant to my college application assuming my career path does not utilize these. The reason is because these subjects show my 'skill' at learning and should reveal positive traits about myself to colleges. 


Why are sports different? People like to play the genetics card, but IQ is genetic as well. Additionally, it doesn't matter whether you have perfect genes for smarts or athletics, both groups work very hard for their achievements. Ultimately, colleges seek dedicated, distinguished, well rounded individuals. While the trope of the dumb football player is humorous, people who play sports have been shown to do, on average, better in school. 


[iq is connected to genetics](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heritability_of_IQ) 


[people who play sports do better in school](https://news.ku.edu/2014/01/15/study-shows-high-school-athletes-performed-better-school-persisted-graduation-more-non) </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
