<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="397999908.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6kyip0/cmv_students_who_excel_in_sports_should_not_have/">
    <title>CMV: Students who excel in sports should not have their sporting achievements weighed the same as someone with strong academic achievements in terms of being admitted into high-schools and universities.</title>
    <original_poster>sourmilky</original_poster>
    <original_post>Firstly, let me start by setting some context for my CMV.

The universities I know have specific criteria in which they can admit for points for someone who is trying to get into a degree. Hypothetically speaking, if Person A and Person B got the same final mark and is both trying to get into a degree - Person A would have an numerical advantage as they would be awarded with additional points/marks on their total mark due to their excellence in sports in an university, but does not have any relevance to their degree.

While I understand there maybe benefit in increasing notable alumni or their yearning for well-rounded students, I believe if they want to admit people for their strengths in extra-curriculars - they much either admit everybody that excels in acting/dance/music/acting, or none at all. It's incredibly unfair that certain students get an advantage over others because they know how to kick a ball, especially since it's irrelevant to the degree they pursue. In saying this, the odds of having sporting alumni 'making it' onto a team is very small. While it's nice to have an athletic person represent to school and dominate every game - it doesn't seem like a wise long-term investment for some short-term gain. Unlike disciplines which have a high employment rate, I don't understand how there are aspects like sporting scholarships which is on par with academic scholarships, when there doesn't seem to be a lot of jobs. 

The purpose of academia scholarships is to provide a financial cushion to bright students in hopes for their long-term contribution into society. I don't see how sports provide the same effect (and when I talk about long-term contribution into society, I mean the ability to provide essential help as a community). The purpose of sports I see is collectively as a form of entertainment which helps bind society and enjoying together - but isn't this concept also applicable to other extra-curriculars?

Due to this, I presume schools do this in order to increase school's image and gambling on the hopes for famous sporting alumni. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29490320319.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hypothetically speaking, if Person A and Person B got the same final mark and is both trying to get into a degree - Person A would have an numerical advantage as they would be awarded with additional points/marks on their total mark due to their excellence in sports in an university, but does not have any relevance to their degree.

Is that true, though? Honestly, I don't know how the actual points were awarded, but the colleges I applied to absolutely took into account all extracurricular activities. So if Person A did sports and Person B did *nothing*, A would get in. But if Person B participated in some other non-athletic extracurricular, it would contribute points to her/his admittance score.

And, like you mention, universities are looking for well-rounded individuals, and one way to measure that is by participation in things outside of standard academics. I don't think it makes sense to exclusively use academics as a measure of admittance. For instance, I think it's perfectly reasonable that a student with a 3.6 who participated in extracurricular activities or held down a job outside of school would be admitted over a 4.0 student who did nothing beyond academics. While colleges are about academics, they're also about building engaging communities on campus, and in order to do that it takes people who will participate beyond going to class and doing homework.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29490336096.0" user="sourmilky" delta="False">
    <text>I'm speaking for a contextual view in Australia where certain points are awarded on top of our final mark - sports being included alongside with others which are variations of academia.

I do agree well-roundedness is essential for a university culture, however I believe there is a sense of hierarchy when it comes to which extra-curricular. From experience, sporting achievements are more favoured over musical or artistic achievements, mainly due to how it can increase popularity and monetary gains of the school itself. I feel like if schools want to have more people who are well-rounded, I agree, but I don't think it should be limited or favoured towards those who excel in sports.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29490373471.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I feel like if schools want to have more people who are well-rounded, I agree, but I don't think it should be limited or favoured towards those who excel in sports.

But it is not limited to sports, which you agree with in saying "sports being included alongside with others," so your problem is that sports are favored vs. other achievements. Is that true, though?

&amp;gt; I'm speaking for a contextual view in Australia where certain points are awarded on top of our final mark

Are the points awarded such that sports counts for more than other activities? All other things being equal, if student A is an exceptional swimmer who participated in 4 years of swimming, and student B is a champion debater who participated in 4 years of debate club, does A earn more points than B?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493850362.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Very few sports at very few schools turn a profit. Almost none do outside of men's football at the highest levels (top power 5 conference schools) and men's basketball (less overhead to overcome compared to football). Schools continue with sports because of tradition, entertainment, and community-building. Few other events can draw entire communities together like a football Saturday in a college town. Sports are big business and many schools offer sports-related academic programs such as athletic training, physical therapy, sports management, turf/ golf course management, physical education, coaching, and, in rare cases, professional athlete. There are a lot of people making a living in the world of sports and colleges and universities should offer programs to train those people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
