<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="398392859.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6l6xwb/cmv_i_dont_understand_why_everyone_loves_wonder/">
    <title>CMV: I don't understand why everyone loves Wonder Woman</title>
    <original_poster>LilYonsan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Could someone help a cis-gendered white male understand why critics and people alike are raving about the new Wonder Woman movie? Having seen the movie myself, I really just don't understand what all the hype is about and when I think about this movie I seem to think about three main points that I just can't get around: the movie felt formulaic, the music was sub-par and predictable, and finally the movie's role in relation to my current ideas of gender.

**Wonder Woman felt formulaic:** 
This is one of my main criticisms of the movie, and I think it has come from the movie market being over-saturated with superhero movies as of late. Other than the first two batman movies (and maybe the third), I laugh at the relative quality of DC's live-action movies compared to their Animated Universe counterpart. Wonder Woman does what every other superhero movie has already done, the only difference was that it was a female lead (which I'll get more into later), my complaint was the result to me felt uninspired and the execution of the scenes was unoriginal (When viewing many of the fight scenes in this movie, I was reminded of 300)

**The Music Felt Bland:**
As a musician myself, I feel the music also played a large role in my lack of interest. I'd like to start off this point but suggesting readers watch this video [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vfqkvwW2fs) to get a better understanding of where I'm coming from on this point. You don't have to, but it might help. If not, basically the point of the video is that, due to many factors, the music in movies and what composers are actually allowed to compose has been limited, resulting in a more neutral and uninspired soundtrack as a whole. There are only two sections in the movie featuring a cello playing a leading-tone into a tonic with loud drums behind it that stood out, and honestly I think the only reason it stood out was because they turned the music up slightly louder than they did the sound effects. 

**With regard to Gender:**

Which brings me to the point of this movie that I'm really trying to wrap my head around. "Maybe", I thought, "that is the point. That it's just like all of the superhero movies that feature men, but shows that a woman can do it just as well". Before I go on this topic, I'm glad to see more movies that feature female leads (this and ghostbusters I think do some good in a societal level, especially given some of the political turmoil this country has been in as of late), but if that is the entire point then, like my other complaints, movies like Kill Bill and Alien did it better because they weren't so preachy about it. To me, Wonder Woman took the approach "she does this despite the fact that she's a woman because she's powerful, rooooaaaar!!", whereas Ripley in Alien and **bleep** in Kill Bill were just badasses because they were and that was the end of discussion. 

In summary, it's not that I thought that Wonder Woman was a terrible movie, but I don't think it deserves nearly the praise and hype that it received, and I felt like I could have spent the time watching that movie doing something more meaningful. But, as I mentioned at the beginning of this topic, I'm a guy, so maybe I'm just not getting something here. Please, change my view reddit because I would really like to understand better what I don't already! 

Thanks for reading! 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29493282303.0" user="Terex80" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't part of the hype from it's competence in comparison to the other DC movies? I know that's not a good justification in of itself but it is important. If the studios know this is a good movie we'll likely get better stuff in future  (assuming they listen to criticism) 

Also with regards to gender, wouldn't it be weird if people didn't make a point about her 'just' being a woman given the setting of WW1? Ripley is several hundred years in the future and as far as I can see there isn't any hint of widespread sexism at all in the alien  universe like there was in the early 1900s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493297089.0" user="LilYonsan" delta="False">
    <text>Call it a personal bias if you will, but I think that if DC and Warner were to promote their Animated Universe the way they promote their movies, I think they would be in equal competition with the kinds of movies that Marvel/Disney are putting out. And one movie being good when compared to the two or three that came before it being flops to me should not constitute hype. Hell, I wouldn't even encourage that sort of behavior because we really don't need another superhero series. Enough is enough, I'm tired of looking around everywhere seeing a superhero or something related to superheroes. The saying in comedy when you go too long on the same joke is called "beating a dead horse". If you were to apply that here, the horse at this point is ground meat that is nice and tender. 

I see what you're saying on that second point, but I still feel like the creators of the movie were being preachy about it, and that ended up getting in the way of the quality of the movie. If anything, I would argue that the fact that Alien is a movie that came out far before Wonder Woman, and yet treated having a female lead that much more maturely when presented in the context of the movie just goes to show how much better of a movie Alien was, and how much less creative Wonder Woman was. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493313890.0" user="Terex80" delta="False">
    <text>Of course genres go in cycles of use. The exact same thing was being said about westerns when they were big. But the thing is movies will adapt and improve the genre, just look at marvel with deadpool. 

But imagine in wonderwoman if they all went around being 'Gee I completely have faith in that woman, I mean she shouldn't be able to vote but I won't say anything about her gender'. I'd argue many would find it a bit weird to say the least if no-one mentioned it. For context women only got equal voting rights in 1926 and even then it was a move to increase Conservative vote share 

I don't think it's relevant how good 
alien is though, most movies are crap compared with it, this isn't about whether wonder woman is somehow better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493374983.0" user="LilYonsan" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that in those scenes they should have just entirely ignored the fact that she was a woman, that would have seemed entirely out of place, but if we're going to talk in the sense of realism, then we should deal with the fact that a potentially compromised spy walked almost freely around war-time London, having unfettered access to world leaders at his whim, instead of reporting to someone directly in the military was a bit odd too. Personally, I felt like the whole bit where she came in to the world leader's felt kinda forced because I didn't think it would have been congruent with the life that a spy would lead. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29495353405.0" user="stegateratops" delta="False">
    <text>I guess the difference is that spies were not a disenfranchised group, or the subject of massive social inequality, with far-reaching and ongoing implications on current society. 

It's not really an issue to stretch realism in the depiction of a spy. But deliberately ignoring historic sexism and misogyny would be extremely controversial and political.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493452147.0" user="on_my_lunch_break" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if DC and Warner were to promote their Animated Universe the way they promote their movies, I think they would be in equal competition with the kinds of movies that Marvel/Disney are putting out.

But those two types of media have very different audiences.  Marvel live action movies are mainstream now,  not a nerd thing anymore.  But *animated* superhero movies are decidedly not mainstream,  and i don't see how they could appeal to those crowds. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493551332.0" user="LilYonsan" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps, but I think many of us could agree that their current plan of releasing movies like Suicide Squad hasn't really been doing them any favors either</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493563669.0" user="on_my_lunch_break" delta="False">
    <text>Sure. Which is why Wonder Woman is a breath of fresh air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493852829.0" user="este_hombre" delta="False">
    <text>It's been doing them the favor of making money. WB would never try to promote a cartoon with a big summer blockbuster release because they want people to take it seriously. I don't agree that cartoons make it less serious, but a significant portion of the population would write off an animated DC movie without seeing it. WB is first and foremost trying to make money, which Suicide Squad does a thousand times better than Assault on Arkham. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493454052.0" user="on_my_lunch_break" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I still feel like the creators of the movie were being preachy about it

Can you give some examples of how they were being preachy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493577829.0" user="LilYonsan" delta="False">
    <text>**spoilers ahead**

The primary example is when she's talking to (what I assume?) are the house of Lords. I felt like the scene itself was somewhat shoe-horned in because not only was the fact that a spy was there without anyone asking any questions was unrealistic but because something like that was so absurd I would argue the entire point of putting the scene in was because she's a woman and to demonstrate her force of will. That sort of demonstration is all fine and dandy, but it leaves me with the feeling that I'm being preached to. 
 
Now I identify as an "adult" male, so I obviously have NO understanding of how that sort of scene would impart on younger children, especially young women. 

I think a lot of these arguments are going to change too depending on how they write Diana's character in the future. If they keep her as this innocent woman who hasn't seen the world yet (which I think the movie made pretty clear they weren't going to do, nor would that make sense), then I think that would work against the progress a movie like this might make. If they turn her into a bonafide badass with no room for questions, hell yeah let's see some cool stuff. Until then, given the fact that there is only one movie we're basing this off of, that's the only example I can give. I'll let you decide if you think that's good enough or not.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493765050.0" user="epicazeroth" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that scene was about Diana being a woman.  It was more about her being an outsider – she doesn't understand how modern war works, and she so she's both naïve and clear-eyed about the (real or perceived) callousness of the generals.  Steve was there because he was high enough in the command structure to warrant it.  It was his information that they were talking about after all.

And I think that BvS (and the JL trailers) proves that modern day Diana is nowhere near as innocent as she was a hundred years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493970429.0" user="LiterallyBismarck" delta="False">
    <text>I really did not get the feeling that the whole scene was that unrealistic or "absurd". Pine wanted to get the information to someone who was ranked highly enough to do something as fast as possible, and that person happened to be in a war council at the time. I think it actually did a very good job establishing Diana's character, and I think all the reactions to her barging into the meeting were appropriate for men at a time when women weren't even allowed to vote. What, specifically, seemed strange to you about the scene?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493641903.0" user="FroVice" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that many people were sexist in the WW1 time period, but I would have been more than happy to suspend my disbelief if there had been way less overt sexism. I mean, the movie is about gods fighting, I think the dedication to realism is out the window.

That being said, it kinda feels like this movie isnt trying to prove that women are equal to men in the way that Alien or Kill Bill do it, by ignoring gender roles. As I think about it, the movie is trying to empower women and show that they deal with a lot of bullshit because of sexism but prevail through it all and kick ass.

I can imagine being a woman and relating to a lot of the sexism portrayed in the movie (although it seems a bit exaggerated compared to current times in America) and feeling validated/inspired by her rise to respect and power.

I am not a woman and dont know exaxtly what I'm talking about, but thats my first thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493773463.0" user="orpheus090" delta="False">
    <text>I think you completely nailed it. 

However, Ripley and Kill Bill are not really progressive movie characters that equalize gender at all. They are women that are, ultimately, playing male roles. I think that type of gender subversion in film is important and can be especially fun but it does send the message that for a women to considered truly equal, they must give up that which makes them women and behave like men.  

On the flip side, Wonder Women is actually a women's story. To conflate a character like Ripley with that of Wonder Women really belies the discomfort many men still feel when confronted with stories that are not wholly about them or their experiences.  It's kind of sad that telling a women's story using arguably the most iconic and culturally impactful female character in fiction is considered preachy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493870507.0" user="Inelukie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  It's kind of sad that telling a women's story using arguably the most iconic and culturally impactful female character in fiction is considered preachy. 

Very interesting comment. I'd even say you are right with that statement.

The threshold for being "preachy" is essentially using "the female perspective". But isn't this true for the other side as well? Super "male" movies are so much over the top, it usually is a comedy or a brain-dead action movie. Normal male characters don't make a point of showing males being super male either. The characters just happen to be awesome. Same for Ripley. That concept works.

On the other hand and with all due respect: I'm honestly not interested in this female perspective as a male. Its literally not my world. It doesn't speak to me at all. I'm not against it, I'm just left with this "Ok...and now? Why was that important? I don't get it." feeling.

I liked WW as a hero, but the way she was presented was too forceful at times, too bland at others. The whole plot made no sense whatsoever and it left me with an Ok-ish feeling. Maybe these imperfect points where on purpose, to make her relatable for women. For me as a man, I still like Black Widow more, even though I adore WW for being so feminine. I loved her being so womanly, so feminine for real! Yet, the results are... mediocre at best.

To state this clearly: I'm not against making movies like that. If women think thats a cool thing, have fun with it! For some reason women might be more comfortable with watching "male" movies than guys are with watching "female" movies. I really don't know. "Chick flicks" just don't click with me. I don't feel like I'm the audience who is supposed to watch this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29495337874.0" user="stegateratops" delta="False">
    <text>I think part of the problem is this idea that "women's films" are chick flicks, and not aimed at men. 

Reverse it and imagine a woman declaring that she isn't interested in the male perspective in films. The odd male character is fine, maybe as a support, but an overtly masculine lead role is off-putting. What would this leave her with? A handful of romantic comedies at best. 

You can afford to say you don't relate to female leads, because the majority of films cater to this view. A female lead is unusual in an action/crime/sci-fi/fantasy film (basically any genre except romantic comedy). If you're a woman who enjoys those genres, then you don't have the luxury of saying you don't like male leads. 

I would love it if there came a time when men and women were in the same boat, and neither could say "I don't watch female/male leads" because this would exclude them from too many great films</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29496830866.0" user="orpheus090" delta="False">
    <text>You say with all due respect but your view is the epitome of disrespectful. Maybe you believe that no actual respect is due to a woman's perspective or maybe you are simply oblivious to how fundamentally sexist your mindset is. Either way, I hope you engage in some serious introspection and are one day able to unpack your sexist attitudes so you can see woman and their experiences as worthy of the same respect and dignity you afford to men. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
