<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="398392859.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6l6xwb/cmv_i_dont_understand_why_everyone_loves_wonder/">
    <title>CMV: I don't understand why everyone loves Wonder Woman</title>
    <original_poster>LilYonsan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Could someone help a cis-gendered white male understand why critics and people alike are raving about the new Wonder Woman movie? Having seen the movie myself, I really just don't understand what all the hype is about and when I think about this movie I seem to think about three main points that I just can't get around: the movie felt formulaic, the music was sub-par and predictable, and finally the movie's role in relation to my current ideas of gender.

**Wonder Woman felt formulaic:** 
This is one of my main criticisms of the movie, and I think it has come from the movie market being over-saturated with superhero movies as of late. Other than the first two batman movies (and maybe the third), I laugh at the relative quality of DC's live-action movies compared to their Animated Universe counterpart. Wonder Woman does what every other superhero movie has already done, the only difference was that it was a female lead (which I'll get more into later), my complaint was the result to me felt uninspired and the execution of the scenes was unoriginal (When viewing many of the fight scenes in this movie, I was reminded of 300)

**The Music Felt Bland:**
As a musician myself, I feel the music also played a large role in my lack of interest. I'd like to start off this point but suggesting readers watch this video [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vfqkvwW2fs) to get a better understanding of where I'm coming from on this point. You don't have to, but it might help. If not, basically the point of the video is that, due to many factors, the music in movies and what composers are actually allowed to compose has been limited, resulting in a more neutral and uninspired soundtrack as a whole. There are only two sections in the movie featuring a cello playing a leading-tone into a tonic with loud drums behind it that stood out, and honestly I think the only reason it stood out was because they turned the music up slightly louder than they did the sound effects. 

**With regard to Gender:**

Which brings me to the point of this movie that I'm really trying to wrap my head around. "Maybe", I thought, "that is the point. That it's just like all of the superhero movies that feature men, but shows that a woman can do it just as well". Before I go on this topic, I'm glad to see more movies that feature female leads (this and ghostbusters I think do some good in a societal level, especially given some of the political turmoil this country has been in as of late), but if that is the entire point then, like my other complaints, movies like Kill Bill and Alien did it better because they weren't so preachy about it. To me, Wonder Woman took the approach "she does this despite the fact that she's a woman because she's powerful, rooooaaaar!!", whereas Ripley in Alien and **bleep** in Kill Bill were just badasses because they were and that was the end of discussion. 

In summary, it's not that I thought that Wonder Woman was a terrible movie, but I don't think it deserves nearly the praise and hype that it received, and I felt like I could have spent the time watching that movie doing something more meaningful. But, as I mentioned at the beginning of this topic, I'm a guy, so maybe I'm just not getting something here. Please, change my view reddit because I would really like to understand better what I don't already! 

Thanks for reading! 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29493466113.0" user="ShreddingRoses" delta="False">
    <text>As a woman and feminist there were a couple points where I felt the treatment of women in the film was above par.

1) little to no sexual objectification. This is actually uncomfortably prevalent in comics and comic based film adaptations.

2) wonder woman is a tank. Her powers aren't cute. She just kicks ass and she does it as a flying brick.

3) pine's character never once seems to be threatened by her strength or independence. This chick could literally snap him in two but he is still willing to hit that. He is woke as fuck.

4) her thighs jiggled on screen.

5) it passes the bechdel test.

It really did do justice to women as representation goes. It was, Ill admit, not actually groundbreaking in other realms but that doesn't matter. Little girls everywhere have a really solid feminine role model now and that's positively a good thing.

I do agree that Aliens does it way better. Ripley could have been written as a man and it wouldn't have altered the story at all which is how it should be done. Plus she looks positively unattractive when she gets sweaty and that's much more true to reality. Still. Wonder woman did a pretty damned good  job in its own way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493774045.0" user="epicazeroth" delta="False">
    <text>Minor note:  Ripley is a fundamentally different character from Wonder Woman.  Ripley was purposefully written as gender-neutral before casting, and Sigourney Weaver happens to be a woman.  So it makes sense for Ripley's femininity to be a non-issue, but Wonder Woman is inherently specifically about a woman in WWI.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493780212.0" user="ShreddingRoses" delta="False">
    <text>Right. Ripley was a character who was not defined by her gender while wonder woman is a character who IS defined by her gender but in overwhelmingly empowering way. It's two very different takes but both feminist as fuck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29494602793.0" user="thesmokingpants" delta="False">
    <text>No it's about a superhero who has nothing  to do with real people at all. Ripley was a realistic character that people can relate to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29494657655.0" user="epicazeroth" delta="False">
    <text>Just because a character has superpowers doesn't mean they're not a person.  Wonder Woman is still (for all intents and purposes) human.  Are you saying that no character with powers has ever faced struggles relatable to those of people in the real world?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29496674350.0" user="thesmokingpants" delta="False">
    <text>That's exactly what it means though. She is a demigod. A fantasy that doesn't apply to reality. It can serve as a childish emotional release an not much more. She is deeply simplistic. A God can't be a role model because it doesn't have limitations like a human does. Role models are about what you can do with your limitations and how to get past your fear and weakness. 
Focusing on wonder woman as a breath of fresh air is more of a sign of our infantalizing culture more than anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493804762.0" user="SupriseGinger" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;4) her thighs jiggled on screen.

Sheeeeiiiiit I really need to see this movie huh?

As a somewhat related aside to your other comments, I just don't get why men in general are ever threatened by a capable women (well I understand, but it just seems so dumb).

As a guy, nothing is more attractive than a women who could kick my ass at something I am good at or highly value. Not only is it a sign that she can take care of herself and be a functioning person on her own, it also means I could potentially learn or better myself from her. 

As dumb as it sounds, for all the bitching and swearing I might do when losing in a video game,  I am probably enjoying myself the most at those times because of the challenge. 

Friends are fun but a "rival" is funerer! I mean have you ever [hate cuddled someone](https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=vVJDI_2BrZk), you got to try it :p</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493809409.0" user="ShreddingRoses" delta="False">
    <text>They're threatened because they think they're supposed to be. It's so dumb honestly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29494043520.0" user="TheConstipatedPepsi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As a guy, nothing is more attractive than a women who could kick my ass at something I am good at or highly value.

then you are in the vast minority of guys, there are plenty of things greatly more attractive than a woman who can kick your ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29494059580.0" user="SupriseGinger" delta="False">
    <text>Is there something you are getting at? Your post appears to have some subtext, but I'm not sure what exactly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29494094283.0" user="TheConstipatedPepsi" delta="False">
    <text>All I'm getting at is that very few guys share your belief that nothing is more attractive than a woman who can kick their ass. Attraction is an extremely personal thing on which people have no real control, a man not being attracted to a woman who overpowers him in some domain is not automatically sexist or bad in some way, it's simply a personal preference, you can argue that this preference is caused by society, and it probably is to some extent, but I don't think that a given person is doing something morally bad by having that preference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493824724.0" user="politicalanalysis" delta="False">
    <text>I think your point on number one is really, really important as to why the movie is being praised so much by feminists. It's sort of subtle because we have come to expect that when a woman dressed sexily (as Gal Godot is in her Wonder Woman gear) we will see a camera shot panning up her body giving the viewer time to think about how much they want to fuck her. This film doesn't do that. Gadot has her sexy outfit, but it is just that, a costume or uniform. It isn't something used to sell men on the movie or to sexualize the character. We don't get a slow pan of her tits and ass. We get shots of her as we would any other character. 

Examples of the sort of thing I'm talking about: https://youtu.be/w6zGX2qpxzU
https://youtu.be/pMYyemI0nxY

Both clips have really good looking women wearing similar things. One objectifies the woman, the other doesn't. That's a big deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493832690.0" user="ShreddingRoses" delta="False">
    <text>Yup. It's what I appreciated the most honestly. Shes clearly drop dead gorgeous, but they aren't trying to sell that fact. It's incidental.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493884874.0" user="wineandcheese" delta="False">
    <text>It was actually *remarkable* the difference between the **same** motherfucking character and how she was represented by a female director and a male director. I saw WW first, in theaters, and then I watched B v. S because I wanted to sort of...complete the collection, I guess. Anyway, there was one point where WW is wearing a white suit...without a shirt. Like, where is her shirt? She's just not wearing one. It was completely jarring after watching WW and seeing how it's possible for a woman to be shown on screen without being sexually objectified.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493944865.0" user="k9centipede" delta="False">
    <text>When I saw WW there were so many scenes where I was like "and now for the panty shot!" Etc, and it never happened! 

I think maybe once scene got close, when they were swimming, but I think it would have been shot the same way if it was a dude, so I wouldn't count it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29494727617.0" user="FroVice" delta="False">
    <text>Good post, one thing I didnt like was that it didnt seem to pass the bechdel test once she left the island. Also Chris Pine blew a conversation with the villain woman because WW was hotter than the villain.

Also Im pretty sure that ripley's role was written as male or female, and just happened to be cast as female, which is the way a lot of things should be, but arent.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
