<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="398392859.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6l6xwb/cmv_i_dont_understand_why_everyone_loves_wonder/">
    <title>CMV: I don't understand why everyone loves Wonder Woman</title>
    <original_poster>LilYonsan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Could someone help a cis-gendered white male understand why critics and people alike are raving about the new Wonder Woman movie? Having seen the movie myself, I really just don't understand what all the hype is about and when I think about this movie I seem to think about three main points that I just can't get around: the movie felt formulaic, the music was sub-par and predictable, and finally the movie's role in relation to my current ideas of gender.

**Wonder Woman felt formulaic:** 
This is one of my main criticisms of the movie, and I think it has come from the movie market being over-saturated with superhero movies as of late. Other than the first two batman movies (and maybe the third), I laugh at the relative quality of DC's live-action movies compared to their Animated Universe counterpart. Wonder Woman does what every other superhero movie has already done, the only difference was that it was a female lead (which I'll get more into later), my complaint was the result to me felt uninspired and the execution of the scenes was unoriginal (When viewing many of the fight scenes in this movie, I was reminded of 300)

**The Music Felt Bland:**
As a musician myself, I feel the music also played a large role in my lack of interest. I'd like to start off this point but suggesting readers watch this video [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vfqkvwW2fs) to get a better understanding of where I'm coming from on this point. You don't have to, but it might help. If not, basically the point of the video is that, due to many factors, the music in movies and what composers are actually allowed to compose has been limited, resulting in a more neutral and uninspired soundtrack as a whole. There are only two sections in the movie featuring a cello playing a leading-tone into a tonic with loud drums behind it that stood out, and honestly I think the only reason it stood out was because they turned the music up slightly louder than they did the sound effects. 

**With regard to Gender:**

Which brings me to the point of this movie that I'm really trying to wrap my head around. "Maybe", I thought, "that is the point. That it's just like all of the superhero movies that feature men, but shows that a woman can do it just as well". Before I go on this topic, I'm glad to see more movies that feature female leads (this and ghostbusters I think do some good in a societal level, especially given some of the political turmoil this country has been in as of late), but if that is the entire point then, like my other complaints, movies like Kill Bill and Alien did it better because they weren't so preachy about it. To me, Wonder Woman took the approach "she does this despite the fact that she's a woman because she's powerful, rooooaaaar!!", whereas Ripley in Alien and **bleep** in Kill Bill were just badasses because they were and that was the end of discussion. 

In summary, it's not that I thought that Wonder Woman was a terrible movie, but I don't think it deserves nearly the praise and hype that it received, and I felt like I could have spent the time watching that movie doing something more meaningful. But, as I mentioned at the beginning of this topic, I'm a guy, so maybe I'm just not getting something here. Please, change my view reddit because I would really like to understand better what I don't already! 

Thanks for reading! 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29493738754.0" user="punromantic" delta="False">
    <text>Here's my two cents that will be buried and never read:

I, as a girl, have spent my life believing that it is the terrible things that happened to me that make me strong. I am strong for making it through a suicide attempt when my depression was too much for me to handle. I survived a sexual assault and I'm enduring the PTSD that came from that, and I know I am strong because I have persevered. It is my weaknesses and traumas that make me strong, and that's a good way to view trauma.

But Wonder Woman didn't have a traumatic childhood. She wasn't brainwashed and tortured and orphaned like Black Widow. She's surrounded by love and support. She has a happy life. And she's strong as hell.

I feel like Hollywood often portrays men as already possessing strength, while women must struggle to become strong. That's why WW stood out to me. It might be baloney to you, and I respect that opinion, but it meant a lot to me and other people that a movie could have a strong female hero and no one tortured her to make her that way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29495191527.0" user="rialismus" delta="False">
    <text>This is a really really great point. I was sort of in OP's boat watching it, probably because I over hyped it, but that is so real. It is pretty radical for women to just day one be strong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29495930452.0" user="qvolt" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely agree that WW is a great role model, but I have to point out that traumatic events are fairly normal in super hero movies, but I feel like they are reserved for heroes that don't have powers: e.g.
Iron man gets blown up and held hostage
Batman's parents are killed
Black Widow (from your example)

Since WW is part of a super powered race of women, she fits in with heroes like Thor or Superman, which have less trauma in their past, because they were super from birth.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29496132695.0" user="punromantic" delta="False">
    <text>That's fair. However, Iron Man and Batman started out with the "powers" they were going to have (intelligence/money). They needed a call to action to make them superheroes, but they had their powers and strength all along. Black Widow didn't. 

It's just good to see WW fit in with heroes like Thor or Superman. It's just good to see a movie with a strong female lead who has inner strength. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
