<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="398392859.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6l6xwb/cmv_i_dont_understand_why_everyone_loves_wonder/">
    <title>CMV: I don't understand why everyone loves Wonder Woman</title>
    <original_poster>LilYonsan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Could someone help a cis-gendered white male understand why critics and people alike are raving about the new Wonder Woman movie? Having seen the movie myself, I really just don't understand what all the hype is about and when I think about this movie I seem to think about three main points that I just can't get around: the movie felt formulaic, the music was sub-par and predictable, and finally the movie's role in relation to my current ideas of gender.

**Wonder Woman felt formulaic:** 
This is one of my main criticisms of the movie, and I think it has come from the movie market being over-saturated with superhero movies as of late. Other than the first two batman movies (and maybe the third), I laugh at the relative quality of DC's live-action movies compared to their Animated Universe counterpart. Wonder Woman does what every other superhero movie has already done, the only difference was that it was a female lead (which I'll get more into later), my complaint was the result to me felt uninspired and the execution of the scenes was unoriginal (When viewing many of the fight scenes in this movie, I was reminded of 300)

**The Music Felt Bland:**
As a musician myself, I feel the music also played a large role in my lack of interest. I'd like to start off this point but suggesting readers watch this video [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vfqkvwW2fs) to get a better understanding of where I'm coming from on this point. You don't have to, but it might help. If not, basically the point of the video is that, due to many factors, the music in movies and what composers are actually allowed to compose has been limited, resulting in a more neutral and uninspired soundtrack as a whole. There are only two sections in the movie featuring a cello playing a leading-tone into a tonic with loud drums behind it that stood out, and honestly I think the only reason it stood out was because they turned the music up slightly louder than they did the sound effects. 

**With regard to Gender:**

Which brings me to the point of this movie that I'm really trying to wrap my head around. "Maybe", I thought, "that is the point. That it's just like all of the superhero movies that feature men, but shows that a woman can do it just as well". Before I go on this topic, I'm glad to see more movies that feature female leads (this and ghostbusters I think do some good in a societal level, especially given some of the political turmoil this country has been in as of late), but if that is the entire point then, like my other complaints, movies like Kill Bill and Alien did it better because they weren't so preachy about it. To me, Wonder Woman took the approach "she does this despite the fact that she's a woman because she's powerful, rooooaaaar!!", whereas Ripley in Alien and **bleep** in Kill Bill were just badasses because they were and that was the end of discussion. 

In summary, it's not that I thought that Wonder Woman was a terrible movie, but I don't think it deserves nearly the praise and hype that it received, and I felt like I could have spent the time watching that movie doing something more meaningful. But, as I mentioned at the beginning of this topic, I'm a guy, so maybe I'm just not getting something here. Please, change my view reddit because I would really like to understand better what I don't already! 

Thanks for reading! 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29498166562.0" user="allupinthisjoint" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm glad to see more movies that feature female leads [...] but if that is the entire point then, like my other complaints, movies like Kill Bill and Alien did it better because they weren't so preachy about it

Okay so, what you have written here is actually crazy. You say you think it's nice to see more female led and directed films, and I believe you're sincere. On an intellectually level you get that there's a problem with women in film and in culture, but emotionally you haven't fully internalised the extent of it. The very fact that you're having to reach for two films decades apart to make this gender based point - and that doesn't ring any alarm bells in your head - says so, so much.

It can be very hard for straight white guys to get this, but I can try an analogy. I want you to imagine a world where the Terminator, Indiana Jones, The Good the Bad and the Ugly, Schindler's List, The Shining, Lord of the Rings, 12 Angry Men, Bill and Ted, Do The Right Thing, Chinatown, Fight Club, Vertigo, Pulp Fiction, the Harry Potter films, Top Gun, Toy Story, The Big Lebowski, Back to the Future, Blade Runner, The Social Network, Citizen Kane, Monty Python's Holy Grail, Shaun of the Dead, The Ring, Akira, Groundhog Day, Brazil, Office Space, and many many more did not exist. A world without Steven Spielberg, Akira Kurosawa, Spike Lee, Woody Allen, David Fincher, Francis Ford Coppola, Werner Herzog, Quentin Tarantino... I mean they'd be alive, but they wouldn't have gone into film.

Can you imagine a world like this? The colossal cultural gap? How different would the world be? I imagine at least a few hardcore film buffs would genuinely rather die than live in this world. Except actually, we are living in this world right now. An entire gender has been systematically blocked from film, and we never saw their contributions. They had just as much to give, but they never got the chance. In our oppression of women, we will never know the full extent of what we have lost, but I can assure you it was equivalent to the above. That being said, I do like to imagine that there's an alternate universe with a female Charlie Chaplin, a female Kubrick, a female Walt Disney. Where a female directed majority female staffed Godfather starring a woman changed film forever. Where a female directed Star Wars starring a woman left a permanent mark on Hollywood sci-fi an still had legions of fans. Where you, the male, would have to beg for cultural crumbs. Do you like American Psycho and Lost in Translation? You damn well better, because they're all you have. These are the only male led films of any major cultural and critical significance in all history (both, coincidentally, directed by women). Where men were so Othered that women would actually explain to you with a straight face that the Goblin King in Labyrinth was one of the strongest male characters in all film, and they'd sincerely mean it ('it even has a male director! So progressive!'), and they'd get confused and defensive when you told them in your nicest voice that while Goblin King has a special place in your heart as a strong male character, you don't feel the same way.

And then Batman vs. Superman comes out and it blows your mind. You've never seen your gender like this before on screen. Only women get to be superheroes. And then some woman comes a long and says 'it's not as good as American Psycho or Lost in Translation, so I don't understand why you like it'.

You are that woman. Does this help?

**A second point**, you consider Kill Bill and Alien to be adequately feminist, but that WW was too preachy. I'm sorry, there's no way of wording this without it sounding like criticism - is the film really too preachy, or is it you? Like when someone says 'no thanks I'm a vegetarian' and we get all defensive because we think 'are they judging me' and we're worried that they're right and we're morally wrong, and we get all angry and feel preached to when all the person actually said was 'no thanks I'm a vegetarian'. Kill Bill and Alien, both films directed by men with male sensibilities, both are powerful in masculine ways (men typically do not admire feminine strength), with lingering shots of the actresses bodies and pandering to the straight male gaze, this feminism doesn't challenge you. But a female directed film with female sensibilities, where the camera doesn't linger over her body, with significant female presence beyond just the protagonists, who is physically strong but in a distinctly feminine way - you think of yourself as a good feminist liberal person, but this feels *too* feminist for you. But that clashes with your view of yourself as a good person and you project your own bad judgement of yourself onto the film. Are you sure the film hasn't merely said 'hey here's a female superhero doing cool stuff' and through your own mental baggage you've reached 'THE FILM IS PREACHING TO ME'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29499436363.0" user="gwarsh41" delta="False">
    <text>Something that stood out to me about the OP is that he felt Ghostbusters, a genderswap gimmick movie that used feminism as a selling point did well. However WW, an IP that has always been a woman and didn't use feminism as a selling point, was preachy. 

I believe that ghostbusters horrible marketing failure might have lead to people feeling like WW might go the same path. When it didn't, they couldn't shake the thought that it was, and assumed it had used feminism to push the movie. Instead it just showed that a modern movie with a female lead can do well without making you feel guilty about not watching it. (Seriously, for a while if you didn't like ghostbusters you were called sexist). 


I do want to disagree with your second point about Ripley not challenging masculinity, and there being lingering shots of Sigourney Weaver's body. I cannot speak for Kill bill as I haven't seen it often, but save for when the crew wakes up and the entire cast is in their underpants (not exactly a sexy scene) I cannot think of any time when someone could assume Ripley to be any sort of a sex symbol. 

Sigourney Weaver's character hasn't ever been that of a male character played by a woman either. I've heard the argument about a few female leads, that if you can easily imagine a man playing the role, and it has minimal impact on the movie, then it wasn't really a strong female lead. In Alien, with minor changes, I might see this working. However in Aliens, a man could not have played that role. I would say the same for Sarah O'connor in Terminator. 

On a closing point, I think that the new Ghostbusters has created turmoil about movies with female leads. Adding more skepticism to those who were already skeptical, at the same time making those who want strong female leads, want it even more. So when WW came out, an actually good movie, the responses from both sides were amplified. 

 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
