<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="401821196.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6n8f7w/cmv_lord_of_the_rings_are_great_films_but_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: Lord of the Rings are great films, but it is not a good trilogy</title>
    <original_poster>This_The_Last_Time</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is inspired by a recent Movie Fight debate about what is the best movie trilogy (check it out from YouTube). 

I'd argue, that even though I LOVE Lord of the Rings movies, and have seen them dozens of times, it is not a good movie trilogy. For one simple reason: the movies do not work separately. 

I think for a movie trilogy to be good or better than most, the parts of the trilogy have to work both individually as single movies and as pieces of a greater whole. 

LOTR does not work as individual films. None of the themes or storylines are resolved within a single film, with the exception of characters who are both introduced and killed within one film (Boromir, Shelob). 

LOTR films are individual films only in technical sense: they all have their separate release dates, each one ends with ending credits, etc. But the story contained in these films does not work when viewed as a single piece, because you do not get to see the big picture. LOTR films are really a single film, single story, released in three separate parts. 

I think for a trilogy to be good, or great, any single movie in it has to work without any companion pieces. Sequels should not be requirements. Story cannot be truly great if it does not end. Imagine if Fellowship of the Ring was a box-office bomb, and the two others films were never released. Who would call Fellowship a self-contained, resolved film? It would still be a good film, just without resolution. Audiences would think, what then, only to be answered, nothing. A good story does not ask questions it does not try to answer. 

Then look at Godfather. If Godfather Part 2 was never released, Godfather 1 would still work perfectly on its own. Part 2 enchances the first one, and vice versa, but neither requires the other.  And no one needs the third one. 

Lord of the Rings films are great. But in reality they are a trilogy only in technical terms, as the story within is one single story, not three complementing ones. If you only watch one of the films, but not the others, story is flawed and incomplete. If you watch the films out of chronological order, nothing makes sense. All the plot threads and all the character archs in the trilogy take multiple films to reach their conclusions, with the aforementioned exception of characters who are introduced and killed within a single movie. 

An exceptional trilogy of films should work both individually, where you only see one of them (not necessarily even the first one), and still feel like you got everything you needed and wanted, and as parts of a bigger whole. Lord of the Rings films do not work without the other parts of the trilogy. Without them, story is incomplete, unresolved, and the character archs unfinished. 

CMV. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29521069786.0" user="burnblue" delta="False">
    <text>I'm looking up the definition of trilogy and nothing here says that individual entries have to be independent. A trilogy is 3 related stories. If the stories are good, that's a good trilogy. If the relation is good, that's a good trilogy.

If the 3 stories also work independently without relation, what you call that is a bonus. It has no bearing on it's quality as a trilogy. You've already said you think each film is a good film and that they all fit together, so it's a good trilogy.

Good trilogies that are also 3 good individual movies are even better but moving the goalposts of the definition of unfair</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29521112872.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>Yeaah, that was my argument. They are not three related stories, they are one story, each movie delivering one third. 

I'm not moving the goalposts, that was the goalpost all along. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29521446708.0" user="burnblue" delta="False">
    <text>I understand. Knowing your angle I shouldn't have used the word stories.

&amp;gt; a group of three related novels, plays, films, operas, or albums.

&amp;gt; a group or series of three related things.

Per definition. Each of them was a film. An individual object. Something you can buy on its own DVD. Those are all the units you need.
.
To drop the hard definition and go back to your semantics, I would still argue that each film is a story, with a beginning, middle and end. There are lots of stories that leave the audience wondering what happened before or what happens next, but they are still stories and that suspense can make them even better more intriguing stories.

Finally, there are people that would argue the opposite of your view: that it's no good to call something a trilogy when its units are wholly independent, and the only good multifilm story is one that doesn't have disjointed discrete parts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
