<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="403343304.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6o51oo/cmv_retard_is_not_an_offensive_or_ableist_word/">
    <title>CMV: "Retard" is not an offensive or ableist word because the connotation has changed from referring to mentally handicapped people to referring to stupid people, much like how the meaning of other words like "dumb" and "lame" have also changed meanings dramatically.</title>
    <original_poster>Dillon-psm</original_poster>
    <original_post>So a lot of people find the word "Retard" used as an insult to be incredibly offensive, akin to saying the n-word to a black person. They say that this is because historically the word means mentally handicapped person and it was used in a patronizing and derogatory way during a time when there was a massive cultural stigma and disgust with mental disabilities. 

Yet, many words over the course of history change. Hell, a lot of the words we use today to refer to someone as an idiot - including the word idiot - were historically used to describe mentally ill/handicapped people. 

To this day, words like Imbecile, Moron and Cretin are used to describe stupid people (or troublemakers, in the case of cretin), yet these words actually mean the exact same thing as "retard". 

So why is retard singled out as "ableist"? Are people who take offence to the word simply being resistant to the natural evolution of language, or does their anger have merit? 

EDIT: Everyone made very good points. I'm considering them, but based on the fact that for the most part I had *nothing* to fire back with, I'd say my views have been thoroughly changed and I'm going to phase this word out of my vocabulary. I'm guilty of frequent use - it's easy to just turn to a buddy and say that in good fun without even thinking, but I'll be mindful in the future. 

Thanks people. Also You get a delta, you get a delta, and you get a delta, everyone gets a delta!!!!!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29532149045.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>From Wikipedia:
&amp;gt;The first time that any form of the word retard was used to describe mentally disabled people was during the 1960s when "there was a push among disability advocates to use the label mental retardation". This push from advocates was because older terms for the mentally disabled, like moron, imbecile, feeble minded and idiot, had developed negative meanings. Retard was not used to refer to mentally disabled people until 1985. It was widely accepted to refer to people who are mentally disabled as mentally retarded, or as a retard. From there, it turned quickly into a pejorative term, as people began to use it interchangeably with words like stupid, or idiot.

It kind of sucks that they have to keep changing the term, right? And that it became a pejorative almost immediately? You're kind of arguing that because enough insensitive jerks used the term as an insult, advocates of the mentally disabled no longer have a right to be offended. They coined the term, people with downs have it hard enough as it , so why not trust the people who find it personally offensive,  as there are are so endlessly many other ways to insult people's intelligence in English that won't make you seem insensitive? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532171073.0" user="Dillon-psm" delta="False">
    <text>But this isn't the only example of the definitions of words changing based on how they are used in common conversation. Look at how the word idiot morphed from first being a word to refer to mentally handicapped people, then to insult people by comparing them to the mentally handicapped, then to simply mean "someone who is observably stupid". 

Do you think that the *reasoning* behind the language shift then is more relevant than the shift itself? That would be a reasonable stance to take. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532215748.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure I follow... the reasoning behind the use of the word matters, and I do believe most people aren't intending to use it as a comparison. But as long as a lot of people are hearing it as a comparison to Down's it's offensive.
Or are you saying that retard is different because there was an active campaign to use it as a neutral term, and then it was co-opted? I think that's true. People really shouldn't have been saying idiot or moron pejoratively back when they were medical terms, but there wasn't as much public advocacy back then explaining to people that it was hurtful, so it was less wrong. People can be offensive without knowing it, and I think that's forgivable. If they're being offensive knowingly that's different. So yeah, the reasoning behind the shift is more relevant than the shift itself, if I understand you right.

As a side note: there are a bunch of subreddits, generally left leaning ones, that will delete your comments and posts for using the word 'crazy' or 'insane' pejoratively. My instinct is this goes too far, but I'd want to hear the opinions of people who have serious mental disorders before making up my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532277855.0" user="relevant_password" delta="False">
    <text>Use whichever term feels the most natural to you. PC is not about "being respectful," it's about "being more respectful than thou."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532298462.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I think PC is that for a LOT of people, and a lot of it is also virtue signaling, but I do want to know what effect my words have on people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532321328.0" user="relevant_password" delta="False">
    <text>If one autistic person says that nobody should use "autistic" as an insult, and one says the first person annoys them far more, who's right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532356244.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>One person doesn't get to decide. I'd want to know what the community as a whole felt. I used to work with autistic kids, so I know most people in that community wouldn't want 'autistic' to be an insult.

But for people who are mentally ill... I think that even they use the word crazy as a pejorative sometimes, and Id think the people who were against it would be more of a fringe element.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532398357.0" user="relevant_password" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like you to be 100% honest about the following question: how many of those students have told you they don't like autistic being used as an insult under any circumstances?

If the answer is less than 2, you've admitted to projecting your own opinions onto people with autism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532462626.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Not the kids themselves, they were in grade school and many couldn't speak, but their parents. Parents are protective. They were very concerned that other people would make fun of their children. The use of the word 'spaz' came up a bunch of times. I don't care if they're projecting onto their children (but the kids pick up on a lot more than you think at first). It hurts if people make you feel like your child's medical condition is some sort of joke. And given that autism rates are rising, there's just a good chance that whoever Im talking to might have an autistic friend or relative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532504413.0" user="relevant_password" delta="False">
    <text>1. I said under "all circumstances." How can your students can pick up on the fact that autism can be used as an insult, but can't pick up on the fact it's not always an attack on them personally?

2. Parents have claimed that baseball games need to not have score or the self esteem of children will be harmed. This is one among many things done in the name of "self esteem." Many of those same parents are now claiming that millennials can't deal with conflict. If parents teach their kids that any insulting use of the word "autism" is against them personally, especially young ones, are the kids really reacting their own opinion? Do you know what the kids picked up, or are you assuming? How do you know they won't eventually grow up to think like those "self esteem baseball players," or they are like that now and you're assuming otherwise?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532550475.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I never said I knew what the kids pick up. I also don't know if these kids will grow up to be 'self esteem baseball players'. I was just trying to teach them how to identify simple objects mostly.

All I said was that many people I know would be personally offended if autism was used as an insult. That's just a fact. You're arguing now that they shouldn't be offended. Ok. I never said they should be. I just said the parents I know would be. You seem to want me to change the way society is. I bet the parents of autistic children are more sensitive than other parents. Many of them would be offended over things I personally did not find offensive. But what do you want me to do about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532610934.0" user="relevant_password" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; One person doesn't get to decide. I'd want to know what the community as a whole felt. I used to work with autistic kids, so I know most people in that community wouldn't want 'autistic' to be an insult.
&amp;gt; I don't care if they're projecting onto their children (but the kids pick up on a lot more than you think at first).
&amp;gt; But for people who are mentally ill... I think that even they use the word crazy as a pejorative sometimes, and Id think the people who were against it would be more of a fringe element.

&amp;gt; I never said I knew what the kids pick up.

You have resorted to lying about your past statements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532655103.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand? I know what the autistic community thinks... the friends, relatives, educators, etc... because I've talked with them. I could have been more clear there, but in the next comment I say that I don't know what the kids are thinking, just the parents. The kids don't have much of a voice in this community because many are non verbal. It's still a community and it has opinions.
Then I said that the kids picked up on more than I thought. I didn't say I knew what it was they were picking up, but sometimes they'd surprise me and I'd realized I underestimated them.
With the mentally ill... how does this fit in? I'm saying what I think this community (which is much wider than just autism) might believe, not claiming to have any knowledge here, just guesses?
Don't understand how this adds up to lying. 

And it's late and I don't understand why you want to argue over this. I have problems with PC culture too. I don't personally find autistic, used as an insult, offensive in every situation. But I know people who would. There's nothing I can change here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532771518.0" user="vlad_biden" delta="False">
    <text>Just my thoughts on the "crazy" thing. I have anxiety and depression, and don't personally feel offended by it - I actually use it all the time to describe people whose actions make no sense to me. I think it's inoffensive to me because no one's going to be literally diagnosed with "crazy" by a psychiatrist. Like I know no one's referring to my condition when they say "crazy". It does bother me, though, when people use actual modern medical terminology in an insulting way or take it out of context, e.g. "I'm so OCD about cleaning my room" or "she was acting like a schizo".

It's like the word idiot - maybe at one time it was closely associated with a medical condition, but now it's pretty removed from that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532927992.0" user="foolishle" delta="False">
    <text>As a mentally ill person I feel uncomfortable when people use the words "crazy" or "insane" to mean "over the top" or "busy" or as emphasis or whatever. Unless someone asks, though - as you just have - I just deal with the discomfort and refrain from using those words in that way myself.

I think it hurts me more than some other mentally ill people because I am (or have been) *that kind* of crazy. The kind where people would use the word crazy to describe me. Erratic, throwing furniture, yelling swear words at strangers in the street, kicking brick walls hard enough to break my own toes etc. I am better now and I don't expect I will have many episodes like that again but... yeah. I do find it hurtful. Of course I know other mentally ill people who have absolutely no problem with the word crazy and use it to describe themselves and also use it to describe "a really tough day at work". Everyone is different. 

Personally I just try and say what I mean instead of using comparison terms which insult others by proxy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
