<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="403990146.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6oiwsi/cmv_the_british_welfare_system_is_not_currently/">
    <title>CMV: The British welfare system is not currently fair to people with disabilities and needs a reboot.</title>
    <original_poster>SubaruToyotaFan1986</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been endless stories about PIP [Personal Independence Payment], a British welfare payment, in the major newspapers and how it affects parents or adults with disabilities.

Rather than forcing people to join work-related groups and being target-driven, the system needs a reboot.

People who have a LLOND [Lifelong Neurological Disorder] which could be defined as:

Autism Spectrum Disorder [ASD]

Rett's Syndrome

Down's Syndrome

Foetal Alcohol Syndrome

Spina bifida 

etc.

should be entitled to a new DQLA [Disabled Qualify of Life] allowance which would be for their entire lifetime.

I am a male in my 30s with Asperger's Syndrome so cannot be accused of throwing stones in glass houses, so to speak. I *do* work [albeit within the limits of DWP for disabled people].

Rather than having ATOS force them to attend interviews, the focus would be on [questioned document examination](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Questioned_document_examination) and assessing how valid the documentation is - much as historians have to do, to ensure absolute authenticity.

Anyone can claim to be disabled, but some disorders, like autism spectrum disorder or Down's Syndrome have "tell"s that they have the disability. It is a lot harder to fake having a condition like ASD and spina bifida. Increased public awareness by charities about disability has made it easier now than it was in the 1990s to understand disability.

Theresa May's government are not disability-friendly in this regard, and I can very well understand *why* parents of, and adults with a disability are not satisfied, and expect her to be out of office soon.

In the U.S., Donald Trump should also implement a policy like this, it may prove a PR coup for him and take the public's mind away from things like links with Russia and election manipulation, the dismissal of Sally Yates and the recent dismissal of James Comey, and other issues.

These are my opinions, change my viewpoint if you can.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29537413911.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>My main qualm is that autism spectrum disorder, as it is a spectrum disorder, is nebulously defined and includes a wide range of people of varying ability. Would you agree that ASD, for the purposes of determining employability, must be more narrowly tailored?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29537453894.0" user="SubaruToyotaFan1986" delta="False">
    <text>My argument was that people with ASD - or indeed any disability that is a lifelong condition - should get help from the government for something that is not something they chose to get.

I didn't choose to have Asperger's, but I'm making the best of life as i can.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29537520823.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not arguing that you should be provided help. It's just that some people with ASD are highly employable, some are less so. I think any system should take that into account when providing unemployment benefits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29537566673.0" user="SubaruToyotaFan1986" delta="False">
    <text>That's partially my point. ASD and autism are seen as homogenous by the DWP and ATOS.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29537586791.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I agree then.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
