<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="408864224.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6rfdnk/cmv_impeaching_donald_trump_is_actually_not_a/">
    <title>CMV: Impeaching Donald Trump is actually not a very good idea</title>
    <original_poster>Shanghai1943</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress and the DOJ are investigating the collusion between the Trump campaign and the Russian government in the 2016 Russian election. Robert Muller has been appointed as special counsel to investigate this matter, and today he has [impaneled a grand jury.](http://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-a-grand-jury-robert-mueller-trump-russia-2017-8). Which could ultimately result in the impeachment of Donald Trump.        

For the most part since the Trump presidency, Vice President Mike Pence has been kept away from the spotlight. This may be a move by the party in the case of an impeachment that the new president would start from a clean slate. Although Pence is a much much more presentable president for America, he serves a similar agenda to Donald Trump and the current Republican leadership, not to mention he has a very poor track record on abortion, LGBT rights, climate change, education, among others.       

In the case of a Trump impeachment, Mike Pence becomes the new president. In my view, he is just a more competent version of Donald Trump that is presentable to the public, but at the same time perhaps much better than Trump at pushing the same type of Republican backed bills through congress. Lets not forget that the skinny repeal was only 1 vote short from passing.        

America might look silly with Trump as the president, this is manly due to his personality and unstable nature. But because of his unstable nature, people in congress, even in his party bound to oppose him. In the 6 months he has been president, he has gotten almost nothing done. Since Trump has been so awful, all Pence has to do is a little good and he would seem like a saint, which would prolong the Republican run, and at the current state of Republican leadership, this is no good. Thus in my view, keeping an idiot running things for the next 3.5 years would be better for America in the long run than putting Mike Pence in the driver's seat as he is just a more competent Donald Trump.

Edit: Thanks guys, my views have been changed, I have ignored his foreign policies in this thread as well as the precedence he sets if we accept his behavior.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29575725011.0" user="Matthew100001" delta="False">
    <text>For starters, Trump has already committed an impeachable offense a few months back when he terminated Comey for the purpose of trying to end the investigation into possible collusion between him and/or his campaign and Russia, obstruction of justice.

And it seems like you are on the "pence is worse" train, as many on all sides are. I agree, Pence is worse, but if Trump is removed before the halfway point in his term, Pence can only be elected to said office once, as is described within the first section of the twenty second amendment to the constitution. " No person shall be elected to the office of the President more than twice, and person who has held the office President, or acted as President, for more than two years of a term which some other person was elected President shall be elected to the office of the President more than once." It's either deal with leaders like this for as much as 16 years, or as little as eight, or even 12 depending on when Trump is removed from office.

I hate Trump, and I hate Pence even more, but the reasons behind why I want Trump gone has more to deal with limiting the amount of damage the two men can do by limiting their time in office.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
