<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="408864224.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6rfdnk/cmv_impeaching_donald_trump_is_actually_not_a/">
    <title>CMV: Impeaching Donald Trump is actually not a very good idea</title>
    <original_poster>Shanghai1943</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress and the DOJ are investigating the collusion between the Trump campaign and the Russian government in the 2016 Russian election. Robert Muller has been appointed as special counsel to investigate this matter, and today he has [impaneled a grand jury.](http://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-a-grand-jury-robert-mueller-trump-russia-2017-8). Which could ultimately result in the impeachment of Donald Trump.        

For the most part since the Trump presidency, Vice President Mike Pence has been kept away from the spotlight. This may be a move by the party in the case of an impeachment that the new president would start from a clean slate. Although Pence is a much much more presentable president for America, he serves a similar agenda to Donald Trump and the current Republican leadership, not to mention he has a very poor track record on abortion, LGBT rights, climate change, education, among others.       

In the case of a Trump impeachment, Mike Pence becomes the new president. In my view, he is just a more competent version of Donald Trump that is presentable to the public, but at the same time perhaps much better than Trump at pushing the same type of Republican backed bills through congress. Lets not forget that the skinny repeal was only 1 vote short from passing.        

America might look silly with Trump as the president, this is manly due to his personality and unstable nature. But because of his unstable nature, people in congress, even in his party bound to oppose him. In the 6 months he has been president, he has gotten almost nothing done. Since Trump has been so awful, all Pence has to do is a little good and he would seem like a saint, which would prolong the Republican run, and at the current state of Republican leadership, this is no good. Thus in my view, keeping an idiot running things for the next 3.5 years would be better for America in the long run than putting Mike Pence in the driver's seat as he is just a more competent Donald Trump.

Edit: Thanks guys, my views have been changed, I have ignored his foreign policies in this thread as well as the precedence he sets if we accept his behavior.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29575782578.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't make sense to compare Trump and Pence the way you have; Pence is in no way a "competent Trump."

Trump has essentially no ideological consistency, nor is he pragmatic - he does what he thinks will make the people he chooses to recognize like him.  He has no idea how to negotiate with anyone who disagrees with him because he doesn't know how to compromise.  He doesn't know how to compromise because he's temperamentally disinclined and he has no real idea what most political disagreements are actually about.

You need to realize that this is a man who deals with his frustration over Afghanistan by castigating and threatening his generals and floating the idea that the enlisted men should be consulted on grand strategy.  (As a former enlisted man, that is the single stupidest idea I think I've ever heard.)

Liberals tend to overemphasize this threat, but it exists nonetheless: as long as Trump is president, there is a chance he will do something both stupid and irreversible.  There is a chance he'll find one of those points we hoped to never find where our only constitutional protections are the presumed goodwill of our leaders and pry it open.  I'm talking about that moment where he gives a general an order and the general has to decide in that moment who his real commander is: the president or the law.  The answer really might not be clear in some cases.

Chances are we'll go four years and never hit that point, but we shouldn't be comfortable with it.  If he were to do something like that, the best case scenario leaves us with a deeply discredited and delegitimized presidency.  We don't want that.

Pence is an experienced politician.  He may be one you disagree with, but he's also cognizant of certain realities - like the necessity of compromise and the value of foreign alliances and agreements.  He may *want* things you don't want, but he knows enough to know that he can't just *have* them.  He knows he has to compromise with Democrats, he knows he has to restore faith in institutions, and he knows that charging headlong to get what he wants won't work.

From your perspective: you can negotiate with Pence.  That's good enough.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
