<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="408864224.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6rfdnk/cmv_impeaching_donald_trump_is_actually_not_a/">
    <title>CMV: Impeaching Donald Trump is actually not a very good idea</title>
    <original_poster>Shanghai1943</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress and the DOJ are investigating the collusion between the Trump campaign and the Russian government in the 2016 Russian election. Robert Muller has been appointed as special counsel to investigate this matter, and today he has [impaneled a grand jury.](http://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-a-grand-jury-robert-mueller-trump-russia-2017-8). Which could ultimately result in the impeachment of Donald Trump.        

For the most part since the Trump presidency, Vice President Mike Pence has been kept away from the spotlight. This may be a move by the party in the case of an impeachment that the new president would start from a clean slate. Although Pence is a much much more presentable president for America, he serves a similar agenda to Donald Trump and the current Republican leadership, not to mention he has a very poor track record on abortion, LGBT rights, climate change, education, among others.       

In the case of a Trump impeachment, Mike Pence becomes the new president. In my view, he is just a more competent version of Donald Trump that is presentable to the public, but at the same time perhaps much better than Trump at pushing the same type of Republican backed bills through congress. Lets not forget that the skinny repeal was only 1 vote short from passing.        

America might look silly with Trump as the president, this is manly due to his personality and unstable nature. But because of his unstable nature, people in congress, even in his party bound to oppose him. In the 6 months he has been president, he has gotten almost nothing done. Since Trump has been so awful, all Pence has to do is a little good and he would seem like a saint, which would prolong the Republican run, and at the current state of Republican leadership, this is no good. Thus in my view, keeping an idiot running things for the next 3.5 years would be better for America in the long run than putting Mike Pence in the driver's seat as he is just a more competent Donald Trump.

Edit: Thanks guys, my views have been changed, I have ignored his foreign policies in this thread as well as the precedence he sets if we accept his behavior.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29575906962.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>In addition to the points that have been made in regards to foreign policy/diplomacy and the precedence of his candidacy, there's also a serious question in regards to whether or not Mike Pence would no be similarly disqualified in any proceedings which arise as a result of a trial on Trump. The [timeline surrounding all the constant news of the Trump administration](https://www.reddit.com/r/TrumpInvestigation/wiki/doc) is massive and convoluted, but there's plenty of evidence that Trump is not alone in having dirty hands here. Flynn was brought onto the team even after Flynn himself made the campaign aware that he was under investigation for connections to the Russians. Spicer has recently come out and admitted that he collaborated with Fox News to fabricate false stories about the administration as a distraction tactic to deceive the American people. Steve Bannon is still in the cabinet, and Briebart news is still one of the few news organisations who's journalists have any kind of close access to the white house....

If Trump is found guilty of many of the things he's been accused of- colluding with the Russians, taking bribes, bribing others, attempting to obstruct justice and have others swear loyalty to him, etc... Pence will likely be found similarly unfit for office. As VP, Pence can't be entirely blind to all of what's gone on. He's had to have had a say in decisions such as bringing on Flynn to the team, been aware of Flynn's activities, and that he was under investigation... and as the right hand to the President he would be privy to everything that's being revealed and more. Likely, if Trump is impeached, Pence is impeached. And they're both impeached, we're left with Paul Ryan... [who has also has been found in leaked tapes to have suspected Trump of having ties to Putin as far back as June 2016, and having fellow congressman swear themselves to secrecy.](https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/house-majority-leader-to-colleagues-in-2016-i-think-putin-pays-trump/2017/05/17/515f6f8a-3aff-11e7-8854-21f359183e8c_story.html?utm_term=.940a4f6d4077)

After Paul Ryan, next up is Orrin Hatch. Also not a good choice... but at least with either Paul Ryan or Orrin Hatch you'd likely get a typical status quo Republican. Which we have lived under before- we've got people joking now that they never thought they'd be wishing for old "W" Bush back, but we have lived through people like him before, and been just fine.
Honestly, as we pull this thread further and further, I think we're going to see the whole tapestry quickly come apart, and I do believe most of the GOP leadership, if they aren't directly involved in some way, have allowed themselves to be indirectly complicit in a large scale treasonous transgression against our country. Our elections were tampered with, and our leadership is currently a mess of lies, corruption, and insolence to our nation's liberty. If Trump goes down, I think he might very well go down flailing, taking down much of the GOP leadership with him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29577398679.0" user="M_de_Monty" delta="False">
    <text>Moreover, if it ends up being Paul Ryan or Orrin Hatch in the White House, they will probably end up being mostly lame-duck, stay-the-course presidents. This is because they'd ascend to the presidency without a mandate i.e. without election, so they wouldn't have popular or legislative support for their agendas.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
