<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="408864224.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6rfdnk/cmv_impeaching_donald_trump_is_actually_not_a/">
    <title>CMV: Impeaching Donald Trump is actually not a very good idea</title>
    <original_poster>Shanghai1943</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress and the DOJ are investigating the collusion between the Trump campaign and the Russian government in the 2016 Russian election. Robert Muller has been appointed as special counsel to investigate this matter, and today he has [impaneled a grand jury.](http://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-a-grand-jury-robert-mueller-trump-russia-2017-8). Which could ultimately result in the impeachment of Donald Trump.        

For the most part since the Trump presidency, Vice President Mike Pence has been kept away from the spotlight. This may be a move by the party in the case of an impeachment that the new president would start from a clean slate. Although Pence is a much much more presentable president for America, he serves a similar agenda to Donald Trump and the current Republican leadership, not to mention he has a very poor track record on abortion, LGBT rights, climate change, education, among others.       

In the case of a Trump impeachment, Mike Pence becomes the new president. In my view, he is just a more competent version of Donald Trump that is presentable to the public, but at the same time perhaps much better than Trump at pushing the same type of Republican backed bills through congress. Lets not forget that the skinny repeal was only 1 vote short from passing.        

America might look silly with Trump as the president, this is manly due to his personality and unstable nature. But because of his unstable nature, people in congress, even in his party bound to oppose him. In the 6 months he has been president, he has gotten almost nothing done. Since Trump has been so awful, all Pence has to do is a little good and he would seem like a saint, which would prolong the Republican run, and at the current state of Republican leadership, this is no good. Thus in my view, keeping an idiot running things for the next 3.5 years would be better for America in the long run than putting Mike Pence in the driver's seat as he is just a more competent Donald Trump.

Edit: Thanks guys, my views have been changed, I have ignored his foreign policies in this thread as well as the precedence he sets if we accept his behavior.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29576206316.0" user="darwin2500" delta="False">
    <text>Social issues in the US maybe pushed back by Pence, but relatively few people will die as a result and the ground can be regained over the next few decades of politics as usual.

In the meantime, Trump is a clinical narcissist, deeply unstable and unpredictable, belligerent, violent, obsessed with revenge and saving face, and has the ability to launch a nuclear strike whenever he feels like it.

The worst case scenario for Trump is not that he pushes back social issues or collapses the economy or even screws the planet over climate change.  The worst case scenario is that his unstable and insane actions lead to a nuclear war, and human civilization is wiped off the map in a rain of cleansing hellfire.

I'm not saying there's a 100% chance he will do this, but I *do* think there's at least a 5% chance that he'll do this, and a 5% chance of wiping out the human race is  *more* than enough reason to impeach him ASAP.  

Pence may screw a lot of shit up and hurt a lot of people, but he's mentally stable and politically experienced enough to avoid the worst-case scenarios.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29578412016.0" user="metamatic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The worst case scenario is that his unstable and insane actions lead to a nuclear war, and human civilization is wiped off the map in a rain of cleansing hellfire.

This. North Korea has ICBMs now, we nearly had a nuclear exchange on at least 3 occasions during the cold war, and there's basically nothing to stop Trump from launching a nuclear attack if Kim Jong-un calls him a pussy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
