<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="409977160.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/">
    <title>CMV: Self proclaimed "anti-SJWs" are just as annoying and entitled as the people they oppose.</title>
    <original_poster>Ninjachibi117</original_poster>
    <original_post>Allow me to preface this with saying that I have an idpol bias and am a leftist, so this may make my views on social issues somewhat skewed or biased to one side. I'd also like to say that personally, I couldn't care less where someone stands on social or political issues as long as they're not an ass about it; in fact, talking and politely debating with people you disagree with is excellent and should be encouraged.

As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death (this is a general meaning, not directly true for every "sjw"). This is in part both due to and responsible for the advances in rights and equal treatment for minorities and marginalised groups with the exceptions of a few classes of people. Now personally, I'm all for the betterment of marginalised people, but there's certainly people who take these matters a bit too far, even going so far as to send death threats or other negative shenanigans to those that they perceive as opposing them even if their target agrees with them on most things. Tumblr is a popular social media for this type of people though there is a fair mix of more moderate and even some extreme contrarians on that platform.

With this comes the contrarian trend of "anti-SJWs", people who adamantly oppose those perceived to be social justice warriors and dedicate sometimes extreme levels of energy to combating them. Popular examples include many 4chan users, r/TumblrInAction and some blogs hosted, ironically, on Tumblr. These are varied in firmness of opinion from mild dissent ("oh shut up, nobody cares") to firm opposition (see: the amazing atheist) to comical levels of devotion (4chan vs Shia Laboeuf).

Now, the concept of these anti-SJWs is a weird one to me as it seems unnecessarily contrarian; nobody's hurting you so severely by believing they're a fox from another world with six dicks that you need to devote large amounts of energy and time to do nothing but basically just be a dick to them for the luls. However, that aside, the thing many of these anti-SJWs seem to fail to grasp is that, at least from my view point, they're just as bad as the people they devote their time to, if not worse. Nothing is achieved by spamming some 14 year old kid's Tumblr with gore and hate mail or getting a man arrested for defending yourself other than showing what a petty asshole you choose to be.

Many of the points they rag on "SJWs" for are things they're guilty of as well. Popular points include intolerance of dissenting opinions, dedication to harassment or personal attacks of people seen as disagreeing, being whiny/petty, rejecting science, and being entitled and unable to function in the real world. Yet the entire movement is based on this intolerance and these attacks, with pettiness or simply being whiny being a major cause. They commonly reject modern scientific findings on matters such as gender, neurodivergency, and other topics that they accuse "SJWs" of misrepresenting. And this might just be me, but nothing seems more entitled than spending your free time attacking or harassing people (often children) because they think they're some thing you don't believe in or because they see an inequality somewhere you don't.

Don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you have to agree. You can believe someone's an absolute fucking idiot, but that doesn't mean you need to go after them. Anti-SJWs are part of and worsen the "SJW problem" they dedicate themselves to combat.

EDIT: I'd like to make it clear that my point is about the main, general concept of each movement or belief and not about specific beliefs or people as people on all sides are diverse in background and in thoughts. If it helps you visualise this better, make an imaginary example of each general idea instead of focusing on specific real world views. Thanks to u/Cupcakesarethedevil for helping me clarify.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29585722755.0" user="Kolop" delta="False">
    <text>What annoys me about SJWs is that they really are attacking free speech. I understand the desire to protect everyone's feelings,  but in my opinion free speech is more important than an individual or groups feelings. Anti-sjws can be annoying, but they aren't anti free speech. They might be hate spewing bigots, but they aren't trying to tell me what I can and cannot say. They annoy me less at least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585814344.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>This is off topic, but individuals can't attack your free speech. Free speech means the government can't tell you what to say, not that the people can't react negatively to you saying things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587043889.0" user="palsh7" delta="False">
    <text>That's not correct. You're thinking of one's 1st Amendment rights. That's different than free speech. Freedom of speech isn't a concept relegated to the first amendment. It is an independent philosophy. Why do we have the 1st Amendment? The purpose isn't just to keep people out of jail, it's to promote free and honest discourse. That goal, that ideal, not to squash speech by any means, whether by threat, intimidation, or other avenues of chilling speech, is a cornerstone of academia, journalism, good business practice (internal), and countless other venues. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587164334.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like to introduce you to the idea of free association. Basically, you are free to say and express yourself as you wish; but it is my right to choose not to associate or work with you. Now, let's say I run a speaking forum. If you routinely say or do things that would look bad on the forum or that I fundamentally despise, it's my right to refuse to associate with you including refusing to allow you to associate with my forum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588575932.0" user="palsh7" delta="False">
    <text>We know.

And that is not what free speech advocates have a problem with, although your freedom not to associate with me as a friend or as an organizer of a televised forum can have a freezing effect on speech and therefore intellectual honesty, truth, and the dialectic as a whole, if you have a too-broad definition of things that offend you. When the mob decides that only fundamentalist Christianity can be tolerated in their town, they may have the right to disown children, disinvite guests, and pass on publishing books, but those rights don't imply that they are doing something ethical and helpful for public discourse. 

And they most assuredly don't have the right to ban you from their business as a customer. As an employee, it does get more tricky, and the courts, if I'm not mistaken, have essentially said that you have to prove the employee's expression of their beliefs effected the business adversely. You can't just say "I don't want to work with a Trump supporter." In the case of Google, they may have a good case, although if data and facts expressed in a careful way are able to hurt a company, there's maybe a bigger problem on the horizon. 

And that's the point. Universities can disinvited academics that small groups of protesters have a problem with, and HBO can cancel a show that a small number of protesters have a problem with, and your boss can ask his lawyers to find a legal excuse to fire you when a small number of protesters have a problem with you, and a newspaper can decide to edit out portions of your article to appease the expected protesters who will not like that news, etc., etc. But while that may all be legal and even intelligent, it leads to inconvenient truths going unspoken, and can lead to a similar outcome as government suppression. After all, in a country without the 1A, you're still able to speak: just not to speak without consequence. And how different is it for the speaker to be fired, publicly shamed, disowned, and unfriended rather than fined or jailed by the government? I'd argue they can carry the same weight. 

I'm not arguing that individuals should draw no lines in the sand where speech is concerned, simply that we're becoming a very trigger-happy society when it comes to offense, and we are letting the most extreme dictate the terms. People are quick to block when they might be able to converse and learn. People are quick to shout down instead of listen, keep quiet instead of explain. Innocuous statements and long established scientific facts are now labeled treachery. And the trend is now moving towards steeper and steeper punishments for saying the wrong things. Violence for being a "Nazi" and redefining Nazi as anyone who disagrees with you. I wouldn't have thought this slope could get so slippery, but here we are. 

So again, it isn't freedom to associate that I have a problem with, but the choices people make with that freedom. I'm free to drink myself to death, but it's not healthy to do so. We should all encourage a public discourse that is more charitable and reasoned. If I'm Intelligence Squared, I can choose not to let someone speak on my program, but as a debate show, at what point am I just hiding facts or opinions by doing so? It's my job to decide what is valuable to hear. If I start thinking only in terms of what might get the show protested, all is lost. 

Protest is vital to a democracy, as is standing up to bigotry and stupidity, which is why we should be very smart about how we do it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
