<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="409977160.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/">
    <title>CMV: Self proclaimed "anti-SJWs" are just as annoying and entitled as the people they oppose.</title>
    <original_poster>Ninjachibi117</original_poster>
    <original_post>Allow me to preface this with saying that I have an idpol bias and am a leftist, so this may make my views on social issues somewhat skewed or biased to one side. I'd also like to say that personally, I couldn't care less where someone stands on social or political issues as long as they're not an ass about it; in fact, talking and politely debating with people you disagree with is excellent and should be encouraged.

As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death (this is a general meaning, not directly true for every "sjw"). This is in part both due to and responsible for the advances in rights and equal treatment for minorities and marginalised groups with the exceptions of a few classes of people. Now personally, I'm all for the betterment of marginalised people, but there's certainly people who take these matters a bit too far, even going so far as to send death threats or other negative shenanigans to those that they perceive as opposing them even if their target agrees with them on most things. Tumblr is a popular social media for this type of people though there is a fair mix of more moderate and even some extreme contrarians on that platform.

With this comes the contrarian trend of "anti-SJWs", people who adamantly oppose those perceived to be social justice warriors and dedicate sometimes extreme levels of energy to combating them. Popular examples include many 4chan users, r/TumblrInAction and some blogs hosted, ironically, on Tumblr. These are varied in firmness of opinion from mild dissent ("oh shut up, nobody cares") to firm opposition (see: the amazing atheist) to comical levels of devotion (4chan vs Shia Laboeuf).

Now, the concept of these anti-SJWs is a weird one to me as it seems unnecessarily contrarian; nobody's hurting you so severely by believing they're a fox from another world with six dicks that you need to devote large amounts of energy and time to do nothing but basically just be a dick to them for the luls. However, that aside, the thing many of these anti-SJWs seem to fail to grasp is that, at least from my view point, they're just as bad as the people they devote their time to, if not worse. Nothing is achieved by spamming some 14 year old kid's Tumblr with gore and hate mail or getting a man arrested for defending yourself other than showing what a petty asshole you choose to be.

Many of the points they rag on "SJWs" for are things they're guilty of as well. Popular points include intolerance of dissenting opinions, dedication to harassment or personal attacks of people seen as disagreeing, being whiny/petty, rejecting science, and being entitled and unable to function in the real world. Yet the entire movement is based on this intolerance and these attacks, with pettiness or simply being whiny being a major cause. They commonly reject modern scientific findings on matters such as gender, neurodivergency, and other topics that they accuse "SJWs" of misrepresenting. And this might just be me, but nothing seems more entitled than spending your free time attacking or harassing people (often children) because they think they're some thing you don't believe in or because they see an inequality somewhere you don't.

Don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you have to agree. You can believe someone's an absolute fucking idiot, but that doesn't mean you need to go after them. Anti-SJWs are part of and worsen the "SJW problem" they dedicate themselves to combat.

EDIT: I'd like to make it clear that my point is about the main, general concept of each movement or belief and not about specific beliefs or people as people on all sides are diverse in background and in thoughts. If it helps you visualise this better, make an imaginary example of each general idea instead of focusing on specific real world views. Thanks to u/Cupcakesarethedevil for helping me clarify.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584384976.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/Ninjachibi117 (OP) has awarded 1 delta in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [**here**](/r/DeltaLog/comments/6s3jcr), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view [doesn't necessarily mean a reversal](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/index#wiki_what_is_a_.27view.27.3F), or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
