<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="409977160.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/">
    <title>CMV: Self proclaimed "anti-SJWs" are just as annoying and entitled as the people they oppose.</title>
    <original_poster>Ninjachibi117</original_poster>
    <original_post>Allow me to preface this with saying that I have an idpol bias and am a leftist, so this may make my views on social issues somewhat skewed or biased to one side. I'd also like to say that personally, I couldn't care less where someone stands on social or political issues as long as they're not an ass about it; in fact, talking and politely debating with people you disagree with is excellent and should be encouraged.

As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death (this is a general meaning, not directly true for every "sjw"). This is in part both due to and responsible for the advances in rights and equal treatment for minorities and marginalised groups with the exceptions of a few classes of people. Now personally, I'm all for the betterment of marginalised people, but there's certainly people who take these matters a bit too far, even going so far as to send death threats or other negative shenanigans to those that they perceive as opposing them even if their target agrees with them on most things. Tumblr is a popular social media for this type of people though there is a fair mix of more moderate and even some extreme contrarians on that platform.

With this comes the contrarian trend of "anti-SJWs", people who adamantly oppose those perceived to be social justice warriors and dedicate sometimes extreme levels of energy to combating them. Popular examples include many 4chan users, r/TumblrInAction and some blogs hosted, ironically, on Tumblr. These are varied in firmness of opinion from mild dissent ("oh shut up, nobody cares") to firm opposition (see: the amazing atheist) to comical levels of devotion (4chan vs Shia Laboeuf).

Now, the concept of these anti-SJWs is a weird one to me as it seems unnecessarily contrarian; nobody's hurting you so severely by believing they're a fox from another world with six dicks that you need to devote large amounts of energy and time to do nothing but basically just be a dick to them for the luls. However, that aside, the thing many of these anti-SJWs seem to fail to grasp is that, at least from my view point, they're just as bad as the people they devote their time to, if not worse. Nothing is achieved by spamming some 14 year old kid's Tumblr with gore and hate mail or getting a man arrested for defending yourself other than showing what a petty asshole you choose to be.

Many of the points they rag on "SJWs" for are things they're guilty of as well. Popular points include intolerance of dissenting opinions, dedication to harassment or personal attacks of people seen as disagreeing, being whiny/petty, rejecting science, and being entitled and unable to function in the real world. Yet the entire movement is based on this intolerance and these attacks, with pettiness or simply being whiny being a major cause. They commonly reject modern scientific findings on matters such as gender, neurodivergency, and other topics that they accuse "SJWs" of misrepresenting. And this might just be me, but nothing seems more entitled than spending your free time attacking or harassing people (often children) because they think they're some thing you don't believe in or because they see an inequality somewhere you don't.

Don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you have to agree. You can believe someone's an absolute fucking idiot, but that doesn't mean you need to go after them. Anti-SJWs are part of and worsen the "SJW problem" they dedicate themselves to combat.

EDIT: I'd like to make it clear that my point is about the main, general concept of each movement or belief and not about specific beliefs or people as people on all sides are diverse in background and in thoughts. If it helps you visualise this better, make an imaginary example of each general idea instead of focusing on specific real world views. Thanks to u/Cupcakesarethedevil for helping me clarify.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584418815.0" user="sokolov22" delta="False">
    <text>Whenever I hear "virtue signalling" my first thought is... wait, aren't you literally doing the same thing by saying those words?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584419738.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean? Sorry, I'm going to have to ask you to clarify a bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584432547.0" user="sokolov22" delta="False">
    <text>One of the terms that anti-SJWs say often use is "virtue signaling" to describe someone who they believe is saying stuff just to sound superior without doing anything actually effective about the issue - but when I hear that from someone, they are almost always trying to sound superior to the person they are criticizing in exactly the same way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584436506.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but I'm not sure how this is contributing to the discussion as it's agreeing with and providing an example of my initial argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585094291.0" user="GepardenK" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One of the terms that anti-SJWs say often use is "virtue signaling" to describe someone who they believe is saying stuff just to sound superior without doing anything actually effective about the issue

As someone who could probably be described as an anti-SJW in most settings (though that's not a label I personally use) I would like to point out that this is not exactly what we mean by "virtue signaling".

Saying something just to look morally superior to an opponent is moral grandstanding. "Virtue signaling" on the other hand is doing/saying something not because you believe it is right but because you need to show your peers that you are on the 'right side'. It's essentially about sacrificing personal integrity to either gain glory or avoid shame among your peers. A extreme example would be to have a large picture of your party leader on your wall even if you despise him just because it would help you gain a promotion (or maybe help you avoid jail). Or publicly praying to a god every day even if you don't believe in him etc etc. Virtue signaling is a universal thing that everybody does to some degree, but it is more extreme in cultures (and/or personal relationships) where you have to walk on eggshells to avoid being branded a traitor or outcast. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585245719.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>The leftist version of "virtue signaling" is "performative allyship"; calling out often menial problems or microaggressions to look good as an ally, such as a white person telling another white person not to wear dreads or a cis woman "calling out" transphobia for the sake of their own reputations. I get where the virtue signalling idea comes from, it's just a bit overused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585398752.0" user="sokolov22" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but if you look at the way the term is thrown around by many conservatives, particular on social media and the like, it basically amounts to: "Look at this dumbass, I so much more woke than he is."

It's simply become a way to discredit a point of view you disagree with, rather than a term that describes any serious commentary. And this is how a lot of this rhetoric seems to be aligned - instead of discussing the merits of the issue, the person is attacked instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585434936.0" user="GepardenK" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's simply become a way to discredit a point of view you disagree with, rather than a term that describes any serious commentary.

If/when it's used in that way it is invalid, and the best response is to point out why it is invalid. Simply put: Just because I am "virtue signaling" doesn't by itself prove that I am wrong. 

The concept of "Virtue signaling" is valid when used as a critique against a culture. The argument being that said culture suppresses individual's integrity by social peer pressure. However, claiming a person is "virtue signaling" can not be used to disprove that persons particular position on any given issue - that would be a 'ad hominem' or 'muddy the water' fallacy (ie. calling the speakers motive into question instead of tacking the speakers argument directly). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587026418.0" user="palsh7" delta="False">
    <text>Well aren't you just virtue signaling by saying that calling out virtue signaling is virtue signaling? 

Is it virtue signaling all the way down?

You're playing word games. It's like saying a person can't be selfless because it feels good to be selfless, therefore is selfish.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587036267.0" user="sokolov22" delta="False">
    <text>That's a philosophical debate that's been going for hundreds of years, so calling it "word games" is a bit insulting to many outstanding moral philosophers in history.

As for my comments, I just think it's annoying and hypocritical.  I am not suggesting I am better than they are or anything - I am sure I do things they find annoying and hypocritical as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587054254.0" user="palsh7" delta="False">
    <text>In your opinion, is it theoretically possible to critique someone without "virtue signaling"? If not, then your pointing out the hypocrisy is actually stating an aversion to all critiques, everywhere. But if so--if one can criticize without being attention or fame or praise-seeking--then one can (and should) call out said behavior. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587094024.0" user="sokolov22" delta="False">
    <text>I think so, yes.  If you actually argue against the merits of their argument then that seems fine to me.  The thing with "virtue signalling" is that it is often used in place of any actual discussion - it's just used as a wide brush to completely dismiss anything the person has said.  And to me, that is what lacks any productivity and can ONLY be virtue signalling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29589162530.0" user="sokolov22" delta="False">
    <text>Also note, when someone does this, as I am claiming, I have NOTHING to argue because they haven't provided me with anything other than this charge of virtue signalling, therefore my own logic here doesn't apply to myself because I am literally critiquing the only thing made available to me.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
