<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="409977160.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/">
    <title>CMV: Self proclaimed "anti-SJWs" are just as annoying and entitled as the people they oppose.</title>
    <original_poster>Ninjachibi117</original_poster>
    <original_post>Allow me to preface this with saying that I have an idpol bias and am a leftist, so this may make my views on social issues somewhat skewed or biased to one side. I'd also like to say that personally, I couldn't care less where someone stands on social or political issues as long as they're not an ass about it; in fact, talking and politely debating with people you disagree with is excellent and should be encouraged.

As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death (this is a general meaning, not directly true for every "sjw"). This is in part both due to and responsible for the advances in rights and equal treatment for minorities and marginalised groups with the exceptions of a few classes of people. Now personally, I'm all for the betterment of marginalised people, but there's certainly people who take these matters a bit too far, even going so far as to send death threats or other negative shenanigans to those that they perceive as opposing them even if their target agrees with them on most things. Tumblr is a popular social media for this type of people though there is a fair mix of more moderate and even some extreme contrarians on that platform.

With this comes the contrarian trend of "anti-SJWs", people who adamantly oppose those perceived to be social justice warriors and dedicate sometimes extreme levels of energy to combating them. Popular examples include many 4chan users, r/TumblrInAction and some blogs hosted, ironically, on Tumblr. These are varied in firmness of opinion from mild dissent ("oh shut up, nobody cares") to firm opposition (see: the amazing atheist) to comical levels of devotion (4chan vs Shia Laboeuf).

Now, the concept of these anti-SJWs is a weird one to me as it seems unnecessarily contrarian; nobody's hurting you so severely by believing they're a fox from another world with six dicks that you need to devote large amounts of energy and time to do nothing but basically just be a dick to them for the luls. However, that aside, the thing many of these anti-SJWs seem to fail to grasp is that, at least from my view point, they're just as bad as the people they devote their time to, if not worse. Nothing is achieved by spamming some 14 year old kid's Tumblr with gore and hate mail or getting a man arrested for defending yourself other than showing what a petty asshole you choose to be.

Many of the points they rag on "SJWs" for are things they're guilty of as well. Popular points include intolerance of dissenting opinions, dedication to harassment or personal attacks of people seen as disagreeing, being whiny/petty, rejecting science, and being entitled and unable to function in the real world. Yet the entire movement is based on this intolerance and these attacks, with pettiness or simply being whiny being a major cause. They commonly reject modern scientific findings on matters such as gender, neurodivergency, and other topics that they accuse "SJWs" of misrepresenting. And this might just be me, but nothing seems more entitled than spending your free time attacking or harassing people (often children) because they think they're some thing you don't believe in or because they see an inequality somewhere you don't.

Don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you have to agree. You can believe someone's an absolute fucking idiot, but that doesn't mean you need to go after them. Anti-SJWs are part of and worsen the "SJW problem" they dedicate themselves to combat.

EDIT: I'd like to make it clear that my point is about the main, general concept of each movement or belief and not about specific beliefs or people as people on all sides are diverse in background and in thoughts. If it helps you visualise this better, make an imaginary example of each general idea instead of focusing on specific real world views. Thanks to u/Cupcakesarethedevil for helping me clarify.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584285351.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>This is all going to depend on how you define both categories which I am not sure how you can do without serious straw-manning. The most vocal an extreme are the ones you see on the internet which don't represent mainstream views and if it's not mainstream views you are cherry-picking which are pointless when talking about broad ideas like you seem to want to.  In addition very few people who an anti-SJW would call a SJW would call themselves a SJW for example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584290666.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>I explained in my post the general idea of both movements and even acknowledged that such broad generalisations don't hold water in the real world. However, for sake of conversation, I'll edit to clarify that I'm talking about the main concept of both movements and not specific people as again, people aren't cut and dry like words on a page are. I'm a bit confused by your last sentence though; I'm not sure what it's supposed to mean whether it's the manner of writing or just my own incompetence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584296883.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>SJW at least started off as a pejorative phrase used to dismiss people as extremists. Just like every racist will say "I'm not a racist ... but" very few SJW will identify as a SJW.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584300377.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>That's kind of my point, though there are a growing number of people who self identify jokingly or otherwise as either one. As opposed to considering someone calling themselves one, think of the kind of person typically associated with or referred to by that name, derogatory as its origin may be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584311197.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;think of the kind of person typically associated with or referred to by that name, derogatory as its origin may be.

This is definition of straw-manning, if we are not going to talk about specific examples, but instead boogeymen we are imagining we can't have a reasonable discussion or change your view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584333321.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>That's not quite how that works. Discussing broad topics or beliefs is most of what this sub is, and is certainly not a strawman fallacy. Now, if I were deliberately misrepresenting the views of specific opponents or people to argue against, that would be different, but this isn't a post about the merits of social justice versus its counters, rather about the hypocrisy and entitlement common in a movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584345913.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>We can have a discussion about this but since SJW and anti-SJW have different meanings to different people you are going to have to define them and stick to those definitions for this discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584347864.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>Which is why I provided a brief overlook and explanation of each in the post. Take a stab at a reread, perhaps?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584524707.0" user="mooi_verhaal" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death

This is an inadequate definition - it's hyperbole for one - what does 'life and death" mean here? Is it meant to sound pejorative? Honestly, you need a better definition, which is what /u/cupcakesarethedevil is getting at. I certainly, for one, don't think I define SJW the same way as you do. For one thing, it seems to be a strictly online term? Perhaps denoting people who say but don't do. And it's meant to be derogatory in flavor I think. I'm a bit confused.  

Edit: You wrote this down the sub too. &amp;lt;"SJWs" are angry and offended over a thing they conceptually disagree with without context&amp;gt; Is this part of your definition? 

It seems you are comparing a group that is externally defined (SJWs) with a group that is self-defined (anti-SJWs) - is that right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587014339.0" user="palsh7" delta="False">
    <text>Can you point me to a reference proving that Social Justice Warrior originated as a pejorative? I find it plausible but far from obvious. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29586014430.0" user="Jessiray" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In addition very few people who an anti-SJW would call a SJW would call themselves a SJW for example.

If you look on tumblr and certain sects of youtube, reddit, etc. you will certainly find people who self-identify as anti-SJW and make it a mission statement of sorts. 

Self-identifying as an SJW is a bit more rare, as that term is usually used as an insult and I have seen people accuse anyone from a moderate liberal who maybe voted for Clinton or Sanders all the way to a kid who self-identifies as a trans space fox with 9 penises of being SJWs. A few years back people mostly accused the later, but now the term has lost a lot of meaning because it's being applied to people with fairly moderate opinions as a means of dismissing them. 

Like if you say trans people have the right to exist or you don't want the KKK posting propaganda in your town, you're an EVIL SJW WHO MUST BE STOPPEDD!!! to some people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
