<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="409977160.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/">
    <title>CMV: Self proclaimed "anti-SJWs" are just as annoying and entitled as the people they oppose.</title>
    <original_poster>Ninjachibi117</original_poster>
    <original_post>Allow me to preface this with saying that I have an idpol bias and am a leftist, so this may make my views on social issues somewhat skewed or biased to one side. I'd also like to say that personally, I couldn't care less where someone stands on social or political issues as long as they're not an ass about it; in fact, talking and politely debating with people you disagree with is excellent and should be encouraged.

As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death (this is a general meaning, not directly true for every "sjw"). This is in part both due to and responsible for the advances in rights and equal treatment for minorities and marginalised groups with the exceptions of a few classes of people. Now personally, I'm all for the betterment of marginalised people, but there's certainly people who take these matters a bit too far, even going so far as to send death threats or other negative shenanigans to those that they perceive as opposing them even if their target agrees with them on most things. Tumblr is a popular social media for this type of people though there is a fair mix of more moderate and even some extreme contrarians on that platform.

With this comes the contrarian trend of "anti-SJWs", people who adamantly oppose those perceived to be social justice warriors and dedicate sometimes extreme levels of energy to combating them. Popular examples include many 4chan users, r/TumblrInAction and some blogs hosted, ironically, on Tumblr. These are varied in firmness of opinion from mild dissent ("oh shut up, nobody cares") to firm opposition (see: the amazing atheist) to comical levels of devotion (4chan vs Shia Laboeuf).

Now, the concept of these anti-SJWs is a weird one to me as it seems unnecessarily contrarian; nobody's hurting you so severely by believing they're a fox from another world with six dicks that you need to devote large amounts of energy and time to do nothing but basically just be a dick to them for the luls. However, that aside, the thing many of these anti-SJWs seem to fail to grasp is that, at least from my view point, they're just as bad as the people they devote their time to, if not worse. Nothing is achieved by spamming some 14 year old kid's Tumblr with gore and hate mail or getting a man arrested for defending yourself other than showing what a petty asshole you choose to be.

Many of the points they rag on "SJWs" for are things they're guilty of as well. Popular points include intolerance of dissenting opinions, dedication to harassment or personal attacks of people seen as disagreeing, being whiny/petty, rejecting science, and being entitled and unable to function in the real world. Yet the entire movement is based on this intolerance and these attacks, with pettiness or simply being whiny being a major cause. They commonly reject modern scientific findings on matters such as gender, neurodivergency, and other topics that they accuse "SJWs" of misrepresenting. And this might just be me, but nothing seems more entitled than spending your free time attacking or harassing people (often children) because they think they're some thing you don't believe in or because they see an inequality somewhere you don't.

Don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you have to agree. You can believe someone's an absolute fucking idiot, but that doesn't mean you need to go after them. Anti-SJWs are part of and worsen the "SJW problem" they dedicate themselves to combat.

EDIT: I'd like to make it clear that my point is about the main, general concept of each movement or belief and not about specific beliefs or people as people on all sides are diverse in background and in thoughts. If it helps you visualise this better, make an imaginary example of each general idea instead of focusing on specific real world views. Thanks to u/Cupcakesarethedevil for helping me clarify.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584368706.0" user="jack_hof" delta="False">
    <text>Most anti-SJW content comes about as a response/counter to something that the SJWs did. The anti-SJWs wouldn't exist without the SJWs, but the SJWs would exist without the antis. Therefore the SJWs are most annoying. They stir the pot and create the chaos, the antis just try to keep things in check/sane. The "W" in SJW basically comes about by a person taking the original idea too far, and so naturally people will crop up from the woodwork to call them out. That's like saying the people who call out real racism are as annoying as the people commit the racism. tl;dr one is a response to the other and if you got rid of the former the latter would go away as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584375403.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>That might have been true at the start, but now the counter culture has become a culture itself much like the punk scene or graffiti. It's intellectually dishonest to claim that SJWs are fully to blame for stirring the pot or creating chaos; and the idea of the actions of a lot of anti-SJWs is far from keeping things in check or sane. And for that matter, what is there to keep in check? As I said in my post, what are you accomplishing by heckling a child because they think they're a multigendered cartoon alien?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584379353.0" user="jack_hof" delta="False">
    <text>It would seem that it takes a culture to counter a culture. The far-leftist ideologies and the ideologues who propagate them have become more and more prevalent as of the past half decade or so, and people are starting to get pissed/annoyed, and yes it has spawned a counter-culture. So much so that I believe that is what put trump in the white house. Put simply and juvenile - they started it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584386166.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>Disagreement about Trump and the merits of SJW culture and counterculture aside, as that's off topic, I will agree that "they started it". My issue is with, as mothers everywhere lament, "sinking to their level". Done well, as u/thecommonclay highlights, this opposition can be a positive contribution; my issue is with those who handle it less than ideally such as r/TumblrInAction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584377199.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>Also, in reference to your edit, getting rid of so-called "SJWs" would be a net harm, not a good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584387022.0" user="jack_hof" delta="False">
    <text>Well we clearly know where you stand on the matter. It's definitely a discussion whether or not social justice is a good thing, but the extremists of that ideology (or any ideology for that matter) are always a bad thing. SJWs (by my definition anyway) are precisely those who take the concept of social justice "too far" or who go about trying to achieve it in the wrong way. Much like how I agree with feminism on paper and by definition, but most all of what the modern "third wave" form of it seeks I generally don't approve of. It's the "W" part that people hate, not the "SJ."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584390935.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>I did preface my argument with my own personal bias. And I don't much like the tone of your first line as it does seem a little inflammatory, but maybe I'm reading too far into it. However, while there are certainly extremists on this as all sides, it's important to note that with a broad label any progress or social issue groups could be labeled as "SJWs". This is all somewhat irrelevant to the post though, so it's best to leave this here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584661657.0" user="polysyndetonic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well we clearly know where you stand on the matter. It's definitely a discussion whether or not social justice is a good thing, but the extremists of that ideology (or any ideology for that matter) are always a bad thing.

What about the 'extremists' who opposed monarchy in favour of liberalism and democracy in the 18th century?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584929520.0" user="PM_ME_YOU_BOOBS" delta="False">
    <text>You mean like the French Revolution? The revolution which was ten years of chaos and bloodshed with hundreds of thousands dead? The same revolution that directly lead to the napoleonic wars that killed millions? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584940301.0" user="polysyndetonic" delta="False">
    <text>So you think it would be better for the blood to be spared and to still have monarchy instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584981233.0" user="PM_ME_YOU_BOOBS" delta="False">
    <text>Well for the people living at the time yes very much so. However bad living under the French monarchy was, it can't compare to economic turmoil and colossal loss of life that the revolution caused between 1789-1815. I can't really comment on if it would be more beneficial for those living in 2017 due to the butterfly effect. 

Plus there are still plenty of countries that live under a monarchy, I live in one of them. Thanks to various (mostly peaceful) political reforms over the last couple centuries, most monarchies are practically no different to live in than a republic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585093691.0" user="polysyndetonic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Plus there are still plenty of countries that live under a monarchy, I live in one of them. Thanks to various (mostly peaceful) political reforms over the last couple centuries, most monarchies are practically no different to live in than a republic.



All of them have been hugely influenced by the events of the french revolution.they didnt just drift whiggishly into utopia</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29586066808.0" user="Jessiray" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that the antis have the potential to be worse because:

* They are being hypocritical. They're 'exposing extremism' by being extreme.

* Many SJWs just kinda exist in their own, dumb bubble. There may be an autistic 12 year old who think's he's a trans wolf lady and post that on tumblr. He's cringy to be sure, but so are most people at that age. Is it really called for to harass and dox someone online for being cringy? I know SJWs do this too, and anti's will be quick to point out things like the whole Steven Universe debacle, but then turn around and do the same thing to children.

* The obsession and fixation on certain people can border on creepy. There are entire youtube channels dedicated to tearing down 'famous sjws' like Laci Green, Anita Sarkeesian, Franchesca Ramsey, etc. The worst of the Anti's will fixate on certain people who are annoying and factually wrong *at worst* and start very creepily obsessive harassment campaigns against them that often include specific threats of harm. SJWs might do this on occasion as well, but at least it's usually literal nazis like Richard Spencer and the like. IDK about you, but while violence is never justified, I think calling for the genocide of non-white people is *much* worse than being wrong about women in video games. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
