<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="409977160.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/">
    <title>CMV: Self proclaimed "anti-SJWs" are just as annoying and entitled as the people they oppose.</title>
    <original_poster>Ninjachibi117</original_poster>
    <original_post>Allow me to preface this with saying that I have an idpol bias and am a leftist, so this may make my views on social issues somewhat skewed or biased to one side. I'd also like to say that personally, I couldn't care less where someone stands on social or political issues as long as they're not an ass about it; in fact, talking and politely debating with people you disagree with is excellent and should be encouraged.

As most people know, there's been a recent trend in visibility of so called "social justice warriors"; people who take identity politics and social issues as a matter of life and death (this is a general meaning, not directly true for every "sjw"). This is in part both due to and responsible for the advances in rights and equal treatment for minorities and marginalised groups with the exceptions of a few classes of people. Now personally, I'm all for the betterment of marginalised people, but there's certainly people who take these matters a bit too far, even going so far as to send death threats or other negative shenanigans to those that they perceive as opposing them even if their target agrees with them on most things. Tumblr is a popular social media for this type of people though there is a fair mix of more moderate and even some extreme contrarians on that platform.

With this comes the contrarian trend of "anti-SJWs", people who adamantly oppose those perceived to be social justice warriors and dedicate sometimes extreme levels of energy to combating them. Popular examples include many 4chan users, r/TumblrInAction and some blogs hosted, ironically, on Tumblr. These are varied in firmness of opinion from mild dissent ("oh shut up, nobody cares") to firm opposition (see: the amazing atheist) to comical levels of devotion (4chan vs Shia Laboeuf).

Now, the concept of these anti-SJWs is a weird one to me as it seems unnecessarily contrarian; nobody's hurting you so severely by believing they're a fox from another world with six dicks that you need to devote large amounts of energy and time to do nothing but basically just be a dick to them for the luls. However, that aside, the thing many of these anti-SJWs seem to fail to grasp is that, at least from my view point, they're just as bad as the people they devote their time to, if not worse. Nothing is achieved by spamming some 14 year old kid's Tumblr with gore and hate mail or getting a man arrested for defending yourself other than showing what a petty asshole you choose to be.

Many of the points they rag on "SJWs" for are things they're guilty of as well. Popular points include intolerance of dissenting opinions, dedication to harassment or personal attacks of people seen as disagreeing, being whiny/petty, rejecting science, and being entitled and unable to function in the real world. Yet the entire movement is based on this intolerance and these attacks, with pettiness or simply being whiny being a major cause. They commonly reject modern scientific findings on matters such as gender, neurodivergency, and other topics that they accuse "SJWs" of misrepresenting. And this might just be me, but nothing seems more entitled than spending your free time attacking or harassing people (often children) because they think they're some thing you don't believe in or because they see an inequality somewhere you don't.

Don't get me wrong, I'm not saying you have to agree. You can believe someone's an absolute fucking idiot, but that doesn't mean you need to go after them. Anti-SJWs are part of and worsen the "SJW problem" they dedicate themselves to combat.

EDIT: I'd like to make it clear that my point is about the main, general concept of each movement or belief and not about specific beliefs or people as people on all sides are diverse in background and in thoughts. If it helps you visualise this better, make an imaginary example of each general idea instead of focusing on specific real world views. Thanks to u/Cupcakesarethedevil for helping me clarify.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584396649.0" user="KingMarshmalo" delta="False">
    <text>I would like to challenge the view by instead insisting that they are much, much worse than the people they oppose. 

First reason is because SJWs just don't exist. The most important part of attacking political factions is self identification. If I criticize Libertarians or Anarcho-Primitivists, I am criticizing the tactics or beliefs of the people who identity as that political faction. With SJWs however, no such self-identification exists. Nowhere on the internet or real life are people proudly proclaiming themselves social justice warriors, which makes SJW a label and an insult rather than a legitimate political position. Furthermore, the concept of an SJW falls into the category of circular reasoning. The title of SJW is usually painted on individuals that the center right sees as "radical leftism", who are criticized for being radical. This creates a circle, as the people who are being criticized for being radicals are only in that group because they are radical. The concept of an SJW is completely flawed, and should not be entertained in mature discussion, therefore any attempts to compare a real group comprised of millions (as confirmed by YouTube comments and Like-Dislike ratio on YouTube, as well as the fact that they denote themselves as such) such as anti-SJWs.

Second reason is because the frequency and intensity of negative actions committed by anti-SJWs are somehow worse than the strawman that they label as SJWs. For virtually all SJWs, a person that meets the criteria of SJW perhaps more than anyone else is game critic Anita Sarkeesian. Let's examine a game created by an anti-SJW called "Beat up Anita". This game is centered around physically abusing the face of Anita, leaving bruises and blood for your entertainment. Now let's examine the worse thing somebody labeled an SJW has done, which seems to be acknowledging the existence of 63 genders. I'll let you decide which one is worse. Additionally, anti-SJWs generally lack empathy, as can be seen with their obsession with dark humor, racist and sexist humor, staunch homophobia, insistence that transgender people have a mental illness, and complete and total hatred towards overweight women. The left has no equivalent. 

Edit: As expected I'm being downvoted. It's almost like only one side exists. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584402109.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree with the sentiment, for the sake of fairness it's important to consider things such as the prevalence of doxxing, death threats and anonymous hate mail in social justice communities and the frequency of widely excommunicating someone from these circles due to disagreement on a single point; though this last feature is true everywhere. Is it as bad as Beat Up Anita or any laundry list of things done in opposition? Maybe not, but it's still not exactly moderate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584408819.0" user="KingMarshmalo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the prevalence of doxxing, death threats and anonymous hate mail in social justice communities 

Are these people who explicitly identified as SJWs? And are there any specific examples? I can name lots of gamergate figures who received death and rape threats and many pro-equality YouTube videos (i.e. International women's day video) that have negative reactions. Can you do the same? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584414862.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>When I was a preteen and teenager, I frequented forums and later Tumblr social justice circles, even participating in some questionably pointless but at the time important seeming issues. The sheer number of people I know who've received death threats, including celebrities, authors, and artists, is almost absurd. I've personally received a good handful from all sides of the spectrum for a variety of reasons, and been spammed with gore 4 times by people who would commonly be regarded as extremely pro-SJ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584421565.0" user="KingMarshmalo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; be regarded as extremely pro-SJ

Did they personally identify as an "SJW"? Because it's easy to find people who identify as an anti-SJW. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584423736.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>Some did, some didn't. It's the principle of the matter. A extreme, militant third-wave feminist that participates in the "SJW" side of every issue big or small with personal commitment fits neatly into what would be considered an sjw in the context of this argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584663240.0" user="polysyndetonic" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this works either.Richard Spencer would not probably self identify as a neo nazi but he is in all but name, in my view, and in the view of many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585083858.0" user="laconicflow" delta="False">
    <text>But that's obviously bullshit. And also not the worst thing sjw's, although they are not self-proclaimbed, have done. Remember that college where traditionally, minority students took a day to get away from white people, sagfe spaces, and then a faction of students wanted white people to leave the campus they paid to attend for a day, and the professor who opposed that was given a bunch of shit by that faction? The guy who wrote the bell curve was protested against, along with Ian Hersey Alley, (sorry for spelling,) and this opposition was founded on emotional moral outrage, rather than facts. . . SJW's don't want to hear what they don't want to hear. And it doesn't matter they don't claim the label. Most modern American women are feminists, no matter that most don't call themselves feminists. Americans who like medicaid/medicair/wellfair, or believe the programs should continue are some kind of socialists, even if they never call themselves that. What you are saying is that only self-administered labels are valid, and that's wrong. . . And what you may be missing is that people who oppose sjw's come in different stripes and do so for different reasons. For myself, I don't like these kids throwing tantroms when speakers with different viewpoints go to speak at colleges. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585237982.0" user="Ninjachibi117" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, this is true to a degree. But I want to focus on one line of this:

&amp;gt; SJWs don't want to hear what they don't want to hear.

Is this not equally true of antis? Some antis throw a huge bitch fit when they're told, for example, that being transgender isn't a mental illness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585433876.0" user="KingMarshmalo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; although they are not self-proclaimbed

And just like that all criticism becomes invalid. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585535975.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585588041.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry TT454, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+TT454&amp;amp;message=TT454+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6s38eg/cmv_self_proclaimed_antisjws_are_just_as_annoying/dlagpnr/\))</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
