<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584733058.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>even if we accept the premise that somehow tomatoes have the ability to suffer, despite having no brain or nervous-system, it is still more ethical to be vegan. what do think a pig eats before it gets slaughtered? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584757905.0" user="Kor03d" delta="False">
    <text>Plants have the ability to change their biology in response to external stimuli. It is not the exact reflex-type reaction a nervous system can produce, but it is still a reaction. it is not fair to treat plant suffering differently because they feel in a different mechanism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584774992.0" user="16072016" delta="False">
    <text>I think you've missed the stronger point (based on your concerns)
&amp;gt;what do think a pig eats before it gets slaughtered

Just eating meat doesn't mean you are sparing the life of plants, animals we eat are either directly or indirectly eating plants for energy.  In fact all energy on Earth (save negligible amounts from geothermal) comes from the sun.  The further removed from the sun the less efficient you are being with this energy (plants expend energy to grow, animals to grow and move around).  Since humans cannot perform photosynthesis the best we can do is to get our energy from plants (sun -&amp;gt; plants -&amp;gt; humans) as opposed to animals (sun -&amp;gt; plants -&amp;gt; animals .... -&amp;gt; humans).   This is both more efficient with energy, but also wastes less of our other resources such as water and fertilizer.

Again, by eating meat you are not saving the life of plants, you are just killing more things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584798697.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>the ability to response to external stimuli is not the same as the ability to suffer. Your mobilephone can react to external stimuli, just like plants. but they cant suffer. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584806177.0" user="Gloriouscdmaster" delta="False">
    <text>A pig eats its own poop, that's why it's a disgusting animal no one should eat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584949634.0" user="DarkMaster22" delta="False">
    <text>Dogs eat their own poop. Are dogs disgusting?
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
