<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584825452.0" user="VredeJohn" delta="False">
    <text>Have you considered that animals also require food. If you "kill" a tomato and eat it you gain close to 100% of the nutritional value of that tomato. But if you feed an animal that tomato only a fraction of the nutritional value will be converted to edible meat.

So to get a tomato's worth of energy a vegetarian has to "kill" one tomato while a meat eater would have to "kill" ten tomatoes to feed an animal before the question of killing that animal even comes up.

From that perspective the vegetarian might not be morally justified, but they would be morally superior because they choose to "kill" as little as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
