<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29585166580.0" user="exotics" delta="False">
    <text>When we pick a tomato we don't kill the plant.  We pick the tomato.. this is the same with apples, berries, peas, beans, corn, and so forth.  The plant lives.   So certainly when eating some fruit/vegetables.. there is no death involved whatsoever.  When we kill an animal, it's dead.  The housing conditions in which we keep livestock animals is pretty bad.  And killing day old male chicks just because they wont lay eggs is also terrible.  Gestation crates are pens that keep pigs immobile, they are worse conditions than dogs breeding for puppy mills are kept in, and pigs are as smart as dogs.  How is that okay?  It is cruel.  The dairy industry takes calves away and keeps them immobile as well so they will be veal, it's very cruel.  I could go on but I have to go to work soon..

Hunting is far more humane than how we raise livestock.  Most people eat more meat than they actually need to eat so in North America particularly, more animals suffer and die than need to even if people were not vegetarians.

I am not a vegetarian.

Also - note that vast areas of trees are killed to grow crops to feed farm animals.  If people ate less meat, or more people ate no meat at all, then the environment would thrive.

Farming has contributed to deforestation which has contributed to climate change and the extinction of many plants and animals.  Some people are vegetarians for the sake of the environment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
