<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584816977.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>This is a simply stated CMV with broad implications.  I'd argue that veganism and vegetarianism are ethically superior to a standard diet simply because those two diets have a far lower carbon footprint than one that incorporates meat.  Any diet that increases the rate of climate change and would thus hurt *everything* regardless is worse than one that doesn't.

But as far as animal lives are concerned, yes, they are separate from plants.  It's not a matter of being harder to relate to.  Physical pain, nociception, is an effect of a nervous system.  Plants don't have the same systems as animals, plainly put.  Their suffering may be different but not in any way is it observably larger than ours.  Pain is not some ethereal thing you experience - it's directly related to a nervous system.  Even people have various tolerances of pain.  Some people suffer from an inability to feel pain, meaning if they get hurt they won't know it.  Sounds amazing at first until you realize how important pain is to stopping further injury.

It would certainly be sadistic and cruel, reflecting the personality of the person doing it, to "torture" a jellyfish who doesn't feel pain like we know it, but that's like an alien species coming to Earth and torturing me by blowing warm air onto me and massaging my back because they hate anything warm and all physical touch.  It would certainly reveal their character but what would it mean for me?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588313364.0" user="Hotblack_Desiato_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I'd argue that veganism and vegetarianism are ethically superior to a standard diet simply because those two diets have a far lower carbon footprint than one that incorporates meat.

As I said elsewhere in the thread, this only applies to meat produced in a certain way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588449124.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>Unless it's made in a petri dish, how exactly would a cow's carbon footprint change?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588588023.0" user="Hotblack_Desiato_" delta="False">
    <text>If it's range-fed its entire life, all the way up to slaughter.  Feedlot cows are what are so environmentally horrible, and most of a cow's carbon footprint comes from the energy used to produce fertilizer used to grow the feed (usually a corn byproduct).  Another thing that environmentalists complain about is water use, but cows only require that much water because the feed used is extremely low moisture compared to what cows evolved to eat, and because they need extra water due to the completely different metabolism of the feed.

Range-fed cows require almost no water, because the bulk of their water intake comes from the grass they eat, which is at least 50% water, probably more.

&amp;gt;But that land can be used to grow food for people!

No.

The steppes where cows evolved and thrive is extremely infertile.  The reason that only grass grows there is because only grass CAN grow there.  There's nowhere near enough water or soil nutrient for anything else.  In terms of rainfall, it's only a few inches of rainfall a year above being a desert.  In order to cultivate human food in that environment, you'd need lots of expensive, carbon-intensive fertilizer and irrigation systems.  The most environmentally-friendly thing to cultivate there would be cows.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
