<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584725288.0" user="Latera" delta="False">
    <text>watch the documentary Cowspiracy, it will show you that vegetarianism is at least ethically superior because of the climate situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584762422.0" user="Kor03d" delta="False">
    <text>It is a fair point, but my post was about ethical side of killing for food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584786083.0" user="Latera" delta="False">
    <text>Would you say that helping to destroy a planet - the planet that 7 billion people live on - is ethically okay? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585466694.0" user="Kor03d" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that only thing we are threatening to destroy is our own comfortable way of life. We are not protecting our environment because it is ethical, we are doing it because of a selfish and understandable urge to not to live in Mad Max universe. As a humanity, we will probably need at least thrice as much nukes as we have to destroy moon, let alone our giant planet.

And as I already said earlier, in my post I do not consider the environmental side of various dietary habits. It is only about killing for food.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585535955.0" user="Latera" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding your last parapgrah: no, your headline is literally 'not ethically superior' </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
