<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584725519.0" user="Staross" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato.

They are very much different, a tomato doesn't have the neural basis for experiencing suffering, it's basic biology.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nociception

Also there's strong environmental arguments for eating no/less meat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584775125.0" user="Kor03d" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you. I can't reply to all comments with this argument, so I added an edit to post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588309483.0" user="Hotblack_Desiato_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They are very much different, a tomato doesn't have the neural basis for experiencing suffering, it's basic biology.

...that humans appreciate.  People using science to back up arguments like this come across as pretty silly because they come across like scientists in the 19th century who said that the only things left for science to do are resolution of some minor details, the rest is pretty much figured out.

It ignores the very basic fact that the list of things we don't know is much longer than the list of things we do know, and an even bigger list of things we don't know that we don't know.  There is so much we don't know about plants.  MANY plants CLEARLY exhibit behaviors that can only be explained by their being able to perceive their environment, but damned if anyone knows how they do it.  So your statement looks pretty ignorant.

Also, those environmental arguments only apply to meat produced in certain ways.  Please stop pretending that it applies to all meat produced in all ways.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
