<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584720823.0" user="xiccit" delta="False">
    <text>A tomato is not an animal. You can live without eating animals. This is not opinion, it is fact. If you'd like to debate the definition of an animal that's a whole different game. And I love meat.  

If you want to use less water and make less animals who arnt tomatoes suffer, being a vegetarian makes sense.   Last I checked tomatoes don't form emotional bonds. 

How is the death of a sentient being not different than that of eating a non sentient plant? The hell?    </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584760732.0" user="Kor03d" delta="False">
    <text>1. You can also live without killing plants, restricting to killing animals.
2. A lot of animals don't have complex nervous system allowing human-like emotions, either, but I have never seen anyone advocating eating worms and insects instead of mammals.
3. Well, yes. How the hell it is different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29584812502.0" user="Sveet_Pickle" delta="False">
    <text>[There's plenty of advocacy for eating insects](https://www.vox.com/2014/4/30/5664782/insects) vice also just finished a piece on Chinas bug eating industry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29587907441.0" user="Mephanic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can also live without killing plants, restricting to killing animals.

By proxy, you are still killing plants. The animals eaten by humans also needed food, which means plants again. (If you eat a carnivore, that animals still ate other animals - follow the food chain and you end up at plants.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588316434.0" user="Hotblack_Desiato_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A tomato is not an animal. You can live without eating animals. **This is not opinion, it is fact.**

No it isn't.

There are a number of fatty acids that are essential to health that can only be derived from animal sources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588978002.0" user="xiccit" delta="False">
    <text>Ah yes I forgot anyone who's a vegan is dead within a year... 

One second of googling would have shown you all fatty acids are available in a non animal sourced way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29588986179.0" user="Hotblack_Desiato_" delta="False">
    <text>Do everyone a favor and look up the difference between "life" and "health."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29589099448.0" user="xiccit" delta="False">
    <text>ok then go ahead, what fatty acid is not available without an animal source, and is essential to health?
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
