<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410036793.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6s4iex/cmv_veganism_and_vegetarianism_are_not_ethically/">
    <title>CMV: Veganism and vegetarianism are not ethically superior to standard omnivorous diet</title>
    <original_poster>Kor03d</original_poster>
    <original_post>There is no point in becoming vegan or vegetarian in effort to save animals lives. Suffering or even death of a farm animal are no different to those of a tomato, even if it is harder to emotionally compassionate to the latter, as it is easier for us to relate to animal feelings. You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food, and animal lives are not more important than plants or fungi in that regard.

Please note that does not account for switching diet for own health reasons.

*EDIT: Yes, in my view I consider that plants can suffer even if they don't have the same mechanisms of perception animals do. Jellyfishes don't have a nervous system anywhere close to ours, yet it would still be unethical to cut one in pieces for amusement. Jellyfish would still perceive injury and its normal biological cycles would be hindered. Same goes for plants*
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29584744551.0" user="suizidraupe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  You can not exist without ending other creatures life for food

This is not true. You do not kill a tomatoplant by taking tomatoes or kill chicken by taking eggs from a chicken (when they are not fertilized). You only reduce their possibility to produce offspring (in the case of the chicken not even that).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29585435203.0" user="Precious_Tritium" delta="False">
    <text>That's actually a fair point. Fruit in general (apples, tomatoes, etc) exist to be eaten to help spread the seeds and propagate the plant. It's in a way beneficial to the plant, or should be.

Killing a pig is in now way beneficial to the pig.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
