<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621622464.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>A number of Presidents have served successfully without having a prior elected office.  Most notably, Taylor, Grant, and Eisenhower came to the Presidency from a military background.

Hoover also never held an elected office before he was President.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29622228488.0" user="JorahTheExplorer" delta="False">
    <text>There's also some evidence that Abraham Lincoln suffered from depression. He's today usually placed as one of the top three presidents. Disqualifying him would've been a tremendous loss.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
