<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621269167.0" user="brock_lee" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with tests is often who gets to make them. We know there is a serious problem with gerrymandering in the US, and can we not assume there would be a similar issue with a mental competency test?   It's possible that they could be biased toward whoever makes them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621271114.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>That's definitely fair, especially given how ridiculous his physical bill of health was. Maybe a competent professional could be selected by a joint congressional committee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621274830.0" user="brock_lee" delta="False">
    <text>Congress itself is supposed *to be* the checks and balances of government. Yet, they can't be trusted to make the tests, or pick the doctors who make the tests, of even create the committee that recommends the list of doctors who gets voted on to form a committee to make the tests.

If it's not one party or other, you can be sure the joint session would be biased toward the wealthy, since Congress is mostly wealthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621276047.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe so, but I would still be happy to see an attempt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29625874210.0" user="rocksalamander" delta="False">
    <text>The supreme court justices are confirmed in a similar manner, and judging  (pun intended) by how the last year has gone, we can safely say Congress and the President collectively game the system. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
