<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621281213.0" user="zh1K476tt9pq" delta="False">
    <text>This is something that sounds good in theory but is very difficult to implement in practice.

For example, how much experience in politics is enough? And why is it X years and not Y years? Which level of experience counts? Also why does only politics count? Politics isn't rocket science, just because Trump is bad at it doesn't mean that being in charge of a large organization isn't useful experience. In fact it's quite common that people move from senior positions in fields outside politics into politics and do well. Furthermore "politics" often means being part of body that creates laws whereas the president is in the executive branch. So it isn't really the same skill set and experience anyway. E.g. you can be a politician for decades and still have only very limited leadership experience.

&amp;gt; whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

This is obviously flawed. I am sure someone like Trump could get a seat somewhere and hold it without putting in much time and effort. Many seats, even in congress, are held by people that don't actually spend a lot of time working as politicians, e.g. they aren't in any commissions or don't have any specific functions, they just vote when it's important. So they don't gain much relevant experience and it doesn't really stop people that aren't qualified. At the same time you are excluding many qualified people. In fact it might be better to have people in charge that are more like bureaucrats and less like politicians. This is quite common in Western Europe, many people want to have a boring president that look more like an accountant.

&amp;gt; Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.

This is also quite vague. Psychology isn't math where something is right or wrong. Trump is likely the perfect borderline candidate. I don't like him but it's questionable whether he is really mentally unfit. Many people in leadership positions have narcissistic tendencies. So where exactly do you draw the line? How much narcissism is too much? Also who does make this decision? It's seems kind of extreme to give a bunch of psychologists such extreme power especially for something that isn't really quantifiable. And who decides who those psychologists will be? I mean what if those psychologists happen to be conservatives and e.g. removed Bill Clinton for being a "sex addict"? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621292534.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I hadn't thought of a mental health examination as giving individual psychologists a lot of power, that's a good point.

As for experience, a lot of people here seem to be thinking I meant it as "if you're experienced, you'll be better at the job." Sorry if I wasn't clear. I meant that prior experience would be a window into that individual's governing style, which I believe is valuable information.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621340930.0" user="zh1K476tt9pq" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I meant that prior experience would be a window into that individual's governing style, which I believe is valuable information.

Okay, I misunderstood you then. How does that related to Trump though? His views have been very public for years. E.g. the whole birther movement started long before his 2016 campaign. Also politicians are changing their views all the time anyway. E.g. Romney was far more liberal as a governor than as a presidential candidate.

&amp;gt;   individual's governing style

Again, not politics doesn't mean you are governing. Politicians in the legislature, and that's where most politicians are, don't really govern but mainly just vote. Being a good politician in the legislative branch is quite different than in the executive branch. A president is more like a CEO as the president basically runs a large organization (the federal government). The legislative branch is more about forming alliances with other politicians to pass/prevent laws. It's also more about forming public opinions, e.g. debates. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29622675304.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>I really don't think that he is as borderline as you might thing. 

People have been sounding the alarm that he is unfit for office from the get go. People from all walks of life and people who represent the entire political spectrum. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
