<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621291158.0" user="Pisoo" delta="False">
    <text>How do you determine what a mental illness is? For example, the APA considered homosexuality a disorder or disturbance until 1987. Does that mean gay people shouldn't be able to President?

How do you determine which mental disorders are relevant to the Presidency, or are all mental illness considered disqualifiers? 

What if the President develops a mental illness like depression during his/her lifetime?

How do you prevent the institution which decides *what* is a mental disorder and *which* are relevant from attempting to thwart Presidential elections if/when they politically disagree with a candidate? 

The problem with examinations is there's too much room for corruption and too many complexities. If the President is truly incompetent or dangerous, there are ways to remove a President (25th amendment). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621296578.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>That's definitely a fair point. It's very hard to qualify these factors and the only sort of solution I could think of would be to have congress assemble a team of psychologists to make those decisions, but as someone else said above that's a large grant of power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621340540.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>Not only is this a huge grant of power, but Congress is not an impartial player here. Depending on who controls Congress they could get psychologists that shoot down the best candidates for the other party. Plus, what happens if they just decide to not pass any candidate from the other party? It seems like a super easy way to game the system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621415707.0" user="johnny_moronic" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, an opposing party could really abuse it. For example, what if a capable and qualified candidate had slight OCD issues. Minor, but potentially disqualifying. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621513320.0" user="Caddan" delta="False">
    <text>The simple solution there is that there would be a single team of psychologists, and both major parties would be allowed to contribute equal amounts to it.  Say, 3 from GOP and 3 from DNC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621542245.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>
Then you might as well not have them at all. Neither party is going to pick a psychologist that would disqualify their candidate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621557846.0" user="Caddan" delta="False">
    <text>That depends on when the evaluations take place.  I'm sure even GOP-picked psychologists would have disqualified Trump from even being a candidate, much less being able to run against the other GOP contenders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621646658.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>Except plenty of people actually like trump. Beyond that they would've almost certainly found Clinton unfit and she is actually fit to be president. Besides, it's the people who make the final decision on who is fit by their vote. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621709422.0" user="Caddan" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not denying any of that.  I'm just pointing out that a GOP-picked psychologist could easily disqualify a GOP candidate.  Likewise, a DNC-picked psychologist could easily disqualify a DNC candidate.  That goes counter to your comment of "Neither party is going to pick a psychologist that would disqualify their candidate."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621733076.0" user="sharkbait76" delta="False">
    <text>Just because they can doesn't mean they will. A GOP psychologist could disqualify a GOP candidate, but realistically the chances are near zero. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29625872049.0" user="rocksalamander" delta="False">
    <text>If that was a viable option, then the Supreme Court would not have a political leaning, but I think we can objectively agree that's not the case (unfortunately).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
