<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621690241.0" user="TBFProgrammer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Perhaps not, but you haven't shown why it is useful. If we were to admit every limitation that wasn't, of its own accord, unreasonable, the burden of meeting all those limitations would be unreasonable. As such, a limitation needs to stand out as providing something of great importance to merit being put in place.

&amp;gt; the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record.

You obviously have very little background regarding psychology if you think this would catch *anything* beyond a dementia so severe none could fail to note it during the debates. Most of the elements on which mental health is evaluated are proffered by the person being evaluated. Someone with the resources necessary to mount a successful presidential campaign is going to be well versed in hiding anything that would betray a personality disorder before the psychologist gets a chance to speak with them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
