<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621280014.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er

Do you hold this criticism of all minority presidents? Can someone only be a good president if they belong to a majority group? Being a 1%er means that Trump belongs to the largest minority group in america complete with it's on set of persecutions (wealth envy/hatred from the masses being one of the biggest) I don't especially empathize with that position myself, but if a person belonging to a minority group is not a good qualifier because of their minority status then your argument basically states that someone has to belong to a majority group to be a good candidate.


&amp;gt;&amp;gt; I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Experience doesn't make someone good at something. It makes people less bad at something. All experience is, is the correlation of mistakes over time. So it's a slippery slope to assume that just because someone has political experience they are a *good* politician furthermore just because someone is a *good* politician does not equate to being a good or outstanding president. 

Talent, which is not teachable is the actual sign of excellence, but obviously you cannot build a system to foster talent only experience.

I'm not saying Trump is talented, he's actually pretty mediocre but political experience is a very arbitrary metric because it doesn't correlate to anything. All it actually means is that a politician was only actually good at keeping their job for a long time it says nothing about their ability to perform or run a country or even be of benefit to the people. Everything else that you conceivably use as a qualifier is something Trump is very experienced with. He's obviously got the capacity to move big money successfully, he knows the art of the deal and while grandiose he's good at business. He's also very intimate with taxation since his minority status grants him insight because he's got so much to lose from being taxed.

As for the mental stuff, obviously any person should be physically or mentally fit to rise to the task. However I would like to refocus your position to the fact that it is purely speculation and no medical professional has assessed Trump such that you should actually have to be worried about it yet, and doing so without confirmation is unscientific. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621287530.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I said nothing about "being in a minority group" being a bad qualifier, that's not what I meant at all. I meant that specifically being a 1%er in my opinion does not make him a man of the people, but the opposite. 

As for experience, I agree that it doesn't make someone better at the task, but I do believe that it can show governing style so we have an idea of what we're getting before we vote for it.

And as for mental competence, I'm not saying that because Trump might have a mental illness, but because I believe that it should be a prerequisite for *any* elected office, especially one so high as the presidency, mostly for transparency's sake.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621309208.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;I said nothing about "being in a minority group" being a bad qualifier, that's not what I meant at all. I meant that specifically being a 1%er in my opinion does not make him a man of the people, but the opposite.

Does being black/hispanic/latino/gay/trans/queer disqualify a person from being a man of the people in your view as well? If not, I hope you can see why it's ideologically inconsistent. A 1%er is a minority just like any other minority. It's just the one that everyone wants to be apart of.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;As for experience, I agree that it doesn't make someone better at the task, but I do believe that it can show governing style so we have an idea of what we're getting before we vote for it.


That is still a slippery slope just because someone is a good mayor senator or governor doesn't speak to anything about their presidency or their style while in office. It might loosely indicate *something* but not anything you could confirm scientifically/objectively.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;And as for mental competence, I'm not saying that because Trump might have a mental illness, but because I believe that it should be a prerequisite for any elected office, especially one so high as the presidency, mostly for transparency's sake.

I mean I don't particularly disagree with you in principle but I will say this. If you want the best pool of candidates you cannot add a bunch of conditionals to the position.

To have a shot at being president as it stands right now you have 2 major hard qualifiers and a bunch of soft qualifiers:

The Hard qualifiers:

1.) You have to live to be 35.

2.)You have to be born an American citizen on American soil.

The Soft:

1.)You probably have to be college educated at an ivy league school at this point in time to even be considered by the general public.

2.) You have to have the wealth or capacity to generate enough wealth to finance a campaign 

3.) People have to idiosyncratically like you.

4.)You have a major disadvantage if you're not white.


You can imagine that, there are probably less than 1,000 people who could take a presidency right now and probably a smaller amount of that 1,000 who would event want to take office in the first place. Adding the mental wellness thing only makes the pool even smaller. While they should be fit to take office, I don't think a perfectly clean mental state is necessarily a requirement.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621313659.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>Okay I definitely did not mean being a minority is a bad qualifier. I want to nip that in the bud right now. I *specifically* and *only* meant that, from an economic point of view, being in the top 1% disqualifies him from relating to the people that he claimed to represent during the campaign, even though many saw him as "one of us."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621376534.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Okay I definitely did not mean being a minority is a bad qualifier. I want to nip that in the bud right now. I specifically and only meant that, from an economic point of view, being in the top 1% disqualifies him from relating to the people that he claimed to represent during the campaign, even though many saw him as "one of us."


Being a 1%er makes him a member of a minority group you understand this right? What you're saying is that the thing that makes him different from the majority of people disqualifies him from being "one of us" either you must accept that his 1%er status  is irrelevant to him being "one of us" or you must extend that to all minority groups, because the metric by which you are qualifying this sentiment is the thing that sets him apart from the majority. If the thing that sets a person apart from being the majority makes it impossible for someone to be "one of us." whatever minority group they belong to shouldn't matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621380258.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I need to extend that opinion to all minority groups. Being an economic 1%er is decidedly not the same thing as being a racial minority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621388422.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>That's arbitrary and inconsistent.  The point you were attempting to make is that being a 1%er isolates Trump from the issues the lamen experiences and perhaps clouds his judgement. How could you not then extend this to other minority groups just because they aren't the 1%. Trans people for example represent .03 percent of the population. How could you possibly say the same thing about them without extending the same consideration to a 1%er? The two groups lead fundamentally different lives than the majority group of middle class straight white people. That's the crux of your position and you're ignoring it to save face.

What grants a person minority status is 100% irrelevant whatever about being a minority that isolates a person from being "one of us"  is intrinsic to being a minority not to what qualifies you as a minority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621392983.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying it's objectively wrong for me to say that someone whose always been a multimillionaire can claim to be representative of someone working for 10-20k a year?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621398018.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Can someone who's got gender dysphoria and has transitioned and dealt with trans based oppression be representative of someone who's been cishet and white their entire life?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621406919.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking strictly about economic factors. If those people are both in the 99%, then yes, in this context. If we're talking about the social factors of being an oppressed trans person versus being a cis white person, then no, an oppressed person does not represent the same social standing of someone who is not oppressed, because the cis male has never had to deal with the same hardships.

I'm talking economic context, and you're twisting my words into a strawman argument about me being bigoted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621443813.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>It seems you are getting hung up on the wrong part of the argument.  Economic factors has nothing to do with it  and restating as much doesn't actually change your position. I am going to restate your argument so you can understand where you went wrong.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. 

You are saying here that because trump is a 1%er he cannot be "one of us"

I then went on to produce the fact, that being a 1%er is a minority status. He is a member of the 1% of the population with the most money. Thus the fact that he belongs to a minority group means he can't possibly understand the plight of a typical American. I also attempted to establish that what you are saying must then apply to all minority groups.

In effect your argument summed up:

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;If a person is a 1%er how can they be expected to be able to relate to the majority group in our country they do not experience the same financial hardships as the laymen they are not "one of us."

In effect my argument summed up:

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;If a person is Trans how can they be expected to be able to relate to the majority group in our country they have only ever been oppressed and do not experience the same life experience is the laymen they are not "one of us"

What I am trying to establish here is that your argument nessecerily presupposes that a person cannot be "one of us" and also belong to any minority group. The fact that Trump is a 1%er minority does not have any bearing on the idea that a minority is not a good fit to be president your argument requires that anyone who cannot understand the plight of the majority laymen cannot be a good president since minority groups generally do not include the majority or the laymen then any minority president cannot represent the majority group. The minority they happen to belong to is irrelevant because according to your argument being a 1%er (a minority) sets someone apart from the people so much they aren't a good candidate. While the minority status is granted by economic factors, it's the minority status and not how they got there that is the issue.


&amp;gt;&amp;gt;I'm talking economic context, and you're twisting my words into a strawman argument about me being bigoted

It's not a strawman. It's a major hole in your argument. You are not being ideologically consistent you are making a special exception to one minority group because it's one you probably dislike. You are saying that a minority that isn't a 1%er  can relate to the layman when your view says they actually can't because of what sets them apart from the majority. You are making special rules for 1%ers because it suits your argument. As far as you being bigoted, it was never my intention to make you feel that way. Frankly I don't care if you are or are not bigoted either way. I am here to have a discussion, and change your view, and your position is inconsistent and the best way to demonstrate that is by showing you that you either must consider all minority groups to be bad leaders because their experience is nessecerily different or we can have minority leaders even 1%ers.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621455117.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you're saying, I just don't believe that he can *claim* to represent the middle or lower class in the same way that I don't believe Bernie Sanders (~300k salary) could *claim* to represent the upper class. I didn't mean to bring social issues into it, I think the economic context of leadership *is* very separate from the social context. I apologize for not articulating that well and losing my cool a little bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621471691.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Bernie Sanders (~300k salary) could claim to represent the upper class.

The 1%er status only requires 150k combined home income annually. Bernie is a 1%er without adding in the income of his wife.

What makes you think (assuming you support him) Bernie is somehow more capable of understanding the plight of the laymen than Trump. In terms of relativity they both lead the same lifestyle compared to joe schmoe. No Bernie can't afford 10 private jets and a superyacht  but he will never have to worry about a mortgage or putting food on the table. He certainly does not have the same monetary concerns as the average american. I personally don't see a point in comparing pocketbook sizes, they both live a different experience than I do. Which means their understanding of my life or the life of the laymen is relatively the same in terms of leadership.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621477709.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't saying that because I support Bernie, that was a bad example. I'm just trying to say that having those private jets and that kind of economic privilege, to me, means that Trump can't claim to understand or empathize with someone who's had to live on food stamps or cut coupons, or pay a mortgage on a house in the suburbs. I certainly wouldn't claim to know how a billionaire lives on my hourly wage, and if I did it would clearly be a farce.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621491458.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Again though, those things are all arbitrary. The point of your argument is that

"They are too different to be one of us."

Most politicians are too different to be "one of us." Specifically for economic reasons. You are holding Trump to an unfair standard simply because he has a few extra 0s in a long list of 0s.

Let me reframe it one step further.

Trump is worth 7 billion. Jeff Bezos (owner of amazon) is worth 90 billion.

Do you think Bezos is more privileged than Trump or do you think that after a certain point another digit in your pocket book doesn't matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621472513.0" user="alnicoblue" delta="False">
    <text>Really though, why does any of this matter?

Relating this to the topic of your CMV, I don't see how you *need* to relate to someone to represent them. You need basic human empathy, a good education and a deep understanding of social issues.

Trump's problems don't stem from his money or political experience, they stem from him being an egomaniac. He completely dismisses opposition and is hostile to anyone who doesn't share his worldview or platform. I don't know the man but he just strikes as a *bad person*. 

Using Trump or any other poor leader to set strict guidelines for future presidents is throwing the baby out with the bath water. You can be wealthy and still fight for the lower class and you can have human empathy for people in life situations you can't necessarily relate to.

In addition, adding a political experience prerequisite to the presidency further constricts the people's ability to choose. You remove a big category of candidates and widen the perceived gap of representation between the voters and the candidates.

Part of why Trump was elected is because people have grown weary of career politicians. Do I agree with this? Not at all. I'm okay with career politicians. But people on both sides want something different and I don't feel that they should have that choice taken away because of one bad president. 

And as others have pointed out-your mental health requirement opens the door for the parties to filter out candidates they don't like in addition to the fact that mental health as a science changes with research and new treatments making a concrete rule almost predestined to be rendered insufficient over time.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29625885662.0" user="rocksalamander" delta="False">
    <text>No, he's actually not, nor do I think he's saying you're bigoted- it's as simple as saying this:
1) you believe the President should be a man of the people 
2)you believe that having "x" trait which is only held by 1% of the population means he cannot relate to a preponderance of the population 
3) if he cannot relate to the vast majority of the population, he is by definition, not a man of the people.

X could be anything, if it means a difference in relatable culture- wealth, race, and other factors all fit this bill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621412441.0" user="luludog98" delta="False">
    <text>A person who is black, but was raised middle class and in public education, still has more in common with the "average american" than someone like Trump. A person who is trans, but worked two jobs in college and still came out with debt, has more in common with the collective American "us" than Trump. 

If I understand OP correctly, simply belonging to a minority group of any name does not preclude you from the presidency, being wholly and demonstrably out of touch with the very people you claim to be fighting for precludes you from the presidency.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
