<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621284863.0" user="chocolateAltoids" delta="False">
    <text>Before I begin, Mental Health is a serious issue, and people should not be ashamed or looked down upon for seeking professional help with whatever their personal issues may be.

I'm going to ignore the bits about Trump. Mainly because if this precedent is set for a presidential candidate, it'll affect those way beyond just Trump.

So my issue with anytime Mental Health exams are brought up for anything (presidential candidate, gun ownership, drivers license, etc.) is that we, as humans, know so little on the exact causes of mental health issues. Psychology only takes us so far, and there are some things that are subjective on diagnosis depending on the Psychologist / Other Medical Professionals.

Even if there is an issue with mental health that is generally agreed upon, where do we draw the line for 'fit' or 'unfit' for office? What happens when the American Psychology Association chooses to change diagnostic standards for certain mental health issues and something we, as a society, defined as 'fit' becomes part of an 'unfit' category.

If we understood the mind and mental disorders, than yes, we should do this. However, do to our full lack of understanding of how the mind and these disorders work, we can't justify their correctness 100% of the time.

--------------------------------

On a completely different note, I think we should just get rid of the idea of presidents and go with another sort of house/senate for the executive branch. How'd that work, I don't know, but quoting you OP:

&amp;gt; The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization.

I feel like for anyone, even the most perfect candidate, that is too much power for just one person now and days. But then again I'm just some guy on the internet rambling :P</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
