<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="414669111.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6uvsqf/cmv_the_presidency_us_should_require_the/">
    <title>CMV: The Presidency (US) should require the prerequisites of a history in any elected office and a mental health examination.</title>
    <original_poster>asheddrva</original_poster>
    <original_post>The presidency is the most symbolic, if not the most powerful, position in the United States, and arguably one of the most in western civilization. Although the idea of "anyone can be president" is charming, such an important position, I believe, should carry with it a good resume and security of sound mind. For example, Donald Trump was seen as a "man of the people" during his campaign due to his lack of political background, but that did not change the fact that he is a lifelong 1%er. I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

Additionally, although there may be nothing to the rumors/speculations of dementia, BPD, or narcissistic personality disorder, the public has no way of being secure in the idea that our leader is mentally sound without a simple mental health examination available for public record. After all, the president serves the people, and it's time to say the people need to know what they're getting into.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29621263820.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think it's unreasonable to require some kind of history of elected office to file for candidacy-- whether that be a governorship, a seat in congress, or just a local or state representative seat.

How does this help?  Lets say Trump was elected local councillor in some tiny town in the middle of no-where for a year.  How does this change anything?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621267734.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>It might not necessarily "help," but I would have found some slight security in knowing he had been elected before. Maybe the local representative path wouldn't be enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621269140.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>It also would present some small bit of history on his governing style.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621280073.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>People knew his history (his lack of experience, how he handles people in business, how he acted on the campaign, etc) so they knew how he worked.   Having an elected job would add nothing.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621299754.0" user="asheddrva" delta="False">
    <text>I think it would have been a good view into his style of governance. Running a business and running a district or country are not the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29621315878.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>The majority of what people object about could have been seen in his businesses (e.g. some of his companies went bankrupt).  It wouldn't have mattered since they would have still voted for him - if they didn't object to him saying "I don't even wait. And when you're a star, they let you do it, you can do anything ... grab them by the pussy" they aren't going to object to his voting record on recycling.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29625877241.0" user="rocksalamander" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree with the other poster that his governing style was easily observed by how he governed his business, part of his appeal to the voter base was specifically his supposed *lack* of political history. People (of all stripes, not just Rep.) were tired of career politicians.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
