<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29628172290.0" user="Spikewerks" delta="False">
    <text>Slavery, many hundreds of years ago, was normal and widely practiced. The 18th and 19th Century saw it abolished throughout the world, and from then on it was considered immoral and wrong. In history we do not look at figures from hundreds of years ago and say "they were wrong", we acknowledge that their actions today would have been wrong. What is more important to examine in historical figures is what they did, and what came about as a result of their actions.

And what these Confederate soldiers, for which statues were made, did was fight against the United States of America, and supported slavery (long past when many countries in the world had abolished slavery; the US was actually late to the abolitionist trend). These men were enemies of America, seeking to bring an end to a country that told them their practices were unlawful and immoral. And when they lost the war, a majority of them accepted the fate of the South: the CSA was no more, and slavery was abolished.

The current debate over Confederate monuments is not one of historical importance; that is why we have museums, libraries, and numerous works in media examining and documenting the events of the Civil War. There is no shortage of documentation of that period in history; to remove these statues is no loss to history. These statues were erected as a form of continued resistance to abolition, and a vast majority were raised in the 20th Century, in the midst of civil rights movements.

Statues are not always very important historical artifacts. Should Iraq have left their statues of Saddam Hussein standing? Saddam played a very significant role in Iraq's history, but his statue was removed because he was a despot. In Ukraine,[ 1,320 statues of Vladimir Lenin were removed](http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/lenin-statues-removed-soviet-union-russia-crimea-ukraine-bolshevik-communist-petro-poroshenko-a7903611.html); Lenin was undoubtedly a very important historical figure, yet to keep his statues standing would be a testament to something long dead.

The case is the same with these Confederate monuments: they honor a failed state that opposed America and supported slavery. They may have been built to honor historical figures, but today, they are monuments to oppression and hatred.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
