<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29627109366.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Let's just assume you're right about everything you've said. Slavery was not as big a deal then as now, yeah? We'll just assume that and move on.

Answer this for me:

**Why should we have monuments to traitors?**

Which countries have monuments up to traitors who tried to secede from the country and failed in their rebellion? When Velupillai Prabhakaran led the [LTTE](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberation_Tigers_of_Tamil_Eelam) in the Sri Lankan Civil War, his group (which was made to help the Tamil people secede from Sri Lanka) lost and Sri Lanka [built a monument at the place of his death honoring the people who killed him](http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/south-asia/Lanka-army-erects-monument-where-it-killed-Prabhakaran/articleshow/5654248.cms). This guy was popular among a certain section of the population, fought for their right to secede from the union, and he lost. He doesn't have any statues anywhere in the country because that would be ridiculous.

There aren't statues honoring traitors in most countries. Even [the Boot Monument](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boot_Monument) commemorating Benedict Arnold's service in the Revolutionary War does not actually name him so as not to honor him for being a traitor. There aren't statues to members of the IRA in Northern Ireland. The Basque separatist group ETA does not have any monuments in Spain.

We shouldn't have monuments honoring and commemorating the memory of people who tried to separate the United States of America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627155449.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why should we have monuments to traitors?

I don't consider them traitors any more than I consider Washington, Jefferson, Franklin, or Adams traitors. 

The Confederate states did not attempt to overthrow the US government. That would be treasonous. The Confederates States did not march an army into Kentucky, Indian, Illinois, Or Michican in an attempt to force them to join the Confederacy. The states "in rebellion" *withdrew* from the union, which was legally debatable at the time, and had been considered by other states before. Secession did not become illegal until after the war. 

Even so, the war was not popular in the northern states as many northerner felt the same way the southerns did...if the union wasn't representing them or their desires, they had the right to withdraw. Lincoln went to great efforts to squash opposition to the war, even going to so far as to illegally jail a congressman who opposed it.

Now, if southern representatives had remained in congress and attempted a coup in order to force the entirety of the US to accept their laws and their governance, you may have a point. But they didn't did they? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627204521.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't consider them traitors any more than I consider Washington, Jefferson, Franklin, or Adams traitors. 

But it doesn't matter what you consider them. They were traitors to the United States of America because they tried to secede from it. Washington et al tried to secede from Britain, so they were traitors to Britain, but we don't live in Britain.

&amp;gt;The Confederate states did not attempt to overthrow the US government.

Neither did any of the people that I mentioned, they simply wanted to withdraw from the governing state and secede.

&amp;gt;Even so, the war was not popular in the northern states as many northerner felt the same way the southerns did...if the union wasn't representing them or their desires, they had the right to withdraw.

Doesn't matter. Same was true for the IRA.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
