<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29628483786.0" user="SometmesWrongMotives" delta="False">
    <text>I feel it's a little weird to say "oh it was just different then" and be done with it.  I've gone with the flow when people around me were doing the same thing, and still known it was the wrong thing to do.

A quote from an unknown woman's journal from Nazi Germany: "My fingers are shaking as I write this. Everyone in now turning their backs on Adolf. No one was ever a supporter. Everyone was persecuted and no one denounced. What about me? I was there. I breathed what was in the air. It affected all of us." Does it really sound like she had no idea that people might be mad about what they were doing while she was "breathing the air"?  It's not the same as if she were the leader, sure, but to claim she didn't know?

People knew enough then to act differently, we've all heard the heroic stories about people who didn't just bow to it.

Sure, times are different sometimes, but the bystander effect is real.  It takes more to stand up against if you're a lone dissenter in Nazi Germany, say, but I think it's rare that people don't know how what they're doing affects other people, or that somehow "back then" people didn't know how to make excuses.  I've been reading the Old Testament of the Bible recently and I find it relate-able.  I don't think people have really changed that much.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
