<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626290731.0" user="Genoscythe_" delta="False">
    <text>Removing statues is not about rewriting history. We are not pretending to remove statues retroactively a hundred years ago, *we are removing them today*, for our own sake. 

It's one thing to say, that American slavers were respectable in their own time.*  But we are not them, we are living in our own time, in 2017, and WE are deciding that the people of 2017 do not want to continue putting slavers on literal pedestrals. If the peope of the past considered slavery an ambigous issue, that's their business, but WE don't. WE have a right to say that for us, slavery is a black and white issue, a monstrous crime, and that WE consider the ones who fought for it, to be monsters, and that WE don't want to venerate them in OUR public spaces. 

It's one thing to understand, that there once was a time when most people didn't share that morality, but we are not obliged to keep agreeing with them. 

Understanding that different eras have different moralities, swings both ways. We have to understand that the past's values were different from ours, but also that our values are different from the past, and not beholden to it.  

---
 *Although that's not really correct either. Chattel slavery always did have a fierce abolitionist opposition on a moral ground. John Brown didn't die for abstract "economic reasons", but for a virtous cause that he believed in. Preachers didn't say from the pulpit, that “The tree of Abolition is evil, and only evil—root and branch, flower and leaf, and fruit; that it springs from, and is nourished by an utter rejection of the Scriptures”, because of some detached, morally neutral economic reasons. Plenty of people in the 19th century have believed that slavery was a black and white issue, it's just that we are now more uniformly clear on which side was the black one and which side was the white.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626586627.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>But we are not them, we are living in our own time, in 2017, and WE are deciding that the people of 2017 do not want to continue putting slavers on literal pedestrals.

When was the last time someone commissioned a statue of a Confederate general?

Also, if that is then the case then why are we not removing the Jefferson Monument in DC? Why are we not blasting Washington's face from Mt Rushmore? These men were slavers and fought for their right to own their slaves during the revolutionary war as part of their war for independence (or did you miss the part of history where England banned slavery in the early 1700's and Great Britain right around the time of the revolution?)

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626611109.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>I found articles showing confederate statues going up in 2007: https://www.google.com/amp/s/amp.cnn.com/cnn/2017/08/18/us/new-confederate-monuments/index.html

The reason we're not taking down statues of Washington and Jefferson is because they're being celebrated for founding the country, not fighting for slavery. While slavery was illegal in England during the revolution, not because the brits banned it but because it was never made law, the abolition movement in the empire didn't start until 1783, after the 13 colonies considered themselves independent. Washington and Jefferson fought for independence from a government they weren't represented in, confederates fought first and foremost to preserve slavery. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626999808.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty of people are trying to rename school currently named after George washington, or Christopher Columbus, or thomas Jefferson, all because these people owned slaves or did things we now consider immoral. Many people seem to consider confederate statues just the first step in a purge of anything bad from the past. It is not just removing a few specific people who acrually.fought to uphold slavery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627012059.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a purge of history to rename a fucking school or aknowledge that we probably should not celebrate a Spanish moron who sparked a genocide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627347092.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>That is why I said it was the first step. Native Americans killed each other all the time, better get rid of those statues. The Greeks had slaves, better stop mentioning that they invented democracy. The Egyptians had slaves, better tear down those pyramids. The Romans commited untold atrocities in their 1500 years in power, and the NFL and watch makers have the gall to use their numbering system! 

The individual renaming may not be a purge, but when these people are calling for more and more to be renamed and removed so we don't ever think nice thoughts of anyone from the past who may have done bad things too, where does it end? America was founded on that genocide, shameful as it was. Are you giving up your house and money for a native American family? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627384904.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>It's like you don't understand anything about this issue at all.

Edit: Like going from, "we might not want to memorialize certain people due to their horrible actions" to, "youbhave to give up your house to native Americans!!!" is baffling to me.

Where does it end? Who knows, but we're not talking about purging or erasing history or even not feeling negatively about history. Fuck, this lets us have some god damn honest discussions about history! Can you imagine trying to critically examine the civil war in Robert E Lee High? Or talk about the atrocities committed by Columbus the Friday before you're off to celebrate a day dedicated to him?

We get to honestly look back at the humans who were a part of history and stop sucking their historical dicks for once and everyone is flipping the fuck out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627404869.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>I understand completely. Its like you think a mob is rational. 

The group that wants specific confederate military leaders removed makes sense. The group that is latching on to this and wants buildings renamed because George washington, one of the fathers of this country, owned slaves is ridiculous. And if your only criteria for renaming and removing and calling people from history "bad" is that they owned slaves, or did things we would call morally wrong now, you are going to need to remove just about everything. You seem to think that is insane, when it is already happening. 

Asking "where does it end" is perfectly logical when this is already happening. You pretending this can't or won't happen when *it is already happening* is not logical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627420830.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Who gives a fuck if a school is named after George Washington or not? What harm does it do to us as a society to see him for the flawed human person he was?

This has nothing to do with a mob, it has to do with us taking an honest look at our society and our history and being honest with ourselves. Owning slaves was a *bad thing to do*. I don't think that's a controversial statement.

Washington wasn't a perfect human. He was of his time, and he lived during a flawed time. Why should he be venerated without question? Why not debate the merits of naming things after him? I personally have no problem with things being named after him but it's a discussion worth having and considering.

I'm going to go out on a limb and say that you've never once attended a school named after a man who owned people that might have been your ancestors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628225087.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What harm does it do to us as a society to see him for the flawed human person he was?

it does none. i am all for learning a more complete version of some of these people's lives. in school. but to truly get in depth on the founding fathers is probably a college-level course by itself. you think that needs to be explained to everyone before they can see a school named after george washington? or does the fact that he was flawed(as our current view of morality/society indicates) preclude admiration? because that seems to be the main thrust of your arguments here. anyone who did something we now view as bad is not to be admired for any good thing they did.

&amp;gt;This has nothing to do with a mob, it has to do with us taking an honest look at our society and our history and being honest with ourselves. Owning slaves was a bad thing to do. I don't think that's a controversial statement.

you are demonstrating your bias here. your view is not at all controversial now, but it would probably get you killed or at least beat on in 1700s georgia. 

&amp;gt;Washington wasn't a perfect human. He was of his time, and he lived during a flawed time.

so here you admit that he is a product of a flawed(read- not present) time. so what is the point of judging him by our moral and social values? it is completely useless. again, i am not saying we should gloss over or ignore the "bad" things he did. but demonizing him for that makes no sense. why didn't the early european explorers use googlemaps? why did those settlers take so long to get to oregon? why didn't they just drive? why pan for gold by hand when machines would be so much faster? why did henry ford assemble his cars with people, robots are way better. these are meaningless questions. if you want to consider his moral merit, judge him on the morals of his time, not ours. i don't understand why this is such a difficult issue.

&amp;gt;I'm going to go out on a limb and say that you've never once attended a school named after a man who owned people that might have been your ancestors

i have not. so what? my ancestors came here from holland and germany in the 1880-1890 range. no one in my family owned slaves, nor have they been owned. 

from your edit:

&amp;gt;Like going from, "we might not want to memorialize certain people due to their horrible actions"

i agree to some extent with this. there are certainly sole pretty vile southerners that get statues that don't deserve it based on anyone's version of good/morality. i have no problem with yale renaming calhoun college, as calhoun was kind of a piece of shit.

[lee](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_E._Lee) was not.  i absolutely think people should learn about him and what he did before and after the war. i think he was loyal to a fault, and it was his bad luck to be loyal to a southern state when the war started. i am no expert on lee, but "Lee rejected the proposal of a sustained insurgency against the Union and called for reconciliation between the two sides." he seems to have been more of the military guy doing his job, until his job was done. i can see why people have a problem with him, but i can also see why virginians especially would look up to him for reasons other than fighting for slavery.

&amp;gt;Where does it end? 

this is what is worrying most rational people. the discussion is not "we should rename/remove because these people were objectively terrible and the statues were only added in the 1960s." no, these people are using owning slaves as the sole criteria for name changes. and that is lunacy. like people 100 years in the future renaming obama library because obama drove fossil fuel powered cars and had a huge carbon footprint. [this](https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/9kkkby/lets-get-rid-of-mount-rushmore) is kind of a click-bait article, but it is at least partly serious.

&amp;gt;Fuck, this lets us have some god damn honest discussions about history!

i would love an honest discussion about history. i think most people's knowledge of even general history is abhorrent, and i am not much better. but i'm curious what that has to do with buildings being named after famous people. should the building have a 500 page book attached to "contextualize" washington, or columbus, or roosevelt, or alexander the great, or whomever? 

&amp;gt;Can you imagine trying to critically examine the civil war in Robert E Lee High?

who is critically examining anything in high school? and why would the name of the building impact that? lee is dead, has been for quite a while.

&amp;gt;Or talk about the atrocities committed by Columbus the Friday before you're off to celebrate a day dedicated to him?

yeah, columbus was pretty terrible. but he never came to what would be the united states, the reason for columbus day is pretty lame. but that was more than 500 years ago. if everyone in the world is going to hold grudges about stuff that happened 500 years ago, the world would be much shittier than it is now.

you say there is no slippery slope, that we are not going to erase anything. i want to believe you, but if already you have people wanting to get rid of mentioning jefferson and washington because slavery, how long before more things that are "hurtful" to talk about get banned as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628335976.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it does none. i am all for learning a more complete version of some of these people's lives. in school. but to truly get in depth on the founding fathers is probably a college-level course by itself. you think that needs to be explained to everyone before they can see a school named after george washington? or does the fact that he was flawed(as our current view of morality/society indicates) preclude admiration? because that seems to be the main thrust of your arguments here. anyone who did something we now view as bad is not to be admired for any good thing they did.

Who said it precluded admiration? Just that perhaps we can discuss a monument. There might be a good reason to change the name of a school, but keep the Washington monument. There is room for discussion and nuance.

&amp;gt; you are demonstrating your bias here. your view is not at all controversial now, but it would probably get you killed or at least beat on in 1700s georgia.


Yes, I am biased against slave owners.

But so were a lot of people in the 1700's - they were called abolitionists.

&amp;gt; so here you admit that he is a product of a flawed(read- not present) time. so what is the point of judging him by our moral and social values? it is completely useless. again, i am not saying we should gloss over or ignore the "bad" things he did. but demonizing him for that makes no sense. why didn't the early european explorers use googlemaps? why did those settlers take so long to get to oregon? why didn't they just drive? why pan for gold by hand when machines would be so much faster? why did henry ford assemble his cars with people, robots are way better. these are meaningless questions. if you want to consider his moral merit, judge him on the morals of his time, not ours. i don't understand why this is such a difficult issue.

"Slavery is bad" is not such a modern ideal that it is akin to using google maps. But hey, maybe he willed freedom for his slaves after his death because he personally thought it was an amazing institution. Slavery in America was about treating *human beings* as property.

It's fine for us to look back and go, "hmm this historical figure owned slaves. Owning slaves was not a cool thing to do, even if it was accepted at the time."

&amp;gt; i have not. so what? my ancestors came here from holland and germany in the 1880-1890 range. no one in my family owned slaves, nor have they been owned.

The point is many children *do* go to such a school. Try and see things from their perspective.

Not everyone gets to look back on the foundation of the country with reverence. And I'd say that the people enshrined in the constitution as only being worth 3/5ths a white person have that right. The revolution wasn't exactly a positive thing for slaves, and they had no choice to come here.

&amp;gt; lee was not. i absolutely think people should learn about him and what he did before and after the war. i think he was loyal to a fault, and it was his bad luck to be loyal to a southern state when the war started. i am no expert on lee, but "Lee rejected the proposal of a sustained insurgency against the Union and called for reconciliation between the two sides." he seems to have been more of the military guy doing his job, until his job was done. i can see why people have a problem with him, but i can also see why virginians especially would look up to him for reasons other than fighting for slavery.

Lee was a white supremacist who fought to keep slavery. 

&amp;gt; this is what is worrying most rational people. the discussion is not "we should rename/remove because these people were objectively terrible and the statues were only added in the 1960s." no, these people are using owning slaves as the sole criteria for name changes. and that is lunacy. like people 100 years in the future renaming obama library because obama drove fossil fuel powered cars and had a huge carbon footprint. this is kind of a click-bait article, but it is at least partly serious.

Why is it lunacy? I already provided you with an argument for why maybe we don't name a high school after a slave owner.

Seriously, just imagine going to school every day and seeing the name of a man who kept people like you as property. Again, this isn't comparable to driving fossil fuel cars. Were talking about owning human beings.

&amp;gt; i would love an honest discussion about history. i think most people's knowledge of even general history is abhorrent, and i am not much better. but i'm curious what that has to do with buildings being named after famous people. should the building have a 500 page book attached to "contextualize" washington, or columbus, or roosevelt, or alexander the great, or whomever?

Sends a mixed message if you're learning about the civil war in a school named after a confederate general, or its president.

&amp;gt; who is critically examining anything in high school? and why would the name of the building impact that? lee is dead, has been for quite a while.

You should be critically examining everything in high school.

&amp;gt; yeah, columbus was pretty terrible. but he never came to what would be the united states, the reason for columbus day is pretty lame. but that was more than 500 years ago. if everyone in the world is going to hold grudges about stuff that happened 500 years ago, the world would be much shittier than it is now.

It's not a grudge, it's a desire to stop celebrating the man.

&amp;gt; you say there is no slippery slope, that we are not going to erase anything. i want to believe you, but if already you have people wanting to get rid of mentioning jefferson and washington because slavery, how long before more things that are "hurtful" to talk about get banned as well?

Who is advocating we "get rid of mentioning jefferson and washington"? Because renaming a school is not doing this. But heck, who is calling to rename a school?

Your argument for why there *is* a slippery slope is very uncompelling.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628491453.0" user="descuidadojose" delta="False">
    <text>The sole reason for the existence of the Confederacy was the issue of abolition. If they had seceded for another reason we wouldn't treat them the same way. George Washington and Thomas Jefferson were flawed individuals but they are celebrated because they fought for representative government, a value that lead to abolition/civil rights, even if they didn't practice that value perfectly. The southern generals fought the US government because they wanted to be able to own slaves. If slavery hadn't been on the table that civil war would never have happened. The fact of the matter is, Some people might want to take down GW and TJ's statues. Maybe we should. But right now the vast majority of Americans as well as the communities of people around statues and monuments to GW and TJ are ok with it. A majority of people in the south who live around Confederate statues want them taken down. No one is saying we shouldn't learn about the good or the bad parts of history. We're saying that there are appropriate places for every part of history. These statues belong in museums or collectors homes, not in public. they are traitors and racists. The government should not have PUBLIC statues to honor a cause that was objectively evil. Thats why its different than Washington. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627012798.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>Cite a source for any notable movement trying to rename things named after Jefferson or Washington, you won't find any. Columbus is a different matter entirely, even by the standards of his day he was extremely brutal, there are primary sources discussing how awful he was.

And the slippery slope argument is a fallacy. Just because people think removing statues of people who fought for slavery is just the first step, doesn't mean it is. No it is just about removing people who fought explicitly for slavery.

You also ignore the fact that none of these statues were put up by the confederacy, they were put up after the war during Jim Crow and the civil rights movement to show support for the ideals of the confederacy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628497671.0" user="UnicornSexCowboy" delta="False">
    <text>I used to think that the focus of this war was slavery, however most of the historical data does not support this. This video had some interesting points https://youtu.be/RPOnL-PZeCc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29629114051.0" user="Se7enineteen" delta="False">
    <text>Most historians do not agree with you and posting a youtube video isn't really going to change anyone's mind.

https://www.reddit.com/r/AskHistorians/comments/352b2e/was_the_civil_war_about_states_rights_or_slavery/

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29629179495.0" user="UnicornSexCowboy" delta="False">
    <text>There doesn't seem to to be much consensus on that reddit. They seems to push most of the arguments of the Pragar video that were debunked. I only posted that video because it contains a lot of information that I had not heard of. I am descended from those that fought for the north, but a student of history. There appears to be a narrative lately to rewrite what happened. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626633515.0" user="karnim" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When was the last time someone commissioned a statue of a Confederate general?

Mostly the '40s, but this is an ongoing thing. Georgia just started selling license plates for the Sons of Confederate Veterans in 2014.

Oh, and Iowa put up 3 confederate monuments from 2005-2007, including one of some generals. And missouri put up a statue in 2009.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626786023.0" user="ThatSpencerGuy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also, if that is then the case then why are we not removing the Jefferson Monument in DC? Why are we not blasting Washington's face from Mt Rushmore? These men were slavers and fought for their right to own their slaves during the revolutionary war as part of their war for independence (or did you miss the part of history where England banned slavery in the early 1700's and Great Britain right around the time of the revolution?)

Because, at least right now, they are primarily remembered for other contributions to the country. A day might come when that changes, and then we may change or remove those kinds of monuments. You say in your title that we should not apply the morality of today onto the past... but what about the other direction?
Why should we be saddled with the morality of past people who erected statues that don't represent contemporary morality?

Remember, statuary are not primarily about the specific individuals they depict. They are about the ideas that those individuals have come to represent. 

We don't build statues for *them*; we build them for *us*. And when these public works have no more use for people currently living--or worse, when they have a use that goes against our values--we should feel comfortable putting them in storage. 

There will always be books and classes about these people and events. Public monuments are a different thing entirely. They are aspirational and political by their nature, and as the things to which we aspire change, so can our public works. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626972687.0" user="groman32" delta="False">
    <text>Pro tip: before you ask a rhetorical question of CMV, Google it, because if you don't we will. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628141926.0" user="leonprimrose" delta="False">
    <text>When do you think that statue was erected?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
