<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626297465.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues confederate generals but even of supreme court justices, and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.

Can you articulate how the removal of Taney's statue removes our ability to have debates about history? As far as I know nobody who advocated the removal of the statue has said, "and don't teach about the Dredd Scott decision either!" Nor have they made any attempts to stifle discussion about the case, Taney himself, or the ramifications of his decisions made on the bench.

This goes for all of the statues being removed. They're not a way to debate or even contextualize history, they're a way to memorialize and venerate it. And I'm not sure why we should memorialize people who fought to keep an institution like slavery even if a good number of people of the day were just fine with that "perculiar institution" (this also ignores the many who were abolitionists).

Edit: Honestly, the people I see playing fast and loose with history are those who want to keep the statues up and perpetuate the "lost cause" narrative of the civil war. Nobody who wants to remove these monuments wants to forget history, quite the contrary. They want our history to be acknowledged so that we never do it again.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
