<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626440378.0" user="goroboldo" delta="False">
    <text>For as long as there has been slavery, there have been people *against* it as well. You erase *them* from history when you act as though 100% of people back then were fine with it, that it's *only* our modern moral mind that's able to see the evil. That's completely wrong. Maybe, just maybe, we're acknowledging that those people who were a minority at the time were *right*, and *they* should have statues put up in their name.

And yet, for all their interest in history, the groups who put up those monuments all over the Confederacy had an extremely narrow view of who mattered. I've seen no monuments to Nat Turner, for instance, or Harriet Tubman, or Frederick Douglass that were erected by "The Daughters of the Confederacy", who was one of the primary group sponsoring all these ones of Confederate soldiers and generals. Speaking of Generals, there are few Civl War figures who had a bigger impact on the Confederacy than William Tecumseh Sherman, but there are to my knowledge exactly zero statues of him south of the Mason-Dixon line. These self-proclaimed history buffs, in fact, show no interest at all in Union generals or Union soldiers, anti-slavery figures, or slaves themselves, in any way shape or form. It's as though the "history" they're presenting is extremely one-sided and telling only a tiny, tiny piece of the story that valorizes the wrong people.

What happened here is that history was erased and sanitized *when these statues were put up in the first place*. They were a propaganda campaign to whitewash the Confederacy and the war, and a wildly successful one. People downplay the role of slavery with a straight face, and talk about "States Rights" without having a clue what the Fugitive Slave Acts were. They're mad that a statue of a slaver comes down, but would be even more enraged if the statues were modified to, say, put a whip in the slaver's hand. Either their historical interest isn't sincere, or they really haven't thought it out beyond, "This will make a good retort to throw at liberals."

tldr: What's happening isn't a re-writing of history, but an un-re-writing of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626472838.0" user="belgarionria" delta="False">
    <text>Minorities didn't "exist" before the internet because they had no platform to speak on. The average person barely had news, once or twice a year, about the current ruler. Forget having news about the neighboring village or the conditon of x% of the population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626665191.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Lol what? Minorities didn't exist before the internet? Are you saying Martin Luther King had the internet, or that he didn't talk about minorities? 

Also, did not know that newspapers were only delivered once or twice a year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627368879.0" user="belgarionria" delta="False">
    <text>Im talking about 10,000BC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627393521.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Ok then - not what first leaps to mind when I think of the pre-internet age but technically correct. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627679975.0" user="belgarionria" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe I expressed myself wrong. I meant pre long range communication and global litteracy. :p</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626792852.0" user="groman32" delta="False">
    <text>We're not talking about the middle ages here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627367328.0" user="belgarionria" delta="False">
    <text>You're right. We're talking about 9000 years before the middle ages. Thats when slavery started.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626659765.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;For as long as there has been slavery, there have been people against it as well.

I don't disagree, however not everyone opposed to slavery did so on purely moral grounds. much of the opposition to slavery in northern states stemmed from other minority groups competing for jobs, and some states banned slavery for the racist intention of keeping "negros" out of their state. 

&amp;gt;I've seen no monuments to Nat Turner, for instance, or Harriet Tubman, or Frederick Douglass that were erected by "The Daughters of the Confederacy", who was one of the primary group sponsoring all these ones of Confederate soldiers and generals.

That is not to say monuments to [great leaders of the freedom](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harriet_Tubman_Memorial_(New_York_City) and [civil rights movements of the day](http://archives.chicagotribune.com/1899/05/29/page/10/article/frederick-douglass-statue-in-rochester-it-will-be-unveiled-on-june-9) do not exist. Harriet Tubman has entire national park named after her. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626780819.0" user="groman32" delta="False">
    <text>1. There being some non moral objections doesn't refute my point about the moral ones. 

2. Were those monuments erected by the DotC or the other groups who put up the bulk of Confederate one? No? My point stands.  Those Confederate statues weren't put up to mark history, they were propaganda for white supremacy during Jim Crow  and then later reactions against civil rights pushes. Their "but history!" refrain is revealed to be facile at best by the carefully curated subject matter of their monuments.         </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
