<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29627166437.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Sometimes I look at a view and I think "I don't think this is really about what the person says it's about."  This is not at all to accuse the person of duplicity or deception or obfuscation, but rather because I start to wonder if the rhetoric around the issue is getting mucked up with the central part of the view.

So let me just ask straight out: do you REALLY care so much about historical complexity and nuance?  Or is this statue thing really about something else for you, centrally?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627718598.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>It's not just a "statue" thing. I have contemplated the role of confederacy in our history and in trying to understand that history, as a southerner, I have come to conclusions that obvious run counter to the "flavor of they day". I believe this is precisely because I have studied the period, not as a historian, just as a citizen looking to gain more knowledge, and in that study I have found that the period is FULL of nuance that either just isn't taught or talked about, or flatly rejected. It all seems to circle back to taking a moral position on the history of time and using our morality of the day to paint a picture from 150 years ago.

I had the unique opportunity of have a father who was 50 years old when I was born, and a grandfather born before the turn of the 20th century whom I never knew because he passed away in 1960 at the ripe old age of 80 something. My dad grew up in a time when racism was commonly accepted. Blacks and white didn't mix and segregation was the law of the land. He was a racist, but not a bad person. I grew up in the 80's, in a very desegregated society, with black playmates when I was a child and black friends all through out my life. My morals were different from his, but his would have likely been different had he grown up when I did. This lead me to consider how morality has changed over the years and how we apply that to our study of history. Simply calling confederates traitors and removing statues that honor war heroes in the south, or even worse, memorials to the soldiers who fought (like in Durham), does a great disservice to understanding the nuance of the history of our nation and that tumultuous period of time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628239169.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>But the statues stand TODAY.  Why shouldn't we apply today's morals to things we can see out our window right now?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
