<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626268911.0" user="LiableMucky" delta="False">
    <text>You're incorrectly conflating taking down statues with a desire to rewrite history. Keep in mind that the extreme far left views you see in media outlets are just that, the extreme views. They are the radical 1% of the left, much like the Nazis are the radical 1% of the right, not representative of all the right. The majority of people who express concerns about these monuments are not saying 'Let's pretend this never happened to solve a problem', the problem they see is that these are statues that a. touch on the roots of contemporary, very real problems and b. are in very prominent places.

The reason nobody cares/would care about statues of dueling is because it's no longer a socially relevant issue. It's not a controversial part of life that splits the States significantly. Or statues about the laws of consent, that's not exactly controversial any more, if someone says "I want to fuck a 7 year old" that doesn't exactly get a varied outcry, everyone agrees that's wrong.

Slavery (and the confederate flag) are, at their core, fundamentally race-oriented issues. Those issues are 100% still relevant today. KKK membership is on the rise, Charlottesville happened. Whatever your stance on this, one thing is irrefutable: the issues pertaining to the statues in question are ones that are still absolutely socially relevant.

Which leads me to my main argument, having established that. The problem with these statues is that they represent to minorities and persecuted groups a lack of remorse by their nation for its past. Were it the case that the civil rights movement had happened, race relations eased completely, and racism was no longer prevalent in the USA, nobody would care about or be angry about these statues of slave owners. They would be like the previously mentioned hypothetical monuments to dueling, because they wouldn't be relevant. However, POC perceive these monuments as a homage to a system of oppression that is *still in place*. The fact that they are in public spaces such as Universities, is not a reminder of the horrors of the past as much as it is a reminder that things haven't changed as much as we might hope. The anger at these statues is not at all an attempt to rewrite history or hold it hostage to contemporary morality, but rather to recognise that the statues in question are roots of social problems manifesting today. When a black student sees a statue on a daily basis commemorating a southern slave-trader, an individual who implanted the idea that black people are inherently less worthy and even sub-human (for personal profit), and then also sees the current, real-term manifestation of those ideas in the form of reemerging white supremacy, I think that anger is justified.

I agree with you. We shouldn't attempt to superimpose contemporary morals onto historical time periods. I personally happen to believe the statues should probably be left, or perhaps moved to a museum. But the visceral reaction against the protest has shown an unwillingness to listen to the complaints of ethnic minorities. This has never been about the past as much as it is the present. And thus toppling these statues are not a protest to the past, they are a protest to the present. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
