<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626242957.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Unlike dueling and age of consent, more than half of America thought slavery was immoral, backwards and shameful from the get go. Even among slave owners, slave traders and slave drivers were considered morally tainted and were avoided by polite society. The morality of slavery in America was never a majority opinion.

Also, while other societies kept slaves, American and European whites were the only people's to institute a system of chattel slavery based on racial superiority.
Previous forms of slavery were based on the necessities of war. Many societies do not have a military penal system to process prisoners of war, so when the enemy surrenders in large numbers they can either kill them all or enslave them. They do not enslave them because they believe they are racially inferior. They still retain some rights, such as the right to some property. Often they are paid a pittance, and allowed to eventually buy their freedom. And they are not bred like animals to produce more slaves. 

Chattel slavery is much more vicious. Unlike other systems, it is practiced not for reasons of military expediency, but for profit. Unlike other systems, the slaves are bred, and their offspring are born slaves that do not belong to the mother but the master. Children were often, then, sold off to other plantations, splitting until families. Previous forms of slavery only enslaved individuals, but chattel slavery enslaved generations. It was the most brutal and inhuman system of slavery in history. It was considered immoral not only in its own day, but the practitioners of other earlier forms of slavery would have found it immoral too. So if we can not judge slavery by our own standards, surely we can at least judge it by the standards of its own day, and those standards were not favorable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626468304.0" user="belgarionria" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, you're justifying [11 000 years of slavery](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slavery#Early_history) because it concerns you less than the one in that happened in USA. Greece's slaves were treated exactly how you describe them in your second and third paragraph. Slave from birth to death, while having children, whom were also born slaves, and slaved their entire lives. The 'pay' you speak of was so small, that it was passed down from generation to generation, hoping that 10 generations from then, it'll buy the freedom of one slave. The only reason for that pay was to remove the incentive to run away. When runaways did happen, they were put into mental hospitals because 'running away' must be a mental sickness.

Millions upon millions of people were enslaved throughout history. You can't put a generalization on it and say "my slavery is harder than your slavery"...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626541803.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Saying American Slavery is worse than Greek slavery does not "justify" Greek slavery. Both are bad. The Holocaust was worse for Jews than it was for homosexuals - this does not mean I am justifying the murder of homosexuals.

Also, are you saying Ancient Greek slavery should concern more more than American slavery? Or just it should concern me equally? I totally reject this kind of moral relativism. Not only was American slavery far worse, it was perpetrated by *my country* and *my ancestors*, and we are still today living in the ruinous shadows of its 260 year legacy of torture and rape.

It was much more common to free ancient slaves, because they were mostly household slaves, and it was not especially profitibale to keep them, and the slave owner did not necessarily think he was superior to the slave, just that the slave was unluckier. The Roman government had to put a cap on the amount of slaves that someone could free in a year, as it was effecting their economy. They also were not bred like animals. This meant slavery rarely lasted for generations. Also, most slave children were the children of the slave owner and were not treated as slaves (nor were they treated as ordinary citizens). This is all of course repugnant but not as repugnant as American slavery which is worse *in every respect*. Also: what sort of mental hospitals do you imagine the ancient Greeks had?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626597244.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>I don't even know where to begin with the grossly inaccurate history you've in your post but suffice it to say that it doesn't even come to my mind, and in fact probably reinforces my idea that historical education is severely lacking in today's society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626783762.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>And how exactly do statues of confederate generals help people learn the history of chattel slavery in the United States?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29626976035.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Great rebuttal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627047634.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627674564.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; more than half of America thought slavery was immoral, backwards and shameful from the get go. 

Citation? From what I have read many northern states banned slavery not because it was the "moral" thing to do (although some did) but rather from the desire to A) prevent black people from moving or living there, which they felt would be unavoidable if they allowed slavery as with slavery there would eventually come free blacks or B) prevent competition from slave labor. I think saying that half the country thought slavery was immoral is a gross generalization of the history of the time based more on interpretation over the years than facts of the time period. People seem to forget that slavery was legal in states like NY, PA, NJ, RI, DE, MD, and MA, well into the 19th century, and in some cases even during the war itself. 

&amp;gt;Also, while other societies kept slaves, American and European whites were the only people's to institute a system of chattel slavery based on racial superiority. Previous forms of slavery were based on the necessities of war. Many societies do not have a military penal system to process prisoners of war, so when the enemy surrenders in large numbers they can either kill them all or enslave them. They do not enslave them because they believe they are racially inferior. They still retain some rights, such as the right to some property. Often they are paid a pittance, and allowed to eventually buy their freedom. And they are not bred like animals to produce more slaves.

Seriously? Someone should tell all the slaves in South America, The Caribbean, and Africa how good they really had it compared to slaves in the southern US.

&amp;gt;Chattel slavery is much more vicious. Unlike other systems, it is practiced not for reasons of military expediency, but for profit.

Most all slavery through out history has been for profit. Slaves have always had monetary value. This is just ignorance of slavery as an institution in other civilizations and a rationalization to support a poor knowledge of history from which to argue from.

If you think this  "is pretty much in line with currently accepted history" then the US has done a poor job of teaching history to its students.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628578837.0" user="descuidadojose" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not going to deal with the first point you list because I think its fair to say that they north didn't fight the war or abolish slavery out of the kindness of their hearts. They did both because slavery was wrong but also because they didn't want to lose political power and because they had business interests, respectively. 

Your second point on the other hand seems, tangential I guess? 
&amp;gt;Seriously? Someone should tell all the slaves in South America, The Caribbean, and Africa how good they really had it compared to slaves in the southern US.
I think he meant them too. All of that was included in Chattle slavery. All of that was bad too. Those slaves were also believed to be racially inferior by French/Dutch/Spanish/Portugese slaveowners who thought of themselves as white, whatever you may think of them as today. So that doesnt really invalidate his point that the type of slavery used in the American south was more evil than say, that of the Romans or Persians. The Egyptians might have been comparably bad but thats a discussion for another time. Basically yes slavery in south america was also worse than slavery in the ancient world because it was the same type of slavery. 

&amp;gt;Most all slavery through out history has been for profit. Slaves have always had monetary value. This is just ignorance of slavery as an institution in other civilizations and a rationalization to support a poor knowledge of history from which to argue from.

I believe what he meant was that slavery has been used in the past to create public works, and was seen as a way of making up to your conquerors for fighting against them. This obviously wasn't always the case and I would certainly mirror your sentiment that the slavery of the ancient world was still cruel, however, I still think that he makes a good point. 

I'm still not totally sure what I think about this, but I will say I agree with the sentiments expressed above that, slavery in the form it existed in the American South (among other places) was exceptionally evil, so much so as to distinguish itself from other forms of slavery, and furthermore that this was apparent enough to the people of the time, that we shouldn't consider them sufficiently ignorant to be exempt from moral judgement. I mean do you seriously think that the rich Southern families who organized the revolt, almost all of whom owned slaves, were unaware of its evils? Do you think that when slave owners beat or raped their slaves, that they were so stupid that they couldn't see the evil of what they were doing? How it was hurting people? So at the very least, the most important members of the Confederacy can definitely be held to a modern standard because of their up close and personal interactions with slaves. 

In summary, I don't disagree with your general post title, merely that it applies to this instance. We aren't applying todays morality to different historical time periods by taking down statues of slave owners. We are holding them to a standard they absolutely should have held themselves to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29631920726.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>iOnlyHaveThisFor, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostility extremely seriously. Repeated violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+iOnlyHaveThisFor&amp;amp;message=iOnlyHaveThisFor+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/dlz6g9e/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627576745.0" user="eclecticnovice" delta="False">
    <text>If you look at the beginning of the Wikipedia page for [prisoners of war](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prisoner_of_war) in the beginning of the section on ancient times it mentions that prisoners of war were routinely enslaved. Many gladiators were actually prisoners of war that were captured and enslaved. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29628497100.0" user="descuidadojose" delta="False">
    <text>What part is inaccurate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627174232.0" user="cookietrixxx" delta="False">
    <text>How do you think slavery in the US compares to other new world nations?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627246646.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Are you talking about Latin America? I only have a general understanding of the history there, but my general impression was that it was more or less as monstrous as the US system, but different. Punishments were often crueler - lots of hands being cut off for instance. But racism wasn't as integral to the institution as it was in the US south - more tolerance for racial mixing for instance. But they were both horrible, and both worse than other kinds of historical slavery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627293751.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I love the idea that chattel slavery in the United States is okay because it was worse elsewhere. All part of this narrative that slaves were well taken care of.

The only reason life expectancy was higher in the US was because there was a lucrative business in selling off your slaves *children*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627339752.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I know! Or how about: "How can slavery be racist when Africans had slaves too?" And the right-wingers are supposed to be against moral relativity!
But, having a child of my own, the idea that someone could just say your child does not belong to you, and sell her to the highest bidder, and I would never see her again or know if she was suffering, that's bad enough, but then to imagine that happening to hundreds of thousands of families for generations... some of our crimes are so huge, there is no historical perspective or context that can ever make them right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627411221.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>That's the weird thing about this whole, "erasure of history!" nonsense. The only people interested in erasing (or at least revising) history are those who tout the lost cause myth or otherwise downplay the horrific history America has endured.

Does the fact that George Washington owned slaves make him a bad person? I don't know, but it sure doesnt make him a perfect person worthy of nothing but praise. He was a man, a man of his time, *and that's okay*.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
