<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626916691.0" user="darwin2500" delta="False">
    <text>Academics and historians are by no means losing sight of the context of the Civil War.  All the ideas and discussions you're asking to preserve are alive and well, and we know that to be the case because you are aware of them and repeating them here.

We're not talking about historical discussions, we're talking about government-sponsored monuments.  Monuments are about celebrating something and signaling your respect and reverence for it.  Government-sponsored monuments convey the support of the government for a person or ideal.  

The government should not be putting up monuments for 'complicated, nuanced issues that look bad now but made sense in their historical context'.  They should be celebrating our actual, current, modern values.  

They should be preserving the *history* of the full context, and they do so at the Smithsonian and other historical institutions. But you don't need monuments to fill that function.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627102120.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not an academic or a historian, I just like to think I  have a tendency to think critically about situations before forming an opinion.

In some cases we are talking about government sponsored monuments, but in some cases not. Just a few days ago a statue was defaced at Duke university, on private property, not commissioned by the government. The double equestrian statue recently removed from Baltimore was not government sponsored, even though it was placed on government property. It also held relevance to art history as the first double equestrian statue in the country as well as the sculptor being a women selected over over very prominent artist of the time (learned all of that listening to debate about this topic among art historians on NPR). 

Regardless, the debate (and my opinion) is not solely about statues. It's about history and its context and how we apply our modern morals to these highly charged political situations. Currently, one might think that no racism ever existed north of the Mason Dixon line, that lynchings were a uniquely southern reaction to slave emancipation and race relations, or that no southern was worth a damn since they all supported slavery and went to war for it. 

Can anyone tell me what the value of slavery in 1860 in today's dollars? Can anyone tell me the impact of the various tariff acts of the early and mid 19th had on politics during that time? Can anyone tell me how many non-confederate states either banned outright the immigration of free blacks, or placed tests or fees on their entry to their states. Can anyone name the person who uttered the words *"I have no purpose to introduce political and social equality between the white and black races. There is physical difference between the two which, in my judgment, will probably forever forbid their living together upon the footing of perfect equality, and inasmuch as it becomes a necessity that there must be a difference, I, as well as Judge Douglas, am in favor of the race to which I belong having the superior position."* or *"Our republican system was meant for a homogeneous people. As long as blacks continue to live with the whites they constitute a threat to the national life. Family life may also collapse and the increase of mixed breed bastards may some day challenge the supremacy of the white man."*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
