<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626845691.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>This is a complex topic, and my perspective is that the _physical location_ - a key element of "context" - matters in this discussion.

For example, when a statue is erected in town center that is a singular location - it is scarce.  At the time the statue was placed there it made sense.  We then arrive 100 years later and you ask us to see it in its historical context.

However, I believe that we should absolutely keep these statues around to continue to understand our past but that a place like town square should reflect _today's_ values.  That is a scarce space it should not contain symbols that suggest that we are still celebrating an idea that should have fallen into its place in history.  The idea of a location in which we put a statue - it's place for public to enjoy, to reinforce and celebrate ideas that matter to society _today_ should continue lest we relegate all our public spaces to being "history" and not being perpetual re-envisiioned for today's public.

So...I'd like to change your idea a bit and agree that these are historically important, but that the space they are in needs to be continued to be relevent and important to the current times and therefore we should remove symbols that don't reflect current values and relegate those to spaces that are designed for representation of history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627124279.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So...I'd like to change your idea a bit and agree that these are historically important, but that the space they are in needs to be continued to be relevent and important to the current times and therefore we should remove symbols that don't reflect current values and relegate those to spaces that are designed for representation of history.

So in other words, if someone is even remotely offended by something in public that holds any significant historical value, it should be removed to someplace that the offended party won't have to be offended? Where would that be? Do black people not go to museums? Are ALL offending statues on public property (not the statue that was defaced at Duke university, that one was on private property).

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627163916.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>That's an absurd response, to be blunt.  

In a context that is about understanding history (e.g. a museum) we have the context of it ... being about history.  No one denies that there really was a bunch of slavery in the past, or that we were a bunch of racist mofos.  This is _very different_ then saying that a central part of our modern life - a place for socializing, for gathering, for representing the values of the community at large - should retain imagery _for the purpose of historical perspective_ (OPs position).  We clearly cannot avoid offending everyone, but we also know we absolutely would not put up honorarium of leaders of the confederate revolution in town centers _today_ because it would re-enforce a set of values _today_ that we no longer have, or that we almost universally want to be rid of.  

The town center isn't a place for history, it's a place for the representing and furthering the values of the town.  If it's value is something we all generally acknowledge to be _historical_ then either make the place about history explicitly (e.g. the old town hall in Boston isn't the current town hall and represents some history that we might disagree with today) or move the things who only have value in historical context to place that carries that context rather than one that is about society today and today's values.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
