<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29628425907.0" user="rrnbob" delta="False">
    <text>I see a lot of good points down below, but I'll take a stab at it.


It's important to bring up the moralities of the issues because many of these acts/people/etc *are* ***immoral***. That's the point of doing so. And ***not*** pointing that out legitimizes those who actually *agree* with these things *now*.


Because the thing is, *these things are wrong*. *Slavery* ***is wrong.*** *Racism* ***is wrong.*** *Sex with children* ***is wrong.*** These should not be controversial statements.


**Yes**, different cultures throughout history have had wildly different views on these issues, but the fact that they disagreed with us makes them no more right. We judge these things differently because *our sense of morality has* ***grown*** *and ***improved*** *since then.* This is no different than our understanding of *physics* or *astronomy* improving over time. Cultures were as wrong about the morality of slavery as they were about the Earth being the center of the universe. 


Historical context is ***great*** for understanding ***why*** people *behaved the way they did*, or *thought the things they did*, which events *mattered* and *why they did*; but historical context **doesn't excuse** the flawed thinking that went into those decisions, or beliefs, or practices. Historical context is ***great*** for knowing ***why*** people burned women at the stake for """witchcraft""" but it **does not** excuse it.


The problem with statues (specifically mentioned in your post) is that they are pretty *definitively* the ***bad guys***. Confederate Generals, or soldiers, or politicians fought because **they wanted to own other people as property**. That's the bottom line. You can argue it was about economics of slave labour until the cows come home, but whether it was for increased profits, social prestige, or pure racism, *they wanted to own people*. ***Why*** **they did simply doesn't matter.** They were **wrong.** Period.


These statues are of bad people who did bad things. They are **memorials** for these people, and their legacy. Ironically enough ***they do not have any historical context.*** They are misplaced glorification. There are people **right now** who agree with these people, and the ideas they, **and their statues** represent; and so long as memorials to these people are up, we legitimize the people **right now** who think that way.


This is why this is important.


TL;DR: These people were still wrong &amp;amp; these statues glorify bad people and legitimize racists right now

(EDIT: formatting)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
