<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29627607808.0" user="ShowerGrapes" delta="False">
    <text>let me ask you something for clarification. let's take it away from the politically charged confederacy. 


is your position that we should never ever take down a statue once it's put up? and if not, then what are the acceptable criteria for removal in your mind?


How much time has to elapse before it's considered cemented there? what level of atrocity must the person enshrined have to be found to have committed before it can be removed? how much should our views change before we find it no longer acceptable to keep it up? what level of change is necessary? for example, if a country changes government and tears down all the old statues (like the soviet ones for example) is this ok? what percentage of people have to be aligned with its removal? is 100% still not acceptable for removal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627762216.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; is your position that we should never ever take down a statue once it's put up? 

That is a good question that I have not contemplated. If people of a time erect a monument or statue, they did so for whatever they felt was a good reason at the time right? 

The Arc de Triumph still stands in France even though it was erected by a dictator celebrating his victories in conquering his neighbors right? 

So when does a sculpture, monument, or memorial become a work of art rather than a symbol of what cause it was erected for?

&amp;gt;for example, if a country changes government and tears down all the old statues (like the soviet ones for example) is this ok?

I don't know...people were pretty upset at the Taliban when they destroyed statues that were thousands of years old. Statues of Stalin still exist across the former soviet union although may were removed when the union broke up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627929413.0" user="ShowerGrapes" delta="False">
    <text>also does it have to be a certain quality to qualify as art? as many people have pointed out, many of these confederate statues were mass produced and not really art at all. is taking down a print the same as taking down a painting off a wall?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627945244.0" user="ShowerGrapes" delta="False">
    <text>also, i'm not saying that no statues should ever remain up, even controversial ones. some thing like the arc clearly, in the people's minds, for now at least, supersedes any lingering associations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627948997.0" user="ShowerGrapes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If people of a time erect a monument or statue, they did so for whatever they felt was a good reason at the time right?

not necessarily. the government could do it on their own, which presumably happened during soviet russia. i doubt the people wanted statues of their overlords but felt compelled to leave them up or face imprisonment or death. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
