<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29627066690.0" user="ModernContemplative" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you that historical context is important, very important. However, that does not mean that we do not recognize right and wrong today, and do everything we can to make our situation good for all people.

You might consider a situation where as a child, you were a complete jerk to your sibling or friend. In fact, for years you teased them and they developed a body image problem largely because of what you did.

As an adult, now your friend has a lot of bitterness and its evident in how he talks and jokes with you. 

You might think: "I was just a kid, get OVER IT!"
He might think: Fuck you! Or, on a deeper level: you fucked me up, how could you.

In a sense, both sides are right. You are right you were a kid, dealing with your own shit and also wildly lashing out at those around you. You deserve to be forgiven, because when we understand your situation fully, we understand why you did that. 

But today, the situation remains that your friend regularly, in many social situations, has a body image problem. 

What does it mean to reconcile given this? Well, it means that together you move forward. 

The equivalent of tearing down statues might be his now adult "joke" in which he gave you a new nickname he uses for you exclusively: "bully" - "Hey bully, grab me a beer"

This only deepens the divide and aims to blame, rather than heal. In the same way, we need to seek reconciliation and healing as a nation. 

We don't need to tear down symbols and constantly poke at each other in regards to the harm we and past generations have done. But we do need to accept the harm and act accordingly.

With your friend, maybe that means you are just a little more patient in some situations than you would normally be. Or maybe you help coach him through some dates.

In modern society, figuring out how to respond in a way that acknowledges the situation is a living conversation, a big task. 

But I fundamentally disagree with your view, because as we understand ourselves, our behavior, and each other more and more, we must as a moral imperative, apply this understanding moving forward. It's just that, a part of understanding our past bad behavior, whether personally or society, means accepting the reasons for our ignorance and harm, and THEN figuring out how best to proceed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627116003.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's just that, a part of understanding our past bad behavior, whether personally or society, means accepting the reasons for our ignorance and harm, and THEN figuring out how best to proceed

I agree, but I don't think you accomplish this by reducing history to black and white arguments painted with today's morality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29627159206.0" user="ModernContemplative" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I agree, but I don't think you accomplish this by reducing history to black and white arguments painted with today's morality

I don't exactly know what you mean by black and white arguments. I am not defending the liberal identity politics approach of blame, bitterness, divisiveness, and often hate.

But, I am advocating for clearly acknowledging the harm done (this may or may not align with what you mean by black and white).

For instance: Yes, my friend, I fucked up those years ago when I essentially bullied you for being a skinny dude. I am legitimately horrified by how this might be still causing you harm today. I am so sorry dude. Truly.

Here, we are clearly saying: yes, there was harm. No doubt. Black and white. 

But where this absolutes style ends is how we approach it- our attitude. It is not that I give my friend permission to call me names (as liberals call people racists with hate in their hearts), but instead he begins to forgive you... because he sees that you were also just an insecure dweeb, and you made a mistake. 

There is a sense of personal responsibility here. Personal responsibility means we take responsibility for the present situation, and we allow no excuses of things outside of our control to prevent us from bringing our utmost, our best, our most moral and wise and best selves.

If we did harm, if our parents did harm, if our boss or anyone affiliated with us did harm. Hell, if anyone ever does harm, we must acknowledge it, and if appropriate, own it. 

A child grows up. A child sees he was a child before, and now he's an adult. Now he uses his understanding to act as an adult.

You need to step out of your box about "today's morality" and start thinking about it like growing up, understanding more.

How many times have I understood my actions in the past were doing harm - countless! And I grow up by owning them, and then changing. I know better now. I know better that just because I'm angry, doesn't mean I can hit someone. I know that just because I am insecure, doesn't mean I can belittle others. I know that just because someone is doing harm, it doesn't mean they are inherently evil - just that they don't understand.

In other words, if you agree that understanding our past behavior means accepting the reasons for our ignorance, and THEN acting... you MUST bring your morality/understanding from today, from right now, this moment, and reflect on the past.

It does not mean that we "reduce history" to some shadow or caricature. It does not mean that we pretend we were just an evil child. It doesn't mean we pretend racists and slave owners are intrinsically evil. But it is a moral imperative that we bring our moral understanding to these harmful deeds.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
