<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29655399565.0" user="Best_Pants" delta="False">
    <text>Its all dependent on what your personal priorities are.  There are a lot of ubiquitous privileges and opportunities that Americans take for granted that you won't find in a European municipality.

Here's a list of things that American municipalities have more than European ones: sports fields, theme parks, museums (the US contains over [half](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_museums_in_the_United_States) the [world's](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_museums) museums), outlets, churches, foreign restaurants, warm sandy beaches, natural wonders, unspoiled landscapes, parades, school choices, movie theaters, science centers, 7-Elevens, popular band/musician tours, children's playgrounds, basketball courts, zoos, tropical destinations, race-tracks, skate parks, fast-food restaurants, new construction homes, ski mountains, off-road destinations, preserved ships and aircraft (there are 9 battleships left on earth - all American), mountains with gigantic faces carved into them, paint-ball ranges, swimming pools, golf-courses, drag-strips, casinos, rodeos, strip-clubs, hunting grounds, aquariums, laser tag, symphony orchestras, comedy clubs, food trucks, roads with signs and markings...

Have you looked at homes in Europe?  They're comparatively tiny, old and lacking in modern amenities.  European homes outside cities are more likely to lack road access and utility connections.  Did you know the UK is going through a major [housing crisis](http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/if-it-is-change-that-the-voters-really-want-which-party-can-solve-the-housing-crisis-a7878601.html)?

What do European municipalities do better?  Bars, classic architecture, long histories, quiet streets at night, small urban centers, catacombs, relics, travelling by foot or bike, and lower crime rates.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656678222.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>I can't be bothered to go through every single item on this list but I think you're missing the point OP is trying to make. OP is arguing that European cities, in general, are more aesthetically pleasing than American cities. I don't see how sports fields, parades, school choices, movie theaters etc. make American cities more attractive aesthetically? And yeah the US has gorgeous natural beauty but he's talking about cities. He's not saying the Lake District or the Black Forest are more beautiful than Yellowstone or Yosemite; he's saying that Stuttgart and Tallinn and Rennes are more beautiful than Kansas City, Orlando and LA.

He is talking about open spaces, town squares, memorable architecture, even just streets that are a joy to walk down. [This is a map of UNESCO World Heritage sites](http://whc.unesco.org/en/interactive-map/). You might have more churches in the US but how many are considered so spectacular they are considered worthy of protection by international law?

&amp;gt;What do European municipalities do better? Bars, classic architecture, long histories, quiet streets at night, small urban centers, catacombs, relics, travelling by foot or bike, and lower crime rates.

I can't tell if it's funny or tragic that you saw fit to include 7 Elevens, strip clubs and 20th century warships in your list for "things American municipalities do better" and then put out this pathetic attempt at looking balanced. I'm not about to go and make my own list with things like "schools that don't get shot up, Lidls and public spaces that aren't sold to the highest bidder to push consumerism onto every human around" but I certainly could.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656827998.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>Yes! Thank you so much! You understand my point exactly! </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
