<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29655461480.0" user="greasy_r" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't seen anyone in this thread highlight how nice it is to have *space* between you and your neighbors.  As someone who has lived in urban, suburban, and rural environments, the cramped nature of the dense urban areas gets to me (although walkable neighborhoods certainly have their benefits).  

A list of things it's harder to do in a dense european-style city:

* Let your dog hang out in the yard.
* Have a workshop where you can tinker on projects without having to use a maker space.
* Pee off the porch.
* Park a pull-behind camper.
* Plink steel cans with an air rifle or .22
* Garden
* Raise chickens or bees
* Not become familiar with your neighbor's sexual schedule
* Have a barbeque and play yard games

I'm sure in a lot of cases you could do a lot of this in the city but it's certianly a lot more expensive if you want this kind of space. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655755183.0" user="colako" delta="False">
    <text>People WALK their dogs in Europe.
No needs for rifles, go find another hobby
Buy eggs. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655821932.0" user="greasy_r" delta="False">
    <text>It's nice to let the pup roam the yard when the weather's nice while you're at work (or if you're too busy or tired for a proper walk).

The point is some people have different opinions about what's best.  Your comment was not helpful or constructive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656753238.0" user="Rat_of_NIMHrod" delta="False">
    <text>I am pretty sure they are really talking about having enough space to choose how you want to use it.  It's nice to have that choice rather than being confined in how you utilize your own space.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656783659.0" user="colako" delta="False">
    <text>I get it, but there are a ton of shit owners whose dogs never see world beyond their backyards, it is pretty sad and selfish. If you cannot that care of your dog, don't own one. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656818420.0" user="Rat_of_NIMHrod" delta="False">
    <text>If there is room to plink cans with a .22, there is room for a dog to run.  I'd assume by "yard" they are referencing the mowed area closest to the house on a multi acre property where the dogs have plenty of space.  This is the rural terminology I understand anyway.

Yes, there are too many shitty dog owners.  I agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656831401.0" user="colako" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for clarifying</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
