<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29654945960.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>European cities were rarely designed. They grew hodge podge over centuries. American cities were designed in a grid layout. The grid is far superior for navigation. 

As for not being able to walk places. That is a cultural difference and neither is superior or inferior. Being able to be self sufficient in your transit is a massive benefit, as is being able to operate without a car but neither is superior to the other. 

Our water systems are on average far better than Europe. We are not commonly poisoned, and Europe having much older systems is more likely to see poisonings. And our food is of great quality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29654953670.0" user="noott" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Our water systems are on average far better than Europe.

http://archive.epi.yale.edu/epi/issue-ranking/water-and-sanitation

Actually, the US has worse water than most of Western Europe.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29654994156.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>Also- Fair critique- European cities weren't designed. They grew organically. Maybe that's our big problem. 

I don't think walk-ability is mere cultural difference. There are directly measurable heath impacts to spending a significant portion of your time driving. Car-centric living literally kills people, as people get killed in car accidents far more frequently than walking or bicycle accidents. 

Lastly, I disagree that American food is of "good quality." Perhaps "good enough." But - If our food is of such good quality, why do we always want to imitate European food or import it? Why is Italian Parmesan more expensive if ours is just as good?  Seems like European food often has an edge. Additionally, their rates of hunger and malnutrition are far lower than ours. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655000333.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The only cheese allowed to be called parmesan is from Italy. It is the name for a regional product. Similarly you cannot call sparkling wine Champagne unless it if from Champagne France. 

We "imitate" European food because we are ethnically primarily of European decent. That is our food heritage and the settlers brought the food with them from their homeland. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655144481.0" user="Syric" delta="False">
    <text>That's a matter of Europe having tasty recipes for things. It has nothing to do with food quality.

Italian Parmesan is more expensive because it's imported. Obviously.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655510442.0" user="tinyp" delta="False">
    <text>EU Law is far stricter on food safety/quality standards than the US. This is a whole thread in the Brexit debate, with many fearing leaving the EU will result in the UK being flooded with food of a inferior quality and with poor standards of animal welfare from the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656338013.0" user="Squindig" delta="False">
    <text>Not true. The UK is the land of Mad Cow disease and Foot and Mouth disease.  Of horse meat masquerading as beef. British meat is filthy and disgusting compared to American meat. That's why the best steaks (in steak restaurants) are imported from the USA and Japan.  You are falling for the propaganda of British domestic meat producers who want protection from competition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656534685.0" user="tinyp" delta="False">
    <text>That is possibly the dumbest comment I have ever read.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655190815.0" user="salixirrorata" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't address what was brought up about ease of navigation. Do you deny this is a benefit of American cities?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655196781.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that the benefit is substantial compared with the costs associated with the auto-oriented development pattern. I've found most European cities plenty easy to navigate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655929074.0" user="qwerty11111122" delta="False">
    <text>Ever been to New York?

Avenues are numbered and everything is pretty square, so you only ever really need to make a single or two turns to get where you want to go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656191726.0" user="TheBrownieTitan" delta="False">
    <text>I live in a city in Europe that was gridded in the 1800's. I also lived in Bruges. I genuinely remembered where everything was in Bruges way better. (Which has narrow streets everywhere) 

I think the type of city layout is better is depended on your preferences. I can't say that grids aren't easier to plan though, they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656751899.0" user="0100101010110" delta="False">
    <text>The difference, then, seem to be the ease of memorizing your surroundings vs the ease of finding your way around in a new place. Gridded city layouts are far easier to get around in. Rather than "go two blocks passed the blue house and make a right, then the second right around the roundabout at the fountain", you can just say "7th and harrison, number 210".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656322177.0" user="KetchupTubeAble19" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't say that's necessarily a benefit. Sure, grid system and numbering are easy for finding something, but they're bad for remembering because the shape of roads and most buildings in those squares is the same -&amp;gt; harder to remember, compared to European urban "design".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656355983.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>I don't consider NYC a "typical American City"- it's one of the largest, densest, and most transit-oriented cities in the Manhattan doesn't have a sprawl issue. It is utterly exceptional in a host of other ways too, and stands in a class I would consider that has much more in common with European cities than other American ones. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656610244.0" user="petersbro" delta="False">
    <text>The Mormon Pioneers used the plat system to lay out basically every town in Utah (I can't think of an exception). It breaks down a little with sprawl, but overall, navigation is super easy. It's not just NYC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656648065.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>Trying to ignore New York when discussing American cities, and then further limiting New York to only Manhattan, is dancing on the edge of a No True Scotsman fallacy. Manhattan doesn't have sprawl because it is an island that is built all the way to the water. New York city absolutely sprawls, especially if you consider north New Jersey and Long Island's suburbs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656811816.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>That's ridiculous. NYC was built with no parking minimums, no setback requirements, no height or density restrictions- all of which allowed the city to develop in a dense, compact, and beautiful way. These rules are absolutely exceptional. It's my understanding that there aren't more than a handful of US cities that were primarily built with such relaxed development requirements. 

If NYC was built and the government said that every landowner has to set their home at least 35 feet from their property line, and 80% of Manhattan was reserved for single-family housing, and three 12-lane parkways with strip malls on either side were built up and down the length of Manhattan island, then NYC would be built according to the rules required in many other american cities (abet, a bit caricatured for argument's sake). It's status as an island would not prevent this. Calling NYC exceptional isn't a No True Scottsman fallacy, because there are real differences between it's pattern of development and most American cities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656875561.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>There are numerous other cities built in the same era as New York that didn't follow its pattern of development. Recall that Manhattan didn't spring from the ground fully formed, much of the island *was* single family homes and even pasture land. So why isn't it now? They ran out of room to spread out and so had a financial incentive to build upwards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656877687.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>But the rules there allow them to build up!Most cities have laws against this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656900441.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>Many other cities have either no good reason to (just build out) or good reasons not to (the ground wouldn't support it, disaster concerns) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656741027.0" user="qwerty11111122" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, it has ~3% of all people in the US, so I'd consider that a decent chunk :P</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655219963.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>A grid-system isn't easier for navigation. Why would you think that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655450347.0" user="spacing_out_in_space" delta="False">
    <text>In a grid, all you need to know is the general direction of where you eventually want to end up.  If I know my destination is northeast, I walk/drive north and east until I get to the proper latitude/longitude.  I don't even have to be familiar with the streets that I'm taking; I'm literally never lost in Chicago regardless of whether I'm familiar with the particular area that I'm in.  Just take one look at the layout of Chicago versus Boston or pretty much any European city and it's really easy to see which one is easier to navigate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656341497.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, but this does kinda fuel the "Americans are stupid"-cliche if you think cities need to gridlines, otherwise you'd get lost. Are you listening to yourself? Getting lost isn't a real issue for me (and for most people here in the Netherlands), even if the roads aren't neat gridlines. Or you know, everyone has Google Maps these days.

But seriously, look at Almere-Stad if you want an example of reaaaally good modern road infrastructure. Even if gridlines are easier to navigate, there are so many reasons why building cities like that is bad (and also pretty ugly). You need sooo many traffic lights to let the traffic flow properly. Question though, do you use a lot of priority roads in your city? Isn't your route also determined by the road type and speed limit?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656716803.0" user="spacing_out_in_space" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not going to respond to your comment other than to tell you that you're condescending as fuck, and you sound ignorant for thinking I'm stupid based on my preference for a more basic city layout. I never implied that I NEED a grid to get around. Of course I know how to use Google maps or gps to navigate any city. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657844389.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry dude, I just don't really know how to respond to this. Maybe there are some good arguments for a grid-layout for your city, but I think navigation is just an incredibly silly argument to give.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655617360.0" user="supreme_cx" delta="False">
    <text>If I drop you on one end of Manhattan and ask you to walk to a particular point, it'll take you a lot less time than the same distance in London without a map .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656330528.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>But you'll never ever walk to another point in London. You'll be more likely to take public transit. And then you'd look up the stations and where to go. It'll probably take less time in London, as you have the advantage of better public transit. Furthermore, walking takes less time in London, as the city is more centered around more forms of transport. AFAIK in most cities in America, the infrastructure is focused on the car.

It's such a silly argument. I've never really thought to myself "oh boy, this city is so difficult to drive through, if only it were made up of extremely simple gridlines".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656287249.0" user="GTI-Mk6" delta="False">
    <text>I'm no fan of the grid system as I find them boring and plain, but the major reason the exist is navigational simplicity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656332791.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>Why? How? Is there any proof of this?

I mean, only if your city is designed for cars, then maaaaybee it is simpler. But I think you'd only end up with major congestion as you need traffic lights for even the high throughput lanes of your city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657179865.0" user="GTI-Mk6" delta="False">
    <text>Well I take a pedestrian first approach to cities, so I cant really speak for cars.

 Grids offer frequent intersections which offer many choices for changing direction when needed. Portland Oregon's 200x200 foot grid size is generally considered the ideal grid size. 

Grids also are easy to have simple names. In my town, the northernmost Street in the grid is called 1st Street, with the numbers rising as you move South (new streets to the north aren't possible due to a physical barrier) and streets running north &amp;amp; south can be ordered alphabetically, for example. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657293874.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>But intersections in almost all circumstances are a bad idea. They halt traffic flow. Even worse when you mix it up with pedestrian paths. And I don't really think that the advantages in grid-cities are inherent to grid-cities. If you design a city with pedestrians in mind, you can allow a lot of shortcuts which make navigating a lot easier. It doesn't need to be grid-like.

Aside from that, I always thought that grid cities would end up looking dull and aesthetically unpleasing. But I'd be glad to be proven wrong on that.

As for the naming scheme, there are other ways to make it easier for people. Over here in the Netherlands, streets in a neighborhood often have a thematic name. In my home town, for example, there is a "music neighborhood". Every street would be called after a musical composition (fugue, overture, melody, opera, etc). Could also be way simpler, such as naming them after types of butterfly. That way, when you hear the name of a butterfly as the street name, you often know which neighborhood it is in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655432630.0" user="CWM_93" delta="False">
    <text>As someone born in the UK, I get lost more easily in places with street grids because I rely in part on the street shapes (and landmarks) to navigate, rather than counting streets. When you have irregular shape streets, every junction looks different, even when the buildings have a similar style - or that might just be what I'm used to, and what makes sense with what I've grown up with!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656044084.0" user="argentumArbiter" delta="False">
    <text>Well, sure, but you've grown up there and already know where all the landmarks are relative to each other. For a tourist or a newcomer to the city, it's a lot easier to follow "go down this street until you reach x other street, then go down that one until you reach your destination" in New York than follow all the roundbouts and turns needed to find your way around Paris.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656366582.0" user="CWM_93" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that I use this approach to navigation in places I've never been before - not just the places I already know. I got easily disoriented in Barcelona, for instance, because the (mostly) grid street layout meant that I couldn't easily compare turns in the road to the map to verify I was in the right place: on the map every street looks the same.

The other thing about non-planned street layouts is that they tend to link up major landmarks as the path of least resistance anyway. Also, streets tend to radiate out from the centre, so if you're going into the city centre, once you find a major street, it'll tend to lead you straight there.

Bonus fact: because non-grid streets lie at a wider variety of angles than grids do, the average navigable distance between two given points tends to be shorter.

NB - I'm primarily talking about walking and cycling rather than driving, because I don't own a car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655782808.0" user="TELL_ME_YOUR_FEARS" delta="False">
    <text>I have to disagree with that point. Certain cities like NYC sure the grid is incredibly easy to navigate, but most US cities are not actually laid out on a grid, or they are laid out in collections of grids that overlap each other and make a mess</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656174489.0" user="dby" delta="False">
    <text>The lack of public transportation in the U.S. is honestly shocking. It's definitely harder to get to your destination in the U.S. than almost anywhere in Europe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655367393.0" user="shadowarc72" delta="False">
    <text>Imitating European dishes is not the same as having lesser quality food. Food would be, is our beef of the same quality as theirs or wheat or other food stuffs. 

In most cases I wouldn't count food as a dish except in this case the things that make one better than the other come down to technique rather than ability. 

Dishes would be, we need to create a wholly original dish that no one else has come up with. For a bunch of immigrants from Europe that's a pretty tall order. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656192435.0" user="WF187" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imitating European dishes is not the same as having lesser quality food. Food would be, is our beef of the same quality as theirs or wheat or other food stuffs.

Just going to add that American beef is slaughtered younger than European beef. It's the major reason why America didn't have the problem with the build up of bovine hormones from the American-style feed that lead to Europe being ravaged by Mad Cow Disease. We eat a lot more beef: young, tender, almost veal-like-quality yummy beef.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655414958.0" user="UEMcGill" delta="False">
    <text>Our food "problem" is largely due to affluence. We have been the richest country in the world since the end of world War II. You can track the rise of obesity directly with sugar production and affluence. The more affluent, the more sugar consumption. Great Britain started the trend and the US has been at the front since the 40's.

I've been all over, including some amazing restaurants from Paris to New York and frankly NYC is the greatest restaurant city in the world.  I love Paris but no where on earth can you literally get anything for dinner as easily as NYC. Europe does have less chain garbage places, but they also have lots of mediocre places too. France is pretty good for average, Germany is MEH,  I could go on. I've eaten too many mediocre meals in Europe to count because I was in some podunk manufacturing town. 

Go to a grocery store in France, Germany Italy etc and they have all the same processed food we do. Hell in Italy it's a huge complaint that young people don't cook, they eat out and grab take away.

The food industry is gearing up for it. It's a huge trend because the world is getting rich (and fat). Prepared food is coming worldwide.  As the world catches up in affluence so will go a lot of scratch made food. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655498696.0" user="UncleCarbuncle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can track the rise of obesity directly with sugar production and affluence

You can do the same with meat and dairy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656440490.0" user="RMCPhoto" delta="False">
    <text>For every McDonald's or taco Bell here there is a shitty kebob  shack in any European city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655587432.0" user="kairisika" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why is Italian Parmesan more expensive if ours is just as good?

Why is one brand of clothing more expensive? Original source products are all about branding, not quality. Unfortunately you seem to have bought in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655625836.0" user="not_homestuck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why is Italian Parmesan more expensive if ours is just as good?

Also, Italian parmesan is...imported??? So obviously it's more expensive than parmesan that was made down the road. 

OP is under the assumption that expensive things are inherently better quality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655630750.0" user="kairisika" delta="False">
    <text>Heh, also a very important factor!

Yeah.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656313906.0" user="Steppdeckenwolf" delta="False">
    <text>Copying a reply to another comment:

Parmesan is also more expensive in Europe, including Italy, than comparable hard cheeses, including Italian ones. The difference is that the name Parmesan is protected in the EU to only apply to the real thing, so things that might be sold as "Parmesan" elsewhere have other names here.

Importing things doesn't actually make them expensive. Just think about the world travels of a simple cheap t-shirt. Parmesan is expensive because it requires a long ripening time, i.e. storage space, and because it is of high quality with regards to ingredients and craftsmanship. There other great Italian hard cheeses, but if you so a taste test, you will taste a difference.  I've not been in the position to try American Parmesan knock-offs, but I would be surprised if they tasted the same, based on the difference in cattle food alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655620343.0" user="not_homestuck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think walk-ability is mere cultural difference. There are directly measurable heath impacts to spending a significant portion of your time driving. 

You're forgetting that the U.S. is WAY bigger and largely more rural than Europe. Most people in the U.S. depend on cars and many people commute to bigger cities for work. 

I'm not saying that pedestrian-friendly cities aren't great (I wish we had more of them!) but you cannot take away the car-centric lifestyle of the U.S. (unless you implement expensive infrastructure for public transport). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656134361.0" user="LusoAustralian" delta="False">
    <text>That's the point. European cities have infrastructure and therefore are better designed and more livable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29660617311.0" user="not_homestuck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; European cities have infrastructure

If anything, American cities are better designed because they generally were pre-planned - the difference is that they were pre-planned with cars in mind in a lot of cases. European cities have the challenge of building modern accommodations around buildings that are often hundreds or more years old. A lot of cities in Europe still have literal cobbled streets, for example. They're just more pedestrian friendly because they were built with pedestrians in mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29660754014.0" user="LusoAustralian" delta="False">
    <text>Which makes it even more astounding that few American cities other than NYC, DC and Boston have proper public transportation systems capable of allowing a significant proportion of their urban population to commute without a car. The age of European cities should be a disadvantage yet they often have much better systems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656461225.0" user="Pleberal" delta="False">
    <text>You could actually have pavement to walk on that would greatly help for little cost.

The amount of streets in the US that packed sidewalks was turely absurd. Also Americans drive like Italians but instead of mopeds and small cars is huge trucks and SUVs. I'm amazed more of you don't die on the road.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29660607657.0" user="not_homestuck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also Americans drive like Italians

I've lived in Italy and I can promise you that's not true, haha!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29661033222.0" user="Pleberal" delta="False">
    <text>Admittedly I've only seen the very north.  I guess it gets crazier as you go south. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655699047.0" user="jamin_brook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why is Italian Parmesan more expensive if ours is just as good? 

Generally speaking this is due to the fact that it's from fucking ITALY.

&amp;gt; why do we always want to imitate European food 

Always? 

What about the Mexican food in Europe?  Cuban food? How about **any** Latin American Food?

Is the sushi in Munich and Berlin really better than the sushi in San Francisco and LA?

Bottom line is we have all the options you guys do but more of them. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656253032.0" user="nickykittie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Mexican food in Europe

No such thing. There is only Tex-Mex.

Source: mexican-american living in europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656312385.0" user="Steppdeckenwolf" delta="False">
    <text>Parmesan is also more expensive in Europe, including Italy, than comparable hard cheeses, including Italian ones. The difference is that the name Parmesan is protected in the EU to only apply to the real thing, so things that might be sold as "Parmesan" elsewhere have other names here.

Importing things doesn't actually make them expensive. Just think about the world travels of a simple cheap t-shirt. Parmesan is expensive because it requires a long ripening time, i.e. storage space, and because it is of high quality with regards to ingredients and craftsmanship. There other great Italian hard cheeses, but if you so a taste test, you will taste a difference.  I've not been in the position to try American Parmesan knock-offs, but I would be surprised if they tasted the same, based on the difference in cattle food alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656574308.0" user="mechesh" delta="False">
    <text>Your comparison is off.  A t-shirt is lite weight, compact and non perishable so it is inexpensive to ship, and you are comparing it to a dense perishable item.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656575692.0" user="Steppdeckenwolf" delta="False">
    <text>Parmesan lasts for months if not years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656578399.0" user="mechesh" delta="False">
    <text>In the right conditions, yes.  It can also spoil quickly in the wrong ones.  

You also didn't address the density.  heavier denser things are more expensive to ship than lightweight compact items.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656595809.0" user="Steppdeckenwolf" delta="False">
    <text>And you didn't address the fact that Parmesan is also more expensive than other hard cheeses in the EU including Italy, the reasons for which I have outlined above. That shows transport and import are unlikely reasons for the price difference in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656830036.0" user="mechesh" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I am not a cheese expert and I don't know the prices of Parmesan cheese in the US vs. Europe.

But let me get this straight, you are saying that size and weight have no effect on product price due to shipping costs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657037667.0" user="Steppdeckenwolf" delta="False">
    <text>If I was saying that, I probably would have written that instead of everything else I wrote. What I'm saying is, Parmesan's higher price is to a large extent explained by quality and ripening time (which again translates to quality), which is why it's more expensive than other similar cheeses *anywhere in the world*. The fact that it's imported does not explain most of the price difference, the difference in quality does. You can verify this very simply by comparing the tastes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657047129.0" user="mechesh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Importing things doesn't actually make them expensive

Importing things *can* make them expensive.  Importing T-shirts does not make them expensive because you can import a large quantity of them in a shipping container so the cost is spread out over vastly more t-shirts than the cost of shipping a dense perishable product.  

I agree that the aging process is a large factor of the costs of Parmigiana cheese, but don't pretend that shipping and import fees play no role. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656204753.0" user="ithkrul" delta="False">
    <text>Comparing food of Europe and USA is easy.  France has the most 3-Michelin star restaurants.  All of the other European countries have fewer than than USA after that.  USA has more than Italy or Germany.  However if you want to really want to rate food by region, you should compare city to city IMO.  The USA has a huge population, but France has been at this game for way longer :)

In the west, Paris and NYC are the clear winners.  While Japan smokes everyone out of the water.

The reason food in Europe is often what is imitated, goes back to how established Haute cuisine got started.  French(17c), Italian(18c), and Japanese(?).  Literally, they wrote the book on it...The Cookbook

Arguably, the Japanese have the best food on Earth presently.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Michelin_3-star_restaurants

Arguably, Id claim that the USA makes the best beer these days.  Largely thanks to the craft brew movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656302976.0" user="Steppdeckenwolf" delta="False">
    <text>What's it look like when you do Michelin star restaurants (of all mentioned restaurants in the guide, whatever) per population?

&amp;gt;Arguably, Id claim that the USA makes the best beer these days.  Largely thanks to the craft brew movement.

Belgium has the best beer and the largest variety of great beers in the world. There is simply no comparison. Plenty of countries have "craft beer movements" and the US were not the first, just probably where the recent very visible/hipsterized/well-marketed one started. But Belgium never needed one of those, because the entire country's history is basically a craft beer movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656649661.0" user="ithkrul" delta="False">
    <text>Except that Belgium doesn't hold a gold ranking in any brew category this year, from the international brewing awards, and the USA holds three.  

Edit* note, I love Belgian wit bier, and that style of beer is made everywhere.  There are just so many other categories.
 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656653624.0" user="ithkrul" delta="False">
    <text>Japan is the superstar for Michelin star count, but given their population I dunno.  Again I'd want to break it down by city.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656285491.0" user="NSNick" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why is Italian Parmesan more expensive if ours is just as good? 

Probably because it's expensive to ship things from Italy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656293353.0" user="MrWigggles" delta="False">
    <text>You keep bringing up that the US is fatter then Europe. Europe and the US are about equally fat as each other. France is one of the fattest countries in Europe. And its also not like Us and the entirety of Europe was miles apart. According to the WHO, 23 percent of Europe are obese, and 27 percent of US is obese. Not that wide of a margin. The average Commute in the US, is 23 minuets whereas the average Commute in Western Europe is 43 minuets. Post industrial countries are fat, not because of car use. Its because of diet and lifestyle. We eat a lot, and sit a lot. Ergo, we're fat. 

And Bicycles and cars are about as safe. Bike stats are hard to come by, as bike accidents and miles ridden are under reported, but even with low level figures for bikes an actually known figure for cars plays Bike Fatalities (Death) is somewhere around .31 to 1.26 per 10 million miles ridden. Compared to automotive fatalities, of .11 deaths per 10 million miles driven. In other words, riding bikes in the US is more deadly then riding in a car.

I'm starting to think that the basis of this europhile tendency, is not based on any research.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656760684.0" user="autisticperson123" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Europe and the US are about equally fat as each other.  

Not true at all, North Americans are on average 10kg heavier than Europeans. 

&amp;gt;France is one of the fattest countries in Europe. 

That's like saying Mississippi is one of the fattest states in the US. Your point being?

&amp;gt;And Bicycles and cars are about as safe.

Yeah, right. It's much harder to cause a lethal accident with a bike than it is to cause a lethal accident with a car.

&amp;gt;Bike stats are hard to come by, as bike accidents and miles ridden are under reported, but even with low level figures for bikes an actually known figure for cars plays Bike Fatalities (Death) is somewhere around .31 to 1.26 per 10 million miles ridden. Compared to automotive fatalities, of .11 deaths per 10 million miles driven. In other words, riding bikes in the US is more deadly then riding in a car.

Those "bike deaths" are actually caused by cars, and should therfore be called "car deaths". Bikes almost never cause accidents, in the sense that a biker kills himself by biking into a tree, or a biker kills another person in transport.

The statistics also aren't hard to come by at all, at least not for European countries. 

&amp;gt;I'm starting to think that the basis of this europhile tendency, is not based on any research.

You don't have to do any research to know that a giant 1000kg+ metal brick with liters of gasoline in it with a top speed of 160km/h+ is more lethal than a ~10kg metal object with a top speed of about 30 km/h for people who are not athletes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656822595.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>Yes! Exactly! Thank you for your common sense!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656608065.0" user="Complaingeleno" delta="False">
    <text>Car-centric living also requires infrastructure for cars which takes up huge amounts of land and is horrible for the environment. And in addition to our cities being poorly designed, our transportation guidelines are also horribly designed, and have over the years, created more and more ridiculous standards for things like road width that have no basis in reality.

There's a lot of writing about how a standard lane used to be 10 feet wide and is now often 12, 14, or even 16 feet (depending on whether or not you live in Florida) because some traffic engineer decided that wider roads made for safer travel. Turns out they just encourage speeding and increase the number of accidents. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655050715.0" user="Angdrambor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As for not being able to walk places. That is a cultural difference and neither is superior or inferior. Being able to be self sufficient in your transit is a massive benefit, as is being able to operate without a car but neither is superior to the other. 

What benefit do you see to having a city so spread out that a car is required? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655100340.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Things are less crowded. Homes can be larger. Stores can be larger and hold more variety of things. Schools can be larger and have proper space for classrooms as well as outdoor sports, band, etc. You have more green space and more citizen parks. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655185575.0" user="nickykittie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;European cities were rarely designed. They grew hodge podge over centuries. American cities were designed in a grid layout. The grid is far superior for navigation


So true. As an American living in England, trying to give or get directions can be an absolute nightmare. The roads are just sort of melded together haphazardly and everyone navigates by landmarks in a very arbitrary way. The streets are also so narrow in lots of place that you often have to pull onto the sidewalk to let other cars pass, or back up all the way down a street and turn backwards. It always seems horribly dangerous to me.


&amp;gt;As for not being able to walk places. That is a cultural difference and neither is superior or inferior.

So true. Driving places = more time at the gym, specific activities. Walking and public transportation= spending more time doing light exercise (sometimes, depends on how far you live from the bus stop!) and it taking lots more time to get to and from places. For this reason, I actually exercise less than I did when I lived in the States because it's harder for me to get to the classes I want to take.

&amp;gt;Our water systems are on average far better than Europe. We are not commonly poisoned, and Europe having much older systems is more likely to see poisonings. And our food is of great quality.

Yup! You have to be careful and heed the "Not drinking water" signs! Filling up a water bottle in a bathroom feels like living dangerously sometimes. Annoyingly, in the UK there are hardly any water fountains around in public spaces, so staying hydrated can be really difficult.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655417581.0" user="dismantlemars" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The streets are also so narrow in lots of place that you often have to pull onto the sidewalk to let other cars pass, or back up all the way down a street and turn backwards. It always seems horribly dangerous to me.

I always wondered why US driving tests seemed so much easier than ours, I never really thought about how we're learning to drive on roads that were never designed for cars. 

&amp;gt;Yup! You have to be careful and heed the "Not drinking water" signs! Filling up a water bottle in a bathroom feels like living dangerously sometimes. 

This feels relatively rare these days, it's only really in old buildings that haven't had their water storage tanks removed. 

&amp;gt;Annoyingly, in the UK there are hardly any water fountains around in public spaces, so staying hydrated can be really difficult.

All premises that serve alcohol in the UK are required to provide free potable water to anyone who asks. They are allowed to charge you for use of a glass though... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656246103.0" user="nickykittie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All premises that serve alcohol in the UK are required to provide free potable water to anyone who asks. They are allowed to charge you for use of a glass though..

Yeah, I know I can get free/cheap water from places but I'm used to there being drinking fountains wherever you go, like shopping centres, grocery stores, and public parks. The only place I can reliably find free, cold water that I don't have to bother anyone for is the water coolers at my uni and there aren't very many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655217795.0" user="Tangerinetrooper" delta="False">
    <text>Grid layout is an awful way to design your city. Look at Almere-Stad if you want to see a well-designed infrastructure for a modern city.

Public transit is superior as it allows more people with less traffic density. Can't see how you view these as equal.

Also, we have better food protection agencies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655521675.0" user="zmaax" delta="False">
    <text>As an European I really had to laugh when I read your last sentence :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655549071.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever had properly cooked brisket or fresh Tex-Mex? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655656694.0" user="You_Will_Die" delta="False">
    <text>You actually got almost all of it wrong lol. You dont have better water, it actually taste like poolwater. Also from what I can remember Flint doesnt agree on your praise over water system. You dont have better food either, we have much higher restrictions and quality checks to ensure the low quality stay out. The US even moans about the regulations when exporting to us. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656005309.0" user="TheAtlanticGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Where in the United States did you try the water?  The quality varies pretty wildly, and certainly can't be judged in its whole by Flint's local train wreck.  I've had tap water here varying anywhere from great to disgusting.  Where I live in Virginia it's thankfully actually pretty good, better in fact than some of the water I've tried in Europe.  Maine meanwhile practically has bottled-quality filtered water come out of their faucets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656402374.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>"Preferences" for how water from different places tastes is mostly down to personal bias IME. I live in a part of the UK that has soft water and I can't stand the water in places like London but my friends who live in London prefer it.

Anecdotally I see a lot of comments on the internet from Americans who swear by bottled water because they don't trust tap water but that's really not a thing I've ever seen from Western Europeans. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655641007.0" user="no_dad_no" delta="False">
    <text>As a whole, I agree that European were not designed. Try grew organically and most commonly aournd a city center dating back to the middle age, with a street network that is quite chaotic. Buy after, the more recent extension and also the demolition that took place during WW2, and the planning that started after that, you'll see that most cities got main roads/big avenues. Even in London, which is one of the biggest european cities, you'll see a network of major axis that allows you to figure out where you are. As someone else said, for some people, it's easier to navigate an European city than an American one, because of the variety of street size for instance.

And I really really don't think that one can say, in 2017, that there is no better or worse between a walkable city and a spread out city... we know right now that we can't and shouldn't rely on cars, so right now, in that situation, European cities are simply more efficient than American ones. 

I figure that it's just that, when that rural exodus exploded is when American cities exploded, and that's when the car was considered a given. The same things happened in Europe with quick and massive urban and suburban development in the 20th century, and lots of bad decisions were made. But it was on a smaller scale because the cities were already huge because of their histories, whereas lots of American cities were merely developing.

What I mean is that the way we evaluate cities is linked with the period, and American cities such as Los Angeles were an example for European cities in the 70's. 
Right now, a European urban organisation in clearly better considered, and for good reason. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655651792.0" user="no_dad_no" delta="False">
    <text>And I don't get what you mean about water system. If you compare the USA with countries of similar development, I don't think you'll find that the states have better water system. Here in france in 30 years of existante I've never heard of public water being poisoned. Whereas I've been hearing about Flint for a couple of years now. I get that the situations are different but I completly agree with OP that the fact that lots of European countries have this culture of having a stronger and more interventionist state leads to good (better) publics services such as water distinction and city planning. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655794273.0" user="Dilbertreloaded" delta="False">
    <text>Not walking and always being inside an enclosed space explains an average Americans lack of understanding of others, obesity, and Trump phenomenon. Being so car dependent has resulted in parking space requirements and buildings getting further and further away from one another. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655797180.0" user="Dilbertreloaded" delta="False">
    <text>US Food is also not great quality. Diseases and obesity and healthcare costs are literally killing people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656140060.0" user="LusoAustralian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As for not being able to walk places. That is a cultural difference and neither is superior or inferior.

Having fewer options for transport for both residents and visitors is inferior and can't just be boiled down to a "cultural difference". And having lived in American for a good few months I'd say the average quality of the food is much lower. Not that you can't find good quality food easily, just that the vast majority of people don't look for good food and often eat terribly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656366297.0" user="Sherlocksdumbcousin" delta="False">
    <text>"our food is of great quality" 

Really? It's very difficult to find fresh products in the US and a lot of your meat and agricultural products don't pass the legal standards we have in Europe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656388014.0" user="vuxanov" delta="False">
    <text>I'm curious about where did you come up with American food being better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656407346.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>Have you never seen Americans on the internet talk about how their country is some sort of promised land when it comes to eating out? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656458609.0" user="Pleberal" delta="False">
    <text>Citation needed on poisonings in drink tap water all the time. I've seen videos of US water literally catching fire. 

Being walkable is superior to car centric. You can still drive in Europe you are just not forced to. In the US you must drive or not travel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656464572.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The only real point you raise here is the grid being superior, which while being debatable certainly for navigation has a point.

The point about transportation is simply invalid because of ecological points and  the one about water is straight up wrong while the one about food isnt related at all and subjective to top it off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656523448.0" user="JitteryBug" delta="False">
    <text>You're confounding self sufficiency with Independence. You can be self sufficient taking excellent public transport, but with other people around you, v. needing to have your own space in your own car. 


I agree that the origin is cultural but I believe that one is indeed better than  under objective measures. Total cost, costs to individuals, emissions, city design.. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656557219.0" user="jacenat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Our water systems are on average far better than Europe. We are not commonly poisoned, and Europe having much older systems is more likely to see poisonings.

I hope you are not serious. Water is heavily regulated and of excellent quality in all of the EU (not sure about SEE).

&amp;gt; And our food is of great quality.

Yeah ... not even gonna start on that one. If quality for means that it has a lot of calories and sugar, sure. It's probably the opposite of healthy though. Food in the EU is (like many things) highly regulated.

&amp;gt; American cities were designed in a grid layout. The grid is far superior for navigation.

This is probably the only ligitimate argument. Can't see anything wrong with that. Most US cities have a much clearer layout and are far easier to navigate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656768503.0" user="lyzedekiel" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Being able to be self sufficient in your transit is a massive benefit, as is being able to operate without a car but neither is superior to the other. 

I don't get this. For me, being able to operate without a car _is_ being self-sufficient. Why do you equate your car with your self?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656781970.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Using public transit means you are depending on bus drivers, train operators, taxis, uber, etc. That is not self sufficient. Only if you bike or walk are you self sufficient, and then you cannot carry anything of large quantities or that is very heavy with you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656793249.0" user="lyzedekiel" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that only walking and biking are self-sufficient. Which is why cars are not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29665882226.0" user="RektSquared" delta="False">
    <text>Flint mate. I live in England and haven't died from tap water yet.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
