<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="41" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29732492226.0" user="Pepe_Silvia96" delta="False">
    <text>You were trying to argue superiority on the grounds of aesthetics with a bunch of braindead Americans. You never had a shot, but I admire your effort. One asshole literally said 'if statistics won't change your view then I don't know what will.'  Like statistics is what your concern is lmao.

Let that be a lesson to you on the dangers of technology dawg. The western world is so enthraled with everything technology that as a collective we're trying to imitate all the traits of technology we admire. We like to pretend that we can be just like computers in our day to day lives by formulating opinions through absorbing raw data, processing it and churning out the most appropriate and objective conclusion. As a result of this shitty shit desire to be technologically precise we've pretty much entirely suppressed for the better part of the last century the most profoundly human component of our being, that being the innate attraction to beauty of any kind. Whether its the beauty of a painting, of a human or of architecture, we're all to one degree or another out of touch with the reality of beauty.

So no shit that in this age of a complete refusal to acknowledge the value of beauty we stay complacent with shitty glass and steel filing cabinet office buildings and disgusting grey concrete freeways that cut through our city centers. Some idiot in this thread even went so far as to justify the existence of those miserable structures. 

Technology is concerned with efficiency so naturally I guess that's what Americans want out of their cities...aesthetic integrity was never a thing American urban planners took into account, all they cared for was efficiency. How can we decrease this laborers commute to get the most out of his work. 

I highly recommend you watch this https://vimeo.com/128428182




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29732827528.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for that- you completely understand what I was aiming at. Roger Scruton is one of my favorite thinkers. I wish he was more well-known on this side of the Atlantic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
