<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29654919099.0" user="InvalidLusername" delta="False">
    <text>I believe there are multiple things that you are mixing here. One is the way cities are build and operated. 2nd: the American way of life (car-centric, food, etc). 3rd: Environmental concerns (lead/arsenic in water, etc) 4th: Culture and the value people put on culture. 

The way cities are built and operated: most European cities were not designed. They grew organically and in this growth certain things emerged. Is it better or worse? It's better from certain point of view but worse from others. IMHO the American cities are built to be functional first. They do have a center/downtown but the emphasis is not on how cool it is to be or live in the center of the city. (Major European cities have serious issues w/ congestion in the city center to the point of banning people to drive through the center) 

2nd: American way of life == suburbia. At least that was the working idea when most cities were established. Nobody wanted to have a social life in the city. The city is were you go to work. The evolution the city is a response to what people needed. The dream of suburbia is fading away, but we cannot and some would argue we should not, transform things over night. (Mass transit? Hahahahaha)

Environmental: except for a few areas I believe Americans are not intentionally destroying the environment. We are actually paying attention, asking the questions and letting other nations deplete their resources/poison themselves. We get away with this because of the huge economic weight the dollar (still) carries.

Culture: people have other values. Period. You care about what you value. It's not good or wrong. It's different.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655056076.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>I think the way cities are built and operated relate to each other. A given design promotes a certain management. Just like how the design of a saw alters how one can use it effectively, the design of a city requires it's users and administrators to act in certain ways. As for the assertion that US cities are functional, I think this is true, but almost tautological. If the city exists, it must "function." All cities where people live are "functional" insofar as people live there. What I'm asserting is that European cities generally outclass American ones objectively. I think European cities make choices such that the balance of costs/benefits is far greater than than here. Of course, you can get cheap gas in the US, and drive as much as you like. But this seems to be at the cost of generating massive economic barriers for minorities, the poor, and immigrants. It prevents the poor from accessing schools, jobs, and social resources of the rich. That I believe was the primary motivation for building without density. 

I don't think American cities developed out of "need" as much as greed. Real estate developers and land speculators have benefited far more than the average American by the design of American cities. Insofar as suburbia is the American way of life, then the American way of life began sometime after WW2. Most small American cities before the Great Depression had extensive transportation networks, including trolleys and trains. These were destroyed when auto-manufacturers bought them up, in order to replace them with bus systems, which have proven far more inefficient and less reliable from a development/investment perspective. 

You're right that most Americans are probably unaware that their urban form is environmentally destructive. While Americans may not be aware of it, but the way their cities are shaped are almost certainly destroying the environment. By necessity, each person in an urban center uses on average dramatically fewer resources than suburban dwellers, and this is especially highlighted when you contrast a European city with an American one. European cities are by design more likely to take advantage of passive solar heating. Fewer miles of road and water pipe must be maintained, and whatever maintenance is required is more efficient to pay for because it services more people. Buildings are heated more efficiently when they're closer together. Urban centers in the US built before WW2 were almost always built on a hilltop or some other raised area compared to the surrounding countryside, just as European ones were, because this area would be the least likely to flood. However, once this was occupied, sub-urbanization required moving into the valleys, deforesting the countryside, draining swamps, and destruction of wetlands- the very things that would prevent major flooding. Of course, it seems like most American cities understood this until the 50's and 60's where they started tearing up older parts (and usually minority neighborhoods) to install highways. 

Whether most Americans realize it or not, I think most cities were made a) to hurt the poor and minorities by creating capital thresholds for civic participation and social engagement and b) to speedily extract resources from the environment as quickly as possible, regardless of the consequences. Cities were built for Capital in America, it seems to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655502255.0" user="KilroysSports" delta="False">
    <text>You're ignoring the centuries of pollution European cities pumped into their surrounding ecosystems.  The Tiber River in Rome was a massive polluted sewer for most of the city's existence.  There's no telling what kind of environmental damage that caused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656202627.0" user="SconiGrower" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, pollution was rampant when European cities were young. But we barely understood disease, eutrophication, and environmental resources. Now we understand better and have better tools to deal with the pollution and yet the USA continues to produce more pollution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29664507337.0" user="KilroysSports" delta="False">
    <text>Really?  Because last I check European Cities polluted far worse than the average city in North America.

https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/12/science/who-says-europe-trails-us-in-reducing-air-pollution.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29664528589.0" user="SconiGrower" delta="False">
    <text>European cities do struggle with air pollution, however they also have greater population densities, as do the entire countries. On a per capita basis, the US is quite bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29664575172.0" user="KilroysSports" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't higher density make it easier to reduce pollution as resources can be shared across more people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29665006332.0" user="SconiGrower" delta="False">
    <text>That's why on a per capita basis, Europeans produce less pollution. But just by the simple fact that there are more of them means they produce more pollution. European cities are very dense, but that doesn't mean everyone takes public transit. Private cars causing heavy traffic is a common problem in large European cities.
And due to incomplete information during the policy making process, a great many of their vehicles are diesel, so that also contributes to their air pollution problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29665020360.0" user="KilroysSports" delta="False">
    <text>So maybe the design of European cities is encouraging rapid population growth, in turn creating more pollution?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29665137997.0" user="SconiGrower" delta="False">
    <text>Europeans are having children slower than people are dying. Across the EU, the birth rate is 1.6 births per woman. Flat population growth is somewhere around 2.1 births per woman. European cities are dense because they were built in a time before cars. Everyone had to walk where they wanted to go. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655675967.0" user="InvalidLusername" delta="False">
    <text>What does better mean? 
I guess you have some criteria in mind but you need to spell it out. Better for who? 
What are we minimizing/maximizing? Number of office buildings? Cinema? Commute time? Power consumption? Environment impact - on what dimension? 

European cities are not better on all dimensions. There are tradeoffs that are made, implicit or explicit</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
