<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29655283385.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones.

The opposite mate. This is **THE** main thing that Europeans are nevious of Americans. Is their cities who were built as a modern city from a get go.

European cities are old. Most if not all of them are older than US itself. Which meant they were built as "primitive" city centers from grounds up. Cities are swarming with ill shaped squigly roads, walkways, houses. You have trouble fitting anything in there, most canalization is awkward, and hard to upkeep. The street and house labelling is weird and often seemingly changes standards mid way, just because they have to adjust for all those incompatible exceptions, etc...

This is an example of Czech city [Prague](http://www.vidiani.com/maps/maps_of_europe/maps_of_czech_republic/prague/large_detailed_historical_map_of_prague_city.jpg). Yes, yes it's beutiful, and has it's charm. But then you look on city like [New york](https://i.pinimg.com/originals/14/04/2c/14042ce0d5ca59c88a47d33adcd49ca6.jpg) and you immediately understand what I mean. It's every architects wet dream. It's build for pourpose, large and wide roads for cars and trams. You can fit anything, anywhere with little to no problems. You can walk seemingly in straight line from one side to the other and you won't get lost.

There is a reason why European cities have such a good public transport. It's because you often flat out can't use cars in cities. And when we say public transport, we mean 10 differnt kinds of public transports, because there is no way in hell you could leave a tram, or rail, or even buss through most of it. Too small, too low, too uneaven, too narrow. That together with cars. And because those cities grew "organically" there is no space to put highways arround the cities. Not to buldoze over "priceless castles, and churches, villages, etc..." or belonging to one protection organization or the other. And the result you have cities with the worst traffic in the world, excluding the overpopulated Asian cities.

&amp;gt; Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. 

I have been to US. Not true at all. I mean yes it depends where you live and your culture and all that jazz. But it really is pretty much the same. There are things that are vastly better at US gatherings, and you have spaces for such. If there is big event in DC, you know where it will happen. If there is big event in any of the Europan cities. You just do that whenever is space. Which there often isn't, which is why none of them is REALLY happening.

&amp;gt;The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one

Again, European cities were here often for around 1000 years. That is some 700+ years head start at the very least to cultivate the productivity.  Most of easilly accessible natural resources were mined out before US was even founded. Which is why the "elite" moved into the cities and flourised from there. While in US there were incredible natural resources still untapped in modern era. A rural life flourished there first. There are so many historical factors to answer this one, none of which is the "cities" fault. But rather time in history fault.

&amp;gt; Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment.

Again, part of the environment for a really long time. 

&amp;gt; and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.

Do you know how many major houricanes or natural disasters were in Europe? During all of it's existence probably less than you have in US. Most of Europe is in the absolutely mildest climate you could ever imagine. No Earthquakes, no rainstorms, no huge icing, or snow. If you moved the same city in the location of some US cities. It would just stop working.




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656483839.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is THE main thing that Europeans are nevious of Americans. Is their cities who were built as a modern city from a get go.

Do you have a source for this claim? I see way more Europeans criticising the sterile, planned and sprawled out nature of American cities than I see yearning for a city where nowhere is walkable and cars are the privileged citizens.

&amp;gt;  There are things that are vastly better at US gatherings, and you have spaces for such. If there is big event in DC, you know where it will happen. If there is big event in any of the Europan cities. You just do that whenever is space. Which there often isn't, which is why none of them is REALLY happening.

I son't understand what you are trying to say here. No events happen in European cities because nobody knows where they would happen?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656602131.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you have a source for this claim?

The first part is my anecdotal evidence :D
The second is common knowledge. [Here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_planned_cities#United_States) you have list of planned cities. US has more planned cities than the entire Europe together. The population boom in those cities happened mostly after the advent of car and mass transport, so it changed entirely how the city looks and works.

&amp;gt; I see way more Europeans criticising the sterile, planned and sprawled out nature of American cities than I see yearning for a city where nowhere is walkable and cars are the privileged citizens.

Okay. I see ton of stuff being said about virtually anything. That means nothing :D. I cannot comment on how people **imagine** the ideal city should look like. And how many Europeans **prefer** European cities (surprise, surprise). What I can give you is only architectural opinion of why American cities are build as a cities. And function as such much more efficiently than European ones.

Viz me talking about traffic congestion, sewer maintanence, road repairs, etc...

&amp;gt;I son't understand what you are trying to say here. No events happen in European cities because nobody knows where they would happen?

Eh no. This was more of an offhand commend about a specific thing OP said. Europeans or at least people from my country don't really do these kinds of events. You know the big televised marches, protests, presidential adress,etc..
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
