<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29656736302.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>You can't separate the two- cultures built cities and cities shapes culture. So yes, they have cities that were not built for car, but so did we. Every single city across the world before the automobile was built to function without the presence of automobiles.

Of course- you can drive and car in European cities and American ones. But what was the cost of the "easy driving" for American cities?

Where did the room for inner-city highways, parking decks, and parking lots come from? We didn't build cities before the automobile with large empty tracts of land in close proximity to functioning and useful businesses. We built homes and factories and shops all within the distance appropriate for the technology we had (walking, trollies, trains, bikes). We destroyed hundreds of acres of our cities. We bulldozed thousands of homes and businesses, in order to make our cities more "car friendly." We bought up whole minority neighborhoods and crushed them beneath highways. 

To take as one example – the city of Winston-Salem in North Carolina. It was no big city, it was not "exceptional" in the 1910's- but it had 14 tramlines and more than 40 tramcars moving around the city. Then, to make room for cars in the 40s and 50s, like most American cities, the city tore up and shut down it's tram system.

The Europeans just decided that people were worth protecting more than cars, so they never took the time to destroy the homes, neighborhoods, businesses, buildings, and transit systems we did.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
