<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29656386638.0" user="ThePyCoder" delta="False">
    <text>Living in Belgium here. 


We don't really have cities anymore, more like continuous suburbs. It's a phenomenon called "lintbebouwing" or chainbuilding roughly translated. It's the idea that in other countries, like the US, you have a city then a bunch of roads in nature, then another city. 

We don't have that in Belgium. You never really leave the urban area, everything beside a road has been built on. It's not only ugly, it's bad for the environment and an absolute nightmare for urban planning. Houses aren't centralised and therefore this type of planning would simply not work in a much bigger country like America. 

And that's a bug argument: urban planning. 

The diameter of our country is barely 200km and only about 80% of the houses has a sewer connection (source: a course I'm having a re-examination of right now, but should look up more up to date figure). Energy, gas and Internet lines are the same. Everything is spread out but just barely close enough for everything to stay connected. 


There seems to be no clear reason for anything to be where it is. 


Then there is the road system. So many exceptions, special cases, weird roads and addresses that you can't even seem to find with a GPS. You guys could start fresh and used it well to build large spacious roads perpendicular to each other with clear names so that when you say I live on the Crossing of x and you street you know where it is. Everything is just so needlessly more complicated here with dead ends, streets split in 5 pieces with the housing numbering just laughable. 


And don't get me wrong, the bigger cities are beauties, but everything smaller... Churches aren't used here anymore but for the elderly mostly and therefore are just relics maybe used for better purposes. 


Even the placement of windmills and highways looks haphazard to me, everything breathes chaos, no planning involved. It has its charms yes, but it can be mayorly impractical at times... And ugly. 


I don't know man, but from my point of view our urban planning just looks like a mess made in the middle ages that nobody has bothered to break apart and start anew with. Everything existed already and as long as it doesn't pose a problem, the government just doesn't care. You can go from a brand-new silent asphalt road to a roman cobblestone road from centuries ago. 


I'll try to find a source but if I remember correctly Ibm once said it only wanted to test their smart city traffic systems in Belgium when they were 100% confident in it because they called Belgium the most difficult traffic in the world. Chokepoints everywhere as a result of renovating a road network that was built ages ago instead of starting over. 


Everything has its advantages and disadvantages and sure our countries with their heritage and all seem nice to people visiting, living in it on a daily basis brings on a whole new set of mainly practical problems. I didn't even touch the abdominal air quality as a result...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
