<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29655001372.0" user="LibertyTerp" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there.

Do you have any examples or evidence?

&amp;gt; Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history

Why would a small town have a major monument? I agree that more American cities should have "city centers". But I live in central Maryland and we have a ton. It seems like more are popping up every day. As far as history, there is historical stuff all over the place. Maybe you just don't find it as interesting? We do only have about 300 years of recorded history rather than thousands.

This is what main stream in a lot of small US cities looks like. I think it's nice: http://az616578.vo.msecnd.net/files/2017/01/27/636211377171180956-1589276188_4dfd714525ccd79c58b08f4bbef3a629.jpg

&amp;gt; In the US. there are few places to gather. 

This seems like a really exaggerated claim. There are numerous restaurants, movie theaters, parks, etc.

&amp;gt; The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities.

Do you have any examples or evidence?

&amp;gt; Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. 

Europe is almost completely white compared to the U.S. In the US you can be a first generation Chinese immigrant and everyone will consider you America. I have heard that that is not the case in Europe. That's one great thing about American cities.

&amp;gt; The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter.

Maybe in certain places, but in many other places that's not the case. It does seem like Europe has more interesting architecture, even though the US has tons of variety.

&amp;gt; People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European.

Is this not true in small European cities? I thought that's what we were talking about. Besides, I prefer getting around by car. It's 10 times faster. I don't have to carry shit on long walks. It's air conditioned. I have music. It's for transportation, not exercise, and it's far superior to walking as transportation.

&amp;gt; Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. 

This is factually wrong. The US is #3 in the world in productivity per hour behind only tiny Luxembourg and Norway. If US states were listed, they would dominate the rankings, including probably the top 10 in a row.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_GDP_(PPP)_per_hour_worked

&amp;gt; We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. 

Any evidence or examples?

&amp;gt; Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. 

What do you mean they're integrated into the environment?

&amp;gt; We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. 

Americans earn 40% more than Europeans on average, so we spend more on virtually everything because we have a lot more money. I'm actually surprised that Europeans aren't more outraged that they are so poor compared to the US and throwing out all their political leaders.

&amp;gt; Our food isn't as good quality. 

Maybe compared to Italy, but the US has fantastic food from all over the world.

&amp;gt; Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems. 

I don't think this is true at all.

&amp;gt; European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are.

The US has virtually no smog and has no problems due to rising seas except when a hurricane hits, which has been happening for millions of years.

&amp;gt; I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones.

It seems like you kind of generally dislike America and like Europe and this is just a personal preference rather than any kind of objective truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655112474.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>I thought this was were you change my view- I may have unjustified opinions. Y'all redditors were here to present evidence to challenge my view, and I don't think your questions count as evidence either. 

However- as to your remark on the poverty of Europeans: I'm absolutely shocked. Is it your view is that in general Americans get 40% more value from their labor than Europeans do? If so, that's remarkable. It seems to me that the opposite is true, but I'd love to see your evidence.

For all their wealth, Americans we get less free time and fewer vacations, and it seems to me like the ability to take time off work is a clear sign of wealth, because, you know, you're not working. It appears we can't afford things that Europeans can, providing healthcare to all citizens, making sure everyone can get an education, or providing decent maternity and paternity leave for new parents. For all that, we may still are the ones with "more earnings." Well, for all we Americans earn, they don't seem to be getting much out of it. Oh, except for a rising infant mortality rate. so there's that.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655156630.0" user="tydontkmow" delta="False">
    <text>Free healthcare in Europe is in part because of America, we do a lot of the research and development of drugs and treatments methods, so European countries don't have to front that bill. America also has a higher survival rate for practically every disease there is. We also have less wait times for seeing our doctors. Our healthcare system isn't perfect, but it's not the worst either. And to your point in time off and vacation, I work 40 hours/wk, three day weekends every weekend, plus 3.14 hours of vacation added every two weeks and paid holidays. Plus 24 hours of sick time every year, and every 4 months I get 8 hours PTO for being safe. I get a lot of free time with a full time job. Purely anecdotal, but I'm sure I'll not the only one in the US like this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655275693.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>Well, according to some reports, the US is pretty inefficent in its healthcare allocation. Perhaps Europe is getting some benefit from the US, but I did see anything cited. https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/infographics/most-efficient-health-care-around-the-world.html 

Wow! Three day weekends every weekend! That's spectacular! I've never heard of someone in the US having it that good! Really outstanding. 
I bet that you're in the top 1% of vacation-getters in the USA. Salary.com says that the average person who has worked for the same company for 15 years gets 21 days of vacation per year. Most European companies appear to give their citizens more than 20 days as a matter of course. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_minimum_annual_leave_by_country
http://www.salary.com/time-off-paid-time-off-from-work/
http://www.businessinsider.com/american-worker-less-vacation-medieval-peasant-2016-11</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655308064.0" user="tydontkmow" delta="False">
    <text>http://blogs.sciencemag.org/pipeline/archives/2010/11/09/where_drugs_come_from_by_country according to this just under half of all new drugs are being developed in America, paid for by American consumers. 118/257, the next countries have about 20 each. So that's a big help America is giving to the world. And like I said, our healthcare system is flawed, but it's not horrendous. I'd rather have a higher chance of survival than free healthcare. 



There's plenty of jobs out there that allow alternative work schedules that would get you three day weekends, I work 10 hour shifts Monday-Thursday. And like I said, that's purely anecdotal, there's people that get more and less vacation than me. But like someone said above, America is #3 when it comes to production, so it's a trade off. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655331984.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>Ok- Fair point with regards to the productivity tradeoff. Personally, I don't believe it's worth the trade-off to this degree, but I see you make good sense.

Getting back to City design- I think we could also produce more new drugs and have lower costs if our cities were shaped like European ones because people would be healthier all things considered when they walk more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655350545.0" user="tydontkmow" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I don't believe it's a good trade off for me as an individual, but if we're talking about for the good of the country (which I believe we are), it's a phenomenal trade off. We work more than other countries, but we produce a ton more as well, which boosts our economy. It's gotten us to the top of the world economically speaking. We have a 1/4 share in the entire world's economy, because we work more than others. 


European people also tend to live right on top of each other, I'd rather have space between my neighbors and I. I want to have a big backyard. You can't have the perks of living in small town America in Europe, well you can, but it's not as abundant. You can still walk places, or ride a bike, there's no reason you have to drive. 


A lot of European cities were built before trains and cars, so you had to walk everywhere. The rich would live in the interior of the cities so they wouldn't have to walk as far, while the poor lived in the exterior. While America, you had the same thing at first, but then trains came so the rich started living in suburbs, outside the cities. Then cars came and people could get around even better, so they started spreading out more. We have way more space to be able to spread out than most other countries in the world. 



Crime is probably another factor, crime rate in major cities are much higher in America than Europe, so people that could afford to leave and move outside the city, or farther away from people, did so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655567401.0" user="revvupthosefryers" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you answer everything so rude and sarcastically? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656756302.0" user="brocahantas" delta="False">
    <text>Because he's one of the posters who thinks his opinion is “right” and has made it clear that he isn’t here to have his view changed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656877354.0" user="iagainstiagainsti" delta="False">
    <text>A full week's work for a lot registered nurses is 32 hours. Same goes for nurse practitioners and lots of PAs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655417990.0" user="pbmonster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Free healthcare in Europe is in part because of America, we do a lot of the research and development of drugs and treatments methods, so European countries don't have to front that bill.

Why do you think that? It's not like an US company develops new medication and all the European Countries just make cheap copies and run with it. Europe respects US pharma patents. New and expensive drugs are expensive in Europe as well.

They're just by far not *as* expensive. But the reason is certainly not that American sick people already paid for it. The reason is that many European countries have public, non-profit health insurance systems that do collective bargaining when shopping for medication.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655445530.0" user="tydontkmow" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying they make cheap copies, but the US government plays a part in funding a lot of the r&amp;amp;d of these drugs. European governments don't have too. The fact that European governments or the insurance companies set reasonable prices for these drugs doesn't really have anything to do with it. So basically US taxpayers pay for part of the development of these drugs, and then pay again in order to use them, while European countries only have to pay to use them. I may be wrong, but that's how I understand it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655477237.0" user="pbmonster" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that cost is included when we talk about the cost of healthcare. People in the US pay a lot for healthcare - in insurance premiums and actual hospital bills. And we need to compare those costs with what people in Europe pay.

Government expenditure of tax money in research grants and subsidies come on top of that. Finding actual numbers about that is difficult, though. I would be very surprised if it's more than a couple of hundred of dollars per citizen per year, though (ballpark: the US spends around $1600 per citizen per year on defense - pharma research grants will probably be less than defense spending - which means it will be much less than average annual health insurance premiums). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655211717.0" user="Rielglowballelleit" delta="False">
    <text>As a reaction to the 40% more earning:


Was this measured before or after tax?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656682562.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>And was it measured before or after accounting for the benefits you get out of cheaper healthcare, higher quality public schooling, a police force that isn't trigger happy, superior public transport, and so on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656477790.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you have any examples or evidence?

[Nantes](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e1/Place-royale_nantes.jpg)

[Dresden](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/45/Dresden-nightpanorama-dri.jpg/1000px-Dresden-nightpanorama-dri.jpg) - bombed to oblivion by the RAF and USAAF and rebuilt after the war

[Maaseik](http://www.hotelroomsearch.net/im/city/maaseik-belgium-2.jpg) - a town of 25,000.

&amp;gt;Why would a small town have a major monument? 

Let's go back to [Maaseik's main square](http://www.hoteldemaaskant.be/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/maaseik.png). Why would a small town have a major monument? Because individual towns have centuries of history and their own identity and over the course of their time they have expressed that identity with monuments, statues, public art, etc. Maybe towns with &amp;lt;30,000 people have their own identities in the US as well but how do they express that? Maaseik has its own flag and coat of arms - does Blacksburg, Virginia have its own flag and coat of arms? 

&amp;gt;This is what main stream in a lot of small US cities looks like. I think it's nice: 

Where is that? Is that not just a "generic small town" with no unique or standout features that make you remember what it looks like? What's interesting or unique or memorable or aesthetically pleasing in any way about cities littered with strip malls and parking lots? [This is Little Rock](http://i.imgur.com/z726Do2.jpg) with parking lots highlighted.

&amp;gt;Is this not true in small European cities? I thought that's what we were talking about. Besides, I prefer getting around by car. It's 10 times faster. I don't have to carry shit on long walks. It's air conditioned. I have music. It's for transportation, not exercise, and it's far superior to walking as transportation.

You can live in pretty much any European city without even knowing how to drive a car. And as a result you don't have tragic scenes like [this](https://i.imgur.com/hfmNHTq.png). 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
