<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29655382450.0" user="shadowarc72" delta="False">
    <text>I do not agree that car travel makes us more unhealthy. I live in a city with extensive public transportation and I fail to see how sitting for an hour waiting and traveling on a bus is any different from traveling 15 minutes sitting in a car.

If you are talking car vs biking/walking. Biking in most smaller cities is more dangerous than driving because the cars are not prepared for bikes and people freak out.

And for both it is distance. It is 4 miles. Mostly uphill for me to get to class. It is average upper 80s to low 90s with 100% humidity where I live so if I were to walk or bike I would need a shower as soon as I got to class, not to mention the significant time increase. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656687445.0" user="twersx" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I live in a city with extensive public transportation and I fail to see how sitting for an hour waiting and traveling on a bus is any different from traveling 15 minutes sitting in a car.

You don't think it's remotely new information to say that cycling is more dangerous than driving because of cars do you? Like that's literally the entire reason cyclists want bike lanes and why they want more people to take up cycling so that people get used to them and don't freak out. Shock horror, sitting on a bike is more likely to lead to death than sitting inside several tonnes of metal. Cycling is less dangerous to everyone else.

&amp;gt;And for both it is distance. It is 4 miles. Mostly uphill for me to get to class. It is average upper 80s to low 90s with 100% humidity where I live so if I were to walk or bike I would need a shower as soon as I got to class, not to mention the significant time increase.

If you live more than 4 miles from your lectures at a European university you're doing university wrong. I live a 10 minute walk from my university and the furthest most people who go there ever live is a ~30 minute walk in first year. The point about European cities is that they are designed to be walkable, it's not some European predisposition to liking the idea of walking for an hour just to get to work or class. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29656915624.0" user="shadowarc72" delta="False">
    <text>I will conceded that more cyclist would potentially make the roads safer. But again my area is pretty cyclist heavy and it is still very dangerous, many bikers bike lanes etc.

I understand they were designed to be walkable I think a lot of that comes from the fact that a lot of them grew organically. Also 4 miles is a close number for most of the things I do. My uncle drives 40 miles to work each day, my sister drives 10, my wife drives 7. Things here are just more spread out I guess even in areas that are more keen on walking. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
