<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29655429737.0" user="Less3r" delta="False">
    <text>So, me being myself and you being you, we seem to have different perspectives here, where many of the things you're saying are not obvious to me. So your view is your view, but I naturally question some of the statements you've made.

For us to arrive at a universal answer, some research needs to be done. However, few of us have good time for that, and I googled a few things and didn't find much. So, let's talk around some concepts.

I notice there are a few conflicting statements, here.

"The typical/average American city is awful by any objective comparison."

So then why do you list things that are subjectively determined?

* No major monuments or sense of history

* Architecture looks cookie-cutter

* Quickly gets dated in the way of art

These could all be seen as "a waste" in a certain objective comparison, say "what time, effort, and money is spent on", where money would best go to other things like helping the poor. Now, if as you claim, European cities are more productive, then you can't knock off American cities as being "terribly administered" comparatively, if the administration doesn't have an equal amount of money.

Now also, I ask where are you getting all of this information.

* The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities

* People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average european.

* The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one

The purpose of cities is to be more productive, have people live closer to work (not have to drive), and get to be with each other more.

* Many European cities are built integrated into their environment

Where did you get this information from? I'm not quite sure what "built integrated into their environment" could mean, since cities usually replace environment. Unless you're talking about not cutting down hills, in which case, flatter cities are more easily traversed.

* Our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to european water management systems

Again, where is the information from? I can't find anything supporting either one being better.

* Despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average

If European cities are more productive and thus wealthy, then this likely is the case *because* of their productivity, not "despite" productivity. Same goes for Art, Social Life.

* Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic

What does "often" mean here? Number of cities? How often the levels reach a certain amount?

* Our food isn't as good quality

Is this really a city issue, or American culture issue? Which are you getting at?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
