<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419387628.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xoxkc/cmv_euthanasia_for_terminally_ill_or_chronically/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia for terminally ill or chronically ill patients should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>KvotheOfTheHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>When the quality of life of our beloved pets drops it is considered humane to put them down, meanwhile, when the quality of life of a person drops, even they ask for it, many think it is wrong to let them die. 

First of all, I believe that a person who requests to die most answer the following (and reasonable) criteria:

* Has a terminal/incurable illness 

* Sound of mind and is not under outside pressure to make this decision (Including a psychology examination to conclude that)

* Their quality of life is objectively extremely poor and is not expected to get better

I think that if in the future I will contract a deadly disease which would leave me in pain and the when I know that there is no cure I would love to know that I have the *option* of ending it all. It is my life and unlike regular suicide, it is not a selfish act. I'm going to die soon anyway, and personally, I might prefer that my family will remember me as an independent strong person rather than a needy patient.

Even if I have a couple years, everyone has a different pain tolerance and maybe a level of pain that YOU can withstand is not a level of pain someone else could. Could you imagine living day after day with insufferable pain? Lying in your hospital bed at night, possibly alone, having to *feel* enormous pain throughout your entire body after each single breath you take? 

For others, there are worst things than pain or death. Some parents would not want their children or family see them suffer. A father may know that he is a hero in his child's eyes. The only other thing than seeing your hero dying is seeing his suffer without the ability to help himself. Could you try and put yourself in that father's position? 

And the important thing to remember is, I'm not saying that every terminally ill patient should be euthanized, I'm just saying that if that person answers the requirements above, they could make that choice for themselves.
Here are some of the more popular reasons and my answers to them:

**There are miracles in the world! And Also sometimes doctors make mistakes**  
Yes, there are some inexplicable "miracles" and human errors, however, this is not a common enough occurrence to even consider as a point! It would be the equivalent of telling the power company not to cut your power out because you just bought a lottery ticket and there is a chance that you will win. 

**Poor people would be in disadvantage because suicide is cheaper than end of life treatment**  
This one is simple enough. Most developed countries have free healthcare so it is not really an issue, and those which do not, are not obligated to offer euthanasia for cheap. Second or even third opinions should be gathered from doctors before taking the step, as well as a psychological evaluation and probably a board of directors to review all the information gathered and approve the request. The prices can add up really quickly.

**Corporate interests could push people into assisted suicide because it is cheaper than treating an illness**  
This point only applies to America. Most of the developed world doesn't have that problem. I'm arguing that it should be a human right. As far as I care, it can still be outlawed in the States until they fix their very broken welfare system meanwhile being OK in most of the developed world. 
 
**It is against Hippocratic Oath for euthanize patients/it is not ethical for doctors to do it**  
I agree. We should not expect doctors to "pull the trigger". There should be specially trained people to commit this task, much like some prisons use for executions. 

That's all I could think on on my own. Please change my view. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29666177641.0" user="SalientScotsman" delta="False">
    <text>My problem with Euthanasia isn't so much with the idea of someone in incredible pain or incapacity wanting to end their life, but rather what policy could occur afterwards.

Ok, I disagree with Euthanasia on any level on principle, and don't think that a policy of any degree which legitimises death is a positive step forward for the human race. That being said, I do understand that people feel differently and many of these individuals would question my capacity to comment on the mental state of individuals e.g. That are paralysed from the neck down. I can begin to understand how horrific a situation that would be, and understand WHY someone would feel like suicide is a way out, but I don't agree with it. 

My main issue lies with how legalisation would impact future policy decisions. We live in a world where mental health is being progressively viewed more and more as akin to some physical conditions in terms of severity in a medical context, and rightfully so. For the Euthanasia debate this comes at a cost. In actual fact, in finding this thread I scrolled past a similar question asking if suicide was the same debate as Euthanasia. I think that if euthanasia was legalised, it would normalise the notion of ending one's life when in a place of extreme suffering, and having the support of the state to do so.

What happens when Joe Bloggs wants to kill himself because of his Depression? Is that ok too? Where does the line get drawn in terms of severity of what you're going through? Further, if it is a case of an unconscious or "brain-dead" individual, how does one legally tease apart the "caring" from the straight-up murderers? Could this not be taken advantage of? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
