<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419387628.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xoxkc/cmv_euthanasia_for_terminally_ill_or_chronically/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia for terminally ill or chronically ill patients should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>KvotheOfTheHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>When the quality of life of our beloved pets drops it is considered humane to put them down, meanwhile, when the quality of life of a person drops, even they ask for it, many think it is wrong to let them die. 

First of all, I believe that a person who requests to die most answer the following (and reasonable) criteria:

* Has a terminal/incurable illness 

* Sound of mind and is not under outside pressure to make this decision (Including a psychology examination to conclude that)

* Their quality of life is objectively extremely poor and is not expected to get better

I think that if in the future I will contract a deadly disease which would leave me in pain and the when I know that there is no cure I would love to know that I have the *option* of ending it all. It is my life and unlike regular suicide, it is not a selfish act. I'm going to die soon anyway, and personally, I might prefer that my family will remember me as an independent strong person rather than a needy patient.

Even if I have a couple years, everyone has a different pain tolerance and maybe a level of pain that YOU can withstand is not a level of pain someone else could. Could you imagine living day after day with insufferable pain? Lying in your hospital bed at night, possibly alone, having to *feel* enormous pain throughout your entire body after each single breath you take? 

For others, there are worst things than pain or death. Some parents would not want their children or family see them suffer. A father may know that he is a hero in his child's eyes. The only other thing than seeing your hero dying is seeing his suffer without the ability to help himself. Could you try and put yourself in that father's position? 

And the important thing to remember is, I'm not saying that every terminally ill patient should be euthanized, I'm just saying that if that person answers the requirements above, they could make that choice for themselves.
Here are some of the more popular reasons and my answers to them:

**There are miracles in the world! And Also sometimes doctors make mistakes**  
Yes, there are some inexplicable "miracles" and human errors, however, this is not a common enough occurrence to even consider as a point! It would be the equivalent of telling the power company not to cut your power out because you just bought a lottery ticket and there is a chance that you will win. 

**Poor people would be in disadvantage because suicide is cheaper than end of life treatment**  
This one is simple enough. Most developed countries have free healthcare so it is not really an issue, and those which do not, are not obligated to offer euthanasia for cheap. Second or even third opinions should be gathered from doctors before taking the step, as well as a psychological evaluation and probably a board of directors to review all the information gathered and approve the request. The prices can add up really quickly.

**Corporate interests could push people into assisted suicide because it is cheaper than treating an illness**  
This point only applies to America. Most of the developed world doesn't have that problem. I'm arguing that it should be a human right. As far as I care, it can still be outlawed in the States until they fix their very broken welfare system meanwhile being OK in most of the developed world. 
 
**It is against Hippocratic Oath for euthanize patients/it is not ethical for doctors to do it**  
I agree. We should not expect doctors to "pull the trigger". There should be specially trained people to commit this task, much like some prisons use for executions. 

That's all I could think on on my own. Please change my view. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29658008982.0" user="jobojosephine" delta="False">
    <text>SHOULD BE ILLEGAL?
Let's look at some different ethical theories.

Perhaps we should look at Kantian ethics here. Kant says that an action is only moral if you can universalise it. Could we universalise euthanasia? This would be in the sense that everyone who wanted to die, could. I don't think we could. It would cause chaos and perhaps emotional harm that would lead to further suicides.

Legalisation could also mean the extension of even more medical ethical boundaries. Someone doesn't think they could ever be happy in a wheelchair? Euthanasia. Someone cannot cope with an emotional trauma? Euthanasia. Perhaps it could incur a domino effect. 

We could also look at Joseph Fletchers' situation ethics. This is actually more positive about euthanasia. It says we should look at the situation and decide whether it is the right thing to do at that specific time. Although this could be in favour of euthanasia, it's not a solid guideline for making these decisions. 

Utilitarian ethics may shed more light. It says that an act is ethically good if it brings more pleasure than pain. Or another way of thinking about it is whether it pleases more people than it displeases. In this case, it may only suit the individual and hurt the family members who are stricken with grief. But it could also suit the family members who cannot care for the individual anymore. So it does require context to be used as an ethical guideline. 

One last thought to consider, what if, just after you take the pill and ate euthanised, they find a cure. It may not seem likely, but many things are improbable yet still happen. It is perhaps a silly way to think but just food for thought. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29658918519.0" user="miche1angelo" delta="False">
    <text>Watching people grasping for intellectual straws (and the good 'ole Kantian argument, might as well brought the veil of ignorance in too) to rationalize is always fun.  
Simply remember there are 7 billion? 8 billion? people in this world. Assuming a suicide rate of 1/100 and there will still be more humans than needed.  It's not like we're gonna run out of people--</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29658919467.0" user="jobojosephine" delta="False">
    <text>Haha not really grasping, I study it in school and it helps to talk about arguments and get involved in debate. A sort of revision. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29659754195.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662764737.0" user="NoThanksCommonSense" delta="False">
    <text>Please stop defacing Kant. 

Kant doesn't tell you what moral actions are, he explains to you how you come up with your own moral actions. He provides a framework for which you can objectively analyze what morality is in itself. In consequence to this, you can only really use Kant as a logical consistency check, not to determine what is or isn't moral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662767335.0" user="jobojosephine" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I know that lol
Your point??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662799314.0" user="NoThanksCommonSense" delta="False">
    <text>Point? I'm asking you a favor, to stop defacing Kant. 

Either you are defacing him intentionally, or you are not concise enough with your language, or you don't understand Kant; either way please stop. What you are doing isn't beneficial to anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
