<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419387628.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xoxkc/cmv_euthanasia_for_terminally_ill_or_chronically/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia for terminally ill or chronically ill patients should be legal</title>
    <original_poster>KvotheOfTheHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>When the quality of life of our beloved pets drops it is considered humane to put them down, meanwhile, when the quality of life of a person drops, even they ask for it, many think it is wrong to let them die. 

First of all, I believe that a person who requests to die most answer the following (and reasonable) criteria:

* Has a terminal/incurable illness 

* Sound of mind and is not under outside pressure to make this decision (Including a psychology examination to conclude that)

* Their quality of life is objectively extremely poor and is not expected to get better

I think that if in the future I will contract a deadly disease which would leave me in pain and the when I know that there is no cure I would love to know that I have the *option* of ending it all. It is my life and unlike regular suicide, it is not a selfish act. I'm going to die soon anyway, and personally, I might prefer that my family will remember me as an independent strong person rather than a needy patient.

Even if I have a couple years, everyone has a different pain tolerance and maybe a level of pain that YOU can withstand is not a level of pain someone else could. Could you imagine living day after day with insufferable pain? Lying in your hospital bed at night, possibly alone, having to *feel* enormous pain throughout your entire body after each single breath you take? 

For others, there are worst things than pain or death. Some parents would not want their children or family see them suffer. A father may know that he is a hero in his child's eyes. The only other thing than seeing your hero dying is seeing his suffer without the ability to help himself. Could you try and put yourself in that father's position? 

And the important thing to remember is, I'm not saying that every terminally ill patient should be euthanized, I'm just saying that if that person answers the requirements above, they could make that choice for themselves.
Here are some of the more popular reasons and my answers to them:

**There are miracles in the world! And Also sometimes doctors make mistakes**  
Yes, there are some inexplicable "miracles" and human errors, however, this is not a common enough occurrence to even consider as a point! It would be the equivalent of telling the power company not to cut your power out because you just bought a lottery ticket and there is a chance that you will win. 

**Poor people would be in disadvantage because suicide is cheaper than end of life treatment**  
This one is simple enough. Most developed countries have free healthcare so it is not really an issue, and those which do not, are not obligated to offer euthanasia for cheap. Second or even third opinions should be gathered from doctors before taking the step, as well as a psychological evaluation and probably a board of directors to review all the information gathered and approve the request. The prices can add up really quickly.

**Corporate interests could push people into assisted suicide because it is cheaper than treating an illness**  
This point only applies to America. Most of the developed world doesn't have that problem. I'm arguing that it should be a human right. As far as I care, it can still be outlawed in the States until they fix their very broken welfare system meanwhile being OK in most of the developed world. 
 
**It is against Hippocratic Oath for euthanize patients/it is not ethical for doctors to do it**  
I agree. We should not expect doctors to "pull the trigger". There should be specially trained people to commit this task, much like some prisons use for executions. 

That's all I could think on on my own. Please change my view. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29657625640.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>the problem with euthanasia is that it takes its toll on other people, sure the target doesn't have to live with the consequences but the one preforming it does.

if someone is stable enough to give consent they should simply add a knife to the room,  if the target really wants to die he can slit his own throat, no help needed, if he doesn't then he doesn't really want to die he simply wants the pain to stop.

killing yourself is extremely easy if you really want to, most simply don't really want to, so they give the choice out of their hand and stain an others hand with blood</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657640096.0" user="skepticetoh" delta="False">
    <text>For chronically ill patients the one that delivers the medicine has blood on their hands? How so? 

What is wrong with letting someone die peacefully?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657679508.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>people can kill themselves peacefully, as long as they don't drag others into it,  its not them dying i have a problem with, its forcing others to do it for them.  

and with it legal it means there have to be people to preform it.  

if someone fears death more then pain then he should bear the pain, if he fears pain more then death he should not have a problem ending his own.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657721489.0" user="KvotheOfTheHill" delta="False">
    <text>I've already present proofs that people are not "dragged" into it. There are willing people who would do it as a day job. 

No one is forced to kill another person. People do it because they want too. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657722238.0" user="lekanto" delta="False">
    <text>They may not be physically able to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657759132.0" user="skepticetoh" delta="False">
    <text>Who is being forced to deliver the medication?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657649500.0" user="KvotheOfTheHill" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the problem with euthanasia is that it takes its toll on other people, sure the target doesn't have to live with the consequences but the one preforming it does

There are already volunteers who inject deadly injections to death penalty inmates. For example, [Stark prison](http://www.dc.state.fl.us/oth/deathrow/) in FL pays $150 to civilians to execute a prisoner.

Additionally, it is undignified to let someone kill himself with a knife. Euthanasia is unpleasant for everyone involved but at least this way the person gets to say goodbye to his family and gets a painless death. And do not forget about failed suicide attempts! Not only the doctors may be able to save the person, the attempt could leave him worse than before with even more pain. 

E:
And forgot to add to my last point- Think how hard it is to decide to kill yourself. It is not easy, even when you're sure you're dying anyway. If the first suicide attempt fails, think how hard it would be to make that decision twice! Or possibly trice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657742783.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>that's something i also consider unethical,  but the knife was simply an example of a quick way to do it, and lets not forget that someone committing suicide can also say goodbye.

a doctor may be able to safe a person if they do it with hesitation, but many options exist that make it early impossible. 

and of course deciding to kill yourself is a hard decision, but that's irrelevant as both courses require that decision, 

a gunshot to the brain is near instant, by the time pain reaches the brain the brain matter is already splattered on the wall, but still most people hesitate, its not because it would hurt, that's what they are killing themselves to avoid, its the choice to actually do it that they can't accept. consciously or subconsciously.   

and if they can't accept death they should not try to seek it anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657754954.0" user="KvotheOfTheHill" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that acceptance = willing to commit it by yourself. 

It might, but it should not a requirement. 

We've already established that people will willingly assist a person to commit suicide. It is happening already, like my example above!  
Now assuming a person decided they want to die, why force them to do it themselves? Why add pressure to the decision? The decision was made already, professionals reviewed it and signed off on it. Why trouble the patient with questions like how to die? What would be painless? Who will find them? How to get a gun?

And what happens if a doctor stops them or god forbids save them? aren't the dying patiences have enough on their mind already? 

Edit- and also, giving patiences an established way to commit suicide can eliminate unwanted suicide attempts. We don't want people who are troubled by their financial situation killing themselves. Just saying "those who want it bad enough will find a way" is wrong! There is no control, no peer reviews. 

Giving them an established way prevents people from making the wrong decision and just gives those in dire need the option and means to do it peacefully.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657858487.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>and given that it already happens they do not have to make it legal,  the person killing another should accept jail time for his murder,

the decision to die is the most important decision you can and will ever make, its one you need to be behind 100% as it is irreversible, also you don't thing having someone psychologically screened adds pressure?

being suicidal doesn't make a person a moron, its quite common for them to call the police or other friend/families to ensure who finds the body. not to mention if you haven't even though about how your going to do it you haven't given it enough though. 

its not like people won't know either way he/she killed herself, not to mention that your overestimating the difficulty of suicide  an empty needle filled with air into one of your arteries could do it. 

and those who choose to commit suicide usually do it in a emotional mindset not a logical one, thus someone on a tall building would sooner leap of then go through the legal channels.

and if you look online their are plenty of decent sites that show the proper way to kill yourself, not to mention many chemicals have handy dandy this kills people if drank stickers.

and again if people don't even put in the effort to find a suicide method that suits them are they really prepared and accepting of their fate.

hell even thousands of years ago they managed to find peaceful ways to die (hemlock for example) pretending that someone else administering something is the only way to die peaceful is nonsense

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657863282.0" user="KvotheOfTheHill" delta="False">
    <text>Have you even read my previous replies?

I gave an example how the STATE of FLORIDA is paying individuals to kill others. Legally.

I do not understand why you believe they should serve jail time, and it is not murder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657917038.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>yes, but the legality doesn't make it right, or you wouldn't consider making euthanasia legal.

and just because you use another word for it doesn't change what it is at the basis, (sure they may not receive the same length as someone who murders a random person, but they should still receive it.)

and its because the end result is the same, you killed someone because you choose to do so.

just wondering do you belief in life after death? 

(i don't ) so i base my ethics more around the value of life and acceptance of consequences both my own and that of others.

would you help euthanize a stranger if you knew you would be caught and sentenced?


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657960439.0" user="KvotheOfTheHill" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying that killing someone no matter why is immoral. 

Then please tell me why the specific reason I laid above is immoral. Saying "it is simply immoral" is not enough. 

All you've been able to say until now is that it affects other people. I've proved that other people do it happily. 

Please correct me if I'm wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29657688331.0" user="ymiad" delta="False">
    <text>That's completely backward and displays a lack of understanding about what this process looks like. Killing yourself is easy, but that's not the point; it's not about killing yourself. It's about being able to make a choice to end your own life in a way that isn't traumatic and terrible, like pulling the trigger into your own head or slitting your own throat. That's the entire reason that consensual euthanasia needs to be legal; I don't know anyone who thinks it'd be better to come home to find their terminally ill mom or dad hanging from a rope by their neck than to be there with and for their parent as they ended their own suffering in a way that didn't make them suffer even more. It's not like they hire someone to come in and strangle them; a medical practitioner is the one who administers all medications and has a very strong bond with the patient already. It's not 'blood on their hands'. It's a professional who took an oath to uphold the dignity of their patients and to provide the best care possible, and forcing someone in agony to ride out their own excruciating death for weeks or months or years is so much more harmful.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
