<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419976488.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6y1jxk/cmv_municipalities_should_not_hold_easily/">
    <title>CMV: Municipalities should not hold easily politicized elections for apolitical positions like sheriff.</title>
    <original_poster>pr0crasturbatin</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see a lot about sheriffs being appointed through local elections, even seeing people wearing tshirts that say "Re-elect [sheriff's name] for [county name] county sheriff". But to me that seems to politicize a position that is one of considerable power to enforce the law in the area. By politicizing that, a sheriff is able to impose a political agenda to the point where it is literally able to be enforced at gunpoint, and can appoint deputies that align with them. While it makes towns essentially an absolute in terms of political alignment, it also insulates them to changes going on around them, including in surrounding towns or cities, and ultimately stifles progress and lets them get away with things that regular public officials wouldn't get away with because they are essentially their own oversight committee, like we saw with Joe Arpaio.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29662161378.0" user="great_bob" delta="False">
    <text>There are, of course, numerous sheriffs out there who reflect poorly on the choices of the communities they serve. That being said, is there really a problem with the selection process itself? Are there benefits from it?

As much as it's a pleasant thought to say that we are a nation of laws, the truth is that laws are written by people, and people can be fallible. There have been times when the election of public servants, such as sheriffs, can be a powerful tool for the voters. One example would be during the days of prohibition. Here's a national law enacted by a majority, and forced upon communities where the majority felt otherwise. Across regions of the Northeast, voters elected sheriffs who would turn a blind eye to the flow of booze. 

I would also use the example of sheriffs in Pennsylvania and New York who chose not to follow the Dredd Scott decision, and allowed fugitive slaves a chance to escape to freedom. 

There's that old cliche' that says that Democracy is the worst form of government, except for everything else. It's a cliche, however, because it's also true.

A professional ruling class may not be swayed by the will of the mob, but by the same token they could never reflect the will of the people either.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
