<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419976488.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6y1jxk/cmv_municipalities_should_not_hold_easily/">
    <title>CMV: Municipalities should not hold easily politicized elections for apolitical positions like sheriff.</title>
    <original_poster>pr0crasturbatin</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see a lot about sheriffs being appointed through local elections, even seeing people wearing tshirts that say "Re-elect [sheriff's name] for [county name] county sheriff". But to me that seems to politicize a position that is one of considerable power to enforce the law in the area. By politicizing that, a sheriff is able to impose a political agenda to the point where it is literally able to be enforced at gunpoint, and can appoint deputies that align with them. While it makes towns essentially an absolute in terms of political alignment, it also insulates them to changes going on around them, including in surrounding towns or cities, and ultimately stifles progress and lets them get away with things that regular public officials wouldn't get away with because they are essentially their own oversight committee, like we saw with Joe Arpaio.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29664094909.0" user="eDgEIN708" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; While it makes towns essentially an absolute in terms of political alignment, it also insulates them to changes going on around them, including in surrounding towns or cities,

So? Really, though, so what? It insulates them to changes, but how is such resistance to change a negative? If all of the surrounding towns decide to be lenient on drug use, is it a negative for a town to be resistant to that change just because the surrounding towns have done it? If all your friends jumped off a bridge, would *you*?

The benefits and drawbacks of insulation from change is completely dependent on the kinds of change you're trying to insulate yourself from and your reason behind it, which is the result of the individual being elected and the people electing them, and is *not* indicative of a problem with the system itself. 


&amp;gt; and ultimately stifles progress 

What progress are you talking about? It seems to me, given the example you cited, that the issue here might be that you simply don't approve of the fact that some people don't subscribe to your definition of "progress", and you'd prefer to limit their ability to choose someone who doesn't share your values. That's an affront to democracy - the people should *absolutely* be free to choose someone who opposes "progress" if they disagree with your definition of the term.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
