<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419976488.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6y1jxk/cmv_municipalities_should_not_hold_easily/">
    <title>CMV: Municipalities should not hold easily politicized elections for apolitical positions like sheriff.</title>
    <original_poster>pr0crasturbatin</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see a lot about sheriffs being appointed through local elections, even seeing people wearing tshirts that say "Re-elect [sheriff's name] for [county name] county sheriff". But to me that seems to politicize a position that is one of considerable power to enforce the law in the area. By politicizing that, a sheriff is able to impose a political agenda to the point where it is literally able to be enforced at gunpoint, and can appoint deputies that align with them. While it makes towns essentially an absolute in terms of political alignment, it also insulates them to changes going on around them, including in surrounding towns or cities, and ultimately stifles progress and lets them get away with things that regular public officials wouldn't get away with because they are essentially their own oversight committee, like we saw with Joe Arpaio.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29662483542.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Arpaio's horrible, no doubt. But, unfortunately, sheriff *is* a political position. How much of the law to actively enforce, and when, and why, and for whom are all intrinsically political questions.

It would be wonderful if we could have just exactly the "correct" number of laws and exactly the necessary resources to enforce those. But, that's not possible, because lawmaking itself is a (in some ways, the quintessential) political activity.

Once you pile up enough laws (from overlapping jurisdictions, too: from municipal up to federal) it becomes completely impossible (and even undesirable, in many cases!) to actively enforce them all.

Sheriff is an intrinsically political position because it is the position, at a county level, responsible for prioritizing the different elements of the legal system (not just which laws and why, etc., though certainly that, but how best to manage lawbreakers and even how best to reduce lawbreaking [which is part of what speed traps are for, for instance]).

I actually agree with the *preference* articulated in your CMV, but my point is that it's an *impossible preference*. There's no way, in a complex society, for sheriff to *not* be a political role. We have to be able to continue electing sheriffs for all the same basic reasons that we have to be able to continue electing presidents (each is a sort of executive officer), unless you want to get rid of counties altogether (but that would be a separate CMV).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662543917.0" user="monty845" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it is impossible to tailor our laws so they are designed to be fully enforced. You are absolutely right that our laws are not tailored that way today, and that discretion (which should reflect the political will of the community through politics) is an unavoidable necessity today. But we could change the laws, and remove the prohibition on things things that we generally don't want prosecuted, and move discretion to be more about analyzing the facts, and less about the morality in particular cases. 

All that discretion can be very harmful to democracy, when it is used to target people for the wrong reasons. The whole notion of "Show Me The Man And I'll Find You The Crime" really shouldn't be so, and its a major flaw that it largely is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662563905.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Speaking from a U.S. point of view, tailoring laws so that they would be designed for full enforcement is (with our distributed system of governance) a genuine impossibility. Different kinds of jurisdictions prioritize different kinds of things, and you inevitably end up with legal instruments that--at the very least--exceed the scope of enforcement at the level of county policing.

I mean, I'd like to see much less discretion than we currently have, and I think that would be achievable by creating genuine mechanisms for holding police (both individually and institutionally) accountable for their behaviors. The mechanisms we have for that thus far are laughably inadequate, amounting to little more than community input boards (typically run by the people who are most heavily invested in existing structures anyhow). My sense is that diminishing routine abuses of discretion by increasing accountability is possible, and that over the long haul this would drive change in the amount of discretion that's regarded as normal, too.

But, just streamlining the legal system and becoming a real democracy--much as I profoundly agree that we should do this, and maybe even can over the long haul or when we rebuild after the coming catastrophe, or maybe on Mars--is no simple matter. It's not even simple conceptually, and it's exponentially less simple politically.

Which is why, for now, the democratic possibility of elected sheriffs (though routinely abused and traduced, like the rest of our shitty, pseudo-democratic system) is not a good thing to try to do away with, but rather something to come at from the sides (as suggested above).

Regardless, of course, going back to the OP, a sheriff in anything like the current legal environment of the U.S. will continue to be a political position. I'm all for changing that system large-scale, but it's not realistic to say that this one element of the system should be different. It can't be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29663250233.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>By this logic, everything the government does is political. Anything that touches policy is political. Do you think this is a fair assessment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29663489371.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>That's not the extension of this logic, which foregrounds the impossibility of yanking apoliticality out of the forest of competing legislation.

But, yes, broadly, anything that touches policy is political. For better and for worse. It's why, for instance, the U.S. has the dumbest climate policy and some of the weakest environmental regulations in the developed world. There are tradeoffs there, and the people who have been winning those political battles have interests firmly on the other side of those tradeoffs. That would still be true, however, if we were making what someone like me could account good policy. It's just that "our" tradeoffs (which I sincerely think are the smartest ones--folks on opposing political sides often do, though of course there's plenty of self-interest in the mix, too) would then be the political winners.

Policy is political if it has third-party ramifications, i.e., if it has impacts that extend beyond merely those who are direct parties to the making of policy.

That's why we're willing to say that many private contracts are not political (or not in a strong sense).

The fact that policy is always political, though, doesn't mean that all policy arenas are *equally* politically contentious. That varies widely.

The balancing of multiple layers of law, with limited resources, with and against the legitimate concerns of and enshrined protections for those affected in a given geopolitical unit is *intensively* political. And that's what sheriffs are for (shitty as many of them are at it, which is a separate concern).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29663846072.0" user="pbmonster" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic, chiefs of police, all judges (only some are elected, some are appointed) and the head of the FBI should also be chosen in direct elections, no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29665001244.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>No. I'm not weighing in strongly on the first part of OP's position, but rather attack the second part (the core premise that positions like sheriff are "apolitical").

I don't claim to know the best way to fill all political positions, certainly not enough to take a one-size-fits-all on the crazy patchwork hodgepodge quilt of approaches we have across the U.S. So, I'm not saying that every political position should be electorally contested; that's an unwarranted extension of my position.

My argument was primarily intended to show that sheriff *is* very much a political, not an apolitical position (i.e., to demonstrate that the CMV was based on a bad premise). Secondarily, and this is where I do speak to the CMV's first part, the conclusion OP had reached, I think it's probably not a good idea to pick individual positions and make them non-electoral without having a clear and consistent justification for doing so.

In other words, since the premise of the CMV was shown to be false, its conclusion doesn't follow. We *might* indeed want to change the way we select sheriffs (and any other number of political positions), but once the organizing assumption of this particular way of thinking about doing so is shown to be false, that ceases to be an immediately live concern.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
