<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419976488.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6y1jxk/cmv_municipalities_should_not_hold_easily/">
    <title>CMV: Municipalities should not hold easily politicized elections for apolitical positions like sheriff.</title>
    <original_poster>pr0crasturbatin</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see a lot about sheriffs being appointed through local elections, even seeing people wearing tshirts that say "Re-elect [sheriff's name] for [county name] county sheriff". But to me that seems to politicize a position that is one of considerable power to enforce the law in the area. By politicizing that, a sheriff is able to impose a political agenda to the point where it is literally able to be enforced at gunpoint, and can appoint deputies that align with them. While it makes towns essentially an absolute in terms of political alignment, it also insulates them to changes going on around them, including in surrounding towns or cities, and ultimately stifles progress and lets them get away with things that regular public officials wouldn't get away with because they are essentially their own oversight committee, like we saw with Joe Arpaio.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29661989515.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>If you oppose electing sheriffs, what is your alternative proposal for filling the job?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662004192.0" user="pr0crasturbatin" delta="False">
    <text>I had been thinking about that after posting, actually, and I think the best alternative I could come up with is to have the circuit judge for their jurisdiction appoint them. I don't think gubernatorial appointing would be a great way to do it either, because that's again too easily politicized, (see Blazing Saddles as a mostly joking example, but imagine Rick Perry or Scott Walker having that level of control over their localities' governments) and usually federal judges are more insulated politically than governors, so I think it would be a pretty effective solution. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662031532.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>But sheriffs are state or local employees, generally charged with enforcing state and local laws, not federal ones.


Having federal judges appointing state sheriffs would be a conflict of interest.  For example, consider a federal judge appointing an anti-marijuana sheriff in places that have legalized it at the state level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29663389199.0" user="comfortablesexuality" delta="False">
    <text>circuit judges are the lowest of the state court system though, not federal? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29663975467.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>From the context of his previous post, it seems pretty clear he is talking about federal circuit judges.  See the line

&amp;gt; usually federal judges are more insulated politically than governors, so I think it would be a pretty effective solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662050107.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Sheriffs are County employees who enforce state and local laws. They are not federal employees or in charge of enforcing federal law. It is completely inappropriate for a Federal Judge, or any federal position to appoint them. That fundamentally violates State's rights. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662516519.0" user="ibpod" delta="False">
    <text>Ehh i honestly feel like ive seen more idgaf biased judges then sheriffs but maybe not</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29664518578.0" user="UEMcGill" delta="False">
    <text>On a federal level there's a separation of powers.  The judicial branch is separate from the executive.  This is to have checks and balances.

At least with a sheriff being accountable to voters they can choose to vote him out of office.  But if he was accountable to judges there maybe a perverse incentive to enforce judicial preference.  What would you do with a judge who litigates from the bench?

"Go arrest that man for calling me a tyrant because it's contempt of court.  Or I'll find someone to replace you."

In my town the police department is a professional group, hired by the town council and administered by the city manager.  (Weak mayor system).  But they are clearly accountable to the voting constituency.  

On a federal level there's some clear constitutional issues.  Legislators pass laws and finance the country.  The executive enforces said laws and spends said money.  The judicial makes sure they are all within the bounds of the law and constitution to do so.

Under this framework enforcement falls clearly under the executive.  In some states there's a court's Bailiff that is in charge of court protection and executing the court's orders.  In my state that's the jurisdiction of the Sheriff, yet it's still an elected office.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29662827464.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP, but the same way police chiefs are selected in the relevant jurisdiction would seem to make sense.  In most places, that would be appointment by the executive authority of the county.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
