<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419976488.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6y1jxk/cmv_municipalities_should_not_hold_easily/">
    <title>CMV: Municipalities should not hold easily politicized elections for apolitical positions like sheriff.</title>
    <original_poster>pr0crasturbatin</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see a lot about sheriffs being appointed through local elections, even seeing people wearing tshirts that say "Re-elect [sheriff's name] for [county name] county sheriff". But to me that seems to politicize a position that is one of considerable power to enforce the law in the area. By politicizing that, a sheriff is able to impose a political agenda to the point where it is literally able to be enforced at gunpoint, and can appoint deputies that align with them. While it makes towns essentially an absolute in terms of political alignment, it also insulates them to changes going on around them, including in surrounding towns or cities, and ultimately stifles progress and lets them get away with things that regular public officials wouldn't get away with because they are essentially their own oversight committee, like we saw with Joe Arpaio.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29663020037.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29663521198.0" user="whitef530" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry Juankii, your comment has been removed:

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 1\. "Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s current view (however minor), unless they are asking a clarifying question. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1)  

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+Juankii&amp;amp;message=Juankii+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/6y1jxk/cmv_municipalities_should_not_hold_easily/dmklgqt/\))</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
