<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="421582106.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6yzyu2/cmv_tenured_professors_fail_to_do_protest_or/">
    <title>CMV: Tenured professors fail to do (protest or resist) enough to improve universities for students.</title>
    <original_poster>xanth0s</original_poster>
    <original_post>###Assumptions

1. Ignore non-tenured staff because if they protest, they may fail to acquire tenure, or at least fear retaliation.

2. This post presupposes exceptional tenured professors (***henceforth OTP***) (e.g. Fields Medallists or Nobel Prize Laureates), for which consider only the top UK (e.g. Oxbridge, LSE) and US (Ivy League, MIT, Stanford, Berkeley, Caltech) universities (***henceforth TUNI***).

 ###Axioms (Please don't challenge these here; post separately to do so.)  



3. Every TUNI is imperfect, and still suffers at least 1 problem, like expensive tuition, bad teaching, deficient accommodation, etc... 
4. Every TUNI  currently employs Multiple OTP who agree with 3 (that something can be improved).

 ###Arguments
5. If a TUNI still refuses to change positions after formal protests or resistance by many OTP, many OTP should threaten to resign; and if a TUNI still doesn’t budge, truly resign. 
6. OTP's exceptionality makes them employable by most other universities. Even if they voluntarily resign and lose their tenure at OTP, OTP should prioritize [honour, integrity, selflessness](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ridenhour_Prizes) in helping less powerful students against mightier TUNIs and risk losing their employment, over being a silent bystander in these David-vs.-Goliath disputes. 

7. TUNIs will not desire collective resignation of so many OTPs, because then UNIS will lose reputation, prestige, funding, etc…

8. Thus, OTPs have the might to try to change the TUNI.

9. Conclusion and CMV: OTP aren’t doing or protesting enough to improve TUNIs for students.  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29675297298.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Even if I was employable in London or California, I wouldn't necessarily be willing to give up my job in New York over something like high tuition costs.

Professors are people too, and likely have family or social connections in that particular region, and wouldn't be interested in moving across the country to start over again at another institution.

Better to try and fix the problem in your own community than leaving for another which likely has the same problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29677022001.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>Does my 6 refute your first 2 paragraphs? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29677383069.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>No.  As I said, professors aren't obligated to sacrifice the well being of their families for their students.

Saying something like, "Oh, just move from MIT to Berkeley" isn't very convincing when their entire life and family is built in Boston.

Thsts a massive cost to be born by the professors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29681081010.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, but then upholding the status quo implies that OTPs aren't solving the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
