<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="421582106.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6yzyu2/cmv_tenured_professors_fail_to_do_protest_or/">
    <title>CMV: Tenured professors fail to do (protest or resist) enough to improve universities for students.</title>
    <original_poster>xanth0s</original_poster>
    <original_post>###Assumptions

1. Ignore non-tenured staff because if they protest, they may fail to acquire tenure, or at least fear retaliation.

2. This post presupposes exceptional tenured professors (***henceforth OTP***) (e.g. Fields Medallists or Nobel Prize Laureates), for which consider only the top UK (e.g. Oxbridge, LSE) and US (Ivy League, MIT, Stanford, Berkeley, Caltech) universities (***henceforth TUNI***).

 ###Axioms (Please don't challenge these here; post separately to do so.)  



3. Every TUNI is imperfect, and still suffers at least 1 problem, like expensive tuition, bad teaching, deficient accommodation, etc... 
4. Every TUNI  currently employs Multiple OTP who agree with 3 (that something can be improved).

 ###Arguments
5. If a TUNI still refuses to change positions after formal protests or resistance by many OTP, many OTP should threaten to resign; and if a TUNI still doesn’t budge, truly resign. 
6. OTP's exceptionality makes them employable by most other universities. Even if they voluntarily resign and lose their tenure at OTP, OTP should prioritize [honour, integrity, selflessness](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ridenhour_Prizes) in helping less powerful students against mightier TUNIs and risk losing their employment, over being a silent bystander in these David-vs.-Goliath disputes. 

7. TUNIs will not desire collective resignation of so many OTPs, because then UNIS will lose reputation, prestige, funding, etc…

8. Thus, OTPs have the might to try to change the TUNI.

9. Conclusion and CMV: OTP aren’t doing or protesting enough to improve TUNIs for students.  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29675198043.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>Starting with your Axioms (3 and 4)

Why should OTP do anything about it?  There are problems in the world/work that I know that can be improved but I don't do anything about it.  Why should OTP be forced to do something about a problem?

Say the OTP thinks that the problem is the "lessor of two evils".  So tuition is expensive for students but that is the price for the quality of education.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29677020678.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>12. This sounds like a question of remoteness? OTP is working at the same TUNI responsible for the injustice, and (I infer) not for the institution causing the global problems.

13. OTPs shouldn't be FORCED to do something; they should be motivated by themselves. 

14. The last paragraph sounds like the Fallacy of Dichotomy? Why not strive for quality education AND affordable tuition? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29677646611.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; OTP is working at the same TUNI responsible for the injustice, and (I infer) not for the institution causing the global problems.

I am using world problems as an example of problems that people can do something about but do not.  You haven't given a justification of why OTP should do anything at all.

&amp;gt; OTPs shouldn't be FORCED to do something; they should be motivated by themselves. 

Your View is about forcing them to do something, not about motivation - ie "many OTP should threaten to resign" not "many OTP should be motivated to threaten to resign".  Also " OTP aren’t doing or protesting enough" not "OTP aren't motivated to doing or protesting enough".

&amp;gt; Why not strive for quality education AND affordable tuition? 

Because they don't have the solution to do both?  How would you strive for quality education without students (or anyone) paying for it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29681077903.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>I did intend my view to be about motivation, not force. 

I never said that tuition should be 0; I did write 'affordable tuition'.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
