<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="421582106.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6yzyu2/cmv_tenured_professors_fail_to_do_protest_or/">
    <title>CMV: Tenured professors fail to do (protest or resist) enough to improve universities for students.</title>
    <original_poster>xanth0s</original_poster>
    <original_post>###Assumptions

1. Ignore non-tenured staff because if they protest, they may fail to acquire tenure, or at least fear retaliation.

2. This post presupposes exceptional tenured professors (***henceforth OTP***) (e.g. Fields Medallists or Nobel Prize Laureates), for which consider only the top UK (e.g. Oxbridge, LSE) and US (Ivy League, MIT, Stanford, Berkeley, Caltech) universities (***henceforth TUNI***).

 ###Axioms (Please don't challenge these here; post separately to do so.)  



3. Every TUNI is imperfect, and still suffers at least 1 problem, like expensive tuition, bad teaching, deficient accommodation, etc... 
4. Every TUNI  currently employs Multiple OTP who agree with 3 (that something can be improved).

 ###Arguments
5. If a TUNI still refuses to change positions after formal protests or resistance by many OTP, many OTP should threaten to resign; and if a TUNI still doesn’t budge, truly resign. 
6. OTP's exceptionality makes them employable by most other universities. Even if they voluntarily resign and lose their tenure at OTP, OTP should prioritize [honour, integrity, selflessness](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ridenhour_Prizes) in helping less powerful students against mightier TUNIs and risk losing their employment, over being a silent bystander in these David-vs.-Goliath disputes. 

7. TUNIs will not desire collective resignation of so many OTPs, because then UNIS will lose reputation, prestige, funding, etc…

8. Thus, OTPs have the might to try to change the TUNI.

9. Conclusion and CMV: OTP aren’t doing or protesting enough to improve TUNIs for students.  
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29674820134.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so your post is incredibly hard to read because I think you've used some sort of debate construction with which I am not familiar. 

That said, I'm a university professor currently up for tenure. I teach chemistry, run a 13 person laboratory, and will get tenure without a problem. 

I did not resist/protest anything at the university before I got tenure, and I very much doubt that I will resist/protest anything after I get tenure (unless the university does something *truly* outrageous). This isn't because I don't have political views but rather because my principal allegiance isn't to the university or the students bit but rather to my laboratory and the research we do. Any protesting and resisting I do and any feasible consequence of that protesting and resisting would take time and focus away from my laboratory. Again, there *are* circumstances that *would* lead to me protesting things, but they are few and far between. 

If this doesn't address your question, I apologize, but as i said, I found your post pretty difficult to read. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29675011226.0" user="-WedgeAntilles-" delta="False">
    <text>It's not you. I teach composition and rhetoric, and I still found OP's argument impossible to decipher.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29675143694.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>I just want to ask a question: I've noticed (as well as other friends from other colleges and universities) that there are quite a few tenured professors who are very uninterested in teaching students. I know a friend who had a class in which the tenured professor would leave after 3/4 of the class was finished to focus on his research,  and he didn't do that good of a job in teaching his students for that portion.  I guess my question to you is what should be the balance between teaching and research?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29680067460.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, this happens (though I'd argue that it's not as common as students say). I'd say there's a combination of three things going on: 

1) Some faculty honestly only became professors in order to do research. Some are good enough teachers for that not to matter and for their classes to still be good; others aren't. It's important to note, though, that many of us do love teaching and that we can walk and chew gum at the same time. Just because my primary interest is my research doesn't mean I don't relish my time with my students as well. 

2) Teaching isn't properly incentivized for some professors, particularly in STEM. For me, promotions/tenure/prestige have nothing to do with teaching but rather research, publications, and grant proposals. This has gotten better in recent years, but it's not there yet. 

3) Teaching is not always rewarding. At all. For every student or two that busts his or her ass and really wants to learn, there's also one on his/her cell phone, another that don't give a shit, another that complains when anything is difficult, another who doesn't bother showing up to class at all, and another whose parents call you if you give him/her a C. I'd imagine, as you get older (I.e. get tenured) these levels of entitlement get old quick. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29681016521.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely agree with all of your points. It's kind of funny though, because I heard another perspective from a professor at my university, and she thought that the professors were too hard/arbitrary in her field (in this case writing). Guess different people in different fields have different perspectives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29681809991.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confused, what did I say about professors being too easy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29683783567.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>I did not complete what she said. She also said that many professors at my school are not interested in teaching students, or giving them the grades that they deserve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29683960140.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>I'd caution you about listening to single voices about this (mine included), especially cynical ones. Too often, people adopt a cynical tone with the intention of seeming wise or intelligent. 

I'm also not sure what you mean by "giving them the grades they deserve". How would your professor know whether other professors gave anyone the grades they deserve? How would she know?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29684145417.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'd caution you about listening to single voices about this (mine included), especially cynical ones. Too often, people adopt a cynical tone with the intention of seeming wise or intelligent. 

Agreed.

&amp;gt;I'm also not sure what you mean by "giving them the grades they deserve". How would your professor know whether other professors gave anyone the grades they deserve? How would she know?

She and other teachers discussed what grades they gave students to make sure that they were all on the same page in terms of consistency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29677017964.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>10) Apologies. I edited my post now. Better? If not, please suggest what may simplify reading.

11) About your main paragraph: I think 6 refutes it? I'm arguing that prioritizing your academic and research duties over students' welfare, is being a silent bystander and condoning the TUNIs' injustice.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29680038987.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think that I should prioritize the abstract well-being of the student body over other priorities such as research and the well-being of the post-doctoral fellows, graduate students, and undergraduates that I supervise directly? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29681076014.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>How can there be excellent undergraduates and graduate students for your laboratory, if they can't pay for their university education? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29681806945.0" user="Aubenabee" delta="False">
    <text>I teach at a public university that is inexpensive for all and free for many. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29682457330.0" user="xanth0s" delta="False">
    <text>Ah OK. But what if a student is too poor to afford even it? Or nation-states that lack such public universities? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
