<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424649670.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70tps6/cmv_compulsory_national_service_is_bad/">
    <title>CMV: compulsory national service is bad</title>
    <original_poster>advicemonkey69</original_poster>
    <original_post>I debate at school, and the topic is similar to this. While researching, I have come to strongly agree with the negative side and really can't see any justification to affirm the following: In the US, national service ought to be compulsory. By the way, this isn't a homework question or anything, I just really would like to hear others' opinions.

Essentially, national service isn't confined to military service, so if you would like to CMV using examples other than military, feel free.

I believe that making service compulsory defeats the purpose.  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.  Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.  

A draft would only bring citizens to resent their government.  Using utilitarian calculus is not necessary if the outcomes could be produced similarly in a way that doesn't violate peoples' autonomy, such as with voluntary service.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29698686114.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that lots of people don't do anything to help others. 

A lot of times that intrinsic motivation is that it feels good to  relax and play video games. The internal reward for that person is doing nothing. 

There is often a big difference between the people who say they want to volunteer and they people who actually do it. 

As long as the person has a choice as to how they serve, I see no problem is having, as part of citizenship, a requirement to do a reasonable amount of work. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698697405.0" user="advicemonkey69" delta="False">
    <text>Fair, however, as stated, we already have enough people who do so voluntarily. Why force it and generate governmental resent when it isn't necessary? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698723647.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>We don't actually have enough people if you count non-military forms of service. There are many understaffed government programs. Also many that are underfunded, having mandatory volunteer service would help them a lot. I can search around and make list for you but it should be easy to find information. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698855547.0" user="advicemonkey69" delta="False">
    <text>Could you make that list?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698878144.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>Some are serious and you might not want just anybody doing them - in many areas legal and police positions as well as prisons. Then there's school programs, civil support stuff - food banks, shelters, etc., and child protection services which is really depressing if you read about what kind of cases they can't take on due to lack of resources. 

But there's also infrastructure and other very concrete and practical things, we're pretty awful when it comes to infrastructure as a nation. Our train systems and bus systems are a joke for how wealthy we are. Granted, there are some political hurdles and lobbying, it's not just a lack of people to do the work. 

Parks and rec programs also. Some states are better than others.

Sorting out how to get people to take some sort of civic pride in their service would also be important.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699963144.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>None of those would benefit from conscription.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698735624.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>There is still a lot to be done. 

And groups that need help are always looking for people to help them. If you called the literacy center in your town I'm sure they would love to have you. I don't think you would get a "sorry we have nothing you can do."

And I am not seeing the harm caused by some hard work. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
