<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424649670.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70tps6/cmv_compulsory_national_service_is_bad/">
    <title>CMV: compulsory national service is bad</title>
    <original_poster>advicemonkey69</original_poster>
    <original_post>I debate at school, and the topic is similar to this. While researching, I have come to strongly agree with the negative side and really can't see any justification to affirm the following: In the US, national service ought to be compulsory. By the way, this isn't a homework question or anything, I just really would like to hear others' opinions.

Essentially, national service isn't confined to military service, so if you would like to CMV using examples other than military, feel free.

I believe that making service compulsory defeats the purpose.  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.  Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.  

A draft would only bring citizens to resent their government.  Using utilitarian calculus is not necessary if the outcomes could be produced similarly in a way that doesn't violate peoples' autonomy, such as with voluntary service.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699887485.0" user="Sexpistolz" delta="False">
    <text>Military forces are more than just grunts with guns. Aircraft carriers for instance are essential floating cities. Doctors, nurses, cooks, plumbers, carpenters, skills from everything you can think of. SO what it comes to drive to do certain skills, if anything this provides opportunity for many to get the training they desire, or hell just an experience at something different before they go to college. 

This also likely means that people will travel and get away from their bubble of where they live. The US is very diverse and I'd say it's a much needed experience to live on the other side of the tracks for a bit. 

As for people resenting the draft I disagree. It's not mandatory service they are against but their purpose. Most countries' military, mexico for instance, primary function is humanitarian aid not war. There's plenty of places foreign and domestic that could well utilize an organized force such as this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699969781.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Doctors, nurses, cooks, plumbers, carpenters, skills from everything you can think of. SO what it comes to drive to do certain skills, if anything this provides opportunity for many to get the training they desire,

In a system that has both a permanent volunteer force, and a conscripted force, which of those do you think will secure the training and roles that they would like, and who do you think might end up spending their mandatory two years (or more/or less) painting rocks around a parade ground or pumping gas, for less than minimum wage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699983941.0" user="Sexpistolz" delta="False">
    <text>I fail to understand your point. If you want to be a doctor, how does it effect you differently if you go to college first or get trained in the national service? I honestly dont see what your getting at </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700002347.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>Conscripted members don't get trained as doctors.  

Conscripted soldiers get the jobs the permanent force members don't feel like doing. 

They don't get to play doctor *unless* they have used a university deferment and already have qualified as a doctor under their own dime.  
National service has nothing to do with them entering specialized fields or receiving specialized training. It's not cost effective.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
