<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424649670.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70tps6/cmv_compulsory_national_service_is_bad/">
    <title>CMV: compulsory national service is bad</title>
    <original_poster>advicemonkey69</original_poster>
    <original_post>I debate at school, and the topic is similar to this. While researching, I have come to strongly agree with the negative side and really can't see any justification to affirm the following: In the US, national service ought to be compulsory. By the way, this isn't a homework question or anything, I just really would like to hear others' opinions.

Essentially, national service isn't confined to military service, so if you would like to CMV using examples other than military, feel free.

I believe that making service compulsory defeats the purpose.  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.  Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.  

A draft would only bring citizens to resent their government.  Using utilitarian calculus is not necessary if the outcomes could be produced similarly in a way that doesn't violate peoples' autonomy, such as with voluntary service.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699446615.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who experienced compulsory national service I'm going to defeat the purpose of the sub and tell you that I won't ever be able to change your view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699918339.0" user="advicemonkey69" delta="False">
    <text>So...you agree?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699953235.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely.  
For every pro here, I'll throw a con back at them.  

If they ever brought conscription to the UK, I'd do anything in my power to get my son out of it, and that's the primary failure of the system.

The only thing I can ever say in favour of it, is that it *should* encourage voters to chose a government that is less likely to get them or their offspring killed over a patch of dirt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700272060.0" user="mellowvids" delta="False">
    <text>Just because people want to get out of it, that doesn't mean that the system has failed.

The system can be said to have failed if:

1. everyone gets out of it.

2. everyone who participates learns nothing from the experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700344709.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>It's a system of last resort.  
It means that not enough people value the country's military as a lifestyle, career or healthy option to volunteer. Or that the country is participating in events that require a lot of bodies.

I am by no means claiming that some people do not learn, or gain something from it, but faced with the success I had or being given two years of my life back I absolutely know what I would have opted for.

For the record, I finished as a PTI non-com, having worked my ass off for 9 months.  
I wish I was as fit now as I was then, our final qualifying events were a week of runs in full kit with rifle. 3km in 15 minutes, 15km in 100 minutes and 45km in 7 hours.  
I trained as a drill instructor and a weapon instructor too. Made a lot of things go bang, rode in choppers. All that stuff, so I didn't just sit on my arse watching the clock.  
As far as conscription goes I pretty much made the best of it.   
I'd still swap all that and the friends I made in a heartbeat for those two years.

What I hated was seeing the despair in the eyes of those buddies who washed out at 8.5 months due to an injury and spent the next year plus in a guard shack.  
Or the guys whose family knew someone and ended up doing a 10-2 daily shift at the closest base to home.  
Seeing some young Jehovah's Witness get the shit beat out of him because he wouldn't pick up the (non-functioning) rifle used for marching drill practise.  
Or seeing the guys with mental issues not getting treatment, getting shat on by their barrack buddies every day and then finishing the job from a rafter in the showers during the dog watch.  

Being thrown in the pool for "brick in the backpack" water PT and told I had to play lifeguard, while the racist Captain told 140 coloured guys who had never learnt to swim (bar 2 of them) that unless they jumped from the high board they would wash out.  
Coloured guys who were fitter, marched better, were more dedicated and were a damned sight more brave than the 300 white guys they were placed with on the course.
3 of them stayed in the Instructor course barracks that night.  
Fuck that for a game of soldiers.

Everyone eager to recommend conscription either never went through it or had it piss easy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702354484.0" user="mellowvids" delta="False">
    <text>I recognize now that you were talking specifically about military conscription, and I thought you were referencing the topic of the CMV, which OP specified is not strictly about military conscription:  "National service isn't confined to military service".

My mistake.  Sure, military conscription is a bad system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702438221.0" user="WillyPete" delta="False">
    <text>In my experience, national service was always the attempt to rebrand conscription.  
Most countries that have it use that term. I do confess, some extend their system to include the police and other emergency services, but typically not for roles that require professionals. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
