<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424649670.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70tps6/cmv_compulsory_national_service_is_bad/">
    <title>CMV: compulsory national service is bad</title>
    <original_poster>advicemonkey69</original_poster>
    <original_post>I debate at school, and the topic is similar to this. While researching, I have come to strongly agree with the negative side and really can't see any justification to affirm the following: In the US, national service ought to be compulsory. By the way, this isn't a homework question or anything, I just really would like to hear others' opinions.

Essentially, national service isn't confined to military service, so if you would like to CMV using examples other than military, feel free.

I believe that making service compulsory defeats the purpose.  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.  Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.  

A draft would only bring citizens to resent their government.  Using utilitarian calculus is not necessary if the outcomes could be produced similarly in a way that doesn't violate peoples' autonomy, such as with voluntary service.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699544452.0" user="idaell" delta="False">
    <text>A draft is not intended to get high quality soldiers necessarily. In certain times there may be a military need in terms of numbers that is just not met with a volunteer force, this may not be an issue for the U.S. today. The other real reason for a true draft (not subverted by wealth, connections), is to spread the impact and sacrifice of the war across all the peoples of the nation. If we have financial incentives such as the GI bill then we end up with a lot of poor and perhaps desperate recruits. Those with wealth tend to avoid it yet some could argue they benefit the most. Also, if you do not have a draft it can be easy for a nation to ignore the true costs of war, allowing more wars and for them to be extended, as it does not in any notable way impact their lives.  Do you think juries should be voluntary? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
