<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424649670.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70tps6/cmv_compulsory_national_service_is_bad/">
    <title>CMV: compulsory national service is bad</title>
    <original_poster>advicemonkey69</original_poster>
    <original_post>I debate at school, and the topic is similar to this. While researching, I have come to strongly agree with the negative side and really can't see any justification to affirm the following: In the US, national service ought to be compulsory. By the way, this isn't a homework question or anything, I just really would like to hear others' opinions.

Essentially, national service isn't confined to military service, so if you would like to CMV using examples other than military, feel free.

I believe that making service compulsory defeats the purpose.  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.  Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.  

A draft would only bring citizens to resent their government.  Using utilitarian calculus is not necessary if the outcomes could be produced similarly in a way that doesn't violate peoples' autonomy, such as with voluntary service.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699284738.0" user="Nickppapagiorgio" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.

If you are talking about a skirmish with the natives in Iraq as the British used to call it then yes the US can do it with volunteers alone although barely. If you're talking about a War with another major power, no the US can't. In WW2 the US was able to draw in 6 million volunteers into their armed services to fight the Nazis and Japanese. It was nowhere near enough and 10 million Americans ended up being drafted. By the end of the War, 62.5% of American service members were draftees. Given how warfare has changed it is difficult to project what manpower requirements would be in a major War with a military power today. They would almost certainly be somewhat less than the 1940's, but it's not unreasonable to believe it would be an amount that the Pentagon wouldn't be able to fill with volunteers alone, which is why the Selective Service System exists to this day. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
