<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699239965.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>I think we should examine the bigger picture here. Drastically high rent prices, along with rent prices that have quickly risen can have a negative impact on society as a whole, including the rich. 

The middle class and poor are the lifeblood of society. They have the greatest numbers, purchase a great deal of all consumer goods, services, etc. When you begin to displace them and make it impossible to live near city centers, etc, the job markets in the city become less competitive (affecting rich business owners), bars and restaurants and stores in the area lose out (old people tend to go out less), and the overall economy becomes less focused on catering to cutting edge young people with fresh ideas, and instead shifts to cater to an older richer generation (again, wealthy more or less equates to age in this occasion as most young people starting out can't afford expensive rent). 

Therefore it's in society's best interest to make these vibrant areas accessible to a greater number of people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699264517.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>This is true. It is true that ludicrous rent prices are short-sighted and will likely end up harming the economy in the long run. This may make the actions unethical by some standard, but not immoral.

I posted an analogy in another comment and I'll summarize it here (on mobile): 

Kitten in tree

Fireman tries to save

Kitten dies

Good intent, bad outcome.

Is action immoral? (I say no)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699322438.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>That's not a good analogy. The fireman is trying to save something and has nothing to gain in doing so. Using your same analogy you need to enter in the economic incentives that exist in rent

Kitten in tree

Fireman is offered $1,000 and is told if he saves the cat he get's the money, but it has a 60% chance of dying. If you leave the cat it might be stuck in the tree but it will survive.

Fireman tries to save the cat for the $1k

Cat dies.

Many would say it was selfish for the fireman to do so and thus immoral</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699361196.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>Well stain my stand and call me Ayn Rand but I don't think selfish actions are immoral at all (inherently, at least).

Many would say that, though, you're right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699389934.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>Selfish actions are not inherently immoral, but knowingly inflicting harm on someone else for personal gain  is seen as immoral by many libertarians (i.e. my right to swing my fist ends just before your nose). I'm not well versed in Ayn Rand personally, but I don't think she promoted such a cut throat attitude. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699446693.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>That is true, but I do not believe that high rent is harm.

I was joking with the reference, but yes, Ayn Rand did promote such a cut throat attitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699390791.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think selfish actions are immoral at all 

What do you think fundamentally determines whether something is moral or immoral? It seems like that may be a big disconnect on this thread, because I think most people would agree that acting in your own best interest even if you know it will cause greater harm to others is immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699473738.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>First, given the analogy, there was a 60% chance of saving the cat vs a 100% chance of not saving the cat. The money was just a bonus imo.

The intent matters to me more than the outcome. A short-sighted but well-intended action is not morally aprehensible, and a well-planned but maliciously-intended action is immoral.

I believe that housing is moral because capitalism is moral. Nobody is being forced by threat of violence to do anything. All forces in action are purely economic (except in New York, due to government intervention (regardless of said intervention's effectiveness)).

Additionally, the cat can simply be caught rather than dying by lowering rents, selling to poor people, and building low-income housing. If/when the developers realize that that subsidising poor people is beneficial (immediately), they will, naturally, do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699751267.0" user="Gammapod" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; First, given the analogy, there was a ~~60%~~ 40% chance of saving the cat vs a 100% chance of not saving the cat.

If having the cat out of the tree is the only outcome you care about, then this is an okay way to put it. If you only care about the cat's life though, then you could instead say that there's a 60% chance of killing the cat vs a 100% chance of not killing it. Wouldn't you say it's wrong to accept money in exchange for increasing the odds of death?

Since there are two output variables to consider, the full range of possibilities is:

Choice 1
-
40% Alive and rescued

60% Dead and 'rescued'

Choice 2
-
100% Alive and in a tree</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700130905.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>I've lost the relevance of this example to the CMV, but I'll try to answer anyway.

In the case that the two outcomes are 40% success vs 100% success, it would be the correct choice to pick 100% success.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699464588.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>So you agree high rent prices hurt society at large? 

Why would it be moral to take an action that hurts the overall society, making things worse for everyone at the benefit of solely yourself? If anything I'd flip your statement, saying it's arguably ethical (because you're not breaking any laws technically), but overall the action of jacking up prices is more or less immoral. 

It's a selfish action, but not an illegal one. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701469912.0" user="yeabutwhataboutthat" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between "very high rent prices" and "ludicrous rent prices" is...?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702430454.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing. I am using them interchangeably.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
