<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699250572.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well.

The piece that you're missing here is that these luxury apartments aren't being "lived in." The wealthy who can afford these apartments are, by-and-large, using them to;

* Have as a weekend getaway
* Have as a crashpad for sporadic business trips to the given city (instead of patronizing hotels and using other hospitality services that stimulate the local economy)
* Hold as a speculative market investment
* Sublet at higher rates for profit

In a vacuum, each of these things may be generally acceptable from a capitalist standpoint. In practice, however, this means that these apartments do not contribute to the local economy as usual - small businesses are not being patronized, public transit is not being used, etc. by the residents who don't *really* live there. There is limited land for development within major metropolitan areas, however - housing is a zero sum game. This either forces the people who can't afford these apartments (i.e. the *vast* majority of the urban population) to move out of the city, or pay egregiously high rent for sub-par apartments.

&amp;gt;As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.

In these terms, the supply (land &amp;amp; permits for building apartments) is being met with two competing demands - superfluous income &amp;amp; property for the extremely wealthy, and basic housing for the rest of us. One of these demands is much more profitable than the other, but serves far, far fewer people. 

I'll leave the points from /u/gogoboldo and /u/cdb03b alone, but they do need to be addressed by you as well - I think your economic assessment is off-base, but even if it weren't, sound capitalism does not equate to sound morals. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699296579.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with all that you said. It's all true. Except the conclusion that it's all immoral.

The rich demand beats out the poor demand, and this is unsustainable and short-sighted. This could be construed as unethical by some standard (utilitarian). It is not, however, immoral.

The supplier is fairly supplying a good to a consumer that fairly pays for it. What the consumer does with it is irrelevant to the morality of the housing being made and sold.

If a rich person and a poor person are stuck in a desert on the verge of starvation. Someone comes up with a hamburger in his hand and a pricetag of $1,000,000,000. This is ludicrously overpriced, and the vast majority of hamburger consumers could not afford this price. If either person does not eat, they die. The rich person can afford the burger and happily pays for it. The poor person dies. Was this immoral? Would it have been immoral to force the rich person to die, or the hamburger salesman to sell for less? I think so.

A poor person goes to an art auction, and bids $5 on a priceless Bob Ross painting. The next bid is $1,000. The poor person obviously can't afford this and cries out, "hey! This is unfair!" And is rightfully laughed out of the room. Should the auctioneer be forced to sell to poor people at a lower price? Should the wealthy buyers be forced out of the auction?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699345319.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This could be construed as unethical by some standard (utilitarian). It is not, however, immoral.

Well, if you're a utilitarian, yeah it is immoral. What moral framework do you propose instead? Economic / legal moralism aren't valid moral frameworks. 

&amp;gt;The supplier is fairly supplying a good to a consumer that fairly pays for it. What the consumer does with it is irrelevant to the morality of the housing being made and sold.

How do you support that claim of irrelevance? What's your moral framework? I say that it *is* relevant, since it has a predictable &amp;amp; demonstrable negative impact on many more people than it helps. 

&amp;gt;The rich person can afford the burger and happily pays for it. The poor person dies. Was this immoral?

Very arguably, yes. Plus, you're missing the point that the rich person **isn't eating the hamburger** for the analogy to work. They're just holding on to it to increase their net worth, or to sniff that burger smell on the weekends. They have other means to survive. 

&amp;gt;A poor person goes to an art auction, and bids $5 on a priceless Bob Ross painting. The next bid is $1,000. The poor person obviously can't afford this and cries out, "hey! This is unfair!" And is rightfully laughed out of the room. Should the auctioneer be forced to sell to poor people at a lower price?

Bob Ross paintings aren't required for survival - I fail to see how this is analogous. No one is arguing about the pricing of luxury goods. 

Look, my point is that you can't just call something moral without supporting that claim, something you've not yet done. The actors (realtors &amp;amp; property developers) have adequate knowledge of how their decisions will negatively impact a plurality if not majority of populations in the areas they're working in, and make those decisions anyway for short term personal gain. There is certainly an argument for the immorality of this, and claiming it to be sound economics is not a sufficient challenge. You have to provide more. 




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699559660.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What moral framework do you propose instead? Economic / legal moralism aren't valid moral frameworks.

I agree, but I also don't have a framework to offer. My reasoning is that capitalism is not inherently immoral, that there is no harm currently taking place, and that if harm were to take place, there would be economic incentives for developers to fix it.

&amp;gt;since it has a predictable &amp;amp; demonstrable negative impact on many more people than it helps.

So then guns, drugs, candy, and any other worthless item are all immoral? I don't personally think so.

&amp;gt;They have other means to survive.

If we're going to get literal here, so do the poor people. There are cheap cities and ways to make expensive cities cheaper.

&amp;gt;luxury goods

Luxury housing (most of the housing development) is not a luxury good?

&amp;gt;make those decisions anyway for short term personal gain

I disagree that this is harm, and it can be easily rectified once there is economic incentive to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699602827.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My reasoning is that capitalism is not inherently immoral, that there is no harm currently taking place, and that if harm were to take place, there would be economic incentives for developers to fix it.

Right, and my counterargument is that, actually, harm **is** taking place, as a *direct result* of the fact that perpetuating this harm is economically incentivized. 

&amp;gt;So then guns, drugs, candy, and any other worthless item are all immoral?

Depending on the contexts, sure. You keep drawing analogies in broad terms that ignore the specifics of this situation. No one is claiming that *all* luxury apartment sales are problematic - just that they are *functionally* problematic based on the current situation. 

Are candy sales immoral? Categorically, no. Is the only vending machine in the elementary school selling soda and candy bars instead of water and granola to a captive audience of developing children with poor impulse control immoral? Arguably, yes. 

&amp;gt;If we're going to get literal here, so do the poor people. There are cheap cities and ways to make expensive cities cheaper

If we're going to get literal here, no, they absolutely do not. Moving and finding new employment is astronomically costly. It takes significant time and planning, time that has to come away from other areas, like work and the enormously long commutes required for that work because **they cannot live close to their urban jobs because they cannot afford to.** Family structures are often relied upon to manage childcare, housecare, and other needs - moving away cuts off these resources. It's a cycle. 

&amp;gt;Luxury housing (most of the housing development) is not a luxury good?

**Housing** is not a luxury good, and the luxury good of fancy housing comes at the direct expense of the availability of housing. 

Coca-Cola is a luxury good that requires water, a non-luxury good, to be made. If Coca-Cola drains all of a community's water supply to bottle &amp;amp; ship their product to other areas, that community must now go through undue financial/material hardship to acquire the water that they need. This may be sound economics for Coca-Cola, and for the Coca-Cola customers in other areas who can afford Coca-Cola, and that doesn't make Coca-Cola a non-luxury item. It *definitely* deprives a population of something they absolutely need, however. 

&amp;gt;I disagree that this is harm, and it can be easily rectified once there is economic incentive to do so.

And from where does that economic incentive come? From the people who have no money to afford the product to begin with? They have no economic power in this scenario. 

No one is claiming that luxury housing isn't *profitable*. It decidedly is. That's the whole problem. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700090633.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>The term you're looking for is "profiteering," and yes, it is generally considered immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700133835.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I am looking for that term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701467751.0" user="yeabutwhataboutthat" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed, you're closing your eyes and trying to pretend it's not there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702431689.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't think it's that, either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701464435.0" user="yeabutwhataboutthat" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the hamburger example was immoral.  If you come up upon two people starving in the desert and you have a hamburger, give them each half of the hamburger.  Jesus fuck's sake what kind of rank asshole would exploit that situation to try and become a millionaire?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702441801.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>For the sake of the example, the two people required a whole hamburger to live. Half wouldn't have cut it.

The kind of rank asshole that would exploit that situation to try an become a millionaire is the analogy for someone with a very high demand for a low value good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29704888961.0" user="yeabutwhataboutthat" delta="False">
    <text>Half would have cut it.  That "whole" lie is just what the asshole guy told you to account for his assholery.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29705196366.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>First, when I say for the sake of the analogy I just want an answer within the bounds of the scenario. I don't care very much if you think changing it would make it more of a direct parallel. It very well could, but I'm trying to demonstrate a point with the analogies, not completely mirror the exact situation being discussed.

Say half *could* cut it, it wouldn't matter and you would be needlessly complicating the analogy because it's not the responsibility of the rich person to provide for the poor person. It is the responsibility of the poor person (and possibly the government) to provide for the poor person.

Not sharing my million dollar burger is not being an asshole, just as much as not sharing any other burger is not being an asshole. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701986590.0" user="ChuckJA" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In these terms, **the supply (land &amp;amp; permits for building apartments)** is being met with two competing demands - superfluous income &amp;amp; property for the extremely wealthy, and basic housing for the rest of us. One of these demands is much more profitable than the other, but serves far, far fewer people. 

Why not increase the supply, then? Isn't the *root cause* of this issue artificial property scarcity imposed by the local government?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702031949.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why not increase the supply, then?

...how? What unclaimed land is there in the U.S.? 

&amp;gt;Isn't the root cause of this issue artificial property scarcity imposed by the local government?

No, it's developers opting to build a luxury apartment complex to make LOADS of profit instead of building affordable apartment complexes to make SOME profit while also invigorating the local economy.

I'm not arguing that it *isn't* in developer's immediate financial interests to take this route, I'm arguing that acting on this interest is to the detriment of many. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702865984.0" user="ChuckJA" delta="False">
    <text>If zoning laws were relaxed, and permits more permissively granted, wouldn't there be enough construction to meet everyone's demand? Once the demand for high end units was exhausted, wouldn't developers move downmarket?

And if space physically runs out before the demand is exhausted, then the value of that living space is truly extraordinary. Why should the land owners sell it below market value? Maybe those who can't afford to live in a city center *shouldn't* live there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29702900195.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If zoning laws were relaxed, and permits more permissively granted, wouldn't there be enough construction to meet everyone's demand?

It's not that more permits need to be granted, it's that the permits that *are* granted need to be granted to low and middle income housing developers rather than high-end housing developers. 

&amp;gt;Once the demand for high end units was exhausted, wouldn't developers move down-market?

Theoretically, yes absolutely. The question is what damage will be wrought upon the vast majority who cannot afford housing in the meantime / what damage will be wrought upon the local economy as customers dry up, employees cannot make commutes, fewer taxes are collected, etc. and so on, in the meantime?

&amp;gt;And if space physically runs out before the demand is exhausted, then the value of that living space is truly extraordinary. Maybe those who can't afford to live in a city center shouldn't live there.

You're also missing the point that these luxury apartments are being *sold* but not *lived in*, by-and-large. 

If a lower/middle class tenant rents an apartment, sure the rent payment will be lower and that's less money for the landlord/municipality, but that person will spend the majority of their time living there. They will then use public transit, patronize local businesses, work jobs within their commuting radius, pay employment and sales taxes, engage in local political issues, volunteer, et cetera and so on. There are far-reaching economic benefits beyond just rent and mortgage dollar amounts. 

When the ultra-wealthy purchase luxury apartments in urban centers, they usually do *not* live there year round (see my first comment). If we carry your idea through to its conclusion, then the majority of housing units in a city will be sublets, weekend getaways, or speculative investments. Local businesses lose customers who aren't buying from them, lose employees who can't reach them, and the municipality loses out on those tax dollars and community benefits.

&amp;gt;Why should the land owners sell it below cost for below cost housing?

I agree that right now they have no incentive to. I'd argue that city governments need to create incentives for and prioritize these sorts of developments, and disincentives for those who would hold an apartment without living in it a substantive amount of time per year. I'd also agree with the position that "the market will sort it out" more were it not for the fact that many luxury apartments are *not being lived in* after sale/rent. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
