<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699268047.0" user="Lurial" delta="False">
    <text>Devil's advocate:

Morality is experienced separately, to the real estate owner, it is an A-Moral decision. they can achieve higher rents and higher profit, so they do. for the poor renter it is a moral decision. perhaps they cannot afford housing and so must make decisions that might put their children at risk (living with strangers/in ghetto's/high crime area's) the higher rent has caused them to take an immoral choice vs the moral choice of living in the higher rent-Lower risk area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699371773.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>I am of the belief that if you are financially unstable it is immoral for you to have children in the first place. Anything after that is your fault, high rent included.

Ignoring that, though, you could simply move to a safe part of a cheaper city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701237532.0" user="qwerty11111122" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am of the belief that if you are financially unstable it is immoral for you to have children in the first place

But on the flip side, people don't often consider adopting out their children when they are fired from their job unexpectedly. Your financial circumstances when you conceive can be different from later on.

&amp;gt; move to a safe part of a cheaper city

Moving houses is a hell and a half. My family is upper middle class and moving was still really bad each time we did it. We took a 100k loss after the bubble burst and moved houses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701430724.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But on the flip side, people don't often consider adopting out their children when they are fired from their job unexpectedly. Your financial circumstances when you conceive can be different from later on.

This is true, but a "poor person" was, in theory, poor when they had their children as well. Someone who was wealthy but has hit hard times is different from a "poor person" imo.

&amp;gt;Moving houses is a hell and a half.

So is being homeless because you can't afford housing in the city you live in.

&amp;gt;My family is upper middle class and moving was still really bad each time we did it.

I was middle class (like, median income middle class) when I was a kid, and moving wasn't that bad once you get over losing your friends the first time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
