<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699568863.0" user="exotics" delta="False">
    <text>You have to live somewhere... no matter what the cost of rent is.. you have to live somewhere.  Landlords that charge high rents are the scum of the earth (in my opinion) as they are making money off of the fact that people need shelter.  Imagine if grocery stores charged as much as they wanted?  People would have to pay or starve to death.. it's getting pretty bad with both, but landlords are worse.

When a landlord demands a high rent the people have to make sacrifices elsewhere and do so solely for the landlord's best interests, not their own.

Landlords own the property - they likely will make a profit when they sell it.. a moral landlord would be okay with that and wouldn't gouge renters.. they would just use the renter as "help" with the mortgage, and that's about it.. a little bit more perhaps to help cover repairs..

It is immoral to ask for more than you "need" so by the very nature of the word, any landlord who asks for a high rent is immoral.  Thinking only of themselves and not others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700869645.0" user="billy_bobs" delta="False">
    <text>Being a landlord is a job, and a business. If landlords didnt profit why would they take the risk of buying the property and investing their time in renting it? Risk comes with reward, you wouldnt risk your money on an investment property just to make the mortgage, would you? 

You are naive to think that just because you own property your gonna make a profit when you sell, and that landlords should give up their piece of the pie for you or another renter. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701010084.0" user="exotics" delta="False">
    <text>Some landlords.. not all.. are the ones who own a house and live in the upper part of it, and rent out the basement.  Or they are people who, for some reason, have two houses (like two people each had a house and met and got married and kept both houses but decide to rent one out.  These people work and have jobs, they rent out for bonus income - which they may not even declare at tax time.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
