<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29701729951.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>NYC rents are so damn high because an enourmous amouny of capacity is vacant. Why? Because the world's oligarchs and international criminals use NYC's real estate to [park and launder money](https://mobile.nytimes.com/2015/02/08/nyregion/stream-of-foreign-wealth-flows-to-time-warner-condos.html?rref=collection%2Fnewseventcollection%2Fshell-company-towers-of-secrecy-real-estate&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=us&amp;amp;region=rank&amp;amp;module=package&amp;amp;version=highlights&amp;amp;contentPlacement=1&amp;amp;pgtype=collection&amp;amp;referer=https://www.nytimes.com/news-event/shell-company-towers-of-secrecy-real-estate). 

The result is that much of the best living spaces are off the market, pushing the high end renters down to raise rents on lower end rentals. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
