<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699888139.0" user="dickposner" delta="False">
    <text>I'm mostly on the side of free market economics, but here there may be some wiggle room for some non-market intervention, and the concept can be called the "wealth effect." (the term "wealth effect" is also used to describe a separate economic phenomenon)

The basic justification for free market allocation of resources is that by and large, free markets allow resources to go to the most efficient user of that resource.  If person A prefers oranges to bananas, and person B vice versa, then the free market allows person A to purchase all of the oranges, and person B to purchase all of the bananas, and they're both better off than if the govt tried to guess at what would make them happy and likely ends up "fairly" rationing each of them to take half bananas and half oranges.  

However, in some situations the market is not well developed enough (not enough housing stock for instance), and there is too much of a wealth disparity among certain segments of the population such that the very wealthy can afford to buy up ALL of the goods, even ones in which it would be efficient for other consumers to have.  In our very simplistic orange/banana scenario, say person A is a working adult, and person B is a 6 year old with a lemonade stand, and the only available food for sale is an apple and a banana.  The working adult can afford to buy up both the apple and the banana without batting an eye and outbids the 6 year old for the banana that the 6 year old desperately craves.  

In that case, the free market really isn't functioning well in allocating resources efficiently because of the too large differential in purchasing power (the wealth effect).

Similarly, with limited housing stock/building permits, and with housing being such a necessity for living, it could very well be argued that high rent prices could be rationale for govt intervention because of suboptimal markets.





</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700062696.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>This is true. The free market is notoriously bad at providing common goods to all.

This is not immoral, however, as it is simply economics at work. (It has been pointed out to me that in New York and San Fransisco governmental regulations have created a perverse environment in which the poor are unfairly forced out of the market (and this was the intended effect), which I would consider immoral)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700102442.0" user="dickposner" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it is simply economics at work

Anything suboptimal, to a utilitarian (like most economists), is by definition somewhat immoral.  

So, when markets malfunction, there is some degree of immorality (because the results are suboptimal for maximizing utility) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700153071.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>It is not suboptimal from the perspectives of the rich person or the developer (yet, presumably).

If you want, you could say that all industry is, to some degree, unethical based on utilitarian ethics due to inevitable inefficiencies somewhere, and I will gladly award you the delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700181776.0" user="dickposner" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It is not suboptimal from the perspectives of the rich person or the developer 

I'm judging from the perspective of the utilitarian policy maker, not the poor person or the rich person.  

&amp;gt;If you want, you could say that all industry is, to some degree, unethical based on utilitarian ethics due to inevitable inefficiencies somewhere

No that's no what I'm saying - most industries in a free market with robust property protections and certain anti-monopoly/collusive regulations are working as well as you can hope for.

I'm saying that this is a special case of malfunctioning markets due to a variety of factors - wealth differential being the primary one I focused on, but also contributing factors are in-elasticity of demand (family/job) /high transaction costs of moving, government introduced market distortions like rent stabilization programs and high hurdles of entry for new builders/buildings...

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
