<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699333252.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>Economic theories also dictate that it is immoral.  Simply saying "capitalism" doesn't remove moral implications here, in fact it opens up some obvious moral problems:

1. we already recognize things like anti-trust regulations as means to limit the _moral_ problems associated with unfettered capitalism.  That someone with capital might end up with power that is not well checked is _obvious_, that it is happening in a specific circumstance may be more challenging to discern.  That one then _abuses_ said power seems at least possible, we've all seen it and it may be common!

2. We have all sorts of rules about price manipulation, gouging and so on.  Why would we deny that these can happen with housing?  These are in place because of _moral concerns_.  

3. We recognize lots of things as uncomfortable in their relationship to supply and demand.  We don't price babies based on supply and demand, nor human organs.  While "your home" isn't the same thing as these, it's on s continuum and it's not like bread or iPads.  Given that, it seems the same sort of moral concerns arise with housing as do with selling babies and organs.  You might enjoy Dr. Radin's book "contested commodities" - goes into how and why we aren't comfortable with the moral aspects of treating all things with commoditizing forces.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699423576.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>1 And 2 are similar so I will address them at the same time:

Do we regulate trusts, price manipulation, etc. for moral reasons or *practical* reasons? You admit that unchecked power can exist without being abused.

3: Housing and babies are not equal. An apartment is much closer to bread and iPads than it is to babies on the continuum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699489303.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>1. We regulate it for moral reasons.  Clearly.  If it were for practical reasons, then anti-trust wouldn't be inapplicable to things like luxury items (e.g. you can have 100% of the market of luxury pens and you're not in violation of anti-trust laws, but not if you have 100% of the market on a food staple or a raw material).  

2. Not equal, as I said.  On a spectrum.  If you think having a roof over your head is like an iPad, then you and I have a fundamental disagreement here.  We don't have a national problem of "ipadlessness", now do we?  Either way, if you acknowledge the spectrum then being anything but the far end means moral issues seep in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699580720.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>1. Luxury items are not deemed necessary, therefore government intervention is not deemed necessary. If a luxury item was suddenly deemed necessary, I guarantee you the gummint would start sticking their fingers in the pie.

2. Fair enough, not equal. My point is that a roof over your head *in New York specifically* is basically an iPad, and that housing is closer to an iPad than a baby because it is not a living thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
