<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699426374.0" user="little_snailor" delta="False">
    <text>Unaffordable rent prices are immoral because we consider all individuals, even the poor, as human beings who have the right not to sleep out in the rain, snow, heat, and elements. High rent price would make it a struggle to live off the streets, yet the city needs minimum wage workers like food service, transportation, garbage, etc. to function. Don't those people deserve a home in a safe neighborhood as much as a CEO does, even if they make less money? 

Supply and demand does not equal moral. If you and 50% of the population were dying of a treatable disease, but ten other billionaires could spend more money on treatment than everyone else combined, would it be moral for doctors to refuse to see everyone else because they could make more money only treating billionaires?

The city where I live has 30,000 vacant homes, but 6500 homeless people. The average person here spends 40% of their total income on rent. Again, having a roof over your head is seen as a basic human right. In that context, doesn't it make sense that widespread housing reform is needed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699496263.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Don't those people deserve a home in a safe neighborhood as much as a CEO does, even if they make less money?

They deserve to pay exactly the same price as the CEO.

&amp;gt;would it be moral for doctors to refuse to see everyone else because they could make more money only treating billionaires

This is a whole new can of worms, because medical ethics are notoriously tricky. It could be yes because they are not "doing harm", but it could be no because one could argue that not helping is harming, in a medical scenario.

From a non-medical perspective, yes, absolutely.

&amp;gt;seen as a basic human right

Yes, to pursue not to have.

&amp;gt;doesn't it make sense that widespread housing reform is needed?

Given enough time, the market will correct itself. For those that don't want to wait, yes. Though, the efficacy of housing reform is debated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699602739.0" user="little_snailor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They deserve to pay exactly the same price as the CEO.

They *can't* pay the same price as the CEO. They're poor. You are arguing for a society where everyone except for the wealthy can't access a normal quality of life. 

&amp;gt;Yes, to pursue not to have.

I think what you're saying is that someone's rights only extend to being able to say, "No, I don't want a house." What about someone's rights to avoid dying in suffering, starvation, and humiliation? If you don't believe in respect for human life and happiness, it will be very hard to consider a system that promotes homelessness immoral.

Why will the market correct itself? You just said this is basic supply and demand. From an "economic" standpoint, it would be totally okay for the majority of people to suffer from disease, not have enough to eat, and not have shelter, even while many of them work to make *your* life better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
