<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699231109.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Economic theory in no way dictates, and barely even addresses the morality of something. It is fully possible for something to be dictated as necessary or the most beneficial action in economic theory and it to still be a completely immoral action. Driving rent prices up to the point that you force poor people to move is one such action. It does not matter if you have economic reasons it is still immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699241644.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, assuming economics has nothing to do with morality, how is the act of driving rent prices up immoral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699258037.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>You force people out of their homes and businesses. Forcing people to move save for due to imminent danger is an inherently immoral act. Doing so solely for increased profits is even more immoral because you are only seeking material gain. Note I say profits, increasing rent because you costs (fees, taxes, maintenance costs, insurance, etc) have gone up is moral. But raising prices such so you can make more profit is not if your price increase is high enough to harm people. Forcing them to move is harm. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699310338.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>1. Profit is not inherently immoral. Material gain is no more or less immoral than any other justification. It would be wildly stupid for a landlord to reduce his profits. If someone will pay, who gives a shit who it is? (From the landlord's perspective)

2. "Forcing" someone to move is not immoral. If the person can't afford the house they shouldn't live in it. If they can't afford any housing, they should not live anywhere. Sucks but it's true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699586271.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Profit from harming someone is immoral. 

Your entire second point is immoral. Everyone deserves to live in a home. Forcing someone to be homeless is immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699586399.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Profit from harming someone is immoral. 

Your entire second point is immoral. Everyone deserves to live in a home. Forcing someone to be homeless is immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699588009.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>1) Profit from harming someone is inherently immoral. Forcing someone to move is harming them. 

2) This entire point is immoral. Allowing homelessness to be a possibility is immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700093891.0" user="ProfessorHeartcraft" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "Forcing" someone to move is not immoral. If the person can't afford the house they shouldn't live in it. If they can't afford any housing, they should not live anywhere. Sucks but it's true.

Most people would consider that position grossly immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29700096212.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I am not most people, then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701405153.0" user="Epicloa" delta="False">
    <text>The whole basis of your logic has a pretty clear cutoff point though. In your theoretical world what would stop people from completely monopolizing/price-fixing housing? Since there's no moral repercussions in your book that is clearly the logic thing to do, and since there's really no limit to how large that bubble could get and people need housing you're pretty much guaranteed to have a very small but extremely wealthy group of land owners and then everyone else in complete poverty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701426624.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In your theoretical world what would stop people from completely monopolizing/price-fixing housing

1. Assuming fair business practices, a monopoly that works against the people could not form. It gets sketchy with the housing law, but generally speaking if someone could provide housing for less, and there was a demand for it, competition would arise.

2. In the unlikely event of a complete unfair monopoly, the market would crash or a new market would form separate from the old.

3. A bubble will always burst given enough time, monopoly or otherwise. Once the speculation stops, the value plummets and landlords are forced to rent at a price that people are willing to pay.

Here's an example:

Bob owns all the housing in New York and nobody can enter the market. He sets the rent unilaterally to $1,000,000/month and whips up a frenzy of rich idiots to rent his housing. Eventually the frenzy dies down and the money runs out, and Bob is left with an empty city because all the rich speculators have left. Naturally, Bob then sets the rent to something that *someone* will pay, and works it back up from there until an equilibrium is reached.

Price-fixing is immoral btw because it gives the illusion of competition, altering the perceived value of the goods. It is a lie. Price-fixing is also not inherent in capitalism, and is illegal in the real world.

&amp;gt;everyone else in complete poverty.

Or living fine in another city.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701444665.0" user="Epicloa" delta="False">
    <text>1. Why assume fair business practices? If it's not immoral I see no reason it wouldn't occur, which also negates your "move to a new city thing" because everyone would be doing it because there is no downside. I'd argue that the reason it doesn't occur is specifically because of the resultant outrage due to it's level of immorality.

2. Why would it crash? People need a place to live and if their work/family/livelihood is in the city they will pay ever increasing prices to stay there. Look at prices of apartments in NYC/LA, they are high enough to force people to room with 3-4 other people just to afford the cost of living, and that exists with spotlight and regulation. If that was removed all that would change would be increasing the density of people in single apartments, which has a load of negatives for those people but just equals increasingly more money for the landowners. The opportunity of these cities keeps people coming to them, and leaves them ripe for manipulation and exploitation. A more extreme example to me are the cities in Asia with insane population density, would you consider those immoral or are those people just choosing to live in those conditions despite them being their only options?

3. This is not a bubble, it's a planned exploitation of a necessity. 

Why is price-fixing immoral? If people are willing to pay that price doesn't that justify the capitalist aspect of that? By your own admission they are not actively hurting people they are just finding the upper limits of what someone would pay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699732595.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>Forcing people to move is immoral?

That's laughable at best.

Let's make a scenario here. 

I purchase a house for $150,000.  I used a mortgage to get 80% of the capital.  20% of the capital was mine.  For whatever reason, I decide to move (say, I get married).

I then find some renters and we agree to a rent value for a year.  After that year, I go and do a bit of research and discover that my house has gone up in value.  Let's say 7%.  As such, for it to be worth my while to continue renting, I need to increase rents.

You're telling me that it's immoral to raise the rent?  That I have to continue renting the house for that same rate for all time?  My costs haven't changed.  The mortgage payment is the same, insurance, taxes, etc. are all still roughly the same.  

Additionally, I'm not allowed to sell this house to someone who intends to live in at as their primary residence?  What about if I'm reasonably confident that the future landlord will raise the rates?  Can I sell then?

I have to sit here and bankroll my renters for the rest of time because I entered into a 1 year lease and that 1 year is now over?

Sorry man, but I don't see how morality plays into this at all.  I should be able to charge what I want to charge.  I can't fuck people over mid-lease sure, but I shouldn't be expected to continue charging people at both below market rates and at "negative opportunity cost" rates (you understand what I'm saying, right?) given the amount of capital I now have tied up in the investment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701409451.0" user="Epicloa" delta="False">
    <text>I mean that's a pretty arbitrary line to draw though and that's what makes this a difficult topic. A 7% increase may be totally acceptable but what if say 3 people own all the apartments in a complex and agree to hike all the rates 25%? Does that become an immoral action? The intent is the same, the only difference is the amount changed, and if it is just a certain threshold how would you quantify that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29701556417.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, collusion is immoral. That's the huge difference in these two examples.  One landlord is reacting to market forces and ensuring he gets a fair price for hit capital tied up in the house, the other 3 are colluding and driving up rent prices independent of market forces.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29705258961.0" user="Epicloa" delta="False">
    <text>But that isn't how rent works, they are only responding to market forces in the sense that they are trying to hit the peak of what someone will pay, and that is not true in pretty much any other product to the same extent because there will always be truer competition. Landlords can charge pretty much whatever they feel is right in major cities because they know that someone will buy it, and no amount of competition would change that unless people we're buying up entire zones of housing which would never happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29705302037.0" user="Pinewood74" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not even sure how to respond to it because A) it's nonsense that landlords can charge "whatever they want" (if that's the case, why are rent prices vastly different between the 20 largest cities in this country?) and B) it's gone pretty far from the topic of "forcing people to move is immoral" which is what I was attacking.

You're obviously not the above poster, but the above poster posited that my 7% raise would be immoral as it would force someone to move.

No landlord owns a monopoly in any of the major cities.  There is ample competition.  The reason rent prices rise is because the demand outstrips supply.  If supply outstripped demand, then rent drops.  You can't charge "whatever you want" because if you charged $15k for rent on a studio apartment, folks wouldn't pay it, they'd go next door to someone charging a reasonable amount or they'd drive an additional 20 minutes every day for someone charging a reasonable amount.

Landlords charge what the market can bear (or the peak of what they'll pay), but if housing prices rise by 7%, they're going to need to charge more for rent or it makes little sense to continue owning the house unless they anticipate more 7% increases in housing.

Lastly,

What does this even mean?

&amp;gt;no amount of competition would change that unless people we're buying up entire zones of housing which would never happen.

Wouldn't "people" buying up entire zones of housing be what would allow someone to charge "whatever they want."  Having more owners in a certain area rather than less allows for more competition, but you're putting forth the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
