<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="427286909.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/72e8ot/cmv_advertisements_data_mining_and_targeted/">
    <title>CMV : advertisements, data mining and targeted marketing isn’t unethical</title>
    <original_poster>The_IOvOI</original_poster>
    <original_post>With all these posts on the front page and comments on the measures people undergo to avoid targeted advertisements and data mining I was curious as to why there is such a strong opposition to this. The way I’ve always seen it is that google / amazon etc are providing a service, and instead of paying 20 cents every google search you let google use your data so that they can be profitable. I’m curious as to why people seem so against this as opposed to paying every time to use the service. 

Also as a sidenote, aren’t targeted advertisements a good thing? Instead of being shown silly ads that don’t do anything good for you your getting things that are actually relevant towards your interests. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29718861458.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>What's problematic is what the landscape is going to be like in 10 or 20 years. Google will know everything about you, your locations, habits, money spending, private emails, and even your private most thoughts (i.e. what have you typed into a search bar past 30 days in private mode?).

With this massive erosion of privacy, what sort of nightmarish reality might we face? 

People instead would like to limit what google and others know about you on a personal basis, to avoid a potentially hellish experience in the future. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29719362793.0" user="The_IOvOI" delta="False">
    <text>How could google use this to make a “hellish” experience? I’m struggling to think of reasons they would have to exploit people with this information other than how they already do, with targeted ads and such. If google was ever caught selling people’s private information to criminals or using it with the intent to steal or harm people there would be massive backlash. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29719436743.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>One scenario - say you had powerful people in Google who wanted to influence an election, or appointment of a new CEO. All they would have to do is dig into the multitude of private info, find something compromising, leak to the press and boom the candidate is eviscerated. No one would even know google was behind it. Top dogs in google could wield immense world power through this initiative. 

Second, all these infrastructures could be taken hold by a hostile government between now and the next 200 years. They would know absolutely everything about us and could police us based on our searches, emails, etc. 

Just two examples, both are hellish.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29719637632.0" user="The_IOvOI" delta="False">
    <text>Ahhh thank you, makes a lot more sense now </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
