<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="427286909.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/72e8ot/cmv_advertisements_data_mining_and_targeted/">
    <title>CMV : advertisements, data mining and targeted marketing isn’t unethical</title>
    <original_poster>The_IOvOI</original_poster>
    <original_post>With all these posts on the front page and comments on the measures people undergo to avoid targeted advertisements and data mining I was curious as to why there is such a strong opposition to this. The way I’ve always seen it is that google / amazon etc are providing a service, and instead of paying 20 cents every google search you let google use your data so that they can be profitable. I’m curious as to why people seem so against this as opposed to paying every time to use the service. 

Also as a sidenote, aren’t targeted advertisements a good thing? Instead of being shown silly ads that don’t do anything good for you your getting things that are actually relevant towards your interests. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29718855440.0" user="SOLUNAR" delta="False">
    <text>issue is how much is too much? for me to target to you successfully i ned to mine more than your probably comfortable with. Let's say i start going through your bank records to see where you shop the most, i can now send you some awesome deals for those restaurants but i also had a peak at your financials.

The upside? awesome ads

downside? i have all of this data, and odds are someone is looking to get it for malicious purposes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29719368735.0" user="The_IOvOI" delta="False">
    <text>Ok that makes sense, however could you explain to me how this could be used maliciously? I know with the example of equifax people’s identities could get stolen but the vast majority of companies the information they gather couldn’t be use to directly attack people, right? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
