<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="429689730.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/73tqpu/cmv_in_the_future_we_should_have_a_privacyfocused/">
    <title>CMV: In the future, we should have a privacy-focused AI research initiative to identify and end violence and crime.</title>
    <original_poster>AnimeVRexpert</original_poster>
    <original_post>What I mean is that in 5-10 years(or more), when AI is advanced enough to identify and understand with 99.9%+ accuracy exactly what people are doing, we should have them monitoring us worldwide, of course without any human being able to access the recordings. Why?
                                                                                               I 
I can't see many disadvantages to this if done right.
1- Crime would be 90%+ reduced and everyone enjoys a peaceful life because as soon as a crime happens, police would be notified instantly or maybe the AI itself could handle it.

2- Privacy will not only be maintained, it will be increased since there will be fewer excuses for human surveillance.

3- End of terrorism since AI would predict the act before it happens

4- AI could predict suicides and give statistics like "people are 30% happier in the UK" or something like it, helping the world become a much better place.

5- The possibilities are endless, we could save countless lives and help people live better in unimaginable ways.

Disadvantages:

People seem to be against this idea, I [posted a comment](https://www.reddit.com/r/news/comments/73r0uu/active_shooter_at_mandalay_bay_casino_in_las_vegas/dnswcz3/) about the recent tragedy that happened in LA and got massively downvoted(Maybe the part about the drones contributed, what I meant was an AI controlled pacifist drone that would only use tranquilizers so no one gets hurt), this means my view is probably wrong, and I realized now is a perfect time to use CMV.

Would appreciate if you could tell me why my view is wrong or maybe I just presented it the wrong way in the comment.     </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29737616818.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the biggest issue with your proposal is the fact that we have no idea how to create an AI like you are suggesting.  We can't even develop models that predict _the weather_ more than a couple of days in advance due to the number of variables involved and such a model would be near infinity simpler than a model that could predict human behavior so well as to predict 99.9% of all crime.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29737624548.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that's what the OP is proposing. I think he's proposing AI surveillance of occurring crimes through a video system. Not some kind of precrime division. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29737627871.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>I'm basing this assumption off of the second sentence in the OP:

&amp;gt;when AI is advanced enough to identify and understand with 99.9%+ accuracy exactly what people are doing

He also discussed other "predictions" the AI would make, like ending terrorism and suicide.  Seems reasonable that he is advocating for some type of pre-crime like system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29737638591.0" user="AnimeVRexpert" delta="False">
    <text>[Machine learning](http://news.mit.edu/2016/teaching-machines-to-predict-the-future-0621) is advancing very fast, one day not more than 10-20 years, we will probably be able to do it, Google, Microsoft and other big companies are putting a lot of money into research, Elon Musk has [expressed his views](https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/aug/14/elon-musk-ai-vastly-more-risky-north-korea) about the future of AI and other very important people have too. Of course, the future can't be predicted with 100% accuracy, but I think it will probably happen, and I believe AI can be used for good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29737644211.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that machine learning is advancing fast is a _far_ cry from what you are suggesting is feasible in crime prevention.  We have been building computer models of the weather for nearly 50 years and we _still_ can't predict it more than a few days in advance.

Yes, maybe _someday_ AI like this _might_ exist, but it is so far off  in the future that is may as well be magic.  Moreover, how do we know that _when_ such an AI could exist that the problems that really cause crime (like socioeconomic difficulties) haven't already been eradicated by other inventions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29737670464.0" user="AnimeVRexpert" delta="False">
    <text>More specifically as the link from MIT I gave above, predictive AI is advancing very fast, even if socioeconomic difficulties are 99%+ solved, there will still be crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
