<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="430134660.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/743a10/cmvmen_are_more_annoying_than_women/">
    <title>CMV:men are more annoying than women</title>
    <original_poster>fayhill92</original_poster>
    <original_post>


Ok, I don't want to be sexist towards men, I really don't, I have a good few male friends. But I've had some really bad experiences with men, and very few bad experiences with women relatively speaking.

As a child I was abused at home by my brother, and was bullied at school, mostly by boys. My closest friends in primary school were girls, who often stuck up for me, same in high school too. My childhood psychologist was also male and did such a fucking shit job, just saw me as a problem child and didn't help at all that if he didn't get fired I would be maybe not surprised, but worried about the UK's mental health services. Furthermore I'm visually impared and had 3 social workers to help with this, 2 female one male, guess who the only one was that wasn't good, yep the male one who was utter shit.

On top of that I've had 2 guys shout in my face to try and scare me, and multiple guys shout at me in general, hit me, slap my arse, harass me such as one who wouldn't let me use the male toilets(I'm trans but haven't started to transition yet) and I never get any of this trouble from women. And of course they put on badman voices innit bruv to prove how bad dey is innit bruv, and usually the incidents happen late at night when I'm by myself, and as well as being visually impared I'm small and not even slightly intimidating in looks and do look androgenous, doubt I'd get this shit if I was a 6ft muscled guy.

Furthermore, as I said I have male friends, but it's only with my female friends I feel comfortable talking about more personal issues. Plus when with the guys it can get annoying as I'm not out as trans and they can tease me in a friendly way for being effeminate using the gay slur. I know it's not meant to be hurtful, but I really disagree with using gay or anything similar as an insult even a teasing insult or whatever. It can also get annoying as they talk about women sexually...a lot, with the girls they do talk about guys, but talk about relationships, relationship issues etc. Stereotypical I know, but this is my experience. Considering I am not into just seeing women as sex objects(duh :p ) or not crude like that it can get annoying. It can also be annoying as they are in general a lot more crude, rude and well laddish I guess than my female friends. It sounds like I hate them xd, I don't but too much of this full on masculinity can be annoying.

So yeah, sorry for the long post. But I don't want to be sexist, but I've had a lot of bad experiences and the fact incidents such as being shouted at, harassed etc still happen and it's only men who do it really makes it hard for me to not be sexist. Plus masculinity is a lot more toxic than femininity in my experience, my female friends never call each other lesbians for not being girly enough or tease me for not being manly enough, and in general seem much more comfortable not having to comform to gender stereotypes. So yeah any help challenging this view would be much appreciated, thanks in advance :) .</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29741469319.0" user="FyrW" delta="False">
    <text>You're sexist and if you don't want to be sexist, then don't. Not all men are like that. And grow a pair</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
