<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431884814.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/">
    <title>CMV: Islam is not a religion of peace or tolerance.</title>
    <original_poster>VanGoghingSomewhere</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Koran speaks of women as property, Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer and pedophile/polygamist who thought women had inherently deficient minds. Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom. ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran. Jihad has existed as long as Islam. Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates. What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism. Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.    
  
  EDIT:  
  
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
For anyone saying that violence and intolerance are only a misinterpretation of subtext (though many who are educated on the Koran in the thread have explained that Allah's word is strictly set and not to be interpreted), I encourage you to read these passages. If the Koran is a text to be interpreted by it's followers, how do you spin these words to be peaceful or tolerant? I truly don't get it.  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  

&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement"
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  

&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.
Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*  
  
  EDIT 2:

Any attempt to change my view in this thread has been a apologist answer citing false equivalency, or an appeal to emotion by trying to separate the wheat from the chaff (nice Muslims = peaceful Islam).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29755847582.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>All you need to be a Muslim is to follow the 5 pillars of Islam, which are:

-Believe that there is one God, and that Muhammad is a prophet of this God, and publically declare this regularly

-Pray to that God 5 times a day

-Give 2% of your income or more to charity

-Fast during the day during the month of Ramadan

-Go to Mecca at some point in your life

Anything else is fluff. Maybe that fluff is intolerant or violent (really it's more nuanced than that, some of it is and some of it isn't), but it's still fluff. The religion itself isn't inherently violent or intolerant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756620800.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Mohammed's word, specific commands, and specific guide to life (Sharia) are not fluff. Ignoring them as fundamental aspects of the religion is negligent. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757000381.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>You're saying that because a lot of Muslims take Mohammed's word as law, right?

That's certainly true, but not all Muslims do, because you don't need to take his word as law in order to be a Muslim.

In order to condemn a religion, you need to focus on the religion itself, and Islam is the 5 pillars.

Don't take this as an appeal to faith (because I don't know what your religion is), I'm only bringing it up because it's the first good example outside of Islam:

A common criticism of Christianity I hear is about the law that you can't mix fabrics. It's invalid because it's not central to Christianity. Christianity is believing that there's only one god worth worshipping, and that this god's son (take it literally or figuratively) forgave you of your sins (and what that means is up for debate and has always been debated).

That's not a valid criticism because it doesn't attack the religion itself, it attacks a sect or individual belief, just like citing the Qur'an and the words of other Muslims isn't valid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757253180.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>To say that passages in the bible about mixed fabric are as central to Christianity as Mohammed's word is to Islam is to make a wild false equivalency.   
  
I've stated this many times in this thread, being a peaceful Muslim does not make Islam a peaceful ideology. Period.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757257780.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>It's extreme, but it's the same thing.

Mohammad's word is not central to Islam. Only the 5 pillars are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29761129550.0" user="TaneCorbin" delta="False">
    <text>Mohammed is considered a prophet, not a messiah the way Christ is considered to Christians. It's more fair to interpret his words the same way a Jew or Christian would interpret Moses' words. That is, generally, as a product of the times and more about what God thought people needed to hear than literal instructions. Moses had slaves and multiple wives, etc yet your post doesn't claim that Judaism is inherently not a religion of peace or tolerance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757099858.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Mohammed's word, specific commands, and specific guide to life (Sharia) are not fluff.

First, the foundation of Islam is the statement, "There is no god but God, and Mohammed is his prophet".

Second, there are multiple competing traditions of Sharia law.  Which one is the true fundamental component of Islam?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757262564.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Which tradition of Sharia Law is peaceful or tolerant? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757392368.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Which tradition of Sharia Law is peaceful or tolerant?

For the record, this response by necessity contains extremely broad generalizations about different schools of Islamic thought.  This is pretty much necessary to keep this response succinct while still addressing differing opinions regarding a centuries-old religion spanning multiple continents.

Several reformist schools of Sharia have no problem with other religious faiths or with non-religious people, and many not only expect but welcome secular law traditions when dealing with non-religious matters. While most Muslims traditionally consider Sharia to be immutable, most also acknowledge that the *fiqh* or human interpretation of Sharia, to be fallible and open to correction, criticism, and differing interpretations.    

For instanced, followers of some sects of Usuli (itself a subset of Ja'fari jurisprudence, primarily followed by Shia Muslims) are quite liberal, and consider secular, cultural, and historical circumstances to be an important source of Islamic law.  However it's worth noting that Iran operates largely under a version this school of thought, so not all followers of this approach to Sharia are necessarily peaceful or tolerant.

In contrast, the Sunni schools of jurisprudence Hanafi, Maliki, Shafi'i, and Hanbali are in general much stricter.  Hanbali is, in general, the strictest of these due to its refusal to accept community practices or community consensus as a source of Islamic law when conflicts arise.  Essentially, these traditions differ on the extent to which current and past historical context matters.

Within all of these schools of thought and sects of Islam are subsects which disagree on what exactly constitutes religious law, and what level that law is.  For instance, many disagree about whether an action is something that all Muslims *must* do, or is it merely a strong recommendation?  e.g. Can a person who is extremely ill or malnourished be allowed to eat during Ramadan? (most Islamic traditions say yes).  

This is an extremely diverse and complex topic, and the massive disagreements between groups make stating anything about all Sharia law pretty pointless.  It's a lot like saying "well Christian doctrine *demands* you not wear any mixed fabrics".  Yeah, some sects of Christianity require their followers to do that (e.g. the Amish), but others don't.  

So yeah, there's some messed-up shit in the Q'uran, and there are differences between Islam and Christianity (Islam, for instance, tends to have more direct involvement in political systems than Christianity does, though this was not always historically the case).  I don't think that makes Islam inherently violent or intolerant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760975528.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>If you're not going to even bother responding to thorough replies to your arguments, what exactly would it take to change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757563702.0" user="anooblol" delta="False">
    <text>I have to disagree slightly. 

&amp;gt; Anything else is fluff. Maybe that fluff is intolerant or violent (really it's more nuanced than that, some of it is and some of it isn't), but it's still fluff. The religion itself isn't inherently violent or intolerant.

This is not a valid statement. Catholicism, all you need to do is accept Jesus Christ as your lord and savior. The requirement of being Catholic is very simple, but it does not define Catholic values. Technically, you do not need to follow the 10 commandments. But it's something that's still a part of Catholicism, and is valued.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757589430.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>A Catholic is a Christian who follows the Pope. So Catholic values are anything the Pope says are Catholic values.

Catholic values are included in what it means to be Catholic.

Although I don't like that phrase because it implies that Christian values are included in what it means to be Christian, but here "values" are different to in Catholic values, and Christian values (in that sense) are not included in the definition of Christianity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757596830.0" user="anooblol" delta="False">
    <text>A christian is not required to follow the pope. Literally **the only thing** you need to do, is accept Jesus Christ as your lord and savior. All else, even following the Pope is fluff. The fluff is important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757604819.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>Correct. A Christian is not required to follow the Pope. That's just fluff.

However, a Catholic is required to follow the Pope.

The fluff (or lack thereof) is what makes a religious sect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757617532.0" user="anooblol" delta="False">
    <text>That's just being pedantic. Fine, Christianity. Point still holds. The fluff is important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757622393.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>The fluff is important, but it's still fluff.

Criticizing the fluff is criticizing the sects and people that contain the fluff, not the whole religion itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757625589.0" user="anooblol" delta="False">
    <text>Then by that logic, the only thing that matters about being a christian is accepting a deity. Christianity is a religion about arbitrarily accepting someone as God.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757637526.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>No, Christianity is about accepting this god (and no other god) and believing that this god's son (whether you take that literally or figuratively) forgave you of your sins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757662887.0" user="anooblol" delta="False">
    <text>You're completely nullifying everything about the religion. This is certainly **not** what it means to be a Christian. This is merely the requirement of being one. Masses are held, and people are taught a certain way of life. Those are incredibly important aspects of the religion that you are flat out ignoring. You need to look at the fluff to make an accurate judgement of the whole religion. The requirements are not the teachings of a religion. There's a lot more to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757681091.0" user="SparkySywer" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, exactly. That is not what it means to be a Christian, it's the requirement of one. Fluff is a very important part of religion.

But it's still fluff. By attacking fluff, you aren't attacking the religion.

If it's possible for a person to adhere to a religion without participating in some fluff, then it's not a criticism of the ideology.

For a non-religious example, let's take the ideology of not liking Nazis.

All you have to do not like Nazis is not like Nazis. So by attacking people who don't like Nazis and beat people up when they think they're Nazis, you're only attacking them. You aren't attacking everyone who doesn't like Nazis.

It's the same thing. Fluff isn't central to a religion, so by attacking the fluff, you aren't truly attacking the religion.

Everything OP cites in his criticism of Islam is fluff. Yes, there is a valid point behind his criticism, and the fluff he cites can and does inspire violence and intolerance. But it's not a valid criticism of Islam because it *is* fluff. It isn't Islam, it's an extension of Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
