<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431884814.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/">
    <title>CMV: Islam is not a religion of peace or tolerance.</title>
    <original_poster>VanGoghingSomewhere</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Koran speaks of women as property, Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer and pedophile/polygamist who thought women had inherently deficient minds. Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom. ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran. Jihad has existed as long as Islam. Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates. What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism. Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.    
  
  EDIT:  
  
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
For anyone saying that violence and intolerance are only a misinterpretation of subtext (though many who are educated on the Koran in the thread have explained that Allah's word is strictly set and not to be interpreted), I encourage you to read these passages. If the Koran is a text to be interpreted by it's followers, how do you spin these words to be peaceful or tolerant? I truly don't get it.  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  

&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement"
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  

&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.
Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*  
  
  EDIT 2:

Any attempt to change my view in this thread has been a apologist answer citing false equivalency, or an appeal to emotion by trying to separate the wheat from the chaff (nice Muslims = peaceful Islam).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29755157249.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>On paper, Islam preaches tolerance-ish and peace.

On paper, Islam is no more violent than Christianity.

On paper, Islam doesn't oppress women any more than Christianity, and generally just preaches division of labor.

*Muslims* on the other hand, have carried out something like 75% of global terrorism, still practice slavery, treat women like domesticated animals, and have a shockingly high rate of inbreeding.

You aren't going to get many good faith replies, OP.  You're in for a lot of silent downvotes and condescension.  I honestly believe this is the best you're going to get.

Islam itself is pretty neutral.  It's Muslims that ruin its reputation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755196693.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Catholics believe Christ's word is law.  
 Muslim's believe Mohammed's word is law.    
  

As it is suggested, Christ lived a life without sex, vice, or greed, and taught absolute forgiveness and tolerance toward your enemy.    
  
As is suggested, Mohammed lived a life of rape, murder, and discrimination.
  
If the end all be all of these two religions are their prophets, then Christianity is tolerant and Islam is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755212573.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Christ condoned and tolerated slavery, but I’ve never met a Catholic who did the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755228355.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus never said slavery was cool, he merely allowed it because everyone around him was practicing it. 

And you are missing the main point.  Jesus Christ walked around and preached rules that were incredibly progressive around his time.  A follower asks him what is your most important rule and Jesus replies, "love your fellow man".  Muhammad replies "Jihad".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755231106.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Which line of the Koran is that from ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755247803.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>I am sorry I am mistaken Muhammad says Jihad the is the 3rd greatest deed.  And this cannot be found in the Quran, it can only be found in the Hadiths.
I asked Allah's Messenger (ﷺ), "O Allah's Messenger (ﷺ)! What is the best deed?" He replied, "To offer the prayers at their early stated fixed times." I asked, "What is next in goodness?" He replied, "To be good and dutiful to your parents." I further asked, what is next in goodness?" He replied, "To participate in Jihad in Allah's Cause." I did not ask Allah's Messenger (ﷺ) anymore and if I had asked him more, he would have told me more.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755263535.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The ahadith refers to different hadith collections, and different branches of Islam (Sunni, Shia, Ibadi) consult different collections of hadith, while the relatively small sect of Quranists reject the authority of any of the hadith collections altogether.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hadith

Which sects are you referring to in your comment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755285549.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know exactly what the Quran is?  It is the words Muhammad says when he channels Allah. 

Imagine a play called the Sirah and you only have the lines from one character when he is channeling another character.  And they are out of order in the story.

You would have no idea what the plot would be. That is why you need the hadiths which says

1. what the other characters are saying

2. The background of what they are saying

3.What else is the main character saying when he's not channeling Allah.

Now I've never read any of the Shia hadiths, but the Sunnis(90% of Muslims) regard Bukhari as rock solid.


Sahih al-Bukhari is one of the six canonical Hadith collections of Sunni Islam. Sunni Muslims regard it as being the most authentic of the six, and is considered to be the most authentic book after Qur-an.[2] Sahih al-Bukhari contains a chapter "Fighting for the Cause of Allah (Jihad)".[3]

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755241040.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus does not condone slavery. Though he doesn't set His people on a crusade against it. Only God had dominion over slaves, they were no lesser of spirit. Slaves were a prevalent part of society during Jesus's lifetime and Jesus proclaimed that the servant and his owner both belonged to the same master.  
  
This is wholly different than physically taking slaves by the sword and having young sex servants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755984978.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>You're just a few years too late. It's not like there never were any, or even that they weren't the majority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755247590.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>The vast majority of the Bible is not about Jesus though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755263234.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus is not a footnote in the Bible lol. Christianity. Christ. What Christ teaches takes absolute precedent in the Bible. Same goes for Mohammed in the Koran.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755274882.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus is the focus of 4 books in the 43 book Bible.

He's out umbered 10 to 1 by the old testament.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755288490.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus has the final say on the old testament. If he didn't, Christianity would have died with him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755291174.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>Matthew 18:18

The Pope has final say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755926152.0" user="thewanderer0" delta="False">
    <text>Get out of here you know what he meant. Anything in the New Testament supercedes the Old Testament</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755987071.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>Why is the old testament still there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756315063.0" user="insaneHoshi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Matthew 18:18

Thats the new testament.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756558387.0" user="waaza0" delta="False">
    <text>What you are missing about the bible is that jesus condemned litteral interpretation of the old testament. His chapters are filled with him pissing off the religious and conservative jewish leaders. 

I see a number of important distinctions between the bible and the quran. one of them is that the bible is waaay more inconsistent about its main message than the quran is. This makes both books dangerous in different ways. Understanding these differences is extremely important if we want to have a succesful and fruitful war of ideas. 

There is a saying that 'one can defend every position with a bible in his hands', or something like that. This quite true, this makes the bible only as dangerous or as good as the people who follow it. The quran, however, is a litteral word of god with a consistent message that includes a lot of violence. Interpreting the quran peacefully is just a hard task, I'd go as far as to argue that it is impossible to when you examine it thoroughly and rationally. A peaceful someone who either does not really know his texts, does not fully understand them or has an irrational belief system that would not uphold scrutiny. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29758884494.0" user="Swiss_Army_Cheese" delta="False">
    <text>You're ignoring the fact that Jesus returned from the dead, making Christianity *undie* with him.

We're still waiting for someone else to have the final, final say (which is where disputes with Muslims and Mormans come into play, as they stopped waiting).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755476346.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>By the same stroke, its the whites that are the problem if you look at them from a perspective of a black person.

&amp;gt;White people on the other hand, have carried out something like 75% of anti-black oppression in north america throughout history.

OP and you ***will*** get silent downvotes and condescension. Most people aren't interested in getting shallow arguments. 

The rules of this subreddit say you have to attempt to change OP's mind in the initial reply. If you wish to echo each other's beliefs, you have safe space over at T_D.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755496330.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>White isnt an ideology.  Black isn't an idology.

Your argument is flawed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755527899.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>It's not, I drew a parallel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755583589.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>Draw a parallel to an idea then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755586187.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>I did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755627726.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>Which ideology?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755672409.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>[Here.](https://www.google.com/search?q=drawing+a+parallel+idiom&amp;amp;spell=1&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiw0cfRvOLWAhUCI8AKHRmtBHoQvwUIIygA&amp;amp;biw=1366&amp;amp;bih=647)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755708480.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>You linked to Google instead of a comment by accident.

What ideology we're you drawing a parallel from Islam to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755723200.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>Parallel ***TO*** religious ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755810832.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>So you're just drawing a false equivalence.

You could have just saved me a lot of time.

What about white Muslims?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755822132.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>Explain to me how that is a false equivalence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757029106.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>One is an ideology, a choice.  One is a glorified tan.

It's like saying "poor people commit more crimes" and "black people commit more crimes" as separate ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757084121.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>No.

You can draw a, very logical, parallel between racial differences and religious differences. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757091589.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>Not unless ones primary goal in every conversation is to rebut with "but white people are the REAL bad guys".

Can you make a different parallel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757113814.0" user="boomer15x" delta="False">
    <text>I can, but why should I?

This parallel sufficiently explains why your logic is flawed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757124261.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>Your parallel is flawed.

This conversation isn't constructive, goodbye.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757151134.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757224148.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>boomer15x, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 2\. "Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostility extremely seriously. Repeated violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+boomer15x&amp;amp;message=boomer15x+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/do4n0ri/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756196456.0" user="AdmiralSignUp" delta="False">
    <text>I believe you're a bit off in your 75% of global terrorism carried out by muslims. Even within America between 1980 en 2005 the terrorist attacks performed by Muslims is only 6%. [FBI report](https://www.google.nl/amp/s/www.globalresearch.ca/non-muslims-carried-out-more-than-90-of-all-terrorist-attacks-in-america/5333619/amp) 

If you look at the data in the rest of the world Irak and Afghanistan rate high but do not, by far, reach 75% [our world in data ](https://ourworldindata.org/terrorism/) 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757034830.0" user="LoveTrumpedHate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In 2015 four Islamic extremist groups were responsible for 74% of all deaths from terrorism: ISIS, Boko Haram, the Taliban and Al-Qaeda, according to the Global Terrorism Index 2016.

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islamic_terrorism</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
