<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431884814.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/">
    <title>CMV: Islam is not a religion of peace or tolerance.</title>
    <original_poster>VanGoghingSomewhere</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Koran speaks of women as property, Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer and pedophile/polygamist who thought women had inherently deficient minds. Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom. ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran. Jihad has existed as long as Islam. Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates. What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism. Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.    
  
  EDIT:  
  
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
For anyone saying that violence and intolerance are only a misinterpretation of subtext (though many who are educated on the Koran in the thread have explained that Allah's word is strictly set and not to be interpreted), I encourage you to read these passages. If the Koran is a text to be interpreted by it's followers, how do you spin these words to be peaceful or tolerant? I truly don't get it.  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  

&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement"
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  

&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.
Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*  
  
  EDIT 2:

Any attempt to change my view in this thread has been a apologist answer citing false equivalency, or an appeal to emotion by trying to separate the wheat from the chaff (nice Muslims = peaceful Islam).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29755864685.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>If wrote a 15 page term paper on this topic. Pretty hard to summarize with proper evidence and explanation in a succinct manner, but essentially the Qur'an is actually an incredibly peaceful work, and in many cases, progressive for women (again, a lot of backwork, but for a quick example, Joseph is not mentioned in the Qur'an in regards to the Christmas story. Most of the character references are centric to Mary, e.g. Mary's husband. Not sure on the exact phrasing so if you happen to look it up don't hold me to that, but the concept holds true). 

If you compare different stories between the Bible and the Qur'an, the Qur'an often is much more peaceful. The difference however is that in the western world, the Bible is socialized and accepted and thus portrayed in a fairly positive light in conjunction with Christianity, while Islam and thus the Qur'an is not. If you look at the roots of either text and in context of 6-7th century Arabia when the Qur'an first emerged, this is clear to see. 

Religion and scripture are remarkably different. I mean, think of some of the very literal things the Bible has to say about ludicrous things the vast majority of people would just brush off (I believe there's something saying what you can and cannot wear that's very narrowly defined?) as insignificant, largely due to context, differences between ancient Arabia and 21st century modern world, etc. So why don't we do this with the Qur'an? Islam is portrayed extremely negatively due to terrorism and vast cultural differences between the western world and the Middle East. These differences are an entirely different discussion, so let's put that on the shelf for now (for example, women's rights. Definitely an issue, but not a problem unique to Islam or the Middle East.). Just think about it this way: the KKK has certainly hijacked Christianity just as ISIS has hijacked Islam, but the difference is that the western world is used to and accepting of Christianity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755993565.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, Christianity does not claim that the Bible is a first party source for the literal word of God and so it gets reinterpreted, or even rewritten, quite often.

My understanding is that the Quran is not subject to such reinterpretation and is thought to be the literal word of God.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756006173.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>Sort of. The Qur'an is thought to be the literal word of God in the sense that they think God literally spoke through Muhammad and that when he spoke the Qur'an, it wasn't just that he was the messenger, it was God literally speaking. It is said that the actual Qur'an is written on a tablet and that the message was merely relayed -- which is why the Hadith are so important/central to discussions about the Qur'an.

Edit: wasn't drawing the comparison to shit on Christianity, I'm not religious myself. Just at the root, the Qur'an as a document is peaceful. Like anything, it can be misconstrued, and has been, which is why we have the misconception that Islam in its truest sense is a hostile religion. But making this claim is about an entire population is about true as any of the other biased stereotypes we've had in the world about the Other. I don't blame OP or anyone who has this idea in their head, it's totally perpetuated by the media and most people just don't understand Islam at the core. I studied the Qur'an for a year and I'm still learning, so it's totally understandable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756104357.0" user="MenShouldntHaveCats" delta="False">
    <text>You make good points. But if the Bible and Quran were one in the same. You would expect their followers and regions to be more a like or have comparable societies. But anyone who has been to an Islamic country knows they vastly different. Sure some of it is cultural. But it doesn't account for why Islam has never really gone through a renaissance like Christianity has. I think it is the way Islam treats dissidents. Over half of muslims worldwide believe anyone who leaves Islam should be put to death. There are still a handful of countries that have the death penalty for leaving Islam as well.

And we've all seen the videos or read what happens in a lot of Islamic countries for those who criticize Islam. I think a lot of it has to do how Islam was spread. Which was totally by the sword. Anywhere there is a majority of muslims. Other religions are really not tolerated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756224307.0" user="ChaosInfest" delta="False">
    <text>Although it is actually from islamic countries that we have a lot of the early works that the renaissance used as a basis. Many of the ancient greek texts (Plato, Aristotle, e.t.c.) were recovered and translated by Islamic scholars in, I want to say the 1200's? I can't source atm, but remind me and I'll see what I can do tomorrow.

There are also a number of other economic and cultural reasons that the Islamic World never underwent a renaissance in the same way as the west, and the idea that "Christianity" went through a renaissance is also not accurate, as large elements of the renaissance were devoted to the belittling of Christianity as it related to the state. So while it is correct to say that the Christian world was the home of the renaissance, it would be inaccurate to say that Christianity, the religion, went through a renaissance.

Further, a lot of christian communities used to murder, maim, enslave, e.t.c. people who criticised Christianity, or even followed a slightly different interpretation of the Bible. Islam was not spread entirely by the sword, but like christianity was also spread through a combination of warfare, trade, missionary work, e.t.c.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756875458.0" user="MenShouldntHaveCats" delta="False">
    <text>Yes you're correct there was a described 'golden age of Islam'. That some scholars said ended in the 1200's. The cause of it's ending is debated. But their 'golden age' we know was not sustained and if you really look at it all it was was them translating texts from states and empires they sacked and invaded.

This is a good read on it from middle eastern scholars who deconstructe the myth of the Islamic golden age.
http://www.jadaliyya.com/pages/index/17192/beyond-tolerance-and-intolerance_deconstructing-th

Christianity certainly went through a renaissance in which the Vatican was directly challenged. Martin Luther being one of the prime examples. The refermation and enlightment led directly to our western values we live in today. This gives a short overview of each. But you are right Christianity (esp. to new worlds) was spread by force.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christian_humanism

I think the main takeaway is Islam as a whole continues to move in the wrong direction. More towards fundalmentalism and wahabbism. Pretty much every Islamic country has a widespread movement towards this. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756152624.0" user="Targalaka" delta="False">
    <text>You are saying that in comparison to the bible the Quran is more peacefully but if my understanding is correct, it has some calls to violence too as a way of protecting the religion, or I am wrong?.  Is the Quran peaceful with respect to the bible in terms of violence call counts? Or how?. I dont know how good it is to compare two violent books and say that one is peaceful because it is not as violent as the other</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756663690.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah so this is actually awesome you bring this up, it's a highly misunderstood part of the Qur'an. The Qur'an talks about lesser and greater jihad, which means struggle. Most of the protection of Islam the text talks about means lesser jihad -- resisting sin type stuff. I honestly am becoming fuzzy on the semantics because I haven't studied it in a few months, but the one thing hammered home in all of my classes was that the Qur'an really doesn't advocate for greater jihad except in extreme circumstances, which I assume other religious texts probably call to defend against attacked too. Survival, right? Unfortunately, terrorist groups like ISIS misconstrue the word of jihad, and since that's all the majority of people know about Islam, they accept it as truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756163031.0" user="open_debate" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry but this isn't true.

I'm actually going to make another post to try to change OPs view on this but this is the type of argument that actually makes things worse. When you say "The Koran is progressive towards women" people can easily disprove that with a simple google search to find some horrific things written there.

How we actually change people's minds about this is to admit where there are shortcomings and explain why we (or more accurately - Muslims) can use context and interpretation to overcome these - because the majority of Muslims do this on a broad range of topics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756655897.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>I think it goes back to context, as I mentioned but maybe I wasn't clear. As a text, in the culture and time it was revealed in, the Qur'an is incredibly peaceful. Some study of 7th century Arabia and the text will show you this. Most people don't understand these contextual details, though (myself included, before I started taking classes), and so it's easy to see why a false image is spread. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756625265.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>As a few other have stated--if you've read the Koran, it's safe to say that 75 percent of your argument (anything other than discussing Christianity [which we aren't here to do]) is moot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756667048.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>Read it cover to cover (well, clearly not in that order lol), but my point was that most people don't actually understand what they're reading. My point is about the Qur'an as a text, not how people have misconstrued the religion. Again, scripture and religion are/can be vastly different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756671151.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I have read what is between the covers of the Koran--that's the foundation of why I see Islam as violent and intolerant.  I think the more people who read the Koran, the less people we'd have defending it. Especially in Western society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756686746.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>Again, perhaps it is that you didn't understand it. I doubt I would've understood it without studying it in a course taught by various professionals in Qur'anic, Islamic, and Arab studies. It's like anything, without context it's easy to make the wrong case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756700665.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>That's like saying someone who isn't Catholic can't understand Catholicism unless they let a priest explain away anything about it which they may doubt.  
  
The Koran is by far the easiest religious text that I have read and studied to understand. Also, you are assuming that I did not have the Koran taught to me by experts throughout my study of it. You can throw makeup on a pig and make it wear a fancy gown, but no matter how you dress the animal it will still be a pig.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756727583.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>Just to clarify, I'm talking about context, not saying you have to be Muslim/taught by a Muslim to understand, so the catholic analogy doesn't completely compare.

Linguistically, yes the language is very simple. I honestly forget the specifics, but it has to do with meter/the fact that it's a recitation. A lot nuances (e.g. Tonal emphases and patterns) are also lost in translation since obviously Arabic is very distinct from English. Different topic. Apologies for assuming, my fault, but I'd imagine the vast majority of people haven't had the opportunity to study in depth the Qur'anic world and what it means. I've been interested in Islam for a good portion of my life and only got the chance at university.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756751582.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  
&amp;gt; Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement" 
  
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  
Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  
&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.  
  
&amp;gt;Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would bring. But Allah desires killing them to manifest the religion.’”  
  
I'm genuinely confused on how you could see tonal inflection playing a part in altering the effect of these words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756777817.0" user="whatdoiputheretho" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, meant in terms of the linguistic simplicity/recitation why the language is less ornate than some scripture from the Bible or other religious texts from the time period. I thought that was part of what you were getting at, my fault.

I commented earlier about the concept of lesser and greater jihad, but I honestly don't have time right now to give that a comprehensive read/reply. Like I said, there are a lot of contextual nuances (of ancient Arabia, Arabic, etc.) and implications most people don't understand, but these can't be explained in a few sentences. It doesn't really seem like you want your view changed, but if others fail to do so I'll come back later today with a more in depth response </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756787407.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Regardless of the context, these are intolerant, violent words from the phrophet/texts themselves that Muslims still agree with, where the Muslims who fundamentally agree with these texts literally carry out what the text commands them to do.  
  
You could argue that the socio-economic and political climate in the Middle East facilitates violent behavior. Doesn't mean the civilian populace isn't okay with ethnic cleansing, wife beating, sex slavery, etc.  
  
They believe all of these things through direct spiritual governing of their Religion, Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757109700.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They believe all of these things through direct spiritual governing of their Religion, Islam.

Then how do you explain peaceful Muslims elsewhere in the world?  Why do you consider their beliefs to disqualify them from being followers of the religion that you consider inherently violent and intolerant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757232030.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>If they disagree with the explicit subset of rules dictated by Islam then they disagree with Islam and are therefore less Muslim (if Muslim at all) than those that agree with and carry out Mohammed's commands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757314794.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If they disagree with the explicit subset of rules dictated by Islam then they disagree with Islam

Then they do not, because they follow the five pillars of Islam, which are the only universally agreed upon requirements to be a Muslim.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
