<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431884814.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/">
    <title>CMV: Islam is not a religion of peace or tolerance.</title>
    <original_poster>VanGoghingSomewhere</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Koran speaks of women as property, Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer and pedophile/polygamist who thought women had inherently deficient minds. Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom. ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran. Jihad has existed as long as Islam. Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates. What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism. Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.    
  
  EDIT:  
  
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
For anyone saying that violence and intolerance are only a misinterpretation of subtext (though many who are educated on the Koran in the thread have explained that Allah's word is strictly set and not to be interpreted), I encourage you to read these passages. If the Koran is a text to be interpreted by it's followers, how do you spin these words to be peaceful or tolerant? I truly don't get it.  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  

&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement"
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  

&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.
Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*  
  
  EDIT 2:

Any attempt to change my view in this thread has been a apologist answer citing false equivalency, or an appeal to emotion by trying to separate the wheat from the chaff (nice Muslims = peaceful Islam).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29756187676.0" user="open_debate" delta="False">
    <text>So this comes down to what you say a religion "is". ie: Is it simply the book on which it is based or is it what it's adherents believe?

I think you could make the argument that the Koran is "not a book of peace or tolerance". However, if you made that argument you would need to make the same argument for the Bible (although the specifics would be different). 

If it follows that a religion "is" its book then we would need to describe why Christians aren't killing non-Christians in the same way some Muslims are (the "thou shalt not kill" commandment is actually specifically about other Christians if you read the whole chapter)

Instead, I would argue that a religion is what its adherents believe. You can research yourself what Muslims believe as there have been a whole host of polls on the matter. Some results are encouraging, some are extremely worrying but the biggest factor is that there is never a consensus. From this the only conclusion we can make is that Islam is neither a religion of peace or a religion of war/hatred/whatever because many people take it to mean many different things.

That said, specific scripture is a problem. However, there are moderate/reforming Muslims who are genuinely trying face these issues head on and persuade others that Islam can be compatible  with liberal values. A good example here would be to say that just because a conservative Christian believes you can't be gay and Christian doesn't mean that a gay Christian IS any less Christian. The same goes for Islam.

I would highly recommend the book "Islam and the future of tolerance" written by Sam Harris (an Atheist) and Maajid Newaz (a reforming Muslim). They go into this in much more detail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756628003.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>While other religious texts are up for interpretation, the Koran by definition is the final word of God through the prophet Mohammed. What he did in life and incited in death, what he commanded of his flock, was violent and intolerant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29759420493.0" user="open_debate" delta="False">
    <text>Whilst this is a specific problem for Islam we are still talking about interpretation.

The Koran often contradicts itself so which side any particular Muslim takes for these contradictions HAS to be an interpretation. They are picking which of the "final words" to live by.

I think its important for me to say I'm not trying to make you pro-Islam here but, we must differentiate the doctrine of Islam from Muslims as people. This is why people will bring it back to interpretation as not every Muslim will have the same interpretation. Bare in mind there are many sects etc that have wildly different beliefs before we even get down to an individual basis. We tend to think about Islam as a block but this is not even remotely true.

That said, it's important for us to admit that the violent/intolerant version of Islam is certainly a plausible interpretation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760469289.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>What I don't understand is that no one in this thread would agree with the last statement you made. This is by far the most reasonable comment I've gotten and the closest to getting me to reconsider. As it stands, I think there is a lot more ammo for Islam being violent and discriminatory than not.   
  
To be noted, I am separating Muslims from Islam. I think Muslims are capable of peace and tolerance. I do not think the sole basis of the ideology is peaceful or tolerant. Even the five pillars don't say anything condemning murder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760510646.0" user="open_debate" delta="False">
    <text>I think this type of thread is likely to attract what you would probably consider Islam apologists. That's not what I'm advocating for. They have good and noble reasons for this but I'm with you in that I believe they are misguided.

There are, Imo, problems with every religion but not all religions are the same. The problem with saying "Islam is violent" is that it ignores the possibility of reform and change. I think it's accurate to say that at this moment in history Islam has the biggest problems. However, look back 400 years and it would undoubtedly be Christianity. Someone could have said at this time "Christianity is violent at its core" and this would have ignored the chance for Christianity to change (it still has massive issues, but is no doubt better than 400 years ago). The same is true of Islam now now. If we say it IS something you actually prevent the progress we want. 

On that front, there's the issue of feasibility. Is it more realistic to expect 1.6 billion people to become atheists or for real reforming Muslims to promote their much more liberal interpretation? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760554178.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>What I think about that is that when Catholicism is bad, people are being bad Catholics. If you follow the Ten Commandments and Jesus's word, you're more of a Catholic than someone who doesn't act virtuously. When Islam is bad, people are being good Muslims according to their doctrine.   
  
Catholics never altered the Ten Commandments or the words of Jesus, they just cleaned up their act.  
  
If violent Muslims today cleaned up their act, they'd be going *against* their religious foundation.  
  
Can you see now why I view most arguments relating Islam to Christianity as a false equivalency? Going against Christ in the name of Catholicism is *bad* Catholicism. It's the opposite of what Christ wanted.   
  
Killing infidels and treating women as property is *good* Islam. It is exactly what Mohammed wanted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760709639.0" user="open_debate" delta="False">
    <text>I absolutely see why it looks like a false equivalency and in one sense it is. However, you're comparing a common interpretation of Christianity today with a (all too common) interpretation of Islam today. Look at some of the ratified beliefs of the Catholic Church in the past you'll see some horrible things. Equally, look at photos of Iraq and other Islamic countries from 40 or so years ago and things look much different (I'm talking specifically about female dress here, not trying to argue they where somehow free and liberal by today's standards)

I'll find a passage from the book I mentioned earlier where Maajid uses a liberal principle purely using quotes from the Koran. He himself makes the point I made earlier that the violent interpretation is valid one, but to say it's the only one is actually what people like ISIS believe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760737769.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>At the end of the day, unfortunately I think ISIS has closer to home than moderate Muslims. Anything that disavows violence is reform Islam and not Islam. Just as Lutheranism isn't Catholicism, it's a more progressive splinter </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760856408.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Just as Lutheranism isn't Catholicism, it's a more progressive splinter

But both are still Christian, no?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
