<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431884814.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/">
    <title>CMV: Islam is not a religion of peace or tolerance.</title>
    <original_poster>VanGoghingSomewhere</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Koran speaks of women as property, Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer and pedophile/polygamist who thought women had inherently deficient minds. Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom. ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran. Jihad has existed as long as Islam. Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates. What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism. Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.    
  
  EDIT:  
  
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
For anyone saying that violence and intolerance are only a misinterpretation of subtext (though many who are educated on the Koran in the thread have explained that Allah's word is strictly set and not to be interpreted), I encourage you to read these passages. If the Koran is a text to be interpreted by it's followers, how do you spin these words to be peaceful or tolerant? I truly don't get it.  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  

&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement"
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  

&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.
Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*  
  
  EDIT 2:

Any attempt to change my view in this thread has been a apologist answer citing false equivalency, or an appeal to emotion by trying to separate the wheat from the chaff (nice Muslims = peaceful Islam).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29755696829.0" user="Smudge777" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom

True.  However, you're neglecting the fact that while "many" do, "most" Muslim do not.  
How can you proclaim that Islam, as a whole, is anything ... when the adherents who do that thing are the minority?  

---
This makes as much sense as saying "France is a country of sexism" because ***some*** French people are sexist.  

There are hundreds of millions of Muslims who are very peaceful and tolerant.  You cannot simply ignore their existence to proclaim that Islam is &amp;lt;anything&amp;gt;.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755709499.0" user="Smudge777" delta="False">
    <text>In addition, I must ask: do you think Islam is alone, or is Christianity also not a religion of peace or tolerance?

&amp;gt;Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer

Yep.  And God, Christianity's deity himself, is a murderer.

&amp;gt;ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran

So does the Westboro Baptist Church, the KKK, and a lot of the African Christian militia groups.

&amp;gt;Jihad has existed as long as Islam

So has Christian oppression and slaughters.  Hello Crusades.

&amp;gt;Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates

So was Christian evangelization, at least until a century ago.

&amp;gt;What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism

Same is true for Christian Extremism.  Those who bomb abortion clinics or shoot up mosques are just Christian fundamentalists.

&amp;gt;Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.

Liberal Christian, LGBTQ Christian, Christian Feminist--these are all oxymorons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756618615.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't come here to discuss world religion or test my belief of other religious doctrines.   
  
Crusades is a card most people pull, here's something that might enlighten you toward the difference between [Christianity vs. Islam by the sword](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I_To-cV94Bo).   
  
Also just because other religions incite extremist actions, to say that violent Christian terrorism is on par with Islamic terrorism is to not be thinking objectively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29758421073.0" user="Smudge777" delta="False">
    <text>That's interesting, considering this is the comment you chose to respond to.  And you chose to ignore my previous comment.

---
I'm well aware of the difference between the Crusades and Islamic jihads.

&amp;gt;Also just because other religions incite extremist actions, to say that violent Christian terrorism is on par with Islamic terrorism is to not be thinking objectively.

To the victims, it is on par.  
But that's not even what I'm saying.  You asserted that "what many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism", and used this to justify your view that "Islam is not a religion of peace".  
But the same can be said for Christianity, Hinduism, etc.

I'm happy enough to not discuss this, but (as I said before), you didn't respond to my other comment, only this one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
