<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431884814.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/">
    <title>CMV: Islam is not a religion of peace or tolerance.</title>
    <original_poster>VanGoghingSomewhere</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Koran speaks of women as property, Mohammed, Islam's prophet himself was a murderer and pedophile/polygamist who thought women had inherently deficient minds. Today, even moderate Muslim men in many parts of the world violently ensure their wives cover their faces and bodies or "adornments" while outside of the house or bedroom. ISIS/The IS/Taliban, etc. all follow the holy text of the Koran. Jihad has existed as long as Islam. Muslim evangelization has been by the sword as far back as the religion dates. What many explain to be Islamic Extremism is usually just Islamic fundamentalism. Liberal Muslim, LGBTQ Muslim, Muslim Feminist--these are all oxymorons.    
  
  EDIT:  
  
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
For anyone saying that violence and intolerance are only a misinterpretation of subtext (though many who are educated on the Koran in the thread have explained that Allah's word is strictly set and not to be interpreted), I encourage you to read these passages. If the Koran is a text to be interpreted by it's followers, how do you spin these words to be peaceful or tolerant? I truly don't get it.  
  
&amp;gt;Quran (2:191-193) - "And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing..."  

&amp;gt;Quran (4:89) "...But if they turn renegades, seize them and slay them wherever ye find them; and (in any case) take no friends or helpers from their ranks."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (5:33) - "The punishment of those who wage war against Allah and His messenger and strive to make mischief in the land is only this, that they should be murdered or crucified or their hands and their feet should be cut off on opposite sides or they should be imprisoned; this shall be as a disgrace for them in this world, and in the hereafter they shall have a grievous chastisement"
Quran (8:67) - "It is not for a Prophet that he should have prisoners of war until he had made a great slaughter in the land..."  
  

&amp;gt;Quran (17:16) - "And when We wish to destroy a town, We send Our commandment to the people of it who lead easy lives, but they transgress therein; thus the word proves true against it, so We destroy it with utter destruction."  
  

&amp;gt;Tabari 9:69 "Killing Unbelievers is a small matter to us" The words of Muhammad, prophet of Islam.
Ibn Ishaq/Hisham 484: - “Allah said, ‘A prophet must slaughter before collecting captives. A slaughtered enemy is driven from the land. Muhammad, you craved the desires of this world, its goods and the ransom captives would 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*  
  
  EDIT 2:

Any attempt to change my view in this thread has been a apologist answer citing false equivalency, or an appeal to emotion by trying to separate the wheat from the chaff (nice Muslims = peaceful Islam).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29755145664.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I know several tolerant, peaceful Muslims.  How do you account for them in your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755153466.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I also know tolerant and peaceful Muslims. I have a close friend who is a Muslim and just enlisted in the US Navy. He is a peaceful and tolerant person because he doesn't act on any of his violent or intolerant beliefs. You can believe that someone is an infidel doomed to hell and still be nice to them. This doesn't change the fact that the *religion* itself harbors an intolerant and violent belief system. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755159814.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know understand how a religion can be inherently intolerant and violent while devout members of that religion are tolerant and peaceful.  Religions are living things; they're in the interpretations of holy texts in the modern day.

If your view is simply that all Muslims have hidden violent, intolerant views that are out of sight, then how is that falsifiable?  How can we argue against the idea that people have these secret beliefs they never show?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755175229.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>The OP cites the Korean and Muhammad's life. I'm assuming the OP is referencing the religion and not the faithful. 

I know many Jews who eat cheeseburgers. But it's certainly true that Judaism forbids it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755185400.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>The religion IS the faithful, because the faithful are the ones who interpret the religion.

Lots of Jews have changed their dietary restrictions to be about eating locally sourced food or veganism, because they think it's a more genuine expression of the physical/spiritual experience that eating provides.  Judaism encourages constant discussion and questioning; it's a bad example if you want to point to a rule system that is set in stone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755201625.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Sharia Law is a rule system that is set in stone. It's a code of ethics that doesn't really have much room for interpretation. Women are property, honor killings are enforced. Always have been--doesn't look like that aspect of Islam is about to change any time soon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755209545.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>You fundamentally don't understand Islam.  Allah's word is absolute.  Their is only one correct interpretation of Islam on this planet and that is Muhammad's interpretation.  All other 1.6 billion interpretations are just trying to match his.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755229601.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>You know what's a good example of a rule system set in stone? Islam. It literally claims to be the unalterable word of God and has even reduced the rate of change of Arabic as compared to other languages over time. 

It's really hard to make the case that Muslims get to interpret the Koran. I guess lots of religions are self contradictory but if you're claiming to follow a prophet as an example as to how to live, you're either doing a bad job or not following Muhammad if you eat pork. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755187012.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that any Muslim you or I know that disagree with honor killings, pedophilia, or extermination/coerced conversion of non-believers is not a Muslim. Though he wouldn't admit it (or even agree), my friend Abdul is not Muslim. The religion is part of his heritage. You can't pick and choose which components of a religion you subscribe to and call yourself devout.
You can't truly be Jewish and believe Christ is the Messiah. You can't truly be Muslim and ignore Mohammed's teachings of religious authority.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755205510.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a circular definition.  You’ve defined Muslims as violent and contend any Muslim who isn’t violent as not a true Muslim because you’ve defined it as such

That’s not very helpful to discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755215072.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I'm here to have my view changed that Islamic *text* is violent and intolerant. No amount of "look at this nice Muslim" will convince me that the religion isn't violent.  
  
The violence of Muslims, though still very prevalent in the world today, is not part of this discussion. Your or my definitions of Muslim people have nothing to do with the discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755226177.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>The text is not the religion.

There are a number of dicey passages in the Old and New Testament, but that doesn’t mean any modern religion based on those texts is condoning slavery, or subjugating women or other things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755244182.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>If you think the text is not the religion then you have a poor understanding of Islam and Sharia Law. Mohammed's word is where the buck stops, according to the religion. His word and actions were violent and intolerant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755291799.0" user="Lindsiria" delta="False">
    <text>If text is religion than Christians are just as bad as Muslims.

After all, there are some incredibly awful things in the Bible.

Don't forget, a lot of what is in the Koran and the Bible come from Judaism. The Koran and Bible are not much different. In fact, the Koran tends to have more progressive ideas compared to the Bible.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755319052.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>The Bible is a story of people and it says awful things because humans do awful things but it never **Commands** awful deeds.  Jesus says the most important thing you can do is love your fellow man.  Muhammad says to slay the unbeliever if they do not convert or pay the jizya.  The Quran and Bible are so completely different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755392459.0" user="CorrectingSomeone" delta="False">
    <text>Deuteronomy 17: 2-7

&amp;gt;If a man or woman living among you in one of the towns the Lord gives you is found doing evil in the eyes of the Lord your God in violation of his covenant, and contrary to my command has worshiped other gods, bowing down to them or to the sun or the moon or the stars in the sky, and this has been brought to your attention, then you must investigate it thoroughly. If it is true and it has been proved that this detestable thing has been done in Israel, take the man or woman who has done this evil deed to your city gate and **stone that person to death**. On the testimony of two or three witnesses a person is to be put to death, but no one is to be put to death on the testimony of only one witness. The hands of the witnesses must be the first in putting that person to death, and then the hands of all the people. **You must purge the evil from among you**.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755401869.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct that is in the Old Testament of the Bible and part of the Talmud. But you miss the point. Does Jesus **Command** the stoning of adulterers.  NO he doesn't, his example is shown when a group of people bring an adulteress to Jesus and ask if they should stone her.  He replies "Let he who is without sin cast the first stone".  This verse is a command from the Jewish god to the Jewish people.  

But Jesus has come down to earth to give a new pact to all of mankind.  However forever, the Jews will continue to be the chosen ones and the old covenant with them and God will last. However Christians are not bound to old testament laws. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755418603.0" user="CorrectingSomeone" delta="False">
    <text>Not disagreeing with you about that point, just was pointing out that your previous statement was wrong. The Bible does command those things, even if Jesus did not later.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755426996.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>Haha that is so technically correct. You're right the bible is telling a story where God is telling the Jews that you must stone the adulterer.  But Jesus never gives a message to tell **Christians** to stone adulterers.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755479955.0" user="Lindsiria" delta="False">
    <text>... And? The Bible has been used to support slavery and other horrible acts. It's how we interpret it that matters. We can pick quotes from both sources to prove our point, like what I am doing below. 

 "O People, it is true that you have certain rights with regard to your women, but they also have right over you. If they abide by your right then to them belongs the right to be fed and clothed in kindness. Do treat your women well and be kind to them for they are your partners and committed helpers."

  "All mankind is from Adam and Eve, an Arab has no superiority over a non-Arab nor a non-Arab has any superiority over an Arab; also a white has no superiority over black nor a black has any superiority over white except by piety and good action."

There are thousands of amazing quotes that he said (or is believed to have said). You can't dismiss all the good for some of the bad. Especially because a lot of what he 'said' is similar to what a lot of the Bible is: letters or sayings from followers, long after the prophets were dead. There are large sections of the Bible that tell of Jesus' life written by those who never had, or very minimal contact with him. Then, you have the catholic church modifying the text over the years.

We have no idea what was really said and how either text has changed over the centuries. We can pick and choose what quotes we want to present to proof our points but in the end, the people who believe in these texts make the choice to be good or evil. The Koran or Bible is just a tool- the person does the actions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755519969.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>Why is there such a huge aversion to say one book is fundamentally worse than the other or one religion is evil and the other isn't and that they are not equal.

The Quran and Bible are more than tools.  They influence the choices that people make.  

Those religions and books are nothing more than stories about man and they try to tell us what is morally correct.  The books alter our choices more than we alter the books.  

We can say oh we can pick and choose so the underlying totality of the ideology and books don't matter.  I can say I can pick the good out of Mein Kampf and Nazism and only do the stuff like be patriotic  , treat animals humanely, and so on, but that is crazy because I am supporting an Ideology whose totality is pure evil.

Islam is evil and it's rules are absolute there is no interpretation but Muhammad's interpretation that is 100% correct.

You can pick out the verse that praises racial harmony but Islam is oppressive in a new dimension. Islam preaches Muslim Superiority.  

Indeed, they who disbelieved among the People of the Scripture and the polytheists will be in the fire of Hell, abiding eternally therein. Those are the worst of creatures. 98:6


Fight them; Allah will punish them by your hands and will disgrace them and give you victory over them and satisfy the breasts of a believing people 9:14

Fight those who do not believe in Allah or in the Last Day and who do not consider unlawful what Allah and His Messenger have made unlawful and who do not adopt the religion of truth from those who were given the Scripture - [fight] until they give the jizyah willingly while they are humbled. 9:29

These Verses were said by Muhammad at his apex. Muhammad commands the extermination of the non-believer.  Islam commands non-stop conquest.  It's verses are unambiguous. 

The difference between Christianity and Islam is that you have to misinterpret Christianity to commit violence and for Islam if you interpret it correctly you will commit violence. Sadly I wish you were the one who was right about these religions, but if you studied Islam and Muhammad its hard to come to a different conclusion.




</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755628124.0" user="3rdOption" delta="False">
    <text>Who gives *you* the right to say that the terrorists are following Islam to the letter? And how do you know that good Christians aren't filtering out the "bad parts"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755654542.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>Muhammad gave me the right to say that.  His texts and his actions are the true litmus test for what is true Islam. Muhammad(PBUH) is the only one who can hear Allah.  But Allah is a figment of Muhammad's imagination so Islam is simply what Muhammad wanted. How can you read those verses in combination with his actions in 610 to 632 and come to a different conclusion.  

These religions are stories who give rules and morals to its followers.  And these stories are very different. I wish it wasn't like this but if you don't believe me you can read Islam's text with an open mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755894849.0" user="Lindsiria" delta="False">
    <text>How am I reading the Koran with an open mind when I have to throw out everything good and focus on only that is bad? Because that is what you are asking.

To read anything with an open mind means you can see the good and bad in all texts, including things such as the communist manifesto and some nazi books. To be open minded does not mean you support all the ideals.

You post quotes about awful acts Muhammad might have said, without realizing Jesus said some pretty awful things as well.

"Brother shall deliver up the brother to death, and the father the child: and the children shall rise up against their parents, and cause them to be put to death."

"I am come to set a man at variance against his father, and the daughter against her mother, and the daughter in law against her mother in law.
10:36 And a man's foes shall be they of his own household.
10:37 He that loveth father or mother more than me is not worthy of me: and he that loveth son or daughter more than me is not worthy of me."

" Those who fail to bear "good fruit" will be "hewn down, and cast into the fire."

"Being filled with all unrighteousness, fornication, wickedness, covetousness, maliciousness; full of envy, murder, debate, deceit, malignity; whisperers,
1:30 Backbiters, haters of God, despiteful, proud, boasters, inventors of evil things, disobedient to parents,
1:31Without understanding, covenantbreakers, without natural affection, implacable, unmerciful:
1:32 Who knowing the judgment of God, that they which commit such things are worthy of death, not only do the same, but have pleasure in them that do them. "


Then you must realize Jesus never said slavery was bad, nor women being subservient to men was wrong. Was Jesus evil for believing homosexuality should be punishable by death? By believing death and destruction will come to the unbelievers? That the catholic church used these reasons to launch their own jihads to Islamic lands (which were much more peaceful and civilized compared to the west).

If Christianity and Islam were reversed (with the west being Islamic and Christianity focused in the middle east), you probably won't see much of a difference. It's poverty that brings out the religious nut jobs in any religion. The only reason Christian fundamentalists are not as bad of a thing in the US or the west is because they have a lot more to lose. Poverty is not nearly as bad here compared to these countries.

BTW, Muslims follow the teachings of Jesus too. They believe him to be a prophet. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755975797.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>We're missing each others points.  

No doubt that C and I have there ups and downs but you have to look at the sum because you're either a C or not or a Muslim or not.  Jesus is guilty of pushing a reactionary view of life.  But Muhammad does that and more. Muhammad is a conqueror that Jesus ain't, he personally killed Jews and demands everyone be converted by the sword.

You say you can swap C and I and nothing would change but the data disagrees with you.  In Africa across the board Muslims favor more extremist views in every category.
http://empethop.blogspot.com/2016/08/comparing-levels-of-extremism-in-muslim.html

You're also misrepresenting  bible verses to show "wow look at the bad they must both be equal" without realizing Jesus' meaning is that he wants to bring radical social change and it will cut between familial ties.  

With any group of people you're gonna get a distribution of people ranging from good to bad but these religions shift the mean and distribution of these people Islam shifts people farther than Christianity.  

You have to take a giant step back away from the followers hokey-pokey views and view Muhammad and Jesus as political entities not unlike Ghandi, Hitler, or Martin Luther King.  And then ask yourself could you possibly say that the packages of ideas brought by these 5 different men, which all have some good and some bad, could possibly be of all equal morality.

BTW Muslims treat Jesus as just another character in the Quran not someone who is to be followed and emulated like Muhammad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757508151.0" user="Roflcaust" delta="False">
    <text>You don't appear to be holding interpretation of scripture to the same standard from the Bible to the Qur'an.  If one text can be taken out of context, so can the other.

It's going to be very difficult to definitively prove one religious text is objectively "fundamentally worse" than the other, so what's the point in trying to make such a claim?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756229983.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>It is correct. 

You have, from the Christian Bible, a command from God telling people to stone other people based on behavior. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756667282.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>You're missing the point 
The question is does the religion Christianity command its followers to stone adulterers.

The answer is no because of its leaders actions and commands to his followers(jesus)

The verse he gives which is in the Old Testament is a command from God to his chosen people(The Jews) its a story about the time BC(before Christ).

It's technically correct but we were asking does Christianity tell its followers to stone people.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756679743.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>Was the God of the OT the one who commanded people before the time of Jesus? Did He make commands?

And do the followers of modern day Christianity still refer to the OT God when talking or thinking about their religion. ? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756732965.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>It's the same God but in the Old Testament he is commanding only the Jews his chosen people. 

That is why Jesus came down in the New Testament.  To make a new covenant with new rules but this time with all of humanity.  Those rules are still there but they will forever apply to the Israelite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756743822.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>So because of this new covenant, Christians would never make any declarations on God's statements based on Scripture from the OT. 

Because Christians should be forcused on the ideas and Gospels of Jesus. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755469211.0" user="spacereallysucks" delta="False">
    <text>Muslims follow Jesus as well. They just dont believe he is the son of god</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755639483.0" user="3rdOption" delta="False">
    <text>You see, it's people like you who are no better than the terrorists. When both sides are claiming that Islam promotes these things, no peace can be achieved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756189241.0" user="NotACockroach" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you think the text is not the religion then you have a poor understanding of Islam and Sharia Law. 

If your entire view is based on this assumption without justification that a religion is equivalent to a literal interpretation of it's base text then your not going to be able to have a useful discussion with people because you're just defining words diffently.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756228225.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure that if I followed you around for a few days with a copy of OT I could come up with multiple reasons to stone you or people you interact with. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756314139.0" user="insaneHoshi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; poor understanding of Islam and Sharia Law.

So you know more about islam than tolerant and peaceful muslims?  What actually qualifies you to say that?  Have you studied texts, and religious discussions and dogma?  Have you ever had a conversation with a Imam?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757755589.0" user="UndeadMessenger" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you think the text is not the religion then you have a poor understanding of Islam and Sharia Law.

I've said this before on this subreddit and elsewhere, but I'll say it again: *there is no meaningful distinction between a religion and its followers*. Religion is a distinctly human creation, embodied in practices, communities, rituals, cultures, and many other elements outside of pure belief and doctrine. All of these things combine in fluid and complex ways, in particular locations and environments, to form this massive thing we call 'Christianity,' or 'Islam.' This means that, if you wanted to understand what Islam actually *is*, you would need to understand how it is understood or practiced in a particular context, and in everyday life. You can't just point to a handful of verses and say "See! This is Islam!" 

If your particular reading of a sacred text constituted *the* religion, and if everybody mindlessly acted on this interpretation, then you would have millions of modern Christians calling for the government to outlaw collecting interest on loans, to ban clothing made out of multiple types of fabric, and to tie millstones around the necks of those who lead children astray. The fact that they don't demonstrates that any religion is considerably more than just a sacred text, and that these texts are not an almighty authority on all matters. 

All you're doing here is taking a poorly informed understanding of religion in general, and Islam in particular, to make baseless generalizations that aren't the least bit true. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756206250.0" user="OrbitingTpot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The text is not the religion


Isn't the Koran regarded as the LITERAL word of Allah? That is not something that is precedent in Christianity at least and Christianity gives man free will partly (in my arguably limited understanding) in order for man to find and seek God voluntary. 


One important difference is also how the central figure in both Christianity and islam spread their faith, Jesus by word and example and Muhammed by the sword. Convert or die.




You can't honestly say that they are the same or just say "muh crusades" because they are waaay more contextual than just "bad Christians take holy land deus vult".


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756533435.0" user="waaza0" delta="False">
    <text>There is a very important distinction that can not be left out when comparing christianity to islam. The bible is not perceived as the literal word of god (the bible is sometimes refered to as the word of god but that is not meant in a literal sense). Christians know that the bible is written by prophets who, themselves, are imperfect. This gives christians the logical freedom to interpret or discard certain pieces from the book. 

The quran, however, is stated as the **literal** word of allah. And allah is omniscient, all powerfull and perfectly good. Therefore, if you discard a text such as:
Quran (2:191-193) -*"And kill them wherever you find them, and turn them out from where they have turned you out. And Al-Fitnah [disbelief or unrest] is worse than killing... but if they desist, then lo! Allah is forgiving and merciful. And fight them until there is no more Fitnah [disbelief and worshipping of others along with Allah] and worship is for Allah alone. But if they cease, let there be no transgression except against Az-Zalimun(the polytheists, and wrong-doers, etc.)"*, 
then you are basically ignoring the commands of an omniscient, all powerfull and perfectly good being. Which seems quite irrational to me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756202342.0" user="NotACockroach" delta="False">
    <text>The definition of Muslim does actually really matter to your view, since when people offer counterexamples you just say that their not a true Muslim.

If the definition of a Muslim from the text is so clear as you say it is, quickly summarise it here so we can examine it and then we can more easily move on in the discussion. 

Consider including it in your original question as being specific about definitions is key to a solid argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755248122.0" user="blue-sunrising" delta="False">
    <text>I can just as easily claim that you just have to believe that Mohamed was the prophet and that makes you a Muslim, whereas to be a Christian you have to believe in murdering homosexuals, forcing a whole bunch of sexist shit and hell, that even eating shellfish or wearing mixed fabric makes you an infidel.

But lets face it, neither faith is as simple as believing "X is the prophet", they all have a bunch of other shit in their holy books and a lot of that shit is questionable.

Yet all faiths consist mostly bunch of regular people that pick and choose what to believe and ignore the nasty shit.

If those Muslims are no true Muslims, then the Christians are no true Christians and the Jews are not true Jews and so on. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755275954.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Why are you the arbiter of of who's a real Muslim and who's not? Why isn't my friend the one why can decide?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755291077.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Neither of us are the arbiter of what makes a real Muslim. Mohammed is, and his guidelines for being a real Muslim are very concrete.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755328792.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>What are his guidelines, specifically?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756523357.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Shariah Law. It's called law for a reason </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757044858.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>This is not specific.  Could you lay down the specific guidelines he says make a good Muslim?  Any... pillars, perhaps?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757245378.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1.1 Shahada: Faith.  

&amp;gt;1.2 Salat: Prayer.  

&amp;gt;1.3 Zakāt: Charity.  

&amp;gt;1.4 Sawm: Fasting.  

&amp;gt;1.5 Hajj: Pilgrimage to Mecca.  
  
Nothing about being peaceful toward infidels or treating women equally. The tenets apply to Muslim men, in accordance with Muslim men. Infidels do not count, for they are to be converted or killed.   
  
Within those 5 tenets is a book filled with violence and intolerance perpetrated and commanded by the prophet of these tenets, in the name of the God of these tenets. According to the Koran, his word is final.  
  
EDIT: Read my main edit, then let me know if the 5 pillars are a blanket of rules for ethical peace.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757353445.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I think we need to take a step back here, because you need to acknowledge that you are not particularly educated about the Koran and Islamic theology, because you clearly just pasted that from your google search, and your arguments against them are nonsensical.

How much do you know about the *extent* of what the Koran says about, for instance, how to treat non-Muslims?  You clearly know some cherry-picked passages about it, but there are passages that say the opposite.

If you really want your view changed, why don't you speak with a liberal Muslim religious leader in your community or a nearby one?  Specifically tell them you know the Koran says things that you find disturbing, but you see them trying to act morally, and ask them how they reconcile that.  

Either you're uninterested in the actual theology and philosophy of your view, or you're for some reason avoiding going to a source which would actually get the answers you're looking for.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760125731.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nothing about being peaceful toward infidels or treating women equally.

Nothing in there about being violent towards infidels or treating women unequally either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760473050.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>Gotta take the wheat with the chaff. Those parts are left out because they are encouraged in the text. The pillars and the entire Koran are not mutually exclusive. You're ignoring the implication there, which is valid and obvious.   
  
EDIT: you can't be Christian without believing Christ was the messiah. You also can't be Christian if you believe Christ was the messiah but think the Ten Commandments aren't valid.  
  
Islam is the pillars, and the words of Mohammed, who is the final and indisputable messenger of Allah. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760520670.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Gotta take the wheat with the chaff. 

Yet you're only allowed to look at the bad, and ignore the good?

&amp;gt;Those parts are left out because they are encouraged in the text.

In some parts, an in others they a discouraged

&amp;gt;You're ignoring the implication there, which is valid and obvious.

You're ignoring whole sects of the religion, whole passages in the Q'uran, and whole groups of people who selectively interpret the Q'uran in a peaceful and tolerant manner.  

&amp;gt;you can't be Christian without believing Christ was the messiah. You also can't be Christian if you believe Christ was the messiah but think the Ten Commandments aren't valid.

According to who, exactly?  What makes you the arbiter of who is and who is not Christian?

&amp;gt;Islam is the pillars, and the words of Mohammed, who is the final and indisputable messenger of Allah.

Sure, but you are completely neglecting the differences in how those words are interpreted.  And those differences matter *a lot*, because some types of jurisprudence include cultural, historical, and secular norms as valid sources of Islamic law under different circumstances.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760560716.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I  not the arbiter of what makes a Christian, Christ was.   
  
I am not the arbiter of Islam, Mohammed was.  
  
One's main message was love your fellow man, the other's was dominate or kill non believers.  
  
Mohammed is the final interpreter of Islam. That is very clear in the Koran.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29760692225.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I not the arbiter of what makes a Christian, Christ was.

Well that sucks, because Jesus said:

Matthew 10:34 "Do not suppose that I have come to bring peace to the earth. I did not come to bring peace, but a sword."



&amp;gt;I am not the arbiter of Islam, Mohammed was.

I actually agree with you.  The problem with that is Mohammed has been dead for over 1000 years, and people have taken his words to mean different things.

&amp;gt;One's main message was love your fellow man

You mean like when Mohammed said: 

”And feed with food the needy wretch, the orphan and the prisoner, for love of Him [saying]: We feed you, for the sake of Allah only. We wish for no reward nor thanks from you..” Quran [76:8-9]

Those who spend in prosperity and adversity, and those who suppress anger and pardon men; and Allah loves those who do good.  (Quran 3:135)

"As to those, [non-Muslims], who are not fighting you because of your religion, trying to undermine your faith or driving you out of your homes, [that is committing oppression or aggression against you], you should deal with them in kindness and justice, for God loves those who do good." Quran(60:8-9)

 "Repel [evil] with what is better. Then will he, between whom and thee was hatred, become as it were thy friend and intimate. And no one will be granted such goodness except those who exercise patience and self-restraint." (Quran 41:34-35)

&amp;gt;the other's was dominate or kill non believers.

In the book of Matthew 11:20-23 (and Luke 10:13-16) Jesus condemns entire cities because they don't believe in him as the messiah.   

He also condones the beating of slaves (and thus gives slavery the OK) in Luke 12:47-48 "That slave who knows his master’s will but does not get ready or follow his instructions will be beaten with many blows. But the one who unknowingly does things worthy of punishment will be beaten with few blows. From everyone who has been given much, much will be required; and from him who has been entrusted with much, even more will be demanded."

Now Jesus also said that he approves of all the Old Testament rules in Matthew 5:17 

"Do not think that I have come to abolish the Law or the Prophets; I have not come to abolish them but to fulfill them."

Which means he agrees with God when god said:

Deuteronomy 17:5 "Then shalt thou bring forth that man or that woman, which have committed that wicked thing [unbelievers or people of other religions], unto thy gates, even that man or that woman, and shalt stone them with stones, till they die.

And Jesus also agrees with Moses when Moses orders people to kill women and children, except for those women who are virgins, which they can keep for themselves.

Numbers 31:14-18 Moses was angry with the officers of the army—the commanders of thousands and commanders of hundreds—who returned from the battle.  “Have you allowed all the women to live?” he asked them. “They were the ones who followed Balaam’s advice and enticed the Israelites to be unfaithful to the Lord in the Peor incident, so that a plague struck the Lord’s people. Now kill all the boys. And kill every woman who has slept with a man, but save for yourselves every girl who has never slept with a man."

The bible also says in the book of Revelation (which is in the New Testament and everything): 

Revelation 21: 8 "But for the cowardly and unbelieving and abominable and murderers and immoral persons and sorcerers and idolaters and all liars, their part will be in the lake that burns with fire and brimstone, which is the second death."

Meaning that unbelievers are considered equal to witches, liars, murderers, and all other immoral people.


So which one of those is the "Love your fellow man" one, and which is the "dominate or kill non-believers" one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757093316.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>There are multiple competing traditions/interpretations of Shariah Law, just like in any legal tradition.  Which version is correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757235229.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I will answer your question with another question: which version is tolerant or peaceful toward non-muslims?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757579000.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>See my reply to your other comment [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/do4s6wg/?st=j8klgueo&amp;amp;sh=8e9bf810)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756631088.0" user="Occams_Lazor_" delta="False">
    <text> in the Koran he instructs his soldiers to rape the wives of his captured enemies, even when they don't want to

He captures and beheads innocent Meccan caravan drivers and steals the stuff they carry

He orders the assassination of several poets/peaceful dissidents who crossed him with words

He kindles a fire on a man's chest to torture him until he gives up the location of some treasure 

He beheads all makes with pubic hair in a Jewish village who crossed him and sells the women and children into slavery

These may not be guidelines, those are bad too, but they show what kind of a person he was</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756195037.0" user="NotACockroach" delta="False">
    <text>Have you even read the Quran? It's vague and contradictory all over the place...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756524779.0" user="VanGoghingSomewhere" delta="False">
    <text>I have read it, sections where the Koran tells you the correct way to deal with the women you own are pretty clear </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757095960.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>Just out of curiosity, do you feel the same way about the bible's passages about how to deal with rape victims, slaves, or homosexuals?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757817832.0" user="NotACockroach" delta="False">
    <text>There are sections in most religious texts that very clearly state some pretty bad things. Then there are other sections that cast some doubt on that. In other religious texts like the Bible for example, you seem to suggest that having these good passages is enough to allow for a peaceful interpretation. 

You make only one exception to this standard,  the Quran, where you apply a different standard. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755502959.0" user="pensivegargoyle" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't you adopting a highly fundamentalist view of the religion yourself by doing that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756817042.0" user="expresidentmasks" delta="False">
    <text>That's clearly not his view. His view is about teachings not individuals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29757126987.0" user="LibertyTerp" delta="False">
    <text>There are peaceful Muslims, but it is still by far the most violent religion in Earth. In an increasingly peaceful world, the Muslim world is in conflict with nearly all of its neighbors.

Muslims have conflicts with Hindu India, Buddhist China, Christian/atheist Russia, Jewish Israel, Christian subsaharan Africans, Christian Phillipinos, and Christian/atheist Europeans.

And the Muslim world itself is home to some of the world's worst civil wars and human rights violations, especially against non-Muslims, women, and gay people.

No other religion is the cause for so many conflicts and human rights violations.

One or two of these problems could be blamed on something else, but the pattern is too obvious and the perpetrators are upfront about Islam being their motivation.

My best friend is a former Muslim and he feels even more negatively towards it, possibly because the penalty for apostasy in some countries is death.

Religion of peace my ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755902297.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756008383.0" user="Evil_Thresh" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry bgaesop, your comment has been removed: 

&amp;gt; Comment Rule 5\. "No low effort comments. Comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes', for example. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments." [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+bgaesop&amp;amp;message=bgaesop+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/754sge/cmv_islam_is_not_a_religion_of_peace_or_tolerance/do3w95l/\))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755196501.0" user="mike90909090909" delta="False">
    <text>That is simple, many Muslim do not fully understand their religion.  Islam is hard to understand in the beginning because it's main text the Quran has it's chapters out of order.  You couldn't get the gist of the religion unless you immerse yourself in Muhmmad's story from 610 to 632. You need to put all the chapters in chronological order and know the back story to each aya to get the meaning behind them or else you will misinterpret.  Muslims will quote Chapter 5 verse 32 but not realize the context of it.

For example that verse was a quote from the Jewish Talmud and the Quran merely says it, but it does not **command** it.  

You understand Muhammad's commands, his actions and his deeds from the study of the hadiths(stories about him), the Sira(his biography), tafsirs(exegesis explanation) and then you understand the true nature of Allah, Muhammad, and Islam. You realize why Allah allows Muhammad 5 more wives then normal muslims, why Muhammad smashed the Pagan Idols, and why Muhammad kills all those Jews in that one village.  You can then piece the verses in chronological order and then finally understand the Sharia. 

The Muslims you know are good people **inspite** of their religion being the worst religion on the planet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755715616.0" user="Dinosaur_Boner" delta="False">
    <text>"Islam causes violence and intolerance in many people" is completely compatible with your experience of it. It's statistically guaranteed that not all followers will be effected by its harmful influence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29755717354.0" user="synicalx1" delta="False">
    <text>Several people is a bad sample size for 24% of the world population.

Why not look at several countries with majority Muslim populations instead? Would you describe Iran as peaceful and tolerant? How about Saudi Arabia? Turkey? Libya? Syria? Iraq? etc etc.

As with any group, it's never accurate to paint all of its members with the same brush. However when the vast majority of the members of that group behave or act in a certain way, then it's not unreasonable to say that any individual member of that group is likely to follow that pattern. If that group is formed around a text and/or belief (aka a religion) that text/belief is the single common factor between all members. So if you have a group with only one thing in common, and most of its members are acting in a certain way, it's not unreasonable to say that the 'common factor' is the cause. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29756623229.0" user="Occams_Lazor_" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't address his argument at all. Some people who call themselves Muslims and may or may not follow all of the tenets of the corpus of Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
