<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="433630069.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/76673p/cmv_i_should_be_able_to_sell_my_organs/">
    <title>CMV: I should be able to sell my organs</title>
    <original_poster>stupidrobots</original_poster>
    <original_post>In short I should receive adequate compensation during life for use of my organs after my death.  The goal of this is to provide a financial incentive to increase the supply (and thus reduce cost) of organs required for transplant.  The benefits I see are as follows:

1) it gives the poor and disadvantaged a way to make money and get on their feet without requiring higher education or years of experience, relieving debts.

2) The financial incentive gives people reason to donate organs who might otherwise not.  This increases supply and drives down cost, and reduces time on waiting lists.  

3) A profitable program of organ collection would allow advertising for agencies that do this service and write up contracts, increasing the visibility of the needs of people who require organ transplants.

4) The argument that this creates a black market for organs is silly.  If someone wanted to kill you and take your organs, laws against it won't really help because now we're talking about maniacs.  

Furthermore my organs are my property, and I get to say what happens to my property during my lifetime and at the time of my death.  To deny this is to deny that individuals have the right to their own bodies.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29768922957.0" user="LogicalEmotion321" delta="False">
    <text>The more people measuring something, the more optimization will happen. The closer to optimization, the more people will push the envelope to gain an advantage.

More organs, more supply, cheaper prices on organs.

Now businesses want to make money, how do we make more money now that there is more supply. Somehow, we have to create more demand! We need more people having failing organs to increase prices. 

Businesses at first might do it the nice way, and just discover existing problems that can be a new source. But if a company wants to survive they will have to be competitive. 

So, now instead of cars breaking down quicker than they used to, we will start to notice bodies breaking down.

You don't have to kill people quickly, that would be too easy to spot . Do it at a rate of increase at 2% a year buwahaha.  

But yeah. The problem with allowing people to measure things, is that they make it more efficient.

The increase of people measuring supply will lead to people measuring demand which will increase problems.

By having a lack of supply it encourages society to keep its demand in check. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29768995489.0" user="super-commenting" delta="False">
    <text>We already have for profit doctors and hospitals and they aren't going around injuring/sickening people on purpose. Your caricature of evil businesses is laughably ridiculous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769379590.0" user="LogicalEmotion321" delta="False">
    <text>It won't happen in an extreme like you suggest. It will be more along the lines of slowly the available insurance money, and the % of doctors recommending patients to get transplants will go up.

As much inefficiency and cost they can get away with will be packed in for them to stay competitive. 

Without there being a way to extract lots of value in that domain, less investors will want to try and game it.

It's currently being exploited. But adding liquidity to it, will make that exploitation exponential.



</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
