<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="433630069.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/76673p/cmv_i_should_be_able_to_sell_my_organs/">
    <title>CMV: I should be able to sell my organs</title>
    <original_poster>stupidrobots</original_poster>
    <original_post>In short I should receive adequate compensation during life for use of my organs after my death.  The goal of this is to provide a financial incentive to increase the supply (and thus reduce cost) of organs required for transplant.  The benefits I see are as follows:

1) it gives the poor and disadvantaged a way to make money and get on their feet without requiring higher education or years of experience, relieving debts.

2) The financial incentive gives people reason to donate organs who might otherwise not.  This increases supply and drives down cost, and reduces time on waiting lists.  

3) A profitable program of organ collection would allow advertising for agencies that do this service and write up contracts, increasing the visibility of the needs of people who require organ transplants.

4) The argument that this creates a black market for organs is silly.  If someone wanted to kill you and take your organs, laws against it won't really help because now we're talking about maniacs.  

Furthermore my organs are my property, and I get to say what happens to my property during my lifetime and at the time of my death.  To deny this is to deny that individuals have the right to their own bodies.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29768887843.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>From your first sentence, it seems that you feel this only happens _after_ you die, yet you get the compensation before your death.

Here is the one big problem - what happens if we can't use your organs?  What happens if you live to a ripe old age and everything in you is just too old to be viable?  What happens if a bus squishes you like a bug and nothing is usable?

Do people get their money back?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769002568.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>The insurance industry deals with risk assessment all the time.  Yes a certain percentage of people will have unusuable organs.  Maybe even a high percentage.  But that's what you use to set the market price.  This isn't new.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769009055.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>If that is what you want, you are going to get next to nothing for your organs while you are alive.  They won't help anyone get out of poverty as you suggest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769044452.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>$500 is better than $0.  It might be the shave, haircut, and new clothes that help you get a job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769103929.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>I doubt it would be that much.  Let's do the math!

A kidney on the black market is worth about $250,000.  That is alot, but we can expect prices to go down if people start selling them.  Still, lets stick with that number.

There are about 20M people that need kidneys right now and about 320M Americans - so about 300M potential donors.  Now, if we assume that _half_ of those people would opt into your program (why not, you don't lose the organ until after your dead, after all!) that is 150M donors when we only need 20 - we have so "spread out" our payments to all the eligible donors, which means each of those 150M donors is worth $33k

However, that is 33k _when you die_ but you get the money _today_ which means we need to do a [discounted cashflow analysis](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discounted_cash_flow).  A kidney in 60 years isn't worth the same as a kidney today, after all.

So, what is the value _today_ of $33k in 60 years?  Well, if we use the average S&amp;amp;P return rate of about 10% and assume that you opt in (and get paid) at 18 but have a life expectency of 78 (60 years), that gives you a payment of:

**$108**

That won't lift you out of poverty.  Sorry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769365100.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t forget to include the cost of administering the program, that’s not free either.  Would easily drop it below $100.

PS you should xpost this to /r/theydidthemath.  If you don’t, I will</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769368856.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks - I left out admin just because I felt it would be tough to calculate that.

Feel free to post it there if you like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769400508.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769689840.0" user="LatinGeek" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I can tell why you have 200+ deltas. Good work there!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
