<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="433630069.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/76673p/cmv_i_should_be_able_to_sell_my_organs/">
    <title>CMV: I should be able to sell my organs</title>
    <original_poster>stupidrobots</original_poster>
    <original_post>In short I should receive adequate compensation during life for use of my organs after my death.  The goal of this is to provide a financial incentive to increase the supply (and thus reduce cost) of organs required for transplant.  The benefits I see are as follows:

1) it gives the poor and disadvantaged a way to make money and get on their feet without requiring higher education or years of experience, relieving debts.

2) The financial incentive gives people reason to donate organs who might otherwise not.  This increases supply and drives down cost, and reduces time on waiting lists.  

3) A profitable program of organ collection would allow advertising for agencies that do this service and write up contracts, increasing the visibility of the needs of people who require organ transplants.

4) The argument that this creates a black market for organs is silly.  If someone wanted to kill you and take your organs, laws against it won't really help because now we're talking about maniacs.  

Furthermore my organs are my property, and I get to say what happens to my property during my lifetime and at the time of my death.  To deny this is to deny that individuals have the right to their own bodies.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29768907731.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I should receive adequate compensation during life for use of my organs after my death.

How much do you think a hypothetical organ is worth? If I give you money for your liver today, I have no way of knowing when or if I will ever get a viable organ. You could die tomorrow and I could have a perfectly useful liver, or you could die in 60 years when your liver is useless. This risk in, along with the time value of money (i.e. $1 today is worth $1.05 in a year), means that you're not going to get paid very much for your organs today.

&amp;gt; 3) A profitable program of organ collection 

How is this program profitable? There will be immense waste. For example, if I give 100 people money today to take their kidneys when they die, I expect *most* of those people to live to an age where their kidneys, upon death, are essentially useless for a transplant. This will be true with most organs. We've now created a system in which most of the money spent is wasted (used to buy useless organs). 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769000448.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>In assessing risk and payouts, insurance companies do this sort of thing all the time.  We can assume that me as a 30 year old male who doesn't smoke or drink will probably die in 40 years with a relatively healthy liver.  They would probably screen me for health trouble before a payment is made, and that would only be to my advantage.

And you may be overestimating how much money an organ-after-death is worth when the company is taking a gamble.  They may be only willing to pay $500 for it, maybe even less.  Regardless, that's $500 that the homeless man did not have which he could then use to help get back on his feet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769050068.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And you may be overestimating how much money an organ-after-death is worth when the company is taking a gamble. They may be only willing to pay $500 for it, maybe even less.

No, that's the point I was trying to make. The financial incentive won't be much. Sure, the homeless person will sign up, but how influential is that $500 going to be to the target group of healthy people who aren't already voluntary organ donors? If the goal is to increase the availability of organs for transplants, it seems a simple [opt-out donation policy](https://sparq.stanford.edu/solutions/opt-out-policies-increase-organ-donation) will be immensely effective. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769057781.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>Opt-out donation policy assumes organs are community property after your death which is frankly disgusting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769078751.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>Not necessarily. There are ways to implement the policy that includes informed consent. For instance, everyone could receive standardized information and sign a paper either consenting to be a donor or, by checking a box, not consenting to be a donor in the process of registering for a gov issued ID, starting at 16/18.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769082542.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I don't have a permanent address.  How do you get me the paper?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769098463.0" user="muyamable" delta="False">
    <text>Getting a government ID requires you to be somewhere in person. It's an easy point of physical contact that would reach every single person who has a government issued ID. 

I don't need your address because you're right in front of me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769073481.0" user="paneubert" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  that's $500 that the homeless man did not have which he could then use to help get back on his feet.

So the insurance company in their review of the homeless guy's health (to determine how much to offer him) is going to deem him a low enough risk to do a deal and pay him $500?  Doubt it.  Homeless = high risk, and probably high enough that they wont even think of making a deal.  Homeless = low offer for organ, if any offer at all.  Even if $500 was your value for a "risky" situation, $500 for an organ is not a lot of money....and how do they even track the homeless guy down to harvest?  He is homeless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769076654.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>that low dollar value would be associated with a high risk person.  An olympic sprinter would probably command a higher value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769089106.0" user="paneubert" delta="False">
    <text>I get what you mean, but I still think it illustrates a core flaw with your first listed point.  Only the well off/healthy population is going to be really benefiting, and the "high risk" (in this case the poor and disadvantaged) folks will not.  Even if they wanted to, I think the insurance companies will say "no thanks".  Or as the meme goes, "That'll be about tree fiddy".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
