<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="433630069.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/76673p/cmv_i_should_be_able_to_sell_my_organs/">
    <title>CMV: I should be able to sell my organs</title>
    <original_poster>stupidrobots</original_poster>
    <original_post>In short I should receive adequate compensation during life for use of my organs after my death.  The goal of this is to provide a financial incentive to increase the supply (and thus reduce cost) of organs required for transplant.  The benefits I see are as follows:

1) it gives the poor and disadvantaged a way to make money and get on their feet without requiring higher education or years of experience, relieving debts.

2) The financial incentive gives people reason to donate organs who might otherwise not.  This increases supply and drives down cost, and reduces time on waiting lists.  

3) A profitable program of organ collection would allow advertising for agencies that do this service and write up contracts, increasing the visibility of the needs of people who require organ transplants.

4) The argument that this creates a black market for organs is silly.  If someone wanted to kill you and take your organs, laws against it won't really help because now we're talking about maniacs.  

Furthermore my organs are my property, and I get to say what happens to my property during my lifetime and at the time of my death.  To deny this is to deny that individuals have the right to their own bodies.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29768936264.0" user="AurelianoTampa" delta="False">
    <text>**Edit: Realized upon rereading that your post is about after you die. Oops. My post was based on the idea of selling your organs while you're alive.**

**Perhaps the quickest rebuttal to that is: Getting paid now by agreeing to have your organs harvested after death is incredibly hard to quantify monetarily. Who knows what state your organs will be in after death? If you drink yourself to the grave your liver's going to be good for nothing. If you splatter yourself in a car accident going 100 mph, your organs will be liquified.** 

**As an alternative, why not just make the organ donor designation "Opt-Out" rather than "Opt-In"? You'd get a ton more organs, with no financial incentives attached.**

*Original post:*

Should you be able to sell *any* organ, or just ones that have duplicates, like a kidney, lung, or, uh, testicle? I'm bad at listing body parts...

Perhaps the strongest rebuttal that comes to mind is that you usually need your organs to remain working for you in order to live a healthy life. Allowing a person to sell their organs now means they likely will have more health issues in the future because they're without the organ(s) they need. I could see this working for kidneys, but pretty much no other organs. 

To your specific points:

&amp;gt;1) it gives the poor and disadvantaged a way to make money and get on their feet without requiring higher education or years of experience, relieving debts.

But isn't this kind of a case of the rich cannibalizing the poor? And it kinda puts a ghoulish twist on the practice; got college debt? Can't pay it? Well, give an eyeball to the debt collection agency and we'll call it even!

&amp;gt;2) The financial incentive gives people reason to donate organs who might otherwise not. This increases supply and drives down cost, and reduces time on waiting lists. 

Not really "donating" when you're "selling," is it? Same kind of issue as above. Also, this seems to introduce a detrimental effect - the highest bidder gets access to better medical care, rather than the people who might need it the most (or are better suited for it). Keeping organs separate from financial incentives means that everyone faces the same rules and responsibilities. 

&amp;gt;3) A profitable program of organ collection would allow advertising for agencies that do this service and write up contracts, increasing the visibility of the needs of people who require organ transplants.

I'm not sure how this is unique to selling/collecting organs. I mean, hospitals regularly put out calls for blood donors despite not paying for said blood. Dedicated advertising may increase the amount of organs coming in, but they're going to the collection agency, not to hospitals. 

&amp;gt;4) The argument that this creates a black market for organs is silly. If someone wanted to kill you and take your organs, laws against it won't really help because now we're talking about maniacs. 

Not sure how this would make a black market (as it would be legal). But as I mentioned before, introducing organ collection as a potential way to pay off debts does increase the odds of someone getting tricked or bullied into doing so. A maniac will drug you, scoop out a kidney, and leave you in a bathtub of ice. An unscrupulous organ collection agency armed with lawyers could do much the same, but be protected by law and bureaucracy. 

&amp;gt;Furthermore my organs are my property, and I get to say what happens to my property during my lifetime and at the time of my death.

Your organs are part of *you,* not simply your property. And you already have the right to say what happens to them at the time of your death. It's called being an organ donor! But the difference with you postmortem is that you're not using them any longer. 

&amp;gt;To deny this is to deny that individuals have the right to their own bodies.

Selling the organs off isn't just like selling your eggs/sperm, or acting as a birth host, or working a job. It's permanently taking away a part of your body. You can donate your organs, but that's an altruistic choice that you likely don't feel unfairly pressed into making. Adding a transactional component to it means you're required to do so - and the government regulates commerce. You have a right to your own body, but the government has the right to tell you what is illegal to sell - and organs are prohibited under the National Organ Transplant Act of 1984. NOTA's been challenged in recent years in court (for bone marrow and patented cell lines), but neither time was it overturned. Much like how the right to "freedom of speech" has its limits, so too does your right to do what you want with your own body. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29768987237.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, thanks for seeing what I meant.

And it's just like any market, the prices will be set by supply and demand.  Who ever figured out how much someone would pay for a car or a cell phone?  That's just how prices work.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769009088.0" user="AurelianoTampa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, thanks for seeing what I meant.

It's too bad, I thought it was a pretty unique view to hold and had a lot of fun writing about it :)

As for the actual post, why add the monetary component to it at all? How is it superior to opt-out as default? You bypass the whole issue of the NOTA of 1984, and don't need to introduce a business acting as a middleman which would likely just increase the prices hospitals pay for organs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769041554.0" user="stupidrobots" delta="False">
    <text>Opt out assumes that your organs aren't actually yours to begin with.  It's a disgusting moral stance that your body after your death is somehow community property.  Sure from a practical standpoint it makes sense but it's dehumanizing.

And what would stop hospitals from paying for organs directly?  Nothing in my scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769115231.0" user="AurelianoTampa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's a disgusting moral stance that your body after your death is somehow community property.

That's... kind of an extreme reaction, and not one I would have expected. Is it any more disgusting than, say, mandatory vaccinations? We already have a precedent where bodily autonomy can be waived for the individual in specific situations if it's for the good of the community.

&amp;gt;Sure from a practical standpoint it makes sense but it's dehumanizing.

I'm honestly not understanding how it is dehumanizing; would you explain why you feel this way? Or maybe I'll make a CMV about it if you don't want to get too off-topic on this one.

&amp;gt;And what would stop hospitals from paying for organs directly? Nothing in my scenario.

Would said collection agencies be run by hospitals in your scenario? If not, there's a middleman doing the collecting and setting the price. As I understand the current situation, there is no cost (to the organ donor, hospital, or recipient) for a transplanted organ - the only cost (to the recipient) is for the labor and supplies needed for the operation. If we're suddenly putting a price tag on organs then prices will increase, and probably quite drastically. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769719554.0" user="-pom" delta="False">
    <text>Hi. Asset valuation consultant here. 

Prices of assets are decided over a trial-and-error method that starts with the price of the materials, labor, R&amp;amp;D, overhead, and other costs integrated into it. 

For assets like cars, those numbers are obtainable and quantifiable. Prices of services are determined based on labor hours, necessity, estimated value in profit to the firm, etc. Many estimates are based on market values or using a certain calculation. 

For organs, the value is impossible to determine without a direct valuation after death. The state, quality, reusability, capability, and compatibility of the organ is more or less unknown and impacted by multiple factors including method of death, foods eaten before death, physical fitness, diet, genetics, etc. 

Because the value is impossible determine (as there is no standard product that is similar and reproducible reliably with the same quality), it's also extremely easy for an organ sale system to be abused. No one will be spending that much time trying to find the exact value of every organ and pay it to your estate when they can just claim that your organ is not as good as it is and then lie about the actual worth. 

Market prices are not determined by supply and demand; although they are a major factor, it's not nearly that simple. Additionally, a product like an organ does not have a supply or demand because there is no constant in the equation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29769474072.0" user="das_american" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to save your comment and maybe post my own CMV later when I have more time. I think people should be able to sell their organs while alive. In fact I think *maybe* they should even be able to sell vital organs, for instance if a person is suicidal but wants to give family members or friends a better inheritance. Sorta ties in nicely with the assisted suicide CMV I did the other day.

Should be a fun debate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
