<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="436829637.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/782rwl/cmv_accusations_alone_should_not_be_printed_by/">
    <title>CMV: Accusations alone should not be printed by the media.</title>
    <original_poster>OGHuggles</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't care what percentage of them are true, innocent till proven guilty is a thing. The erosion of privacy and civil liberties is of great concern to me now and in the future. While I'm glad plenty of women that would have been ignored before aren't anymore, I don't think accusations should be straight up believed. I think they should be taken seriously, but they should not get media attention until a case is actually made. 

False accusations are a thing and lives have been ruined because of them. The most infamous case of this guilty before proven innocent going wrong, is the Duke Lacross case I'm sure most people have heard of.

Why should I not be concerned about this? Why is it ok to ruin people's lives based off of accusations alone?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29793967263.0" user="yunyun333" delta="False">
    <text>Should the media not be allowed to report on trials? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794006281.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>I am presuming in the OP's view reporting on a trial isn't akin to publishing a story about an accusation. In the former, you're reporting on a trial. In the latter, you're reporting just a story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794321490.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>They can report on trials objectively, I'm specifically referring to the habit the media usually has of depicting people as guilty before trials.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
