<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="436829637.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/782rwl/cmv_accusations_alone_should_not_be_printed_by/">
    <title>CMV: Accusations alone should not be printed by the media.</title>
    <original_poster>OGHuggles</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't care what percentage of them are true, innocent till proven guilty is a thing. The erosion of privacy and civil liberties is of great concern to me now and in the future. While I'm glad plenty of women that would have been ignored before aren't anymore, I don't think accusations should be straight up believed. I think they should be taken seriously, but they should not get media attention until a case is actually made. 

False accusations are a thing and lives have been ruined because of them. The most infamous case of this guilty before proven innocent going wrong, is the Duke Lacross case I'm sure most people have heard of.

Why should I not be concerned about this? Why is it ok to ruin people's lives based off of accusations alone?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29794215273.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>Going through the list:

"Erosion of civil liberties": In what sense is being publicly shamed a loss of your civil liberties? Should people be unable to say anything negative about others because it loses them respect and standing? And beyond that, how is limiting the ability of people to spread their story not a violation of *their* civil liberties?

"False accusations are a thing and lives have been ruined because of them": Why do you believe that false allegations are more likely to cause more serious harm than protecting anybody who has committed crimes, but not in a way that enables legal prosecution? It's obvious you're referring to Weinstein, who had a massive reputation and has over a dozen women accusing him, and who also had explicit clause in his contract protecting him from being liable for sexual assault and had assistants and others willing to cover for him. How is his right to continue assaulting people privately more important than the right of these women to have their story told?

"Duke Lacrosse case": [If we're swapping anecdotes, how about this one?](https://www.propublica.org/article/false-rape-accusations-an-unbelievable-story) A woman (Marie) filed a police report for being raped by an unknown assailant, but the police officer doubted her story due to her strange behavior. Later, he convinced her to recant her story, then forced her to sign a confession saying she filed a false report. She lost all reputation with her few friends, was jailed, and her story was widely shared (it made the front page of Reddit).

But she wasn't lying. She was raped, and photographic evidence on the computer of a serial rapist proved it. Because of the obsession with the idea of "false rape claims" being a common thing, a woman's life was ruined and police failed to work with other departments, leading to the rapist being able to act for much longer. Marie's life and others were ruined because people believe so strongly that false rape reports are a serious problem.

So sure, what happened to the Duke Lacrosse team was awful. But what happened to Marie was worse. And that's why this paranoia about false rape reports doesn't just defend the innocent, it actively gives rapists cover and makes women fear seeking help from law enforcement.

"Why is it OK to ruin people's lives based on accusations alone?" Why are you more concerned about the reputation and livelihood of rapists like Weinstein than the woman hurt by it? There's no perfect solution, but why *should* I care more about the very unlikely prevalence of false rape reports than the very real prevalence of women who do not feel empowered to do anything against their rapists?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794320530.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not against investigations, I'm against the media blowing things up. 

People can say whatever they want, but it's very different than having the media blow things up. Accusations should be taken seriously by the police but they should remain on the down low until sufficient evidence is provided to launch a trial.








</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794370080.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>But that's the thing: With Weinstein and others, it's clear that legal channels have failed and will continue to fail. Beyond a reasonable doubt is a fine standard for the law, but when multiple people have had the same experience with an abuser and know that the police will not help them, why should they be silenced to protect the reputation of a rapist? And how can they hope to fully establish their case if they are barred from doing anything to cause more people to come forward to eliminate any reasonable doubt? Why is protecting those who commit sexual assault the line in the sand, when no other reputation or career ruining act requires such a huge standard (even when they're much easier to prove to that standard?)

None of the questions in this post or the previous were meant rhetorically; I want you to answer them. Because I honestly want to know what leads you to believe that false rape accusations are such a serious problem that *massive* limitations should be put on people's ability to make any accusation, and why you think that making it much, much harder for women to identify and protect themselves from predators is a worthwhile sacrifice to protect people like Weinstein.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794404228.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>Have legal channels failed? Prove he is guilty. If you can't, they haven't failed. If you want a system that favors prosecution, go look at japan.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yFINmgSzK6E

I don't believe false rape accusations are a serious problem, as I've already said in another post. Statistically, they are very low. But innocent until proven guilty is a thing, and these media storms need to stop because of what they threaten to do to the fundamental legal system we hold dear. The issue here isn't the practicality of enforcing justice for me, it's about the fundamental assumption of our legal system being over turned by angry mobs.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794437634.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Have legal channels failed? Prove he is guilty. If you can't, they haven't failed.

[Weinstein most likely bribed a district attorney to not bring charges against him.](https://www.salon.com/2017/10/06/harvey-weinstein-cyrus-vance-jr-david-boies/) He has been getting away with assault for years, and only got some justice due to public accusations. In what sense is that not a failure of the legal system? It hasn't worked to investigate crimes and it allowed more people to be victimized. And again, why is sexual assault, which has a *massive* problem with unreported/uncharged offenses, the one crime you are focused on preventing public accusations of? Why should sexual abusers be afforded protections that nobody else is in terms of silencing their accusers?

&amp;gt;I don't believe false rape accusations are a serious problem, as I've already said in another post. Statistically, they are very low. But innocent until proven guilty is a thing, and these media storms need to stop because of what they threaten to do to the fundamental legal system we hold dear. The issue here isn't the practicality of enforcing justice for me, it's about the fundamental assumption of our legal system being over turned by angry mobs.

But why do you believe that's happening? If you do not believe false rape accusations are a huge problem, why do you believe that public, *truthful* accusations are causing our legal system to be turned over to angry mobs? Because being fired, or publicly shamed, is not the same as being convicted and going to jail for the rest of your life. Nobody is saying "Weinstein is a rapist, so we should extrajudicially imprison him." They are accusing him, and letting the people who associate with him make the free decision to no longer do so.

Again, innocent until proven guilty beyond a reasonable doubt is a fine standard for law enforcement, but the public is not law enforcement and people are free to make judgments on much less strict standards. If you are not fearful of false rape reports, *why* do you think it's so horrible that people are punished in the public sphere for doing horrible things?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794450643.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't know he bribed anyone, that's a problem obviously, and I'm not solely focused on rape in the slightest. Innocent until proven guilty is something that should be applied to all criminal offences. 

Generally speaking, I am very distrustful of large groups of people parading on about anything. Mobs are scary thoughtless things. 

Being publicly shamed on a national scale and essentially becoming a pariah is effectively ending someone's life. People are social creatures. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794462976.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Being publicly shamed on a national scale and essentially becoming a pariah is effectively ending someone's life. People are social creatures.

Weinstein *raped people.* Why is public shaming and disgrace so much more abhorrent than stopping him from continuing to rape people? Because if you aren't concerned about false rape reports, which you've explicitly said multiple times, this is being more concerned with unease at Weinstein being heavily inconvenienced than with preventing him from victimizing others. Why should his feelings be put on a pedestal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794474066.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>See, the issue here is *I don't know if he raped people.* All I know is a lot of people are saying he raped people. The only people who actually know he raped people, are him and the people who came forward. I'm not aware of any evidence that confirms this. If there are biological tests, cameras, audio, whatever then I'm game and that's sufficient enough for public shaming until an actual trial is held. 

This isn't about weinstein specifically, as an individual I have no clue who he is other than he made a few shitty movies and looks like a guy I wouldn't get along with. This is about our societal attitude towards individuals without sufficient physical evidence and it's about mob rule and sensationalization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794498463.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>And it loops back to the point you've been avoiding.

You say that false rape accusations are rare. You say that you're glad the victims aren't being ignored. You say that they should be taken seriously. So why is it that with all those statements, you still refuse to actually believe the victims? Because all of those look like empty words when you don't *actually* take the victims seriously, wish to ignore them in favor of a mass of evidence that is almost never requested for non-sexual crimes, and are open to the possibility that over a dozen people are all making a very rare false rape report.

So again, it looks to me like you are weighing the extremely thin chance Weinstein is innocent (he isn't) over the massively more probable chance that he'd continue to victimize people if he wasn't publicly shamed. That is what I want you to think about: What makes that slim possibility Weinstein has been shamed unnecessarily so much more horrifying than the massive possibility Weinstein would continue to rape people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794517686.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>See, what you don't understand here is the definition of ignoring. The police should work on this, find evidence, track him, all of those things. This isn't ignoring victims. What shouldn't be happening, is the media going wild before a case is even made. 

Once again, this isn't about weinstein. This is about the bigger issue, how accusations are handled in the media. The public very clearly shapes how our legal institutions function.

With how you speak of this I doubt I'd want you to affect how our legal system works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29795051071.0" user="Rabornius" delta="False">
    <text>He's not refusing to blame any victims until it's shown that they are.  This is the correct stance.  You're equating an accusation with a guilty verdict.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29795072740.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>No, I am simply not equating the standards of evidence required by the court of law as the same standards of evidence required for day to day interactions. People don't have the time or ability to dig deep into everything everybody says and determine if there's guilt beyond a reasonable doubt, and the argument that standard *should* be required only seems to crop up with sexual abuse allegations.

E: As a hypothetical, shoot from the hip: Was OJ guilty or not? Because the vast majority of people think he was guilty, and I'd be surprised if you didn't. But he was unable to be convicted beyond a reasonable doubt... but he was still guilty and it's perfectly reasonable to believe he's a murderer. So why is it that *specifically* with sexual assault, the argument always seems to crop up that you can't believe victims unless the accused has been found guilty?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29795111913.0" user="Rabornius" delta="False">
    <text>It's not *specifically* with sexual assault. It's all claims.  If society is allowed to do that,  why do we need courts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29796713018.0" user="Sadsharks" delta="False">
    <text>Because there was an actual investigation and a trial in OJ’s case instead of just accusations and rumours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29796023274.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>Can you elaborate on how media storms threaten the fundamentals of our legal system? That only makes sense if we assume a total inability on the part of both the public and the law to distinguish between public opinion and the standards of the justice system. A person is innocent until proven guilty, but that doesn't mean that the public isn't free to believe what they want. When you talk about the fundamental assumption of our legal system being overturned by angry mobs, what specifically are you referring to? It's not like the mob has any say in the verdict.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800233598.0" user="bracs279" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it's clear that legal channels have failed and will continue to fail. 

So the answer is vigilantism?

&amp;gt; why should they be silenced to protect the reputation of a rapist?

An ALLEGED rapist, that's a huge difference. Also, just because multiple people tell the same story doesn't mean its true.

&amp;gt;Why is protecting those who commit sexual assault the line in the sand, when no other reputation or career ruining act requires such a huge standard 

I agree here, ALL reputation ruining accusations should be held from the media until they are proven true.

&amp;gt; making it much, much harder for women to identify and protect themselves from predators is a worthwhile sacrifice to protect people like Weinstein.

This isn't a womens issue, ANYONE can get raped. Also, you are assuming the accused IS a predator. The vast majority of cases aren't as clear cut as Weinstein's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800265740.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So the answer is vigilantism?

Where did I suggest vigilantism? Social ostracization and freely dissociating with somebody are not mob justice, they are simply forms of speech.

As for the rest: no, multiple allegations do not *guarantee* something is true, but they do make it seem pretty likely, and people can act on that information how they wish. No, I don't believe that the 1st amendment should be revoked to protect from the boogeyman of false rape accusations. OP pretty specifically wrote his post about women alleging Weinstein rape or otherwise harrased then without saying it directly, so I replied to that.

As for the overall point: the fact is there are no perfect solutions and social consequences happen to people for all sorts of reasons without needing a massive, massive bar of proof. In this case, false accusations are so rare that the benefit of more crimes being reported and more people feeling empowered to stop predators outweighs the negative effects, and the negative effects of your argument made in another post to default to "a woman is lying when she makes a rape accusation" would be massively damaging to a massive number of people just to protect against the spectre of a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800281071.0" user="bracs279" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Social ostracization and freely dissociating with somebody are not mob justice

Come on, that's the start point of mob justice. Don't you know that people can and have been attacked from false claims in social media?

&amp;gt; the boogeyman of false rape accusations. 

Its not a boogeyman, its a real issue with multiple verified accounts. You are trying to paint false rape accusations as some crazy thing that we shouldn't waste effort in.

&amp;gt;false accusations are so rare

We can't possibly know that, specially with rape where the accuser has a strong incentive NOT to confess the accusation was false.

&amp;gt;"a woman is lying when she makes a rape accusation"

You keep making this a women's issue. My point was that ANYONE'S accusation is false until they are proven true. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794635274.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794922033.0" user="howbigis1gb" delta="False">
    <text>Your comment has been removed because it's been found in violation of 

Rule 2:

Don't be rude or hostile to other users. 

If you feel this is in error please message the moderators</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800220185.0" user="bracs279" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Because of the obsession with the idea of "false rape claims" being a common thing

This is not an obsession, its a basic tenet of a fair society. ALL RAPE CLAIMS ARE FALSE UNTIL PROVEN TRUE, its just another form of saying innocent until proven guilty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800244742.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>Not really.

Innocent until proven guilty is a legal standard that prevents punishment until proven beyond a reasonable doubt. It does not imply that everybody must treat them as innocent until a conviction, or even treat them as innocent after their conviction (for instance: I think OJ is a murderer!)

Beyond that, it is absolutely *not* meant to imply you assume the victims are lying. Nobody goes into court assuming that, if you claim a dude stole your wallet, you actually gave him the wallet and made it up for attention. Assuming that rape claims are specifically *false* is absurd. There is at least an argument for assuming nothing about the truthfulness of the claims, but assuming that all women who say they've been raped are lying is a tremendously harmful ideology that gives predators massive amounts of cover to act with impunity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800264952.0" user="bracs279" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Innocent until proven guilty is a legal standard that prevents punishment until proven beyond a reasonable doubt. 

I know that, i'm arguing that we should apply the same standard off the courts, and OP makes a good point that the media demonizes people accused of rape before any kind of evidence comes up.


&amp;gt;Nobody goes into court assuming that, if you claim a dude stole your wallet, you actually gave him the wallet and made it up for attention.

That's a false analogy. Theft is very clear cut and NOBODY consents to it. That's not the same with rape, consent is a dynamic thing that can change multiple times during the event in question.

&amp;gt;Assuming that rape claims are specifically false is absurd.

Why?? Many people aren't even sure they were raped, thanks to the many grey areas that exists around the consent concept.

Go to /r/TwoXChromosomes and see what i mean, plenty of women seek advice to better know if their experience was in fact rape.

&amp;gt;but assuming that all women who say they've been raped are lying is a tremendously harmful ideology that gives predators massive amounts of cover to act with impunity.

Again, this isn't a women's issue because men can get raped too. 
Also, not everyone accused of rape is a predator and it doesn't really matter if they are vanishing few false claims. 

Benjamin Franklin said it best: ""it is better 100 guilty Persons should escape than that one innocent Person should suffer"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800290815.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>Requiring proof beyond reasonable doubt for everything is baffingly. It would take days to make basic decisions and require actively doubting everything people tell you. There is a reason why civil courts use a preponderance of evidence standard and people believe their freiends for little reason other than "I kinda know this person."

It isn't a false analogy. You can give somebody money. You just don't want to accept that your argument about reasonable doubt doesn't actually hold up.

Assuming rape claims are false is absurd because it requires assuming motivated lying on the part of the people making the claim. Do you not recognize the difference between assuming a statement is false and assuming you don't know?

When it comes to the government, protecting against tyranny in law enforcement is great. But treating people who accuse others of rape as liars is not protecting the innocent, it is letting the innocent be victimized by predators who take advantage of a culture that makes it extremely difficult to seek criminal or civil actions against perpetrators of sexual assault. Creating hundreds of innocent victims because of the spectre of negative social consequences for innocent people is not a good trade.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29800312549.0" user="bracs279" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It would take days to make basic decisions and require actively doubting everything people tell you. 

So your answer is to treat people as guilty? I think is better to assume everyone is innocent until further information is acquired.

But no, i'm not going to participate in ostracizing some guy from work just because someone accuse him of rape. That isn't fair by my standards.

&amp;gt;You can give somebody money. 

Then it isn't theft, you chose the worst possible example to make your point.

&amp;gt;it requires assuming motivated lying on the part of the people making the claim.

Not really, plenty of people can make a rape accusation without knowing if the event in question was actually rape. 

Also, people DO have the motivation to do shitty things such as a false rape claim. is that somehow in doubt?

&amp;gt; it is letting the innocent be victimized by predators

That would apply if we are sure the accused are actual predators, we don't know that.

&amp;gt;who take advantage of a culture that makes it extremely difficult to seek criminal or civil actions against perpetrators of sexual assault. 

Which culture is that one? I see nothing but support for people that come up with accusations, huge campaigns suchs as #metoo that have been already translated in multiple languages, plenty of famouse people speaking up against rape. Who is making it extremely difficult?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
