<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="436829637.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/782rwl/cmv_accusations_alone_should_not_be_printed_by/">
    <title>CMV: Accusations alone should not be printed by the media.</title>
    <original_poster>OGHuggles</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't care what percentage of them are true, innocent till proven guilty is a thing. The erosion of privacy and civil liberties is of great concern to me now and in the future. While I'm glad plenty of women that would have been ignored before aren't anymore, I don't think accusations should be straight up believed. I think they should be taken seriously, but they should not get media attention until a case is actually made. 

False accusations are a thing and lives have been ruined because of them. The most infamous case of this guilty before proven innocent going wrong, is the Duke Lacross case I'm sure most people have heard of.

Why should I not be concerned about this? Why is it ok to ruin people's lives based off of accusations alone?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29793970273.0" user="_shifteight" delta="False">
    <text>Not actually sure where I stand on this, but wanted to bring up two thoughts:

What if an accusation of rape wasn't reported and the accused rapist was able to commit multiple more rapes since the public was unaware there was a potential rapist around?

What if an accused rapists gets set free because someone in the general public that holds key information to prove guilt was unaware of the accusations?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29793977119.0" user="relevant_password" delta="False">
    <text>Do you apply the same logic to accusers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794018340.0" user="_shifteight" delta="False">
    <text>Great question. And since I haven't put a lot of thought into this topic,  I am not sure. Happy to hear opinions. Initial thoughts are:

* If accusers are printed in the media, it might reduce the the likelihood a traumatized victim will be willing to report.

* If accusers are not printed, a serial false accusers could ruin the reputation of many people before they have the chance to be proven innocent. Also, a falsely accused person could be wrongfully imprisoned because evidence about the false accuser was lost in the unknowing public. 

It seems that the second consequence is less likely than the first, as serial false accusers would be risking their legitimacy by accusing frequently. This doesn't mean that it wouldn't be horrible for the additional falsely accused due to preventing the accuser's identity to be published. It seems like the least damaging option however. 

Perhaps the best is a more informed public on the difference between accused and guilty so that reputations are not ruined from accusations. Unlikely, I know.    </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29794334329.0" user="OGHuggles" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn't make much sense to me. Everyone is a potential rapist, there are always potential criminals around. I doubt the public is only on guard about crimes if there is a story in the news about a single case. 

The public being aware of a rape is very different from the police doing their jobs, I'm not against the latter. 

If someone holds key information to prove guilt, they are criminals for not coming to the police about it. At a trial witnesses are summoned, I doubt they need the media to do that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29795324143.0" user="Chris_Lifts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If someone holds key information to prove guilt, they are criminals for not coming to the police about it. At a trial witnesses are summoned, I doubt they need the media to do that.  

This can only be done assuming the person actually knows that the person is being prosecuted. The police isn't aware what all the people do at any time of the day and who could be witnesses outside of the direct witnesses at the time of the crime (and even not all direct witnesses are known).

Often people do small things that raise a suspicion, but that suspicion isn't strong enough to go to the police for. For example really bad jokes regarding abuse or being very derogatory to women. Once people know that the person in question is being accused of a crime, the other people may chime in with their stories. However, I do agree that there has to be a reasonable suspicion of the crime being committed. Just an accusation isn't enough. Going back to the rape crime, a report and bruisings around the genitals can be a good indicator of the crime having been committed (not exclusive though, some like it rough). 

The way this evidence is handled is not the way of "he made derogatory comments about women and is being accused of raping someone, therefore he is guilty" but both sides (defendant and prosecutor) will have to take this into account.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
