<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29805950236.0" user="johnbbuchanan" delta="False">
    <text>There are at least two parts of your view that should be changed:

(1) Neither separation from the circumstances of birth nor lack of a biological basis need apply to gender on an account of gender as a social construct. In fact, I can't think of any psychological, sociological, feminist, or philosophical account of the social construction of gender that holds either of those views about gender (but no doubt there are some). So you should not take as a given that gender is divorced from biology (e.g. that there is no correlation between someone's gender and their genes) if you have any interest in understanding what people mean by gender being a social construct.

(2) Anything I've seen in the psychological, sociological, feminist, and philosophical literature recognizes that race (as a racial identity of, say, *being black*, *being Filipino*, *being French*, *being Scandinavian*, etc.) suggests that the consensus is that race is a social construct. So, you should not need to be convinced that race is not a social construct, unless you're asking to be convinced of an unusual, minority view in academic discourse on race.

Starting with (2), I'll point you first to the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy which [casually mentions](https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/social-construction-naturalistic) race as one class of object social construction has been applied to in the humanities and social sciences, before later going into more detail on accounts of the social construction of race. Within anthropology and sociology, I'll point you to the [1996 statement](http://www.virginia.edu/woodson/courses/aas102%20%28spring%2001%29/articles/AAPA_race.pdf) from the American Association of Physical Anthropologists which presents an overall picture that our species cannot be subdivided along lines of inheritance into subcategories and that "culturally defined groups" do not corresponds to any groupings of people by inherited traits (rather the inherited traits of an individual generally show only "varying degrees of association with" other people within a population group) and to the quote from a 1994 book cited by [this paper](http://med.stanford.edu/content/dam/sm/cirge/documents/activities/journalclubs/shiao%20Genomic%20Challenge%20to%20Social%20Construction%20of%20Race.pdf) which states the general agreement among its academic audience that race is socially constructed. You can throw a stone into psychology papers on race and either find casual mention that racial groups are socially-defined or find someone arguing against this consensus.

Regarding (1), I'll focus less on the consensus that biology is relevant for social constructs (which you can see from reading anything I've sent you above anyway) and more on how the concept of social construction is perfectly compatible with some dependence on biological factors. Consider the question: how do people go about using a socially constructed category? Let's think about monetary value: Americans can work with categories such as '20 dollar bill' because the category *refers to physical properties* that different objects can share. Similarly, with gender, people can apply categories such as 'woman' because the category *refers to observable properties and behavior* that different people instantiate. In most of the literature, the broad term for what is observable about a person's gender is what is called **presentation** or *presenting as some gender*. For 'woman', what counts as presenting is largely in flux, greatly varies between different societies (each constructing their own categories), and includes virtually no necessary or sufficient conditions but does include wearing dresses and skirts, having breasts, speaking in a higher pitch, checking off 'woman' on questionnaires, etc. Some of these ways of presenting "have a biological basis" and depend "on the circumstances of your birth" and, in this way, someone's gender is connected to biology (even correlated with genes).

Given (1) and (2), it also is far from mysterious why Rachel Dolezal might not be regarded as black and why many say that a transracial identity is impossible. I don't mean to say that she is or isn't black; I genuinely don't know what is part of the American concept of 'being black' and I even suspect there are multiple such socially constructed categories or at least, if there is one, that category is vague enough to be indeterminate in her case (like how as you go down a mountain it eventually becomes indeterminate whether the rocks you see are on the mountain or not - there is no sharp boundary between 'on the mountain' and 'not on the mountain'). But I'm no expert on what it is to be black, especially since I'm not a member of any of the communities involved in constructing that category (I'm neither black nor American), so I just have no idea where those boundaries of the category are.

With that in mind, I'll mention the possibility (which I've seen cited in response to Dolezal but also see this unrelated [psychology today article](https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/without-prejudice/201612/race-social-construction) on the subtleties of how being black is categorized in relation to social responses) that the American concept of being black could either *refer to growing up being treated as black* or *refer to black ancestry*. If either of those is the case (e.g. if the "one drop" condition is leftover from colonial influences), then identifying as black would require one of those two backgrounds. This reference must itself depend on societal responses if being black is socially constructed as a category but these might be societal responses with a specific content (viz. growing up with some indirect influence from the history of slavery or of colonialism in Africa). Perhaps these components of the socially constructed category of being black (when combined with your false belief in (1)) are what initially gave you the false impression that people widely regard race as not a social construct.

Perhaps to better understand what it is to be socially constructed it will help to contrast a socially constructed category like race with a natural category like electron - obviously the connection of that category to the word 'electron' is socially constructed (that is to say that the assignment of linguistic meaning to symbols is socially constructed) but the category itself does not depend on minds at all (only other concepts of charge, mass, spin, the details of QFT or at least experimental QM, etc.).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
