<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="77" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29807964854.0" user="YourFairyGodmother" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that race should be viewed as a social construct but your reasoning is all wrong.  

From a scientific standpoint the notion  of race is horseshit.  We base our notions of race on just a few externally visible traits.  But there's as much genetic variance between me and my very similar in appearance white male neighbor as between me and some random guy in Africa. It's human nature to focus on the familiar, on the plainly apparent, and also to categorize based on that.  It's natural for us to do so but it's still erroneous.  We mistakenly associate lots of other traits that have nothing to do with the small handful of genetic factors that give rise to those external features.  Humans are such stupid silly geese.  

We do the same thing with gender, but it's even more complicated.  Let's be clear - gender is absolutely a social construct which we erroneously conflate with sex.  People tend to think of sex as being determined by genitalia - the mostly external or at least visible, the gross morphology.  Genitalia don't determine your sex, your genitalia is determined by your sex. 

We also, in our typically simplistic way, think that there are only two sexes.  Because we focus on the familiar, disregarding all the cases that don't fit our preconceived notions.  In fact there are many sexes.  Chromosomal variations abound.  Wont go into details here but there are at least six distinct sex classifications based just on chromosomes.  As example, some people have two X chromosomes mixed with a Y fragment.   These people _look_ to be males but the  two X chromosomes means they are biologically female!  

It's even more complicated than that though, as what your body _looks like_  (both inside and out) depends not just on the composition of your X and Y chromosomes but also very much on poorly understood epigenetic factors.  Identical twins, who have identical chromosomes,  can be markedly different, right? 

But wait - there's more!  It gets even more complicated when it comes to gender. In the service of simplicity, let's say gender is how one perceives their sex identity, their inner sense of who/what they are. 

For a very long time, parents  have noticed that children express strong  preferences for certain colors, toys,and clothing , colors and clothing, at an early stage - like two to three years of age. That's the expression of gender identity.  

“What we know from typical gender development is that kids generally know and can say whether they’re a boy or a girl around age 2 or 3,” says the developmental psychologist Kristina Olsen.  Kids who look to be male sometimes feel even at that early stage they are female, and vice versa.  

&amp;gt;But, if someone can change their gender 

And there's the biggest problem with your analysis.  Are they deciding to _change_ their gender?  What are they changing _from_?  They aren't changing their gender, only how they _express_ their gender.  

 &amp;gt;or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender

You're getting closer but still miss the mark.  Did you _decide_ to identify with whatever gender it is you do?  Of course you didn't.  (It's always fun to ask anti-gay bigots when they chose to be straight.) Nor is there any "change" or "different" involved.  Its not a decision to somehow be something different than what one is but a _recognition, an awareness_, of what one is.   (Again, people don't decide to be "not gay" or "not straight," they become aware of what they already are.  

So no, race - which is a silly notion -  isn't anything like gender identity. On that basis alone your argument is, frankly, poppycock.  But since "race" doesn't even exist (though racial identity surely does), well, that should be enough to change your mind I hope.  
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
