<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29806390633.0" user="mechantmechant" delta="False">
    <text>One big difference between the two, "trans raceuals" and transexuals is that the latter have proven their sincerity for centuries. We know there have been millions of transexuals who have been committed and consistent, who have worked extremely hard to be accepted. Maybe a numbers game isn't fair, but it certainly makes it easier to believe and understand that Jazz, for example, is among one of these millions who truly believe their stated identity than that Rachael Donezel is sincere when there's her and Grey Owl and that hideous German woman, and the only ones we've ever heard of made money on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807697637.0" user="kankyo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Rachael Donezel [made money]

You mean "had a job"? Afaik this wasn't a very high paying job, compared to what she could probably land had she continued to use white privilege...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29810200377.0" user="mechantmechant" delta="False">
    <text>And Grey Owl could have written mystery novels that take place in England. So what? They both felt so entitled to speak for people who were born those races that they tried to make a living doing it and they had no business doing it. There is a privilege that allowed them to get these positions-- they knew how to communicate with white people and make their chosen races palatable to white people and that's what allowed them to get these positions. She did get scholarships that were meant for black people. Maybe she just got sucked into that initial, money grabbing lie. I don't know, I don't care.

But anyway, maybe there are very nice, quiet, not trying to speak for the whole race people who consider themselves trans-racials and bother no one and cause no problems. My point is that transsexuals have earned what little acceptability they have through millions of individuals and thousands of years showing that they are sincere, that they aren't doing it to make fun, that they aren't doing it to make money or get a good story or a good scholarship, who in fact, do it at great personal cost. Transracials haven't done this work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29810306455.0" user="kankyo" delta="False">
    <text>Sure (although “thousands of years” is hyperbolic). I don’t think it’s fair to require this type of sacrifice and proof is all I’m saying. Especially not when it comes to race which is a lot of nonsense anyway. To me it’s a bit like being upset that people from say Hong Kong are Livermore fans in soccer. Live and let live...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29811276871.0" user="mechantmechant" delta="False">
    <text>According to Wikipedia, there's evidence of trans people in ancient times. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transgender_history

But try to hear how "live and let live" when it comes to white people assuming black or aboriginal people: no matter what they do, they aren't allowed into whiteness-- as that horrible racist joke goes, "What do you call a black man with a PhD? N-----" or more officially, "any known blood"-- any ancestor who wasn't white in Confederate America meant someone couldn't be white. But here come white people demanding that they have the right to be black or aboriginal because they merely feel that way deep inside. Did anyone ask those black or aboriginal people how they felt deep inside, if they would rather be white? And it's mostly black and aboriginal groups who are offended by cultural appropriation, when there isn't an ugly, violent history, groups generally don't care if you decide you're Japanese, for instance, or Indian.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29811619102.0" user="kankyo" delta="False">
    <text>You screwed up at the end when choosing two examples that are just crazily off base. Those two groups care immensely. You could try for two new examples but I think you’ll find the same problem. 

In any case: You are talking historical injustice as a justification for imposing current injustice. I find that argument weak. Enforcing racism now is hard to swallow as a solution to anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29811633865.0" user="mechantmechant" delta="False">
    <text>Injustice? The real victim here is white dudes who get flack for their dreads?!  That's racism?! Yeah, whatever. I know what my real screw up was... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29811653953.0" user="kankyo" delta="False">
    <text>That wasn’t my example. But we can discuss that example if you’d like. A person claiming ownership for a hair style for their race then physically assaulting a random person is obviously racism. It’s a silly thing compared to slavery of course though. Both things can be wrong at the same time! You don’t have to choose a side between one racist and another. Physical assault is always wrong. I can’t believe I have to write that. 

A white dude being assaulted is just as wrong as a black dude getting assaulted. Claiming otherwise, no matter the direction, is the very definition of racism. You seem to be implying that physical assault is ok or at least irrelevant if the victim is of a certain race. Think about that for a second. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29811819799.0" user="mechantmechant" delta="False">
    <text>"getting flack" doesn't mean a physical assault. It means getting criticism. And that's the thing, black people are so often accused of physical violence for speaking up for themselves and so rarely do it. Yes, you're allowed whatever hairdo you want, and people are allowed to think it communicates something about you. That's not violence. And if your biggest problem is that some people think your hairdo communicates that you're ignorant, you really haven't thought much about things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29812226608.0" user="kankyo" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you didn’t see the same video I did. 

And I don’t think that’s the biggest problem. Which I wrote quite explicitly. You seem to be pissed off at someone else and reading into what I’m writing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29812837961.0" user="mechantmechant" delta="False">
    <text>Why am I pissed off? You're not being very nice, for one thing. 

But also, do you have any empathy about how offensive it is to constantly have to justify one's existence as a trans person with these ridiculous false equivalencies. My original response is the best argument there can be-- people have fought with blood, sweat and tears to prove themselves-- lots of them, for a long time, to prove that they are trans sexual. Comparing us to Rachael Donezel, Grey Owl and Joseph Boyden is offensive-- three jerks selling books is not the same as all the millions of people who say they are trans sexual. And yes, for the record, you can allow gay people to marry without letting some pervert marry his dog. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29812945069.0" user="kankyo" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not trying to be offensive. I do know that text on their internet is hard and it’s very easy to come off quite badly when you’re trying not to. I’m sorry about that. I hope you can believe me that I’m trying to be civil but also have an argument, a balance that is pretty hard to strike. You don’t make it easier by implying things about me that aren’t true and using straw man arguments. 

I wasn’t saying it’s the same thing. It’s not. I agree with you 100%. I’m just saying that just because some people died for a right doesn’t imply other people must first die for another group to get those same rights. Or, at least, I don’t think that’s something to strive for. Maybe there are tens of thousands of people who are trans-racial (I agree that the word sounds offensive but I don’t know what to do about that) that are just in the closet and who are now even more entrenched there as they’ve seen the vitriol against Rachel. I don’t know. I’m just saying we shouldn’t judge a group of unknown size and composition by the likability of three people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
