<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29805299178.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>Gender isn't a social construct and race is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805312730.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>I think people get hung up because it is symantec, but that's exactly what it is.

If I put on a nice summer dress and heels, it would be said i was 'dressing like a woman' , but there is nothing genetic about a dress and heels. I am 'expressing a female gender' by doing that, the dress and heels convey 'gender' in it's socially constructed form. 

So , gender is expressed through social queues, and sex is your genetics. 

In that way, it just doesn't seem to be the hot button issue everyone wants it to be, no to me anyhow...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805316446.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>In the same way that race is , we agree there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805344629.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>The only use for gender is telling if someone has a dick or a vagina. Anyone who turns their gender into a huge part of their identity are wholly responsible for what they want to be called or how they want to be treated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805371411.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>well ok. Do you think your gender is not a huge part of your identity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805377596.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>No it isn't a huge part of my identity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805393397.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>I think that could probably use some introspection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805422870.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>Why? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805569677.0" user="MustLuvPolarBearDogs" delta="False">
    <text>Dude legit. Seriously, female here. Being a woman doesn't mean shit aside from the fact I get to watch Shark Week every month and pop out crying bundles of nerves and skin. Being a dude is more than being able to pee anywhere you want and sports. My identity is forced to mostly relate to my gender because of a social construct. 

Resiliancy might be a trait that I have maintained into adulthood, from some schoolyard day where I wasn't allowed to play kickball because 'girls dont play kickball' and subsequently worked hard to become a kickball master as an adult. The dedication during those years are a result of a construct about my gender, not because its innate in me. Its made up. 

The thing about Rachel is just nonsense. Thats a whole nother' thread. That brings in a different discussion, because she is also unwilling to hear about actual struggles from women of color. She also doesn't experience any of them. Also, she lied to make other people believe she was black (her parents are white). Thats more of a discussion on systematic oppression than anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805619051.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think your personal anecdote applies to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805635036.0" user="MustLuvPolarBearDogs" delta="False">
    <text>I meant the fact that you being male, doesnt entirely define you. You know you are, but its not the entirety of your *identity.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805668023.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>As I said earlier

&amp;gt;No it isn't a huge part of my identity.

What benefit is there in changing this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805735706.0" user="MustLuvPolarBearDogs" delta="False">
    <text>I was agreeing with you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805374905.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>Or more so, you say the point of gender is to identify sex, sure that's your opinion. But there you recognize the difference, that 1 is a social act, and 1 is biological.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805386547.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>yeah, and can you guess which component I care about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805395642.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care. But you are directly countering what you said above, that gender is not a social construct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805405059.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>I've outlined what context I mean, biology. Me acknowledging gender can be used differently is not a contradiction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805408699.0" user="rogerdodger77" delta="False">
    <text>ok.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805488031.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>Glad we can agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805332196.0" user="I-Am-Keith-Perfetti" delta="False">
    <text>How's that work?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805353664.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>because society doesn't dictate who has a dick or a vagina. Race is entirely dependant on what society labels you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805394627.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>Most arguments that gender is constructed work by specifying that sex (which includes things like what genitalia you have) and gender are two different hings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805419773.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>OP never mentions sex once. His entire dilemma is not making this distinction. What is the difference? one has a practical use and the other is a semantics debate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805429281.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>Implicit in OP's post is that they're already working from the standpoint of the sex/gender distinction, even if they haven't entirely fully worked that out.

To say that there's no biological basis for gender is a different claim than there being no biological basis for sex. The whole point of making the distinction is that there appear to be aspects of what we typically take to connote "man" vs. "woman" that are *entirely* social: the way people dress, proclivities toward certain activities, "typical" personalities, etc. People who make this distinction *don't* have in mind things like genitalia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805485111.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>If someone uses the word gender to mean something else other genital identification, then we aren't talking about the same thing and I've explained many times this is what I mean when *I* say "gender". If someone wants to use it to mean something other than that, give context. I have no care for what people want to broadly label "gender" or you get into said semantic debates or conclude strange things such as OP's title for this thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805493596.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If someone uses the word gender to mean something else other genital identification, then we aren't talking about the same thing and I've explained many times this is what I mean when I say "gender". If someone wants to use it to mean something other than that, give context.

The context is the entire context of the discussion of this issue in the social sciences.

With all due respect, you are just not using the word the way anyone with any knowledge of this debate/area will understand it. It's like if we were talking about colours and I called a blue thing red and when called out said "It's what *I* mean when I say red."

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805555451.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, i don't know if you noticed, but this whole thread is just a huge semantic debate and no one seems to agree on a single usage. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805559886.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm sorry, but that's not what's happening. There is an established history of talking about sex and gender as distinct. It's one thing not to agree that they are, it's another to refuse to accept that this *is* a distinction which has come to be the primary way we talk about gender. The only one who appears to be disagreeing about usage here is you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805572958.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>Whatever you say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805576723.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>You don't believe that this isn't what's happening in this thread, or you don't believe that talking about sex and gender as distinct is an established viewpoint?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805640902.0" user="unrequitedfucks" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah no, You've lost me. Read the top comment and don't use double negatives. I've never denied this thing with gender and sex, just your claim that this was somewhere clarified in this thread... full of nothing but semantic rabble.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805821013.0" user="I-Am-Keith-Perfetti" delta="False">
    <text>That's not the gender of a person that is the sex of a person.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
