<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="46" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29806483926.0" user="MutatedSpleen" delta="False">
    <text>This is a difficult, but also very interesting question, and I'm glad you asked it.  I want to preface what I write here by saying that I'm a little tone deaf when it comes to discussing serious and potentially hurtful topics online.  Please know going forward that I mean absolutely nothing negative whatsoever.

Okay, let's do it.

Your basic question has one significant and important flaw in it - the term "gender".  "Gender" is essentially a shorthand term that colloquially can mean a couple of different things.  Typically, the social justice-inclined (and specifically LGBTQ+-focused) communities make use of two different phrases instead of the somewhat foggy term "gender".  They use "sex assigned at birth" or "biological sex" to refer to the physical markers that make up someone's sex or "gender", and they use "gender identity" to refer to the lived experience of sex or gender, the latter of which you (accurately) made reference to yourself.

"Sex assigned at birth" is not, itself, a 100% perfect term - there are intersex conditions that exist which dilute the phrase somewhat, but for general discussion, those aren't super necessary to include I think.  I bring this phrase up, however, to argue that relevance of the latter term (gender identity).  Gender identity IS a social construct - its descriptive terms (male, female, trans, etc) refer to specific things in regards to our their relationship to greater societal norms and expectations.  Sex assigned at birth, however, is NOT a social construct - it's a term that makes reference to the physical and biological markers that differentiate maleness, femaleness, and the areas in-between.

I'm going to gloss over most gender identity terms - male, female, agender, etc - as they aren't relevant to your initial question.  The terms we need to think about are transgender and cisgender.  Transgender is when your gender identity - the way you live and perceive your gender in the greater context of society - does not align with that which society expects from you as a result of your sex assigned at birth (e.g., gender identity doesn't align with sex assigned at birth).  Cisgender is when your gender identity DOES align with your sex assigned at birth (e.g., I'm cisgender because I was assigned male at birth and I identify as male).

To sum up so far - gender identity isn't just how you experience your gender, it's how you experience your gender in relation to the sex you were assigned at birth.

What makes the concept of race (which itself, is a very shakey and loose concept) so different from gender identity is the concept of ancestry.  You simply can't distance ancestry from race - even though it can (and often does) get a little cloudy when you look back through generations and see parents and grandparents of different races/ethnicities.  All of this ALSO ties - very directly - into class, wealth, and to a large extent, geography as well.

So, to actually go back and answer your question...sure, race IS a social construct, but it's a social construct that has a very important tie to ancestry and history in it, whereas gender identity doesn't.  I think your question itself, however, wasn't exactly whether or not race is a social construct, I think it was whether it's okay or not to accept the concept of being "transracial".

To that extent, I would argue that it's not okay to claim someone else's history and ancestry as your own.  The Indian man you described can "feel" black because he grew up in a black neighborhood, faced skin-color discrimination like some of his friends and family may have, and so forth, but he can't claim the same history and the same shared lineage as his friends of African descent.  His own ancestral story might have its own share of horrors and oppression, but it isn't their story.

And to an even greater extent, he won't get treated the same as his friends.  He might be treated similarly, but not the same.  I don't want to get into many of the specifics of what stereotypes will be assigned to these folks and what not, but they aren't the same, and society treats them differently.  He's more likely to be assumed to be an IT professional than to be a street criminal, for example.

That's why Rachel Dolezal got so much negative feedback.  She was claiming to be part of the history, the ancestry, and the story of Black Americans, and that just wasn't her history.  Psychology has a phenomenon known as generational trauma (sometimes "transgenerational trauma") that basically refers to the transfer of trauma from survivors of one generation to survivors of the next.  There is a lot of reading about this topic specifically in regards to holocaust survivors, but it's a reality within a lot of black communities as well.  Rachel didn't have that trauma - it wasn't a part of who she was, but claiming blackness as her own, she was claiming that trauma.

I got pretty ranty there.  I hope that was mostly coherent, and though I don't know if I'll change your view at all - I'm not actually even sure I am trying to - I hope I was able to provide a useful perspective.  I spent a very large amount of time in school studying the psychological and sociological phenomena that exist within the spectra of race and gender, and these are a large basis of my continued work within the field of social work, so they are topics very near and dear to my heart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807016126.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>How is any of this different than claiming to be part of a certain gender's heritage, culture, ancestry, history, etc. when you aren't really that gender? Men and women have their own distinct historical and cultural practices that differentiate them from the other gender, just like races do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807050017.0" user="MutatedSpleen" delta="False">
    <text>I don't mean to be daft, but I pretty much explained that.  Gender doesn't take ancestry or lineage into consideration - you have an equal chance of being either gender/sex regardless of any other circumstances of your birth, but your race is defined before you are even conceived.  Or, in other words, you aren't a woman (and therefore have the societal issues of women) because your mother was a woman.  But you are black (and therefore have the societal issues of being black) because your mother is black (I don't mean to exclude mixed-race people or anything or that nature, there is a whole lot of history that makes that a complicated subject, I simply chose this as an easy example).

Heritage, culture, ancestry, and history are all different things.  You can appreciate each of them, regardless of the circumstances of your birth, and you can claim some of them regardless of those same circumstances.  Like OPs example of the Indian man in a black community - he may have some legitimate claim to aspects of black culture, but he doesn't have any claim to black ancestry, heritage, or history.

On the other hand, there's no such thing as "female heritage" or "male ancestry" (not to be confused with "male ancestors", which would refer to your literal forefathers and such).  I do think these sorts of things get a little pedantic, and I think that is exactly why these issues are as complicated as they are.  We use lots of words to mean the same thing when, really, they don't.

That's my view, anyway.  I'd be interested in hearing more about yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807180824.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the response, and apologies for missing whatever it was the first time around. I can't really see what you're trying to address in regards to my comment in your OP, but that might just be my fault for expressing myself poorly. 

Of course race is determined pre-conception, I fully agree with that. And in that sense "heritage" is unique to race. But in terms of when what you are, be it a certain gender or a certain race, actually starts to matter, you're well past the point of conception. 

What I meant to say is that, in terms of lineage, heritage, culture, ancestry, history, etc., everything that makes, say, Indian people Indian instead of Scandinavian is rooted in that history, etc., rather than biology. The reason we have differences in culture between racial and ethnic groups, and resulting behavior from that, is our typically multi-hundreds-of-thousands years of history where, for instance, Indian people lived around Indians in India, and Scandinavians lived around Scandinavians in Scandinavia for a sufficient period of time to develop different cultures and histories. 

That said, men and women from all cultures and backgrounds also share similar histories and, for lack of a better word, cultures. You can see the parallels across virtually every culture: men are the hunters, protectors, and providers; women are the gatherers, nurturers, and child-bearers, for one example. I'd even argue that these differences, rooted in our nature, separate genders more surely than the fact that Indian cuisine favors curry while British cuisine includes tea. 

Part of me being a man is that I'm expected to be tough and lack emotion. I'm expected to earn well and provide for my wife and children. I'm expected to know how to start a shitty lawnmower, and be the designated spider-killer of the house in spite of my crippling arachnophobia. My girlfriend is expected to present a pretty face in public, framed by new, nice clothing. She's expected to put her career on hold for child-rearing. She's expected, or perhaps allowed, to show emotion in abundance and cry at the movies or go nuts when we're on a walk and someone with a cute baby or dog passes by us. 

These traditions are partly a product of societal conditioning, but also rooted in biology; my girlfriend would be much more poorly equipped to hunt a mammoth than I would; I'm much, much, much more poorly equipped to produce human offspring than she is. Since they have both biological and societal influences, I'd say they're even *more* deeply ingrained than anything separating cultures between races or ethnicities; in high school my passable Farsi and mastery of Persian cuisine earned me the title of "Honorary Persian" among many of my fobby friends, because despite my white skin, I had more or less proved myself adequate in most things typically Persian. I've also had Asian friends who would have identified themselves as "more white than you are," so Americanized they were. A male-to-female trans woman, though, will never, ever, no matter how hard she tries, be able to experience things like pregnancy, birth, menopause, and PMS. It's not as simple as learning a new language and being able to fry up a few dishes and understand cultural archetypes for a person to be a gender they aren't; they simply can't do it for purely biological reasons. And those biological traits *shape who we are as a member of our gender,* in a much more immutable way than any racial phenomenon could. 

Also worth noting that for a trans person to even attempt to get close to the gender they're trying to emulate they have to take some very drastic measures. A Korean kid can become Americanized by just dropping Korean culture and not speaking with an accent; for your average female-to-male trans person to have a hope in hell of benching the kind of weight I can she's going to have to start chopping off body parts and put herself on a daily routine of mind and body altering drugs. 

I clearly rant as well as you do, but the long to short of it is that everything that defines a race as a race is also prevalent in what it is that defines us as a man or a woman. Every single societal construct is present in that definition as well as it is with different racial groups, and they all contribute to why men and women act the way they do. But unlike racial groups there are biological reasons why men and women act the way they do and not the opposite, or exactly the same. If anything trans-racialism is *more* easy to accept than transgenderism, because one can learn in full the culture and traditions of any given race, even if they weren't born into it, but nobody can really overcome the drastic biological differences separating different genders. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
