<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29805332323.0" user="Cadfan17" delta="False">
    <text>Tons of people believe that race is a social construct. Probably as many or more than those who believe gender is. 

The argument for it is straight forward. People who believe this acknowledge that some genetic differences exist between humans, but argue that these genetic differences do not group humans on the same lines that our social concept of race does. They argue that the social concept of race can’t be recreated from biological “facts on the ground,” even for relatively simple and non-prejudiced visions of what race means. Instead, if you want to know what race a person is, you have to look at their society and how it divides people into groups. 

They’re pretty much right. If you try to come up with a genetic basis for what it is to “be white” you’re going to either have a monumentally simplistic one (low melanin production?) that nevertheless still includes and excludes people in ways that don’t match society, or, you’re going to fail outright. Plus whatever definition you come up with will fail the test of comparison to history, because our idea of what it meant to be white or black or whatever keeps changing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807689487.0" user="rathyAro" delta="False">
    <text>Why doesn't melanin production work as a way to identify race?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807865648.0" user="Cadfan17" delta="False">
    <text>It “works” in the sense that it is an observable fact that maps well to society’s racial divisions (since society observes it and typecasts people), but it is a poor predictor of geographic ancestry, genetic heritage, and other details traditionally believed to be racial (there are a ton of people with both European and African ancestry and melanin is not a great way of figuring out how much they have if each), and it starts falling apart even further if you try to use it for any racial grouping other than “black” versus “not black.” </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807933642.0" user="rathyAro" delta="False">
    <text>I see, good point.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
