<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29805368069.0" user="Genoscythe_" delta="False">
    <text>You got things precisely backwards. 

Transgenderism is vindicated exactly by the existence of neurogically ingrained gender identities, and by the fact that in that regard, gender is more than a social construct. 

Gender roles are a social construct. There is no inherent reason why women wear skirts, or feminine things are marked with pink, only cultural ones.  

Similarly, yes, we are pretty clear that racial categories were set up in a social construct. Human skin tones are a gradient scale, that we arbitrarily divide into "Black" and "white" and even weirder ones like "latino" that is sometimes black and sometimes white, or into "asian" that isn't actually a skin color and that sometimes includes indian and middle-eastern, sometimes not. 



 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805679424.0" user="pewiepete" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty sure it was whether you had a dick or a vagina that determined your gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805693004.0" user="Genoscythe_" delta="False">
    <text>Then what if you have both, or neither?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805901215.0" user="pewiepete" delta="False">
    <text>In the vary rare case that does happen, seek professional guidance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805921331.0" user="Genoscythe_" delta="False">
    <text>Well, of course, but what happens then? 

You lose your dick in an accident, and seek professional guidance... and? 

Will the professional guidance say that without a dick, you no longer have a gender? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805956131.0" user="pewiepete" delta="False">
    <text>Wait what?! So you're saying if a person who was already born a man gets his penis amputated? Then of course he's still a man. He just had an accident. I though you mean someone who was born without either, or a hermaphrodite. 

Of course you're still a man. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805740852.0" user="ylimemily92" delta="False">
    <text>That identifies your sex, not your gender </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805928560.0" user="pewiepete" delta="False">
    <text>I've never understood this point. Can you explain please?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805957292.0" user="ylimemily92" delta="False">
    <text>The internet is a good source of knowledge and I don’t profess to know all the answers but I do know there is a difference between these two, even though they are confused/used interchangeably at times with similar terminology. Your sex is based on your physical attributes (penis v vagina). Your gender is based on an innate feeling and is expressed via a set of actions and behaviours and roles which can come from expectations based on your sex. Sometimes it matches up, sometimes it doesn’t. It’s a bit like sexuality - it can be connected to your sex, but not always. I like to think sexuality and gender are fluid and you can be anywhere on the spectrum - humans like to label everything (which can do more harm than good sometimes when someone doesn’t fit into a pre-approved box)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805987174.0" user="pewiepete" delta="False">
    <text>So Sex = what you are, and Gender = how you feel? 

If the implied line here is that sexuality is based on social constructs I would wholeheartedly disagree with that statement. There is a very obvious biological explanation for the majority of most every human (and animal for that matter) sexual attraction. 

I would also stress that physicality alone is not the only determinate for Sex. You can be a 30 year old man and cut off your dick, but that doesn't make you a woman. In my mind, people like Caitlyn Jenner are still men. 

"Gender is based on an innate feeling..." What if I feel like a Ford Explorer? Can I now be treated as such. Do you also sympathize with otherkin? What if I'm biologically 16, but feel like a 21 year old and demand someone sell me alcohol? 

The way you feel does not determine who you are. Just because you say you're a woman (or a man) does not mean you are. 

This is my main problem with all of this "gender fluidity" stuff; it's all based on feelings. You cannot base such distinctions on feelings alone. And don't get me wrong, I'm all for applied sciences like psychology. They too don't have hard facts like Physics or Chemistry. But they have more of a leg to stand on than this shit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806100547.0" user="Governor-Amos" delta="False">
    <text>This is the most standard argument imaginable. It's not that you're wrong or not entitled to this opinion, it's just devoid of nuance.

Whether you think that transgenderism is a mental illness or not, this is the social construct that is being put before us. 

So, instead of giving the most base argument, you might consider that even if you disagree, there are people who feel like &amp;amp; want to become the opposite sex, and society is enabling them. Your fight should be with society, not individual trans people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806154489.0" user="pewiepete" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have a problem with someone who wants to be trans. If that's a person's inclination then go ahead, I don't care. What I care about is how much I am supposed to participate in their choice. 

I'm not going to indulge someone who thinks they're something they're not. I won't call a trans woman a woman, because that's not correct. Just as I won't indulge someone who thinks they're Otherkin. 

Live your life how you want, but don't force others to treat you because of how you see yourself and not the reality of who you are. Rachel Dolezal can dress up all she wants, but I will not pretend she is a black person. 

And society is at fault when they recklessly encourage others in their delusions. You ever seen that TLC show "I Am Jazz?" This poor child had a mental problem, and rather than help them to understand their condition, they encouraged them to become the opposite sex. Barbara Walters went as far as to interview a 6 year old about their "gender identity." Now I've worked with kids for the last seven years. These kids don't even know how to tie their shoes. Many still believe in Santa Claus. How the fuck are they supposed to know who they are? 

It is dangerous as a society to encourage very young kids to pursue things like gender reassignment. Adults are one thing; kids are another. We need to be more responsible as to how society treats these sort of incidents. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805729462.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>If gender roles are a social construct, then how do you explain that nearly every living binary sex mammal, insect, etc have distinct gender roles?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805753001.0" user="pennypinball" delta="False">
    <text>wouldn't you say that they also have social constructs as well then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805771340.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>no, i would say their behavior is being guided by biological determinism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805911161.0" user="punking_funk" delta="False">
    <text>Can you define "biological determinism"? Because it seems like biological determinism just creates social constructs (usually to increase efficiency) which enforce gender roles</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805930199.0" user="mudra311" delta="False">
    <text>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biological_determinism

For example, the fact that women should wear dresses and make up is a social construct.

While the fact that men should pursue more labor careers than women, because men are genetically stronger, would be more in line with biological determinism. The reason why this is coming up recently is because we aren't able to ascertain (particularly with jobs) why exactly men and women pursue different careers. Some will argue social construct, others say biology. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805935931.0" user="Genoscythe_" delta="False">
    <text>Animals don't have cultural traditions, therefore their gender roles can't be socially constructed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805984508.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>Then where do their gender roles come from? Their mass-media?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805987869.0" user="Genoscythe_" delta="False">
    <text>instinctual behavior, mostly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806000673.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>yep. Biological determinism, just like us humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806002289.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806004245.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, Genoscythe_ – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; No low effort comments. This includes comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes'. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+Genoscythe_&amp;amp;message=Genoscythe_+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/doxq2k1/\)+because...)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806098703.0" user="ConsiderTheLemming" delta="False">
    <text>Why make the leap to saying that because gender roles in animals are not socially determined the same is true for humans? Are you going to tell me that women wearing dresses is completely biologically determined?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806275859.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>Even monkeys who don't understand what a gendered toy is have gendered preferences:

&amp;gt; Socialization processes, parents, or peers encouraging play with gender specific toys are thought to be the primary force shaping sex differences in toy preference. A contrast in view is that toy preferences reflect biologically determined preferences for specific activities facilitated by specific toys. Sex differences in juvenile activities, such as rough and tumble play, peer preferences, and infant interest, share similarities in humans and monkeys. Thus if activity preferences shape toy preferences, male and female monkeys may show toy preferences similar to those seen in boys and girls. We compared the interactions of 34 rhesus monkeys, living within a 135 monkey troop, with human wheeled toys and plush toys. Male monkeys, like boys, showed consistent and strong preferences for wheeled toys, while female monkeys, like girls, showed greater variability in preferences. Thus, the magnitude of preference for wheeled over plush toys differed significantly between males and females. The similarities to human findings demonstrate that such preferences can develop without explicit gendered socialization. We offer the hypothesis that toy preferences reflect hormonally influenced behavioral and cognitive biases which are sculpted by social processes into the sex differences seen in monkeys and humans.

- https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2583786/

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806288324.0" user="ConsiderTheLemming" delta="False">
    <text>Again, why assume that what is true of monkeys is true of humans? Also you didn't address my other question. Do women wear dresses because of biology?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806300638.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Male monkeys, **like boys**, showed consistent and strong preferences for wheeled toys, while female monkeys, **like girls**, showed greater variability in preferences.. 

Because many academics blamed gendered toy preferences on socialization when clearly that has very little to do with it. There's an innate and biologically determined preference for a great deal of our behavior. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806310472.0" user="ConsiderTheLemming" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not trying to say there aren't innate differences. Why do you assume that societal factors don't play a role in gender though? And can you answer my question about the dress thing please?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806482557.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>Here, this [person has explained it](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/doxt9r4/) better than i'll ever be able to:

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806421032.0" user="TabulaRasa85" delta="False">
    <text>Correlation is not causation. Just because both male monkeys and humans like the same toy does not equate to biological markers as the root cause in both cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806457515.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>quack, quack.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806361213.0" user="long-lankin" delta="False">
    <text>Are you suggesting that women are biologically driven to wear dresses and like pink? 

Or, more insidiously, are you asserting that women are naturally less talented when it comes to STEM fields, and so on and so forth?

The curious thing about all that is if you really believe it, then I don't see why you bother arguing about it anyway. Surely your perspective should be that as culture and society doesn't affect behaviour, why not just leave well alone? If you're right, men and women will keep behaving as always. And if you're wrong, well, people will do what they want to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806389672.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>Yawn. Such a tired argument you're trying to make. There's always going to be a social influence on behavior and choice, but that plays only a small and superficial role. When you strip away all the window dressing, you can clearly see that each of the sexes is generally governed by their biology. Observing the world around you can quickly confirm this idea and no amount of social engineering is going to change our innate behavior. In fact, the harder you push, the more resistance there is.

Here's a short doc on what happened when Norway tried to enforce behavioral equality:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p5LRdW8xw70</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806408179.0" user="long-lankin" delta="False">
    <text>And yet, despite claiming that it only plays a very superficial role, you seem very eager to force people to conform to your own rigid expectations. 

I'm not talking about forcing people to do anything. I'm not even claiming that without societal pressures there'd be 50/50 representation in STEM, though I think it's certainly possible. Sure, there are general differences between men and women - but I don't think they're anywhere near as critical as you make out.

All I think is that without people telling others what they can and can't do, influencing them from youth, maybe you'd find that the role of biology is overstated. 

Incidently, please you can offer anything to suggest that it is nature, and not nurture at all, that plays a critical role? I would point to studies showing that girls are as good as boys at maths and reasoning tests, but perform worse when reminded boys are better at those subjects etc. Unfortunately I'm on mobile, though I'll try to get round to it later.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806442087.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>I think the proof that it's nature over nurture can be easily understood through observation of the world around us. Nearly all binary animals behave in binary ways without any societal conditioning. When humans are left to their own devices, we unanimously gravitate towards a stereotypical gendered behavior. 

I find it to be a beautiful harmony, a natural balance and a complimentary relationship. Two halves creating a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806461975.0" user="long-lankin" delta="False">
    <text>Okay,  but what evidence do you have that that's the case?

In any event, I can understand saying 'Men are stronger And more aggressive in general, so they tend to make better hunters and labourers. But none of that accounts for the reality of the modern world, and the complexity of human society. Being more suited to hunting doesn't mean you're better at being a programmer or coder. Even if you can make the correlation, it still doesn't seem anywhere enough to explain the current deficit alone.

And once again, if it is the case, why do you dislike telling people they're free to do whatever they want?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806510400.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;why do you dislike telling people they're free to do whatever they want?

I think you wildly misunderstand my position. I genuinely believe in absolute freedom of behavior and choice. The people who are forcing the genders to conform to their belief of behavior are those who think we should be 50/50. But i also believe that given the choice, you'll find we go right back to the balance we've always had. Men will gravitate towards traditionally masculine pursuits and women towards theirs. Ye ol' biological determinism...

Exactly like [what happened in Norway](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p5LRdW8xw70).
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806267598.0" user="GlyphGryph" delta="False">
    <text>*Do* animals have "gender roles"? That... doesn't seem likely. Most animals don't really have "roles" at all, not the way you seem to be thinking of them, just bundles of instincts and physical traits. But roles imply a "should" and animals don't really have "should"s - their communication doesn't get that complex.

One of the things that differentiates humans from most other animals is that we've largely suppressed out instincts and adopted a much more plastic, adaptive approach to... basically everything.

Arguing animals have actual gender roles is like arguing animals have an actual species - both are just constructs humans can *apply* to the animals to try and create useful communicative shorthands for commonly (but generally not strictly) bundled traits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806463903.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>What do you call it when nearly all males of a species behave differently than females of the same species?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806943899.0" user="Horricule" delta="False">
    <text>These are sex roles, not gender roles, as only humans have been known to have the social construct of gender. Our construct of gender is based largely upon instinctual sex roles, but not entirely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806990100.0" user="earthsworld" delta="False">
    <text>While that may be true, nobody knows what sex roles means, not even [wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_role)...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807003665.0" user="Horricule" delta="False">
    <text>You just said said sex roles are. When animals have distinct roles based off of what sex they were born as that every member of that animal's sex follows, (ex. Female lion hunts, male lion doesn't) then that is their sex role. The reason why us humans don't really have something like that (or something exactly like that) is because we created gender. And we not only created gender, but we have seperated gender from sex. And the reason why we refer to these actions done by the animals as gender roles and not sex roles is because that the word sex is often used with an entirely different meaning, which is the entire reason why gender as a synonym for sex was popularized in the first place. Our gender roles are different from these sex roles as not only are they related directly to gender instead of just sex, but many of them are societal memes based off of biological instinct instead of pure biological instinct itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807224027.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806575894.0" user="edie_carm" delta="False">
    <text>There is a reason why women are forced into the trappings of femininity - men hate us, want to hurt us, and oppress us. Do you think that there is something, some neurological ~~flaw~~ """just a difference""" in our laydee brains that make us *want* to be paid less, wear crippling shoes, get raped? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806816901.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807296189.0" user="whitef530" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, earthsworld – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostile behavior seriously. Repeat violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+earthsworld&amp;amp;message=earthsworld+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/doy7j45/\)+because...)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807858117.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807998516.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, Rec1umWrecker – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; Don't be rude or hostile to other users. Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2)

**Please be aware that we take hostile behavior seriously. Repeat violations will result in a ban.**

If you would like to appeal, please [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+Rec1umWrecker&amp;amp;message=Rec1umWrecker+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/doytuit/\)+because...)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29808033939.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807002306.0" user="ZeroDagger" delta="False">
    <text>I find it problematic to suggest that we only accept transgenderism because of scientific evidence. What if there was proof of no difference between the male and female brain? What would happen to trans people then?

We should accept these people because we respect them, not because science "commands" us to.

For the record, I support Dolezal as well.  I guess she seems genuine to me. Maybe we all need to be a little more tolerant. It wouldn't kill us, would it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29808424265.0" user="circlhat" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you, Gender roles are a social construct, but gender is not nor is sex</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
