<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="438235887.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/78wwz3/cmv_if_gender_is_a_social_construct_then_so_is/">
    <title>CMV: If gender is a social construct, then so is race</title>
    <original_poster>BoppeBoye</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let us take, as a given, that gender is divorced from the circumstances of your birth, that it is not a mental illness, and that there is no biological basis for what gender identity someone should express. Have I phrased that effectively? I'm trying to be concise, but I want to portray that premise correctly.

Why, then, should race be different than gender? If race carries with it "shared experience" and "lived experience", etc - that assumes that the only way you could understand what it's like to be a minority is to have lived your entire life as that particular minority. I'm not arguing against that, I agree that there are certain experiences that I could not comprehend - for instance, overbearing &amp;amp; strict Asian parents with exceedingly high expectations. 

But, if someone can change their gender or decide (?) that they identify as a different gender without having the prior lived experience of said gender, then why can't someone identify as a different race?

I'm not able to encompass all the variables which could lead someone to identify as another gender, but is it not possible for someone to come to the same conclusion with their race? What if an Indian man grew up in a predominantly black neighborhood, saw or experienced the same (or similar) discrimination as them, had minimal exposure to Indian culture; and this led him to conclude that he identifies more closely as a black man, rather than Indian? 

I would also like to cite Rachel Dolezal, who was uniformly mocked for being (afaik) the first trans-black woman in the public eye. It seems similar to transgender discrimination to me, assuming that there is something wrong with her mentally for deciding to become a black woman... Anyway, I'm not really defending her because that's not really in line with what I described in the previous paragraph (she grew up privileged IIRC), but the public reaction of mockery goes against the leftist belief of acceptance, by my perspective.

So, in short, why can there be no such thing as trans-racial people, the same way there are transgender?

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29805277390.0" user="aRabidGerbil" delta="False">
    <text>Just for clarification, is there anyone who argues that gender is a social construct but race isn't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805291114.0" user="bayes_net" delta="False">
    <text>Does anyone really think that there is no biological basis to sex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805320662.0" user="aRabidGerbil" delta="False">
    <text>There are plenty of biological basis for sex but there isn't one defining one.  You can define sex by chromosome, gonad, phenotype, neurotype, hormones, etc.  None of them are the "right" way to define sex they're just useful in different situations; personally, I'd consider a person's neurotypical sex to be the most important when determining the sex the person should be because I think a someone's brain is far more linked to who they are than the rest of their body.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805373979.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>"Gender" and "sex" are sometimes used interchangeably. However, when they're used to talk about different things, "sex" usually refers to biology and "gender" refers to social and cultural differences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805418376.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>There are people like Judith Butler who think that what constitutes "sex" (i.e. in terms of the binary "male/female") is as much a product of social and political forces as gender is, e.g. the arbitrary assignment of one or the other sex to intersex individuals. 

As /u/aRabidGerbil suggested, the thinking from people like Butler and others is that it's actually a lot harder than we tend to assume it is to pinpoint what makes someone's sex "male" and what makes it "female." As soon as we recognize how many exceptions and edge cases there are when it comes to the biological indicators we use to determine sex, you can see how someone could make the case that sex isn't necessarily a more stable category than gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805325114.0" user="darwin2500" delta="False">
    <text>Most people, yes.

The breakdown is that 'sex' is a scientific term that refers to biological traits and 'gender' is a social construct that refers to personality traits.

Most people would either say that 'race' refers to both the biological traits and cultural background, *or* that 'race' refers only to the biological traits and something like 'culture' or 'heritage' refers to the cultural background.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805371275.0" user="LiberalTerryN" delta="False">
    <text>I think what you're missing is that "race" is a social construct in that certain biological traits fall into certain categories of race. What makes Anglos the same race as Italians or Greeks? What makes the Spanish a different race from Arabs? What makes Koreans the same race as Hawaiians? 

Lines between races need to be drawn, but the closer you look, the more it seems that the lines are drawn according to social convention at the time, and that the lines will shift over time to accommodate changes in society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805409653.0" user="darwin2500" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, that is true because, as I was trying to express, 'race' is typically used to refer to some poorly-defined conglomeration of biological, cultural, and heritage-based traits.  Therefore race is *partially* defined by traits which are social constructs, but not *entirely* - if you *only* used constructs to determine someone's race, you would make classifications that no one else would, and be unable to communicate with them about the topic.

I do think it would be better if everyone agreed to consistently use separate biology/background terms, like 'race' and 'heritage' or something (the way we are trying to convince people to do with sex/gender), but we're not there yet and I think 'race' would end up referring to biology anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805564749.0" user="LiberalTerryN" delta="False">
    <text>But sex is a binary categorization that holds for all sexually reproducing animals. An alien visiting from outer space with no knowledge of human anthropology could determine the sex of animals, including humans.

Race, on the other hand, cannot have a fixed biological definition separate from social convention. Skin color, eye shape, etc. are not enough, because differences in those attributes are neither necessary nor sufficient to demonstrate lines of demarcation between races. Ultimately, the physical phenotypes that define race are socially selected attributes that aren't necessarily related to one another. That's why a light skinned Korean guy can be the same race, in American society, as a dark skinned Pakistani guy or a brown skinned Hawaiian guy. But that same categorization of race might not hold in a place like China. And an alien with no knowledge of human anthropology wouldn't be able to predict which physical attributes get clustered into which taxonomic groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29805812922.0" user="darwin2500" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But sex is a binary categorization that holds for all sexually reproducing animals.

No.  There are many hermaphroditic animals that reproduce sexually, and animals that naturally transition between male and female roles through their lifetime. Even humans have a variety of hermaphroditic and intersex conditions that would be hard to classify into a simplistic binary, especially for aliens.

&amp;gt;Race, on the other hand, cannot have a fixed biological definition separate from social convention.

Although this is not the way it is currently done in all contexts, you could have biological definitions of races that are based on ancestry and heredity, or genetic classifications centering on specific gene clusters that are typical for one race but not another.  This is similar to how we denote taxonomy for animals, which is why dolphins are mammals rather than fish and why penguins are birds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806252430.0" user="MrEctomy" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely. Everyone who laughs at rachel dolezal, but claims to support the transgender community. She has lived her life as a black woman for many years now, she's studied African American culture, taught classes about African American culture for over ten years with no complaints, lead the Spokane chapter of the NAACP for years with no complaints, and one interesting thing you never hear anyone mention, she's made dozens of afro-centric paintings as part of her degree.

What is her end game if she doesn't actually feel like a black woman? Are we just waiting to see how long until she gives up the "act"? What if she continues living this way until the day she dies? What then? Will we have a new world record for "longest facade"? If living her life as a black woman isn't good enough, what is? Who has the right to say she can't? Black people? Black people took her classes, marched with her in protests, admired her, even loved her. Everyone loved her until they learned the truth of her race, then suddenly decided she was just a master manipulator.

By the way, she recently released a book about her life as a black woman. I guess she's really doubling down on her deception.

And yet many people who support transgender people think Rachel dolezal is laughable. To me, these people are extreme hypocrites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806827393.0" user="teleekom" delta="False">
    <text>She is laughable</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807028138.0" user="MrEctomy" delta="False">
    <text>Can you tell me why you think that is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807397239.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>You're creating a false equivalence. What determines gender and what determines race are different. The terms "man" and "woman" typically concern ideas of masculinity and femininity. For example, we think of skirts as an item of clothing worn by women. We think of sport coats as an item of clothing worn by men. Nothing is stopping a male or female from wearing any specific article of clothing, though. There is no scientific law that explains why we associate pink with femininity and blue with masculinity. Gender is an idea we humans invented to describe a pattern of behaviors. Those behaviors can be exhibited by people of any sex. That is why it is a social construct.

The concept of race, on the other hand, is rooted in geography. Race is a social construct because human beings are all taxonomically identical. There is no biological difference between people of different races. Country lines are arbitrary and manmade. The idea of race stems from appearance and geographical background, with the latter being the primary determinant. Rachel Dolezal cannot be "black" in the same way she cannot be "Martian," she has no significant black-African-based heritage. She can, and has, adopted black culture, but she cannot change her heritage, and thus, cannot change her race. I hope my explanation was clear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29807684968.0" user="Snuffleupagus4Pres" delta="False">
    <text> &amp;gt;There is no biological difference between people of different races.

This is not true.  It is a small difference, and attributed to geographic location of ancestry, but there are biological differences.

I.e. what is skin pigmentation but a biological difference?

No objective "better or worse," but the difference is there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29808338494.0" user="PinkyBlinky" delta="False">
    <text>If race is based on appearance and appearance is based on genes than how can race be a social construct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29808680285.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>Because you can have the appearance of someone of a particular race, but not actually be a part of that race. I can get plastic surgery to make myself look Asian. A black woman could bleach her skin and wear contact lenses to look more European. At the end of the day, people of different races can look very different from one another; so, appearance is not the best way to determine race. 

Race is a social construct because the things that define race (geographic borders) are social constructs. Is the border between France and Germany logical? Is there some scientific law or natural process that explains why France's border is the current shape it is? Not really, it's completely arbitrary. Because we define race based on these arbitrary factors, that is why it is a social construct. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29809520654.0" user="Thepotatohaslanded" delta="False">
    <text>Are you trying to say race is skin deep? You they can find the race of a murder victim by looking at the skull's structure and shape, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29806953723.0" user="Horricule" delta="False">
    <text>I argue this. There is a clear divide in the meaning of the word sex and the word gender, sex is what you're born with and gender a social construct that ususally (but not always) correlates with gender. There is a similar divide in the difference between race and culture, except that race is considered what you're born with and culture is the social construct. Granted, race can get messy at times as what is and isn't considered a race does change over time (the Irish were at one point not really considered white) and the race of latino is a giant mess at times. However, the definition has not changed and race does still not change. I also have not found any cases or evidence of "race dysphoria," or at least a disconnect bad enough to cause a poor mental state. Most people just identify with their culture instead.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
