<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836296248.0" user="uselessrightfoot" delta="False">
    <text>You have the whole paradigm wrong. People will not and do not need to come together. 

People fall into the trap that there is are two legitimate sides to every issue and they just need to come together and find something in the middle that'll please everyone. 

But in real life, that's not how people think. It is, in a very real way, us versus them. Take the example of workers being fired for unionizing or striking. Their billionaire owners, the politicians, are taking away their rights and their livelihoods. How do you "come together" on that?

Take the example of an elderly person who relies on medicaid and medicare to stay alive. How do you expect them to come together with Republicans and their plan to cut healthcare and benefits?

Or an undocumented immigrant, who will be deported. How does she come together and compromise? What does a compromise look like?

What does compromise look like in any of the political situations? In most cases it doesn't exist in any real sense.

So politics isn't about coming together with the other side and trying to convince them, you won't. There are inherent, deep-seated reasons why people believe in what they do, and people don't change their minds.

More than that, people who have power and privilege, resist any change that might take that away from them. There's a reason that women's suffrage was a struggle. That civil rights was a struggle. That we fought a whole war over slavery. In South Africa, during Apartheid, most whites didn't believe in one person one vote for blacks. In America, during Jim Crow, most whites didn't believe in desegregation. Today, most wealthy people don't believe in higher taxes. 

Rights aren't won through compromise or dialogue, they are won through activism and disruption and, sometimes, war. Tell Nelson Mendela all he needed to do was come together and compromise with his oppressors.

The goal of politics shouldn't be to come together with those who believe in the polar opposite of what you want. That is a bad and failed approach. The goal is to find like-minded people and bring them together. 

Say you believe in universal healthcare in America. The approach shouldn't be to go after Republicans who don't believe in taxation to convince them that this is right. The approach is to find people who want the same and then build political pressure on your representatives through that, or get the right people elected. Or go further if that doesn't work.


I think partly you are complaining about the media coverage. Yes, the discourse on CNN and MSNBC and Fox News is terrible. They don't talk about real issues. And that is a huge problem for our democracy.

But we do have plenty of good publications and many good journalists doing good work. And with the internet now the TV media holds a lot less power. It is easier to call out their bullshit and put real issues into the mainstream. So there's hope there.

Here Bernie Sanders basically came from nowhere and raised a lot of money through grassroots fundraising and small donations. And came close to toppling a political giant in Clinton, despite either being ignored or derided or dismissed by the mainstream media.

So there is hope that if a leader has ideas that appeal to people we can come together and do something big. He didn't win but a lot of his ideas are gaining mainstream acceptance. And this didn't happen by him trying to bring people together. He was very partisan, very us-vs-them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836819115.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>You raise solid examples to point out civil discussion is not always the way out. In this view, what is the point/purpose of democracy? What can an elected leader accomplish through the maze of corporations and bureaucracy that activists and rebellions civil wars can't? 

*(Disregarding the deaths involved, i.e. glorifying such acts a bit for the sake of argument.)*

Additionally, what does this view mean for the current state of affairs. Do you think some aggressive activism is inevitable? In all this, I'm not becoming more hopeful, but then that may exactly not have been your point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837114245.0" user="uselessrightfoot" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose of Democracy is to build power through activism and organization, and get people who agree with you elected, or put pressure on elected officials to bend to your will.

Recently the Republicans tried to repeal the Affordable Care Act (Obamacare). Thousands of activists around the country were showing up at their representative's offices protesting, getting arrested. Showing up at their public meetings to voice their displeasure. It was enough that 4 or 5 of them caved and allowed Obamacare to live. 

The activism was needed, because there wasn't going to be a debate. The republicans weren't going to sit there with the Democrats and hash out a better bill. That wasn't their goal. So public pressure was needed.

And that brings us to how bad our democratic setup is. Both parties lean to the capitalist right. The Republicans apologetically support policies that only benefit their rich donors and racists. So there's no room for political compromises that actually work for the people.

So political debate and compromise won't work. Especially in a country where half the population watches Fox News and doesn't have a grip on reality. The only solution is to defeat them.

The good news is, we can. Yearning for the better times when problems could be solved by debate is pointless because those times never existed and never will. 

But, people do fall in line once the winds of public opinion start to shift. So gay marriage a decade ago would have been a hugely controversial issue. But through activism, through public pressure, we got marriage equality. Obama in 2008 said he believed marriage was between a man and a woman. But since public opinion shifted, in 2012 he was signing marriage equality into law.

The good news is that we can make a difference. Not through sitting down and compromising with racists, but going out there and promoting causes that we believe in. In whatever small you can. 

And we're taught to bemoan the partisanship and bickering in politics. That's okay, even good. That means people are actually standing up fro what's right. That's far more preferable to people nodding in agreement with Paul Ryan pretending he's saying something legitimate when he proposes to cut healthcare for the poor and elderly. Conservatives will love to cry about the death of discourse but they need to be fought.

So this polarization is good. Radicalization is good. Don't water down your beliefs to protect some vague notion of civility and discourse. Go out and there and get involved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838144739.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>I guess we'll agree to disagree on it being good. I remember now why I didn't like politics in the first place- this us vs them thinking and promoting radicalization, effective as it may be, just doesn't sit well with me. I think I rather will try to be involved with politics a bit less, and invest more time in the fields and topics I am interested in and comfortable with (that being mostly my study). All th while I will keep an eye out for political news that is important to me, such as when it threatens my way of living directly or there is something I feel I can help with / combat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29839833873.0" user="uselessrightfoot" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know how you can disagree when ICE is going around arresting kids from hospitals and schools, fossil fuel profits are being put above the very real and imminent danger of climate change, innocent people are being massacred every day in unjust imperialist wars, rights are being stripped from minorities. 

As long as these bad forces exist, you need people to vehemently oppose them and fight for what's right. Martin Luther King Jr. railed against what he called "white moderates" because they opposed radical action and thus were complicit in racism and oppression.

Politics is wrongly framed as two sides bickering at each other. It's actually a struggle of people against the elite class, the struggle of those who seek social change against those who are racist and backward. 

I don't blame you for finding this depressing. It is. But either we have this struggle or the bad guys win. So your wish can only come true if you remove all the selfish and evil forces out there and produce an ideal world where all people of different opinions are truly coming together to find the best solution. But that is never the case. The oil corporations lobbying to cut back environmental regulations is not a position to be debated and compromised on. It can only be fought.

And I think what you have is a good solution. Focus on what's important to you and help in any way you can.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837138102.0" user="Lurking_Chronicler" delta="False">
    <text>I would personally argue that the purpose of democracy is less about *accomplishment* and more about *representation*. 

Democracy is, frankly, an extremely inefficient way of getting stuff done. It's prone to gridlock and partisan struggles over decision-making, and its all too easy to influence people to vote against their own interests.

However, what democracy can excel at is getting the public invested in their government, and ideally, getting the government to remember the public's interest. In order for any elected government to be successful, its crucial that the public believes that they have a say, that their issues are being heard. And simultaneously, the government must listen to what its citizens have to say, lest it lose public support.

In other words, the purpose of a democracy is to make the government and public depend on one another. It's not a perfect system by any means, and its easy to see the problems with it, but I vastly prefer settling disputes with votes &amp;amp; political wrangling to settling disputes with bloodshed or dictatorial fiat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837235958.0" user="uselessrightfoot" delta="False">
    <text>good point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838138508.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the government must listen to what its citizens have to say, lest it lose public support.

In my view, it is clear that the government apparently is not as bound to this as one would think. I cannot think of one person that is not in the government who would honestly support abolishing net neutrality, for example. Those are not things sprouted, supported and employed by citizens, but by government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838483070.0" user="Lurking_Chronicler" delta="False">
    <text>The government is not as opposed to net neutrality as you think- the fact that efforts to abolish it time and time again should be indicative of that.

Plus, the reason why you hear about congressmen trying to do away with it is because the current government is a Republican dominated one- and, as Trump's latest approval ratings show, the public's will doesn't always align with the dominant party.

And you know what? The great thing about democracy is that if the dominant party's interests don't align with the public, they can always be voted out- which I have a suspicion the GOP may discover in the next set of elections.

You can't say the same for non-democracies. In those, bloodshed and revolution would definitely be required to make such a change. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
