<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836422193.0" user="KittysOwner" delta="False">
    <text>Humans generally don't organize in peaceful ways. Continuous violence is the historical norm. The fact that we're yelling at each other, instead of slaughtering each other is a moral improvement, not a slide backwards.

In earlier years in the USA, high profile politicians got into honor duels and shot each other. There was occasionally physical violence in the senate. Now we just tweet mean things at each other.

We are more peaceful now, than at most points in history. It looks bad to millenials, because we grew up in the 90's and 00's, during the peace dividend from beating the USSR and the national unity engendered by 9/11, respectively.

Yes, in the short term, it looks worse. But in the frame of longer historical trends, it's much better.

The media contributes to the atmosphere. "People have discussion, disagree on some points, agree on others" gets far fewer clicks that covering what some moron on twitter has to say. "Trump behaves like Republican President" gets fewer clicks than "WOMEN AND MINORITIES FEAR THAT HITLER II IS HERE!" They have a profit motive in making it look like we're on the edge of a second civil war, because that gets more eyeballs than a less hysterical depiction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836802816.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>The first part of your comment paints some well needed perspective, hurting each other with words is at least better than hurting each other with sticks and guns. That being said I don't think we should underplay the damage negative discord can have on people and politics and, in turn, the real world. I don't think sensationalism is good for any nation in the long term. 

And the second part of your comment only seems more evidence that we are beyond hope because media will always report items such, causing more heated arguments, causing more headlines, etc ad infinitum.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
