<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836208077.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly is the problem you perceive?

Let's take the political issue of immigration.  How, specifically, do people talk about it destructively?  How, in a perfect world, would they talk about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836435891.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>The way I see that example, (exegerated, since i only note the extremes/problems in this case) people are often either fearmongering about all the terrible stuff the foreigners will do to us (us can be any people, dutch or american or whatever) or calling conservatives evil for not wanting to help their fellow man. I guess a perfect world would contain much more nuance? I'm not sure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836532338.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Nuance like what, and resulting in what?

I'm not asking you to suddenly be an expert on immigration policy, but it seems like you're implying there's some sort of obvious middle-ground that is correct and which people are unwilling to go to, and I'm wondering what that would be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836773052.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>In this case a middle ground would be a quota or other measure, but maybe we're deviating from my main point/complaint, which is that the hostility I see sometimes can feel like it is too much to come back from.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
