<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836714661.0" user="ZeusThunder369" delta="False">
    <text>Can you point out a developed/industrialized country you feel does not have toxic politics? Basically a country where pretty much all the politicians mostly agree on the big issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836769273.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>Uh, no, I don't think I can. Not sure if that's due to none existing or my very limited knowledge of countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836782621.0" user="ZeusThunder369" delta="False">
    <text>I can't either. Okay, so then toxic politics isn't really all that bad. So it seems countries do okay despite the toxic politics.

&amp;gt; I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together

Is this not seen after every tragedy? The donations of money/time after the big hurricanes? The line of people donating blood after the Vegas shooting? The thousands of examples of random kindness from people posting to gofundme to get help for something?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836823385.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>I don't follow your logic that because we can't think of countries with civil discord, that means toxic politics is not bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836840889.0" user="ZeusThunder369" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that it isn't bad at all, it's a question of how bad is it really?

If someone said people putting their bags on empty transit seats, forcing others to stand, is the #1 issue facing our country today, you'd call them crazy. But everyone would agree that this practice is bad.

Perhaps you're over estimating how bad toxic politics is to a country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838146139.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe I am. What do you think are bigger problems than toxic politics, that isn't influenced by toxic politics?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838921518.0" user="ZeusThunder369" delta="False">
    <text>I'll give you one. Copious amounts of added sugar in most food products. This causes millions of deaths every year from diabetes. Wait the nevermind more. Too many people are not saving for retirement. This is going to be a huge problem in 20 years.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
