<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836304177.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>I would challenge you to get involved in local politics. Far too often we let national politics define our views of politics in general, but a great deal of policy is made on the local or state level. Granted, there are issues there as well, but often you can take part and influence them for good. And if *you* can make a difference, then, well . . . it's just up to people who care about these issues to get involved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836790738.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not in the usa actually, but also I have no idea how to get involved in local politics. Do you mean like, become an activist, get involved in discussions (where and how?), actually become a politician?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836801333.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>I mean boots on the ground kind of involvement. But as a foreigner, you could also pick a few localities to start reading about. As an ex-pat, you could start a column/blog, or start calling up old friends from where you used to live.

But if you don't live in the US, I guess I would wonder most why you're using it as your chief test of, to paraphrase, "humans' ability to get along and come together." Surely there's politics where you live as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836830235.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, partly it's because I generally come into contact with a lot more us politics than local, (every headline and reddit post reads trump), and partly because I realised I'm starting to feel the same in The Netherlands but felt the chances of someone replying were higher if I took the US as start-of point. Really, it's semantics because I'm thinking of 'humans' in general, only I only know Dutch and American humans in that sense, I don't know a lot about other politics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836859476.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I would still urge you to get involved in politics, then. I know next to nothing about politics in the Netherlands, but I would imagine there are ways for you to get involved, right? Is there a party you could volunteer with at the local level? Could you talk to local representatives, or even your national representative (parliament?)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838145280.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>I have absolutely no idea, but also I really don't see myself apt to be a politician. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838937414.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>you don't have to be a politician to talk to your political representatives or get involved in a political party. Most people working on this stuff will never hold political office. Or, eschewing parties, to volunteer for candidates or interest groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29842218704.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>I'll try to look into it if I have time some day. I'll just look up 'how do I get politically involved in [my area]', can't be the first one to ask google that surely so I'll probably end up somewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
