<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836204419.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>You are seeing a skewed picture of the world.  The more time you spend on the internet, the more you will be subjected to the vocal fringes of society.  Most people do not get into a screaming match every day about gun control.  Most people never bring up their stance on abortion in conversation.  Most people have very little interest in debating climate change.  Most people don't know what net neutrality means.

The end result of that is that most people are not nearly as passionate as hanging out on the internet would lead you to believe.  Most people DO talk about disagreements in a productive way, because talking face to face will force you to be a bit more civil in most cases. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836778938.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>What you mean is that if I were to discuss these topics in real life as opposed to the internet, I will be met with less hostility? I guess that brings up an interesting point as I don't discuss politics a lot with friends, and when I do, we usually agree or at least remain civil- but those are specifically people I can also be civil with online.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
