<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442231991.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7bakdz/cmv_christianity_is_held_together_through_fear/">
    <title>CMV: Christianity is held together through fear</title>
    <original_poster>M1STER_B0NES</original_poster>
    <original_post>My opinion is that if the fear of going to Hell was not present in the Christian ideology, then most of the followers of the religion would not be there.

Before I decided I was agnostic, that was my only reason for continuing to identify with the religion. Then, I decided I wasn't going to let fear control me. 

All in all, I don't see how this is any different than blackmailing a person to do what you want. You present your instruction, then tell them how you will completely devastate their life if they do not follow through.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29837599867.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>Are you approaching this from the presumption the Christian god is real or not? 

Because Christians believe god created them with free will, so I don't know how you can consider that blackmail. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837608672.0" user="CraftyCanine" delta="False">
    <text>And to add to that, is this under the assumption that "Hell" is literally "fire and brimstone" or simply a place where you are separated from God.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837624239.0" user="M1STER_B0NES" delta="False">
    <text>To answer both questions, I don't, but known many people who do, and have been taught it for my whole life. As for hell, I have been told that being separated from God is worse than any fire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838112854.0" user="Wwendon" delta="False">
    <text>Late to the party, but: assuming the Christian God does exist (for sake of argument), and is therefore literally not only the source of everything good in the universe, but the perfection of everything good in the universe, then being separated from that *would* be the worst thing you could possibly experience. However, there's still a difference between God designing a place of pain to punish those he doesn't like, and God honouring a person's free choice to be separated from him, even though it will ultimately hurt them. 

Basically: yeah, a bunch of Christians, now and through history, have tried to coerce belief through fear. But not all Christians; and those who do are generally ignoring some of the most important parts of Christian theology to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
