<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442231991.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7bakdz/cmv_christianity_is_held_together_through_fear/">
    <title>CMV: Christianity is held together through fear</title>
    <original_poster>M1STER_B0NES</original_poster>
    <original_post>My opinion is that if the fear of going to Hell was not present in the Christian ideology, then most of the followers of the religion would not be there.

Before I decided I was agnostic, that was my only reason for continuing to identify with the religion. Then, I decided I wasn't going to let fear control me. 

All in all, I don't see how this is any different than blackmailing a person to do what you want. You present your instruction, then tell them how you will completely devastate their life if they do not follow through.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29837650487.0" user="810h6zard" delta="False">
    <text>I think that has more to do with how you were raised under Christianity. It's not intended to invoke loyalty through fear, but rather through understanding and acceptance of it. I personally have become a Christian myself after seeing more of the world around me and realizing how corrupt it was, and seeing that the ideals illustrated in the bible have made my life better, and seeing the ruin that follows when we abandon these principles, as supported by science. I don't follow it out of fear, but rather because I see it as the truth. If you nly followed it because of fear, then you never really believed it in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837656276.0" user="M1STER_B0NES" delta="False">
    <text>I think I would say that many of the Bible's core morals are very useful to hold close, but following it just because you think it has a good moral code shouldn't automatically mean that the spiritual deity associated with it is real. However, I'm sure you have already thought about this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29837664824.0" user="810h6zard" delta="False">
    <text>I see where you're coming from, but there's more behind it than that. Everything I see points to a Creator, and the instructions in the Bible detail that Creator and his instructions thoroughly. Nothing else has been able to work so well for me, and it would make sense that whoever inspired the bible had a high understanding of humanity. It only makes sense, at least for me, to believe in that Deity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838281741.0" user="Buddy_Smiggins" delta="False">
    <text>Christ follower here - wanted to offer some thoughts

&amp;gt;  following it just because you think it has a good moral code shouldn't automatically mean that the spiritual deity associated with it is real

You are correct to an extent - I think a lot of Christians believe such because they take the "Christianity is real because it works" approach, but it should be "Christianity works because it's real". 

If you concede the Bible's moral "usefulness", so to say, would you not also concede its moral authority (Yahweh/God)? In a general sense, and absolute morality necessarily references a absolute moral source (many call this a "Supreme Moral Being", or SMB). It so happens that the evidence, after some study, points to Yahweh as this SMB.

I would argue further that there should be less value in seeking to be a "good person" leading us to God, rather, we should value seeking God leading us to being a good person (Philippians 2, Romans 12:2). Many Christians and non-Christians get caught up in this idea of "behavior modification". What Christ really came for and what God calls us too is "heart modification" (2 Corinthians 5:17, Ezekiel 36:26, Sermon on the Mount in Matthew 5).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29839411503.0" user="methegreat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In a general sense, and absolute morality necessarily references a absolute moral source

There is no such thing as 'absolute' morality. 'Good' and 'Bad' and any other related quality is 100% subjective, by very nature of those concepts. 

They are concepts which are, by definition only applicable from a subjective viewpoint. The concepts are literally subjective.

There is only  a scale of authority. A local authority telling you to do something would be more effective than a random stranger. A state/federal establishment would have more authority. A king (in  the past) would have the most authority. A God would have much higher authority than all of these (provided you believed in that god). You have much more reason to listen to god than you do a king. So God telling you what's 'good' and 'bad' is much better than anything else, and can be treated as 'objective' for all practical purposes (even athiests can treat certain moral standards as objective for all practical purposes).

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29839491120.0" user="Buddy_Smiggins" delta="False">
    <text>Hello there and thanks for responding!

Based on your comments about scaled authority, I'm curious - would you concede that God/SMB would be at the "top" of the morality scale? I ask because I think we're saying the same thing, just in different approaches.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29841084852.0" user="methegreat" delta="False">
    <text>Correct.

If you believe in an omnipotent God who created everything, why would you not listen to him ? There is every reason to listen, the most basic of which is your own self interest. So yes, if you believe God is real, he is undoubtedly at the top, for very obvious reasons. Again, think of it as if God appeared to everyone physically in some powerful form and everyone knew his nature and knew he existed. Just about everyone would listen to him, at the very least out of self-interest. There is no human who could even hold remotely the same authority.

The reason I'm making the distinction from your approach is because 'absolute good' is often used to prove God or some kind of authority at some higher level. As I said earlier, that doesn't work because good is not 'absolute' in any way. It is basically a word that people use to describe things that they like.  People settle for some standard and call it 'absolute' or 'objecitve', but that's it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29841295639.0" user="Buddy_Smiggins" delta="False">
    <text>Some great feedback, thanks for sharing, and thanks for responding to my question!

&amp;gt; Again, think of it as if God appeared to everyone physically in some powerful form and everyone knew his nature and knew he existed.

I cannot think of a better description of Jesus!

&amp;gt; People settle for some standard and call it 'absolute' or 'objecitve', but that's it.

IMO, this isn't an incorrect position, necessarily, but I can understand where you're coming from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29841580630.0" user="methegreat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I cannot think of a better description of Jesus!

He didn't appear to everyone though, just a small section of people a long time ago. Everyone else  needs  to decide if they want to believe in what the Bible says about Jesus and his nature. 

&amp;gt;IMO, this isn't an incorrect position, necessarily, but I can understand where you're coming from.

I agree, it's not 'incorrect'. Infact, it's the most practical way of doing things. Athiests, for example don't have God as a possible standard, but it's still best for everyone if some standard is chosen, eg : human well-being. For all intents and purposes, that standard can be taken as 'objective'.   It's not literally 'objective', but it doesn't matter - that's just words and definitions, and it's pointless as far as morality is concerned.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
