<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442231991.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7bakdz/cmv_christianity_is_held_together_through_fear/">
    <title>CMV: Christianity is held together through fear</title>
    <original_poster>M1STER_B0NES</original_poster>
    <original_post>My opinion is that if the fear of going to Hell was not present in the Christian ideology, then most of the followers of the religion would not be there.

Before I decided I was agnostic, that was my only reason for continuing to identify with the religion. Then, I decided I wasn't going to let fear control me. 

All in all, I don't see how this is any different than blackmailing a person to do what you want. You present your instruction, then tell them how you will completely devastate their life if they do not follow through.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29840165779.0" user="remake7" delta="False">
    <text>Why fear something that doesn't exist? If you dont believe in God than why should you be afraid of hell? Although I would agree with maybe agnostics who keep going to Church out of fear of hell but the fear of hell is not enough to make someone Religious. Even agnostics have a reason beyond fear of hell for being uncertain whether God exists (assuming they are agnostic toward the God of a religion). There has to be something more to it to base the belief on.

Although i am not going to deny that there are people who are religious because it gives them confort or they were raise that way (as some people in the comment section have pointed out). Many religious people are religious because they do think it is true for various reasons. 

I was once Agnostic Theist. The reason i thought there may have been a God was, among other reasons, was how Christians speak in tongues. My Dad had even spoke in tongues without realizing it while praying for me and i realized the sickness was gone within a minute after the pray. I also found it hard to believe natural selection was enough to create live the way it is inspite of all the arguments saying  how it just gets a bit more complex over time.

What really grounded my belief in Christianity was when I had a bad day and went out for a walk. People were talking crap about me going to University and I also happened to get into a tense argument with my doctor about the medication and its affects on the brain. As i walked I saw my mum's car go past with my brother in it (they were heading to where i lived) and i felt as though God wanted me to tell them what was up. Then I thought it was a psychotic thought (I had a psychotic episode 1 year prior) but being open to the possibility that it was God I said to God in my head "God if this is you, you have to make it clearer than this because you cannot expect me to believe these things when I'm like this" I kept walking and went down two streets, as i walked down the second street a man pulled over and got out of his car and said "i thought I would do a quick prayer" at this point i just thought he was in a happy mood and was going to do the prayer and walk into his house. He first started praying in Moari (As New Zealand Christians sometimes do). The prayer was going longer than expected and it made me realize this guy probably wasn't about to go into his house - God was answering my prayer. I leaned in waiting for him to start speaking in English hoping for a message from God. When he did he repeated two statements "You know how you are wired" and "Chase your dream, chase your passion" and at the end of the prayer he said "chase it, because it has been planned by God, God has sent me here to tell you this" I knew what the two statements meant straight away. The first statement "you know how you are wired" was referring to the medication meaning "you know how your wired, therefore dont take the medication" and "Chase your dream, chase your passion"  meant i shouldn't listen to what people were saying and go to University because to accomplish my dream i needed to go there. Better yet i want to become a Cognitive Neuroscientist and my aim is to find a 'cure' to Psychosis not through medication but by means of rewiring the brain through work on part of the person with Psychosis! Chase your dream, chase your passion can relate to almost everyone one but you know how your wired, thats not going to relate to many people especially not as much as someone intending to become a Cognitive Neuroscientist. Sure enough when we finished talking to each other he got back into his car and headed off. He pulled over just to pray for me.

These sorts of things happen much more than it appears. Christians generally dont talk about it with non-Christian as people will just think we are crazy. We have more grounds for our beliefs than it appears.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
