<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442231991.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7bakdz/cmv_christianity_is_held_together_through_fear/">
    <title>CMV: Christianity is held together through fear</title>
    <original_poster>M1STER_B0NES</original_poster>
    <original_post>My opinion is that if the fear of going to Hell was not present in the Christian ideology, then most of the followers of the religion would not be there.

Before I decided I was agnostic, that was my only reason for continuing to identify with the religion. Then, I decided I wasn't going to let fear control me. 

All in all, I don't see how this is any different than blackmailing a person to do what you want. You present your instruction, then tell them how you will completely devastate their life if they do not follow through.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29838070067.0" user="Gloriouscdmaster" delta="False">
    <text>All 3 monotheistic religions claim you’ll go to hell if you stop believing, but that’s hardly a practical solution, especially in today’s world, where ideas are easily exchanged across continents and cultures. So, while fear is indeed an ingredient, it doesn’t suffice to keep rituals alive. 

Christianity only exists because of its alliance to a state. That’s how it emerged in the 4th century, and how it survived to this day. As state support disappears, so does Christianity. Look no further than Nordic countries for numerous examples. Christianity is still strong in the US, only because political parties make it a campaign argument, something that’s hardly a matter of discussion in Western Europe.

Christianity is retreating, and will ultimately become a minor religion, exactly as it used to be, unless the state acts either as a protector, or an enforcer. This is especially true for Catholicism, the most deranged branch of Christianity, where priesthood is only offered to males, and requires bachelorhood. I mean, what parents in their right minds will groom their sons to be spouse less, and childless?

Islam will take over, IMO. It’s far more efficient in ensuring the practice of rituals, as each believer is his own thought police, and also because Islam allows *mild* coercion to quash dissent, especially amongst unruly explorers of thoughts, a.k.a teenagers, gays, freethinkers. Before using brute force of course.

More importantly, climate change will predominantly affect countries located around the equator, and the tropics, which is where Islam has its grounds, for historical reasons. If Islam is to survive, it must move north, in place where it can feed its people. Otherwise it will die off. But that’s another problem. 

The reason I bring islam is to stress the importance of group coercion, either sanctioned by a community, or by a state in maintaining religious beliefs. Islam has survived 1400 years almost unchanged because the use of force against its own people is perfectly legal, so long certain conditions are met. There is the threat of Hell, obviously, but physical coercion is far more effective.

If you are still unconvinced, ask yourself what will happen if you want to build a Buddhist temple in a) the UK b) Egypt. Which country will treat you equally, which one will stop you?

Now calculate your chances of success, besides getting your temple off the ground, in finding your first followers? Do you really think you can give away flyers on a farmer’s market after the Friday prayer?

And I’m not even talking about advertising for an atheist meetup...

So fear, as in fear of Hell, isn't a sufficient factor in ensuring religious practice. Sanctioned group-coercion is a necessary and sufficient factor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838348936.0" user="Buddy_Smiggins" delta="False">
    <text>Some thoughts, if I may:

&amp;gt; All 3 monotheistic religions...

I assume you mean "Abrahamic religions", as there are other monotheistic religions (Sikhism, for example). And I use the "Abrahamic religions" term very loosely, because Judiasm and Islam take very different paths from Christianity, which is much more what Abraham's life &amp;amp; belief system embodies.

&amp;gt; ...claim you’ll go to hell if you stop believing...

In regards to Christianity, Hell is intended for the person who chooses to reject God. The "belief" mechanicsm isn't the primary vehicle here, rather, it's choice. As CS Lewis says, there are two responses to God - "thy will be done or my will be done".

&amp;gt; Christianity only exists because of its alliance to a state...

This whole paragraph is based on some misconceptions, IMO. Christianity, in the purest sense, has been oppressed by the organized State since its founding. Heck, the Roman Empire (Nero chief among them) was decidedly anti-Christian, and violently so. Christianity *should* have died out immediately after Jesus' death. But He arose 3 days later, and even more, left the Spirit immediately after His ascension to Heaven to proliferate the Gospel.

Even in Old Testament times, pre-Christ Jews were oppressed by State powers such as Babylonians, Egyptians, and Persians.

In today's world, Christianity is openly oppressed by other States - China is the most obvious example, and other secular (Turkey) or theocratic (Iran) Islamic states are more examples where Christianity faces active persecution, to varying degrees. The irony here is that these are the places where the Gospel is flourishing the most, although from a biblical perspective, this is ironic in the least.

&amp;gt; Christianity is retreating...

In the West, maybe, as we as a whole depart into radical humanism/secularism (we're seeing Romans 1:18-32 and 2 Timothy 3:1-4 in full force, it seems), in places like [China](https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2017/04/china-unregistered-churches-driving-religious-revolution/521544/) and [Iran](https://opentheword.org/2014/09/26/why-is-the-christian-population-exploding-in-iran/), the Gospel is spreading like wildfire. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838702627.0" user="Gloriouscdmaster" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, Abrahamic religions, or if you prefer Judaism flavours. The flourishing of Christianity in the middle east, or Iran? you haven't been paying attention lately.

We're not really discussing what keeps believers into observing religious rituals, but merely what may attract people to christianity. For argument's sake, there are plenty of reasons why a sound-minded person would go to Christianity, chiefly, why spending so much energy in persecuting your neighbour? I wished Christians remembered that when the line between state and religion is blurry, or when a 12 years old girl who endured rape, has to go to an abortion clinic.

But that's hardly the point. A religion with no mechanisms to defend itself is bound to become irrelevant. What you see in Asia is the natural inclination of individuals to a peaceful life.

But what does peace mean when your opponent is morally allowed to kill, to enslave, or to put you in jail? What does peace mean when a Christian thanks his God for the murder of his child? Jews have gained statehood only because they choose not to be victims anymore. Unlike the Christians.

To the exception of those who think they will find their God like their prophet did, Christianity will disappear, just like the religions that came before it. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838757966.0" user="Buddy_Smiggins" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, your responses don't make much sense. It seems you have an axe to grind but I hope I'm wrong. I want to address a few items though.

&amp;gt; The flourishing of Christianity in the middle east, or Iran? you haven't been paying attention lately

As with many things, just because you don't see something (or don't want to see something), doesn't mean it's not there. The article I posted in my previous comment was a single example; there are many others if you're interested.

&amp;gt; A religion with no mechanisms to defend itself is bound to become irrelevant.

* Quick reminder that Christianity is much much more about a [relationship than duty-driven religion](https://www.gotquestions.org/Christianity-religion-relationship.html).
* As Christians, we trust God for our preservation as well as preservation of the Church as a whole, and don't seek vengeance as a means of self-preservation (Romans 12:19, Matthew 5:39).

&amp;gt; What you see in Asia is the natural inclination of individuals to a peaceful life.

From a naturalistic perspective, this is inaccurate - there is no natural inclination of peace, only of survival and reproduction. Peace is only natural from the perspective of "innate morality", referenced in Romans 2:15.

&amp;gt; What does peace mean when a Christian thanks his God for the murder of his child?

This is anecdotal at best, strawman at worst. I'd legitimately question the faith of a Christian who thanked God for the murder of their child. This goes entirely against God's nature and the biblical foundations of parent-child love (στοργή)
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838818778.0" user="Gloriouscdmaster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'd legitimately question the faith of a Christian who thanked God for the murder of their child.

Never heard of Abraham I guess. Or Jesus Christ maybe? Or maybe a christian coptic attending mass after half of his family was blown up the week before?

&amp;gt;From a naturalistic perspective, this is inaccurate

Animals hunt for food, the rest of the time, they are peaceful.

&amp;gt;As Christians, we trust God for our preservation 

Well, I guess your God was busy when the Yazidis, the Egyptian Coptic, or the Armenians were slaughtered like sheep. He's still busy when Christians are burned alive, shot, or stoned in Pakistan.

The duty of tolerance, comes hand in hand with the right to self-defense. But that's not the OP's question.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29839026946.0" user="Buddy_Smiggins" delta="False">
    <text>I appreciate your continued responses, but am honestly not sure how you are getting some perspectives such as:

&amp;gt; Never heard of Abraham I guess. Or Jesus Christ maybe? Or maybe a christian coptic attending mass after half of his family was blown up the week before?

Your implied ad hominem won't help your case either, my friend.

Continuing on, this 

&amp;gt; Animals hunt for food, the rest of the time, they are peaceful.

is a wildly myopic view of nature, on top of a false dichotomy. 

Also not sure how to address your view of God's perceived lack of response to the deaths of Christians across the globe. I'm saddened that this is how you see things, and I want to help push you in the direction of a healthier, biblically sound perspective. Perhaps a reading of Hebrews 11 would clarify some things.

Hope that is helpful! Have a nice day!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29839111533.0" user="Gloriouscdmaster" delta="False">
    <text>So in the face of imminent death, your answer is to jump &amp;amp; pray? But when you die, who's left to pray for your god? Can your god exist if all Christians are killed?

As per myself, I believe in Jews 1948. That's how stuff gets done.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
