<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444420059.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7clgpn/cmv_one_day_we_will_view_people_who_eat_meat_as/">
    <title>CMV: one day we will view people who eat meat as disgusting and immoral.</title>
    <original_poster>oaknugginz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Once, humans had very little regard for any living thing outside of their tribe. We were small nomadic groups who thought little of killing other humans simply to eliminate the risk that they might hypothetically pose to us.

Forming cities and later nation-states, our circle of empathy grew wider. Our tribe was able to grow larger thus our feelings of empathy grew to encompass anyone who was in the enlarged, new model of our old tribe. 

As we progressed and gained more knowledge and wisdom our morals changed with us. We gained empathy over time and our ideas about what was okay and what wasnt have changed rapidly. Not so long ago, it was considered okay to enslave, rape and otherwise brutalise another human, as long as they were outside of your tribes circle of empathy.

The basic things that made us understand that these other people were infact people were simple: they are capable of pain and suffering, and they dont deserve it any more than we do. They deserve freedom from persecution. A very recent example is gay and trans people, who we are currently bringing into the circle.

I believe that our circle of empathy will continue to grow and I believe that it is inevitable that animals will gain entrance to our circle of empathy. And that in many ways they already are. They are capable of suffering and they dont deserve it any more than slaves did 500 years ago.

If you ask people on the street whether or not an animal deserves to suffer, most will say no. But we still cause the suffering and premature deaths of tens of billions of animals every year in factory farms. 

I believe that in the near future, we will be viewed as savage beasts with no regard for what is right or wrong in account of this hypocrisy and implicit acceptance of evil acts.

**edit: im not talking about people who require meat to survive, im talking about you and me.**

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29855106153.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text> Heck, one day people who eat PLANTS will probably be seen as disgusting and immoral. 

Plants are alive and like you said will probably be included in the widening circle of empathy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855137241.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>Plants dont experience suffering</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855142610.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Clearly plants can react to stimuli and work around sources of discomfort.

How do you define "suffering"?

Why do you think the circle of empathy will stop at your definition?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855502506.0" user="FIREmebaby" delta="False">
    <text>There are degrees of moral considerability. Extending our circle of empathy to animals does not imply that we treat animals and humans as equals, only that we treat like suffering equally.

Similarly, plants do deserve some degree of moral consideration. That does not imply that we should not eat them to alleviate our own suffering. It does mean that stifling the growth of a plant for no reason other than enjoyment is to some degree morally reprehensible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855515671.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It does mean that stifling the growth of a plant for no reason other than enjoyment is to some degree morally reprehensible.

Exactly.

At some point we will come up with nourishment that does not depend on taking any live (including plant life) - that's when we will start seeing eating plants as disgusting and immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855529474.0" user="FIREmebaby" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you, but I do not consider eating plants morally wrong. Since it is required and plants are given a lower level of moral consideration than say pigs.

If someday in the far future there is an easy way to gain all nourishment without plants while maintaining the same degree of autonomy you can achieve through farming (for some people), then I agree it would be morally wrong to eat plants. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855697461.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>no. plants cannot experience pain. your mobilephone can react to stimuli aswell. this is not up to debate. were not gonna play stupid like we wouldnt know anything about suffering. we know that suffering happens in the brain, and we know that plants dont have brains or anything similar to that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855751359.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>This is not nearly as simply as you are making it out to be.

Read, e.g.: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2634130/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855777443.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>i did not read not read it, but it seems to be about intelligence which is a different matter than sentience. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855840463.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Right, I think it will be seen as disgusting and immoral to eat  life forms with intelligence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858480563.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>why would they do that? what are they gonna eat then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858497722.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Synthesized food only.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860857058.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>Why? Why would an act which didnt cause any suffering be seen as immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860860230.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>Its weird that when these topics come up people start to pretend not to understand things that they clearly do.

Every human inherently understands what suffering is and I dont need to tell you that plants dont feel pain (or anything else) because it requires a brain and nervous system.

Yes they react to threats no that doesnt mean they suffer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860866102.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;Every human inherently understands what suffering is 

No.  For example, some belive only humans can truly suffer.  Something you disagree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860875220.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>We group experiences into pleasant, neutral and unpleasant. Suffering is an unpleasant experience, something which animals other than humans clearly experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29861437036.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; something which animals other than humans clearly experience.

How do you know that? Have you been inside a mind of a dog? Did a pig tell you how it feels?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855556509.0" user="Klarkson1273" delta="False">
    <text>So if we genetically engineered animals used for meat consumption to not feel pain. Would it the be more moral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855619136.0" user="FIREmebaby" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but we also have to consider that there is a wide range of emotions that an animal can feel besides pain. Pain is only one dimension of suffering. Pigs are aware of their situation, and eliminating pain does not eliminate their suffering.

Lab grown meat is probably the future.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855625607.0" user="Klarkson1273" delta="False">
    <text>So then you could consider plants as suffering as well? There is a wide range of reacting to stimuli which could be considered suffering. If you see a plant withering away you could see it as the plant is suffering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855688019.0" user="FIREmebaby" delta="False">
    <text>I think just as there is a range of consciousness among animals (Humans are more conscious than dogs, and dogs more so than insects) there is also a range of moral considerability.

It may be morally permissible to eat meat under certain circumstances, but that is not the real issue. The issue is whether or not it is morally permissible to eat meat when we have no good reason to.

Since plants seek to thrive and grow, there do deserve some degree of moral consideration, but less so than that of a pig. So it can be morally permissible to eat a plant, if it spares both you from starving and the pig from being murdered.

To some degree it is morally reprehensible to stifle the growth of a plant for no reason whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29857528612.0" user="Shadpw" delta="False">
    <text>This is factually wrong, Under 'stress' i.e limbs being broken. Plants undergo a undenyable form of suffering. When injured plants have been found to strain and attempt to avoid the area or thing that caused the injury and simultaneously releasing an airborne chemical to warn other plants that there is danger near by. This is what the freshly cut grass smell is.

Or at least that's what i've been lead to believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860753964.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>My understanding is that an organism requires nerves to have sensation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860760135.0" user="Shadpw" delta="False">
    <text>from what i understand this is a biochemical response, opposed to neurological. Kinda like how our body turns food into glucose and then our muscles just start eating the glucose to move.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
