<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444420059.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7clgpn/cmv_one_day_we_will_view_people_who_eat_meat_as/">
    <title>CMV: one day we will view people who eat meat as disgusting and immoral.</title>
    <original_poster>oaknugginz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Once, humans had very little regard for any living thing outside of their tribe. We were small nomadic groups who thought little of killing other humans simply to eliminate the risk that they might hypothetically pose to us.

Forming cities and later nation-states, our circle of empathy grew wider. Our tribe was able to grow larger thus our feelings of empathy grew to encompass anyone who was in the enlarged, new model of our old tribe. 

As we progressed and gained more knowledge and wisdom our morals changed with us. We gained empathy over time and our ideas about what was okay and what wasnt have changed rapidly. Not so long ago, it was considered okay to enslave, rape and otherwise brutalise another human, as long as they were outside of your tribes circle of empathy.

The basic things that made us understand that these other people were infact people were simple: they are capable of pain and suffering, and they dont deserve it any more than we do. They deserve freedom from persecution. A very recent example is gay and trans people, who we are currently bringing into the circle.

I believe that our circle of empathy will continue to grow and I believe that it is inevitable that animals will gain entrance to our circle of empathy. And that in many ways they already are. They are capable of suffering and they dont deserve it any more than slaves did 500 years ago.

If you ask people on the street whether or not an animal deserves to suffer, most will say no. But we still cause the suffering and premature deaths of tens of billions of animals every year in factory farms. 

I believe that in the near future, we will be viewed as savage beasts with no regard for what is right or wrong in account of this hypocrisy and implicit acceptance of evil acts.

**edit: im not talking about people who require meat to survive, im talking about you and me.**

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29854961558.0" user="zeppo2k" delta="False">
    <text>Here's an interesting question (hope I don't get in trouble for going on a tangent).    Does it matter if something will be seen as wrong in the future?

Let's say I have absolute proof that five hundred years in the future people think that watching TV is savage and barbaric and everyone has gone back to spending time with their loved ones, playing board games and reading.

Would everyone stop watching TV?   I don't think so.

I mean obviously noone wants to be on the wrong side of history and you like to think you'd be the guy who lived in the south that opposed slavery - but if something is not only accepted but celebrated by the vast majority of people I don't think what our descendants will think of it is that important. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855136782.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that barbaric and brutal acts of the past are morally okay just because people back then thought so? I dont understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855167504.0" user="zeppo2k" delta="False">
    <text>Im saying if something is overwhelmingly seen as moral at the time, then we can't judge people too strongly for doing it because morals changed later.   Or something like that its a complicated issue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860885318.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>You're saying that doing bad things was okay in the past, "because it was okay". And that even if *is* wrong to do something *now*, its okay to do it if other people mistakenly think its okay.

Isnt that a bit retarded?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855367752.0" user="Stokkolm" delta="False">
    <text>Many barbaric acts from the past were seen as such back then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29856110032.0" user="Feroc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Are you saying that barbaric and brutal acts of the past are morally okay just because people back then thought so? I dont understand.

Yes, moral is an always changing social construct and things that were moral 250 years ago (like slavery) can no be seen as immoral by the majority of the population, while things that were immoral (like a lot of sexual related things) are now moral (or at least not immoral).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
