<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444420059.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7clgpn/cmv_one_day_we_will_view_people_who_eat_meat_as/">
    <title>CMV: one day we will view people who eat meat as disgusting and immoral.</title>
    <original_poster>oaknugginz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Once, humans had very little regard for any living thing outside of their tribe. We were small nomadic groups who thought little of killing other humans simply to eliminate the risk that they might hypothetically pose to us.

Forming cities and later nation-states, our circle of empathy grew wider. Our tribe was able to grow larger thus our feelings of empathy grew to encompass anyone who was in the enlarged, new model of our old tribe. 

As we progressed and gained more knowledge and wisdom our morals changed with us. We gained empathy over time and our ideas about what was okay and what wasnt have changed rapidly. Not so long ago, it was considered okay to enslave, rape and otherwise brutalise another human, as long as they were outside of your tribes circle of empathy.

The basic things that made us understand that these other people were infact people were simple: they are capable of pain and suffering, and they dont deserve it any more than we do. They deserve freedom from persecution. A very recent example is gay and trans people, who we are currently bringing into the circle.

I believe that our circle of empathy will continue to grow and I believe that it is inevitable that animals will gain entrance to our circle of empathy. And that in many ways they already are. They are capable of suffering and they dont deserve it any more than slaves did 500 years ago.

If you ask people on the street whether or not an animal deserves to suffer, most will say no. But we still cause the suffering and premature deaths of tens of billions of animals every year in factory farms. 

I believe that in the near future, we will be viewed as savage beasts with no regard for what is right or wrong in account of this hypocrisy and implicit acceptance of evil acts.

**edit: im not talking about people who require meat to survive, im talking about you and me.**

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29855776058.0" user="Iustinianus_I" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes that our circles of empathy will increase, that we have the capacity to include animals within those circles, that there will be viable alternatives to eating meat in the future, and that people will migrate to those alternatives in mass. These are a lot of assumptions and none of them are guaranteed. 
History is not a deterministic march "forward" to future enlightenment. Sometimes things revert back to a previous state, sometimes progress takes us in a direction which people didn't anticipate, and with a *lot* of things people don't end up changing. For example. if there was a global famine, I think people would stop caring about the conditions that livestock are raised in *real* quick and just worry about how to get their next meal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860902976.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This assumes that our circles of empathy will increase, that we have the capacity to include animals within those circles

It very obviously has and does increase and we very obviously have the capacity to empathise with animals already.

&amp;gt;that there will be viable alternatives to eating meat in the future

There have been viable alternatives to eating meat for a very long time

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860967404.0" user="Iustinianus_I" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It very obviously has and does increase

. . . except when it hasn't. Forty years ago, NO ONE would have thought that the Middle East would look like it does today. It was largely secular, modern, and the terrorists really were fringe groups in most countries.

In 1994 we saw a previously peaceful Rwanda descend into genocide. A year later we saw a genocide in Bosnia. Right now we have a genocide in Burma. There are *plenty* of examples that we can point to where people who were previously peaceful retract their circles of empathy and do terrible things to each other. To assume that everyone will just become more and more compassionate, and that compassion will extend to animals to the point where we won't eat them, is not my *any means* a given.

&amp;gt;There have been viable alternatives to eating meat for a very long time

And yet we eat meat. People aren't going to give up their meat unless it can be substituted with something equally delicious and comparable in price--maybe lab-grown meat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29861002389.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>We used to have no empathy for any living thing, human or otherwise, that was outside of our tribe of 10-20 humans.

Then we gained empathy for those that lived in our city. Then we gained empathy for those that lived in our nation. Then we gained empathy for those who shared our culture. Then we gained empathy for those who *didnt* share our culture, for people who didnt look like us, for people who married people who didnt look like is, for gays, and then for trans people etc.

it's a pretty clear and obvious pattern. just because the pattern looks like [this](https://blogs.mathworks.com/images/loren/118/pubQualityGraphics_01.png) and not like [this](http://www.saburchill.com/physics/images_measurements/graphs_09.jpg) means nothing. 

What youre saying is like saying that the financial crash in 2008 means that we havent gained material wealth throughout history.

&amp;gt;People aren't going to give up their meat unless it can be substituted with something equally delicious and comparable in price

Probably. But this doesnt have anything to do with whether or not people care more about the taste of a cheeseburger than they do about mistreatment of animals. We already know the answer to that one.

The point is that once they are in the circle of empathy future generations will see us as barbaric and immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29861033728.0" user="Iustinianus_I" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then we gained empathy for those that lived in our city. Then we gained empathy for those that lived in our nation. Then we gained empathy for those who shared our culture. Then we gained empathy for those who didnt share our culture, for people who didnt look like us, for people who married people who didnt look like is, for gays, and then for trans people etc.

 . . . except in the instances where it hasn't happened. We've had a long period of relative peace and lack of want. If that went away, maybe due to climate change or some other large-scale crisis, I wouldn't expect this abnormal period of human tolerance to last. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
