<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444420059.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7clgpn/cmv_one_day_we_will_view_people_who_eat_meat_as/">
    <title>CMV: one day we will view people who eat meat as disgusting and immoral.</title>
    <original_poster>oaknugginz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Once, humans had very little regard for any living thing outside of their tribe. We were small nomadic groups who thought little of killing other humans simply to eliminate the risk that they might hypothetically pose to us.

Forming cities and later nation-states, our circle of empathy grew wider. Our tribe was able to grow larger thus our feelings of empathy grew to encompass anyone who was in the enlarged, new model of our old tribe. 

As we progressed and gained more knowledge and wisdom our morals changed with us. We gained empathy over time and our ideas about what was okay and what wasnt have changed rapidly. Not so long ago, it was considered okay to enslave, rape and otherwise brutalise another human, as long as they were outside of your tribes circle of empathy.

The basic things that made us understand that these other people were infact people were simple: they are capable of pain and suffering, and they dont deserve it any more than we do. They deserve freedom from persecution. A very recent example is gay and trans people, who we are currently bringing into the circle.

I believe that our circle of empathy will continue to grow and I believe that it is inevitable that animals will gain entrance to our circle of empathy. And that in many ways they already are. They are capable of suffering and they dont deserve it any more than slaves did 500 years ago.

If you ask people on the street whether or not an animal deserves to suffer, most will say no. But we still cause the suffering and premature deaths of tens of billions of animals every year in factory farms. 

I believe that in the near future, we will be viewed as savage beasts with no regard for what is right or wrong in account of this hypocrisy and implicit acceptance of evil acts.

**edit: im not talking about people who require meat to survive, im talking about you and me.**

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29854885230.0" user="snook342" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The basic things that made us understand that these other people were infact people were simple: they are capable of pain and suffering, and they dont deserve it any more than we do.

This is an oversimplification. There are way more factors at play than simply being aware that other people suffer too. Do you think the violent people throughout history weren't aware that they were inflicting pain on their victims? 

I think the argument boils down to necessity. Food is a necessity and animals are an important source of food for many people. Should the Inuit communities stop hunting seals? And do you think the only reason they haven't stopped yet is because they don't know seals experience pain?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29854918853.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you think the violent people throughout history weren't aware that they were inflicting pain on their victims?

It's more to do with the second part than the first. The understanding that they dont deserve it and that its immoral.

&amp;gt;Should the Inuit communities stop hunting seals?

I dont think that people who require meat to survive will ever be seen as immoral any more than other animals that hunt to survive will be. 

I referenced factory farms in the OP, I'm just talking about the average person who would be reading this post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
