<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444420059.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7clgpn/cmv_one_day_we_will_view_people_who_eat_meat_as/">
    <title>CMV: one day we will view people who eat meat as disgusting and immoral.</title>
    <original_poster>oaknugginz</original_poster>
    <original_post>Once, humans had very little regard for any living thing outside of their tribe. We were small nomadic groups who thought little of killing other humans simply to eliminate the risk that they might hypothetically pose to us.

Forming cities and later nation-states, our circle of empathy grew wider. Our tribe was able to grow larger thus our feelings of empathy grew to encompass anyone who was in the enlarged, new model of our old tribe. 

As we progressed and gained more knowledge and wisdom our morals changed with us. We gained empathy over time and our ideas about what was okay and what wasnt have changed rapidly. Not so long ago, it was considered okay to enslave, rape and otherwise brutalise another human, as long as they were outside of your tribes circle of empathy.

The basic things that made us understand that these other people were infact people were simple: they are capable of pain and suffering, and they dont deserve it any more than we do. They deserve freedom from persecution. A very recent example is gay and trans people, who we are currently bringing into the circle.

I believe that our circle of empathy will continue to grow and I believe that it is inevitable that animals will gain entrance to our circle of empathy. And that in many ways they already are. They are capable of suffering and they dont deserve it any more than slaves did 500 years ago.

If you ask people on the street whether or not an animal deserves to suffer, most will say no. But we still cause the suffering and premature deaths of tens of billions of animals every year in factory farms. 

I believe that in the near future, we will be viewed as savage beasts with no regard for what is right or wrong in account of this hypocrisy and implicit acceptance of evil acts.

**edit: im not talking about people who require meat to survive, im talking about you and me.**

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29854954583.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>Your "progression" logic doesn't work. For example, people used to live in tribal community with just one fire for everyone, then people started getting their own homes with a fire in each, and nowadays people have access to much larger amounts of power from electricity and fuel they can readily buy. Does this mean everyone will have a private nuclear reactor in the future?

Vegetarianism seems to be trending now, but it's still just a loud minority (under 10% in most places, much less in most), and has actually been like that for decades. It is possible that someday society will shift so far from today's standards that eating meat will be considered immoral, but if you're counting on the "collective conscience" to follow your morals against their gains for it (eating meat tastes good - berating gays does not), you'll have to wait a long time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855131514.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Does this mean everyone will have a private nuclear reactor in the future?

This seems completely unrelated to anything that I said but yes, I do believe that we are approaching an era of decentralisation of all aspects of life and that we will produce our own electricity rather than relying on utility companies.

I doubt that we will require a personal nuclear reactor for that however.

&amp;gt;but if you're counting on the "collective conscience" to follow your morals against their gains for it (eating meat tastes good - berating gays does not)

Berating gays doesnt feel good anymore because we brought them into our circle of empathy. In the past, to a large majority of people, it did feel good to berate gays and not only were gays persecuted by individuals but by the state.

Animals' entrance to our circle of empathy is a natural progression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855153740.0" user="charles_stiles_MD" delta="False">
    <text>The epitome of "we shouldn't berate gays" is "we should treat everyone with respect because everyone is an individual". It's not "animals deserve the same respect as humans". That's a completely different idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29855169265.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>Natural in what way? Berating gays "feels good" in a way that's more reminiscent of vegetarianism than of eating meat. People do it because it makes them feel morally superior, reinforces beliefs in an absolute natural order of things. This kind of behavior is relatively easier to change, because it relies on man-made constructs.

Meat will taste good even if it becomes immoral, that's just the way people are built. It might become an "acquired taste" (though I doubt it), but as long as we don't have lab-grown meat, having animals killed will potentially allow you to eat tastier things. Most people's decision to eat meat has nothing to do with morality - they just like it, find it nutritious, and are used to it.

The progression from accepting homosexuality to vegetarianism is no more "natural" than from vacuum cleaners to personal nuclear reactors. It could be that in the future everyone will accept vegetarianism, but there's no essential reason for that, nor any indication stronger than those for everyone, say, accepting Islam.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860881242.0" user="oaknugginz" delta="False">
    <text>I dont know what youre talking about and you dont seem to understand what im talking about.

We have a circle of empathy. It grows. Animals are likely to gain entrance to that circle at some point. Which part are you trying to disagree with</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29861522554.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm disagreeing with the following statements for the following reasons:

 &amp;gt; We have a circle of empathy.

Various people are empathetic or tolerant (which are not the same) towards various groups for many different reasons. There's no universally accepted "circle of empathy", and while everyone is generally more docile than in the past, racism, sexism, homophobia, xenophobia, and all the other old forms of intolerance are present and prevalent.

 &amp;gt; It grows.

Even if you do define "mainstream" forms of empathy (which not everyone feels, but most people feel like they should act like they do), they're not growing, only changing. Empathy towards people of different genders and races may be more strongly expected today than in the recent past, but empathy towards the poor, or foreigners is decreased.

 &amp;gt; Animals are likely to gain entrance to that circle at some point.

Even if you do believe that empathy towards different people genuinely increases in everyone over time, the leap of extending that to animals is substantially longer than the changes made in the past.

In order to feel empathy towards someone, you have to be able to imagine yourself in their place. The mental leap required to imagine yourself, say, Jewish is pretty easy, because they presumably perceive the world similarly to everyone else (which you obviously can't tell, but they act like they do), so all you have to do is imagine a different social attitude towards you. Similarly with homosexuality - you may find it hard to imagine what it's like to be attracted to some people, but you can compartmentalize and imagine the social aspects of being gay.

You have no idea, on the other hand, what a chicken feels like. You may *perceive* some parts of its behavior, such as reaction to physical harm, as similar to yours, but you can't really imagine yourself in any meaningful aspect of its life, down to the very physiology, so it's much harder to empathize.

Ultimately, what I'm saying is that empathy draws mostly from societal norms (as is very well exemplified in the past - the people doing all these terrible things were mentally the same as us, they just lived in a different society). Currently, the norm, except in the &amp;lt;10% of vegetarians in most Western countries, is that eating animals is acceptable. It may change, and then in may change back - but there's no universal morality towards which we're going that dictates any single direction.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
