<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444945722.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7cwqbe/cmv_eas_current_feature_of_buying_heroes_with/">
    <title>CMV: EA's current feature of buying heroes with credits in Battlefront is not outrageous or even out of the ordinary.</title>
    <original_poster>PeterPorky</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT: I've changed my view partially because I think BF2's situation is indeed unique, though I think the option of a grind that is comparable to many other games makes it not worthy of outrage.

So the situation is that in EA's new Battlefront game, the internet as a whole is outraged that players must play 40 hours to unlock Darth Vader, or to pay money to unlock that character.

I think this outrage is ridiculous, since paying for the ability to play as characters or to have other abilities is standard in other games, and that playing dozens of hours to unlock characters and abilities in other games is also standard, and has been for a long time.

Examples of pay-for-character/pay-for-ability games:

1. CoD (unlock the level 65 weapon day 1 with pre-order)
2. Most MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2 (very comparable loot crate system)
4. Age of Empires 2
5. Newer fighting games with other characters as DLC

Examples of play-for-character/play-for-ability games:

1. CoD (you must level up for a wider selection of weapons, perks, killstreaks, etc)
2. All MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2
4. Super Smash Bros. series
5. Older fighting games
6. Goldeneye

Unlocking characters after long lengths of play has been a part of games since forever. In Super Smash Bros. Melee you'd have to complete 1,000 online matches to unlock Mr. Game and Watch (or spend dozens of hours completing difficult challenges). Mortal Kombat's Crypt system also had players playing for dozens of hours to accumulate credits to spend to unlock characters at the Crypt. Age of Empires and MOBA's have some characters/civilizations on free rotation, but you must pay money or grind countless hours in order to unlock characters/civilizations.

Unlocking characters or weapons by paying money instead of grinding to get them has been part of games since microtransactions have been a thing. The combination of the two has been a thing for just as long.

The outrage against EA is just part of another gaming echochamber source of outrage against another industry standard being blown out of proportion by an ignorance of looking at how things have been. CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29858872609.0" user="Dr_Scientist_" delta="False">
    <text>In your examples of other games that make you pay to unlock characters, several of those are free to play. League costs nothing to play. Team Fortress 2 is free. 

How do you justify a $60 price tag for the least complete version of a game before you even have access to the microtransaction storefront?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858879068.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>To me it's the same way that you justify having characters locked behind crazy grinds. The Mr Game and Watch example is the most notable to me. 1,000 matches is quite a bit and sparked none of the outrage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859960246.0" user="jm0112358" delta="False">
    <text>The issue with Star Wars Battlefront 2 is making gamers pay for what they already bought. There's a big difference between a progression system that is designed to make the game rewarding to play, but incidentally made it worse, and a progression system that basically is designed to be a paywall for something you already bought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858889813.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>Fighting games are $60 and you must pay money to get other characters as DLC. Paying for other characters in MOBA's is often more than $60. It can be in the realm of hundreds of dollars to unlock all characters within the game. Call of Duty has pre-order bonuses which give you high-level weapons on day 1 or speed up the process in which you level up to unlock other weapons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859066368.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>But Vader isn't DLC, he's a main character and is already in the game. This isn't a character the devs built after release and are now selling, its a main character already in the game, who is functionally behind a paywall.

And day 1 DLC that unlocks content is also BS, people just care less because CoD does not have the same level of excitement that BF2 does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859111836.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This isn't a character the devs built after release and are now selling, its a main character already in the game, who is functionally behind a paywall.

Functionally behind a grindwall, like many other characters in many other games. With an added option to get a *chance* of getting him from a loot crate.

EDIT: Or to be perfectly correct, to be able to buy MASS amounts of loot crates to get enough credits to buy a character outright.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859153590.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>If you keep buying loot crates, you'll quickly have enough credits to buy Vader, regardless of your chance of getting him as a loot crate drop. And a 40hr grind for a character that should be immediately unlocked is ridiculous. It would be like Smash Bros making mario take 40hrs to unlock, or Mortal Kombat making Sub-Zero and Scorpion take that long. This isn't a fringe character that only completionists have an interest in unlocking, its one of the key characters in the franchise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859182093.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.eurogamer.net/articles/2017-11-09-the-price-and-state-of-star-wars-battlefront-2-loot-crates-at-launch

&amp;gt;To give an idea of what you get from them, XfactorGaming bought and opened 85 crates. Out of those they picked seven blue-tier/three-point Star Cards (the penultimate tier), 48 green-tier/two-point Star Cards, "countless" grey-tier/one-point Star Cards, as well as 3915 crafting parts and 18,700 credits.

So 85 loot crates is approximately half as much as Darth Vader.

&amp;gt;And a 40hr grind for a character that should be immediately unlocked is ridiculous. 

Why should one of the most wanted characters be immediately available? This seems contradictory to any sense of reward or progression to unlock something genuinely rewarding and valued. If you have the most valued thing at the start, then shouldn't you have things valued less at the start too? Why unlock anything at all if you have everything you want at the start? It just doesn't make any sense with any other progression system. You spend time to unlock better and more wanted things, that's how rewards systems have always worked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859280341.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure you can turn Star Cards into credits, which would affect that.

As for why they should be immediately available, these are the flagship characters of the franchise. You don't lock essential characters behind a 40hr grind. Like I said in my last comment, its like locking Sub-Zero and Scorpion behind 40hr grinds. These are the basic characters people are ordinarily playing.

Your comment about progression is ridiculous. Look at the original Battlefront 2. No heros were locked at all at any time, except by the number of kills you needed to use them during a match, which is still true here. 

Also, there would be significantly less outrage if it wasn't obvious that the main reason these characters are locked behind a 40hr grind is to encourage people to pay for loot boxes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859969667.0" user="jm0112358" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But Vader isn't DLC, he's a main character and is already in the game. This isn't a character the devs built after release and are now selling, its a main character already in the game, who is functionally behind a paywall.

Many people seem to have a hard time distinguishing between a company charging you more money for _additional, newly created_ content added to a game, and a company making you pay for content that you _already_ bought. The former is just fine, while the latter is very anti-consumer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859631569.0" user="iiiiiiiiiiip" delta="False">
    <text>Team Fortress 2 wasn't free when Valve started putting this stuff in. It's very common for games to start out by having a box fee and then to go F2P later on when sales fall off, Valve's the master of micro-transactions and managing this kind of thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
