<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444945722.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7cwqbe/cmv_eas_current_feature_of_buying_heroes_with/">
    <title>CMV: EA's current feature of buying heroes with credits in Battlefront is not outrageous or even out of the ordinary.</title>
    <original_poster>PeterPorky</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT: I've changed my view partially because I think BF2's situation is indeed unique, though I think the option of a grind that is comparable to many other games makes it not worthy of outrage.

So the situation is that in EA's new Battlefront game, the internet as a whole is outraged that players must play 40 hours to unlock Darth Vader, or to pay money to unlock that character.

I think this outrage is ridiculous, since paying for the ability to play as characters or to have other abilities is standard in other games, and that playing dozens of hours to unlock characters and abilities in other games is also standard, and has been for a long time.

Examples of pay-for-character/pay-for-ability games:

1. CoD (unlock the level 65 weapon day 1 with pre-order)
2. Most MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2 (very comparable loot crate system)
4. Age of Empires 2
5. Newer fighting games with other characters as DLC

Examples of play-for-character/play-for-ability games:

1. CoD (you must level up for a wider selection of weapons, perks, killstreaks, etc)
2. All MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2
4. Super Smash Bros. series
5. Older fighting games
6. Goldeneye

Unlocking characters after long lengths of play has been a part of games since forever. In Super Smash Bros. Melee you'd have to complete 1,000 online matches to unlock Mr. Game and Watch (or spend dozens of hours completing difficult challenges). Mortal Kombat's Crypt system also had players playing for dozens of hours to accumulate credits to spend to unlock characters at the Crypt. Age of Empires and MOBA's have some characters/civilizations on free rotation, but you must pay money or grind countless hours in order to unlock characters/civilizations.

Unlocking characters or weapons by paying money instead of grinding to get them has been part of games since microtransactions have been a thing. The combination of the two has been a thing for just as long.

The outrage against EA is just part of another gaming echochamber source of outrage against another industry standard being blown out of proportion by an ignorance of looking at how things have been. CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29858939894.0" user="Holy_City" delta="False">
    <text>The heros aren't unlocked via grinding, at least not like other games. There is no experience or skill that goes into it. It's purely time spent playing the game. 

It's milking a game for more money after people have already spent $60 on it. Nobody likes being nickel and dimed. And players rightly aren't putting up with it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858977779.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The heros aren't unlocked via grinding, at least not like other games.

Yes they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858995822.0" user="Holy_City" delta="False">
    <text>From what I understand it doesn't matter how you play, just that you play. Same points towards the heros no matter what you do in a match. In every other game I've grinded it's been based on how you play, not how much time you put in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859057374.0" user="ShouldersofGiants100" delta="False">
    <text>This has apparently been changed, with EA saying that they are adding bonuses for getting kills and completing objectives. Initial estimates also excluded credits earned from challenges, which seem designed to be a major source of resources in the game. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859065878.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>I believe how you perform in a match gives you more credits, but it's mostly about the time you put in.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
