<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444945722.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7cwqbe/cmv_eas_current_feature_of_buying_heroes_with/">
    <title>CMV: EA's current feature of buying heroes with credits in Battlefront is not outrageous or even out of the ordinary.</title>
    <original_poster>PeterPorky</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT: I've changed my view partially because I think BF2's situation is indeed unique, though I think the option of a grind that is comparable to many other games makes it not worthy of outrage.

So the situation is that in EA's new Battlefront game, the internet as a whole is outraged that players must play 40 hours to unlock Darth Vader, or to pay money to unlock that character.

I think this outrage is ridiculous, since paying for the ability to play as characters or to have other abilities is standard in other games, and that playing dozens of hours to unlock characters and abilities in other games is also standard, and has been for a long time.

Examples of pay-for-character/pay-for-ability games:

1. CoD (unlock the level 65 weapon day 1 with pre-order)
2. Most MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2 (very comparable loot crate system)
4. Age of Empires 2
5. Newer fighting games with other characters as DLC

Examples of play-for-character/play-for-ability games:

1. CoD (you must level up for a wider selection of weapons, perks, killstreaks, etc)
2. All MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2
4. Super Smash Bros. series
5. Older fighting games
6. Goldeneye

Unlocking characters after long lengths of play has been a part of games since forever. In Super Smash Bros. Melee you'd have to complete 1,000 online matches to unlock Mr. Game and Watch (or spend dozens of hours completing difficult challenges). Mortal Kombat's Crypt system also had players playing for dozens of hours to accumulate credits to spend to unlock characters at the Crypt. Age of Empires and MOBA's have some characters/civilizations on free rotation, but you must pay money or grind countless hours in order to unlock characters/civilizations.

Unlocking characters or weapons by paying money instead of grinding to get them has been part of games since microtransactions have been a thing. The combination of the two has been a thing for just as long.

The outrage against EA is just part of another gaming echochamber source of outrage against another industry standard being blown out of proportion by an ignorance of looking at how things have been. CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29859200811.0" user="BigG7615" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me that, throughout this post, you are not clear on the nature of the complaints against EA; the points you are submitting are valid from an economical perspective - beloved characters, in a vacuum, should cost more and have to to be worked for, as their market value is generally higher. In this vacuum, however, none of these characters could have been advertised as part of the full game ( nor should their status be conveniently neglected in all advertising), and no consumer should to pay full price for a game that they were tricked into believing was worth their full game price money. The economical approach that you are taking is completely valid if all sides are playing by the rules, but EA clearly isn’t. They are tricking consumers. Plain and simple. Which bring ls me to my point.

If none of the conditions in the aforementioned vacuum are met,  the question now becomes an ethical one: should EA, or anyone for that matter, be able to sell a game without telling its audience, cleanly and explicitly, what sort of financial contributions might be required/needed/expected/flat out coerced outside of the full game price? In  a free market, capitalist society, the people ought to be able to vote with their dollar. EA, in these underhanded business tactics, has subverted, circumvented, and outright shat on one of the cornerstones of capitalism. As for any other that does this, their devs are just as wrong. If EA is unwilling to sell us the product they actually made, and prefers to mislead, swindle, and lie, their actions are unethical. Economics be damned.

Plus they have madden and 2k. Do they expect anyone to believe they’re struggling to break even?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859237068.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; should EA, or anyone for that matter, be able to sell a game without telling its audience, cleanly and explicitly, what sort of financial contributions might be required/needed/expected/flat out coerced outside of the full game price?

I don't remember Nintendo emphasizing which Super Smash Bros. characters were unlockable and which came with the base game when announcing which characters were on the roster. Snake, Captain Falcon, and Sonic are all unlockable characters that received the same attention as other characters. Newcomers and popular characters received more attention than others, but stock characters that weren't unlockable didn't seem to get any preference in terms of advertisement. And no one seemed to have a problem with not being able to play the beloved character of Sonic as soon as they opened the game. LEGO Star Wars trailers shows gameplay of characters not unlocked until later. CoD shows multiplayer gameplay with killstreaks and other weapons not unlockable until after a grind.

I can understand how players can be upset about characters/weapons/abilities being locked upon starting the game up, but I don't think BF2 should get any extra attention. It's expected to have an unlockable system in an online multiplayer game. People expect that going into the other games I've mentioned and there's no reason not to expect it in BF2.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859385963.0" user="BigG7615" delta="False">
    <text>In the version of brawl that I played, you didn’t have to pay for snake, sonic or anyone. You payed one flat price for all the game’s content. Killstreaks are a grind to unlock, sure, but it isn’t like it was behind any sort of considerable paywall either. Even if killstreaks WERE behind a paywall, CODs mechanics are so ingrained in today’s current gaming generation that such edges would be the only real way for newcomers to level the playing field and make the game playable. Of course, even then, you would have to get good enough to where you could actually use a killstreak perk that was worth shit. LEGO Star Wars, again, has no characters behind a paywall. So we’re back to square one here.

It seems you may have not read the portion of my argument where I stated that unlocks led that required a financial contribution should be distinguished in marketing. It’s no problem, and I apologize for any snarky tones I might take. I’m used to writing editorials so being respectful can be out or my wheelhouse sometimes .

Back to the topic at hand: the issue is with having to pay for unlockables, or being coerced to, without explicitly being told about it, not an issue of not being told when something will have to be unlocked through gameplay. 

Sorry if that wasn’t articulate enough I’m tryna get to work</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859678666.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In the version of brawl that I played, you didn’t have to pay for snake, sonic or anyone. 

You don't have to pay for him either. You have to grind for him for half as lost as you'd grind for Mr. Game &amp;amp; Watch in Melee.

&amp;gt;It seems you may have not read the portion of my argument where I stated that unlocks led that required a financial contribution should be distinguished in marketing.

They don't require it. They can be ground for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29860024923.0" user="BigG7615" delta="False">
    <text>Or they can be bought, rendering the game more fun for people who have more money to spend on it. This makes the idea of a game pointless, and more of a wallet measuring competition, where people who spend more money upgrade more quickly, dusting any player seeking to win purely. Such a set up is fine, but to provide such an environment without telling your consumers that they are getting that is unethical.

Work should not be required to make a game fun. It should just BE fun.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
