<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444945722.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7cwqbe/cmv_eas_current_feature_of_buying_heroes_with/">
    <title>CMV: EA's current feature of buying heroes with credits in Battlefront is not outrageous or even out of the ordinary.</title>
    <original_poster>PeterPorky</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT: I've changed my view partially because I think BF2's situation is indeed unique, though I think the option of a grind that is comparable to many other games makes it not worthy of outrage.

So the situation is that in EA's new Battlefront game, the internet as a whole is outraged that players must play 40 hours to unlock Darth Vader, or to pay money to unlock that character.

I think this outrage is ridiculous, since paying for the ability to play as characters or to have other abilities is standard in other games, and that playing dozens of hours to unlock characters and abilities in other games is also standard, and has been for a long time.

Examples of pay-for-character/pay-for-ability games:

1. CoD (unlock the level 65 weapon day 1 with pre-order)
2. Most MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2 (very comparable loot crate system)
4. Age of Empires 2
5. Newer fighting games with other characters as DLC

Examples of play-for-character/play-for-ability games:

1. CoD (you must level up for a wider selection of weapons, perks, killstreaks, etc)
2. All MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2
4. Super Smash Bros. series
5. Older fighting games
6. Goldeneye

Unlocking characters after long lengths of play has been a part of games since forever. In Super Smash Bros. Melee you'd have to complete 1,000 online matches to unlock Mr. Game and Watch (or spend dozens of hours completing difficult challenges). Mortal Kombat's Crypt system also had players playing for dozens of hours to accumulate credits to spend to unlock characters at the Crypt. Age of Empires and MOBA's have some characters/civilizations on free rotation, but you must pay money or grind countless hours in order to unlock characters/civilizations.

Unlocking characters or weapons by paying money instead of grinding to get them has been part of games since microtransactions have been a thing. The combination of the two has been a thing for just as long.

The outrage against EA is just part of another gaming echochamber source of outrage against another industry standard being blown out of proportion by an ignorance of looking at how things have been. CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29858903121.0" user="Sayakai" delta="False">
    <text>You're mixing a lot of different kinds of games, which ignores why Vader is the perfect storm of issues that are individually all over the place, but easier to ignore.

- Battlefront II is a full-price game. People are way more tolerant of pay-or-grind models in "freemium" games, as they understand the devs/publishers have to make money somehow. EA already made money.

- Vader is a core character of Star Wars. Remember how pissed people were about the french being DLC in BF1? It's like this. Withholding characters (or other content) is easier to tolerate if it's "fringe" content, not core content.

- The long unlock time isn't balanced by unlocking other characters in the meantime. Usually, where lots of grinding is required for a special character, you're at least unlocking the rest of them easier. 

- The work people have to put in isn't valued via bragging rights, you can't brag about having put in the effort when no one can confirm you didn't just pay up.

- Pay-only means extra content for money, which is a frequent source of complaint in day1 DLC, as it looks like withheld content that should've been included with the regular purchase. Grind-only means most people miss out, but that's usually not a point of contention. Pay-or-grind combines the two in the worst way, where people feel something that would've been much easier to attain normally was put deliberately out of reach (pricing dictating game design) in order to maximise profits (paying twice where you should've paid only once).

Any one of those issues gets some people agitated, but most people just shrug. All of those combined, in a very high profile game, means people get pissed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858945456.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Battlefront II is a full-price game. People are way more tolerant of pay-or-grind models in "freemium" games, as they understand the devs/publishers have to make money somehow. EA already made money.
&amp;gt; 

I named many other full-priced games in my list. Fighting games are full-priced games that have other characters unlocked through grinding or paying.

&amp;gt;Vader is a core character of Star Wars. 

Shouldn't matter. Beloved characters would cost more.

&amp;gt;The long unlock time isn't balanced by unlocking other characters in the meantime. Usually, where lots of grinding is required for a special character, you're at least unlocking the rest of them easier.

There are other characters unlockable for cheaper prices.

&amp;gt;The work people have to put in isn't valued via bragging rights, you can't brag about having put in the effort when no one can confirm you didn't just pay up.

This is a valid point, but I think this situation is also the case with pre-order bonuses and MOBA heroes.

&amp;gt;Pay-only means extra content for money, which is a frequent source of complaint in day1 DLC, as it looks like withheld content that should've been included with the regular purchase. Grind-only means most people miss out, but that's usually not a point of contention. Pay-or-grind combines the two in the worst way, where people feel something that would've been much easier to attain normally was put deliberately out of reach (pricing dictating game design) in order to maximise profits (paying twice where you should've paid only once).

Pay-or-grind is a valid option in many of the games I mentioned. The only difference is the $60 original price tag. If you end up buying all of the heroes in MOBA's the price tag comes out to significantly more than the player would end up paying for Battlefront, and the player would need to grind significantly more.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859012516.0" user="Sayakai" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Shouldn't matter. Beloved characters would cost more.

Beloved characters shouldn't cost anything at all. They're the main draw of the game.

But I think you missed the core point. Yes, each of those points happened before. The problem is that *all* of them are now combined in one high-profile game - and, admittedly, it's released by a publisher that has zero goodwill left, due to a strong track record of screwing people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859058008.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Beloved characters shouldn't cost anything at all. They're the main draw of the game.
&amp;gt; 

The more liked characters costing more than other characters is a standard part of unlockable characters in game. It doesn't matter if they're the main draw. This is how it always is with other unlockable characters. For it to not be the case, less-liked characters would cost less, which wouldn't make any sense. OR you'd have to have no unlockable characters/abilities at all, which is the point of progression and unlock systems in online games.

&amp;gt;The problem is that all of them are now combined in one high-profile game - and, admittedly, it's released by a publisher that has zero goodwill left, due to a strong track record of screwing people.

Most of the other games I've mentioned are high profile games.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859073191.0" user="Sayakai" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Most of the other games I've mentioned are high profile games.

So what other high-profile game combines all of those?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859091784.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>Fighting games such as Mortal Kombat or Injustice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859117541.0" user="Sayakai" delta="False">
    <text>... will never be nearly as high-profile again. Battlefront (the previous one) sold twice as much as the best-selling fighting game of the last 10 years. Fighting games are a genre in decline, and don't cause a fuss outside of their sphere of interest anymore.

Meanwhile, Star Wars is one of the biggest IPs ever, and shooters are mainstream.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859166464.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>They're still AAA titles. Yeah Battlefront II is huge, but that doesn't mean that comparing any game that sells less than it is comparing apples to oranges.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859118942.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>Mortal Kombat only does that with secondary content. You won't see characters as central to the game's narrative as Luke and Vader are to Star Wars placed behind a pay or grind system. If a Mortal Kombat game did that with Sub-Zero and Scorpion you'd expect similar disappointment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859163651.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You won't see characters as central to the game's narrative as Luke and Vader are to Star Wars placed behind a pay or grind system. 

I see these systems in Super Smash Bros., LEGO Star Wars, and Mortal Kombat. Shang Tsung and Shao Khan are integral to the plot and unlockable characters. Luigi is a character you fight in the main story mode, but not playable until later. LEGO Star Wars only allows you to play a handful of characters in the beginning, and you unlock them as you play through the story. Even after unlocking some, you sometimes only unlock the ability to *buy them* from the store with credits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859970927.0" user="CaspAr_The_Ghost" delta="False">
    <text>Luigi is not as integral to smash bros as vader</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859085208.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstand the distinction here. It's not a matter of more vs. less popular characters. It's a matter of core vs. peripheral content. For example, a Mario game where Waluigi costs extra is different in principle from a Mario game where Mario costs extra.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859207723.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>Darth Vader wasn't actively involved in many of the ground battles in the game. He's a peripheral character to most of it.

It's more comparable to a fighting game that has previous boss characters unlocked in later versions of the game, like Mortal Kombat.

&amp;gt;For example, a Mario game where Waluigi costs extra is different in principle from a Mario game where Mario costs extra.

In the main story of Super Smash Bros. you fight Mario and Luigi at the same time, and they both play an equal roll in the story. To unlock Luigi you must grind to unlock Luigi while Mario is already available.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859051409.0" user="Doodoointhepeepants" delta="False">
    <text>The one thing I would say about battlefront 2 is that it isn’t actually a full priced game.  It’s a triple A game from a tech and development POV as well as having along with it, one of the largest licensing fees ever.  Because of this agreement between EA and Disney, any game in this franchise has a pretty large additional cost associated with it.  With this cost comes a need to either reduce content (make a worse game, like we see with almost every movie franchise game ever made), or increase the price.  It’s why all the LEGO games are $60 even though they are just reskins....for years.  For Battlefront EA chose increase the price, they did this with expensive DLC for the first title, and everyone got pissed off.  This time they did it with pay for loot, to allow people the choice to grind in hopes the player base would last longer and they could recoup over time.  People hate that too.  

The reality is, when you add the type of licensing cost that EA is paying, if they want to make a profit, they can’t charge $60 to every gamer if the game is going to run and look like a $60 game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859076178.0" user="Sayakai" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  For Battlefront EA chose increase the price, they did this with expensive DLC for the first title, and everyone got pissed off. This time they did it with pay for loot, to allow people the choice to grind in hopes the player base would last longer and they could recoup over time. People hate that too. 

They could try to... increase the price. Like, if you can't make a profit at $60, charge more than that upfront. Sounds ridicolous, I know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859130301.0" user="Doodoointhepeepants" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, however, in doing test markets on that it likely showed it would reduce initial sales too much (which is why they used DLC last time). If they charge $90 for every BF2 copy it would likely stop every parent who has a list of games to get their kid to buy BF2 vs any $60 game for Christmas (make no mistake, that is a very significant portion of the sales for this game).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859188522.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They could try to... increase the price. Like, if you can't make a profit at $60, charge more than that upfront. Sounds ridicolous, I know.

The change from $50 games as a standard to $60 for games as a standard was met with similar amounts of outrage despite it being less than inflation with the first $50 games that came out. Increasing the price to something like $70 would also be met with outrage.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
