<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29907889077.0" user="SkyLazarus" delta="False">
    <text>One female's perspective:

Men are still "supposed" to make the first move - it's probably just in the male nature to do so anyway. But no matter who makest he first move, that first move is often made without 100% knowledge that it will be well-received. With young people especially, the move that confirms a romantic attraction is often just one of the people going in for a kiss. They may even be 99% sure the other person is receptive, but it's hard to know for sure unless one makes the attempt. 

To maintain healthy attitudes to romance in this society, I think we need to accept/promote three ideas:

1. romance simply isn't the kind of interaction where everyone brings their lawyer and says "you sign here on these forms indicating explicitly what I'm allowed to do, say, or touch," and is often "risky" insofar as the "aggressor" acts without certainty as to how it will be received 

2. The, shall we say, "target" has the right to give a firm "no"

3. if your advance is not received well / your feelings aren't returned, you are not some kind of worthless failure.

When I read OP's thought that creepiness can be unintentional, I think of mean girls I knew in school who would giggle and berate the awkward boy for even daring to think he had a chance with them. You know stupid nonsense like, "he asked you out??? What a creep!" The original question implies that men can be considered creepy and therefore repugnant based on whatever standards the  woman chooses, and that's not fair.

A failed advance does not by itself make anyone a creep. If creepiness is to mean anything, it really has to entail a refusal to take "no" for an answer, for a start. Otherwise, I can see the sexes distrusting each other to the point where we all start wanting to act like Mike Pence and never deal with each other -- that's not a healthy society either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907908060.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>Ok you’re not wrong, but I was more talking about specific approaches that are generally considered creepy by most people. I defined a few creepy behaviors in another comment, and I don’t really see how anyone can look at those and think “yeah, let’s go with that first”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29908005365.0" user="SkyLazarus" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it's just the idea of unintentional creepiness being considered morally repugnant that I disagree with.

As an example, there are these two guys who hang out at the gas station nearest to where I live, and they will say, without variation, "hey, wassup?" to EVERY SINGLE WOMAN who goes in, and if you don't engage with them they will act all wounded like you are a total bitch, and then when you leave the store it'll be "hey, wassup?" again. Like, that's creepy as hell and I have to think those guys MUST know that most women find them creepy. They probably figure it's worth it for whatever reason. I would call those two guys repugnant.

But as far as someone who uses a poorly-chosen "strategy" (for lack of a better word) for what is otherwise an advance made "in good faith" (for lack, again...), then I have to assume there's just a lesson to be learned along the learning curve toward emotional maturity. The firm "no" from the recipient and a bit of self-reflection should help the person's maturation, and there's nothing repugnant about that.  I think repugnance has to come with intent, like the guys at that gas station who try to flirt with everyone and seem to strive to make them uncomfortable. That's just my opinion, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29909521907.0" user="cromulently_so" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Men are still "supposed" to make the first move - it's probably just in the male nature to do so anyway.

I am pretty sure I live in a culture (Netherlands) where females are "supposed" to make the first move more often than males and I'm pretty sure this evolved pretty much due to a mentality that OP had. Males didn't want to come of as creepy so they didn't make moves which only strengthens is because it's rare.

I realize that it's perfectly normal in some cultures for someone to approach a stranger romantically it's in fact _illegal_ where I live and can get you a fine and this law is nominally gender neutral but obviously more so intended to enforced when a male person approaches a female person.

In general when two opposite sex friends grow together romantically the one who first crosses the bridge will be the female one here. I read on the internet that it's similar in Sweden and Denmark too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29910040245.0" user="SkyLazarus" delta="False">
    <text>That's very interesting to hear! As to the thing about when two friends grow romantically attached, I'd say in the US there is less of a "normal" as to whether the man or woman makes the move in that case.

In a way I think it would be funny to see American police arrest a guy for approaching a stranger. "I heard you ask for her snapchat name! You're going downtown, buster!"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
