<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29907770204.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>How do you define "creepy"? Where's the line between "awkward" and "creepy" and "predatory"?

You seem to have a very specific kind of behavior in mind, which I think is part of what you could rest your view on if you develop it more. But if you can't come up with an objective standard for what is or isn't okay behavior before it happens, how can you judge it as immoral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907794797.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>Fair, ok so I guess I define creepy as such (not all inclusive):
-following a someone around.
-cornering someone (i.e. not allowing an easy escape).
-frequent mentioning of sex, sexuality, and sexual things with obvious hinting undertones.
-general lack of respect for boundaries
-excessive staring

Predatory behaviors would be more along the lines of actual stalking, groping, separating, giving an excessive amount of drinks, etc.

Awkward behaviors would be like lack of eye contact, shyness, and tripping over one’s words. I think these are fairly harmless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907818049.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>I think that you are missing something pretty big here - context.  Context for some of those actions matters _a lot_ and may be the difference between those actions being creepy or not.

For example, a comment with a sexual undertone may be appropriate if I'm on a date with a woman and I wish to broach the idea of a sexual relationship; the exact same comment would not be appropriate to someone at work (despite the fact that I may have know that individual better or for longer).  The context of the comment is different, which drastically changes the level of appropriateness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29908693306.0" user="uxbnkuribo" delta="False">
    <text>People tend to ignore this. Context is the difference between putting a lover's hand on my groin while we're fooling around, and putting my co-worker's hand on my groin while we're working.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907823558.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>So is it because "creepy" things *come off* as creepy that they're troublesome? Or were they troublesome from the outset? That is, why frame this around the perception of certain behaviors rather than the creeper's responsibility to know how to behave?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29908040796.0" user="TimTackwell" delta="False">
    <text>In your OP, you say,

&amp;gt; To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent.

Now you say,

&amp;gt;Awkward behaviors would be like lack of eye contact, shyness, and tripping over one’s words. I think these are fairly harmless.

*You* think they're fairly harmless?  Your whole argument is that it's the recipient's subjective experience of being hit on that makes something morally repugnant.  What does your categorizations of these behaviors matter?  Maybe a woman was once assaulted by someone who was, at first, just awkward but not threatening, and so maybe now she is made VERY uncomfortable by that sort of behavior, even if other people would just consider it a little awkward.

The idea that men with no/terrible game should take some responsibility for the effect they have is interesting (although note that this attitude is strongly informed by sexist gender roles and double standards...not that there's necessarily anything wrong with that), but I think it's ridiculous to call any unintentional act "morally repugnant."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
