<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29908048104.0" user="DCarrier" delta="False">
    <text>That's like saying it's morally repugnant to cause a hurricane to hit a populated area because of the butterfly effect. Sure it would be better if you didn't do that, but since it's impossible to predict there's no reason to go into that. Unless you give some instructions that can actually be followed, like not hitting on a woman ever or taking some kind of test to see if you can hit on people in a non-creepy manner, it makes no sense to judge people for it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
