<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29907790682.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>I think the intentions of the one flirting are very important when judging the morality of his actions - if he is deliberately trying to make the woman uncomfortable then surely that is far worse than if he is genuinely unaware that he is making her uncomfortable?

Some people just don't understand the subtleties of social interactions and have so little natural empathy that they find it difficult to know how to treat other people, and need a lot of learning experiences with a lot of honest feedback before they learn.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
