<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29908683555.0" user="AllenGinsbrg" delta="False">
    <text>"Morally repugnant" is a *very* strong position. You have not outlined a clear definition of "creepy". I find those dolls that little girls carry around creepy as hell, some find them cute. Whatever floats your boat. But, in a sense, it is subjective. What one woman may find creepy, another may find absolutely flattering and end up falling in love with that man.  

&amp;gt; Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent.

Must a man be held accountable for the actions of every other man that a woman has interacted with in her life? Do you mean to propose that if one man has wronged a woman, then the next man who speaks to her must also bear the consequences of the previous mans actions? Then, must every man, before he makes a (subjective) "creepy" move on a woman ask for her entire history of interactions with men so he knows not to trigger her? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29909295381.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>To your last point, while I would word it differently, yes to a degree. I date a victim of sexual assault, been with her for a year. While I would never harm her and we trust each other, I still have to bear in mind ways that I might unintentionally harm her and I have to bear the consequences of her past partners. It’s not my fault that I have to do that, but it is a cross to bear, though I would add it’s not a particularly burdensome one. Coming up with non creepy flirting techniques isn’t hard. Initiating intimacy organically is not hard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29909342782.0" user="AllenGinsbrg" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I date a victim of sexual assault, been with her for a year. While I would never harm her and we trust each other, I still have to bear in mind ways that I might unintentionally harm her and I have to bear the consequences of her past partners.

But your example is extremely different. If you've been dating someone for a year now I *would* expect for you to accommodate for them. You're aware of their history, (dis)comfort with certain actions, etc. But a man hitting on a woman for the first time can't accommodate for something like discomfort with a certain action because he's never met her nor does he know anything about her past. Once she tells him, yes, that should be expected of him. 

And I don't mean to defend the idea that all men should be allowed to treat women, on first meeting, in a way that makes them feel unsafe or vulnerable, but they should not be expected to be aware of things they don't know about a woman, considering they've never met her before. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
