<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451657817.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gwleh/cmv_even_when_it_is_unintentional_it_is_morally/">
    <title>CMV: Even when it is unintentional, it is morally repugnant for a man to hit on a woman and come off as creepy.</title>
    <original_poster>Red_giant_lion</original_poster>
    <original_post>I realize that it is difficult for some socially inept men to flirt, but this one has stuck with me for a while. As a man, I can’t claim to know what it feels like to be on the recieving end of creepy flirting, but I can do my best to understand the effect it has on my female friends. Many women are victims of sexual assault, and those who aren’t have a perfectly good reason to be afraid of becoming one. To me, intent isn’t really the problem here, as the effect of making someone uncomfortable is still there regardless of intent. In the worst case scenario, one could even trigger panic attacks or horrible flashbacks regardless of whether or not the one doing the flirting had any predatory intent. These things are obviously harmful and can lead to some pretty unfortunate avoidance behaviors for women just looking to have a good time. I realize however, that this makes me seriously judgmental of something a lot of guys can’t change. So reddit, what are your arguments against this? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29907806896.0" user="Whitesocks14" delta="False">
    <text>How else are these dudes supposed to find mates if they aren’t even allowed to talk to women?  If you argue that they won’t, then good job, all the people who follow this belief won’t reproduce, and as most beliefs come from parents, your ideology will die off.  Good job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907836471.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>I never said they weren’t allowed to talk to women; I believe quite the contrary! I think men should listen to their female peers about what they find creepy and tailor their flirting methods in such a way that their flirting is both comfortable and non invasive. So for instance, starting up a conversation and eventually asking to get a coffee or something is probably ok, as the woman is given an out and it’s on her whether or not to continue the flirting further. Asking a woman to get coffee after cornering her and waiting till her friends aren’t around probably isn’t ok, but that’s something guys might not realize they’re doing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907853192.0" user="2cats2hats" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think men should listen to their female peers about what they find creepy

Why? It's a subjective territory. What one woman deems creepy may be fine with another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907888171.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>Right, which is why you listen to more than one woman. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907896388.0" user="2cats2hats" delta="False">
    <text>Great. So half say it's cool and half say it doesn't. See where we (aren't)going here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29907925238.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>This argument assumes that all approaches are equally subjectively judged, which I haven’t found to be the case. Almost nobody wants to be cornered and separated from their friends or followed around like the man is their shadow, but I’ve yet to have anyone tell me that they hate it when someone walks up and talks about something relevant, letting a wider conversation expand from there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29908235894.0" user="phoenixrawr" delta="False">
    <text>Your opening argument wasn't that "separating a woman from her friends and cornering her is wrong" though, it was that "coming off as creepy is wrong." Lots of innocent interactions can come off as creepy for any number of reasons, it's not always just the predatory/stalkerish behavior that comes across as creepy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29908249622.0" user="Red_giant_lion" delta="False">
    <text>I worded my argument poorly and I appologize for that. I guess the “unintentional” part is that well, guys don’t really think about providing escapes or why something is creepy because we’re just not exposed to that kind of threat in our lives. To me, I can totally see someone doing things most people consider stalkerish, but completely not knowing that it is stalkerish. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
