<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="451763485.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7gyuxp/cmvmoral_objection_to_infidelity_is_probably_only/">
    <title>CMV:Moral objection to infidelity is probably only superficial</title>
    <original_poster>amalopectin</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT-Infidelity isn't really an appropriate word to use here, so to avoid confusion I will clarify that it is more a question of the act of polygamy than of going behind someones back necessarily. 

 I'd like to preface this by saying I don't especially condone anything that will upset or destroy a relationship, nor have I experienced infidelity from either end (though I have seen family go through it.) but from a practical point of view, I don't really understand what is 'wrong' about. Firstly, Monogamy and promiscuity are fairly widespread in society. They are supposedly linked to testosterone levels in both men and women, because of this scientists often debate that it is to difficult to classify humans into monogamy or promiscuity. However they also agree that monogamy is a recent occurrence (Within a few thousand years). This suggests that it is driven by the emergence of society and changing views of religion. (Though as we know even the 'devoutly religious' could get away with promiscuity. King Henry eight is an unfortunate example.)

Of course, monogamy has obvious benefits, that is, two parents are better than one for raising a child, and compared to r select animals, humans are very helpless when they are born and take a lot of energy to raise, definitely k select. However I use the word infidelity in the title because I'm not referring to those who would have children then move on to a new sexual partner. More the secret act people take in of sleeping with another partner, hidden because of the moral view against it.

Humans for one, don't actually value children as the prime goal of sex anywhere near as much as they used to, but more importantly I think is that promiscuity in human relationships doesn't seem to constitute moving on or 'breaking up' by any necessary means. There's even examples of families quite honest and accepting of polygamy, or just relationships. These are of course uncommon and I am not promoting them, simply pointing out that they are quite possible.

 So what is the harm done then by sleeping outside of a relationship? Pride is the clearest answer, people feel as though it means they are less loved or aren't providing for their partner. But that's not a particularly good reason to think your partner doesn't love you if this behavior is natural to some and not to others.In fact it's also suggested that promiscuity can be inherited from a parent. So in that case, it's not so much a matter of values and not loving ones partner as a natural urge. It would be better if this was discussed with openness instead of men or women going behind their partners backs. This would erase a lot of the dishonesty paired with it, and with a shift in views might actually save a lot of relationships. So my question is, why do we view infidelity as amoral? Would it not be better to accept it as natural and discuss it properly with a partner? After all if someone still felt uncomfortable even without the weight of pride, society, or religion they would simply know sooner than if their partner had lied.


(I hope this isn't to sensitive for anyone and clarify that it's only a theoretical discussion.)
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29909881928.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Infidelity is immoral because lying is immoral. Moral objections to lying are not superficial, therefore moral objections to infidelity are not superficial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29909908551.0" user="amalopectin" delta="False">
    <text>Okay I suppose I meant more the idea of polygamy and the need to lie but yes the act of lying is an important factor in this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29909958252.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Do you mean polygamy or polyamory? The latter is by definition ethical (if sex for pleasure is considered ethical). The former is not in theory immoral, but in practice it often is.

IMO, there are no sexual ethics, there are just ethics and we apply our ethical principles to both sexual and non-sexual situations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29911126384.0" user="amalopectin" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I do, I s'pose I hadn't considered my words properly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29909981392.0" user="Salanmander" delta="False">
    <text>If you ask people "do you think infidelity is wrong?" and "do you think polyamory is wrong?", a *whole* lot of people will answer "yes" to the first and "no" to the second. Most people who answer "yes" to the second will do so for religious reasons, I suspect, which is not an angle you're taking in your reasoning. Are you sure you're not arguing against a straw man?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29911124821.0" user="amalopectin" delta="False">
    <text>I do think I have poorly worded the title if that's what you mean.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
