<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="454805894.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7is2h2/cmv_superhero_movies_would_be_better_as_animated/">
    <title>CMV: Superhero movies would be better as animated films, and the only reason animated superhero movies aren't made more often is the Western belief that animation is for kids</title>
    <original_poster>wiibiiz</original_poster>
    <original_post>[The new Spider-man trailer](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ii3n7hYQOl4) just dropped, and it looks amazing. Watching this trailer got me thinking, and I now believe that live action superhero movies as a genre have a lot of problems that could be resolved by simply going down a route that includes animation. I'll list a couple of them:

1) **Art direction.** Great comics feature great art. Often how a comic is drawn says just as much about a story's theme as the actual narrative itself, and can contribute a great deal to a tone or sense of style. As a result, comics as a medium rely on their art just as much as their text to convey story, and many of the best aspects of superhero stories get lost in translation onto the big screen. Marvel produces comics that feel unique and distinct from one another, but their movies feel remarkably generic and often fail to set themselves apart. On top of that, **no** studio has successfully captured the bright, engaging color palette of comics in their live action films: technical constraints aside (I'll discuss those later), these things simply don't look as cool or engaging in real life as they do when slightly stylized. As a result of all of this, the resulting movies have a weak art direction. I believe a move to animation would help solve this problem, but I'd also point out that the tone problem in comic book movies is caused by a lot more than just their art style. To fully understand the problem, we also have to look at...

2) **The influence of big budgets on Hollywood blockbusters.** As a general rule of thumb, the more money goes into a movie the more your investors will want creative control of the project. The result is that high-budget movies often take very few risks and rarely achieve a unique vision, mostly preferring to stick to a proven formula. (This is why Hollywood is cranking out all the sequels and reboots you see these days: New IPs are seen as a sucker's game). DC makes animated movies with much less reach then their live-action films. They reportedly cost around 3 mil to produce according to industry figures I've talked to. Now, some of these movies are terrible and *none* of them have the quality to be mainstream smash hits, but I'd say that even the middling entries in their animated franchise are better than something like Suicide Squad. At lower price points animation is pricier than live-action, but as you approach the most expensive movies the needle swings in the opposite direction. For instance, Frozen reportedly cost 150 mil to make (including marketing) while Age of Ultron cost 250 mil (not including marketing). By moving to animation, Marvel and DC could emulate Disney proper and Pixar by making varied films while still playing it safe enough to rake in the cash.

3) **technical constraints.** Simply put, the action and aesthetic of superheroes simply fits animation better than live action. In order to "fit" modern special effects into live action movies, everything has to be *just so.* The constraints of these sfx affects everything from lighting to cinematography, and the result undermines the artistic quality of these films. If you need a reason for why Marvel movies are grey and DC movies are dark, look no further. Look at scenes like [this,](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TbpR2Oli3pg) and realize that they were done almost 20 years ago with hugely outdated technology. Yet the movement, color, framing, etc. are all miles ahead of what we can achieve even today with live action. This sort of fluidity would really make the action in superhero movies more lively and entertaining.

4) **Continuity of character.** Let's not beat about the bush here, the shareholders who own the Marvel and DC movie rights love money. Yet actors are mercurial and want to stretch their repertoire: very few A list actors intend on spending their entire careers in the cape world. If superhero movies were animated, this would present no obstacle. Both Marvel and DC are running into this problem, with iconic characters forced out of play because of real-world actor fatigue. In Marvel's case this isn't a huge deal because we've grown to know these characters well enough that a story about their departure works on an emotional level, but how the hell is DC going to explain Batman leaving the big screen when Affleck walks away? Issues like this completely disappear with animation.

5) **Distancing these stories from reality.** This might sound counter-intuitive as a strength, but hear me out. Superhero stories feature larger-than-life figures, doing larger-than-life things. By portraying these events in a photo-realistic medium, these movies ultimately make even the most outlandish heroics feel small and hollow. It's no accident that the best superhero movies like The Dark Knight Rises and Logan work with this effect rather than against it. Both movies deal in real-world themes, and while the *characters* and *plots* may be outlandish the *emotions* and *stakes* hit very close to home. These are movies that benefit from real, grounded performances and refuse to rely on high fantasy, sfx-heavy spectacle to thrill or engage the audience. That's fine, but not every film can be Logan. If you want to make a Thor or Superman movie, I'd argue the best way to deliver on that promise is with animation.

Anyways, these are just the top 5 advantages I thought of off the top of my head. Go ahead and CMV!
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29932997797.0" user="TheBananaKing" delta="False">
    <text>I don't like comics, but I love comic-book movies. 

I don't think comics are for kids, but it's really hard for me not to see them as remedial reading. The dialogue is generally stilted to fit in frame, and exposition (let alone introspection) is either overwrought, breathless and hurried, or involves endless droning on while the drawn action fails to advance. At the same time, the typography in combination with the art style pretty much belongs on the side of a carnival ride. It looks sleazy and cheap and I just can't take it seriously.

To me, *the combination of pictures and text just doesn't work*. 

However, *all* of those problems are solved in film. Film has solved almost all of those problems in its own way, and so translating comic-book stories, lore, characters, etc into the language of film makes them accessible to the large percentage of people who would never read them otherwise. 

And honestly, translating them only halfway into animation wouldn't be nearly as effective IMHO, because: 

* A large amount of the cinematography and film language would be lost in the over-stylized art style, and it's reaching too far back towards the form we're trying to get away from here.
* You lose all the human-ness behind the characters. Look at Robert Downey Jr. as Tony Stark: just those suits he wears and the way he moves in them do absolute wonders for portraying his casual hubris. You could try to animate that, but you'd fail. And unless you're going for uncanny-valley levels of realism (which are just creepy anyway), you're left with Johnny-Bravo levels of stylized characters that can't *act*. 
* The over-9000 problem: Special effects aren't impressive when animated; you just do bigger shitty anime sunbursts. You don't have a realistic environment to act as a baseline, so it's all a lot more arbitrary and the impact is lost. 

&amp;gt; Superhero stories feature larger-than-life figures, doing larger-than-life things. By portraying these events in a photo-realistic medium, these movies ultimately make even the most outlandish heroics feel small and hollow.

I don't agree. It's being grounded that makes them feel worth anything at all. 

Look at the self-deprecating comedy all through *Thor Ragnarok*. I don't think it'd survive being any less small and hollow; that was the point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29933513878.0" user="wiibiiz" delta="False">
    <text>I think I'd challenge your first point: there are lots of comics that absolutely marry the two aspects of the medium perfectly. There's lots of comics out there with bad art and worse writing, and more still with adequate showings in both which still don't add up to a cohesive whole. But when artist and writer find a "groove" and produce emotionally resonant pieces of art which fit together, the result is nothing short of beautiful. I'm an English and history double major-- I read a lot of "serious" fiction during my college years. There are comics out there which I believe are just as worthy of serious consideration as much of the canon I read in my studies.

As for your three points:

1) Cinematography and film language still absolutely exist in animation. In fact, I'd argue that these things are in many ways stronger in an animated film because you can reduce everything in the frame to its most essential elements. Something you'll notice in animated film is that emotions that live-action films usually have to play in static close-up can often be zoomed out or made dynamic because the amount of visual information in the animated wide is more digestible.

More to the point, the Marvel movies have *terrible* cinematography. I mean, cmon, look at clips like [this](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J0oDm4J3YOg) and tell me these movies need live-action because of the great camera work. Someone like [Brad Bird](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiXZMujutI0) does better cinematography than anything I've seen in Marvel.

2) I disagree with this. There are plenty of incredible animators out there who fill their work with human, vital characters. All it takes is an intimate understanding of human behavior and an attention to detail which honors its nuances and quirks. Like I wrote earlier (and like Brad Bird argues), animation is a medium and not a genre. If it comes of as cartoonish or uncanny it's because the tools are used badly. There's not any limitation on animation that stops you from producing great art. I think comparing someone like Lasseter (for all his sins) or Miyazaki to Johnny Bravo just conveys an ignorance about what's possible with animation. 

3) Same argument here, tbh. I could just as easily say "special effects aren't impressive in CGI; you just do bigger robots punching each other." DBZ is a show known for its outlandishly huge stakes and conflicts; there are animated shows that do fight scenes just as well as live action can pull it off. [Here's](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=utLWiscq8d4) a fight scene from my childhood I really enjoy. The dialogue's a little cheesy (which fits the character in context), but the action itself is unimpeachable: to me it looks a lot better than something like [this.](https://youtu.be/V5xN5Fb3Y8s?t=38)

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
