<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29943129733.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

But as we saw from the failed Project Veritas attempt to have a woman lie her way into a story in the Washington Post as another Roy Moore assault accuser, clearly people are doing their due diligence when it comes to reporting these accusations.

&amp;gt;With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end.

To be frank, you should be prudent in your life to avoid such suspicions coming upon you. The burden is on women in so many social situations in so much of life. Will it kill you to maintain decorum with your colleagues and never be in situations such where it becomes a he-said, she-said (or he-said) thing? Most offices record their premises. If yours don't, try to have a more open-door policy. Don't go drinking alone with another colleague. If you maintain basic standards in your work life you don't have to worry about this.

&amp;gt; Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing.

Then don't give extra attention to specific ones of your colleagues. Don't give gifts to your colleagues unless it's a workplace-sponsored gift-giving. These are basic tenets of professionalism, and you acting like these being enforced upon you is an affront to your rights and a threat on you is quite unreasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943502152.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know that the Washington Post is the right standard to believe  corporations hold themselves to.  In all cases the corporation will look out for the corporation first.  In almost every case erring on the side of getting rid of the harasser is prudent, because it will then be incumbent for them to prove wrongful firing.  Otoh if there is an unacted upon complaint they open themselves to getting whacked with a hostile work environment lawsuit, which is essentially proven showing complaints exist.  
 
I don't disagree with you about maintaing standards.  It sucks but as I said in another comment, I just ensure that I'm never in a situation where any impropriety could be perceived.  Sure it means I refuse to interact with female coworkers in the same way as with male ones (ie post work beer dude - ok, post work beer dudette -never without a full group), but the protection from potential problems is well worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943642125.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sure it means I refuse to interact with female coworkers in the same way as with male ones (ie post work beer dude - ok, post work beer dudette -never without a full group), but the protection from potential problems is well worth it.

I'm not advocating this. I'm advocating for gender-neutral treatment of colleagues in such a way that accusations of impropriety are impossible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943673069.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>That's not possible. I've mentored several new engineers over the years.  After a big project a post work beer to chill and talk about what went right or wrong seems like a good thing to do.   I can ask the male ones out for a beer post work.  I cannot do the same for female ones, as it could be perceived as inappropriate especially given the power differential the mentor mentee relationship has.  Or are you saying that we should remove any activity that could ever be perceived as inappropriate for being performed ever?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943696459.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've mentored several new engineers over the years. After a big project a post work beer to chill and talk about what went right or wrong seems like a good thing to do.

Lots of people end up harassing others because they do what "seems" like the right thing to do and don't consider the bigger picture first.

&amp;gt; Or are you saying that we should remove any activity that could ever be perceived as inappropriate for being performed ever? 

Not ever, just currently. Be prudent. Don't take a colleague out **alone** for drinks, no matter the gender. **Go in groups or not at all.** If you need to have a one-on-one meeting, do it with the door open, in a glass-walled room, in the office under security cam, etc. Don't make inappropriate comments, even if they can be seen as jokes. Don't deprecate other employees, even if you think it's meant to be humorous. You're acting like having to change your behavior is a travesty, but it's exactly what we mean when we tell people to act "professionally".

It is absolutely possible. If you can decline to offer a post-work beer to a female employee you can do the same to a male employee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943759357.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm interesting, so your position is I should actively remove growth opportunities from males, because the same can't be offered to females because of potential impropriety?  If this is the case, doesn't that argue as a justification for the exclusion from females from workplaces?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29944743782.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No.

Growth opportunities should not depend on personal, one-on-one, outside-of-work activities. That's just Professionalism 101.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29945263892.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>Mentoring in an informal environment can allow the mentee the opportunity to express themselves and learn in an area of less pressure.  I can't guarantee that they'll gain a ton from it, but sometimes they do.  That activity is acceptable to do with a male and unacceptable with a female.  So there are 3 options.  
 
1.) Try to do the perfectly professional thing with both.  This is unacceptably risky to me.  I can't know before hand that this won't be misinterpreted, ergo I won't do this.
 
2.) Do this with the male, but not the female.  You don't like this because it's unfair to the female.  It's me doing the best I can while avoiding any situation where there could even be the perception of impropriety.
 
3.) Do these with neither.  This is absolutely fair in that it's perfectly equal treatment, but has two problems.  Why should I not do something that is appropriate to do with male colleagues?  Second given that we're removing opportunities for learning from males, without giving any benefit to the females doesn't that make the case that females in a professional environment are a negative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29946711778.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Obviously the answer is 3.

&amp;gt;Why should I not do something that is appropriate to do with male colleagues? 

Because it's not professional. YOU think it's appropriate. Others will not agree. You are already bending your activities to what others think is appropriate by not doing the same activities with women.

&amp;gt; Second given that we're removing opportunities for learning from males, without giving any benefit to the females doesn't that make the case that females in a professional environment are a negative?

No because those opportunities for learning should not exist outside the workplace. If you want employees to express themselves and learn in an area of less pressure, make your office a place of less pressure. Develop spaces and procedures that will help them feel more able to express themselves and less pressured when necessary, don't take them one-on-one to a bar where no one else from work can see you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947049305.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to want to be hung up on the bar.  I don't know anyone who thinks the post work beer is unprofessional besides you, but that was just an example.  I don't think inviting a female colleague to a post work beer is unprofessional, I am just aware that it could be perceived that way even if it likely won't be.  Working lunches are the same thing.   My office is the same thing (assuming I had a door).  I wouldn't close the door with a single female employee as the only other person there.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947627555.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't know anyone who thinks the post work beer is unprofessional besides you

We are literally talking about changing the way people act because the climate is changing towards more scrutiny of personal interactions with employees. I don't care about the bar. Keep work at work and personal life personal. Don't plan to meet up with colleagues outside of work one-on-one, plan to do it in some group. Want to mentor a colleague? Why not mentor multiple at once?

&amp;gt; I don't think inviting a female colleague to a post work beer is unprofessional, I am just aware that it could be perceived that way even if it likely won't be.

Right, that's why you don't do it, because of other's perceptions. Other people can perceive the same situation with a male employee as inappropriate as well. What if they are gay? Be gender-neutral and prudent. I don't care if you take colleagues to the bar, the drive-in movies, McDonalds, Las Vegas, it doesn't matter. But NEVER alone outside of work. Ask a third colleague to join. It's really very simple.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947639630.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>Well not just outside work right?  Never alone with a female colleague ever.  Beyond that it just seems safer to never mentor other employees ever.  But now we're back the question I asked earlier, if we have to give up that much for women to exist in a workplace, is that worth having them there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947666359.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well not just outside work right?

If your work is glass windows, open spaces, cameras, etc. it's fine.

If not, maybe set some up in your office? Webcams are cheap. You can get a good one for $20.

&amp;gt;if we have to give up that much for women to exist in a workplace, is that worth having them there?

You don't have to give up anything except what is basically necessary for professionalism, which means not taking colleagues out one-on-one away from work and work-sanctioned events. Go in groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947687901.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno you seem to want to redefine what professionalism is, while at the same time instituting a police state to ensure safe spaces for women. Doesn't that seem like a pretty big ask?  I should mention that your solution of just get a webcam probably isn't practical.  First, it is illegal to record without explicit permission in many states.  Second, you set up a catch 22.  If you don't ask to record and you're found out that's pretty creepy.  Otoh, asking to record someone could easily be perceived as harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947704480.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's not a police state. Your work already records your screen, what you do on your work computer, what websites you visit, etc. Most workplaces have cameras around.

It's not a big ask. Hey, you don't want to do it, enjoy trying to prove your way out of a "I said, They said" game. The only way to win is not to play. Why can't you just refrain from meeting with employees alone outside of work?

Scrap the webcam, have open-door meetings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29948216486.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>I think we disagree about what a big ask is.  I don't disagree that what you say makes sense in terms of protecting oneself.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29944954194.0" user="primes23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  your position is I should actively remove growth opportunities from males, because the same can't be offered to females because of potential impropriety?

You don't offer these same kind of growth opportunities to women? That's rather unfortunate for the women you're mentoring. 

&amp;gt;If this is the case, doesn't that argue as a justification for the exclusion from females from workplaces?

Maybe instead it could be used as justification for more women in higher up positions who are capable of mentoring people? Instead of excluding females from the workplace? Alternatively, you could change your practices so that women are not disadvantaged in comparison to men, so that they receive just as many good growth opportunities as males? 

Additionally, having established a good, professional relationship with these women you're mentoring, it would probably be fine to talk to them in a setting outside of work like you do with men. Not necessarily a post work beer, maybe a post work coffee? It would be ideal if you could adapt and be a good mentor to people other than those who are just like yourself. After all, it's not just women who you might need to change your style with; there are people (e.g. muslims) who it also might be inappropriate to have a post-work beer with (in the case of muslims, possibly because their religion prohibits them from drinking alcohol).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29945281705.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>No I don't offer any sort of growth opportunity where my actions could hint at impropriety.  
 
I can't provide the same opportunities to women as men without opening myself up to potential sexual harassment issues.  I choose to never put myself in a position where my actions with a female colleague could be interpreted as improper.  
 
I don't disagree that it would probably be fine.  I'm not ok with probably not destroying my career. The venue doesn't really matter post work beer, mid day coffee, or sandwiches at lunch are all activities that cannot be equally given to men and women safely.  I certainly wouldn't invite a Muslim colleague to a post work beer, but sure a post work coffee is fine.  In every case the point is I cannot do any action that involves a 1 on 1 out of work meeting with a female  and know beforehand that I won't have my actions misinterpreted as harassment.  I can think they won't, I can be pretty sure they won't, but that isn't good enough when weighed against my career.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29945359320.0" user="primes23" delta="False">
    <text>I really don't think a 1 on 1 out of work meeting would destroy your career, even if the woman perceived the idea of such a meeting as inappropriate. Supposing that the woman did perceive it as inappropriate, there is no guarantee that she would act on that feeling; she most likely would not. Even if she did act on it and tell someone, you would be able to say that you do the same with male colleagues, and at most all I can see happening is you being advised not to ask people/women you're mentoring to 1 on 1 out of work meetings.

Do you think it would help to have more women who are at your level, so that if women are uncomfortable being mentored by men and experiencing all the potential growth opportunities that come along with a male mentor, OR if men are uncomfortable with mentoring women because of the potential for your actions to hint at impropriety, that women still have some way of getting quality mentoring? If your field was instead female dominated, would you not appreciate having at least some men around who you could relate to and be mentored by? Would it not be disappointing if you only had female superiors, and the way in which your female superiors offered growth opportunities was by doing something like going to get their nails painted with you; something I assume you would not rather not participate in?

It is disappointing to hear what you are saying, as a female studying a male dominated field (mathematics/computer science). I have a male supervisor who I get on very well with. I showed enthusiasm for mathematics and one of my male tutors took note of it, and was very encouraging of me. At the same time, there was one lecturer who made me feel uncomfortable, by kissing me on the cheek and offering to buy me maths textbooks, and staring at me when I attended maths talks. I made no official complaint about this. There was another female 3rd year student who was contacted by one of her lecturers through facebook, who told her she had a pretty smile, and she didn't tell any maths staff. These things, I guess, are not a huge deal, despite making female students uncomfortable, and partially because they aren't a huge deal female students don't bother to do anything about it.

All the other lecturers, aside from the one who kissed me on the cheek, have been great and encouraging. It would be a shame if I was denied growth opportunities because I am female and mathematics is male dominated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29945636312.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>In general I agree that a one on one meeting is unlikely to destroy my career, but unlikely isn't the same as won't.  Ultimately, the issue is even if she just suppresses it, you can end up in the same place.  In  order for it to never be an issue, it would have to be something where the expectation is that if something makes a female uncomfortable, she informally clearly communicates that (unfortunately hinting isn't really practical).  
 
It could help to have more women at my level, but even then they wouldn't have the same focuses and specialities I do so they wouldn't be a clean swap.  I think a lot of people are taking what I've said to mean I just ignore the females I mentor, which isn't the case.  I do the best I can, I just refuse to do things where it could ever be considered inappropriate.  I think the issue isn't that these activities are things that females wouldn't like to participate in, it's that we've created an atmosphere, where I at least am hesitant, because it could be perceived as wrong.  
 
I definitely don't want bad actors in any environment making people uncomfortable on purpose, but I think we've swung the bar to a much too subjective place.  In this super subjective zero tolerance environment I think my outlook is somewhat inevitable.  We need to understand that there are gray areas and misunderstandings and those aren't the same as outright harassment.  
 
In my opinion, I think we look at the whole sex discrimination and equality in STEM problem the wrong way.  We look at the distribution and attribute any deviation from 50% as a result of some sexual issue (either discrimination or people being socialized out of the fields).  This has lead to an overzealous approach to how we deal with things in the workplace.  Instead we should focus on removing barriers and creating clear expectations with an understanding that men and women think and behave differently and there will be friction and the way to deal with it is measured solutions not black and white type solutions.  Ultimately, I think the current environment is doing more harm to people in your position than it is helping them, but clearly that's just my perception.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29946955627.0" user="primes23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We need to understand that there are gray areas and misunderstandings and those aren't the same as outright harassment.

I agree with this, or more generally, I agree with the idea that there is a sliding scale of harassment or inappropriate behaviour, from grey areas to things that are fairly clearly inappropriate but minor, to things that are appalling, unfair and harmful. The idea, for me, that telling someone that the lecturer who kissed me on the cheek had made me feel uncomfortable would end up destroying his career is part of what discouraged me from saying anything about it. When I spoke to friends/family about feeling uncomfortable with his behaviour, I was advised by them **not** to say anything because it would destroy this person's career. I would like for "minor" things like my experiences to be dealt with in more reasonable ways; something between the situation which I fear, which is nothing happening except me pissing off this lecturer who may go on to affect/damage my positive relationships with my **other** lecturers (his colleagues), and the situation my lecturer would fear, which is his reputation being "destroyed" and him losing his career. I personally think having more gender diverse workplaces helps create an environment in which these kind of things are dealt with in a more reasonable way. 

I don't know what the best way to deal with these grey area/minor offenses is. Ideally for first "offenses" which are minor or almost fall into a grey area, the lecturer/employer is just warned/counselled about their behaviour, and if more complaints come in about this person or they escalate their inappropriate behaviour, they then face more severe disciplinary action, i.e. get fired. Ideally, the employee/student would feel comfortable informally letting their lecturer/mentor/employer know that they were made to feel uncomfortable, but this isn't always the case. I certainly would not be comfortable talking to this man who kissed me on the cheek, in fact I was even a tiny bit scared of him, or at least I was sufficiently anxious when near him that my heart pounded and I wanted to get away. He did not seem like the kind of person who would be receptive to hearing that I felt uncomfortable, I believe this would have just pissed him off and he would tell me off, and maybe later he would talk to his colleagues about how I overreact to friendly gestures and they should be careful around me, resulting in the other lecturers being reluctant to be as helpful as they were previously, or let me see them for consultation, etc etc. 

What would be best is if the whole culture/environment of the workplace is reasonable and supportive, so that minor to moderate offenses both (a) don't get blown out of proportion but also (b) don't get completely swept under the rug. Ideally the culture/workplace is sufficiently supportive so that people feel comfortable both formally **and** informally talking about behaviour that they felt was inappropriate, so that everyone who actually has good intentions can come to a mutual understanding, and so that people who actually have bad intentions can be more clearly identified or their behaviour rectified.

In my experience, there is not, in general, an overzealous response to dealing with minor/moderate offenses in workplaces. Instead, the response to offenses is "how much of a stink will this person kick up? can we effectively get them to shut up and not have to do anything ourselves? (if so, let's do that) can we do nothing but pretend to be doing something to placate the person who perceives themselves to have been harassed, or so that they can't really complain? the alleged offender is a star employee/my friend, so i choose to believe these offenses are an exaggeration of what really happened or a one time thing, and so we will effectively do nothing. finally, if the alleged "victim" is kicking up a stink, capable of damaging our reputation, I suppose we should do something about it/fire the alleged offender".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29947036148.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>You seem pretty in line with my view on what actually happens offense wise and I do agree that the way we deal with stuff seems to be either of the doing nothing sort or the go all out variety neither of which seems correct to me.  
 
Honestly I don't think it's a workplace diversity kinda thing.  I think  it's more of a general respect kinda thing, though obviously I could just be personally biased.  The thing in my mind that mucks it all up is the companies are the ones policing.  If they don't have too many harassment worries they'll probably try to sweep anything and everything under the rug.  Once they hit the tipping point suddenly the become zero tolerance places where everything is a permenent mark.  
 
Unfortunately, I think just talking to people should be a first line, but shit like that ends up in your file and is just there.  It's then, even if they don't take you out right away, a ticking just cause for offense firing waiting to happen.  It sucks because we're struggling with something that is complex and nuanced and trying to make it black and white.  I think that's fairly common in the growth of the sex discrimination type laws.  Personally campus sex rules are terrifying to me for much the same reason.  We took something complicated and in order to curb the abuse that is absolutely there we've tuned the filter to error on the side of punishment.  And I see the campus stuff and it just makes me want to be super safe myself.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
