<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29946394030.0" user="ResIpsaBroquitur" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse

I'm an employment defense lawyer; I am the buffer. 

The people who we're seeing get fired are high-profile figures with credible accusations against them -- involving major wrongdoing, usually not just trivial slights. With 'normal' people, we're at least going to investigate the allegations. Here are the most common outcomes:

* Unable to substantiate the allegations. You get reminded of the company's anti-discrimination/harassment policies, and HR keeps an eye on you.

* Able to substantiate the allegations, and you admit wrongdoing/apologize/etc. If the allegations aren't too bad (e.g. you made a couple of off-color jokes) you get a final warning, and you hopefully avoid shitting where you eat in the future.

* Able to substantiate the allegations, and either you insist that your actions were totally fine or you *really* fucked up (e.g. you actually raped someone). Now you're a liability, and you'll get a pink slip.

You're right that there are many allegations about minor stuff, but that cuts both ways. I recently handled a matter where Harasser was accused of harassing Victim by making a comment insinuating that Harasser had sex the previous night. Harasser told me something like "It didn't seem like a big deal to make a single comment in passing about sex", and I replied with "Yeah, which means that it shouldn't be hard to avoid making any more comments about sex". Incidentally, Harasser was female and Victim was male.

It's not a perfect system. Some innocent people might get left out to dry. But the status quo right now really isn't all that bad for men, and most social interactions (including things like asking someone out on a date) are still totally feasible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
