<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29942916850.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like to point out one thing here": you linked an NPR article where an editor was accused of forcibly kissing women who did not consent, but only brought up "unwanted attention" and "unwanted gifts". Did you miss the part where the editor committed actual assault?

Further, those could very easily be terrible things that don't sound bad in plain language! Constantly commenting on somebody's appearance or hovering over them specifically to micromanage could be "unwanted attention." Buying them clothes or sex toys could be "unsolicited gifts!" Those would clearly be sexual harassment.

And even if they weren't overt things like that, it's definitely at least worth noting in a file if somebody constantly behaves in a way that makes an employee uncomfortable enough to report it to HR.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943065057.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Worse, sexual harassment allegations **have included** claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations **that could contribute** to someone's firing.

I didn't say the NPR executive was fired solely for that. I said that those allegations contributed to his termination. I will 100% concede that you are right if this guy actually brought in "sex toys" as unwanted gifts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943089947.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I recognized your hedging language there. My comment was because, as part of your overall argument about men being fired on extremely minor evidence, you *implied* an NPR editor was fired for minor, harmless sounding things by not mentioning that he was also accused of assault. It's accurate, but misleading, and the example only works in the context of your argument if the multiple assault accusations don't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943354639.0" user="Curates" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, he is not accused of forcibly kissing women. He is accused of simply kissing one woman, and attempting to kiss another. When two people kiss for the first time, explicit verbal permission is rarely sought, and to suggest that failure to successfully mindread in this situation is sexual assault is insane and effectively criminalizes male sexuality. Even the article doesn't go so far as to characterize that as assault, instead opting for the murky and kafkaesque "sexual misconduct".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
