<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29943001717.0" user="ibbity" delta="False">
    <text>Any man's life could come crashing down with a single email? Not really, unless the email was undeniable proof that he had been assaulting someone. A mere allegation is not going to destroy someone---witness all the support, and the closeness of the race, for Roy Moore, against whom there are dozens of actual irl witnesses. Sexual assault victims are frequently called liars and their assaulters believed over them, especially if the assaulters is in a position of power like being the boss. Any *woman's* life can come crashing down with a single assault. Any man's, too. Men are sexually assaulted, mostly by other men, at far greater rates than they are accused of perpetrating assault.

 A professional environment in which employers feel the need to go out of their way to avoid even the appearance of sexual inappropriateness is beneficial for both sexes, and the dangers are far less than the fearmongers would have us believe. Only about 1/3 of full blown rapes are ever reported, according to the FBI. Only about 1/10 go to trial. Sexual assault is a *huge* problem. Taking steps to try and make it less appealing to those who might otherwise go for it is a step forward for potential victims of both sexes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
