<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29944783748.0" user="Babybaluga1" delta="False">
    <text>I just don’t see it. But I know that other men do. When I was in then Army a lot of my male soldiers complained about this. I asked them if they needed to be inappropriate in the work place in order to relate to their fellow coworkers. Your wife is right. Men act like they’re stepping on eggshells. Its very easy to get through the work day without saying something inappropriate. Everyone has their own methods: I stop and think would this make my wife uncomfortable if her coworker talked to her like this (substitute mother if you don’t have a wife or gf).

I think the greater problem is that a lot of men grew up unchecked by their parents and thinks what they say is ok. Just because a lot of men are fucked up does not mean there’s a witch hunt or that women are being too sensitive. 

I don’t know that I’m disagreeing with you even. Maybe a middle ground would to say let’s not even let it get to the witch hunt. Tell drunk d bag at your holiday office party to cool his jets when he gets handsy or says something sexist and don’t let him use “I’m drunk” as an excuse - confront him the next day. Honestly it seems like alcohol in a professional setting is where things get bad. But I’m so GD sick of people using their poor behavior under the influence as an excuse

Sorry rant over lol </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
