<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29942912030.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that any male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job.

I mean... isn't this exactly the problem and the point?  We need to change the culture such that 'any male employer' doesn't consider harassment behaviors to be fairly commonplace and mundane.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943038577.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>This makes a lot of sense and obviously something I agree with. 

But I think the hesitation is over where we draw that line. Where does normal workplace camaraderie end and where does sexual harassment begin? That's a question that all of us disagree on and one that will never yield consistent results. Can a male employee ask a female employee out on a date, or is this behavior crossing the line into sexual harassment? As a society, we'd probably say, "as long as it's in good taste, of course that's alright - lots of people meet their spouses at work."  

But what about just a step further: can a male comment on a female coworker's outfit, or is this behavior crossing the line into sexual harassment? Here is where we start to see a difference in opinion. Some might say, of course this is wrong - one should never judge a coworker based on appearance. Others might say, this isn't so bad - it's a normal social interaction.  And others might attach contingencies, saying that those comments would be okay as long as they weren't creepy or sexual in nature. 

A claim of sexual harassment is a very serious one, and the fact that it is based on such a loose subjective standard means that we, as a society, don't know where to draw that line. And still, we're willing to publicly shame people for crossing it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943070958.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, obviously the answer is 1. Don't be a creep, and 2. Don't come even CLOSE to anything remotely sexy if you're in a position of power over anyone.  These do not strike me as particularly ambiguous or difficult to follow or stifling.

Are you bothered by the fact that there isn't a set of perfect guidelines that lists, behavior by behavior, what's acceptable and what's not?  Because that simply doesn't and can't exist in any kind of human interaction.  And the solution is also very easy: If you're unsure, simply err on the side of not doing the thing.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943099234.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 1. Don't be a creep, and 2. Don't come even CLOSE to anything remotely sexy if you're in a position of power over anyone. These do not strike me as particularly ambiguous or difficult to follow or stifling.

You're trying to tell me that your guidelines aren't ambiguous? Reddit, and especially this subreddit, are not fair cross-sections of how most of society thinks and operates. I mean, we just had a pedophile running for Senate and he still got nearly 50% of the vote. If you asked 100 people, "what does it mean to be sexually harassed?" You'd get 100 different answers. 

I'm not asking for a set of perfect guidelines, but I am asking why and how our collective consciousness of sexual harassment has changed so dramatically in a matter of months. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943123879.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>They're not ambiguous to me, particularly in the context of the second thing I said: If you're really unsure, then just don't do the thing.  

It's like everything else: you have to consider your relationship with the person.  If a woman coworker is your friend and your relationship has established, platonic boundaries, then of COURSE compliment her scarf or haircut.  If not, then be more hesitant about doing it (and same deal for men coworkers too, by the way).

(Also, let me just say, there are different ways to compliment things like clothes, and I think you must know this?  I have never known anyone to get in trouble for it, because it's very easy to do without being a damn creep.)  

&amp;gt; I'm not asking for a set of perfect guidelines, but I am asking why and how our collective consciousness of sexual harassment has changed so dramatically in a matter of months.

Um, because women have started speaking up about how commonly they are made to feel uncomfortable.  These aren't NEW standards, they're just (it seems) new to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943212507.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They're not ambiguous to me, 

Have you ever actually talked to a person at work?

I've been in corporate environments for the past 30 years.  I have never done anything that was genuinely sexual harassment nor have I ever been genuinely sexually harassed.

However, there are weekly (if not daily) examples of joking around at the office where if the story was relayed to you out of context, you'd likely be appalled and say that it was, without a doubt, sexual harassment.  And that goes for both things I've done or said, as well as things said or done to me.

I think if people are honest, most of them would say the exact same thing.  I know it is true for 99% of the people I've worked with.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943243981.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Um, then let me rephrase:  They're not ambiguous to me because I live in a world where I trust women to not maliciously take innocent things I said out of context in a cruel attempt to get me fired from my job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943260164.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I trust women 

And that's the difference right there.  Everyone has different levels of trust of people based upon their life experiences.  Some people think that no one would every maliciously attack them with out of context statements.  Others think that everyone is always "out to get them".

Personally, I treat it on an individual basis and gender doesn't really come into it.  I joke around with some people that I think I can trust and I tone it down around others that I think are going to be easily offended.

Let's hope that we're both accurate with our assessments of people and that it doesn't come back to bite us in the ass someday.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943265549.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>But your cab driver could turn around and shoot you.  Your dad could stab you on Christmas eve.  Anyone can do anything if they're *crazy*, but presumably you don't avoid all other humans.

That's what I mean.  You don't appear to trust your women coworkers to not be crazy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943286552.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>I don't trust people I don't know.  And I certainly don't trust that their perception of a situation will be the same as my perception of that situation.

So, no, I don't fully trust a cab driver but I would trust my Dad.  And, no, I don't trust someone I've worked with for 3 months but I might trust someone I've worked with for 10 years if they had shown they are trustworthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943302895.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Do you trust these women to not walk into your office and shoot you in the face?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943347711.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>For the most part, yes.

But here's the thing about trust:

When women went up to Harvey Weinstein's hotel room, do you think they trusted him?  It seems that trust was misplaced.

When women were asked to come to Matt Lauer's office, do you think they trusted him?  It seems that trust was misplaced.

When women got on military planes with Al Franken, do you think they trusted him?  It seems that trust was misplaced.

You can trust people all day and be right 99.99% of the time.  But you only need to get it wrong once for the shit to hit the fan.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943409632.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, but why on earth do you trust them not to shoot you in the face, but you don't trust them not to maliciously slander you when you least expect it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943421261.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>Because shooting me in the face is likely to put them in jail.  Maliciously slandering me when I least expect it could put them on the cover of Time magazine.

On top of that, with the exact same qualifier, **for the most part**, I trust them to not maliciously slander me.

Care to address the rest of my post?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943216072.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; because women have started speaking up about how commonly they are made to feel uncomfortable.

Being made to feel uncomfortable is not a fair standard for sexual harassment. Every day people are made uncomfortable by someone from another gender. That doesn't mean they were sexually harassed. It just means the other person is an asshole. If anything, I'd rather hear that someone was fired because he was an absolute prick around the workplace than hear that he was fired for making Susie feel uncomfortable for wearing a certain outfit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943240537.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Being made to feel uncomfortable is not a fair standard for sexual harassment.

You're right, which is why if a woman goes to HR and says "That man asked to borrow my stapler; he sexually harassed me," she'd be laughed out of the room.  And also, *no woman is going to do that.*

You appear to know perfectly well what behaviors are 'dangerous' and what behaviors aren't.  You just don't appear to like the idea of men not feeling comfortable performing these behaviors.  

So, there's a Chilling Effect of men not feeling comfortable complimenting women on their clothes (unless they're friends with the woman, have established trust with the woman, and aren't doing it in a creepy way)?  Um... not to be snide, but this doesn't strike me as a tragedy.

&amp;gt; It just means the other person is an asshole.

Sexual harassers are assholes, so I don't understand this distinction.

Also... are you defending being an asshole?  I think not, because of what you say next, but then I don't understand your point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29950578162.0" user="jabberwockxeno" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They're not ambiguous to me, particularly in the context of the second thing I said: If you're really unsure, then just don't do the thing

They are *entirely* ambigious, and going "If you aren't sure, don't do it" isn't at all a good standard because people aren't going to be sure at the same threshold boundaries.

As somebody with aspergers, I am *constantly* unsure if what I am doing is socially appropriate or not. I think you and most other neurotypical people are quite frankly blind to how arbitrary, inconsistent, and arcane social standards are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29951996788.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Ask.

Problem solved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29952385668.0" user="jabberwockxeno" delta="False">
    <text>Asking somebody if it's okay to do X is going to be just as negatively received as if you just did it, look at the drama with Louis CK

Your entire point is just "lol social interactions work for me that's your problem too bad bruh"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29944924221.0" user="The_Smiley_Doctor" delta="False">
    <text>Being actionably 'creepy' is rarely something someone intentionally does. Creepiness is almost entirely directly related to how comfortable you are with the person already, and how much you are or are not attracted to them. Two strangers - one sexually appealing to you and one not - making the same come-on line can get two very different results.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29945496480.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that's a problem. We need people to better understand the line so they can avoid being creeps, not to make it harder to criticize creeps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29946360065.0" user="The_Smiley_Doctor" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe someone being uglier to your preferences therefore makes them 'creepy' for doing the same or similar thing as someone less ugly to your preferences might be. I think that's on you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943072888.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But I think the hesitation is over where we draw that line. Where does normal workplace camaraderie end and where does sexual harassment begin? That's a question that all of us disagree on and one that will never yield consistent results. Can a male employee ask a female employee out on a date, or is this behavior crossing the line into sexual harassment? As a society, we'd probably say, "as long as it's in good taste, of course that's alright - lots of people meet their spouses at work."

Every company I have ever worked for (and I've worked for a lot) have had detailed sexual harassment policies to answer those exact questions.  Moreover, I have never seen _anyone_ fired over a single action that was clearly in the grey area.  The only people I have ever seen fired were people how committed extremely inappropriate things and/or had has previous warnings about their behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943075475.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>It both is and it isn't.  In my opinion there are certainly behaviors that should be curbed.  At the same time given the current climate there are some chilling effects that can be seen.  For instance grab ass, innuendo, sexual jokes bad.  That seems fair.  Inviting coworkers out post work for a beer.  Seems good.  In the current environment, I am unwilling to invite out a female colleague unless it is showable that it's being done as part of a group thing.  On the other hand I would have no problem inviting out a male, even if it's just the two of us.  Because the current standard is not objective and is instead based on how the female (in general) perceives it, I must ensure that my behavior adheres to a standard that is beyond potential reproach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943083941.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, do you know this woman at all?  Are you friends, with a relationship that has boundaries established to it?

If so: of course ask her to get a beer.  If not: Probably no, make friends with her first.  Same deal with a dude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943095473.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I'm talking about females who work in the same group I do.  Theoretically it's not a problem.  But I don't see the cost benefit working out that way.  There is a large chance there is no problem doing it, but to me it's not worth the risk that my career could be destroyed.  At the end of the day, my perception and intentions don't matter, only hers do.  In that environment the potential misunderstanding is not worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943110512.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Let's think about that.  If only her perceptions matter, then why can't she report you for ANY behavior you do?  If she reported you for asking to borrow her stapler in passing, she'd be laughed out of the room.

So, clearly you are perfectly aware that there are some behaviors that are 'dangerous' (others have pointed out how ludicrously exaggerated the danger actually is) and some behaviors that aren't.  So it's disingenuous to act like the workplace is some big minefield when there's obviously behaviors you could avoid (but don't seem to want to avoid).

But if you know her, if your relationship has established platonic boundaries, and you're friends... uh, why on earth would she report you?  She could be insane?  She could be deceptive and trying to get you fired?  What do you imagine is the answer to this question?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943142725.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>Obviously there are behaviors that are clearly safe.  Then there are ones that are certainly wrong and should be curtailed (and I have no issue with that).  Then there are ones in a gray area.  When anywhere near the gray area it makes more sense (to me) to just avoid the area all together.  In this case I wouldn't say we're friends, but I would say we're colleagues (same with basically all males I work with).  I'm almost certain that there wouldn't be an issue and it would be fine.  The key to me is almost certain isn't good enough when talking about my career.  I don't particularly worry about her being insane or partiuclarly malicious.  If it comes off creepy or wrong and makes her uncomfortable then it does and then I'm at fault and it destroys my career.  It's just not worth the risk.  I mean the post work drinks is only an example.  I could notice a male colleagues new haircut and compliment them on it, but I would never do that with a female.  We talk politics a decent amount at work, but I try to avoid speaking about politics with female and minority colleagues.  And the worst part is I'm 99% certain, my colleagues wouldn't have an issue with any of the behavior I'm talking about, but I'm unwilling to chance it.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943190627.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  If it comes off creepy or wrong and makes her uncomfortable then it does and then I'm at fault and it destroys my career.

I mean, no it doesn't, first of all.  You are not going to fired for awkwardly complimenting one person once on their scarf.

&amp;gt; We talk politics a decent amount at work, but I try to avoid speaking about politics with female and minority colleagues.

See, this really jumps out to me.  Unless you DO consider these people somehow insane or unreasonable, what exactly are you afraid of?  Just don't be an asshole and it'll be fine. (Also, it will probably be fine even if you ARE an asshole.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943221074.0" user="flatsixfan" delta="False">
    <text>No offense, but I think you’re completely oblivious to the underlying problem this thread is discussing </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943226630.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>I don't consider them insane or unreasonable.  It's just given the potential impact, probably will be fine is not good enough for me.  All it takes is one person taking something the wrong way or taking offense and then I've got that mark against me forever.  I mean part of it is I tend to be fairly risk adverse, I'm not going skydiving  because probably will be fine is not acceptable vis-a-vis death.  In the same way, refusing to engage in the social interactions is guaranteed to protect me.  Like don't get me wrong part of me thinks it's a more reasonable behavior to joke around with the women who tell risque jokes than to just avoid ever telling one, because given what they're saying it's highly unlikely they'll be offended, but what do I have to gain, and what could I potentially lose?  I view all of this behavior in a similar way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943250527.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; All it takes is one person taking something the wrong way or taking offense and then I've got that mark against me forever.

OK, what mark?  Where are all these terrible consequences that come from one conversation?

Second, you are at risk of getting run over by a car simply by leaving your home.  That's obviously a terrible potential impact.  But, I presume, you leave your apartment.

The thing isn't just risk, it's TRUST.  That's why I keep talking about this "you think women and other races are unreasonable" thing.  You just gotta trust them, the same way you trust other drivers to not smash into your car.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943284132.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>If I get written up for sexual or racial harassment, which would absolutely be the procedure if it was reported as offensive.  
 
Absolutely I could get hit by a car, but I still leave.  That said I don't ride a motorcycle, because the potential benefit (wheee fun) doesn't outweigh the potential harm (road rash and death).  
 
It isn't about trust.  I trust them to follow procedure, which is to report harassing behavior.  If harassment is in the eye of the harassee, then they could be offended by something that I didn't mean offensively.  That's their right.  Sure they probably would just tell me and that would be the end, but maybe it wouldn't be, and if they truly felt harassed then it wouldn't be wrong for them to go to HR.  
 
ultimately what is the benefit I receive in to outweigh the potential risks?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943311603.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I get written up for sexual or racial harassment, which would absolutely be the procedure if it was reported as offensive.

Again, where's this happening, that people get their careers ruined for one comment?

&amp;gt; It isn't about trust. I trust them to follow procedure, which is to report harassing behavior. If harassment is in the eye of the harassee, then they could be offended by something that I didn't mean offensively.

Why do you think lots of people, like me, don't have this issue?  I am not in the least afraid that anything it'd occur to me to do would be taken as harassment by any of my coworkers.  It's not risk-aversion (I'd never go skydiving either), it's a belief that it's not a danger I run, because I know the boundaries of the people I work with, and that they wouldn't be shockingly unreasonable about the way they're likely to interpret things.

What do you think is the difference between you and me?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943335392.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>You're more trusting or less risk averse than I am.  Or perhaps you see more gain out of those interactions so you're willing to accept the additional risk.  Like if for some reason I particularly valued a work relationship with a female colleague, it could swing my cost benefit analysis.  On the other hand, if the protections were higher then perhaps I wouldn't feel the need to protect myself.  At the end of the day I think most people are reasonable, but I do think misunderstandings happen (relatively infrequently).  Given the potential cost and the relative lack of benefit I choose to avoid any situation where any impropriety could be perceived to occur.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943421224.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>This is what I said, though: it's trust.  You don't trust women to not have wildly alien reactions to your behavior... or you don't trust your own behavior to be appropriate.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943465633.0" user="darkagl1" delta="False">
    <text>Eh you seem to think it's wildly alien reactions.  Like inviting a woman out to grab a post work beer or complimenting her on her scarf I tend to think are pretty harmless, but could certainly be perceived incorrectly.  I think there is behavior that is not meant offensively or harassing that can be perceived as such.  I think in almost every case that can be cleared up with simple communication.  But as long as I bear the consequences, to me it is not worth the risk.  Hell, I know in my relationship I am misunderstood on occasion and  she has the benefit of having known and been with me for years.  All it takes is once for the other person to decide they'd rather deal with it through HR.  Maybe I'm personally colored by my past, but I do know I got in trouble once for saying data was bad (because the test used to collect it couldn't work) and ended up in HR, because it offended the person collecting the data.  There was literally zero gray area there.  I had no reason to mistrust this person.  But I ended up there because they thought it implied that they weren't competent at their job.  If well meaning forthright conversation about technical topics can get you in the shit, I see no reason to even begin to approach anything even beginning to show the slightest hint of gray.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943229215.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; then why can't she report you for ANY behavior you do?

Errrrrr.... she *can*!

&amp;gt; If she reported you for asking to borrow her stapler in passing, she'd be laughed out of the room.

^[Citation ^Needed]

&amp;gt; why on earth would she report you? 

She might not report him today, next week, or next year.  But who knows what's going to happen 20 years from now when he's running for the local school board?  Now all of a sudden he was "this creep who I used to work with and was always hanging around my desk asking for stupid stuff like borrowing my stapler or what I was bringing to the pot luck lunch.  Then he started asking me out".

Perception is reality.  And you never know someone else's perception, and it doesn't always match your own.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943217129.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If not: Probably no, make friends with her first

Ummm.... you're telling guys to try to make friends with women at work?  You don't see how that could easily lead to a sexual harassment claim?  "I'm at work to work.  Talk to me about work.  I'm not here to make friends".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943418340.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>No, I honestly don't see any danger about that, because if someone said that to me, I'd not try to make friends with them anymore and the problem appears solved.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943425758.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>The problem arises is when they think it for 6 months, try to drop hints, but never actually say it until they run to your boss or HR whining about how "creepy" you are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943299431.0" user="Curates" delta="False">
    <text>To be clear, you are suggesting that asking a female coworker out to beers is possibly sexual harassment, just in case they're not friends? And you think there's no problem with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943415986.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>No.  The consequence I see is that people stop asking strange coworkers out for beers, and... this seems tolerable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943447989.0" user="Curates" delta="False">
    <text>Well you are wrong, that in fact isn't sexual harassment, and heaven forbid that should ever change, because that is fucking insane. This perfectly encapsulates what is wrong with the state of this national conversation that OP is getting at.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943091560.0" user="angels_fan" delta="False">
    <text>The problem I see with this is that almost all women I've worked with are just as crude as any guy there.  They give as well as they get... Right up until a guy crosses some imaginary boundary of hers.  Then it's a scandal in HR, and the guy is like, "wait... She's just as dirty as all of us!" Doesn't matter.  You crossed her line.  Enjoy unemployment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943097088.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Has it occurred to you that these women might not actually enjoy "giving as good as they get" but rather use it as a defense reaction to "getting"?

Anyway, if a woman was being a creep to me, I'd obviously report her; why wouldn't you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943143939.0" user="angels_fan" delta="False">
    <text>Because I'm a big boy and can handle a dirty joke... Unlike the fragile, coddled women of western society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943171578.0" user="renoops" delta="False">
    <text>Because it benefits you to live in a world where people aren't held accountable for their actions. Got it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943208739.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943331012.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, angels_fan – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **No low effort comments**. This includes comments that are only jokes, links, or 'written upvotes'. Humor, links, and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information.](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5)

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link.](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+angels_fan&amp;amp;message=angels_fan+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/dr7evqb/\)+because...)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29944851173.0" user="thirtiethst" delta="False">
    <text>To give a non-obnoxious, non transparently sexist answer to your question...

If you don’t enjoy it you are more than welcome to not partake. But once you engage in that behavior, willingly or reluctantly, it’s a choice that *you made.* Whether you like it or not, you can’t dish it out and then pout when it boomerangs you. If you’re uncomfortable then make that known, but don’t bring down a dude for the same shit you were *just* doing if they have no indication you aren’t with it. 

And I *hate* dirty jokes/toilet humor. 

Speaking in the second person out of pure inertia btw, I don’t feel like going back and editing every pronoun to 3rd person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943198362.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; harassment behaviors 

Who gets to define what is, and isn't, "harassment behaviors"?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
