<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29943193924.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>Let's start with a clarifying question:

&amp;gt; I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike

What?  Can you explain this?  You actually, honestly believe that fucking RAPE is considered acceptable on college campuses and corporate workplaces?  What has led you to that conclusion?

With that out of the way, let's move on to challenging your view:

&amp;gt; Sexual harassment against women is a real problem,

Is it?  And if so, *why* is it?  Look at this /r/askmen [thread from a few days ago](https://www.reddit.com/r/AskMen/comments/7i7s4g/men_how_have_you_dealt_with_the_trauma_of/).  If you read it, you'll find that many (if not most) men have experienced the same types of behaviors coming from women that many women receive from men and label "sexual harassment".

Is the problem that men treat women in the workplace differently than how women treat men?  Or is the problem that men get over it while women make a federal case about it?

I don't deny that there are legitimate cases of sexual harassment against both genders.  But there are many things that are now being labeled as sexually inappropriate behavior that are really just normal, awkward, misunderstood human interactions.

Perhaps that why you think rape culture exists in corporate workplaces.  Because if "everything is rape", then, yes, it *is* accepted in society.  But everything isn't rape.  An attempted kiss, asking someone out on a date, brushing your boob against someone, touching someone's arm, staring at someone or commenting that someone looks nice today isn't rape, or sexual assault or sexual harassment or sexually inappropriate.  It is normal human interaction.  If it bothers you, that's a problem with you, not a problem with the person doing it.  Get over it.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943239060.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, I don't even know what you're arguing. I'm asking to how our society should contemplate and handle sexual harassment allegations in the workplace and you're throwing in all kinds of stuff that I'm just not going to sit here and unpack. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943279265.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>There are a lot of views expressed in your original post.  The objective of this subreddit is for you to post your views, and us to challenge and attempt to change those views.  Amongst the views you expressed was:

* **rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces**

I'd like to challenge that view, but I am asking a clarifying question because I really don't understand how you came to that conclusion.  Just by general observation of every place I've ever worked, raping coworkers is definitely not something that is accepted.  So I'm not sure what evidence or anecdotes you've seen that have lead you to have this view.

Also amongst the views you expressed was:

* **Sexual harassment against women is a real problem**

I am challenging you on that view because I don't think it is any more of a "real problem" that sexual harassment against men is a "real problem".  I linked you to a thread where men are saying that they experience the exact same types of behavior from women.

So if men are the targets of certain behaviors from women and, for some reason, it isn't and issue and isn't a problem, then why is it a "real problem" when women are the targets of the exact same behaviors from men?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943482266.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>Listen, I think you actually provided some good insight elsewhere in the thread:

&amp;gt; She might not report him today, next week, or next year. But who knows what's going to happen 20 years from now when he's running for the local school board? Now all of a sudden he was "this creep who I used to work with and was always hanging around my desk asking for stupid stuff like borrowing my stapler or what I was bringing to the pot luck lunch. Then he started asking me out".
&amp;gt; Perception is reality. And you never know someone else's perception, and it doesn't always match your own.

That's a good point and a point I agree with.

But as to everything you wrote out above, I disagree. Male sexual harassment against women will always be a bigger, scarier issue than female sexual harassment against men. I understand that men are also date-raped, groped, and sexually harassed by females all the time, but there's one factor that will always remain: the average male has can physically overpower the average female. As long as that physiological difference remains, male on female sexual harassment will always be a bigger and scarier problem.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943885096.0" user="BlockNotDo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  but there's one factor that will always remain: the average male has can physically overpower the average female.

I've heard this argument before, but I've got to say that I don't really buy it.  In these situations, I don't see how the guy's physical strength is relevant.

Take Matt Lauer.  He asked a woman to come to his office and then asked her to unbutton her blouse.  Is it really realistic to think that if she failed to agree, Matt was going to use his brute strength as a man to force her compliance?

Or Harvey Weinstein.  Did the women really believe that if they refused a naked massage, he would just physcially overpower them and force the massage on them?

I just don't see it.  That concern is about as valid as a man getting kissed without consent by a woman, and going along with it because he fears that she's going to pull out a gun and shoot him if he resists.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
