<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="459330880.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7lh1z4/cmvthe_death_of_the_cdalbum_as_the_primary_means/">
    <title>CMV:The death of the CD/Album as the primary means of listening to music and music ownership is bad</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>Growing up, I saw music delivery move from vinyl to cassette to CD, and now to streaming. My friends and I used to spend hours each month at the record store, browsing through new albums and searching for classics or hidden gems. We'd take them home, put them on and listen while reading the liner notes and digging on the cover art. In many ways, the cover art could be just as cool and compelling as a great record. 

Now, streaming has replaced record sales as everyone either downloads songs from itunes or creates their own playlist from spotify, pandora, or some other service. In the end, you don't actually "own" this music, you're essentially leasing it through whatever service you choose. You lose the tactile enjoyment of pulling vinyl from it's sleeve or opening a jewel case. You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

While you can find all sorts of undiscovered music through streaming, you don't necessarily own it. IT might be a good companion because of its ease of use, but owning physical copies of the music you love is still superior to having a copy on your phone.

CMV, that streaming music is inferior to owning either vinyl or cd's of musical artists work.



 
&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29968103885.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

But you literally undo this argument in the next sentence saying

&amp;gt; **While you can find all sorts of undiscovered music through streaming**, you don't necessarily own it. IT might be a good companion because of its ease of use, but owning physical copies of the music you love is still superior to having a copy on your phone.

We discover those tunes through Spotify.

And we aren't limited to just what is on the album. Services can see what we like and offer us music similar to it, I never knew of the majority of the music on my favourite playlist until Spotify recommended them.

The discovery is the same, if not better.

Why is the tactile sensation better? If I lose my phone or if my phone dies, I can just listen to music on my friend's phone or on a computer. I don't have to worry about the media being scratched or broken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968114413.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But you literally undo this argument in the next sentence saying

Not necessarily. Sure, spotify and iTunes makes recommendations, but you didn't discover that because you bought a record for one song, then found out how great some other tune was. 

&amp;gt;Why is the tactile sensation better?

If you've never experienced I don't know how to explain it. I suspect that many of the arguments I will hear are due to a lack of experience with the other delivery methods being THE ONLY option at one time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968411773.0" user="sarcasticorange" delta="False">
    <text>I'm old - like 8-track old - and I don't really get the tactile thing either. I think that might be an individual thing rather than just lack of experience.

I would say that the social aspect of shopping for music is probably where I would have gone instead of the tactile thing, but that is somewhat true for pretty much all shopping today as compared to the past.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968426274.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>No, you undo it.

You are talking about buying an album for one song and discovering another.

But that same thing happens when you listen to an album on Spotify. Because you can listen to entire albums. Plus you get the added benefit of recommendations based on your preferences.

I have experience with physical media, but the danger of it getting damaged far outweighs any sort of tactile benefits. It's why I don't buy physical video games anymore.

Sure I don't own it and I can't resell it and it doesn't look as good as a physical wall of media, but it is much more convenient and less prone to destruction.

Plus due to lower overhead and production costs more money can be sent to the artist and/or their label.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968558168.0" user="paul_aka_paul" delta="False">
    <text>Fellow old guy here. I have heard this sort of tactile argument before regarding ebooks. I just don't have the same nostalgia for this that you and the book lovers have. I did read liner notes, but now I have the internet. Some album art was nice. Some was forgettable. There was something oddly satisfying about the feel the little plastic gears in a cassette between my fingertips. But my phone is only slightly larger than a cassette and grants me access to far more than just one album's worth of music.

I just don't see that much being lost because of how the delivery method feels now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968958916.0" user="-Randy-Marsh-" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not necessarily. Sure, spotify and iTunes makes recommendations, but you didn't discover that because you bought a record for one song, then found out how great some other tune was.

So the discovery is worse because you don't have to spend as much money on it?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
