<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="459330880.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7lh1z4/cmvthe_death_of_the_cdalbum_as_the_primary_means/">
    <title>CMV:The death of the CD/Album as the primary means of listening to music and music ownership is bad</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>Growing up, I saw music delivery move from vinyl to cassette to CD, and now to streaming. My friends and I used to spend hours each month at the record store, browsing through new albums and searching for classics or hidden gems. We'd take them home, put them on and listen while reading the liner notes and digging on the cover art. In many ways, the cover art could be just as cool and compelling as a great record. 

Now, streaming has replaced record sales as everyone either downloads songs from itunes or creates their own playlist from spotify, pandora, or some other service. In the end, you don't actually "own" this music, you're essentially leasing it through whatever service you choose. You lose the tactile enjoyment of pulling vinyl from it's sleeve or opening a jewel case. You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

While you can find all sorts of undiscovered music through streaming, you don't necessarily own it. IT might be a good companion because of its ease of use, but owning physical copies of the music you love is still superior to having a copy on your phone.

CMV, that streaming music is inferior to owning either vinyl or cd's of musical artists work.



 
&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29967987257.0" user="InsideOutsider" delta="False">
    <text>True, things will never be the same as they were. The world has gone digital. The record stores are gone. Radio is almost dead. The album format is a thing of the past. Yet, they are being replaced with new practises that will be someone else's fond memories 25 years from now.

Maybe it's a perfect playlist, sharing earbuds with your crush, or how your favorite artist drops two tracks every couple months to stay relevant and is killing it.

Personally, my collection has grown 1000 fold since digitalization. My tastes more experimental because I don't have to buy an album to hear it or find a radio station that plays obscure artists. Everything is right here a my fingertips if I dare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968027613.0" user="ThisWastesTime" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The record stores are gone. 

Where are all of the people who keep saying this?  My city still has at least half a dozen independent record stores, and a chain record store in a few malls.  Plus all of the other businesses that dabble in physical music sales, even Chapters very recently started a half-assed vinyl display next to the music book section.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968488641.0" user="InsideOutsider" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like you live in Canada. The major stores in the US, Towers Records, Sam Goody, and Musicland are long gone. I'm sure some shops somewhere (like Best Buy) sell new CDs, and a few sell used, yet the market for them is gone. It's a specialty item. Who sells boom boxes or home stereo equipment? Computers don't even always  come with CD drives anymore. There is a withering existing market that is unlikely to replace their current equipment, but instead will change to a more current format, like streaming, when their CD changer bites the dust.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968690280.0" user="ThisWastesTime" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I'm in Canada.  I always enjoy visiting record stores when I travel, but I haven't been to the US since 2015. Will I notice a lot fewer of them next time? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29969368322.0" user="InsideOutsider" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps. Depends where you go, I suppose. You can dig up little shops everywhere I imagine and if you go somewhere less progressive you might even find a record store next to a Blockbuster video.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968042169.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Maybe it's a perfect playlist

Yeah, we used to call those mix tapes

&amp;gt;sharing earbuds with your crush

It's far more hygienic to NOT share earbuds

&amp;gt;how your favorite artist drops two tracks every couple months to stay relevant

Artists were relevant for years on the strength of a great album (See Hootie and the Blowfish, Boston, etc). They didn't have to "release" new tracks every couple of months, unless you count dropping singles from the album.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968050097.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's far more hygienic to NOT share earbuds

How does the hygiene of earbuds compare with kissing? I'm not sure if saliva is more or less hygienic than ear wax. Does it matter if they have dry type earwax or wet type?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968083122.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>I guess you have a point in a roundabout way (regarding hygiene) but sucking face has far greater benefits than sharing earwax, which just sounds gross...although rule 34

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968096047.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I guess you have a point in a roundabout way (regarding hygiene) but sucking face has far greater benefits than sharing earwax, which just sounds gross...although rule 34

Hey, whatever people are in to. I'm just not condemning people who share earbuds and kiss, because the mouth seems far less hygienic than ears. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968514580.0" user="InsideOutsider" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Maybe it's a perfect playlist
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;Yeah, we used to call those mix tapes
&amp;gt;

Now I can share my mixtape with thousands of people without hours of dubbing cassettes.

&amp;gt;Artists were relevant for years on the strength of a great album (See Hootie and the Blowfish, Boston, etc). They didn't have to "release" new tracks every couple of months, unless you count dropping singles from the album.

True. But is that better? Used to be a band spent months cutting an album then toured on that album for a year. The fan bought the album, then maybe saw them live when they rolled into town. An average band maybe half the album had strong songs, then there was not as great stuff or straight up filler. Great bands were great bands with solid albums, that's still the same, but the average band cannot rest on a record deal. There is much more competition. I'll argue that there are countless more bands releasing music now because it's so much easier to do. Ultimately, the consumer is the winner because a band has to be so much better to break through AND stick around.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
