<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="459330880.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7lh1z4/cmvthe_death_of_the_cdalbum_as_the_primary_means/">
    <title>CMV:The death of the CD/Album as the primary means of listening to music and music ownership is bad</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>Growing up, I saw music delivery move from vinyl to cassette to CD, and now to streaming. My friends and I used to spend hours each month at the record store, browsing through new albums and searching for classics or hidden gems. We'd take them home, put them on and listen while reading the liner notes and digging on the cover art. In many ways, the cover art could be just as cool and compelling as a great record. 

Now, streaming has replaced record sales as everyone either downloads songs from itunes or creates their own playlist from spotify, pandora, or some other service. In the end, you don't actually "own" this music, you're essentially leasing it through whatever service you choose. You lose the tactile enjoyment of pulling vinyl from it's sleeve or opening a jewel case. You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

While you can find all sorts of undiscovered music through streaming, you don't necessarily own it. IT might be a good companion because of its ease of use, but owning physical copies of the music you love is still superior to having a copy on your phone.

CMV, that streaming music is inferior to owning either vinyl or cd's of musical artists work.



 
&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29967974208.0" user="gusto_thefilmmaker" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the nostalgic feelings attached to physical music. I’ve personally never bought a CD in my life but I do love album covers and the idea of spending time with your mates discovering music. However Ive always experienced immense joy exploring the internet in search of the rarest, coolest records I could find. There’s countless of weird stuff that I have no doubt would’ve been impossible to find in a store. My point being there’s a section of your argument that’s just based on your emotional connection to physical music.

So why is it bad that you don’t own the music? Why is it superior to have a cheap looking plastic case (vinyls look cool, cds don’t) containing an easily breakable disc?
When music is good and it touches you then it’s going to be with you forever, and in a way you own it, together with everyone else that loves that piece of music. I don’t think having it physically or in your phone matters at all.

Finally I don’t really get your point on singles. Streaming doesn’t stop you from listening to the whole album if you’re interested in the artist beyond a particular song.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968013086.0" user="ThisWastesTime" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why is it superior to have a cheap looking plastic case (vinyls look cool, cds don’t) containing an easily breakable disc?

I never understood the argument that the plastic cases for CDs were "cheap-looking." I think they look a lot better than the oversized plastic cases typically used for DVDs/games.  (The recent trend of selling CDs in flat card sleeves *is* cheap-looking and I don't like it.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29968036240.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I’ve personally never bought a CD in my life but I do love album covers and the idea of spending time with your mates discovering music.

This is partly why I posted this. While I understand that you can certainly discover new music online, it's just not the same as browsing through albums or cds. I can see how someone who has never done it, and experienced music that way, will see the streaming option as being superior. 

&amp;gt;I’ve personally never bought a CD in my life but I do love album covers and the idea of spending time with your mates discovering music.

I think it does. at one time I had a collection of over 1200 cd's. I had immense pride in my collection and it was stolen (all of it), and I was devastated. The passion, the discovery, the joy of building that collection can only be had by purchasing physical copies, knowing that you can pull it out and put it on. Perhaps it's cathartic, but I miss it and I'm sad that younger generations will miss out on that joy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
