<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="459330880.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7lh1z4/cmvthe_death_of_the_cdalbum_as_the_primary_means/">
    <title>CMV:The death of the CD/Album as the primary means of listening to music and music ownership is bad</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>Growing up, I saw music delivery move from vinyl to cassette to CD, and now to streaming. My friends and I used to spend hours each month at the record store, browsing through new albums and searching for classics or hidden gems. We'd take them home, put them on and listen while reading the liner notes and digging on the cover art. In many ways, the cover art could be just as cool and compelling as a great record. 

Now, streaming has replaced record sales as everyone either downloads songs from itunes or creates their own playlist from spotify, pandora, or some other service. In the end, you don't actually "own" this music, you're essentially leasing it through whatever service you choose. You lose the tactile enjoyment of pulling vinyl from it's sleeve or opening a jewel case. You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

While you can find all sorts of undiscovered music through streaming, you don't necessarily own it. IT might be a good companion because of its ease of use, but owning physical copies of the music you love is still superior to having a copy on your phone.

CMV, that streaming music is inferior to owning either vinyl or cd's of musical artists work.



 
&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29968222604.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of people just use music differently these days. Music collections aren't listened to just at home anymore, sitting next to your CD or record player.

Extremely lightweight mobile devices and the ease of having a personal sounds system with you at all times enables more people to listen to more of their favorite music at any time, wherever they want. For these new generations of users, a downloading/streaming based service suits their needs much better than having to manage physical copies or going home to sit in front of their sound system.

And not being forced to buy an entire CD or album also has some big advantages: it's now cheaper to create a music collection just with the songs you like. In the past, one of my big problems was that an entire album or compilation often contained just 3-4 songs that I liked. I like very few artists enough that I would like their entire albums. 

By sampling and selecting individual downloads at around $1 each, I can get much more music that I actually enjoy for the same price of the traditional album price. And sampling (e.g. at [Beatport.com](https://www.beatport.com/) or directly in iTunes/Amazon etc.) still allows you to discover new tracks by chance if you don't want to trust algorithms.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
