<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="459330880.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7lh1z4/cmvthe_death_of_the_cdalbum_as_the_primary_means/">
    <title>CMV:The death of the CD/Album as the primary means of listening to music and music ownership is bad</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>Growing up, I saw music delivery move from vinyl to cassette to CD, and now to streaming. My friends and I used to spend hours each month at the record store, browsing through new albums and searching for classics or hidden gems. We'd take them home, put them on and listen while reading the liner notes and digging on the cover art. In many ways, the cover art could be just as cool and compelling as a great record. 

Now, streaming has replaced record sales as everyone either downloads songs from itunes or creates their own playlist from spotify, pandora, or some other service. In the end, you don't actually "own" this music, you're essentially leasing it through whatever service you choose. You lose the tactile enjoyment of pulling vinyl from it's sleeve or opening a jewel case. You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

While you can find all sorts of undiscovered music through streaming, you don't necessarily own it. IT might be a good companion because of its ease of use, but owning physical copies of the music you love is still superior to having a copy on your phone.

CMV, that streaming music is inferior to owning either vinyl or cd's of musical artists work.



 
&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29968945934.0" user="AlphaGoGoDancer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In the end, you don't actually "own" this music, you're essentially leasing it through whatever service you choose.

This depends on the service. You're right that its possible to just license music temporarily, but you also can digitally purchase music and own it just as much as you'd own a cd. For example Amazon sells MP3s with no DRM.  Once you bought it, you have that mp3 for life.

&amp;gt; You lose the tactile enjoyment of pulling vinyl from it's sleeve or opening a jewel case.

True, but I don't think this tactical sensation is particularly important.

&amp;gt;You the lose the discovery of finding more than one great tune on a record. For example, Fleetwood Mac's Rumours had only four singles, so in today's age how would any discover the great tunes on that record like Second Hand News, Never Going Back Again, The Chain, or Gold Dust Woman?

Same was as before? Go buy the digital album https://play.google.com/store/music/album/Fleetwood_Mac_Rumours?id=B6lhckewfewpe23jlbzipc6ywby&amp;amp;hl=en and theres all the same songs you mention.

Alternatively, you now have all kinds of discovery mechanisms. You could find those songs by having them suggested based on you liking similar songs for example. Sharing is also much easier. 
 Before I'd need real life friends who are in the same place at the same time to share that song with them.  Now I drop this link https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sKj1EFeU-cM  and every one of you can listen to it.  TBH I have never even heard of this song before your post so you've already shared it with me in a sense.  I certainly wouldn't have bought a cd based on your post, but I don't mind googling a song name.



</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
