<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="461440984.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7mqa54/cmv_while_musical_taste_is_subjective_there_can/">
    <title>CMV: While musical taste is subjective, there can be an objective nature to the quality of music.</title>
    <original_poster>ZosoGG</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let me start by saying my overarching premise for this CMV.

Music quality can be determined roughly by the question "If I were to sit down with an instrument (guitar,piano,midi keyboard, DAW, etc.) for 30 minutes, would I be able to make this song?"

I know this seems pretty arbitrary, and its not a hard and fast rule, but it should serve as a good guiding mindset for how I feel about this topic and my best attempt to try create an objective quantifier of "good" music, in a subject that clearly has too many variables to be able to effectively analyse quantitatively. 

I've believed this for a long time and was just reminded of it the other day. I was at a friends place and he put on some trap music, I'm not sure who it was (Lil' Uzi Vert?). Anyway, this guy was super psyched about how awesome the album was, and I was open to listening. Pretty quickly I started to become quite amused at the content. To start off, hip hop beats are quite simplistic. This isn't a problem since I actually really like the simplicity of it and think it's quite enjoyable. However, despite my ability to subjectively enjoy the music, I understand that the beats are nothing groundbreaking. The same samples from 80's songs I've heard in many different rap songs, with a basic bass snare beat in 4/4 time, obviously repeating the same measure(s) for the duration of the song. 

Now the lyrics. I actually have never cared much for lyrics in rap songs, because it is not really what we are discussing at this point. Music is the domain of rhythms and pitches, while lyrics are a poetic pursuit. While I will concede that one can implement some singing and rhythm (flow) into their rapping, it is not largely the point of rapping. But even so, the lyrics were legitimately making me laugh. Nursery rhymes about drugs and repeating the same lines about 'Dubai' or something, with very little variation in word usage. While this is probably the hardest part of my CMV to argue because I don't have an opinion on "lyrical quality", I will refer back to my initial statement at the top and try to come up with, what I believe, would by 'bars' of similar quality as I am sitting and typing this post.

Got that bitch wet,
Make my dick big,
Dont you fucking fret,
Make my dick big

I reserve intellectual property on this btw so don't take it^. This took my less than a minute. 

Also, the background 'singer' sounds were mostly the bread and butter of trap music today. Lot's of "scurrr" car screeching sounds and high pitched "ohhs!" or just repeating the last part of a line. It was comical to say the least.

However, I'd like to stay with what I'm comfortable with, and that is music theory. From a music theoretical point of view, these songs are very simplistic. If you haven't studied western music theory at all, it is pretty standard how it is taught. You have the major scale and its modes, the most popular being the Aeolian or minor scale. From these you can make basic triad chords from each point in the scale with the other scale notes. Many chords progressions are standardized. For example, the I IV V in blues is one of the most influential and common chord progression in popular music. The I V vi IV is also extremely common. With this knowledge, one can sit down and write a blues song in 5 minutes (not bashing on blues music btw, just saying its pretty simple to make). Just pick a key (doesnt really matter), play your I IV and V as you please (probably 12 bar blues), and add in some little spice with various other notes in the pentatonic scale as you see fit, and add lyrics. Boom. Blues song.

Now, most people are very ignorant to music theory, and if they were to hear someone playing a song like that, they might actually think "wow, you're really good!". But the reality is, the effort and time put into that song was minimal and in my book that's kind of a shitty song. 

Obviously I've gotten off track from the trap song/ genre in general, but its not really a central point of my argument, I just thought it was a cool way of presenting it. This same logic applies to some (not all) trap songs. And some (not all) blues songs. And some (not all) really any genre of songs. How much of this song is just a copy of some melodic ideas that someone else already explored before? How much is just copy paste from standard western music theoretical frameworks? Could I improvise this song? Or better yet, *did* the person basically improvise this song? These are all questions I think that can be legitimately asked to answer a question many believe to be unanswerable which is "does this song suck?". 

Look, I guess it might be impossible, but it all comes down to how one would define "suck". If by "suck" we mean that the artist used minimal brainpower, talent, and creativity to make the song, than I think it is possible to at least *try* to answer the question objectively. Why is it that we try to rate performances in the olympics in certain categories such as diving and gymnastics in terms subjective ratings from judges, but as soon as someone tries to rate different types of music on general quality, people get all defensive with "hey man music is subjective". You're right, musical taste is subjective. But are we really going to sit here and pretend that the musical talent of someone like Mozart is incomparable to an artist like Waka Flocka Flame? I mean *technically* one can say that it's impossible, but what if I were to say that I, having never done gymnastics in my life, am not objectively worse than a gymnast having won 3 gold medals at the olympics because the talent and quality of the performance is just too hard to quantify, too many variables. 

Keep in mind, to be intellectually honest and consistent, I do not act like I know the answer to how to rate one song definitively better than another. It is a difficult if not impossible pursuit. I realize that leaving ratings up to certain judges leaves a lot of subjective bias into the mix, and there really is not quantifiable way to say how good one song is. What I am simply saying is that, there is a large gray area in music, but there are some songs that are either black and white, good or bad. A kind of common sense argument, if you will. And that while I don't know the answers, there is some kind of metric out there than can categorize these songs into a good or bad category. Or maybe, more appropriately, a 'bad' and 'not bad' category. And with that, I leave you all with this 

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-ZpcOO6mw-g
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29984314499.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>Of course music can be objectively measured on all sorts of criteria. The problem is that there is no objective way to determine which criteria constitute "good" and "bad" music. Sure, you can say that in order to be "good", music must conform to standard music theory or take years to perfect or... etc. Based on these criteria (and many others), then of course you could say Mozart is better than Waka Flocka Flame. And a lot of people would agree with you. But just because a set of criteria is popular, or a specific conclusion is widespread doesn't mean it is objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29984533980.0" user="ZosoGG" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your reply. And I agree with you. I'm having a flashback about an argument I had with some friends about whether or not minecraft is "harder" than starcraft. And it was a frustrating argument. It was frustrating because I realized, there really is no way that I can objectively prove to them that playing starcraft is harder than playing minecraft. Maybe they just require different skillsets? Creativities? What kind of competition is there in minecraft? It is similar to how I feel with comparing a Waka Flocka song to a Chopin, or Miles Davis. To me, clearly one is of higher quality (creativity, effort in production and songwriting, contribution to their genres, depth and complexity of music theory in songwriting and musical talent in raw hours of practice required to make the song and perform), but technical there is not objective way I can *prove* to someone that one if of better quality. Because I guess like you said, we would have to agree on a definition of quality. And any definition of quality I define, the other might not agree with so as to fit their ideas. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
