<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="464135371.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7oc157/cmv_people_who_hang_around_in_a_group_are_all/">
    <title>CMV: People who hang around in a group are all similar to each other and people who prefer being alone are too different from the them (the former)</title>
    <original_poster>zer0_snot</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Background:**

I've seen that we have two kinds of people in life. Those who prefer to hang out in groups - no matter where they go they end up being part of a group (almost always). And those that are always alone. They tend to be alone most of the time (most of the time).

**Belief 1 that needs to be changed:**

Let me elaborate on these points. For example, in the workplace your whole department might be divided into 5 groups. Then in each of those 5 groups the people are all similar to each other. You could say that group 1 has people of type A qualities, group 2 has people of type B qualities. If group 1 has 5 people then those 5 people are more or less similar to each other. I would say 70% similar in terms of life opinions, behaviors, attitudes etc.

CMV1: This is the reason why the group people get along with each other. It's because they're all similar to each other. They're just lucky that they were born with/absorbed such common behaviors that they always find similar people, no matter where they go.

**Belief 2 that needs to be changed:**

People who prefer being alone are very different from these group-guys. Such people usually end up being alone because they are too different. Their sense of humor is different, behaviors, perceptions, opinions, tastes are all too unique. So when they hang out in a group of people they cannot relate to the conversation or behaviors - because they are too different.

CMV2: No matter how much they try, the people who prefer hanging out alone can never be part of a group. It's because they're too different to fit in. The group-guys will never understand, appreciate or respect the loner-guys. Even when they're all hanging out together. It's only a matter of time before the group-guys start belittling the loner-guys for their lack of group-socializing-skills and making judgements on their whole personalities. It's just unfortunate that the loner-guys were born/developed into tastes that were just way too unique. Group-guys will never accept loner-guys.

**In other words:** 

We all fit into 2 kinds of people. 

The group-guys - who get similar people like them no matter where they go. I'm not saying a 100% similar, but like 70% similar. You all share the same tastes across movies, songs, discussions of the workplace, attitudes towards friends and acquaintances, mannerism of talking, eating/drinking/smoking preferences, hangout location preferences. They understand each other very well and become quick-friends.

The loner-guys - who are way too unique. There's like 1 in 30 guys who are similar to them. They mostly remain alone because they cannot fit in with the group guys. They will never get to be part of any group because of this. The group guys are all similar and loner-guys are way too different.

Please help me CMV!


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30005200884.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I’m an introvert, but I don’t think being an introvert makes more more unique than other people. A huge portion of society is introverted — they prefer to spend time alone, or one on one.

While this does lead to the development of a rich inner life, the root cause is anxiety. People who dislike groups generally dislike them because, since a young age, social situations whose outcomes they could not predict produced fear reactions.

That could lead to you developing different opinions and ideas and senses of humor, but in so far as you participate in social and mass media, your probably still going to be pretty homogenized in your thinking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30005215771.0" user="zer0_snot" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of social media / mass media are we talking about? What kind of interactions do you mean which might make the loner-guys more homogenized in their thinking? I feel that you're on to something here. Just a little more is remaining.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30005363744.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Well social media let’s you read massive amounts of other people’s opinions. That will have an effect. On reddit and most social media platforms, the most popular opinions are seen first. 

Then TV, movies, you are going to most likely see popular shows. Even if you like obscure ones, so do millions of other people, and those obscure ones are still molded by the prevailing media market. 

So your going to be molded by popular opinions unless you cut yourself off from media. There’s going to just be lots of people with opinions similar to you. Maybe no one holds those exact opinions exactly the way you do, but that’s true with everyone. And that’s the same whether your extroverted or introverted. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
