<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="467032240.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7q24ds/cmv_dating_is_like_finding_a_job_it_isnt_good_to/">
    <title>CMV: Dating is like finding a job, it isn't good to put all your eggs in one basket.</title>
    <original_poster>nerdywiththeword</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start off, dating is pretty like the job interview in a relationship. you guys are conversing to see if there is a potential fit for each other. If it is successful then there is going to be an offer for a relationship; if not then either the two is going to be friends or merely walk away and say goodbye without staying in contact.

Like job hunting, one should always be vigilant. When it comes to finding a relationship, one should focus on scheduling as many dates as possible to maximize their chances of being in a relationship. It is not wise to only stick to focusing all your attention onto one person because there is a big chance it wouldn't work out. Instead by talking to as many people as possible you are spreading your eggs in multiple basket and improving your chances at beating the numbers game.

This resonates well with job hunters since doing so many interviews (Or in this case talking to many potential people) will give you more opportunities to improve and sell yourself better down the road. I remember doing like 10 interviews before getting my first job. Each interview I improve upon one another and I feel this could be applied to dating.

Another reason not to put all your eggs in one basket is to be better mentally prepared when the date doesn't workout. You have another person to look forward to meeting so you won't feel too down.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30028087747.0" user="new2bay" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree almost entirely. Most people are not independently wealthy, and, hence, can't afford to be out of a job for an indefinite period of time; one can take one's time finding a new SO.  Having a series of short flings before settling on one person (if that's the objective) is not necessarily a negative thing, as opposed to having a series of very short jobs on one's resume.

Last, but not least, an employer typically has many employees, while an employee typically has only one employer.  This means that the employer has less reason to form a commitment with any given employee, while an employee typically gives all of his/her work effort to his/her single employer.  Then, there's the profit motive, which gives the employer an incentive to screw over the employee the moment they decide it will make or save them a buck.  In combination with the aforementioned fact that most people can't afford to be out of a job for an extended period of time, this means the employee/employer relationship is more like an abusive romantic relationship than a healthy one, and that's not what any psychologically healthy individual wants from an SO.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028095125.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>I would agree with you but what I am talking about haven't even reached the stages of a job offer yet. You are right that having a series of very short jobs on one's resume is seen as a negative light. 

However, my point is that dating is pretty much like a job interview. Having done multiple job interviews is not seen as a negative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028122972.0" user="new2bay" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you're meaning "dating" to be those first, second (and occasionally 3rd) dates you kind of have to go on in order to decide if you want to commit further to someone, ya?  And, sure, maybe those are somewhat similar to a job interview in that sense.  But, I'm arguing that the goal is entirely different, and the context is entirely different (particularly the part about how most people simply can't be out of work for an extended period of time). 

So, I suppose if you define "dating" in that way, and assume that "dating" leads to either "relationship/commitment" or not, then, maybe they have some very superficial similarities.  But I would say that's a vast oversimplification of how humans actually interact.  I've been seeing someone for about 2 months, and I would say we're definitely "dating."  We don't have any agreement in place to not see each other, but we spend a lot of time together and we definitely enjoy each others' company.  In contrast, I was seeing someone for a few months before that, and I wouldn't have said we were "dating"; it was more like a FWB situation than anything, and we were both seeing other people.  Both situations were good, but only one is going in the direction of "dating -&amp;gt; relationship".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30029293784.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30029412723.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Rule 2</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
