<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="467032240.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7q24ds/cmv_dating_is_like_finding_a_job_it_isnt_good_to/">
    <title>CMV: Dating is like finding a job, it isn't good to put all your eggs in one basket.</title>
    <original_poster>nerdywiththeword</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start off, dating is pretty like the job interview in a relationship. you guys are conversing to see if there is a potential fit for each other. If it is successful then there is going to be an offer for a relationship; if not then either the two is going to be friends or merely walk away and say goodbye without staying in contact.

Like job hunting, one should always be vigilant. When it comes to finding a relationship, one should focus on scheduling as many dates as possible to maximize their chances of being in a relationship. It is not wise to only stick to focusing all your attention onto one person because there is a big chance it wouldn't work out. Instead by talking to as many people as possible you are spreading your eggs in multiple basket and improving your chances at beating the numbers game.

This resonates well with job hunters since doing so many interviews (Or in this case talking to many potential people) will give you more opportunities to improve and sell yourself better down the road. I remember doing like 10 interviews before getting my first job. Each interview I improve upon one another and I feel this could be applied to dating.

Another reason not to put all your eggs in one basket is to be better mentally prepared when the date doesn't workout. You have another person to look forward to meeting so you won't feel too down.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30028426702.0" user="JamesDevitt" delta="False">
    <text>I honesty weep for humanity at this point.

I mean it comes down to your goal. If your goal is to be in a "successful" relationship as soon as possible. Then by all means treating dating like doing a job interview. You'll soon have a reasonable person with which to enter a mortgage with and can quickly start producing more workers for the capitalist state.

However, let me suggest that there is another deeper way to think about dating. You want to add meaning to your life. You want what happens to seem really important. You want yes, to have the joy of feeling really connected to someone. But you also want to feel the true pain of missing someone and having heartbreak. In short, you want to be a human and not some means of production. All of this is going to work better if you concentrate your romantic energies on one person at a time: a crush, a date, a partner. You have to realize that all relationships end and most end tragically, but they are worth having anyway. Not putting your eggs in one basket so you can be mentally prepared when it doesn't work out sounds to me a lot like being dead inside. Go into a relationship because you want to cry your eyes out- because if the relationship is real and meaningful at all- that is the guaranteed outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
