<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="467032240.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7q24ds/cmv_dating_is_like_finding_a_job_it_isnt_good_to/">
    <title>CMV: Dating is like finding a job, it isn't good to put all your eggs in one basket.</title>
    <original_poster>nerdywiththeword</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start off, dating is pretty like the job interview in a relationship. you guys are conversing to see if there is a potential fit for each other. If it is successful then there is going to be an offer for a relationship; if not then either the two is going to be friends or merely walk away and say goodbye without staying in contact.

Like job hunting, one should always be vigilant. When it comes to finding a relationship, one should focus on scheduling as many dates as possible to maximize their chances of being in a relationship. It is not wise to only stick to focusing all your attention onto one person because there is a big chance it wouldn't work out. Instead by talking to as many people as possible you are spreading your eggs in multiple basket and improving your chances at beating the numbers game.

This resonates well with job hunters since doing so many interviews (Or in this case talking to many potential people) will give you more opportunities to improve and sell yourself better down the road. I remember doing like 10 interviews before getting my first job. Each interview I improve upon one another and I feel this could be applied to dating.

Another reason not to put all your eggs in one basket is to be better mentally prepared when the date doesn't workout. You have another person to look forward to meeting so you won't feel too down.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30028053511.0" user="capitancheap" delta="False">
    <text>Dating is like job searching. You get the best jobs by showing commitment (eg., having worked in previous jobs for several years). And where perfect is the enemy of the good enough</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028068738.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>Right but when one is starting out with little experience then it is pretty much playing the numbers game. You shotgun many jobs and laser the ones you really want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028073266.0" user="capitancheap" delta="False">
    <text>No, even the most routine jobs require high school because of this very reason - to see commitment from the job seeker. Attrition is *very* expensive for a company</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028083390.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry but I see much better results from applying to multiple companies than just applying to one. I just started out and have little to no interviewing skills. You improve your interview skills by doing many job interviews and improve one upon another.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028102317.0" user="capitancheap" delta="False">
    <text>Smaller options improves one's strategic positon.(gametheory211.blogspot.ca/2014/09/the-paradox-of-commitment.html). In both job seeking and dating, when you show commitment and focus in your objectives (looking for a particular position in a particular field rather than any position at all) you can get better prospects than a shotgun strategy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028109025.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>That's only if you have a skill set that is valuable and have tons of experience to back it up. Are you indicating that I should just apply to one company and call it quits when looking for a job? 
 
When I first started out, I started to apply to any office job to build my skill set before I really start tailoring it to specific office position like accounting. Working a job is better than having no job. This was true for Internships.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028128228.0" user="capitancheap" delta="False">
    <text>I am saying by tying your hands you improve your position. This applies to anything. If you limit your rental options by signing a long term contract, than you get cheaper rent or a better apartment. If you limit your options for college application and accept early admission, then you can get accepted to a better college. If you build a death-hand and limit your options for nuclear retaliation, then your deterrence is more credible, etc   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028134945.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>And where would you draw the line? You can't foresee the future. You sign a long term contract because then you know what to expect. If the Land Lord decides to raise the rent after the contract then you are put into a rut.

There's an opportunity cost for everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028140925.0" user="capitancheap" delta="False">
    <text>You have to watch out if they are in it for the long term too. You would not want to work for or date someone who is indiscriminate just looking for any warm body, because having "any employee is better than having no employee"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028144913.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>That's true. I believe there should be minimum threshold of effort to be put into playing the numbers game. If I get an interview, I am not going to just wing it. I am going to prep over interview questions and think of good questions to ask at the end. Just like how if I am going on a date I am going to adequately prepare myself by doing all proper hygiene routine and thinking about what to talk about.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
