<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="467062429.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7q2rod/cmv_president_trumps_shithole_comment_about_haiti/">
    <title>CMV - President Trump's "shithole" comment about Haiti is not inaccurate, and because Haiti receives American aid, it should not complain</title>
    <original_poster>Petrus_</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll focus strictly on Haiti for this.

Calling certain countries shitholes isn't incorrect. I'm not arguing Trump should've said it, but I am going to defend his assertion that Haiti is a shithole, and it shouldn't complain while it receives American aid.

Shithole is defined as:

A very dirty or unpleasant place

Haiti is a shithole, as it has widespread cholera, HIV/AIDS, hepatitis, typhoid, and leprosy. All of these diseases are spread in unclean conditions, and all of these are unpleasant diseases, qualifying Haiti as a shithole. In addition, if you look at images of Haiti, the gutters are filled with garbage, the sanitation is horrible, or simply doesn't exist, and most of the country lives in squalor.

To compound this, Haiti is also extremely poor, with the average person getting $350 per year, which is ridiculously low, and can in no way be considered pleasant, further qualifying Haiti as unpleasant, and therefore a shithole.

My final point is that Haiti should not complain about calling a shithole (At least not without expecting some repercussions on it's aid), as it is both accurate, and it is receiving foreign aid to "fix" its problems. Each year, the United States spends $1.5 billion in Haiti (I've seen conflicting sources on the exact number, but the point still stands), which is a huge amount of money. In addition, the US provides 500k meals each day to Haitian students, so without the US, Haitians would be starving, so they shouldn't complain while we literally feed their kids.

Tldr: Haiti meets the definition of a shithole, by being both dirty and unpleasant, so Trump's comment was not inaccurate, and Haiti shouldn't complain by biting the hand that (Literally) feeds them.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30028510670.0" user="gamingbeatsworking" delta="False">
    <text>Trump didn't make this comment though. He adamantly denied it via twitter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028712797.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>And numerous people in the room with him (Democrats and Republicans) have said that he did. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028767944.0" user="gamingbeatsworking" delta="False">
    <text>Seems strange to stand up for somethong someone said when the person who said it won't even stand by it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028863152.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>They aren't standing up for what Trump said. They are condemning it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30029016466.0" user="gamingbeatsworking" delta="False">
    <text>Reread the title of the post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
