<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="467032240.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7q24ds/cmv_dating_is_like_finding_a_job_it_isnt_good_to/">
    <title>CMV: Dating is like finding a job, it isn't good to put all your eggs in one basket.</title>
    <original_poster>nerdywiththeword</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start off, dating is pretty like the job interview in a relationship. you guys are conversing to see if there is a potential fit for each other. If it is successful then there is going to be an offer for a relationship; if not then either the two is going to be friends or merely walk away and say goodbye without staying in contact.

Like job hunting, one should always be vigilant. When it comes to finding a relationship, one should focus on scheduling as many dates as possible to maximize their chances of being in a relationship. It is not wise to only stick to focusing all your attention onto one person because there is a big chance it wouldn't work out. Instead by talking to as many people as possible you are spreading your eggs in multiple basket and improving your chances at beating the numbers game.

This resonates well with job hunters since doing so many interviews (Or in this case talking to many potential people) will give you more opportunities to improve and sell yourself better down the road. I remember doing like 10 interviews before getting my first job. Each interview I improve upon one another and I feel this could be applied to dating.

Another reason not to put all your eggs in one basket is to be better mentally prepared when the date doesn't workout. You have another person to look forward to meeting so you won't feel too down.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30027991927.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>Strongly disagree most people aren't just looking to get any job or date any person. They are looking to land a dream job or their major crush. Handing out 20 identical resumes in one day is no different than going into a bar and using the same pick up line 20 times. Even if putting in the minimum effort impresses some it's probably not someone who had very high standards in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028008060.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>Well from my perspective, when you first start dating you want some experience first. Pretty much a casual relationship before branching off to getting more serious relationships. 

I would say those 20 resumes will get better revised as time goes on sort of like ways of looking for a date. I wouldn't even use pick up lines. I would just introduce myself casually and then see where it goes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028065401.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I just don't see the point in making this analogy. Why not make other comparisons? Dating is just like running for office, dating is just like applying to college, dating is just like hiring a nanny, etc. Sure you can make some surface level comparisons but what are you trying to say about dating or applying to jobs by comparing them? Are you trying to say people should be more professional or calculating about dating?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028067395.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>The analogy between dating and job searching just seems so similar. That's why I am making the analogy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028075717.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>Except that the goals and the processes of doing them is completely different</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028090241.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>The process is similar and thus I made the analogy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028095624.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not. If you bring a resume to a date or try and kiss your future boss at the end of an interview you are doing it wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028097035.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>You are obviously trying to relate to it too literally. You resume in a dating sense is pretty much your job, Height, Race, Personality and etc.

Or pretty much your dating profile in a dating app.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028110244.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>If you make comparisons so broad like that it doesn't mean anything though. You could say dating is just like grocery shopping. You should inspect a lot of produce so you don't get any bruised peaches and a grocery list is just like a dating profile! Grocery shopping and dating are almost the smart thing!

Theres no point to analogies unless you are trying to explain a complex idea you can't express by any other means. I don't see the idea you are trying to convey by comparing jobs and dates so the analogy is pointless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028115560.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>Well my point is that dating is like playing the numbers game. Try to talk to as many people at the same time and then improve upon each failure.

I saw it like how it is like hunting for a job but if you don't like analogies then that's fine. However, my main point is just that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028128846.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>Well that idea is still stupid. There's plenty of different levels of effort you can put into an application and a relationship. If you do multiple interviews a day theres no way you could be as prepared or focused than if you had just done one instead just like if you date multiple people at the same time you will never get the same sort of feel for the relationship if you had just put in the same effort to get to know one person. 

The choice is between doing 10 interviews and 3 interviews it's between showing up prepared to 3 interviews or just showing up to 10 interviews.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028140757.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. Multiple interviews a day is absurd. Multiple interviews within a span of a week isn't.

You are going to have to make a bet and see which is right for you. I rather divide and conquer (Which was a valid strategy in the old days) than to do a full on frontal assault on something which I am unsure about.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028178219.0" user="jerseycash5" delta="False">
    <text>Both have listings, both have an interview process, both have a position to be filled. You’re discounting OPs argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028695968.0" user="cupcakesarethedevil" delta="False">
    <text>Are you new here? That's the point</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
