<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="467032240.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7q24ds/cmv_dating_is_like_finding_a_job_it_isnt_good_to/">
    <title>CMV: Dating is like finding a job, it isn't good to put all your eggs in one basket.</title>
    <original_poster>nerdywiththeword</original_poster>
    <original_post>To start off, dating is pretty like the job interview in a relationship. you guys are conversing to see if there is a potential fit for each other. If it is successful then there is going to be an offer for a relationship; if not then either the two is going to be friends or merely walk away and say goodbye without staying in contact.

Like job hunting, one should always be vigilant. When it comes to finding a relationship, one should focus on scheduling as many dates as possible to maximize their chances of being in a relationship. It is not wise to only stick to focusing all your attention onto one person because there is a big chance it wouldn't work out. Instead by talking to as many people as possible you are spreading your eggs in multiple basket and improving your chances at beating the numbers game.

This resonates well with job hunters since doing so many interviews (Or in this case talking to many potential people) will give you more opportunities to improve and sell yourself better down the road. I remember doing like 10 interviews before getting my first job. Each interview I improve upon one another and I feel this could be applied to dating.

Another reason not to put all your eggs in one basket is to be better mentally prepared when the date doesn't workout. You have another person to look forward to meeting so you won't feel too down.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30028181894.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think your analogy is very accurate, but I'll give it a shot.

&amp;gt; Dating is like finding a job, it isn't good to put all your eggs in one basket.

Dating is like finding a job: sign up for a dozen full time jobs and then get fired from all of them because your performance sucks.

&amp;gt; Like job hunting, one should always be vigilant. When it comes to finding a relationship, one should focus on scheduling as many dates as possible to maximize their chances of being in a relationship. It is not wise to only stick to focusing all your attention onto one person because there is a big chance it wouldn't work out. Instead by talking to as many people as possible you are spreading your eggs in multiple basket and improving your chances at beating the numbers game.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; This resonates well with job hunters since doing so many interviews (Or in this case talking to many potential people) will give you more opportunities to improve and sell yourself better down the road. I remember doing like 10 interviews before getting my first job. Each interview I improve upon one another and I feel this could be applied to dating.

You're comparing the wrong phases. The first date is comparable to your first day at work. The "hunting" phase is your tinder swiping, or your pick-up lines at the bar.

You step in with the expectation that this may not be the right choice? It reflects in your efforts, and you get fired/dumped.

Employer/Date finds out that you are looking at other employers/SOs?  Your dedication is questioned, and you are fired/dumped.

You put in 100%, but employer/date doesn't like you? You get fired/dumped.

You could say that you are justified in looking at other choices in the meantime, but that means nothing, because employer/date are well within their rights to fire/dump you, that's their freedom.

Just starting out? Date during your teens/part time work during school holiday.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028189830.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>1. Did you forget that you don't sign up and automatically get a job? You sign up for an interview for your employers to see if you are a right fit for the position. 

2. Hmm I sort of think the first date would be the interview process but I guess I can see how it can sort of be like probation for your new job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028208647.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Did you forget that you don't sign up and automatically get a job? You sign up for an interview for your employers to see if you are a right fit for the position.

In the same way, you don't get a date immediately. Your interests have to align, or your pick up line needs to be good enough, etc. For example, I haven't used Tinder, but don't both you and the person you like have to swipe right and then talk before you actually go on a date?

&amp;gt; Hmm I sort of think the first date would be the interview process but I guess I can see how it can sort of be like probation for your new job.

Depends. If you walk into your first date with almost no conversation, it could be. Most people don't go on completely blind dates with strangers tho, even if you meet up somewhere like a bar, there is some modicum of conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028217846.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>So the conversation leading to a date is the interview. I agree on that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028223063.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>So, your view has changed? If so, delta, or else, what didn't change?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028226556.0" user="nerdywiththeword" delta="False">
    <text>The new point would be talking to multiple people at the same time to maximize the chances of finding a date. I guess date would be the wrong term to use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30028275285.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>That's pretty much a new topic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
