<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="468395254.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7qvc3a/cmv_congress_should_change_congressional/">
    <title>CMV: Congress should change Congressional elections to Mixed Member Proportional to end gerrymandering.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress has the power to regulate and alter the "times, places and manner of holding elections for Senators and Representatives" under Article I, Section 4 of the Constitution.

Currently, under this power, the Congress [has mandated that all members of the House of Representatives be elected from single-member geographic districts.](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/2/2c)

I propose that Congress repeal this provision and replace it with one requiring that members of the House be elected under a mixed member proportional system, with a bare majority of the seats apportioned to a state being divided into geographic districts, and the remainder being used to fill in based on party vote in those seats using the D'Hondt method.

For states with only 1 seat, this would mean no change.

For states with 2 seats, this would mean both districts were "at large."  The party who won the normal "at large" seat would also win the second at large seat if they had 2/3 of the two-party vote in the state, or in the event of a three+ party split, if they had achieved twice as many votes as the next-most-vote-getting party.  Otherwise, the next most successful party would get the second seat.

For states with 3 seats, 2 would be geographic and 1 would be at-large.

For states with 4 seats, 2 would be geographic and 2 would be at-large.  

For states with 5 seats, 3 would be geographic and 2 would be at-large.

And so on.

I don't have a firm threshold for party qualification for at large seats, but I'd be fine with anything from 5-15%.  Members running as independents would be able to run in geographic districts only, and I'd allow that any party winning a geographic district be allowed to get proportional seats regardless of the threshold.



This would effectively end gerrymandering, while still allowing local representation of regions of states with sufficient population to have 3 or more representatives.  The boundaries of those districts would become far less important, because the at-large seats would ensure that packing and cracking have little if any effect on overall partisan makeup.

This would also not require a constitutional amendment, since it would be able to be enacted under the Article I Section 4 power.

I think that at least one party (probably the Democrats) should run on this platform, and if elected, pass it into law.

*edit* fixed an error when I inserted a paragraph at the wrong spot when composing this.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30038551349.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>Is this specifically for the House of Representative, or do you want to change the Senators as well? Senators are already elected at large in states. Do you want to get rid of it, or change the structure of Congress?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038587715.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Senators are as you say, already at large per state.  Changing that would mean changing the 17th amendment, and I am not proposing a constitutional amendment here.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
