<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30085627658.0" user="ASadRedLion" delta="False">
    <text>Books also tend to be a bit more comprehensive. If I were a high school student doing a report on John Adams, I could get a quick summary of his life online. If I wanted to have a more comprehensive view into his life, I would probably be better off finding a biography. So for certain subjects, it is better to read a book than it is to aimlessly search online for information, especially if half of the sites just simple reiterate the same few factoids. Of course their use as sources varies given the subject. For your example, if you were searching for information on teen drug use, the internet might be your best bet. A lot of the information you need would come in the form of raw data. From this you would draw conclusions and use the data to support your argument. You probably wouldn't need a book to give you a more comprehensive look into teen drug addiction. The statistics would give you enough information on the topic.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
