<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30086014136.0" user="NinjApheX" delta="False">
    <text>At the high school level, everything is all about skill development. Learning how to utilize a book source is just another one of the skills that is being taught.

And this skill is important and can be difficult, too. It's not just about finding a book on a topic, it's about knowing how to read it and search it for the information you need. As you noted, you often don't have time to read the entire book, so being able to pick out the relevant chapters and pages is a crucial skill so you aren't just picking random quotes. It's about finding specific information from a much broader source.

In contrast, peer-reviewed papers are often shorter and already focused on that specific information. For this reason, you spend less  time searching these papers for relevant information because it is likely that most of the information in these papers is focused on a single specific topic.

Both sources require different skills to be utilized effectively. For book sources, it's important that you learn how to search for the relevant information within the broader context of the book. For peer-reviewed papers, it's important that you learn how to search for relevant papers and use keywords, databases, and various searching methods properly. 

As you noted, in most cases, modern peer-reviewed papers are going to be more accurate and more current that most books on the same topic. However, there are times when a book source will be necessary - a topic could be too obscure and impossible to find online, you need information from a specific source only available in book form, etc. And at that time, it's important that you have developed the skills to read and search through that book effectively. Those skills are developed in high school because of assignments like the ones you're doing right now. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
