<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30084613024.0" user="ThatSpencerGuy" delta="False">
    <text>High school papers are not like papers written by professionals academics. High schoolers are not generating new knowledge or insight. No high schoolers are creating new, interesting knowledge about The Taming of the Shrew.  

Instead, the paper is an opportunity to build several skills related to writing, researching, reading, and thinking. Finding and using (as in, quickly searching for relevant information and reading it for comprehension) books is an important academic skill. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084718272.0" user="wervousnreck" delta="False">
    <text>True, but it’s also an important academic skill to know some stuff isn’t worth using even if it was published and put in a library. Some teachers lead us to believe “nonfiction and someone printed and published it” = “it’s quality enough material”. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084927505.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and hopefully students should learn that as well. But this is a lesson one can easily learn while still being required to cite published books. There are a LOT of books to choose from.

And in academia it is pretty unusual to cite things as opinion or related work that haven't been published, although they may be published digitally. When a high schooler is getting stuff off the internet they likely aren't using google scholar. They are probably just finding some random blog.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30085607468.0" user="ASadRedLion" delta="False">
    <text>To add to your google scholar point, most of these students probably won't even have access full access to most journal articles even if they used scholar. At most they might see an abstract. Abstracts can often be misleading, especially to the layman. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30091821564.0" user="newschoolerz" delta="False">
    <text>That’s literally me in college now lol

“Ah, this article looks relevant to my topic. The abstract says a couple good facts. Into the bibliography you go!”

Granted I do usually end up reading (skimming) the article when I end up writing the paper, but I won’t lie... I’ve cited many a paper where I’ve only read the abstract and only used info from that lol</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30086161553.0" user="chasingstatues" delta="False">
    <text>Why isn't it worth using?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
