<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30084589476.0" user="leontes" delta="False">
    <text>Often times, assignments are about partially about the how to do something rather than the actual content itself. 

 It doesn't really matter if your books are well sourced or access to them exhaustive, often times these assignments are structured so that you get the experience in what it is to go through the process of finding a relevant book, finding out how to  source it, and get the formatting right in the paper.

By utilizing google books samples, you are bypassing this potential of the educational experience and scaffolding that this assignment provides. 

The fact that you are resentful of the framing, or it feels technologically backwards is precisely the point: you are being asked to do something vaguely uncomfortable and different: what education is.  While people are students, I often encourage them to do it the way that feels backward, or unbelievably stupid, or technologically obsolete--- it may very well be that process that ends up expanding realms of comfort for other tasks in the future.

Also: wikipedia is easily mislead.  I can edit any article right now, and there are some articles that are trash on there due to edit wars.  When something is published in a reference book, it immediately becomes an artifact, but that recorded artifact has value, intrinsic value as something that was chosen as best practices in the now.  

These things are worth being exposed to, I'd recommend getting away from google and down to your local library to read journals and books, rather than access them online for that precise reason: they are different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084688451.0" user="Parrek" delta="False">
    <text>For the record, the trick is to use wikipedia sources and not the article itself since I agree that it can be terrible</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084766371.0" user="lakwl" delta="False">
    <text>The part about using Google book samples really speaks to me. How about the inaccessibility of the books that I'm looking for? For example, my essay needs me to cite books that my local library would definitely never carry. I'm not about to go buy those books or take a 4 hour bus to the larger city library, and the school curriculum shouldn't expect me to do that, especially since I wasn't given a choice regarding the subject material. Our library has simply given up on buying more new books since hardly anyone checks out books anymore. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
