<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30088004792.0" user="fl33543" delta="False">
    <text>At a certain level (grad school) research becomes about finding primary source information. For any sort of research with a historical bent, we call the world's collective trove of books, articles, letters, notes, documents, etc. "the Archive." Almost all of the Archive pre-2000 CE consists of textual documents. Requiring "book" sources gives you some rudimentary practice in finding textual/documentary materials for your research. Should you continue on in academia, these techniques will be fundamentally important. 
In addition, book and document finding can become quite complex. If your library doesn't have a certain book, you might have to track it down at another library, or even initiate an ILL (inter-library-loan). These are all upper-level research skills that build upon the foundation of knowing how to use a catalog, read a reference citation, and navigate the Dewey Decimal or Library of Congress cataloging system. While these skills are not inherently superior to a Google search, they are different. And there's no equivalent online skill to scouring the "stacks" to find a book. It's a skill you might need later that you can learn best by doing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
