<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30086266904.0" user="julesr13" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely agreed with you I was in high school, but as you move forward in academics, books become more and more important, and you'll probably be grateful that you know how to find them. I used to think it was a simple enough skill to search a library database, but around my sophomore year of college I realized I only thought that because I was never that good at it in the first place. I'm a math/physics double major doing independent research for both of my thesis projects, so needless to say I've become very familiar with different ways of accessing information in the last year or so. The things I find useful about books are as follows:

- Libraries are free, and especially in higher academics they are a very powerful resource. Whereas with academic articles, access is dependent on the publisher (whether they charge for their articles, whether your institution pays for a subscription to that publisher), and it's not uncommon even at a large institution to find yourself needing $20 to view a 7-page article, libraries actively try to have as much free information on as large a variety of subjects as possible. It's often the case that I can't read an original academic paper that's important my research, but I can find books that cited it. Combine that with an interlibrary loan system that allows me to search over 200 college and public libraries across the US and have a book from any of them in my hands 24-72 hours, and the result is that there's a hell of a lot more information available to me in print than there is for free on the internet.
- Information is consolidated into a single resource. When I find an academic article related to my research, the best I can hope for is to write 2 paragraphs or so from it; in fact, most of them are only good for 1 sentence. This summer I found a book called "Monte Carlo Methods in Ab Initio Quantum Chemistry," which is basically 50% what my physics thesis is on. That paper is currently 18 pages long, and I don't think I ever go more than 2 or 3 paragraphs without citing that book. I cite the 7 books I used in my math thesis in about equal proportion to the 61 academic journal articles.
- Author credibility is often easier to check. Not only do books usually contain a blurb about the author's history in the field, but you also need to become more established in a field before you can publish a book, and since authors are higher profile that makes it easier to find discussions of their work online. Not that reputation is everything, of course. Some relatively unknown academics have revolutionized their fields, and even Einstein was wrong about a lot of things. But as a researcher it feels a lot better to find something about "Soandso has 2 PhDs in statistical theory and elementary particle physics from UCLA and MIT and has spent the last 13 years focusing on the implications of quantum entanglement in random-population-based statistical pseudocalculation of transcendental quantities" followed by an angry comment about how her opinions on delayed choice experiments are bullshit than to just see "PhD" written next to her name in the author list.
- The focus of short publications is to convey information concisely, whereas books take the time to explain things in more detail when needed. Publishers of both tend to force authors to cut down their writing, but when your first manuscript is 25 pages on a very constrained topic, you lose different things by cutting down length than if you have 450 pages of explorations and examples and tangent topics and insights into modern developments.
- *BOOKS SMELL LIKE REALLY GOOD OKAY*
- I might add more if I think of anything.

Also, to address your comment on not being given enough time to read them, my school does one class at a time, so a class from beginning to end is 4 weeks. It's not uncommon to be given 3 days for a 15 page paper, during which time you also have class, normal homework, and possibly an exam to study for. Usually, the key is learning to get a good overview of the information quickly and then go back and read the important parts in depth. I've cited over 2000 pages of books for a single paper that I only had 3 days to work on, but in reality I only read maybe 150 pages. Occasionally though, you'll find a book that's so related to your topic that you have to just buckle down and read the whole thing, but if that happens your paper is going to write itself when you're done. Pretty good payoff for 
 6-10 hours of your time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
