<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30084582100.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose of this is to teach the students how to determine if a source is trustworthy, to teach them to use multiple sources to come to an opinion on a subject, and to teach someone how to site an opinion they got from something else so as to distinguish from their own personal opinions. 

That is the entire purpose of writing a report or research assignment and the only way to do that is to set minimal requirements of those components that meet the standards you are trying to teach. 

And books are inherently more accurate than the internet in that there is less "interference" from false information when you are dealing with sources that have already be vetted in their accuracy. We are talking about children and people who are learning how to tell if a source is accurate and trustworthy. They are learning how to tell if something has been vetted and is trustworthy, or if it is just made up by the guy down the street so has not been proven trustworthy. The only way to teach these skills is to show them the already vetted sources so that they know what they look like. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084736347.0" user="wervousnreck" delta="False">
    <text>My library is full of “Christian parent guides A-Z” and “Teen perspectives on ___”, which I don’t think are really vetted by their publishers for accuracy. I can open those books and see pretty blatantly false/slanted information, even if they claim to be telling all facts. The teachers frame their requirements as “get two book sources and *then* you can go surf the internet (which is where you will find all the bias and wild claims)”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084744444.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Once again, it is about teaching skill. It is about teaching you how to find the vetted materials. Teaching you how to use a card catalog. Teaching you how to determine if something is good or not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30086054712.0" user="nehala" delta="False">
    <text>Also, there are plenty of topics (more specialized topics--this is more relevant with university-level research) where the information you're looking for is only available in print. You'd be surprised how much stuff is not online. 

So while demanding book sources for a report on how the heart functions may be unnecessary, it's unavoidable if you want to research say, the grammar of an obscure African language spoken by 20,000 people.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30086493619.0" user="raanne" delta="False">
    <text>A book doesn't have to come from your school's library. Surely you have a town library as well? And beyond that, sources like abebooks.com where you can buy inexpensive used books. Local colleges and universities likely would allow you access to their library as well. 

Also, stating that it isn't very hard to check out a book, while also stating that you can't find good books in your library are opposing points. If you can't find good sources in your library, then it *is* hard for you to check them out. Knowing how to look for and find good sources is a skill set. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30086497741.0" user="resolvetochange" delta="False">
    <text>The main issue of using books as sources is the problem of trust. It has come up recently in the news with deepfakes showing that soon we will not be able to trust video sources, which could potentially lead to no sources being trusted.

A book that has been published has been read by an editor, they further put money on the line by paying the upfront cost to create the hard copy, and the publishing company puts their name on the line when creating it. For online sources they have a much lower barrier to entry. Anyone with 5-10 minutes can make something up and post it online to a blogging website without putting money/reputation on the line or have any type of vetting; [Here is the website for the flat earth society](https://wiki.tfes.org/Frequently_Asked_Questions) which is not a trustworthy source.

While being published in a book is not sufficient to say that the source is trustworthy, it has gone through a minimum amount of vetting.

It gets worse when you realize that google will show different search results based on your activity, meaning that if you have a political leaning it will try to show you webpages that you agree with more often, skewing what you see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30092868229.0" user="ParentheticalClaws" delta="False">
    <text>Using a source doesn’t necessarily mean taking it as 100% accurate. It is about comprehending the viewpoint of the author, in the context of time and place. Sure, these books would not be helpful if your paper was on the best way to teach children about empathy. For that, you would want psychological studies. But these books could be great sources if your topic is “attitudes toward religion and parenting in the 1990s”. In that case, they could become invaluable primary sources. The requirement to use different types of sources could help students develop the ability to consider sources in multiple ways like this, rather than viewing research as a quest for the shortest path to a definitive answer.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
