<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30084590305.0" user="yyzjertl" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.

Quoting a peer reviewed paper published in a journal _is_ quoting a book. It's quoting the journal, which is published as a book and (until very recently) was consulted and read as such. If your teacher doesn't consider journal-published papers to be book citations, then they're being unreasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30084598376.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>Unless they want you to have the experience of doing research in a physical book--finding the book, using an index, making sure you understand the context for the excerpt, etc. Then getting the journal itself should count, and using a two page sample from google books is actually the thing the violates the spirit of the assignment.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
