<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30086923475.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30086932281.0" user="neofederalist" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/yourguyfromoutback – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+yourguyfromoutback&amp;amp;message=yourguyfromoutback+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/dtkz6qb/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
