<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="474302889.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7udyg9/cmv_making_students_use_at_least_book_sources_in/">
    <title>CMV: Making students use “at least _ book sources” in school for assignments is stupid.</title>
    <original_poster>wervousnreck</original_poster>
    <original_post>In high school we’re often told “for this paper you need five sources, and at least two must be books.” 


This is stupid because:


Books are not inherently more accurate than the internet. In fact, I’d say they’re often less accurate. They don’t always age well. School libraries are also far, far more limited than the internet. It’s ridiculous that I have to consult a 1993 “Concerned Parent’s Guide To Teen Drug Use” glossy picture book (I’m making this specific one up) as equal to peer-reviewed papers by tenured professors of their fields, just because it’s all the library has.



It’s not very hard to check out a book, so I don’t think our library skills will deteriorate as a result of doing all of our research online. Sometimes I think consulting a book can be valuable, like if you have a very large university/public library at your disposal, but even then, I don’t think much can’t be found online. I’ve cited books by pulling what I need from a Google books sample. 



It’s not as if we’re given enough time on these papers to actually read the damn things, either. Picking at random some quote from a low-quality book is vastly inferior to reading a variety of internet articles. 


On a related note, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; the short “topic series” books on library shelves written at one author’s indulgence. And that’s a cheap example, but honestly, Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30086044235.0" user="MysteryArab" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Wikipedia &amp;gt;&amp;gt; most other sources below a certain length/depth.

Ok, so, what you say here might make some sense, because you aren't required to find in-depth research on niche/specialized topics in high school. But it remains that those skills have to be trained prior to post-secondary matriculation. 

There's perhaps a larger point to be made about the failures of standardized education. Some students don't need research training, yet they'll have to put up with it because we use the education system as a uniform safety net that never accounts for individual interests or drives. 

Keep in mind that for a lot of high school students, this is it. Past that their education will either be vocational, personal, or nonexistent. I don't disagree that it may be more beneficial to give certain students some latitude when it comes to what mediums they source from, but to say these skills can't deteriorate or are easy to maintain is to make a somewhat self-centered assumption. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
