<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30105652694.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>People that discriminate against religious groups often don't think that religious individuals can change their religion. Antisemitism for example often has little to do with actual belief and more to do with racial and cultural background.  Anti-islam sentiment is often similar with hate groups saying things like "you can't trust that a middle easterner isn't really Islamic because true apostates are killed in Islam." 

In other words, there is some pretty complex historical hate here that goes well beyond simply professing your belief in something. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105700315.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t see how this doesn’t also apply to politics. Regardless of the reasons why someone might be anti-Semitic we don’t allow discrimination against Jews. It doesn’t matter if they hate their culture or if they hate their religion, it’s all illegal. 

I think that there are a lot of people who discriminate in a similar way against people with different political beliefs. Half the time it seems that the hate isn’t based on the belief itself, it’s based on a distain for “idiotic backwards redneck culture” or “snooty whiny entitled liberal brats”. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105778494.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I hesitate here because politics really isn't a black and white issue. People can have conservative or liberal beliefs or beliefs that don't really fall under either category. In fact, when you look at most people actual beliefs that tend to fall across both sides of the aisle. I'm not even sure who exactly we would be protecting here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105879751.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it shouldn’t really matter if people fall into multiple camps. I’m not just talking about political parties but also political beliefs. Not necessarily “you’re a republican, get out” but it could be more specific such as “you’re pro-life, get out”. Political disagreement shouldn’t be a valid reason to fire someone. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105981566.0" user="F0rScience" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is that the discrimination based on politics/culture that you describe are actual behaviors.  You cant fault someone for discriminating based on actual actions someone else has taken that bother them in some way.  Eg. its not unreasonable to say "you act like X and therefore I don't want to hire you", even if that behavior is inherited from ones parents, its still their choice to continue it.  Nobody is discriminating because your parents are rednecks, its because you are.  

Religion on the other hand is often based entirely on family regardless of a persons beliefs, particularly for Jews and other minority religions.  This can get as extreme as cases where people killed by Nazis didn't even know they were Jewish (largely due to a high level of integration into German culture).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106067469.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Well of course you can discriminate based on an action, but I’m talking about beliefs here - not actions. There’s nothing wrong with being pro-life or pro-choice as far as your work quality is concerned, but you could still get fired for it if your boss found out and had a different opinion. 

Additionally, religion is **not** based entirely on family and I’m not sure why you are saying otherwise. Many, many people leave or switch religions in their lifetime to be something different than their family. I have a few friends who used to be Mormon but have left the church for example. Their families are still Mormon. The Jews that you’re referring to in Germany must have been ethnically Jewish but not religiously Jewish. That’s a different thing since that would fall into the category of race. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
