<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106711440.0" user="EmptyHearse" delta="False">
    <text>I think your question boils down to whether we should tolerate intolerance. And since most of the examples you've used to challenge arguments given here have been centered on Nazi's, I'm comfortable using that genre of ideology as an example for my case. A philosopher by the name of Karl Popper described this paradox of tolerance such that if a society is tolerant without limit it will self destruct, because intolerance will be allowed to fester to the point where it stamps out tolerance altogether. So in order to preserve tolerance, we must be allowed - even obligated - to not tolerate intolerance. You might be right that there is an ideological inconsistency there, but it's one that is actually necessary to preserve the status quo. So applying this to anti-discrimination laws... one could argue that we have an obligation to deliberately stamp out ideologies based on intolerance, and among the gentler ways of doing that is applying social pressure. If you're not being served somewhere because you're wearing a swastika, maybe you don't wear one anymore. If you could lose your job for being discovered attending a white supremacy rally, maybe you stop going. It might not eradicate the ideology, but at least it keeps it from getting out of control. If instead we legislate mandatory "acceptance" (anti-discrimination policies) of intolerant ideologies, they are allowed to fester and grow. Maybe not to the point of eradicating tolerance altogether, but at the very least to the point of increased danger to already threatened minorities. And armchair philosophy aside, if for no other reason than that - that some of these ideologies deliberately beget violence against already vulnerable classes of people - they should not be protected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106749327.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I’ve spent quite a bit of time discussing Popper’s “paradox of intolerance” and I’ve come to a pretty firm conclusion that it doesn’t make any sense. 

I think that the evidence for this is fairly obvious - Nazis have been allowed to assemble, rally, protest, and vote for decades now. They have been tolerated for years and years. And yet, they’re not even close to “taking over and stamping out tolerance” as Popper suggests. Popper claims that if we allow intolerance then it will “inevitably take over” but I do not think that is true. There is no evidence that this is an inevitability, and I think that the real world serves as very strong evidence that this is **not** an inevitability. 

As to your final sentence, that all applies to religion as well. There are religions that advocate violence against gay people, for example. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107043519.0" user="EmptyHearse" delta="False">
    <text>Popper's paradox is mostly just a thought experiment (because it's very hard to find an example of a society with truly limitless tolerance) but I think it's meant to illustrate that societies and people have an obligation to protect themselves from intolerance and that there's a point of diminishing returns when it comes to ideological purity. It's like a society of pacifists under threat of invasion - sure, they can refuse to fight and thus retain their moral purity, but at what cost? 

As to evidence... consider the rise in white supremacism and Nazi violence post-2016, when a voice and a face with a position of power was given to their hatred. That's a step. There's no benefit to tolerating intolerance for the sake of ideological consistency, especially when people's lives are on the line. Moreover, it makes no sense for an ideology based on hatred and discrimination and intolerance to claim protection in the name of tolerance, and even less sense to give it that protection when we don't have to.

Yes... And we are bombing a fair few of them. The most radical elements of religions across the globe are subject to the consequences of their ideology. Why should our own ideologies of hatred be treated differently?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108606780.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's like a society of pacifists under threat of invasion - sure, they can refuse to fight and thus retain their moral purity, but at what cost? 

Not really because in this example if the pacifists don’t fight then of course the invasion will take over. With Nazis it’s perfectly possible to tolerate them and allow them to live in peace while also completely rejecting their views. I mean, what exactly are you even suggesting here? That we ban Nazi thoughts? Good luck with that. That we reject their ideas? Almost everyone does that already. What would being intolerant of Nazis look like to you?

&amp;gt; As to evidence... consider the rise in white supremacism and Nazi violence post-2016, when a voice and a face with a position of power was given to their hatred. That's a step. 

Yeah, now instead of 1000 Nazis in a country of 300,000,000 we have 1500 Nazis. You’ll have to excuse me if I don’t drop everything to run and grab my rifle and helmet. 

&amp;gt; There's no benefit to tolerating intolerance for the sake of ideological consistency, especially when people's lives are on the line. Moreover, it makes no sense for an ideology based on hatred and discrimination and intolerance to claim protection in the name of tolerance, and even less sense to give it that protection when we don't have to.

Again, this doesn’t mean anything until you define what intolerance of Nazis would be. Are you saying we should round them up and put them in concentration camps? I have no idea what you are calling for here. 

&amp;gt; Why should our own ideologies of hatred be treated differently?

Really? That’s exactly what I’m saying in this CMV!! The **WHOLE POINT** of this CMV is that I think political ideologies and religious ideologies should be treated the same as far as protected classes are concerned. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109831514.0" user="EmptyHearse" delta="False">
    <text>All I'm saying is that if the consequences of an ideology based on intolerance and hatred is a certain amount of social exclusion, then so be it. If almost everyone already hates Nazis, then don't protect them from discrimination under the law. Don't arrest them for it, or round them all up or anything, just let people say "no, I don't want you to work here" or "no, I'm going to refuse you service."

We've drifted off topic though. I started with an argument for why we shouldn't accede the same rights of protection to a political ideology as we do to race, religion, creed, etc. It hasn't changed your view, so that's it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107389990.0" user="IdolKek" delta="False">
    <text>But here’s the thing. I think the left has a huge blind spot towards many reasonable people who have different ideas and different solutions than the left. The description of non-lefties as nazis or intolerant is, in many cases, extraordinarily wrong... and convenient. It’s demonizing and discrediting an opponent before taking any time to understanding that someone might actually share a lot of the same essential values... but have a different path to getting there. But the penalty to drifting from leftist orthodoxy is total pariah status these days.  Honestly, I left the left a couple of years ago because they seem as intolerant and fascist as anything I ever thought could be possible in my lifetime.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109855119.0" user="EmptyHearse" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah... the left does have a lot of weaknesses and blindspots, not the least of which is an almost puritanically zealous streak and a "if you're not with us, you're against us" mentality. That being said, I think it's safe to say that most people most places on the political spectrum reserve the word Nazi or neo-Nazi for actual white supremacists, rather than tossing it toward anyone who disagrees with them.

But you're right - demonizing your opponent has become a rich vein of political capital that both sides have been mining for years. On the right, people will even vote against their own well-being even if for no other reason than to fight back against the evil liberals. It's bred so much contempt into our system (on both sides) that cooperation and compromise has become almost impossible, which - in case we forgot - is how democracy is supposed to work.

But... my argument wasn't necessarily from a left-wing point of view (like you, I've distanced myself from that extreme recently). Intolerance on the left is also a problem, and shouldn't be tolerated. Nazi's were just the example I used given OP's context.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
