<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107427070.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign.

In the US, political affiliation is loose and not particularly official. You cannot be born with a political affiliation. You choose one when you are old enough to vote, and it is always a choice you make as an adult. Your decision may be influenced by your family, culture, upbringing, etc., but it is EXPLICITLY an age of majority decision that you make.

Religion is not the same. When you hang a sign that says "No Muslims allowed," what do you mean by that? It's impossible to say, really. There are plenty of people who were born and almost immediately underwent some religious ritual or another to join a faith that they do not practice or practice loosely. There are others who have converted to a faith. And there are still others who were born into a faith tradition and just continued to practice it as part of their heritage, culture, etc. So when your sign says, NO MUSLIMS ALLOWED, does that cover all of those people? Some of them? Only the ones who still attend mosque? How will you know? Who decides who is "Muslim enough" to fail your NO MUSLIMS test?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108636024.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>In this hypothetical world where this was legal, the answer to all of these questions is the business owner who hung up the sign. They are the one who gets to decide how Muslim is Muslim enough. They get to decide who counts. The whole point of this is the idea that the business owner should be allowed to choose who to serve and who not to serve, so all of those decisions are up to the business owner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109089971.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>The point of my post (ie: the primary difference between religion and political affiliation) just sailed right over your head.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109211310.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>No, I get what you’re saying, I just don’t see how it’s a meaningful distinction. 

In your earlier post you said 

&amp;gt; Religion is not the same. When you hang a sign that says "No Muslims allowed," what do you mean by that? It's impossible to say, really. 

It’s not impossible. I’m the one who hung the sign. I know exactly what I meant by that. Just like if I hung a “no Republicans” sign I would know exactly what I meant by that as well. In this situation it’s the business owner who is making the decisions as to what constitutes a republican, a Muslim, a Jew, or a Democrat. They are the one making the decision so whatever criteria they care about is the criteria that matters. 

Sure, *other* people might not know exactly what I mean, but that doesn’t matter because in this situation they aren’t making the rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109487081.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>I'll spell it out for you.

Let's pretend I was born to a family of Muslims. I was raised Muslim, attended mosque, prayed, etc. Then I went off to college and said, "Fuck religion. I am an atheist." Depending on how you define "Muslim," I am still Muslim, even after renouncing. This is how Nazis ended up spending several meetings trying to figure out how Jewish was Jewish enough to warrant repatriation, fewer rights, gas chambers, etc. Plenty of Jews died in concentration camps who had only a distant relationship with the Torah. Because it was a decision made long before they were born, one they had no control over, because of the identity of their parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109640684.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Well yeah and depending on how you define “turkey sandwich” I drive a turkey sandwich to work every day. Fortunately, both “turkey sandwich” and “Muslim” have well understood definitions so there shouldn’t be much confusion. A Muslim is a person who follows the Islamic faith. If you say “fuck religion” and stop following the Islamic faith, then you are not a Muslim anymore. 

And if in your scenario you walked up to a business that said “No Muslims” on the door, then you should be able to enter with no problems. If the owner sees you and thinks you’re a Muslim and tells you to leave, you can explain that you aren’t a Muslim. If they won’t listen to you and they tell you to leave anyway, well that sucks but at this point they’re not discriminating based on your religion. At this point they are probably discriminating based on race, and if that’s still a protected class in this scenario then they could be in legal trouble on those grounds. 

And this is exactly how things are right now with politics. If I walked up to a store that said “No Republicans” on it wearing camo and chewing tobacco, but I happened to be a Democrat, then I might go through something similar. 

You still have not demonstrated any meaningful difference. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109734250.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If they won’t listen to you and they tell you to leave anyway, well that sucks but at this point they’re not discriminating based on your religion.

They won't listen to you and still believe you are a Muslim but aren't discriminating based on religion? That's an interesting definition.

Good luck with your CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109793937.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Probably not though. Picture two men who walk into the store. One is white and is wearing jeans and a hoodie. The other is Arabic, has a big beard, and is wearing a white robe with sandals. Both these men claim that they are not Muslim. I think that if the store owner was the kind of person who might challenge a person’s claims about their beliefs, then they’re probably the kind of person who would believe that the white guy isn’t Muslim and doubt that the Arabic guy isn’t Muslim. That would most likely be based on the fact that they’re Arabic in the first place, thus making it a racially motivated assumption. That’s now racial discrimination, not religious discrimination. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
