<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107903614.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I think I disagree with this. Politically, I tend to be socially liberal and fiscally conservative. In the last election, I probably would have voted for a "normal" republican like Kasich (though not now, after what's changed in Ohio) over a far-left democrat like Sanders. But I would prefer a "normal" democrat over an [insert adjective here] like Trump.

On paper, that would look like my political affiliation changing overnight, so unless there is a better way to define politics that won't change as quickly, I don't think that political beliefs are as base to a person as religious ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108720896.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>But your beliefs didn’t change, the person you voted for changed. That might have made it appear as though your political party changed but it didn’t really. 

What I mostly meant is this - people who are pro-choice don’t just wake up one day and decide to be pro-life. If there even is a change, it’s always very gradual. And even that is difficult for most people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108752761.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But your beliefs didn’t change, the person you voted for changed. That might have made it appear as though your political party changed but it didn’t really.

Right, agreed - *I* didn't really change, but from the outside it would look like I did. If I could *appear* to be a democrat one day and a republican the next, how would the protected class be defined?

Is it discrimination against me if a restaurant had a "no republicans" sign on the door, but I most recently voted for a democrat?

The other protected classes have more clear divisions - I won't appear jewish one day and muslim the next when my beliefs never actually changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108764504.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I could *appear* to be a democrat one day and a republican the next, how would the protected class be defined?

The protected class would just be political beliefs, i.e. you can’t fire some for being a republican or a Democrat so it doesn’t matter which one you are. 

&amp;gt; Is it discrimination against me if a restaurant had a "no republicans" sign on the door, but I most recently voted for a democrat?

That would be for the store owner to decide, they’re the one making the rule after all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108811426.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>I am not sure I know the answer to this, but how would protected classes work if *literally everyone* is in a protected class?

Aren't protected classes currently designed to add special protection for people in minority and/or at-risk populations? If we add *anyone with any political belief* into those classes, does that diminish the protection for anyone else?

&amp;gt; you can’t fire some for being a republican or a Democrat so it doesn’t matter which one you are.

Isn't that the case currently? I can't be fired because my favorite color is blue, but color preference isn't a protected class.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109160448.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am not sure I know the answer to this, but how would protected classes work if *literally everyone* is in a protected class?

The same way they work right now. Race and gender are both protected classes. Everyone has a race and everyone has a gender. All it means to be a protected class is that you can’t discriminate based on that specific trait. I agree that the terminology is kind of weird because it makes it sound like only members of some “class” are protected. I don’t really care for the term either but that’s how things are. 

&amp;gt; Aren't protected classes currently designed to add special protection for people in minority and/or at-risk populations? If we add *anyone with any political belief* into those classes, does that diminish the protection for anyone else?

They are designed with that in mind but they can’t specify particular races because that would be, well, racist. If black people are being discriminated against, they don’t say “it’s illegal to discriminate against blacks people”. Instead they say “it’s illegal to discriminate based on race”. 

&amp;gt; Isn't that the case currently? I can't be fired because my favorite color is blue, but color preference isn't a protected class.

You can totally be fired because your favorite color is blue in most states in America. You can be fired for no reason at all in those states! There are only a few reasons that you can not fire someone, and those reasons are the things covered by protected classes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109185656.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The same way they work right now. Race and gender are both protected classes.

Good call, I'm dumb. I thought of them as protecting *minorities*, but that's not how it actually is. Thank you for the correction.

&amp;gt; You can totally be fired because your favorite color is blue in most states in America. You can be fired for no reason at all in those states! There are only a few reasons that you can not fire someone, and those reasons are the things covered by protected classes.

Thank you again for the correction</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
