<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30105762396.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Religion can be chosen, yes, but SHOULD PEOPLE have to choose a particular religion in order to avoid being persecuted?

Also, religion is a stand-in for many things. I know several Jews... Each has a very distinct set of beliefs about god. All are subject to antisemitism, and that isn't related to those beliefs. My atheist Jewish friend can still get fired for being a jew.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105811351.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Religion can be chosen, yes, but SHOULD PEOPLE have to choose a particular religion in order to avoid being persecuted?

No. People also shouldn’t have to choose a particular political party in order to avoid being persecuted. But, it seems that that’s exactly what some people are forced to do if their employer disagrees with them politically. Although someone else informed me that in California this is illegal. 

I do think it should be illegal at the federal level though. At least, if we’re making religious discrimination illegal at the federal level then it should be. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105882565.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>What kind of political disagreement are we talking about, here? 

Also, what about the Jewish example?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105938932.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Something like a conservative boss learning that their employee is a Democrat and then firing them for it, or a pro-choice boss learning that their employee is pro-life and then firing them for it. Or something like a business refusing someone service because they were wearing a MAGA hat. 

As for the Jewish example, I need to make sure that I follow you. “Atheist Jew” sounds like an oxymoron to me. Do you just mean that your friend is atheist in their beliefs but ethnically Jewish? If so, then I believe that would fall under the category of race and therefore your friend shouldn’t be able to be fired for being Jewish (although there are certainly employers who break these laws). In theory though they shouldn’t be</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106325980.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Something like a conservative boss learning that their employee is a Democrat and then firing them for it, or a pro-choice boss learning that their employee is pro-life and then firing them for it. Or something like a business refusing someone service because they were wearing a MAGA hat.

Doesn't this slippery-slope pretty badly?  Should people be allowed to deny service to someone who doesn't like the same band as them?  Or doesn't have the same favorite color?

&amp;gt; As for the Jewish example, I need to make sure that I follow you. “Atheist Jew” sounds like an oxymoron to me. Do you just mean that your friend is atheist in their beliefs but ethnically Jewish? 

Culturally Jewish.

I worry you have a very unsophisticated idea of religion.  I personally know several people who always recite the blessings on Shabbat, but they don't believe in God. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106470534.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it *does* slippery slope pretty bad doesn’t it? So does religion, and that’s exactly why I personally don’t like the idea of religion as a protected class to begin with. Trust me, I’m not arguing that political beliefs should be a protected class - I actually believe the opposite of that. I also believe that religion shouldn’t be one either. 

My point though isn’t about what each one should or shouldn’t be, my point is that regardless of what we decide they are, they should be the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108362878.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>You keep not talking about the Jewish example, which confuses me a little.  That serves as an example of why religion is different from politics in a specific way, and so it doesn't slippery-slope.

Also, there just historically hasn't been a slippery slope with religious beliefs.  We don't have a huge amount of successful lawsuits for people claiming ridiculous behaviors should be protected because they're 'religious.'

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108749512.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn’t talking about it because I don’t really get what your point is. Ok, so he’s culturally Jewish but he could face antisemitism.... ok? So what? If that’s the case then he isn’t being persecuted for his religious beliefs, he would be persecuted for his culture, which would fall more into the category of race and therefore doesn’t factor into this discussion. If you clarify what you mean I’d be happy to talk about it. 

And ok, so does it slippery slope or does it not slippery slope? If we can prevent ridiculous behavior based on claims of religion then why shouldn’t we be able to prevent ridiculous behavior based on claims of politics? You’re saying that political protections would slippery slope. Then I point out that religion can also slippery slope and you say “well that’s different because we can prevent ridiculous stuff in that case”....... ok? Well why can’t we do the same for political protection?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109272711.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  If that’s the case then he isn’t being persecuted for his religious beliefs, he would be persecuted for his culture, which would fall more into the category of race and therefore doesn’t factor into this discussion. If you clarify what you mean I’d be happy to talk about it.

Whoa, wait, culture is race now?  That's... going to be a difficult position to defend.  There's a whole lot of cultures out there.  

Frankly, no one is worried very much about people being discriminated against because of their religious *beliefs*.  It's not NOT there, but it's minor compared to the extent people are worried about people being discriminated against because of their religious *identities*.  

We're worried about "Catholics need not apply" signs.  We're not super worried about "Whoa wait, you fast on Lent, so I'm going to fire you." 

&amp;gt; Well why can’t we do the same for political protection?

I mean, presumably because you agree with me that protection for political protection is silly, so of course I wouldn't argue in favor of that; you already agree.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109610883.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I do think it’s silly, but I also think that religious protection is silly. I still see no distinction. Both religions and politics have cultures that people could discriminate against. Your culturally Jewish friend is a religious example, and I would call ‘redneck’ culture a political example. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30110307590.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, are you saying 'redneck' is a race?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112086514.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>No, a culture. 

Look, you can’t use “Jewish” interchangeably for a religion, a culture, and a race. You’ve got to pick one and stick with it. I thought we had  agreed on using it to refer to the culture. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30114987439.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>You yourself said 'culture' was like 'race,' which is why it was worthy of protection.  That is a very difficult view to defend.

Frankly, if you have a difficult time wrapping your head around the fact that someone can follow Jewish rituals without believing the Torah is literally true or believing in God, then frankly, you have a very limited and unsophisticated idea of what 'religion' means (clearly overly influenced by protestant christianity).  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30118134894.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Culture is related to race but it isn’t exactly the same thing. I think you’re referring to when I said 

&amp;gt; he would be persecuted for his culture, which would fall more into the category of race and therefore doesn’t factor into this discussion

What I meant is that race and culture tend to go hand in hand. If, for example, someone hung a sign up on their restaurant that said “no one who is into black culture allowed”, that would pretty quickly get shot down in the courts because it’s essentially the same as saying “no black people allowed”. Not because culture and race are identical, but because there’s lots of overlap between members of a culture and members of a race. There is, essentially, no good way to tell if someone was discriminating against someone for their race or for their culture. On the outside it would look the same. 

And anyway, of course I understand that you can participate in rituals without truly believing. I’ve done that myself before. I still don’t see why this matters. People do the same thing with politics all the time, they pretend to have certain beliefs but actually believe something else. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
