<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106434355.0" user="sexyjeremypharoahwiz" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is that too many people believe in politics religiously now.  There's no mixing and matching with what you believe, it's flat "I believe 100% everything the Dems/Reps say."  Their political party has become their religion rather than it being something that you would pick and mix from to represent your personal viewpoints.  Before this huge political polarization, most people would be conservative on some issues, progressive on others.  Most people likely still behave this way.  The increasing polarization of the parties has led people to extreme divisiveness, hatred, and even violence similar to race/religious brawls of the past.  The issue isn't that Religion needs to no longer be a protected class nor that Politics should be a protected class it's that people are believing in politics religiously rather than politically.  Not everything the Dems or the Reps believe is 100% correct all of the time and placing the same kind of blind faith in it that one would in a higher power is a major problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106513706.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Well sure, but I’m applying this even to specific beliefs, not just political labels. Like, for example, a business could refuse to hire anyone who is pro-life or pro-choice. That isn’t going to be solved with less polarization because it’s a specific belief, not just a vague umbrella for some collection of beliefs. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
