<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30105682579.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>When we are deciding what classes of people to protect, we want to make those classes as few and focused as possible while achieving the goal of avoiding the worst discrimination.  It's extremely important to prevent racism, a cancer that has done significant damage to this country and the world; banning racial discrimination makes sense.  Discrimination on the basis of veteran status has no such history.  We would lose little by ending the laws protecting veterans, and would be fools to tweak the rule on veteran status discrimination to also prevent discrimination against non-veterans.

When it comes to religion, the history of violence and hatred directed at minority religions speaks for itself.  If we want to keep our country welcoming to all faiths, we need to be proactive in terms of banning bigotry based on creed.  When it comes to politics, we don't really have the same kind of history.  I mean, not zero - there's that wacko who shot up a Republican softball team and there's that McCarthy guy a half century ago, but we're just not facing tremendous politically-based discrimination.  If we do see more, that should be judged on its own merits.  There is no need to unify it with religion given that the two forms of discrimination don't go hand in hand, don't involve the same perpetrators, and don't target the same people.  

I don't see what "unable to change" has to do with anything.  There are many things people cannot change that are legitimate to discriminate against.  The important question isn't being "logically consistent" in some kind of broad philosophical sense, but in protecting those who really need it while allowing freedom when it's not super necessary to offer protection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105735958.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>We currently have multiple groups in America advocating violence based on political beliefs. There have been several recent situations where a high-profile person has lost their job for their beliefs, and for every high-profile case we hear about there are probably many more that we don’t. Political polarization is the worst it’s ever been in this country, and it continues to grow worse. 

These things are also doing significant damage to the country and to the world.

If we need to be proactive in preventing religious discrimination as you say, then why not be proactive for political discrimination as well? Why must we wait until the problem is already happening before we try to solve it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105811740.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We currently have multiple groups in America advocating violence based on political beliefs

Agreed.

&amp;gt;There have been several recent situations where a high-profile person has lost their job for their beliefs, and for every high-profile case we hear about there are probably many more that we don’t

Agreed.  I believe there are probably at least a few dozen people every year who lose their job primarily due to their political beliefs.  If it were an order of magnitude or two worse than this, I'd advocate for making political beliefs a protected class.  But on its own merits, not tied to religious protections.

&amp;gt;Political polarization is the worst it’s ever been in this country

Well, the worst it's been since the end of WWII.

&amp;gt;If we need to be proactive in preventing religious discrimination as you say, then why not be proactive for political discrimination as well? Why must we wait until the problem is already happening before we try to solve it?

No, I mean we have to be proactive in terms of preventing religious discrimination from rising *again* given its tremendous damage the last few dozen times we've seen it (most notably in Nazi Germany, but far from confined to there).  Political discrimination I'd wait and see it get bad before adopting a policy of "we now have to be proactive from now on about political discrimination".  Because we need to balance the need to prevent horrific political discrimination against the tremendous benefits of liberty and the right of people to associate the way they want (for instance the benefits of not being forced by the government to treat neo-Nazis the same way we treat immigration advocates).

Or if things really do get so bad that it's worth giving up my right not to have my children taught by vocal NAMBLA advocates, very well, but there's no reason the terms of that would have to be identical to the religious tolerance we try to extend to Atheists, Pentecostals, Jews, etc.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105925459.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I’m surprised you think it’s only a few dozen. I would guess it’s much much higher than this, although it would be hard to find good sources since it’s pretty easy to lie about why you fired someone. But only a few dozen? I would guess that more than a few dozen people lose their job because of their race and that’s already illegal! 

As to your point about personal liberty, I agree, but I actually take it even farther. Personally, I dislike the concept of protected classes in general because I believe very strongly in personal liberty. People absolutely should have the freedom to choose who they associate with. However, if we’re going to have protected classes then we at least should be consistent with them. Right now it seems to me that the list of protected classes was slapped together without much thought. 

It can’t be that the list is based on who has been historically discriminated against because as you said, this doesn’t really apply to veterans. It can’t be that the list is based on traits that people are unable to change because religion is changeable. It can’t be based on traits that are core to one’s identity because then political affiliation should be on the list. So what is it based on? There seems to be no rhyme or reason behind which traits are and aren’t on the list. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105969655.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I’m surprised you think it’s only a few dozen

Well, it's pretty easy to hide your political beliefs and I think most people do.  This (incidentally) is another key reason that banning religious discrimination isn't like banning political discrimination.  If you have a little less political talk at work, then work is the better for it - not everyone needs to know my beliefs about the estate tax.  Whereas if people try to hide their religion that can mean hiding big life moments like births and weddings and holidays.

&amp;gt;People absolutely should have the freedom to choose who they associate with. However, if we’re going to have protected classes then we at least should be consistent with them.

Well, why not just be consistent with "as little as needed to protect highly vulnerable groups from organized conspiracies against them"?  That means race and religion.  And then work to eliminate the stupid ones like veteran status, age, genetic information, citizenship, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106053289.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>It isn’t hard to not talk about religion at work. Atheists give birth, get married, and celebrate holidays. There isn’t much about those things that’s inherently tied to religion except maybe a few holidays. And if that’s the case, just don’t mention those. Yes, it might mean that you have to hide something at work. But, for example, I bet that a lot of Trump supporters felt like they had to hide their feelings at work the day after he got elected. And I bet that many Hilary supporters did too. Once again, I don’t see much of a difference here.

&amp;gt; as little as needed to protect highly vulnerable groups

Ok, I see what you’re saying, but this sounds like it’s your idea on how things should be and it’s completely different than what the government seems to think. That’s ok, but it doesn’t really make me feel that the protected class system makes any more sense. 

And regardless, who gets to decide which groups are “highly vulnerable”. I’m going to make a pretty extreme example of what I mean. 

Who is to say that Nazis shouldn’t be a protected class under this definition? Many, many people absolutely despise Nazis. They hate them. Many want them dead. There are huge portions of the population who would refuse to associate with someone if they learned that they are a Nazi. To me, that sounds pretty vulnerable. 

Now, you and I both know that making Nazis a protected class doesn’t make much sense. But do you see where I’m coming from? Most of what I said about Nazis could be said about Jews a few decades ago. Jews throughout history have been despised, hated, wished death upon, and have had people refuse to associate with them. By all those qualities, most would say that makes Jews highly vulnerable. So why is that not true for Nazis?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106394407.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Atheists give birth, get married, and celebrate holidays.

Sure, but if you can't go to someone's sealing because you aren't a Mormon like them that's a thing.  If you celebrate the birth eight days later that's a thing.  If you don't celebrate Christmas or birthdays, that's a thing.  Atheists stand out less in a predominantly-Christian society than members of certain religions do.

&amp;gt;Once again, I don’t see much of a difference here.

You don't see a difference between "I'm not going to tell you how I feel about a contentious election" and "I'm not going to come in this Wednesday and can never work Saturdays and I have to use a fake name"?

&amp;gt;completely different than what the government seems to think.

Not crazy different.  I mean, the only strongly protected classes are race, gender, and religion, and even there the government is pretty weak on gender compared to the others (I mean you can get away with separate bathrooms for men/women but never for black/white).  The other "categories" are not really protected even remotely the same way.  We have to avoid policies that disproportionately affect minority races even if there's no explicit discrimination; the same doesn't apply to national origin/citizenship/veteran/age/etc because those are very weakly protected.  And the "protection" of citizenship status isn't really an individual right so much as the Federal government flexing it's muscle - it can impose discriminatory laws against non-citizens at will, just others can't.  

&amp;gt;And regardless, who gets to decide which groups are “highly vulnerable”

Congress does, they can add or subtract groups at will.  Except religion which gets some of its protections explicitly via the Constitution and race which is obviously what was meant by the 14th Amendment.

&amp;gt;Who is to say that Nazis shouldn’t be a protected class under this definition? Many, many people absolutely despise Nazis. They hate them. Many want them dead. There are huge portions of the population who would refuse to associate with someone if they learned that they are a Nazi. To me, that sounds pretty vulnerable.

In theory maybe.  But in practice ~0 Nazis are killed per year for their beliefs.  ~0 non-Nazis are beaten or boycotted for having sold goods to Nazis.  Really wouldn't qualify even if not for the fact that Nazis aren't worthy of protection or respect and shouldn't be protected even if they "met criteria".  (There's no Constitutional issue about the government picking and choosing ideologies).   But like I said, nobody's actually persecuting Nazis even though we should have the right to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106506635.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You don't see a difference between "I'm not going to tell you how I feel about a contentious election" and "I'm not going to come in this Wednesday and can never work Saturdays and I have to use a fake name"?

Not really. If you can’t work certain days you can just tell them that when you’re hired - no need to specify that it’s for religious reasons. I don’t know what you mean about the name, any person with any name can be any religion, there are no name requirements. 

&amp;gt; Congress does, they can add or subtract groups at will.  Except religion which gets some of its protections explicitly via the Constitution and race which is obviously what was meant by the 14th Amendment.

Well duh, I know that. This whole CMV is based on the fact that I think congress chose wrong. Once again, I think that by any definition of the world ‘vulnerable’ where you might say “Muslims are vulnerable” you could just as easily say “Nazis are vulnerable”. In fact I would argue that Nazis are even more vulnerable than Muslims seeing as how 99% of the country despised them. If your response is “well they brought that on themselves by being Nazis”, I could just as easily respond by saying “Muslims brought it on themselves by being Muslim”. 

&amp;gt; In theory maybe.  But in practice ~0 Nazis are killed per year for their beliefs.  ~0 non-Nazis are beaten or boycotted for having sold goods to Nazis. 

No, but plenty of Nazis lose their job every year for being Nazis, and that’s one of the things that protected classes are specifically supposed to help out with! If Muslims were being fired for being Muslim it wouldn’t matter whether people were actually killing them or not, you would still say they’re being persecuted. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106559595.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Not really. If you can’t work certain days you can just tell them that when you’re hired - no need to specify that it’s for religious reasons

Yeah, if you put in your contract you couldn't work Saturdays any year and September 19 this year and October 9 next year (along with a bunch of the other ones) you think they can't figure out you're Jewish.  Or if your name is Bob Cohen, you're Jewish even if you've formally converted to Catholicism, doesn't matter.  Discrimination based on religion isn't really very different from discrimination based on race, and it's hard to hide certain faiths (or even to leave certain faiths for the purpose of avoiding discrimination).

&amp;gt;In fact I would argue that Nazis are even more vulnerable than Muslims seeing as how 99% of the country despised them

And yet anti-Muslim violence and anti-Muslim conspiracies are *much* more common than anti-Nazi violence and conspiracies.

&amp;gt;No, but plenty of Nazis lose their job every year for being Nazis, and that’s one of the things that protected classes are specifically supposed to help out with! If Muslims were being fired for being Muslim it wouldn’t matter whether people were actually killing them or not, you would still say they’re being persecuted.

No, the whole point of preventing workplace discrimination is a hedge against actual violence and actual conspiracies to refuse to hire/rent to/sell to/interact with a certain group.  If it really were just permanently limited to certain religious groups facing a little employment discrimination (like a few Nazis do, but not "plenty" of them because they can keep their mouth shut and be assumed non-Nazi) then we wouldn't need these laws.  The issue is that (unlike political positions) race/religion is genuinely a fault line on which society cracks.  Where you get shootings and mosque bombings and conspiracies to prevent people of a certain group from living in a certain area with punishments for defectors who rent/sell/etc to them and soup kitchens that deliberately only serve pork soup etc.  That's actually a real threat to society, and if it goes away we can get rid of the race/religion protections but it isn't going away any time soon.  Whereas if political divisions worsen a lot we can consider protecting them, but right now the worst thing we see is people being fired for opening their mouths which isn't nearly bad enough to justify the strong medicine of anti-discrimination laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106606432.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Or if your name is Bob Cohen, you're Jewish even if you've formally converted to Catholicism, doesn't matter. 

No, your employer just *thinks* you’re Jewish. This is no different than an employers assuming you’re republican because you drive a big lifted truck to work. My point is, yes if the employer really wanted to they could probably figure out what religion you are, but they could do the same for your political beliefs. 

&amp;gt; And yet anti-Muslim violence and anti-Muslim conspiracies are *much* more common than anti-Nazi violence and conspiracies.

Probably because there are millions of openly Muslim individuals in America but there are like 1000 people who are openly Nazis. Additionally, Nazis are extremely hated so violence against them doesn’t cause much outrage. Richard Spencer got punched live on camera and people still haven’t stopped cheering. If Muslim leaders were getting punched live on camera in the middle of an interview, wouldn’t you point to that as evidence that they are a vulnerable group?

&amp;amp;gt;No, but plenty of Nazis lose their job every year for being Nazis, and that’s one of the things that protected classes are specifically supposed to help out with! If Muslims were being fired for being Muslim it wouldn’t matter whether people were actually killing them or not, you would still say they’re being persecuted.

&amp;gt; Whereas if political divisions worsen a lot we can consider protecting them, but right now the worst thing we see is people being fired for opening their mouths which isn't nearly bad enough to justify the strong medicine of anti-discrimination laws.

This is circular logic. Let me illustrate the circle. 

1. Political beliefs are not a protected class
2. Since political beliefs are not a protected class, people can be fired for opening their mouth
3. Since people can be fired for opening their mouth, most people don’t open their mouth
4. Since most people don’t open their mouth, not many people get fired
5. Since not many people get fired, we don’t need to worry about making political beliefs a protected class

The same thing would apply to religion. If you could be fired for your religion people would try harder to hide their religion, and most of them would succeed. That would reduce the number of people fired for their religion to a pretty low number. And therefore, by your logic, since not that many people are getting fired it isn’t a problem that religion isn’t a protected class. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107701791.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is circular logic.

No, it's an appeal to history/evidence.

&amp;gt;The same thing would apply to religion. If you could be fired for your religion people would try harder to hide their religion, and most of them would succeed.

Except historically that's not what happened.  Jews who tried to hide their religion in Nazi Germany were still exterminated. Muslim slaves in US plantations who hid their Islam found that their grandchildren were Christian.  More recently, Christians and Animists and Yezidis have been slaughtered and raped for their faith even when they've tried to hide it from fanatics.  

The thing is, we know how bad religious and racial persecution can get under varying circumstances: really really bad as a result of spontaneous mass movements (often aided by the government but not necessarily originating with government).  We also know how bad persecution based on political beliefs can get: terrible when it's top-down political repression by the government, but meh when it's a spontaneous mass movement.  

Let me be super clear: the reason I would make the government force people to hire a group they hate is *not* "hey, you aren't hiring that group if we don't make you".  It's "hey, we're worried there's about to be massive oppression in the form of violence and boycotts and refusal to sell houses to them and passing laws restricting their movements, etc" a la Jim Crow.  Preventing that kind of violence is the big deal that needs the strong medicine of government-enforced integration.  We just haven't seen that kind of violence directed against political beliefs and don't seem anywhere close to it.  If we do get close to it (say, the divisions we saw during the founding between Tories and Patriots) then there would be a case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108677183.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Except historically that's not what happened.  Jews who tried to hide their religion in Nazi Germany were still exterminated. Muslim slaves in US plantations who hid their Islam found that their grandchildren were Christian.  More recently, Christians and Animists and Yezidis have been slaughtered and raped for their faith even when they've tried to hide it from fanatics.  

Well of course that’s how it looks when you choose examples that went that way. How many Jews survived the holocaust because they successfully hid their Jewish heritage? Well they probably weren’t out parading that fact around in the streets so we really have no clue. That’s the thing about hiding stuff, we only really find out when they fail to hide it. When they successfully hide their religion, we never hear about it. 

&amp;gt; Preventing that kind of violence is the big deal that needs the strong medicine of government-enforced integration.  We just haven't seen that kind of violence directed against political beliefs and don't seem anywhere close to it.  If we do get close to it (say, the divisions we saw during the founding between Tories and Patriots) then there would be a case.

You seem to only be concerned with violence. I don’t really think that’s the point of protected classes. The elderly are a protected class so that they aren’t discriminated against in the workplace, not because “we’ve seen how violent things get when the elderly are persecuted”. I don’t think many people are worried about a Grandma uprising anytime soon. 

From what I’ve seen the protected class system is maybe only tangentially related to preventing violence. The primary thing it seems to be concerned with is preventing companies from discriminating. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107376363.0" user="IdolKek" delta="False">
    <text>Except where I work, everyone is extraordinarily vocal about their position and it’s unanimous, including disparaging pics of the president and comments in meetings where everyone is expected to agree. If I didn’t play along, I genuinely expect that I’d be fired. This isn’t paranoia. People equate dissent with being a threat to safety. Their impression of the opposition has no correlation with my actual beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109013074.0" user="Jasontheperson" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have examples of these people who were fired for political beliefs? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109192065.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>James DeMore is one, the subnautica sound engineer is another. Historic examples include all the communist black labeling that happened back in the 50s. 

And countless others that never hit the news. The only reason we don’t hear about more is because since you can be fired for your political beliefs, people tend to keep those hidden in the workplace. It’s kind of a self fulfilling prophecy. Since you can be fired for it, people keep it hidden so that they don’t get fired. So therefore you don’t hear about a ton of cases, although there are still some you do hear about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30111735294.0" user="metamatic" delta="False">
    <text>James Damore wasn't fired for his political beliefs. [He was fired for](https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/19/16911482/james-damore-google-ceo-sundar-pichai-women-in-tech-memo-firing) writing a memo suggesting that some of his co-workers were genetically unsuited to doing their jobs, and circulating it.

That's one of the big differences between race and political beliefs. You don't have to choose to write a memo to get discriminated against because of your race. _Being_ a right winger wasn't what got Damore fired, it was his _actions_.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112127543.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>There’s a lawsuit going on right now to decide if that’s true. I read the memo and it did talk about how Google tends to be very unwelcoming of conservative views. I guess we’ll have to see what the courts decide. 

Honestly though, are you really going to fight me on this one? You don’t think that it’s plausible that someone somewhere in America was fired because their boss found out they have different political views? That’s like, not even close to hard to believe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112284055.0" user="metamatic" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, it probably happens. However, James Damore isn't a good example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112294127.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Personally I think he is, but I can see both sides of it. Like I said, it’s up to the courts now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106109407.0" user="super-commenting" delta="False">
    <text>You're forgetting the communist purges</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106201942.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Those were power solidification and not really discrimination in the usual sense.  They were about loyalty/teams.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
