<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106556763.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>I think you misunderstand how protected classes are formed and why.  Protected classes are not "things you can't control about yourself".  If they were, we'd only have one protected class:  "people with things they can't control about themselves."  (Also, as an aside, religion isn't the only protected class that has nothing to do with who you are intrinsically -- veteran status is *also* something you can control -- don't join the military, you're not a veteran).

Protected classes are *reactions* to **oppression** that we decide (through the political process) that we will no longer tolerate.  So, they are wholly arbitrary.  If someone started murdering skateboarders in the streets, denying them jobs, and making it difficult for them to vote, we'd shortly have a "skateboarding status" protected class.

So I think your mental model about protected classes is simply broken, and therefore you're drawing weird conclusions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106617659.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>But people *do* discriminate based on political beliefs. I get that the political process is what decides these things but I’m having this CMV because I think that in the case of political beliefs the political system got it wrong. 

According to you, there is a principle that exists; we protect those who have historically been discriminated against. And people of certain political affiliations **have** historically been discriminated against. Communists, for example. I know that politicians decide all this, I’m saying I think they made the wrong decision. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106626258.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm asserting is that it's never reached the level that we decided to form a protected class around political discrimination.  All protected classes are *arbitrary* and the political process is how we decide what to protect.  Every single individual everywhere has at some point been discriminated against unfairly.  It's life.  What makes a protected class isn't just "discriminated against unfairly".  It's instead "discriminated against so frequently and so detrimentally that we were able to establish enough common ground in the political sphere that we decided to **do** something about it.  

Political discrimination hasn't reached that point, and most likely never will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106720058.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>This is where we disagree. I think that political discrimination reached that level quite a while ago. You say “we” decided. No, politicians decided, not me. I expressly reject their decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107483357.0" user="TreebeardsMustache" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You say “we” decided. No, politicians decided, not me. I expressly reject their decision.

In a Republic, "politicians decided" is the only "decided" that counts.  That's the power you gave them when you voted in an election.  If you deliberately did not vote in an election, then you're not part of the Republic and have no say.  

That's what it means to live in a representative democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108645441.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t care. In this case the decision they’ve made does not represent me. All of these things were decided years before I was born anyway. 

What are you even saying? We should never be allowed to criticize or question the choices our politicians make since they “represent” us and “that’s what it means to live in a representative democracy”?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108866144.0" user="TheTyrus" delta="False">
    <text>It means that you play your part and they play their part. If you disagree with what the politicians are doing, you're supposed to organise with people who agree with you into a voting block. Talk is cheap unless it's backed by more voices. Voting gives you the ability to mold the government into what you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109166655.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Well organizing with people is hard but I can at least discuss things and try to convince others. Hey, maybe that’s why I made this CMV in the first place 🤔</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108866317.0" user="TreebeardsMustache" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What are you even saying? We should never be allowed to criticize or question the choices our politicians make since they “represent” us and “that’s what it means to live in a representative democracy”?

You did not "criticize or question the choices."  You are allowed, and indeed even encouraged, to "criticize or question."  Them's not, however, the terms you laid out. To wit, you stated pretty clearly and definitively:

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;You say “we” decided. No, politicians decided, not me. I expressly reject their decision.

You're not allowed to rob a bank because you disagree with the politicians decision to make bank robbery a crime. You are not allowed to reject the police officer mandated by the law to apprehend you.  You are also not allowed to 'expressly reject'  the mandated sentence you get when caught.  If you're still not convinced, let me know when you are going to try something like that and I'll bring the popcorn. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109179893.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Houston, we have reached new levels of pedantry. When I say I reject it I mean I don’t accept it. As in I disagree with it. As in I think it’s wrong. As in I wish things were different. As in I do not approve of the decisions that have been made. 

Of course I know I still have to live by their stupid rules. Do you think I have down’s syndrome or something? Literally every coherent adult in the world knows that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109224550.0" user="TreebeardsMustache" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Houston, we have reached new levels of pedantry. 

Don't be a dick.  Refusing to be sloppy with words is not the same thing as pedantry. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109567398.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I googled “reject definition”. Here’s the first result

“dismiss as inadequate, inappropriate, or not to one's taste.”

In case it still isn’t crystal clear, I dismiss those politicians’ decision because I feel it is inadequate, inappropriate, and not to my taste. In the future, please argue against my meaning rather than some strange contrived meaning that you might be able to pull out of a sentence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107749522.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>Reject away friend, in a representative democracy laws only change via the will of the people as expressed by their representatives, and since they're trying to represent a large group of people, unless you can convince enough *other* people to agree with you, you have no hope of affecting change.

Not only that, but I completely and utterly disagree that political discrimination has reached the point of historic race or gender discrimination for example.  In fact, it borders on offensive that you could even assert such a thing.  You understand that we enslaved an entire race 150 years ago, right?  You understand that women couldn't even vote until about 100 years ago, right?  **That** is where we began the idea of establishing protected classes.  There was egregious residual discrimination that needed to be corrected, [and everybody could see it.](http://pictures.ozy.com/pictures/1500xany/7/3/5/75735_BE001140.jpg)  As far as I know, we haven't enslaved Libertarians, Communists, or even Anarchists en mass for their political beliefs, prevented them from getting jobs, or from voting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107943341.0" user="apatite" delta="False">
    <text>There's a whole list of other protected classes other than race. I don't get being offended about the idea of putting policial opinion on a list that includes age and veteran status. 

I don't necessarily think political classes needs protected status because I think it's healthy to challenge your poltical beliefs. But we only have to look back a few decades to see McCarthyism and the red scare. There are still political prisoners in many countries. Civil wars and coups happen. When people look around and see the hatred between the parties, I think it's understandable to be afraid of how it could turn out and to want to do something to prevent more violence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30110336394.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>You guys keep dragging up McCarthyism like it had absolutely no shade of legitimacy.  It **did**.  The Soviets **were** trying to infiltrate Western democracies because they believed in the fomenting of rebellion as a means to bring about their "global communist utopia".  The only thing wrong with McCarthyism was that it *went too far*.  Let's say we *did* have this new "protected class" for political beliefs and actions back then... would we still be a democracy?  Any political belief that's *built* on the idea that the entire current government must go is not a political belief I want protected **at all**.  That's domestic terrorism and spycraft.  That's Timothy McVeigh nonsense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108709862.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; unless you can convince enough *other* people to agree with you, you have no hope of affecting change

Um, what do you think I had this CMV for my friend?

&amp;gt; As far as I know, we haven't enslaved Libertarians, Communists, or even Anarchists en mass for their political beliefs, prevented them from getting jobs, or from voting.

You haven’t been paying attention then because that’s exactly what happened to Communists back in the 50s. If it was found out that you were a communist then it became almost impossible to find a job. In some industries (Hollywood being the most famous) even an accusation of being a Communist could get you blacklisted and end your career. You should look up Joe McCarthy and all the “McCarthy-ism” back in the 50s. 

And anyway, it’s a self fulfilling prophecy. Political beliefs are not a protected class, so people know they can be fired for them. Because of that people tend to keep their beliefs hidden at work, and since they keep them hidden that means that not too many people are getting fired for them. So you can’t point to the fact that it hasn’t happened en mass and claim that it means there isn’t a problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30110315777.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, that was 70 years ago, and it was a dramatically different time.  I know all about McCarthyism.  It was an overblown worry about an *actual* problem.  The Soviets **were** infiltrating all aspects of society.  Given [Nikita Khrushchev's behavior](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mm0yQg1hS_w), it *wasn't* a completely unreasonable response, it was just overblown, and it's hard to condemn our grandparents' response, given that we didn't live through it.  Frankly, if you think protection for political thought should extend to people who are actively asserting that they want to overthrow the government, then I **completely** disagree with you, and I'll **actively** oppose you.  Is that what you're trying to say?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112119892.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; First of all, that was 70 years ago, and it was a dramatically different time.  

So about the same time as Jim Crow laws. Would you also say that racism is irrelevant since it’s been 70 years?

&amp;gt; It was an overblown worry about an *actual* problem.  

Yes, sort of how many people fear Muslims. It’s an overblown worry about actual terrorist threats. 

&amp;gt; and it's hard to condemn our grandparents' response, given that we didn't live through it.  

I don’t condemn their response because I don’t judge the pst by current standards. However, that doesn’t mean we can’t learn from the past, and in hindsight we can see it was a completely overblown response as you said. So anyway, we do have a historic precedent of members of a political party being heavily discriminated against. 

&amp;gt; Frankly, if you think protection for political thought should extend to people who are actively asserting that they want to overthrow the government, then I **completely** disagree with you, and I'll **actively** oppose you.  Is that what you're trying to say?

Sort of. All I’m saying is that religion and politics should be treated the same way. Personally, I don’t think that either one should be a protected class but that isn’t the point of this CMV. The point is that they should be the same. So, if you like religion as a protected class then I’m saying that politics should be one too and therefore the answer to your question is yes. If you do not think politics should be a protected class, then I would argue that neither should religion. If this is the case, then the answer to your question would be no. 

I am not taking any positions on what religion and politics should or shouldn’t be. My position is that no matter what they are, they should be the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112895677.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>I still say you're trying to apply reason to an inherently unreasonable process.  Protected classes don't *have* to be rational because they're completely arbitrary.  Communists were a tiny tiny part of the population, and yes, some percentage of them  were treated unfairly, but *some* of them *were* trying to overthrow the government.  Politics is messy.  I'm not the least bit interested in helping you protect that kind of tiny faction of people.  I also don't care about your discomfort that there's an inconsistency in how protected classes are created, because I believe you're mistaken that they *should* be coherent -- they're simply arbitrary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112912899.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that’s definitely how it seems it is right now - arbitrary. If that’s how you like laws being made then I suppose that’s your prerogative. But it’s absolutely not convincing to me. 

When I say “this law makes no sense” and the best argument in response is “it’s not *supposed* to make sense”, that doesn’t do much to persuade me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112924820.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>Well, learning how the world actually works is sometimes disappointing.  To try to fix every problem in a political system tends to create an overfit system that isn't dynamic.  I'd rather solve major problems, not minor ones if I'm forced to make a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112948618.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I do see this as a major problem, not a minor one. Logical inconsistencies in a justice system are, to me, always major problems because they undermine the entire purpose of the legal system. We set legal systems up specifically because we know that the world isn’t fair, but we would like it to be. So the goal of any legal system is fairness. 

Logical inconsistencies always create unfair results when present in a legal system. They sort of defeat the entire purpose of the system in the first place! There are plenty of them in our justice system and they are all awful, but political opinions was the one I wanted to talk about in this CMV. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30112995243.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>Read about antifragility.  In many spheres of life we're forced to choose between overfit and fragile vs. underfit and adaptive.  By attempting to force the political process to be perfectly fair, it becomes overfit and therefore not adaptive enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30113005797.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t know about anti-fragility but I’m familiar with the concept of overfitting (it’s a big concept in artificial intelligence and that’s what my job is based around) so I see what you’re saying. 

That being said, race, religion, and all the others didn’t cause the system to overfit and cause a collapse from being too rigid, I don’t see how political protection would do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30113024001.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not speaking about "political protection" itself, but about changing the process to try to make it more rigid in definition, which is the larger issue at stake.  By remaining arbitrary, it's adaptive.  As soon as there's enough political will, a new protected class can emerge.  The inherent "work" required to create new protected classes (getting collective agreement) tempers the tendency to overfit.  There has to be *egregious*, *ongoing* discrimination in order for there to be enough political will to change the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30113060712.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not talking about changing the process, Im talking about the results that the process should have produced by now.

It absolutely boggles my mind that there isn’t more political will for this because egregious ongoing discrimination *is* going on and *has been* going on for decades. It’s been going on for so long that a lot of people don’t even realize it!

You’re heading to the biggest job interview of your life. Here’s a question - would it be a good idea to walk in wearing a MAGA hat? 

If your answer to that is “no”, then that proves my point! It doesn’t matter who you are, and it doesn’t matter which company it is because the problem is so widespread that it would be a bad idea at *any* company. It’s just that people have learned to hide it for so long that they forget that they shouldn’t have to! If a Jew were pondering whether or not he should wear a yamika to his interview on account of the fact that it might cost him the job, then that wouldn’t seem very fair would it? Well, that’s exactly as unfair as I see the situation with the MAGA hat.

This isn’t about changing the process, this is about what society should have accomplished by now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30113817246.0" user="greevous00" delta="False">
    <text>There is no egregious, ongoing discrimination relative to political opinions.  There just isn't.

However, I'll try to adjust your assertion and play it out.  First, I wouldn't wear a MAGA hat to a job interview because I wouldn't *ever* wear a hat to an interview... it's just quirky to do something like that.  It makes me stand out for no particular purpose.  However, I see what you're trying to assert, so let's see if we can invent a better version of your assertion... let's see...

Hmmm... harder than I thought.  Uhhhh... so I'm in a job interview and I mention that I don't think my wife should work?  (A clearly conservative viewpoint.)  *Shouldn't* people be allowed to discriminate against me in that case?  I'm asserting something very conservative, but more importantly, I *sound* like I might discriminate against women in the workplace, which we've all already decided is a protected class.

Hmmm.... let's see... is there a more reasonable but subtle version of this?  I mention in a job interview that I think we should build a wall on the southern border of the USA?  First, why am I even talking about that in a job interview?  It's hard to imagine why that would ever come up.  However, again, it *sounds* like I might be the type of person who would discriminate racially in the workplace.

Let's see... So I assert in a job interview that the life of an unborn baby is sacred and abortion should be illegal.  Uhhh... again, how in the hell did *that* come up?  It doesn't seem at all germane to my job flipping burgers at McDonald's, or my skills as a neurosurgeon.  Let's imagine again that *somehow* it legitimately came up.  Again, it *sounds* like I might be the type of person who would discriminate against women, especially a woman who's had an abortion.

I'm really struggling to come up with a situation where I should *ever* discuss politics in a job interview (or at work in general).  Not because I'm scared to, but simply because it's not germane.  It would be like talking about my fetishes or something.  It doesn't matter what I do with my free time.  Likewise, it doesn't matter what my political beliefs are as long as I'm qualified to do the job, and I'm not discriminating against anybody we've all deemed to be a protected class.  It *seems* like simple discretion is all that's necessary, not protected class status.  There *seems* to be a legitimate reason *to* discriminate against people with extreme political views in the workplace, because those political views often bump into how we treat people who are *already* of a protected class.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
