<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106557206.0" user="11816" delta="False">
    <text>The first amendment protects freedom of religion.  The constitution does not protect political beliefs.  As you noted, the rest are immutable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107933218.0" user="ayyy__1mao" delta="False">
    <text>The First Amendment doesn't say anything about what a private employer can or cannot do. Only what the government can or cannot do. People get fired for things they say all the time. The First Amendment doesn't regulate the behavior of private employers at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108008961.0" user="11816" delta="False">
    <text>What does that have to do with this CMV?  

1. OP is stating that political belief should be a protected class, similar to age, sex, orientation, etc.  Those are rights granted by the constitution (the due process and equal protection clauses).

2.  Though you are correct in that the constitution/BOR are limits on the government, the first amendment, and constitution generally, absolutely affect what private citizens can and cannot do.  As a private employer you could not not hire someone because of their status as a protected class, including their religious beliefs.  However, you could because they’re a republican or Democrat.  

Do you think political campaigns want to hire someone who doesn’t adhere to their ethos?  Those are private citizens running private campaigns until they’re elected.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108034911.0" user="ayyy__1mao" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the first amendment, and constitution generally, absolutely affect what private citizens can and cannot do.

Certain parts of the Constitution do. The First Amendment does not. The First Amendment specifically refers to Congress and does not restrict private citizens or organizations at all.

&amp;gt; As a private employer you could not not hire someone because of their status as a protected class, including their religious beliefs.

Yes, but not because of the First Amendment. Protected classes are not enumerated in the First Amendment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108102571.0" user="11816" delta="False">
    <text>You have the right to freely exercise your religion.  Though the main thrust of that protection comes from different parts of the constitution, it has its basis in the first amendment.  

Regardless, that has nothing to do with the fact that the constitution protects religion, and the other categories listed by OP as protected classes.  

Those protected classes have their roots in the constitution.  Political belief does not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108115390.0" user="ayyy__1mao" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it has its basis in the first amendment.

Legally speaking, it doesn't.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
