<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30105770277.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>"Everyone's a Democrat until they get their first paycheck."

We should be *encouraging* people to change their minds between parties, instead of codifying the divide.

The GOP of Lincoln is not the same as the GOP of today. The Democrats pre-LBJ of the South are obviously not the Democrats of today. Political parties are completely artificial and represent instead convenient alliances of the moment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105855166.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>That’s all true, but it doesn’t stop anyone from discriminating against political affiliations. Yes, people shouldn’t do it but again there’s nothing stopping me from hanging a “no Republicans” sign. Encouraging people to change their political beliefs is one thing, but coercing them into it is quite another. And right now it’s perfectly legal at the federal level for an employer to do that to their employee</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105898150.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And right now it’s perfectly legal at the federal level for an employer to do that to their employee

that's just because people (including me) weren't aware of all the posts that were appointed positions, not elected. Judges are appointed. It's all part of the interwoven checks and balances.

The difference between religion and political beliefs are that, more often than not, religion is tied intimately to culture and race. 

Now, a "no Muslim" sign really means "no beards, hijabs, and a certain type of brown skin and facial features." people with 'no muslim' signs aren't interrogating everyone at their door about their particular religious beliefs. It's a very clear proxy for racism. A white Muslim convert with non-specific clothing could walk in without a second look. (I'm just assuming that a white person is doing the sign hanging, excuse the assumption.)

A "no republicans" sign could really only be enforced if you did interrogate them at the door.

So I disagree with you that "religion" is equivalent to "political beliefs" because in practice, it turns into racial profiling. they see a minority race, they assume a religion. conversely, you can't guess someone's politics based on their race.

I do think that if you had a "no Lutherans" sign on your door, because it's divorced from race assumptions, it would not be a big deal (though still illegal, based off a time when such signs were common)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106019729.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that political beliefs are also closely tied to culture, and there’s at least some correlation with race. Someone could hang a “no Obama supporters” sign up as a way to try and filter out black people. 

And there are other ways to discriminate against certain political ideologies. You could kick out anyone wearing MAGA hats, for example. That’s a lot like kicking out anyone wearing a yamika because you don’t like Jews. 

Anyway, the fact that it’s hard to discriminate in that way shouldn’t matter. It can be hard to tell if someone is Jewish if they aren’t wearing anything typically associated with Jews. That doesn’t make it right to discriminate against Jews though, just because some might come and go unnoticed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106051069.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>interesting. I'll grant you that these days, political beliefs, if they were immediately visible, are the single most stigmatizing thing in certain places, more than race even.

And it would be wrong to ban MAGA hats in a store, but shouldn't be illegal, and here's why I think that: the difference is that "protected class" indicates that the class was vulnerable in the first place. Hence minority races, minority religions, disabilities. There would have been no need to protect them if the courts hadn't determined that discrimination existed in the first place.

A few stores that kicked out MAGA hats would not amount to systemic discrimination. Same with an employer who threw a republican's application in the trash. 

Because political beliefs can be held by anyone, it would be impossible to prove on that basis alone that republicans or democrats are vulnerable classes. For every vulnerable republican living in a trailer park on food stamps there is a not-vulnerable millionaire.

Now, if a political party was restricted along religious or low-income lines, that would an interesting debate. but the current parties do not imply a particular vulnerability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106091442.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, let me give you a real-world example that I think challenges this; Nazis. 

Nazis are widely despised throughout the country. Many, many stores in America would refuse service to someone wearing a swastika armband. Many people refuse to associate with Nazis, many people have lost their jobs because it was discovered that they are a Nazis, etc. 

Wouldn’t this make Nazis a vulnerable class? Wouldn’t you say that right now in America, Nazis are heavily discriminated against? I think that most definitions of “vulnerable” that would apply to religions would also apply to Nazis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106167567.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>haha, you did confuse me for a second. well done.

you got to draw the distinction here between what a Nazi's political beliefs are, and their overwhelmingly toxic personalities.

people don't kick them out of stores or fire them because they believe in a white ethnostate. you can stew in whatever racist beliefs you want at home. it's because they are assholes enough to broadcast that or march in charlottesville or wear a swastika armband. once you publicize your own hatred, you lose your vulnerable status.

[the fenians](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fenian) were a political party/terrorist organization. it would fine to ban them the same way we ban nazis from stores.

that's not a double standard; westboro has been banned from entering canada and the UK. religions also lose their vulnerable status once they spew hatred.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106236592.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; people don't kick them out of stores or fire them because they believe in a white ethnostate. you can stew in whatever racist beliefs you want at home. 

Eh, I have a hard time believing that. Racism is widely hated in America. I think that belief in a white ethnostate is enough to make people want you gone, no matter how nice or polite you were acting. 

&amp;gt; it's because they are assholes enough to broadcast that or march in charlottesville or wear a swastika armband. once you publicize your own hatred, you lose your vulnerable status.

But what constitutes publicizing your own hatred? Does wearing a cross necklace indicate that you hate gay people? Some people might say it does. Or something similar for someone wearing a hijab. Granted, Nazis are an example that pretty clearly is hateful but there are plenty of other groups that some might call hateful and others might not. Many would call Antifa hateful, should it be legal to ban anyone from your store for wearing an Antifa patch?

&amp;gt; [the fenians](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fenian) were a political party/terrorist organization. it would fine to ban them the same way we ban nazis from stores.

To be clear, I agree. Personally I don’t like the concept of a protected class at all, and I especially don’t think that religion should be a protected class. I completely agree that it’s reasonable to kick Nazis out of your store. It’s just that I also think it’s just as reasonable to ban certain religions from your store. So my main point is that it makes no sense to have one but not the other. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106320971.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Does wearing a cross necklace indicate that you hate gay people? Some people might say it does. Or something similar for someone wearing a hijab.

A person wearing a cross necklace or a hijab is not bothering anyone. You need to bother someone to bother someone. If you're bothered by the mere sight of a cross or a hijab, the problem is with you.

See the end of my last post about Westboro. These guys are bothering people, and thus lose the protections of their religion. We can now discriminate against them. They might not have chosen to be Baptists, but they are definitely choosing to be Westboro.

American neo-nazis: they might not have chosen to believe whites are superior, but they are definitely choosing to be Nazis. Wearing a swastika is a provocation on the same level as Westboro picketing military and gay funerals. 

I think I despise the antifa too, but I don't know enough about them to relate them to this discussion.

&amp;gt; I think that belief in a white ethnostate is enough to make people want you gone, no matter how nice or polite you were acting.

You might be right--but it's a hateful enough belief (that races should be kept separate) that to talk about it at work is also a provocation. 

Man, I feel like we got sidetracked. To sum up my position:
protected religious classes are lawful because they demonstrated vulnerability to one-sided discrimination. the most obvious one these days is Islam. 

political parties do not qualify for vulnerability because that's impossible to prove that they suffer from one-sided discrimination. Nazis do not qualify for vulnerability because they are provoking others and spewing hateful speech.

what religions are as hateful as nazis? in this country.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106455560.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>A person wearing a swastika isn’t bothering anyone either. I mean, I know that some people would be bothered by it but as you said, that’s on them. You can’t demand all Jews to leave a restaurant when they’re minding their own business by claiming that yamikas “bother” you.

I agree we got sidetracked. To get back on track, let’s focus on the idea that someone being hateful disqualifies them from protections given to other non-hateful groups. 

This sets up a terrible situation - how do we decide who is hateful and who isn’t? Many people in this country would call you hateful if they learned you voted for Trump. Others wouldn’t call you hateful even if you were waving a Nazi flag while wearing a KKK outfit. There is not some objective measure upon which we can decide if some group is hateful. That is the reason that I don’t like this line of thinking. 

I mean, how many people do you think would say that caucasians are hateful? Probably quite a few. Does that mean that it’s now ok to discriminate based on being white? How about old people? Old people are well-known to be more racist on average than young people. By this logic, shouldn’t that disqualify them from their protections?

The answer to that is probably ‘no because they aren’t hateful enough’. But how hateful is hateful enough? How do we measure that? We can’t. That’s why I don’t really think that being hateful is a good reason to disqualify some group. It’s too hard to measure in a fair and objective way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30113252691.0" user="Okamibin" delta="False">
    <text>Protected class means for example race not blacks and gender not women so it has nothing to do with being a minority or oppressed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
