<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106212167.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system.

It would give explicit protection to followers of [(neo-)Nazism and other kinds of fascism](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_political_ideologies#Nationalism). I don't think we want to open that can of worms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106252547.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>You’re right, it does open a huge can of worms. So does protecting religion, and yet we still do it. 

You’ve got to convince me that there’s some sort of underlying factor that makes them inherently different. I’ve actually been using nazis all over this thread as an example of why it’s ridiculous to protect religion, since at their core they have many things in common. They are both ideologies, both have had a history of hatred and violence, both can be heavily discriminated against, neither one is immediately recognizable unless the person is displaying symbols for it, etc. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106319728.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, but at least most religions have big moderate populations as well, so I can at least understand why people think they're worth protecting. I don't think that the same can be said about fascists and Nazis.

While I don't think that religion deserves special protections, I don't think that e.g. employers should be able to discriminate against job candidates based on someone's religion, the lack of a religion or not being of the right religion. So it covers atheists and agnostics as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107919501.0" user="ayyy__1mao" delta="False">
    <text>The can of worms is already open. There is nothing about religious beliefs that make them immune from the hatred that characterizes Nazism. Many people have extremely hateful beliefs that are derived directly from their religious affiliation. These people still enjoy protected class status.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108154933.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Many people have extremely hateful beliefs that are derived directly from their religious affiliation. These people still enjoy protected class status.

I actually agree, and I would prefer a different solution.

You can look at it this way: do we want to make it even worse by adding protection for even more hateful people into the mix? At least, religious protection also protects the majority of good, religious people, and atheists/agnostics. 

The cost of protecting the good ones is that unfortunately, some bad ones are protected as well. With fascists and Nazis, there's no protecting the good ones.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
