<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30105635904.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Political belief is supposed to be a thing that intersects between everything someone can be judged for. People judging other people based on thier political affiliation just don't grasp the concept of politics.

Religion can be a way of life for people that practice it. I think religion has a bigger influence on culture than race does sometimes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105647539.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t really get what you’re saying here. Many many people decide that they dislike someone based on nothing more than that person’s political label. Whether they should or shouldn’t, people definitely **do** make pre-judgments based on political beliefs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105664768.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>They do currently yes but they shouldn't. The laws based on protected classes are based on what should be protected for reasons of civil order.

People that make judgments about other people based on political sides are just assholes. It doesn't warrant a law against it, its just something we have to work on as a community. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105707655.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>Why are people who make judgments based on political beliefs “assholes”, but people who make judgments based on religions beliefs are apparently evil enough that we should outlaw it? If we’re basing laws on how people should act then we don’t need the religious protections because people shouldn’t be discriminating based on religion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105752698.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Becuse politics is supposed to be debated and supposed to be discussed.

Debates between religion are usually an objective fact that God doesn't exist vrs an objective fact that God does exist. In that debate there is a wrong and right answer for each individual person based on thier own beliefs. (Of course there are different debates in religion but it's easier to explain this) 

In political debates there are less definitive facts and more opinions of policy and interaction. Not to forget that politics is about stuff that is 100% fabricated by man. If you are having a debate about religion there is probably at least one of you that believes that the world was not created by us.

The only correlation I see between religion and political affiliation is the assumptions that other people make of them ie, being dumb or lady or even prudish. It is not illegal to assume something about someone becuse they are a religion. But it is illegal to use violence or threatening words towards someone for it and it is still independently illegal to use violence on someone for any reason. Political based violence isnt labeled a hate crime becuse there is nothing holding the groups together but a made up organization that shares some ideas. Religions are a lot more connected than that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105800623.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Because politics is supposed to be debated and supposed to be discussed

Why isn’t religion “supposed” to be debated? I don’t think that religious debates are any more or less “factual” than political ones. For example, abortion is a hot political topic. It’s up to each individual to decide whether a fetus counts as a human life. How is this any different than each individual deciding if God exists or not? In both cases there isn’t any conclusive proof one way or the other. It’s essentially up to you and your opinions to decide the answer to those questions. One isn’t really more “factual” than the other. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105720598.0" user="MeowTheMixer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People that make judgments about other people based on political sides are just assholes. It doesn't warrant a law against it, its just something we have to work on as a community.

But isn't this what the right claims for most of these classes? Look at the cake situation earlier. "We don't need a law to force them to bake a cake, people can refuse to go there and a new baker will do that". 

There are plenty of laws where we shouldn't need them. I should know better than to litter. If I do i'm an asshole and breaking the law. Why can't the community police littering as well? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105761791.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure about your point to be honest, but laws that inhibit the debate of politics would be the same as inhibiting free speech. Politics doesn't need to be a protected class becuse it is made up. Being black or Christian is not made up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106009251.0" user="MeowTheMixer" delta="False">
    <text> &amp;gt;Politics doesn't need to be a protected class becuse it is made up. Being black or Christian is not made up.

But that's not the point you made earlier. Maybe one is "made up" maybe one isn't, being made up doesn't mean it should not be protected. 

You're original statement was 

&amp;gt;It doesn't warrant a law against it, its just something we have to work on as a community.

Why does it not require a law? What makes a being involved with a political party different? Why should this be left to the community? 

Why does race need to be a protected class? We can just shun those who are racists, and make our communities better ourselves. Why does gender need to be a protected class? If you don't hire women, you're putting your company at a disadvantage.  

We require laws for those situations because communities will vary greatly on how they treat certain groups. As we've seen in the past discrimination can run rampant if laws do not protect you.

You can choose to be in the military
You can choose to become pregnant (applies to both pregnancy, and familial status protected classes)

In my opinion you have control over at least these two situations and they are protected classes. So there must be more to it than having a choice or not. 

So what makes being involved with a political party different? 

At the moment I align with OP's perspective. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106214989.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>When I use the term made up I mean that it is fabricated or created for our use. I didn't mean it in the context of making up a lie. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106130277.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>What you mean by "made up"? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106228026.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Made up as in fabricated for our use. Not in the made up a lie sense.

Like government is fabricated to help and take care of citizens. Or that cake is made up of cake batter. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106358631.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>But isn't Christianity also more of a concept than a physically existing thing? Or the idea that [this](https://s-i.huffpost.com/gen/4060138/images/n-SAD-BLACK-WOMAN-628x314.jpg) person is somehow black despite having a lighter skin tone than some white people seems also human created to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106402688.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Well that persons lineage comes from an area that is predominantly black as well as that person would be involved in black culture.

And for someone that believes in Christianity it is more than a concept. It is just a made up thing to people on the outside. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106412012.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>I can be a white person born in south africa while being involved in black culture and people would still call me white based on my looks.

Okay, so if somebody has a political ideology that contains "natural rights", it's now not made up any more to you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106448463.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just saying political ideology doesn't need to be protected becuse it is supposed to be challenged. There is suposed go be a discussion becuse at some point one idea has to win. When you're talking about race or religion there can't be a winner. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106526004.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty of religious people try to convince others to convert to their religion,so there is in fact some challenging going on. Most people see religion as something that can be argued about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105801772.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If anything, I think politics is one of the few areas where it makes the *most* sense to judge somebody. 

Your opinion on whether there's one God, or many gods, or no gods at all, doesn't affect me. If you go to this church or that church, or no church, that's your business and doesn't matter to me at all. That's religion.

Your opinion on whether or not I ought to be deported, or allowed to get married, or whether the local public school should get funding, does. That's politics. It's not like rooting for this or that sports team. It matters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105860799.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Your opinion on whether or not I ought to be deported, or allowed to get married, or whether the local public school should get funding, does. 

Precisely. I'm a bit dumbfounded that people want their position on how society should work to be of no consequence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106261603.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>So if I think for example, that illegals should be deported, I shouldn't be allowed to say that to you? What does the protection actually entail?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106268855.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that you "shouldn't be allowed" to say it, but it's a reasonable basis for judging someone. If I'm an undocumented immigrant, and your political opinion is that I should be kicked out, then your political opinion means I don't want to be your friend. I think that's perfectly reasonable.

I wasn't responding to the OP's point about making political opinions "protected" speech in the same way as religion. I was just responding to your comment about how "people judging other people based on their political affiliation just don't grasp the concept of politics." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106294149.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Well the whole point of politics is to be separate. Some people can want the law to be upheld but also care about thier neighbors.

Like if you voted for Trump but don't call ice on your coworker who is illegal. Separate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108032341.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Some people can want the law to be upheld but also care about thier neighbors. Like if you voted for Trump but don't call ice on your coworker who is illegal. Separate.

That's just being inconsistent. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108132137.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>No it's called being human. You're stuck on the notion that everyone that voted for him is a Klan member. 

That's just being unreasonable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108360620.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It is inconsistent. To say that you vote for someone because you "want the law to be upheld" (as it pertains to illegal immigrants), but you wouldn't call ICE on your neighbor, is to say that you want the law to be upheld for other people, but not the ones you like. You just want to deport *other* people's neighbors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108397455.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Except maybe that's not why certain people voted for him. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108430347.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's the example you gave.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108508286.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure people aren't as one dimensional as you think they are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106124241.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People judging other people based on thier political affiliation just don't grasp the concept of politics.

How do you mean that? Shouldn't opinions be one of the things that actually are useful in judging other people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106224100.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Well for example if I say I am a republican and you know nothing else about me other than the fact I am on this reddit, how would you describe me? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106363763.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>"Republican" isn't really a meaningful information, I agree on that. Political particies have tons of different wings with different opinions, especially big ones such as the Republicans. Your political beliefs, on the other hand, say plenty of things about you.

Are you pro-life or pro-choice? Do you want more or less strict gun control? Do you want higher or lower taxes? Are you for or against mass immigration, diversity quotas, drone strikes, whatever? Where do you think should the minimum wage be? All of those are meaningful questions that define how you view the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106412708.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Well you could say that becuse there is a lot of different types of people who beleive in different types of things that it would be wrong to assume something about someone based on thier general political stance.

Like if I say I'm against mass immigration does that make a horrible person or an idiot? No. Becuse my stance doesn't define who I am. Other people may want to attach me to that and say I'm no bigger than that but that still would be incredibly wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106544908.0" user="BlitzBasic" delta="False">
    <text>The sum of your opinions is a big part of who you are. If somebody thinks that there should be no elections and all media should be state-censored, then I know that I probably don't want that guy around. Or if you think there should be a state religion and all citizens should be forced to follow it. Of course those are extreme examples, but they serve to demonstrate my point, that disliking people because of the worldview they hold isn't irrational.

A more realistic example would be somebody on minimum wage disliking a person that wants to decrease minimum wage. Or somebody with family ties in a middle eastern country disliking people that are pro-drone strikes. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
