<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106530284.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>i guess before all this you need to decide for what reason humans are alive and conscious in the first place before deciding to see how god plays into it.

if there's no reason at all, and we're just an accident, then it doesn't matter why we suffer--it just happens.

if there is a reason we're alive, then you can start deducing from there. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106587602.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Idk why were here, it's one of the reasons I'm asking the question:P</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106651000.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>well what i mean is that if you think joy is better after having suffered, which is the principle behind almost every great story, then God allowing suffering is not a contradiction to his benevolence in the end.

if you think suffering serves no purpose even pursuant to an ultimate joy, then god is not benevolent to you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106676370.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, it's better after having suffered,  but is it not because God made it that way? Could it not have made joy enjoyable regardless of the suffering beforehand?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
