<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107551924.0" user="nap-o-leon" delta="False">
    <text>It’s “change my view” not a argument established by philosophers for thousands of years. No he can’t be both, he was portrayed so the Catholic Church could obtain such influence. Not only is he unimaginable powerful,omnipotent he is morally perfect. You can imagine how they were so powerful in history.
I wouldn’t be such a dick about it, but it is a central and very common argument about god, you could have acknowledged these weren’t your ideas. It seems like you saw this argument somewhere and copy pasted it here for some karma. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107859725.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I'll say once that these are my ideas, as far as any idea can really be yours. And I don't feel the need to prove it any further to you.

Not that that should matter. Does the origin of an idea or a question really come into play when discussing the implications and answers to it?

And I'm talking about a benevolent, omnipotent God as a concept, not as an established religion. So the dogma and history of Catholicism is irrelevant here, in my opinion, unless you're using it for some kind of analogy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107875183.0" user="nap-o-leon" delta="False">
    <text>My point is the church invented god as a perfect being, as they were his representatives. To obtain significant influence over the Christian people. 
Yes any ideas can be yours, but you should admit this argument, about the contradictions of god is a significant and common argument. Search up “god is impossible argument” and you will see it. 
Mainly I saying this because your taking a common argument that has existed for a thousands years and adding nothing to the argument, but omitting significant elements of the original argument. It’s basically “this is what I found, prove it wrong”. Which hasn’t been proven wrong in a thousand years for a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107893092.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps I have a misunderstanding of religion and the idea of God, but I'm pretty sure God evolved independently many different times. You could argue that new gods consider to come into existence today, Even. 

That's why I tried my best to not talk about any particular religion or god. Because then you suddenly have to consider each and every one out there. 

God isn't unique to Christianity,  so only taking Christianity into account doesn't really make sense to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107901418.0" user="nap-o-leon" delta="False">
    <text> No god isn’t unique to Christianity, but the argument against god you used was. And this argument can be used against any religious body. Just the Catholics were the most influential church, who implemented it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
