<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107435706.0" user="Offsubject" delta="False">
    <text>I think the issue here is blaming God for our own actions.  He's holy, perfect, good, and omnipotent.  God desired us to be free from suffering and evil, but we brought it upon ourselves with Adam's original sin.  Adam's sin is our sin.  We cause our own suffering, not God.    </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107442598.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe in original sin. But I was brought up to believe in it. My issue was always that we're being punished for the actions of another man. I haven't talked Christian concepts in a while though, so feel free to correct me if I'm understanding that wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107455351.0" user="Offsubject" delta="False">
    <text>You have that man's (Adam) DNA inside of you.  We are being punished for the actions of our original earthly ancestor. Your logic is sound, but you're anthropomorphizing God.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107463257.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Were we not made in God's image? Therefore, is anthropomorphizing God not the only logical thing to do?

I'm seriously spotty on my bible atm, so I may be neglecting a relevant verse!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108039847.0" user="wheresthebreak" delta="False">
    <text>You've got it backwards: the conception is that we're made in His image, not He in ours. The latter is anthropomorphic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108924521.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>That's what I said. That we were made in his image. But would it not then stand to reason that the qualities that make us human are then some of the same qualities that make God God? I think that's the only logical thing to conclude.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
