<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107340017.0" user="TaggTeam" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is with your working definition of omnipotent. Most people take omnipotent to mean “literally has the power to do anything that is not nonsensical” meaning, can do anything other than things such as make 2+2=5

However a better definition is to say omnipotence means having all the power that it is possible to have. Though admittedly, this alters the concept of what most people imagine god to be. But under this definition it is possible to see how the reason god didn’t create a world as a training grounds about suffering was because for some reason it is not possible (ie the power does not exist) to create a world in which humans are free from evil and also learn and progress the way they are supposed to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107392438.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, provided that is the definition of omnipotence we choose to work with, there is still the problem of benevolence. 

Suffering in life is inevitable, a benevolent god would've made it so suffering didn't exist if that weren't the case. But then why allow life to come to existence in the first place? 

Based on my own life experience: like every one I know is depressed, suicidal, or dying. If that's the inevitability of life, why would a benevolent god create that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
