<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107813702.0" user="dgblarge" delta="False">
    <text>Other related problems with God and suffering etc.

God created everything. God is good. God is the definition of good. God doesn't have an evil bone in his body. So where  did evil come from. In Christian theology it's the devil. But the devil  is Lucifer, bringer of light, formerly  one of God's favourite angels until they fell foul of a demarcation dispute.  So Lucifer is God's creation too. One can conclude that either God is not all good - the violence and horror of the old testament supports this, or God is not the sole creative source in the universe.  Either way God is not as advertised.

As an aside as far as I know the Hindus have the most sensible approach to the whole creation business.  Of all the religions I'm aware of they are explicit  in saying man created God. To my atheist mind this seems obvious so all credit to them. God and the associated beaurocracy that is religion are so obviously human creations. In theory and practice they are so far from the divine it's not funny. 

The other interesting thing about God is that God is faith. Now faith is belief in something for which there is no proof. This is why I find it bizarre that  some folk try to prove God exists. A delightful paradox. Prove God exists and immediately God ceases to exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107882447.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>That's an interesting point. But I think proving god exists would make him a science. But that's semantics, really.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
