<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106570882.0" user="S1imdragxn" delta="False">
    <text>If God is everything then that means God contains within it perfect chaos and suffering but also perfect Love, Logic and Justice

Which would mean that any perceived undo or unjust suffering is really just a misjudgment on the part of us 

Something that is incapable of perfect love or perfect justice is more capable of unjustified horror

This makes sense to me because as terrible as nature and fate can be, it’s pretty obvious that us humans are even more capable of the most sadistic and depraved acts that often outdo nature/God</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106594057.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I think this implies that because the God CAN that they WILL. Which, imo, isn't what omnipotence means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106638322.0" user="S1imdragxn" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not sure what you mean here sorry. 

What I’m saying is that God contains all things within it, suffering is necessary in order to make bliss/ecstasy meaningful and or definable, discrete just by virtue of logic (I’m a Platonic theist) 

Even if you raised the bar to the point of saying something ridiculous like, the worst thing to happen to you is that 5 women a day proposition you for a BJ.

I’d argue that you’d still feel that is unbearable, because then the relative standard of ecstasy would also rise with it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106671863.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, I think that God wouldn't have to follow the same binary logic we do. 

That's the way humans find meaning, but provided God was omnipotent, that's not the way we would HAVE to. Could he not just as easily make it so bliss could be inherently meaningful WITHOUT the need for an opposite, negative emotion?

I think this argument could apply to an omnipotent God, but not a benevolent one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106707546.0" user="S1imdragxn" delta="False">
    <text>Well the best logic we can use imo as humans is this same “binary” seeming, law of non contradiction 

So even if you gut God from the equation I’d like to know how an atheist or non theist non omnipotent being could possibly make a better judgement anyway, as the only frame of reference we have is this clearly rules based and restricted reality


Another point I would add is that an all powerful and all encompassing God would also contain within it the concepts of creation and the concept of meaning, so if we run with the argument that this reality is a creation of God then the meaning of why it appears to be so dualistic is also perfectly reasonable even if we cannot grasp it



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106746384.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>The only objective frame of reference we have is reality,  but, and this is an entire conversation in itself,  we have imagination. 

I think anything we imagine, an omnipotent God would habe to be able to create.  And I imagine a reality in which I'm happy, fuck the specifics.  And seeing as how I don't currently live in that reality, god either isn't capable of making that reality, or chooses not to put me there. 

I'm basically venting at this point,  so sorry for that. Just more shit I have trouble making sense of. Thanks for your responses!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106774123.0" user="S1imdragxn" delta="False">
    <text>Believe it or not I woke up today struggling with the same feelings. 
Unfortunately I’m not 100% certain that God exists, and meaningless suffering is still a concept that haunts me, even if it seems most likely and logical to me that an all powerful creative force does exist.

It could be possible that we’re here doing this on our own terms and projecting ourselves into this distorted “simulation”. 

Or perhaps it’s possible that this is just the timeline of infinite creation that we find ourselves in, like maybe the creations that came before us were even more distorted, vile and chaotic as it emerged from unbound creation and evolves towards perfection?

Idk but I definitely spend probably too much time thinking about these things. 

Thanks likewise for being polite and conversational to me brother/sister and take care</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
