<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107530443.0" user="4skintomandjennytool" delta="False">
    <text>I’m kind of puzzled lol. Can you break it down in a simple way for a dumbass like me? I’m really curious on this </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107848480.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>My original argument relies on the premise that suffering is not an enjoyable experience,  and if god were a benevolent creator, he wouldn't have made it exist.

The response to this could be that the suffering is necessary for whatever reason for life to exist. But implying anything is necessary for an omnipotent God makes that God no longer omnipotent.

I've arrived at a bit of an impasse with some over the definition of the word omnipotence and whether the creation of life was benevolent in the first place.

Imo, omnipotence is the ability to do anything and is mutually inclusive with the omniscience.  Another definition is that omnipotence is the ability to do whatever is possible, which would make an all powerful god, but not a god that could do anything. Some people just differ on that definition,  and so can't come to an actual agreement, but can still respect one another's viewpoints.

The issue of the benevolence of the creation of life is even more complicated. Can suffering be justified if it means that others get to live in relative bliss? The answer to this is probably too individual and deeply rooted to get anywhere through simple discussion,  though.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
