<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107899777.0" user="scrlk990" delta="False">
    <text>I want to have a baby with my wife. If we have a baby, that baby will grow into a child. A beautiful child that we will love with all our heart.

But we know that at times the child might make mistakes. The child will talk back, will hit or kick us, our child will screw up at least once. In addition, that screw up might cause harm to them. But we still want to have that baby. Because one day, after raising the child, the child will love us.

That is God.

I don't believe that true love can exist without choice. Choice to love or not. I think the struggle in your question is that it's hard for us to fully understand benevolence. We understand it from our perspective but not God's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107925526.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Is it really benevolence to create another being know that it will suffer? And when you get into the AMOUNT of suffering on Earth, how can perpetuation of life ever REALLY be justified?

That question is too dependent on life circumstance to really be effectively argued for either way, imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108143338.0" user="scrlk990" delta="False">
    <text>I have given it a little more thought and I wonder if you are using it to invalidate or validate the existence of God. The reason I'm curious is because isn't it better to either fix in one's mind whether God exists and then learn more about him? If there truly is a God, then God can do what he wants. If it doesn't fit our understanding or beliefs on how God should act, it doesn't matter because he is still God. 

Does this answer your question? I think indirectly. You are putting God in a box of your design and your understanding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30108886982.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>My frame of reference is the only way I can ever hope to understand God in. 

I agree, god could be however he is despite us not being able to understand or comprehend. 

But then that begs the question why god would design it so that we couldn't hope to understand him. I would label that a cruelty, purposely stunting our potential growth and understanding. I guess my claim is that a benevolent god would make it so there was no questioning him.

But that dives into the whole free will thing, which would be addressed in another thread, I think!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30118116986.0" user="scrlk990" delta="False">
    <text>One thing I might add is we in modern times think of suffering and death is bad. But all throughout the old testament God did not shy away from bloodshed as far as one can tell. People, whether Israelites or not, died by the thousands. Also, suffering was allowed by God. I don't know if you have but read the book of Job. It's an amazing book even if you don't believe in God. It's about God asking Satan if he has considered God's servant Job. God allows Satan to kill his family, take his belongings, make him destitute, and kill his kids. Then there is this jawdropping speech by God in the last chapters where God chastises Jobs friends and Job. It's amazing.

But one major takeaway from that book is apparently it doesn't violate God's character to allow those bad things to happen and it didn't make the Israelites stop worshipping God. Food for thought.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
