<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106959616.0" user="SSalmans" delta="False">
    <text>I think the most important factor for me is free will. The Christian mindset holds that God wants us to love him and we can't really do that without free will. So, he may be able to fix all of our problems, but if he did that, we wouldn't truly love Him because we couldn't comprehend life without Him. You could argue that if He was omnipotent He would convince us without suffering, but then we would be robots. He wants us to be independent and thinking beings that choose to love Him on our own. So my argument is that He can set up situations and guide us, but for Him to truly have a relationship with us, He has to let us screw stuff up. Like how a parent might let their child get hurt because they know he'll learn from it. They had the power to stop it and they want what's best for the kid, but the parent knew getting hurt would be the best thing for the dumb child.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107030016.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>We'll almost certainly have to agree to disagree,  but I don't see free will as a gift whatsoever. 

Also, what's wrong with being a robot in this case? Isn't that essentially what heaven is described to be (obviously, this will vary from person to person)? No suffering, only bliss? 

And comparing the nature of humanity to the nature of a god just doesn't work imo. God could simply impart any knowledge into us, no need to learn it at all. 

But again, if it comes down to free will for you, I don't imagine well end up agreeing on much:P.

Thank you for your response!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109546775.0" user="SSalmans" delta="False">
    <text>That's certainly justified. I think that you're right, that is what heaven is said to be. I think our time on Earth is what prepares us for that. Maybe without the suffering here, we would end up like Lucifer and not understand or appreciate heaven. 

It is possible that an omnipotent God could just give us the knowledge and supercede any reason to learn, but to me that seems immoral. God has his own moral code probably with some similarities to ours, and it doesn't seem right to me to force His will upon us. If I could force a woman to love me and she would never question it, would I exercise that power? I don't think I should, and I don't think God should either. That love wouldn't mean anything,I she was forced into it. I think that if God did exercise that power to make us believe what He wanted, we would be slaves to Him. If that were the case, we would have no reason to exist at all anyway. We might not agree, but it's great to have a civilized discourse about it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107372361.0" user="Mxlov1n" delta="False">
    <text>I still don't understand why he needs us and even needs a relationship with us. I mean I don't need a relationship with a molecule 78,920,203,923,639 miles away. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109412608.0" user="SSalmans" delta="False">
    <text>That's a fair point. It's a different question, and I really don't have a good answer. Maybe he was lonely? If we're supposed to be created in His image, maybe he wanted to see what he would do if he were like us. Sorry, I don't have anything good to share for that one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109215832.0" user="Aerostudents" delta="False">
    <text>I think this argument is kind of flawed, because it assumes that there needs to be evil and suffering for people to be able to have a free will. However if god created the world he could have easily created a world without suffering and evil where people still have a free will. He deliberately set the world up in such a way that suffering and evil is possible.

It also contradicts the bible as at first adam and eve lived in the garden of eden, where they basically lived without suffering, so did they not have a free will back then?

The free will argument also doesn't adress many of the suffering caused by things that are completely unrelated to free will. For example an earthquake killing many people, how is that related to free will?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30109405099.0" user="SSalmans" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's true. Free will is about choice. If you can't choose to be bad, then being good has no meaning. In my opinion, the Adam and Eve example shows why free will is so important. They lived in a world without evil or suffering and still chose to do the one thing they were told not to. Why? Because they didn't know any better. They needed to learn. If we were just forced to be perfect, it wouldn't mean anything to us and we wouldn't appreciate it.

An earthquake is a example of a situation outside of our control and not because of our actions that forces us to make decisions. Like asking if we will take care of people hurt for no reason in their control. We know we're supposed to, but free will gives us the option to do or not do what should be done. The counter to that argument is that a benevolent God wouldn't do that or let that happen, but I still believe that's like a parent letting their kid make dumb mistakes because sometimes, that's what best for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30110672383.0" user="Aerostudents" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think that's true. Free will is about choice. If you can't choose to be bad, then being good has no meaning. 

I think this argument is interesting, but ultimately undefendable. The problem is that while free will is about choice, it is not about unlimited choice. I for example do not have the free will to fly, live underwater, teleport where ever I want etc. because I am limited by physical limitations. Every choice you make in your life will be limited by the physical limitations of reality, and therefore your free will will always be limited in one way or another. If there was no such thing as evil or suffering this would not limit free will any more than current phyiscal limitations limit my free will to take any actions that require me to be able to fly like a bird.

&amp;gt;In my opinion, the Adam and Eve example shows why free will is so important. They lived in a world without evil or suffering and still chose to do the one thing they were told not to. Why? Because they didn't know any better. They needed to learn. If we were just forced to be perfect, it wouldn't mean anything to us and we wouldn't appreciate it.

This point, while also interesting still doesn't negate the fact that Adam and Eve had a free will in a world without suffering and evil, thus showing that evil and suffering is not required in order to have free will.


&amp;gt;An earthquake is a example of a situation outside of our control and not because of our actions that forces us to make decisions. Like asking if we will take care of people hurt for no reason in their control. We know we're supposed to, but free will gives us the option to do or not do what should be done. The counter to that argument is that a benevolent God wouldn't do that or let that happen, but I still believe that's like a parent letting their kid make dumb mistakes because sometimes, that's what best for them.

One big difference though is that while a parent would let their kid make a dumb mistake, a parent would never let a kid make a mistake that would seriously injure or kill them. However God has no problem with this as he often lets people suffer. Sure you can say that he is trying to teach them a lesson, but I would say that some of the suffering is so bad that this is just incresibly cruel.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30110988636.0" user="SSalmans" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I don't have anything else to offer to defend my argument, so I'll have to stop here. Good on you for listening to opposing viewpoints and looking outside what you've already decided. It's always good to see conversations like this that don't turn into nonsense. Have a good one!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30111263826.0" user="Aerostudents" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, you have a good one as well!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30113040213.0" user="Sadsharks" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn't explain natural evils, i.e. disease, natural disasters, and accidents that cause people to suffer and die but happen independently of human actions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
