<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107052440.0" user="Ray_Charlezard" delta="False">
    <text>You make the assumption that suffering is something that God created - I disagree with that assumption. 

Suffering is something that just exists, just as happiness simply exists. 

Your view could be still be held even if we assume that God is coexistent with suffering - he either cannot (thus not omnipotent) or will not prevent it (thus not benevolent) from affecting humankind. 

I would suggest that God must operate within the natural laws of the universe. That he has a perfect understanding of these laws gives humans the impression that he is omnipotent, but if God must follow law, then he must not fit the strict definition of omnipotent: unlimited power or able to do anything. 

To me, a purely omnipotent being does not seem possible. I do believe however, that an omniscient being is as close to omnipotent as possible. 

If we do accept that God is omniscient, and therefore has knowledge of how to operate within natural laws such that he can do almost anything, then we must still answer the question of benevolence - surely even if he is not strictly omnipotent, there are still things he can do to alleviate or prevent suffering. 

He can, and does, from time to time if the scriptural record is to be believed. So then why does he prevent or alleviate suffering sometimes but not all the time?

This is where the argument that others have made comes into play. There is arguably value to be gained from some suffering in life - without pain or sorrow or suffering, one could not understand or experience the opposite. We would have no concept of happiness if there were not a duality. 

Further, if you believe that God put humans on earth in something of a probationary state in order to learn and grow, you can accept that anything that is allowed to happen here is ultimately for the benefit of the one who experiences it. 

If you assume that God has the power to “save” humankind (and I mean this in the sense of salvation from sin, being able to go to heaven), then people must  be informed of God’s power in order to act accordingly to access it. 

God at times prevents or alleviates suffering so that people can know to what source they should look to in this life. If humankind had no experience with the divine, God’s plan to help humans grow would be rendered ineffective because none would know to follow God. So in some cases, it is a demonstration of power. 

In other cases, he alleviates suffering to conform to those that follow him that they are on the path to him. This is connected to the previous paragraph. God continues to manifest himself to humans to guide them. 

In all cases, he acts for the ultimate benefit of humankind. If he exercises his power to alleviate suffering, it is out of love or compassion. If he allows suffering, it is because, though he doesn’t want to see them suffer, he knows that the end result will be beneficial to those who suffered, and that eventually, they will have knowledge gained from suffering coupled with freedom from future suffering. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
