<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30107519513.0" user="BlackOakSyndicate" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that God is inherently benevolent, but I also don't presume that I am capable of understanding the nature of a being that could be described as "God". In order for "good" to be fully understood or appreciated, "bad" has to exist as it's contrast. By experiencing only once type of stimulation you can't develop any sort of true understanding of the world around you. 

And to assume that Benevolence from your perspective could actually translate to benevolence on a scale that is perceived by God can't possibly compare. Your framing for what can be considered "benevolence" is solely shaped by your relationship to it and what you've gathered from it. 

I'm sure what you consider benevolent could just as easily be dismissed as someone whose understanding of benevolence is different. 

But I'm being roundabout. This basic premise operates on the idea that a benevolent God exists to assuage the existence of man and make the human experience one of comfort and prosperity, and to soften the consequences of free will. It implies that God is a wish granting genie that exists as a reset or do-over button to call on when you fuck up. I personally don't see God that way. 

People state that omniscience + omnipotence + benevolence means that a being would automatically make eliminating suffering a priority. However, it never seems to take into account that maybe suffering may serve a purpose that speaks to God benevolence. Or that the presence of suffering isn't a defining aspect of whether or not a being is benevolent. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107810607.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I understand why people say that presuming to understand a gods benevolence is futile to a human perspective. 

But what evidence is there of that? Human fault on a Godly scale is actually one of the explanations that make sense of suffering  imo. 

Human understanding is the one I have, it's, by definition, the only understanding I can use to understand the world around me. And accepting the answer, "Well you just can't understand," is not only unfounded, it's not an actual answer whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
