<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30142951080.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>You have a point.

But your criteria is wrong.   You should not decide between Bench Trial and Jury trial based on "if you are guilty or not."

Instead you should evaluate what kind of evidence is there against you (super technical?  Easy or hard to understand?)?  Do you plan to testify?  Do you have a reason to think that jury would be sympathetic to you personally?

etc, etc.

Just because you are innocent does not mean that there is no inadmissible evidence that is making your case look bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30142973165.0" user="Mimshot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Instead you should evaluate what kind of evidence is there against you (super technical? Easy or hard to understand?)? Do you plan to testify? Do you have a reason to think that jury would be sympathetic to you personally?

It sounds like you're going in an interesting direction here, but I'm not sure how to complete your argument. How would those things affect my decision?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30142991307.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>One example you gave in OP is "inadmissible evidence."

But just because you are innocent - does not mean that there is no inadmissible evidence that is making your case look bad.

An extreme example:

Imagine you have 8 pedophilia convictions. Now you are being accused (falsely) of a pedophilia offense. Would you really want a judge who is familiar with your conviction history giving you a bench trial over a jury who will not be allowed to know?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143618357.0" user="sjhr23" delta="False">
    <text>Makes sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143779152.0" user="ieatbabies420" delta="False">
    <text>Lawyer here. I'm not super knowledgeable on the ins and outs of the evidence code (my area of practice doesn't really require it), but the 8 prior convictions would probably come in. This is one of those cases where you wonder why the defendant never takes the stand. Once the defendant gets up there and says "I didn't do it", then you can bring in evidence that would not be admissible on the issue of guilt, but it does come in to show that you are not a credible witness (also called *impeachment*). The jury instruction would probably say that the jury is not to consider the priors on the issue of guilt, only credibility. Of course, you average person is not really going to be able to separate the two. The hope is that a judge will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143823661.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>This is NOT coming in. 

If it were to come in for impeachment, the defendant would just not testify.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143798762.0" user="InerasableStain" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t practice criminal law, and it varies by state, but I think evidence of those convictions is coming in. At a minimum, they can be used as impeachment in my state if the possible punishment exceeds one year</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143808941.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don’t practice criminal law, and it varies by state, but I think evidence of those convictions is coming in. 

It's 100% not coming in.

&amp;gt;At a minimum, they can be used as impeachment

1) this is so prejudicial it might not be allowed even for impeachment

2) if this was allowed for impeachment somehow, No lawyer in a right state of mind would allow his defendant to testify, and so he would not be open to impeachment.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143977194.0" user="InerasableStain" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.leg.state.fl.us/Statutes/index.cfm?App_mode=Display_Statute&amp;amp;Search_String=&amp;amp;URL=0000-0099/0090/Sections/0090.610.html

That’s a very good reason why you’d not want a criminal defendant to testify

Though I seem to recall some other provision here that requires you to first ask if they’ve been convicted of a felony, if they say yes, you have to leave it at that. If they lie, you can dig deeper. But I’ve never personally had to deal with this in a civil trial with a witness on the stand, and frankly can’t remember the specifics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143810642.0" user="makronic" delta="False">
    <text>I think OP might be saying (or even if he isn't saying, I am), that in a situation where inadmissible evidence is presented, but later ruled to be inadmissible. 

A jury is less likely to treat it in the same way that a judge would. They might mistakenly take the evidence into account, purposefully disregard the judicial warning not to take the evidence into account, or, try as they may, cannot disregard the inadmissible evidence when making their decision. 

A judge on the other hand is much more experienced in how to treat inadmissible evidence, and to compartmentalise inadmissible evidence so that it affects their decision much less (they are not impervious to it once introduced). 

As to why this would favour an innocent person - OP was most likely referring to inadmissible evidence introduced by the prosecution because it was illegally obtained by the police. Which OP would be correct about. 

However, both sides can introduce inadmissible evidence, there are many ways in which evidence might be inadmissible. The defense could also attempt to introduce inadmissible evidence, which if introduced accidentally and unduly influences a jury, will likely work in favour of the defence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143829946.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think OP might be saying (or even if he isn't saying, I am), that in a situation where inadmissible evidence is presented, but later ruled to be inadmissible. 

That would be grounds for mistrial.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143940775.0" user="Mimshot" delta="False">
    <text>I meant there is likely evidence the prosecutor will seek to admit (and thus the judge will see) that will likely be ruled inadmissible. The judge is supposed to disregard this evidence, but (as /u/Soup_Kitchen noted) the judge being human, I don't completely trust that ability. A jury on the other hand would never see the evidence in the first place.

edit: added other poster's name</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144192689.0" user="makronic" delta="False">
    <text>You're assuming there is a voir dire. There is not always one. 

Many types of evidence may be inadmissible throughout cross examination (can't speak for every jurisdiction but I'd assume in most common law countries: hearsay, character, privilege, etc...). It takes a very quick legal practitioner to always object in time, and once it leaves the witness' mouth, it is too late. 

And if there is a voir dire when something like this happens, a jury will be asked to leave the room while the lawyers and judges talk. You can bet the jury is speculating furiously over what the significance of the last thing they heard was, and why they were asked to leave the room. 

Edit: also whose side are you on anyways :p it sounds like you're saying judges are too fallible. 

Edit 2: a voir dire is when the jury leaves and the solicitors approach the bench to discuss procedural matters such as admissibility of evidence. *Preferably prior to the evidence being introduced.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144062050.0" user="Soup_Kitchen" delta="False">
    <text>So I generally agree with you in so much that if I were going to have someone hear inadmissible evidence and then disregard it, I'd consider a a judge a superior option, but I want to take slight rhetorical exception to

&amp;gt; that in a situation where inadmissible evidence is presented, but later ruled to be inadmissible.

When you're making a selection as to whether to pick a judge or jury, you have think this isn't going to happen.  If your attorney has done a good job, then between motions to suppress evidence obtained illegally, motions to limit any evidence that would otherwise be inadmissible, and timely objections, then there shouldn't be any information heard by the finder of fact that isn't admissible.  Yeah, I know it's going to happen.  It's happened to me, but you make your plans around a mistake.  

Not a real important point, but it's late and I'm arguing to avoid work for tomorrow.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144205645.0" user="makronic" delta="False">
    <text>I take your point, and I see that you've also taken mine. I wrote a longer response just before this one. Long story short, there is not always a voir dire, and it is not always timely enough.

A good litigator will try to minimize inadmissible evidence from the opponent before trial and during trial. I agree. But controlling the flow of evidence during cross examination is quite difficult and haphazard and anything that is said can't be unsaid, all a judge can do is direct the jury to pretend to unhear it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144202296.0" user="MechanicalEngineEar" delta="False">
    <text>I always wondered how this worked with inadmissible evidence.  If I was on a jury and the prosecution showed a video of the defendant stabbing his wife with a knife repeatedly, but then the defense objected and said that the camera which captured that video was illegally installed in the house by police without consent from either the husband or wife and they did not have a warrant to place the camera.  Then the judge ruled the evidence inadmissible, and there was no other strong evidence to prove he killed his wife.  No blood was found as the house had been scrubbed with bleach, the husband said he was on a hunting trip and arrived back hours after his wife had been murdered but there was nobody to prove is story was true or false or the time he actually arrived.  Basically, there was absolutely no other evidence so it was completely plausible that some other person killed the wife, cleaned up, and destroyed the body.

Jurors don't have to show their work or explain why they are voting the way they are, and I would have a very hard time voting him innocent when I know through video proof that he did it.  Sure, if it was some victim-less crime I would be more likely to let him off on a technicality, but for something like murder, I couldn't see myself going "well, I guess he was sneaky and lucky enough that I should let him have this murder. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144230382.0" user="makronic" delta="False">
    <text>It's not so simple though. It is the law after all, every exception has an exception (except this one).

In my jurisdiction, judges can use their discretion (tempered by precedent) to decide whether or not it would be in the interest of justice to admit that evidence. They weigh the probative value of the evidence with the prejudice that it would cause the defendant. 

The prejudice occasioned by illegally obtained evidence to the defendant is always very high. So the probative value better be damn high also. A video of what you described is as high probative value as you can get.

If the accused can be easily identified in the video, a judge in my jurisdiction will most likely allow that. Basically the only defence left is that the video is fake, which unless you have some video genius who can prove that it's fake... good luck. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144234758.0" user="atlaslugged" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imagine you have 8 pedophilia convictions. Now you are being accused (falsely) of a pedophilia offense.

That's not a realistic scenario. If, incredibly, you were convicted of child molestation 7 times and did not spend the rest of your life in prison, the 8th conviction surely would do the trick.

If you escaped and did it again, the whole jury pool would already know of the 8 previous convictions, even if only because "8-time child molester escapes prison" would make the news.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144044009.0" user="sdmitch16" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; is there against you (super technical? Easy or hard to understand?)? 

If the answer to the first question is "Yes, super technical evidence" and/or the answer to the second question is yes, then that'd support picking a jury.

&amp;gt;Do you plan to testify? 

If yes, then it's presumed you'll give a heartfelt testimony and you'd want a jury. If you're testifying because only you know the case, choose a judge since they've most likely be sympathetic to nervousness.
&amp;gt;Do you have a reason to think that jury would be sympathetic to you personally?

If so, then yes. This could include being physically attractive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
