<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30143206606.0" user="naked_avenger" delta="False">
    <text>I'm at work and don't have a ton of time to gather the research on the matter. Your link is an interesting one that I look forward to researching more when I get home.

WITH THAT SAID: You are basing your fate on the *idea* that a judge, knowing of the law, won't be subject to personal bias or whims. 

This idea, however, is not particularly true or safe. With regard to personal whims or mood: [A study showed that merely eating lunch was a significant determiner of a judge's decision on a parole case.](https://www.theguardian.com/law/2011/apr/11/judges-lenient-break) 

With regard to bias, you're assuming they will be able to see beyond the color of your skin, ethnic background, or religious leanings (or lack there of). [That may not be the best idea.](https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/nov/22/judge-racism-judicial-system-black-communities)

While both of these are from the UK, you can assume with safety that this can and is also the case among US judges as well. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
