<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30143781654.0" user="cicadaselectric" delta="False">
    <text>You should decide based on the judge rather than making a blanket statement. Some judges are racist. It’s going to be pretty hard to convince a racist judge you’re innocent. Some judges always come down harder on people charged with sex crimes. Some judges always side with the accused man. Some judges are known to be more lenient. Some are hard asses (yes, even if you’re not guilty). Some judges are old and checked out and are annoyed you’re wasting their time. Some judges were district attorneys a couple years ago and side with the prosecution more often than not. Some judges come from a civil rights background. 

My point is that it’s not that there are more acquittals with bench trials—there are more acquittals with certain judges. Make the choice not now, when you’re not charged with anything you haven’t done. Make the choice on your lawyer’s advice at the time of the charge.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
