<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30142895676.0" user="pagsball" delta="False">
    <text>To me this would depend on the crime. For example, a traffic court judge is more likely going to be merciless against arguments about situational feasibility. Source: personal experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30142966875.0" user="Mimshot" delta="False">
    <text>It's hard to reply based on your personal situation without more knowledge of that case, but it sounds like you actually were guilty, but felt you had a justification? In that case I suppose it would depend whether the law recognized your justification. In either event, it doesn't really address my premise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143059681.0" user="pagsball" delta="False">
    <text>Here's more knowledge of the case: I was towed with 24.25 hours notice on a new, temporary, no parking zone, identified with poorly *and therefore invalidly* labeled sandwich signs. Because my reaction was too slow, and I was not available, and the towing company cannot release the vehicle without the owner or a notarized letter, my car was stored for 4 days, and I had to pay over $400 to get it back.

To the judge, the complexity of the facts of the situation, and my rapid-yet-insufficient response, had no bearing on whether I was guilty. I was, technically guilty, as I got my bare minimum 24 hours notice.

To a jury, the fact that I reacted quickly, and did everything I could do to prevent being towed, and that my fees stacked up due to timing, might have had an impact, if not on the guilt, then perhaps on the fees. The judge was probably sick of hearing people complain about the same problem over and over, and didn't care much for that argument.

So I stand by what I said. I would choose a jury for *some* arrangements where "I could see that happening to me" and "it's complicated" might serve me better than the letter of the law.

In my case, and more directly counter to your CMV claim, I even had the letter of the law in my favor: Sandwich boards are not legally valid unless properly and clearly labeled. Says so right on the DOT website and in the laws. I presented this information, and it didn't matter. The website and law also indicate several best practices, most of which were ignored. I was not guilty, and the judge steamrolled me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143496496.0" user="ChetBenning" delta="False">
    <text>Counter point: in a jury trial, the jury will be instructed to follow the letter of the law by the judge and the prosecuting attorney.

 So they hope you place in the jury comes down to jury nullification against instruction, which has a spotty track record. You would have to be a very sympathetic defendant and be up on something not too heinous to have a shot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143499646.0" user="Snarkout89" delta="False">
    <text>While I can tell it felt good to get that off your chest, and it sounds like a strong case, it still sounds to me like you were, strictly speaking, guilty of the initial crime (parking where it was illegal to do so, and not moving within the time limit of the warning). There were mitigating circumstances (improper labeling), and you probably should have been let off, but it still doesn't quite fit OP's premise.

You'd need examples, or better yet, statistics showing that judges tend to be harsher than juries for traffic violations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144025290.0" user="CDRCool" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. I’ve heard of this going terribly. In Philadelphia, everyone keeps turning left even when the left arrow goes away for maybe two to three more cars. A dude got a ticket for it, fought it with the “everyone does this” defense and the guy elected to have a jury. Judge tells the jury what the law is. They decide that his turning left without yielding to traffic did happen so he’s guilty. Ticket plus court fees which now include a jury. 

I have gone to court twice for speeding and once for registration and the judges reminded me of cops. They seemed like they wanted me to be sorry and try better and were relatively accommodating in punishing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144269400.0" user="princessCuck" delta="False">
    <text>That's what appeals are for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144791678.0" user="Nergaal" delta="False">
    <text>But &amp;gt;24h means you were technically guilty.  The OP argument is about when you are not guilty.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30145396242.0" user="pagsball" delta="False">
    <text>The rest of my post explains why I was not. The signs were invalid. And the law itself is gray about timing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143521240.0" user="EnviroTron" delta="False">
    <text>Traffic court is structured significantly differently than criminal court. I understand you comparison, but for the most part, traffic violations dont typically warrant a jury of peers. Ive been to traffic court several times and a jury was never an option. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
