<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="31" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30144843618.0" user="VladMolina" delta="False">
    <text>If you hire a competent lawyer, they will be at least as aware of the above as you are, and they will make a recommendation to you about whether to shoot for a judge or jury trial.  Their incentives are fairly well aligned with yours, since success or failure reflects on their skills as a lawyer.  They are also aware of a wide variety of other issues which might be to your advantage in a trial by jury.  Much of this would vary from case to case, from locality to locality, from defendant to defendant, or even based on what judge is assigned to your case.

You should take a chance with a jury IF you have a competent lawyer who tells you that you should.  That's why.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
