<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30142933451.0" user="WmPitcher" delta="False">
    <text>There's a variant of a saying about facts and law on your side. It goes, 'If you don't have the facts on your side, you want a judge. If you don't have the law on your side, you want a jury. And if you don't have either on your side, you want OJs legal team.'

Whether you want a jury depends on your story. For example, if you are innocent, but an otherwise unsavoury character, you probably want a judge. However, it depends on the judge you draw. Some lean so hard on the side of guilty for some types of crimes, you might want a jury.  Conversely, if you come across like your community's guardian angel, you probably want a jury. 

So, knowing nothing else, I would agree with you, go for a judge. However, you would be foolish not to explore everything else and make your decision based with that extra knowledge. Under many situations, you would reach a different conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144129396.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>So... If you're Batman, go judge or jury? Is he a guardian angel, or an unsavoury character? :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30144158353.0" user="WmPitcher" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on which movie he is in.  ;-)  Still have to be careful to get the judge you need and not the judge you deserve.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
