<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30143032832.0" user="ZaRocket" delta="False">
    <text>With a judge, 1 out of 1 person has to find you not guilty. With a jury, 1 out of 12 people has to find you not guilty (to at least get a hung jury).  I'll take those odds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143072263.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Which is fantastic if you are guilty.

But if you aren't guilty then all it takes is one person to feel you are guilty to cause a hung jury.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143082160.0" user="ZaRocket" delta="False">
    <text>I'll take multiple hung jury trials over a guilty verdict. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143096476.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>So you would rather go through constant trial after trial, dragging your name through the media and exposing your friends and family to the unrelenting eyes of the world, than have to make an appeal?

If you reach s guilty verdict then one of two things has happened.

1 - You failed to present reasonable doubt and chances are you actually did commit the crime. This also applies to a Judge trial.

2 - Jury nullification which is remedied by an appeal. This doesn't happen in a Judge trial because judges will only act on the admissible evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143143901.0" user="ZaRocket" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't the premise that you are innocent?  You are making a ton of assumptions here...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143481869.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Your premise is a guilty verdict.

Under that premise I am assuming the only way for you to be found guilty is that you are guilty, or that the decision maker(s) find(s) you guilty despite you innocence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143674778.0" user="YborOgre" delta="False">
    <text>Not your job to present reasonable doubt. You are burden shifting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143682716.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>It is absolutely the role of the defense to present reasonable doubt.

The Prosecution explains why you did something. Then the defense pokes it full of holes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143710302.0" user="YborOgre" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry. Not really. Prosecution has to prove a case beyond reasonable doubt. Defense has no obligation to present anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143730631.0" user="YborOgre" delta="False">
    <text>Also. Jury nullification is NOT appealable. Ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143766773.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>1 - If prosecution proves beyond a doubt, then it is the job of the defense to present doubt. Whether thst is the de jure job or de facto, it is what the defense does.

Actually they do have an obligation. At least in Canada they have the obligation to do everything in their power to represent their client.

If the prosecution present a a video showing the accused murdering someone, the defense is still then obligated to examine thst evidence and try to find flaws with it or the story it tells.

At the very least the defense points out why reasonable doubt still exists. Because Who else would do that?

That is literally the reason they are called the defense.

If there is no evidence to defend against then the case wouldn't have gone to court.

2 - Jury Nullification is appealable. Jury Nullification is not just when someone is acquitted who broke the law, it is also when someone is convicted who was innocent. Who (in most countries anyways) has the ability to appeal the conviction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143094882.0" user="spaceunicorncadet" delta="False">
    <text>And all it takes is one person, in the judge situation, to convict; you don't even have a mistrial option. Judge thinks you're guilty, even if you aren't, and that's it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143103181.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>When does that happen?

That happens when you failed to produce reasonable doubt, in which case statistically you did the crime.

Or it happens due to jury nullification, which doesn't happen with judges because they make decisions based purely on the admissible evidence.

Even if they did commit jury nullification (judge nullification) you can appeal and go to a Judge which has a better track record.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143147743.0" user="spaceunicorncadet" delta="False">
    <text>You posit that in a jury trial, it only takes one person thinking you're guilty to make a hung jury, even if you are actually innocent.

My point is that the odds aren't any better with a judge trial.  Still only takes one person.

I'd rather have an 11-1 jury than a 0-1 judge, even if I can appeal.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
