<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30143863426.0" user="TuckerMcG" delta="False">
    <text>You’re overlooking the strategic advantages afforded by voir dire (the jury selection process). For instance, studies have shown that female jurors are more likely to have a bias against a female accuser in a rape case. If you’ve been alleged of rape, having your lawyer select for female jurors via voir dire increases your chances of obtaining a not guilty verdict. 

The classic example of this was the jury selected for OJ Simpson’s trial. If that were an all-white jury, he would’ve been convicted easily. Instead, jurors have come out and said they voted not guilty because they saw this as a chance to get back at “the system” for how it unfairly treats minorities, and the all-black jury voted to acquit.

So whether a judge or a jury is preferable depends heavily on the facts of the case and whether you can select a jury that will be extra-sympathetic to you as a defendant. There is never a clear cut best course of action that never fails in the law - there are times where a judge would be better and times where a jury would be better. That’s just how the law works. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143930452.0" user="uiri" delta="False">
    <text>By the end of the [OJ Simpson] trial, the jury composition broke down as nine black jurors, one hispanic and two white. There were 10 women and two men

I'm not sure where you heard that the jury in that case was all black.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
