<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30143786640.0" user="makronic" delta="False">
    <text>Judges in my experience are more impartial than a jury (source: lawyer, but not criminal lawyer). However, you've made an assumption that juries cannot be biased towards you, and that a fair determination based on the facts necessarily works in favour of the truth.

I'll deal with the second point first. Whether it is a judge or a jury, your hope is that a detailed investigation of the matter, and the chance to have it tested in court. Generally that is the case, but every once in a while, facts will be such that the evidence will point towards guilt. I'm dealing with several cases like this right now (not in the criminal jurisdiciton, but relating to criminal matters). So there will be some cases in which an impassionate judge looking at the evidence will likely find guilt.

Which brings me to the other point. Sometimes the bias of juries works in your favour. Where an impassionate judge will pay attention to the evidence which points towards your guilt, but might be unmoved by human factors which juries might be susceptible to. Judges have also seen hundreds of cases, many of them will have similar facts to yours, and if your facts are similar to those they have found guilty, it is not difficult to imagine that the judge will rely on their previous judgement. Not to say that the judge is being lazy or inattentive to the specific facts of your case, or being intentionally biased, but it is their very experience that you're relying on which might prejudice you.

Judges are also not perfect rational actors. They will each have their idiosyncrasies, and lawyers who regularly appear in their court will know them. For example, some judges might fairly consistently decide one way for a particular set of facts because their interpretation of the law leans that way, or they might weigh certain types of evidence more heavily than others, or they might be more pragmatic than academic in the way they rule. 

You're much better off deciding whether to use a jury on a case by case basis, guided by your legal team, who will understand how juries are likely to behave or react to a certain set of facts, and the peculiarities of the judge/s who might hear the case. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
