<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30142902525.0" user="BeatriceBernardo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained,

I think about the less points of failure. Let's say you are innocent, and your 'victim' is corrupt. All they need is to bribe one judge. In fact, because judges have been judging for a while, it is possible to predict the judge's reaction to bribes. Bribing a panel of jury is more risky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30142934394.0" user="Mimshot" delta="False">
    <text>Worrying that the judge is taking a bribe seems like a rather extreme situation. Perhaps I should have phrased it as by default I should prefer a judge to a jury. I'm not saying that the right to a jury should go away, but just that if I'm not guilty I should trust one professional  to get it right over twelve random people who couldn't get out of jury duty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143042787.0" user="BeatriceBernardo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Worrying that the judge is taking a bribe seems like a rather extreme situation

That is not extreme at all. It could be bribes, it could be bias, it could be bigotry, it could me many things. The issue is the single point of failure. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143210574.0" user="DrunkFishBreatheAir" delta="False">
    <text>why is a bribed judge extreme? It's known to currently happen in America ([for example](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kids_for_cash_scandal))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143587802.0" user="4_jacks" delta="False">
    <text>because when it happens, they get a Wikipedia page about it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143510362.0" user="darkforcedisco" delta="False">
    <text>Judges *are* often elected officials, and some of them may owe favors to certain parties. If a judge is on the fence about your crime, and the decision to send you to jail is something that can be relatively easy to argue and scratch someone else's back at the same time, you may be out of luck.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
