<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="481581918.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7ypyzi/cmv_if_im_not_guilty_i_want_to_be_tried_by_a/">
    <title>CMV: If I'm not guilty, I want to be tried by a judge rather than a jury</title>
    <original_poster>Mimshot</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the American criminal justice system you have the *right* to a jury trial, but you are not obligated to exercise your right a jury. It's possible to have what's known as a "bench trial" where in addition to determining the admissibility of evidence, and sentencing if convicted, the judge determines guilt or innocence as well.

Jury trials are notoriously unpredictable, therefore if I'm actually not guilty of a crime, I want a professional judging my case. Historically, bench trials result in acquittals [more often than from juries](http://www.abajournal.com/magazine/article/judge_v_judge). I understand wanting to be judged by someone who never saw inadmissible evidence, if I'm guilty but the evidence was illegally obtained, but if I'm actually not guilty, why should I take a chance with a jury?

Change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30143578018.0" user="4_jacks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Historically, bench trials result in acquittals more often than from juries.

This is flawed by the fact that defendants ONLY choose a Jury Trial after their lawyer has seen who the judge is and made a recommendation that the defendant chose the Jury over that particular Judge. 

A bench trial SHOULD result in more acquittals!  Selecting a Jury isn't 100% random 50/50 becuase the lawyers will try to weed out jurors they think will not favor them.  (Let's be honest they weed you out by race/age/sex/job description)  But they know more about the judge then they ever do about the random jury selection. Hopefully the lawyer has experience with the judge. At the very least the lawyer can look up the judge's record with similar crimes and defendants.  Even in past jury trials the judge sets the punishment.  So a judge will be known for being lenient or strict. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30143680651.0" user="YborOgre" delta="False">
    <text>Also, you only opt for a bench trial generally in very minor offenses, where no one gives a shit. Only an idiot would go for a bench trial with real time attached. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
