<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="483439173.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7zts1x/cmv_an_econ_phd_program_is_the_best_decision_for/">
    <title>CMV: An econ PhD program is the best decision for me</title>
    <original_poster>GrandHomework</original_poster>
    <original_post>Background: I am 26, male, have no responsibilities outside of my full-time job, and have an undergraduate degree in finance. Currently, I make $68,000 a year and will consistently receive industry average raises, bonuses, and promotions. I’m happy with my current position and can imagine myself happy here for a long time. On a scale of 1-10, 1 being pig trough cleaner and 10 being dream job, I’d put myself at a 6.5 right now.

My reasoning for why I believe a PhD makes sense:

1.	There are very few things constant in my life, but one of them has been a lifelong passion for learning. I don’t play video games, watch Netflix, rarely hang out with friends like the average person, but rather spend all my leisure learning. As a result, I’ve amassed a great deal of knowledge over the years, and I find it unfulfilling if I don’t put it to good use. Aside from using it to play devil’s advocate on this sub with my actual account, of course.  From what I know about academia, a genuine interest in perpetual learning is a key to success.

2.	The general advice is to not get PhDs for the money. Maybe less so for econ, but I do it as a safety measure for employment, not as a foot in the door to private equity. I don’t care about money as long as my basic needs are met. More money is nice, yes, but I could live with my current salary for the rest of my life perfectly fine. I come from a pretty poor family, and have no desire for conspicuous consumption. While in undergrad, I once subsisted off of less than $2 a day for food and drink. Money is not more important to me than spending 40 (or more) hours a week doing something that I find meaningful.

3.	I have a life goal of being at least being remembered, somewhat. I can’t be an actor, or a singer, or a hockey player, but I have a chance of being remembered as an econ professor that students enjoyed learning from, or a researcher who helped publish a groundbreaking study. I'd die satisfied in these scenarios. Not to say that I’m using a PhD as a prop for an ego boost, but as a secondary function (to teaching and furthering research) that makes my career more fulfilling. This is something that I can’t do at my current position, as I’ll probably only ever be remembered by that guy in the company, which is very unfulfilling to me.

Possible avenues to change my view:

a.	Although I mentioned economic PhD program in particular in the title, I am open to entertaining other ideas. Though I’m not sure what transfers just as well from a finance undergrad. Keep in mind it's generally regarded that econ PhDs are very employable relative to other PhDs.

b.	Although my ability to reason is pretty good, my skill at math is quite low. I’d consider myself slightly below average for a STEM student. Competing students that are naturally gifted at such (which economic PhD programs tend to attract) will inherently have the upper hand on me throughout grad school.

c.	Any other opportunity costs of doing a PhD, which is 5-7 years. Keep in mind I don’t really care for money, not more than doing something with my life that is meaningful to me.

d.	The possibility that I will hate research. If most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing, which I have done happily for most of my life leisurely (sometimes on the topic of econ), I have very little reason to believe the same won’t hold true in the future.

e.	That I should get a master’s degree first. Theoretically if all goes well I will start my PhD at 27 or 28, which is pretty good timing. If I spend two years receiving a master’s degree first, I will be forced to complete a PhD program at a much later age.

f.	Anything else about being a PhD student I don’t know.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30157557372.0" user="pappypapaya" delta="False">
    <text>It worries me that you didn't convey an informed and passionate idea of what you may want to work on in your PhD within economics. You did not articulate why you want to pursue a PhD in economics in particular, nor did you mention any particular research areas within economics that you would like to pursue during your PhD, nor what skills and methods you expect to gain to achieve these goals. These are important things to know, as you should have at least an idea of what you are looking for in a department and its faculty in terms of research areas before you apply. The admissions committee will also likely want to see this forethought conveyed in your statement of purpose essay and interviews. The reasons you did give are important but superficial in comparison. If you can't answer these questions, you need to think about this more before deciding to apply.

Actually, you don't seem to even have a clear idea of what research in economics consists of, if you had to ask "if most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing". Depending on your subdiscipline, you'll likely be doing a lot of mathematical modeling, statistical analysis, designing and conducting experiments, maybe some field work, and yes reading and writing but not only. It doesn't seem like you have a clear idea of what you'll be doing, which again suggests you need to think about this more before deciding.

If you're worried about math, economics is a very quantitative field, even for the more empirical subfields. Your core classes will likely contain a lot of probability, statistics, linear algebra, calculus, game theory, differential equations, and proof writing. This will be true at likely any decent PhD program in economics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30158701710.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>You're not the only person to have noticed this vital missing piece of my PhD puzzle. It strikes them odd when I tell advisers the reasons why I want a PhD, yet have not delved into a 10 minute layout of a mastermind plan. 

This is an important thing for most people, but not for me. Economics as a field of study is not simply communism vs capitalism or supply vs demand; it runs the gamut of behavioral, to ecological, to classical Keynesian and everything in between. Trust me, I'm still in the process of determining what this is, and when a final decision is realized, it'll be just as wholesome when I put it all together. 

&amp;gt;Actually, you don't seem to even have a clear idea of what research in economics consists of, if you had to ask "if most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing".

It was an over generalization of graduate school in general, when I should have been more specific about econ graduate school. But yes, I'm aware of the quant heavy nature of econ.

I've not only been worried, but self conscious about my mathematical ability my whole life.  I've acknowledged it as a crutch, but just through sheer effort, I've managed quite well for the most part, I'd say. Top 15% GPA in undergrad, and I have reason to believe my performance at my current job is on par. Unless you think sheer effort somehow does not translate well into graduate level mathematical requirements or is simply not enough, of course.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
