<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="483439173.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7zts1x/cmv_an_econ_phd_program_is_the_best_decision_for/">
    <title>CMV: An econ PhD program is the best decision for me</title>
    <original_poster>GrandHomework</original_poster>
    <original_post>Background: I am 26, male, have no responsibilities outside of my full-time job, and have an undergraduate degree in finance. Currently, I make $68,000 a year and will consistently receive industry average raises, bonuses, and promotions. I’m happy with my current position and can imagine myself happy here for a long time. On a scale of 1-10, 1 being pig trough cleaner and 10 being dream job, I’d put myself at a 6.5 right now.

My reasoning for why I believe a PhD makes sense:

1.	There are very few things constant in my life, but one of them has been a lifelong passion for learning. I don’t play video games, watch Netflix, rarely hang out with friends like the average person, but rather spend all my leisure learning. As a result, I’ve amassed a great deal of knowledge over the years, and I find it unfulfilling if I don’t put it to good use. Aside from using it to play devil’s advocate on this sub with my actual account, of course.  From what I know about academia, a genuine interest in perpetual learning is a key to success.

2.	The general advice is to not get PhDs for the money. Maybe less so for econ, but I do it as a safety measure for employment, not as a foot in the door to private equity. I don’t care about money as long as my basic needs are met. More money is nice, yes, but I could live with my current salary for the rest of my life perfectly fine. I come from a pretty poor family, and have no desire for conspicuous consumption. While in undergrad, I once subsisted off of less than $2 a day for food and drink. Money is not more important to me than spending 40 (or more) hours a week doing something that I find meaningful.

3.	I have a life goal of being at least being remembered, somewhat. I can’t be an actor, or a singer, or a hockey player, but I have a chance of being remembered as an econ professor that students enjoyed learning from, or a researcher who helped publish a groundbreaking study. I'd die satisfied in these scenarios. Not to say that I’m using a PhD as a prop for an ego boost, but as a secondary function (to teaching and furthering research) that makes my career more fulfilling. This is something that I can’t do at my current position, as I’ll probably only ever be remembered by that guy in the company, which is very unfulfilling to me.

Possible avenues to change my view:

a.	Although I mentioned economic PhD program in particular in the title, I am open to entertaining other ideas. Though I’m not sure what transfers just as well from a finance undergrad. Keep in mind it's generally regarded that econ PhDs are very employable relative to other PhDs.

b.	Although my ability to reason is pretty good, my skill at math is quite low. I’d consider myself slightly below average for a STEM student. Competing students that are naturally gifted at such (which economic PhD programs tend to attract) will inherently have the upper hand on me throughout grad school.

c.	Any other opportunity costs of doing a PhD, which is 5-7 years. Keep in mind I don’t really care for money, not more than doing something with my life that is meaningful to me.

d.	The possibility that I will hate research. If most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing, which I have done happily for most of my life leisurely (sometimes on the topic of econ), I have very little reason to believe the same won’t hold true in the future.

e.	That I should get a master’s degree first. Theoretically if all goes well I will start my PhD at 27 or 28, which is pretty good timing. If I spend two years receiving a master’s degree first, I will be forced to complete a PhD program at a much later age.

f.	Anything else about being a PhD student I don’t know.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30157305866.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The possibility that I will hate research. If most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing, which I have done happily for most of my life leisurely (sometimes on the topic of econ), I have very little reason to believe the same won’t hold true in the future.

This is probably the biggest one. I know a lot of people who loved taking the classes, but found the actual research something they couldn't handle.

There is a lot of reading/writing involved, but it's not the same cycle as classwork. The majority of your time is going to be spent on your actual experiment- first designing them, then fixing stuff. often that's going to mean doing mundane stuff like trying to get that damn database to download properly. I'd estimate i don't really spend more than 30% of my time reading or writing, and that's pretty generous, it's probably less. Reading others people's work can help you clarify things/be inspiring, but it doesn't produce results. And you can only write after having some results worth writing about. The bulk is getting those results.

Research is perpetual learning, but it's a very different flavor from reading-learning

&amp;gt;I have a life goal of being at least being remembered, somewhat. If I can’t be an actor, or a singer, or a hockey player, but I can be remembered as that econ professor that students enjoy learning from or published a groundbreaking study, I'd die satisfied. Not to say that I’m using a tenured professor position as a prop for an ego boost, but as a secondary function (to teaching and furthering research) that makes my career more fulfilling. This is something that I can’t do at my current position, as I’ll probably only ever be remembered by that guy in the company, which is very unfulfilling to me.

Getting an econ PhD is no guarantee of a life in academia. In every field, we produce *way* more PhDs than there could ever be faculty positions. That means that competition for academic spots are cut throat.

If you aren't coming from a top program, it's going to be tough. Not impossible, but the cards are stacked against you. You'll also have to be pretty open to moving around the country to land a job opening, and tenure is pretty reliant on staying in 1 place.

I'm not sure about economics, but in a lot of STEM fields, you can also expect to spend another 2-4ish years(YMMV) after you get your degree doing postdocs.

&amp;gt; That I should get a master’s degree first. Theoretically if all goes well I will start my PhD at 27 or 28, which is pretty good timing. If I spend two years receiving a master’s degree first, I will be forced to complete a PhD program at a much later age.

I'm not sure if econ PhDs are different, but in a lot of physics programs, you get your masters regardless.

&amp;gt;Although my ability to reason is pretty good, my skill at math is quite low. I’d consider myself slightly below average for a STEM student. Competing students that are naturally gifted at such (which economic PhD programs tend to attract) will inherently have the upper hand on me throughout grad school.

This will hamper you a bit, although it's hard to say how much. It's entirely possible to be a good economist without the most stellar math skills. But it'll make classes a bit harder, and it's going to limit your research a bit. Odds are, you probably aren't going to be a hardcore theory guy. That means you're more likely to end up in econometrics or something more 'applied'


(This is a pretty weak CMV, i'll be honest as a grad student myself i find it hard to recommend anyone not do it as long as they'll love it. the biggest weeder out by far is whether you actually like research or not)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30157380000.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Getting an econ PhD is no guarantee of a life in academia. In every field, we produce way more PhDs than there could ever be faculty positions. That means that competition for academic spots are cut throat.

&amp;gt;If you aren't coming from a top program, it's going to be tough. Not impossible, but the cards are stacked against you. You'll also have to be pretty open to moving around the country to land a job opening, and tenure is pretty reliant on staying in 1 place.

I'm well aware of the oversupply of academic hopefuls, but it doesn't bother me too much. Coupled with the fact that I don't foresee myself coming out of a top tier program, I honestly don't mind starting low at like a nonranked college, or even a community college and try to work my way up. In addition, I actually like and welcome the idea of traveling (constantly or not) for a career. My current understanding is that you don't just finish up a PhD, and the results of that dictates a final certainty of whether or not you have been granted access into academia. The continual gaining of experience for years after that can potentially open doors to academia.

&amp;gt;I'm not sure if econ PhDs are different, but in a lot of physics programs, you get your masters regardless.

For most econ programs, it's the same. When I mentioned doing a master's first in the OP, it was because people recommend I do a 2 year program first to see if I actually enjoy going into higher ed to do research instead of jumping right into a full blown 5-7 commitment for some of the prime years of my life. But yeah, I definitely can just leave the PhD program halfway through and still at least have a master's, but knowing me I'd probably not do that.

&amp;gt;Odds are, you probably aren't going to be a hardcore theory guy. That means you're more likely to end up in econometrics or something more 'applied'

I disagree. Natural mathematical ability has no relation to a person's ability to theorize or solve overtly abstract problems. I don't believe that highly theoretical positions in econ are reserved for only the mathematically gifted.

I'm confused. When you say this is a pretty weak CMV, are you saying my OP is too easily changeable, or there is little chance your response will receive a delta from me? Because if it's the latter, I will definitely reward, but only if you change my view.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30157435939.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When I mentioned doing a master's first in the OP, it was because people recommend I do a 2 year program first to see if I actually enjoy going into higher ed to do research instead of jumping right into a full blown 5-7 commitment for some of the prime years of my life. But yeah, I definitely can just leave the PhD program halfway through and still at least have a master's, but knowing me I'd probably not do that.

Not sure if it's different for econ, so YMMV. But in physics, the amount of exposure we got to research was very low. Generally speaking, the first 2 years (which are the masters), are almost entirely classes, very little/no research. I wouldn't recommend it.

There's also no real cost (to you) for applying as a PhD student, and just leaving after the masters.

Also, FWIW,most programs (in STEM) aren't looking for masters students, so counter intuitively, you're better off applying as a PhD candidate. If you just want the masters, apply as a PhD and leave early, no one minds. I know people that wanted their masters and were actively told to apply as PhD for funding reasons.

In programs i've seen, the PhD students outnumber people explicitly there for their masters by a large margin. Most funding is for PhD students, whereas if you just want the masters they're way stingier with offering funding. (You can always fund it yourself, of course, but a stipid+tuition waiver is still pretty significant)

&amp;gt;Natural mathematical ability has no relation to a person's ability to theorize or solve overtly abstract problems. 

I would consider those mathematical ability. When you say not mathematically gifted, you mean not great at computation/arithmetic, i would not worry. Having an intuitive "feel" for things is what matters, it's very closely tied to being able to theorize/solve abstract problems (although there are theory/abstract problems that aren't super rigorously math based. so other types of intuition goes far)

edit:
Although i will say, most people have a lot more math intuition than they give themselves credit for. 

&amp;gt;When you say this is a pretty weak CMV, are you saying my OP is too easily changeable, or there is little chance your response will receive a delta from me? Because if it's the latter, I will definitely reward, but only if you change my view.


Poor wording on my part. I was saying I'm not trying very hard to change your mind, because i'm biased and would want you to try your hand at the PhD. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30158808019.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Not sure if it's different for econ, so YMMV. But in physics, the amount of exposure we got to research was very low. Generally speaking, the first 2 years (which are the masters), are almost entirely classes, very little/no research. I wouldn't recommend it.

I should have been more clear. Econ is kind of similar, there's lots of classes in econometrics and statistics and such, and almost no research. My assumption was that I'd will myself to be proactive in forming relationships with professors and network for the opportunity to do research on top of my master's course load. This will give me a feel for research, and whether I'm willing to spend the rest of my life doing it.

&amp;gt;There's also no real cost (to you) for applying as a PhD student, and just leaving after the masters.

&amp;gt;Also, FWIW,most programs (in STEM) aren't looking for masters students, so counter intuitively, you're better off applying as a PhD candidate. If you just want the masters, apply as a PhD and leave early, no one minds. I know people that wanted their masters and were actively told to apply as PhD for funding reasons.

&amp;gt;In programs i've seen, the PhD students outnumber people explicitly there for their masters by a large margin. Most funding is for PhD students, whereas if you just want the masters they're way stingier with offering funding. (You can always fund it yourself, of course, but a stipid+tuition waiver is still pretty significant)

This bit didn't change my view, but is very practical information and I'll keep it in mind going forward. So thanks!

&amp;gt;I would consider those mathematical ability. When you say not mathematically gifted, you mean not great at computation/arithmetic, i would not worry. Having an intuitive "feel" for things is what matters, it's very closely tied to being able to theorize/solve abstract problems (although there are theory/abstract problems that aren't super rigorously math based. so other types of intuition goes far)

&amp;gt;edit: Although i will say, most people have a lot more math intuition than they give themselves credit for.

My definition of mathematically gifted means computation/arithmetic ability and also the intuitive ability to have a feel for it. I don't think I have both. However, I do not agree this has anything to do with a completely separate talent of a person, which is the ability to think abstractly. As a basic example, I'm sitting in a coffee shop at the moment, and (theoretically) I can theorize that many people have much more narrowed-focus under the influence of caffeine. I can conclude this theory, and this entire process did not require me doing any computations of any sort. Actually, I'm on the fence of whether or not (ceteris paribus) the natural or intuitive mathematical ability of a person will increase their separate ability to theorize or think abstractly. I'd love to be proven wrong though.

On another topic, are you doing theoretical physics? I've entertained that idea in the past (as I do have a genuine interest), considered my natural mathematical ability and laughed at the thought of myself brushing shoulders with the top .00001% of the mathematically gifted in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30157575658.0" user="pappypapaya" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I honestly don't mind starting low at like a nonranked college, or even a community college and try to work my way up.

It usually goes the other way. The top PhD programs produce the vast majority of professors at every level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30158874851.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>You may be right, but that doesn't discount the fact that I can't break into academia with my own method, no matter how stacked the odds are against me. If you can convince me otherwise, I'll reward you a delta.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
