<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="483439173.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7zts1x/cmv_an_econ_phd_program_is_the_best_decision_for/">
    <title>CMV: An econ PhD program is the best decision for me</title>
    <original_poster>GrandHomework</original_poster>
    <original_post>Background: I am 26, male, have no responsibilities outside of my full-time job, and have an undergraduate degree in finance. Currently, I make $68,000 a year and will consistently receive industry average raises, bonuses, and promotions. I’m happy with my current position and can imagine myself happy here for a long time. On a scale of 1-10, 1 being pig trough cleaner and 10 being dream job, I’d put myself at a 6.5 right now.

My reasoning for why I believe a PhD makes sense:

1.	There are very few things constant in my life, but one of them has been a lifelong passion for learning. I don’t play video games, watch Netflix, rarely hang out with friends like the average person, but rather spend all my leisure learning. As a result, I’ve amassed a great deal of knowledge over the years, and I find it unfulfilling if I don’t put it to good use. Aside from using it to play devil’s advocate on this sub with my actual account, of course.  From what I know about academia, a genuine interest in perpetual learning is a key to success.

2.	The general advice is to not get PhDs for the money. Maybe less so for econ, but I do it as a safety measure for employment, not as a foot in the door to private equity. I don’t care about money as long as my basic needs are met. More money is nice, yes, but I could live with my current salary for the rest of my life perfectly fine. I come from a pretty poor family, and have no desire for conspicuous consumption. While in undergrad, I once subsisted off of less than $2 a day for food and drink. Money is not more important to me than spending 40 (or more) hours a week doing something that I find meaningful.

3.	I have a life goal of being at least being remembered, somewhat. I can’t be an actor, or a singer, or a hockey player, but I have a chance of being remembered as an econ professor that students enjoyed learning from, or a researcher who helped publish a groundbreaking study. I'd die satisfied in these scenarios. Not to say that I’m using a PhD as a prop for an ego boost, but as a secondary function (to teaching and furthering research) that makes my career more fulfilling. This is something that I can’t do at my current position, as I’ll probably only ever be remembered by that guy in the company, which is very unfulfilling to me.

Possible avenues to change my view:

a.	Although I mentioned economic PhD program in particular in the title, I am open to entertaining other ideas. Though I’m not sure what transfers just as well from a finance undergrad. Keep in mind it's generally regarded that econ PhDs are very employable relative to other PhDs.

b.	Although my ability to reason is pretty good, my skill at math is quite low. I’d consider myself slightly below average for a STEM student. Competing students that are naturally gifted at such (which economic PhD programs tend to attract) will inherently have the upper hand on me throughout grad school.

c.	Any other opportunity costs of doing a PhD, which is 5-7 years. Keep in mind I don’t really care for money, not more than doing something with my life that is meaningful to me.

d.	The possibility that I will hate research. If most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing, which I have done happily for most of my life leisurely (sometimes on the topic of econ), I have very little reason to believe the same won’t hold true in the future.

e.	That I should get a master’s degree first. Theoretically if all goes well I will start my PhD at 27 or 28, which is pretty good timing. If I spend two years receiving a master’s degree first, I will be forced to complete a PhD program at a much later age.

f.	Anything else about being a PhD student I don’t know.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30157636706.0" user="pensivegargoyle" delta="False">
    <text>If you haven't done well in math up to now, you may not have the skills necessary for an economics PhD, which typically involves eating and breathing high-level math for years on end. That doesn't necessarily mean you should drop the idea but it could mean that you have more work to do first. Definitely have some discussions with economics faculty first to find out what's needed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30158721163.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that I haven't done well in math, it's that relative to my peers, my inherent ability is noticeably inferior. For instance, it may take me longer than a counterpart to solve a linear algebra equation, or to find the answer to a mental math problem, or to fully comprehend a mathematical theory in finance undergrad. I simply make up for this crutch through sheer effort, and be more useful as a PhD as a whole through talents I may have in other areas.

Unless you have reason to believe my sheer effort, or inherent inferiority in math does not translate well into a successful econ PhD undertaking, my view stands. As the saying goes, math can be learned. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
