<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488327251.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/82qjpv/cmvi_see_no_real_reason_to_avoid_resurrecting_an/">
    <title>CMV:I see no real reason to avoid resurrecting an extinct animal through cloning, and believe that fears of consequences are wildly overblown.</title>
    <original_poster>Runner_one</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jurassic Park, while a wildly entertaining movie, did a disservice to the public by planting irrational fears in the mind of the general public. 

While there is little chance of resurrecting a T-Rex or other dinosaur, we may be only a few years away from seeing a mammoth or saber-tooth walking the Earth again.  

Many people fear this and some are even actively working to prevent this from ever happening.

Some people argue that the introduction of foreign animals into an ecosystem would do much more damage than good. 

Less common but incredibly vocal are the people that see such experiments as an affront to God or Nature. 

Other people say that funds wasted on resurrecting an extinct animal could be better spent on conserving living animals.

I for one would be overjoyed to see news of living woolly mammoth walking the Earth again.  I also believe such an announcement would result in massive funding influx from private sources that could result even more scientific advances. These advances could have benefits for humans far beyond what we can imagine. 

A perfect example of such unforeseen advances are the many benefits brought about by the Space Race.  There are far too many to list here, but [Wikipedia lists perhaps over a hundred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies). I fully believe such spinoffs in biology would greatly benefit mankind. 
   

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30192815212.0" user="tchaffee" delta="False">
    <text>I do agree this would be a big win for science and we may discover many important things in the fields of biology and beyond. And it also just sounds very cool. But I would put a condition on it that we still have to wait.

Simply look at what we've done to the planet so far. Climate change is threatening to wipe out vast ecosystems and make even more animals extinct. The oceans are dying from both that and literally billions of tons of plastic and other garbage. We can no longer safely eat bigger fish because they contain toxic levels of industrial metals. In pretty much any ecosystem that humans have tried to "fix", we end up with really undesirable results. We've introduced new species before (starlings to America, and rabbits in australia are two examples) and it has never turned out good.

How many species are we responsible for making extinct?

If we can't take care of the existing wildlife already here, why introduce even more complications?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193171168.0" user="Runner_one" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see a valid reason why we can't do both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193336819.0" user="tchaffee" delta="False">
    <text>We are barely cleaning up the mess we have made already and we still don't even know if we can fix climate change in time to save our own species. 

We have demonstrated we cannot manage the species already alive in a responsible way. 

It sounds like a kid who has gotten into an accident every time he takes the car out and now he wants to put a trailer on the car. "This time it will be different, I promise". Well no. Drive the car safely a few times kiddo and then we'll think about putting a trailer on it and complicating things.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
