<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488327251.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/82qjpv/cmvi_see_no_real_reason_to_avoid_resurrecting_an/">
    <title>CMV:I see no real reason to avoid resurrecting an extinct animal through cloning, and believe that fears of consequences are wildly overblown.</title>
    <original_poster>Runner_one</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jurassic Park, while a wildly entertaining movie, did a disservice to the public by planting irrational fears in the mind of the general public. 

While there is little chance of resurrecting a T-Rex or other dinosaur, we may be only a few years away from seeing a mammoth or saber-tooth walking the Earth again.  

Many people fear this and some are even actively working to prevent this from ever happening.

Some people argue that the introduction of foreign animals into an ecosystem would do much more damage than good. 

Less common but incredibly vocal are the people that see such experiments as an affront to God or Nature. 

Other people say that funds wasted on resurrecting an extinct animal could be better spent on conserving living animals.

I for one would be overjoyed to see news of living woolly mammoth walking the Earth again.  I also believe such an announcement would result in massive funding influx from private sources that could result even more scientific advances. These advances could have benefits for humans far beyond what we can imagine. 

A perfect example of such unforeseen advances are the many benefits brought about by the Space Race.  There are far too many to list here, but [Wikipedia lists perhaps over a hundred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies). I fully believe such spinoffs in biology would greatly benefit mankind. 
   

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30192891079.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Let's put aside the more existential reasons and focus on one big one: why? Yeah, it'd be pretty cool to have mammoths walking around, but at what cost? Anything like this would certainly be obscenely expensive, and who would benefit from it?

I don't have a moral opposition to cloning extinct animals, but I don't see the benefits outweighing the costs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193178433.0" user="Runner_one" delta="False">
    <text>New studies seem to indicate that the ecosystem of the far north tundra has been substantially impacted by the loss of mammoths. One recent study suggests that the reintroduction of large herds mammoths would increase carbon sequestration many fold. Is that not a great benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193204701.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Keeping with a cost/benefit look at things: How strongly does the ecosystem of the far north tundra affect most people's lives? If we're going to fund cloning, wouldn't it be of far greater impact to focus on creating human tissue and organs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193224663.0" user="molarunit" delta="False">
    <text>Actually carbon sequestration in that region is a huge deal! I don't know how mammoths would contribute, so I cant talk about that, but I do know that as climate change raises global temperatures its causing the permafrost (the layer dirt deep in the ground that stays frozen year round) to melt, releasing buckets of CO2 that's been locked away for millennia back into the atmosphere, making the problem worse. So who knows, maybe mammoths could help with that? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193247992.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I really don't see how... and given how detrimental cows can be in producing methane, I don't think mammoths would provide much of a benefit we couldn't otherwise reproduce. I'm not really qualified to talk about how mammoths affect the ecosystem in the frozen tundra, but back to the original point: Cost is a real reason to avoid resurrecting an extinct animal, when the money could be spent much more wisely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193313745.0" user="molarunit" delta="False">
    <text>I just thought id share that carbon capture in the tundra is a big deal, I also have no idea how mammoths would effect the current meta of their old ecosystem, though I cant imagine things have changed changed much since mammoths left, its only been a few thousand years, and don't yaks live there? I imagine they would fill the same niche. 

As for cost though, theoretically your only expense would be cloning a few mammoths embryos and implanting them in elephant wombs, and then once you've got a breeding population of maybe 60 you can let them go. Weve done the same thing for other animal populations in the past (minus the elephant wombs part) without breaking the bank, and depending on the benefits, we could be getting a very good return on the investment. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30195176291.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>NO! Because a real, live mammoth would just be intensely awesomely amazing! Cloning human organs? Pish-posh. Bring back the mammoth I say!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193936879.0" user="Shifter1000" delta="False">
    <text>I think this a little bit of the dunning-krueger effect in action. Ecological systems are *very* complex systems, and the differential equations we create to model these systems are based on a finite number of variable, which are far from complete and and far from precise.  From the outside, it might seem simple that adding mammoths to the tundra would fix tundra microclimates by packing brush down with fertilizer. However, this isn't based in a thorough understanding, and if you delved into the ecology, you'd find that there are far more uncertainties than you expect. The ecology of these environments have significantly changed since the extinction of the mammoth, even though it's a relatively recent extinction. The reality is, we don't have a good way of knowing what would happen, just like introducing any foreign species.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30195173995.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>So what? Mammoths roaming the tundra! That's just too awesome *not* to kick off.

Besides, come summertime the mammoths will just roast to death.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193249436.0" user="AlphaGoGoDancer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm nowhere near that field, but as a layman I could see this technology being really useful to curb the mass extinction event we're currently living through.

I don't know that there is specific value in being able to ressurect a wooly mammoth specifically, but maybe we can use the technology to clone species that currently are on the brink of extention, modifying them to be a bit more like their immediate anscestors (to bring back genetic diversity), and keep their species alive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
