<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488327251.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/82qjpv/cmvi_see_no_real_reason_to_avoid_resurrecting_an/">
    <title>CMV:I see no real reason to avoid resurrecting an extinct animal through cloning, and believe that fears of consequences are wildly overblown.</title>
    <original_poster>Runner_one</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jurassic Park, while a wildly entertaining movie, did a disservice to the public by planting irrational fears in the mind of the general public. 

While there is little chance of resurrecting a T-Rex or other dinosaur, we may be only a few years away from seeing a mammoth or saber-tooth walking the Earth again.  

Many people fear this and some are even actively working to prevent this from ever happening.

Some people argue that the introduction of foreign animals into an ecosystem would do much more damage than good. 

Less common but incredibly vocal are the people that see such experiments as an affront to God or Nature. 

Other people say that funds wasted on resurrecting an extinct animal could be better spent on conserving living animals.

I for one would be overjoyed to see news of living woolly mammoth walking the Earth again.  I also believe such an announcement would result in massive funding influx from private sources that could result even more scientific advances. These advances could have benefits for humans far beyond what we can imagine. 

A perfect example of such unforeseen advances are the many benefits brought about by the Space Race.  There are far too many to list here, but [Wikipedia lists perhaps over a hundred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies). I fully believe such spinoffs in biology would greatly benefit mankind. 
   

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30192912118.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>Let's step away from even cloned animals for a minute.

Putting an animal into a foreign ecosystem is typically a bad idea, and catastrophic for the ecosystem. Ask any biologist about invasive species, and they will tell you that they are generally a horrible thing.

And that's just taking a non-extinct animal to a new geographical location where it has no natural predators.

Imagine what sorts of ecological disasters will occur when you bring in a species that has been extinct for potentially hundreds of millions of years. Almost no living animal species today, save for some species of Alligator, have ever shared the planet with a T-Rex, and I'm not even sure about the alligator here. No prey is equipped with defense mechanisms to guard against a T-Rex, and no predator can compete with a T-Rex.

Bringing a T-Rex back will likely cause the extinction of more than one prey or predator animal in the regions the T-Rex hunts. 

EDIT: Yes yes, T-rex isn't an option, fine; replace with whatever other cloned animal and you get the same or similar problems (look at how honey bee global farming has harmed other pollinator species worldwide, or how rabbits have fucked up Australia for examples of non-carnivores)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193177356.0" user="codelapiz" delta="False">
    <text>don't think they would release them to the wild, if you think of the 1000s of tigers in shitty zoos around the world and how few of them escape, think about how unlikely it is one very well kept dinosaur would escape. and it is easy to kill it anyway its not like in the movies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193182330.0" user="Runner_one" delta="False">
    <text>I specifically excluded the T-Rex. I was referring to animals that have gone extinct much more recently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193208557.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>This still goes for basically any animal; A herbivore like a wooly mammoth will have advantages over other animals and will take from their limited food supply.

This is to say nothing of the effects of things like contamination from mosquitoes and other pests that will invariably feed on one of these animals at some point, introducing that blood and its' pathogens out into the wild

Keeping something like this contained is virtually impossible, and that's something that needs to be kept in mind when you talk about cloning an extinct species.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194189968.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>What about the Northern White Rhino, of which there is only one male left in the world and the species is effectively extinct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194214366.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>They have an ecosystem that we fucked up, rather than being prehistoric, so if we can clone them to save the species, then that's a good thing, but my verbiage was admittedly ambiguous. I mean specifically "bringing back" prehistoric animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194250993.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>But the Woolly Mammoth, which you mention, didn't go extinct in prehistoric times either - there was a population that managed to survive until 1650, so the species has only been extinct for about 370 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194288152.0" user="jerothattallguy" delta="False">
    <text>No they died out in the last ice age at least 5000 years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194288341.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>Well today I learned that public schooling has lied to me.

EDIT: A quick wikipedia check on this tells me that the last known colony died off some 4,000 years ago; not quite prehistory, but before it was humans driving extinction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194392908.0" user="Cultist_O" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 4,000 years ago; not quite prehistory, but before it was humans driving extinction

That's not necessarily true. There is a lot of evidence that human predation led to (or significantly contributed to) the extinction of a substantial number of megafauna starting even 10s of thousands of years ago.

That being said, I think the issue is (should be) more about how long it has been since the animal was removed from the ecosystem (and therefore how big a shock it's return would be) than it is about whose fault the removal was or wasn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197533953.0" user="ZeroControl" delta="False">
    <text>But that's what ecologists are for? Why does everyone assume that as soon as we are capable of cloning a species it will immediately be released into the wild without anyone studying its potential impact? I’m 100% on the side of the OP, assuming that proper research is conducted prior to releasing the species, which is something that most people seem to be ignoring. Sure there are plenty of instances where the introduction of a species has had profound effects on native ecosystems but there are also plenty of instances where targeted introductions have worked exceedingly well. Peoples often cite the introduction of rabbits, cane toads, etc. to Australia but I bet most people don’t know that Australia is also home to one of the most successful introduction programs in recent history, The Australian Dung beetle Project.

When European settlers introduced cattle and other livestock to the continent it resulted in a large build-up of dung in pastures. The native dung beetle fauna had evolved to feed on marsupial dung, which is entirely different to the large, wet, dung of cattle. Australia used to be home to beetles that could process such dung however the extinction of Australia’s mega fauna cut off their food source. To fix the problem the CSIRO spent decades and millions of dollars identifying exotic dung beetle species for introduction with the final project releasing over 43 exotic species, 23 of which remain established today. Trial releases of two new species began last year and they’re still identifying species for future introduction. Suppose we had the capacity to clone Australia’s extinct dung beetle species, in what way would cloning and releasing them differ from the introduction of species from Europe or Africa?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197538970.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>This is CMV, I have to oppose OP's view in a top-level post, and I try to give it my best effort. Truth be told I'm irritated that it got as popular as it did 'cause I keep getting this like 3 days later.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197561599.0" user="ZeroControl" delta="False">
    <text>No offence to you mate. Like I said most people only hear about the unsuccessful programs, you just happened to be the top post.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197568294.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>sorry that came off harsher than I meant it; I'm just tired and wasn't super-vested in this topic in the first place, so I don't really have a counter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197597759.0" user="ZeroControl" delta="False">
    <text>Nah your post is fine, I'm used to arguing with my friends so I get pretty combative. Free fun fact: they considered introducing a species of large dung beetle in order to control the cane toad population. When the toad tries to eat it the beetle literally rips its way out of the toads stomach.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197604003.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>Ow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193926913.0" user="aza9999" delta="False">
    <text>Moving away from giant predators like T-Rex, let's look at a simple humble toad.

[The cane toad](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cane_toad) was introduced to Australia to control the cane beetle. They instead spread throughout the country devastating many native species.

This is one of the most clear examples of introducing a foreign animal into an ecosystem that is not designed to handle it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30195171296.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>Why tho? A real live T-Rex would be so awesome and amazing as to immediately nullify any catastrophic ecological disaster. Who cares if all the bees die, there's a fucking T-Rex! Walking around biting heads off Japanese tourists! It's like goddamned Gozilla IRL!

This MUST be done for the sake of awesome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193247051.0" user="molarunit" delta="False">
    <text>I think the "unforeseeable effects on the ecosystem" is a weak argument against resurrecting an extinct species. Its a great argument for why we shouldn't release said species into the wild, but resurrecting, say, a t-rex, would not only make bank for whatever zoo its kept in but also be an amazing resource for paleontologists to study! Of course, it would be very easy to keep an eye on a t-rex and much harder on an ancient species of bug or microbe, but as long as we take the necessary precautions I think the potential benefits outweigh the risk. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193399199.0" user="Almora12" delta="False">
    <text>its most likely impossible for us to clone a T-rex because all the DNA is gone. a mammoth is plausible</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193547579.0" user="Ratfor" delta="False">
    <text>Actually I'm going to disagree with you here. T-Rex would probably do very, very poorly. First, due their cold blooded nature, that basically limits them to equatorial climates. The top predators in those climates are almost always big cats. A sleeping trex would make easy pray for an ambush predator like a panther, or a pack of lions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193567481.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>T-rex, I thought,along with other dinosaurs, have been confirmed avian, and not lizard as we once thought.

Secondly, even if this is true, part of the reason invasive species are so problematic is that predators don't immediately consume them (see: rabbits in Australia).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193917787.0" user="Shifter1000" delta="False">
    <text>I think the lion fish is a great illustration of this, for anyone looking for a concrete example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30194197245.0" user="NOQOL-RII" delta="False">
    <text>What if you only clone one and keep it in an artificial environment designed to replicate the animal's original habitat?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
