<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488327251.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/82qjpv/cmvi_see_no_real_reason_to_avoid_resurrecting_an/">
    <title>CMV:I see no real reason to avoid resurrecting an extinct animal through cloning, and believe that fears of consequences are wildly overblown.</title>
    <original_poster>Runner_one</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jurassic Park, while a wildly entertaining movie, did a disservice to the public by planting irrational fears in the mind of the general public. 

While there is little chance of resurrecting a T-Rex or other dinosaur, we may be only a few years away from seeing a mammoth or saber-tooth walking the Earth again.  

Many people fear this and some are even actively working to prevent this from ever happening.

Some people argue that the introduction of foreign animals into an ecosystem would do much more damage than good. 

Less common but incredibly vocal are the people that see such experiments as an affront to God or Nature. 

Other people say that funds wasted on resurrecting an extinct animal could be better spent on conserving living animals.

I for one would be overjoyed to see news of living woolly mammoth walking the Earth again.  I also believe such an announcement would result in massive funding influx from private sources that could result even more scientific advances. These advances could have benefits for humans far beyond what we can imagine. 

A perfect example of such unforeseen advances are the many benefits brought about by the Space Race.  There are far too many to list here, but [Wikipedia lists perhaps over a hundred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies). I fully believe such spinoffs in biology would greatly benefit mankind. 
   

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30193146371.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>So, I'm going to take a slightly different angle here, and argue that the cloning of extinct animals, while not exactly problematic in its own right, could have dire implications for conservation efforts more broadly. 

Currently, we know that extinctions are driven largely by humans, [primarily due to climate change and habitat destruction.](https://people.uwec.edu/jolhm/eh4/extinction/causeslink.html) The loss of species is one of the most visible indicators of these two underlying crises, which helps to motivate public action, and in turn leads to us taking steps to protect the environment around us.   However, if we were simply able to resurrect lost species through cloning, it's entirely conceivable that pro-environment efforts would decline dramatically, as people might feel less anxiety around extinctions of species they cared about.

If cloning caused this shift in public perception, it would be disastrous on two separate fronts. Firstly, without the compulsion to save beloved species, our efforts to reduce human-generated environmental damage would slow, in turn creating circumstances in which other species will go extinct at a steadily increasing rate. As a result, we might end up in a situation where we started losing species at a faster rate then we could re-populate them, leading to catastrophic environmental breakdown. Secondly, cloning efforts might understandably focus on species more well known to/popular with the public, neglecting less high profile species, even if they're critical to health ecosystems. This could well create a situation in which we manage to save some species, but still see widespread environmental collapses. Of further concern, this doesn't even account for our inability to clone species that go extinct before we are able to discover them. As it is currently believed that [we haven't even identified a whopping 86% of the Earth's species](https://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2011/08/110824-earths-species-8-7-million-biology-planet-animals-science/), it is entirely possible that vital organisms might go extinct long before we recognize the need to try to clone them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30193264283.0" user="molarunit" delta="False">
    <text>I am all for the resurrection of extinct species and I totally agree with you. The last thing we want is to enable a rhetoric of "well if it turns out it was important we can just bring it back" which would just foster reckless abandon. The best conservation efforts cant perfectly restore a decimated ecosystem even when all the species are extant. The technology would have to framed not as a tool for conservation but research. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
