<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488327251.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/82qjpv/cmvi_see_no_real_reason_to_avoid_resurrecting_an/">
    <title>CMV:I see no real reason to avoid resurrecting an extinct animal through cloning, and believe that fears of consequences are wildly overblown.</title>
    <original_poster>Runner_one</original_poster>
    <original_post>Jurassic Park, while a wildly entertaining movie, did a disservice to the public by planting irrational fears in the mind of the general public. 

While there is little chance of resurrecting a T-Rex or other dinosaur, we may be only a few years away from seeing a mammoth or saber-tooth walking the Earth again.  

Many people fear this and some are even actively working to prevent this from ever happening.

Some people argue that the introduction of foreign animals into an ecosystem would do much more damage than good. 

Less common but incredibly vocal are the people that see such experiments as an affront to God or Nature. 

Other people say that funds wasted on resurrecting an extinct animal could be better spent on conserving living animals.

I for one would be overjoyed to see news of living woolly mammoth walking the Earth again.  I also believe such an announcement would result in massive funding influx from private sources that could result even more scientific advances. These advances could have benefits for humans far beyond what we can imagine. 

A perfect example of such unforeseen advances are the many benefits brought about by the Space Race.  There are far too many to list here, but [Wikipedia lists perhaps over a hundred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NASA_spinoff_technologies). I fully believe such spinoffs in biology would greatly benefit mankind. 
   

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30193318247.0" user="Alecarte" delta="False">
    <text>Call me a libertarian but every time I hear any argument along the lines of "the money could be better spent elsewhere" when it comes to scientific exploration (especially space exploration) then I always think "lets just "redistribute" it from the wealthiest individuals who are spending it on million dollar cars and homes and hundred-thousand dollar watches etc because the money could be better spent elsewhere".  There is no issue with availability of funds/resources.  There are issues with the distribution.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
