<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488972359.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/834dhj/cmv_there_is_no_reason_to_refuse_to_sign_a_prenup/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason to refuse to sign a pre-nup unless your reasons for marriage are corrupt to begin with.</title>
    <original_poster>dumbbuttloserface</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know that a lot of people view pre-nups as “insurance” in the case of divorce. And I get it. If someone is entering into a marriage with a LOT of capital, and the other person comes from significantly less, it makes sense to want to make sure that what’s yours, stays yours. 

But I think a lot of people (at least in media portrayals and stories from friends) are very against the idea of signing one and I don’t get it. If you love someone and you intend to be married to them forever, a pre-nup is essentially pointless. To me, it only seems like you would refuse to/be adverse to sign a pre-nup if you’re marrying someone because you see the relationship as potentially beneficial for you in the case of a divorce. 

I’m interested in hearing anyone’s opinion, but particularly the opinions of those who have been in this situation, i.e. the one asking for the pre-nup or the one being asked. Thank you!!

EDIT: I’ve awarded 3 deltas on this post so far because of some very valid points. The most convincing of which was that a prenup compels the person signing to be in a potentially extremely difficult and even dangerous position in the case of abuse. Someone else provided me with a very convincing analogy which put the whole issue in a new light for me. A third person suggested the possibility of an unfair prenup; I understand why you would not sign one, however, after re-negotiating the terms to a place where both parties can be satisfied with the prenup, it would then make no sense to continue to refuse to sign. And if the person asking for a prenup refuses to compromise on unfair terms, you probably shouldn’t be marrying them in the first place, imho. 

Ultimately, my personal experience has shaped my view so that I have no issue with signing a prenup with my partner, but I do see now that the issue is much more multi-faceted than I had previously believed. I suppose my view on the subject now is: there is no reason not to sign a prenup if the terms are satisfactory to both parties and there is room for a discussion between the couple. If your SO refuses to compromise on any point or even engage in a discussion about the terms, you probably shouldn’t be marrying them in the first place as they clear don’t see you as an equal. 

So I guess...view shifted/expanded, but not altogether changed. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30198125439.0" user="soulwrangler" delta="False">
    <text>From what I understand about prenups, both parties require separate representation for them to be valid, and a prenup that would leave one party with nothing after a lengthy marriage(say, 10 years+) would be challenged.  Let's say a couple gets married, husband owns the house prior to marriage, it's 70% paid off, he makes all payments and the prenup protects the value of the property. 20 years later they divorce. In that 20 years though, the wife helped with maintenance and upkeep. When her father died, they used the money he left her to add a bathroom and deck and remodel the kitchen, payments to repave the driveway last summer came from her checking account. Who's house is it? 


That being said, even the most perfect ride or die relationships die.  People that have been together 30+ years get divorced. My grandparents were together for 40 years, but she just couldn't take his bullshit anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198308793.0" user="Freevoulous" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  prenup that would leave one party with nothing after a lengthy marriage(say, 10 years+) would be challenged.

moreover, such prenup would not be signed in the first place. Any half competent legal advisor would advise his client not to sign it in the first place, and fight tooth and claw against the other party's attorney to make the prenup as equal and fair as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
