<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="488972359.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/834dhj/cmv_there_is_no_reason_to_refuse_to_sign_a_prenup/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason to refuse to sign a pre-nup unless your reasons for marriage are corrupt to begin with.</title>
    <original_poster>dumbbuttloserface</original_poster>
    <original_post>I know that a lot of people view pre-nups as “insurance” in the case of divorce. And I get it. If someone is entering into a marriage with a LOT of capital, and the other person comes from significantly less, it makes sense to want to make sure that what’s yours, stays yours. 

But I think a lot of people (at least in media portrayals and stories from friends) are very against the idea of signing one and I don’t get it. If you love someone and you intend to be married to them forever, a pre-nup is essentially pointless. To me, it only seems like you would refuse to/be adverse to sign a pre-nup if you’re marrying someone because you see the relationship as potentially beneficial for you in the case of a divorce. 

I’m interested in hearing anyone’s opinion, but particularly the opinions of those who have been in this situation, i.e. the one asking for the pre-nup or the one being asked. Thank you!!

EDIT: I’ve awarded 3 deltas on this post so far because of some very valid points. The most convincing of which was that a prenup compels the person signing to be in a potentially extremely difficult and even dangerous position in the case of abuse. Someone else provided me with a very convincing analogy which put the whole issue in a new light for me. A third person suggested the possibility of an unfair prenup; I understand why you would not sign one, however, after re-negotiating the terms to a place where both parties can be satisfied with the prenup, it would then make no sense to continue to refuse to sign. And if the person asking for a prenup refuses to compromise on unfair terms, you probably shouldn’t be marrying them in the first place, imho. 

Ultimately, my personal experience has shaped my view so that I have no issue with signing a prenup with my partner, but I do see now that the issue is much more multi-faceted than I had previously believed. I suppose my view on the subject now is: there is no reason not to sign a prenup if the terms are satisfactory to both parties and there is room for a discussion between the couple. If your SO refuses to compromise on any point or even engage in a discussion about the terms, you probably shouldn’t be marrying them in the first place as they clear don’t see you as an equal. 

So I guess...view shifted/expanded, but not altogether changed. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30197942065.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Except the idea of a pre-nup can be insulting.

Like you say, if you love someone and intend to marry them then they should be willing to sign.

But if the other person loves them and wants to live with them forever, why is the idea of a pre-nup even crossing their mind?

It is like saying "I love you, and I want to marry you. Except I think there is a distinct and real possibility we may divorce and I want to make sure I get all my stuff back".

It is planning for failure.

A person may want to refuse because they don't think the person proposing the pre-nup is fully engaged so to speak.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197964560.0" user="dumbbuttloserface" delta="False">
    <text>I kind of understand that side. But i’m also speaking as someone who comes from nothing, like the idea of getting an inheritance is laughable, who has discussed marriage with a man whose family pulls in at least seven figures yearly—honestly i don’t even know exactly how much. 

he and his family want and expect me to sign a pre-nup in order to make sure i’m not planning to marry him and then divorce him in a few years just to get the alimony check. and because i intend to be married to him for the rest of my life, i have no issue signing anything. at worst, i go back to the financial situation that i’m in now which, honestly, isn’t great, but i know i can make ends meet at the end of the day. does that make sense? maybe i haven’t thought about it in terms of someone who is completely caught off guard by a pre-nup??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197977499.0" user="throwaway-person" delta="False">
    <text>It just sounds to me like he's setting you up to be used and then dumped with nothing when he gets tired of your novelty. I'd be terrified to even consider a relationship let alone marriage with someone like that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198005314.0" user="dumbbuttloserface" delta="False">
    <text>he and i have known each other since we were 13 and 11 respectively and our relationship has changed and evolved since then. despite everything, genuine love has been the baseline of our relationship, even when living in different cities and dating different people. if my situation with him wasn’t what it is i might see it differently</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198223082.0" user="tempTemp0001" delta="False">
    <text>Don't listen to the person above. You know best about your relationship. Don't let these jaded people cast doubt on your decision.

If you trust him, which it sounds like you do, then go for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198339728.0" user="throwaway-person" delta="False">
    <text>This is a recipe for disaster. I'm warning OP from experience. It sounds like a trap. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198748301.0" user="Enigmatic_Android" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you trust him, which it sounds like you do, then go for it.

He obviously doesn't trust OP though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199380229.0" user="tempTemp0001" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t believe you people are having this kind of reaction over a fucking prenup. 

So many people have been fucked over in divorces, it’s more than fair to want to protect yourself. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199443419.0" user="Enigmatic_Android" delta="False">
    <text>Asking for a prenup is saying that you don't trust your potential spouse. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199471405.0" user="tempTemp0001" delta="False">
    <text>No, it saying you don’t trust the divorce courts to award a fair judgement. 

Which is totally fair. Because divorce courts are notoriously biased and all around terrible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199344058.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>Her partner gets to question the OP's motives and protect himself from her, yet the OP shouldn't listen to people offering advice and should go with her gut?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199147642.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>What a horribly jaded statement to make. 

It is just as horribly jaded for the man to think everyone is just in it for his money. 

The prenup can be used like Pre-Cana to help ensure a happy and proper marriage. It would protect the premarriage interests of both parties and their families. After all, if one comes with 7 or 8 figures of wealth and the other has next to nothing, it is likely some part of one family would say they were doing it for the money. The prenup answers that question. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30197995814.0" user="Goatfarmercarl" delta="False">
    <text>How much does he make? His families money is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198364890.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>Not necessarily, she could be entitled to inheritances in the event of divorce. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198004449.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>So you are fine with his family essentially accusing you of being a gold-digger and planning for you guys getting divorced?

There shouldn't be a contingency plan for divorce.

If you both love each other and want to live together forever, then you shouldn't need to sign a pre-nup. If you think divorce is a significant possibility, then don't get married.

A pre-nup is essentially his way of guaranteeing he is covered in case of a divorce, just like a lack of a pre-nup is your guarantee in case of a divorce.

If you are already planning for a divorce, then you probably shouldn't be getting married.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198023394.0" user="ixanonyousxi" delta="False">
    <text>There's a difference between planning a divorce and preparing for the worse circumstances. If anyone goes into anything thinking it will be forever then they are optimistic at best, delusional at worse. One can hope the marriage will last forever and still recognize that sometimes people change and grow apart instead of together, through no fault of anybody. In such case, perhaps they want to still maintain the financial status they have now.  

If you think you can predict how you will feel about someone in 10, 20, 30, 40, etc years time, when you yourself won't even know who you'll be by then, then you are delusional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198035911.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see much difference.

You don't become someone different due to external forces, you change due to your own choices.

We choose what we are.

You choose whether you want to grow apart or grow together.

There's no such thing as growing apart through no fault of either party. If you don't have a plan or there is a risk the other person is going to deviate, then don't get married.

Marriage isn't something maintained because two people happen to be similar and everything works out.

Marriages last because both parties work for them to last.

The very idea of divorce coming up shows that at least one person in the relationship isn't fully committed to it.

They can continue if they want, but in my opinion OP is gambling their future by proceeding with the marriage when she knows the other side is already looking to make sure they can get out without any losses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198071094.0" user="dumbbuttloserface" delta="False">
    <text>i don’t see it as gambling with my future because he and i are entering the union openly and honestly and i’m not being blindsided with a prenup. it’s been an ongoing conversation and we arrived at a decision together </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198340691.0" user="throwaway-person" delta="False">
    <text>This honestly makes me more concerned that he has groomed you to devalue yourself compared to him. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198363043.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>What about what they said sounds like grooming? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198736844.0" user="dumbbuttloserface" delta="False">
    <text>i am confused as to how you have arrived at this conclusion? i come from a worse financial background than he does. his family wants to protect their assets, and if i had any (and do hope to have my own before we get married—it’s not on the immediate horizon, could be two years from now, could be ten, when you intend to be together forever, there’s no real rush) i would want to protect mine too. his older sister is currently in her second marriage; her first ended because her ex husband realized he was gay. you don’t go into a marriage expecting that to be the outcome, but shit happens. so it’s best to be protected. 

someone on this thread mentioned you shouldn’t be planning for death when you still have a whole life ahead of you, but the thing is, i could die 80 years from now or i could die tomorrow. there are circumstances outside of your control that might blindside you and it’s best to make sure that you have your affairs in order in case of the worst. i don’t see it as a pessimistic view, i see it as realistic. shit happens—you hope it won’t, but IF it does, you want to be protected. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198346188.0" user="ExuberantElephant" delta="False">
    <text>Marriage shouldn’t be a contractual thing. By introducing one, your partner’s family is showing a clear lack of trust in you and your partner’s relationship. You shouldn’t be preparing for death when you have an entire life ahead of you; that’s just introducing an unnecessary stress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198405639.0" user="Gourok" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Marriage shouldn’t be a contractual thing.

Marriage is explicitly a contractual thing, that is why you sign a marriage contract.

&amp;gt; You shouldn’t be preparing for death when you have an entire life ahead of you; that’s just introducing an unnecessary stress.

Sure you should, you shouldn't be unreasonable focused on it, but life insurance isn't always a bad idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198660088.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>No. Divorce is not death.

Death can be unexpected and unwanted.

Divorce is always wanted. It is one or both of the people saying "I don't want to work on making our marriage better, I just want out".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198746125.0" user="dumbbuttloserface" delta="False">
    <text>marriage is l i t e r a l l y a contract dude. it’s not just wearing rings and that’s the only thing that changes??? like what? if you want a contract free long-term relationship, then just stay in a long-term relationship without /literally/ signing a contract legally, religiously, morally, etc aka what you do when you get married. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200447552.0" user="ExuberantElephant" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that marriage shouldn’t be something tied with contractual obligations. It brings a ‘power struggle’ into something that should just be about treating each other with love and kindness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198668893.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>No, you are gambling.

You want this marriage. Presumably you want to be married for the rest of your life.

The problem is that your partner is already saying "I'm not willing to do everything in my power in order to ensure we remain married."

He is stating now that there are limits on what he is willing to do to ensure the marriage is successful and long-lived.

If you are OK with that, then that's fine. It is your life.

But don't say you plan on being married for life if you are already talking about a life where you guys divorce. That isn't "until death do you part", it is "until these circumstances do you part"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199913634.0" user="Seaman182" delta="False">
    <text>I think this may be a very fundamental difference in philosophy. When I read this:

&amp;gt;But don't say you plan on being married for life if you are already talking about a life where you guys divorce. That isn't "until death do you part", it is "until these circumstances do you part"

My first thought is "what if the circumstances are so bad that being apart is preferable? Should we really just ignore those circumstances?"

Surely you think it's reasonable to divorce a partner who beats you? If you do, then you already agree that there are *some* circumstances other than death that merit divorce. How about psychological abuse? Is that bad enough? What about bitterness that's so bad you're falling into depression? We may disagree about where to draw the line, but surely it exists *somewhere.*

Given that there exists a point where divorce should be an option, and also given the fact that we're mere mortals who can't see into the future, it makes perfect sense to consider the possibility of divorce and have a plan in order to minimize the negative effects of such an event.

Here's another quote that makes me think we're considering this issue in wildly different ways:

&amp;gt;He is stating now that there are limits on what he is willing to do to ensure the marriage is successful and long-lived.

I don't believe that every single problem that might possibly arise in a marriage *can* be solved by the actions of one of its members. As far as I'm concerned, some issues cannot be fixed by one person (and some cannot be fixed at all).

If someone agrees with that sentiment and is also willing to speak honestly, they will have no problem admitting that there are limits on what they are willing to do... Or perhaps those limits are more on what they *can* do, *should* do, or what would be actually *helpful* to do.

Once you've made that admission, it only makes sense to have a plan for the worst-case scenario. After that, you can still hope, pray, and strive to make sure that it never occurs!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200085686.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>If you are getting divorced because they are abusive; then either they were abusive when you got married and you had already decided to abide that, or they became abusive afterwards and you got married without truly knowing the other person.

While it is OK that people get divorced, to each their own and all that. But don't claim it is a lifelong commitment if there are circumstances which you aren't both willing to work through.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200331294.0" user="Seaman182" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you are getting divorced because they are abusive; then either they were abusive when you got married and you had already decided to abide that, or they became abusive afterwards and you got married without truly knowing the other person.

I can't agree with this entirely, probably because I'm of the belief that people can change (for better or for worse).

&amp;gt;While it is OK that people get divorced, to each their own and all that.

Cool, this part is really the main point IMO. If divorce is acceptable, then it makes sense to prepare for it.

After all, the majority of couples *do* get divorced (even the ones without prenups), so it's a practical choice.

&amp;gt;But don't claim it is a lifelong commitment if there are circumstances which you aren't both willing to work through.

I can agree with this, at least to a point... But it's more of a semantic distinction than a factual one IMO. Here's why:

When I call up a hotel to book a room for a week, I tell them I'll be there for seven nights... But I don't actually *know* that. My flight could be delayed (nobody's fault), or the room could be infested with roaches (the hotel's fault), or I could have a midlife crisis halfway through my stay and run off to Mexico (my fault).

And yet, even though I know there is a non-zero chance of these things happening, I still answer "seven nights" when they ask how long I'll be staying. Seven nights is my hope and my intention, and at this moment I have no cause to doubt that that's how long I'll stay.

The exact same is true of a "lifelong commitment" to a partner. That said, yes, a lot of the language goes too far in the "TILL DEATH NO MATTER WHAT" direction. That's probably both a matter of tradition and the fact that nobody will like the way it looks if they make a push to change it (kinda like how pornography is still censored in Japan).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200348136.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>People do change, but people can control how they change.

If OP is saying that she wants the marriage to be for life, then the idea that her fiance has a planned escape route is kind of insulting. It is saying that he thinks divorce is a possibility and therefore is not as committed as she is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200548550.0" user="Seaman182" delta="False">
    <text>The fact of the matter is that a person is a very bad judge of their own future actions. While admitting that is unpleasant to think about, I don't see it as a failing.

Divorce *is* a possibility, and statistically speaking it's a likely one. That means that the majority of people who believe that they and their partner are going to be together forever are objectively wrong.

To put a contingency in place to cover for the (very likely) event that you're wrong seems reasonable to me, and I don't think it increases the likelihood that you're wrong any more than buying fire insurance increases the likelihood that you'll set fire to your house.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198364223.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The very idea of divorce coming up shows that at least one person in the relationship isn't fully committed to it.

I guess I'll stop wearing my seat belt when I drive too, since apparently thinking about risks means your are not committed to preventing them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198646697.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Not quite.

We wear seatbelts because we know other drivers can be idiots that may disregard rules of the road. It is something that we accept and look out for as drivers. We wear seatbelts because unexpected things can and do happen on the road. Things that cannot be prevented.

But a divorce is entirely voluntary and foreseeable on at least one person's part. And preventable if both people are committed to living together.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200192612.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I'm pretty sure no one getting married plans to get divorced, and yet many do. You can have your idealized version of reality all you want, but don't be surprised when you get blindsided by something painful because you were to squeamish to think about it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200212213.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Theb they shouldn't have gotten married in the first place because they didn't talk about things. They didn't know each other and therefore should not have wed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200216048.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>Dude that is just ignorant. What if they both want biological kids but when they try to have them they find out the women is infertile? How long do you think those marriages last? Should those people have to stay together even though there is no way they could have planned for that? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200237574.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>They could have planned by going to the doctor.

That is case of ignorance, you shouldn't be getting married while ignorant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200246518.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>There is not always a medical test to determine fertility, or an accident could occur afterwards that made someone infertile. And if you shouldn't get married while ignorant, it looks like your going to be single forever. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200311750.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>In my view marriage should be a lifelong vow. Regardless of what may happen you should still do what you can to uphold your vows.

If you want to bail out, you can. I'm just pointing out that if you want to say marriage is a lifelong vow, that trumps  what may or may not happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198815415.0" user="ixanonyousxi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You don't become someone different due to external forces, you change due to your own choices.  

You damn well become someone different due to external forces. Your choices don't exist a in a vacuum. Your choices are heavily influenced by outside forces.  

&amp;gt;You choose whether you want to grow apart or grow together.  

No, no one "chooses" to not love someone anymore. No one chooses how they feel about someone. If they did then people wouldn't be in love with people they know are so obviously bad for them or they would be in love with someone who is so obviously good for them.  

&amp;gt;There's no such thing as growing apart through no fault of either party.  

Yes there is. It happens all the time.  

&amp;gt;Marriages last because both parties work for them to last.  

Sure there are unhealthy marriages that last because people choose to stay and "work it out" even though there's no love anymore, but that's not successful just because it didn't end it a divorce.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199423813.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>But those external forces don't dictate who you are. Who you are depends on your choices in reaction to those forces.

You have free will and self-determination</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199593568.0" user="ixanonyousxi" delta="False">
    <text>And your choices in how to react to said influences are directly influenced by past external forces.  

And I disagree that we do have free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200088274.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>If you disagree we have free will, then why bother partake in this sub?

If we don't have free will then your actions here are meaningless and you might as well end your life now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200121988.0" user="ixanonyousxi" delta="False">
    <text>LOL Wow nice low key way off telling me to go kill myself.  

Anyone who believes in God, fate, destiny, etc doesn't believe in free will do you suggest they all off themselves?  

Sure life is meaningless, doesn't mean I can't derive joy from it anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200233890.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't actually telling you to off yourself. I was just saying that if there is no free will then you have no choice, there isn't much purpose because you aren't doing anything. You are just a puppet.

And you can believe in God, fate, destiny, etc while also believing in free will.

God has a plan for all of us, but you have to choose to accept it. This is why there is Heaven and Hell.

You may have a fate, or you may believe you have multiple fates. You can believe in destiny but also believe thst there are different routes to reach it.

But this is getting far too philosophical for the original argument.

My original argument is that you choose who you become so you can always work towards being a good spouse, if you don't do that then you break your wedding vows which often include "for better or worse" in more or less words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30207927172.0" user="ixanonyousxi" delta="False">
    <text>One can have a purpose without having a free will. One can still be happy without free will.  

&amp;gt;And you can believe in God, fate, destiny, etc while also believing in free will.  

No, no you can't. Everything you described below this sentence is not fate or destiny. If you have "multiple fates" or "multiple destinies" then you are not describing fate or destiny. Destiny and fate are set in stone paths that you will follow no matter what. And if you will follow those paths no matter what then you never had a choice in the first place. And God is supposedly all knowing. If he knows the path you are gonna take before you even take it, then you never had a choice, you just don't realize it.  


&amp;gt;you choose who you become  

No you don't. External influences largely determine who you will become. If you get raped you are gonna be a different person, with different experiences, different perspectives, different outlooks than if you weren't raped. Whether that manifests itself in your personality or not doesn't matter, your outlook will still have changed by an external influence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198060801.0" user="brickbacon" delta="False">
    <text>First, if it were easy to revert back to a life you were formally accustomed to (practically or emotionally) alimony wouldn’t exist in all likelihood. 

Second, a pre-nup allows one side to have far less skin in the game, and allows one side to wield financial power over the other. For example, the rich spouse can treat the other poorly without ever having to worry about the financial consequences. It can also be a means of coercing someone to stay in a bad marriage. Marriage is hard, so divorce should also be hard even if only to make people work as hard on their marriages.

Third,  related to the last point, pre-nups are usually coercive and one-sided. They almost never are the brainchild of both sides; it’s the richer spouse presenting a document to the poorer one with little negotiation or explanation. This is made even worse when the controlling party is actually not one of the people getting married (eg. Rich parents of one side). 

Lastly, they basically are less about fairness and more about one party preserving the right to screw the other side if they don’t think that person lived up to his/her side of the deal. Presumably, a rich person is willing to share their assets and money with their spouse the entire time they are married. Given that, it’s not that the rich spouse isn’t willing to let the other spend/use the money, they just want to control the terms and how that money is spent based on the relationship status. That dynamic is toxic even when you don’t have money.  If you need to sign a contract that tells one person what they are entitled to in case things go bad, you probably shouldn’t get married. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198360865.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you need to sign a contract that tells one person what they are entitled to in case things go bad, you probably shouldn’t get married.

Then no one should get married, because that is exactly what a marriage is, a contract that tells one side what they are entitled to if things go bad. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198566620.0" user="brickbacon" delta="False">
    <text>No, not really. A marriage contact is not one sided nor does it prescribe who gets what (that’s based on jurisdiction and specific legal ruling if need be). They are both contracts, but the purpose, scope, and rationale for each is very different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198591374.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>I did not say a marriage contract is on sided, I said it tells one side what they are entitled to, which is not to say it doesn't tell the other side they are entitled to something as well, though perhaps the implication is there. The point of a marriage  contract is to take assets in the event of a divorce. A marriage contract demonstrates much more insecurity than a prenup. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199595150.0" user="brickbacon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I did not say a marriage contract is on sided

That was the context of the statement you choose to quibble with. I said:
&amp;gt; If you need to sign a contract that tells one person what they are entitled to in case things go bad, you probably shouldn’t get married.

You said:

&amp;gt; Then no one should get married, because that is exactly what a marriage is, a contract that tells one side what they are entitled to if things go bad

Your response, as I pointed out last time is not accurate. 

&amp;gt; I said it tells one side what they are entitled to, which is not to say it doesn't tell the other side they are entitled to something as well, though perhaps the implication is there. 

First, this is not true generally speaking.  A marriage license/certificate doesn't tell either party that, state laws typically do. 

&amp;gt; The point of a marriage contract is to take assets in the event of a divorce. 

No. Principally, the point is instructing the state to treat two people as one in a number of situations. The contract doesn't specific what happens during a divorce at all. 
 
&amp;gt; A marriage contract demonstrates much more insecurity than a prenup.

How so?  You need to get a marriage contract to get married generally speaking. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198425381.0" user="DarkKnightRedux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; First, if it were easy to revert back to a life you were formally accustomed to (practically or emotionally) alimony wouldn’t exist in all likelihood.


That only matters to a poor spouse marrying for money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198563445.0" user="brickbacon" delta="False">
    <text>Of course. I think that was implied based on the question and context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199365560.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>Not at all true. 

Try reverting back to life you were formally accustomed to after being a stay at home parent for a decade. 

If doing a double at 7/11 and McDonald's to make ends meet was the life you were formally accustomed to, it shouldn't be a problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199410596.0" user="DarkKnightRedux" delta="False">
    <text>Are you marrying a person or their money? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199560380.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>Is the person who marries someone who sacrifices their financial security and career to raise their child marrying a glorified nanny who can be fired at-will?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199605546.0" user="DarkKnightRedux" delta="False">
    <text>If you're willing to have children and you aren't pulling your weight financially that's a HUGE red flag. That person shouldn't be a parent unless independently wealthy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199903468.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>Making the choice as a couple, like many do, for one parent to stay at home while the other works is a red flag?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199921929.0" user="DarkKnightRedux" delta="False">
    <text>Putting that responsibility on one person and creating a single point of failure is incredibly irresponsible for something so important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199940375.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>For most couples that make this decision, together they have the financial security to make it happen. Individually, one parent is sacrificing their earning and career potential.

Do you see what I'm getting at here or are you opposed to stay-at-home parenting in general?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30201833491.0" user="DarkKnightRedux" delta="False">
    <text>I understand your point, it's just completely irrelevant. If you're not actively participating in an aspect of parenting you are super even on the off chance it was mutually agreed upon. Where are you getting th is is normally an agreement? In 100% of the 39 or so cases I've seen it's been one parent declared it and pretended it was mutual consent while the abused partner is left to scramble for resources. 

Edit: 200 to 100. Fat fingered the keyboard. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30203212453.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>I am having difficulty parsing your comment, leaving some of it ambiguous as to what you mean. 

From what I can glean, you have a problem with stay-at-home parenting in general. 

&amp;gt; Where are you getting th is is normally an agreement? 

From friends and acquaintances. No one was forced or singularly decided that they'd be a stay-at-home parent. In my experience, particularly wealthy families make the decision as they believe it is in the best interests of their children.

I've also dated a few former stay-at-home parents and saw how devastating it can be for their careers when they choose to leave their spouse, voluntarily or involuntarily.

Perhaps our experiences cast a different light on the concept of stay-at-home parenting, but neither perspective changes the fact that there are couples that mutually decide that stay-at-home parenting is the way they want to raise their children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199330013.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; at worst, i go back to the financial situation that i’m in now which, honestly, isn’t great, but i know i can make ends meet at the end of the day. does that make sense? 

At worst, you haven't worked in almost two decades because you got lulled into the false sense of security your marriage provided, came to the decision that being a stay at home parent was a good idea because you can afford to do so with your spouse. Then, you get a divorce, you have nowhere to live and you cannot get a job because your skills are irrelevant.

At worst, you have been working a part time job for the last 5 years, because that's the only work you can find in the town you've moved to. You have no friends here, no family and there is little opportunity, but you moved here because your spouse found a great job/it's close to their family/it's a great neighborhood for the kids. You get a divorce and you don't even have enough money to buy a plane ticket AND ship your stuff back home.

At worst, you've just found the courage to leave an abusive relationship despite having to live in a shelter. You never saw your life coming to this, but you have nothing, no one and can't really explain how it all happened.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199877204.0" user="Seaman182" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You get a divorce and you don't even have enough money to buy a plane ticket AND ship your stuff back home.

A prenuptial agreement is *any contract* entered into by people who are about to be married.

You're acting like it has to read "if I decide to break up with you I get everything; have fun living on the street, moron."

Yes, a bad prenup is a bad prenup. That doesn't mean you shouldn't consider a reasonable one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199910353.0" user="move_machine" delta="False">
    <text>Notice where I prefaced each situation with "At worst".

Hope this helps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199924207.0" user="Seaman182" delta="False">
    <text>Shit, my fault! You're totally right: the worst-case scenario is pretty bad.

I don't think that's any argument against the existence or signing of pre-nups in general, but it's certainly a good argument for reading them first.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30199800054.0" user="Paninic" delta="False">
    <text>Well, actually, at worst you can be married for quite a lot of time and make financial commitments based off of what your combined income is and then be on the hook for that if you divorce and don't have alimony. 

I don't think it's ridiculous to have a pre-nup so much as I think people have forgotten there's legitimate reasons other than money grubbing that people receive alimony for. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198217211.0" user="Freevoulous" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "I love you, and I want to marry you. Except I think there is a distinct and real possibility we may divorce and I want to make sure I get all my stuff back".

But the possibility of a divorce IS real, and they would be an idiot not to realise it. Why would you marry someone who is fiscally irresponsible?

It is planning for failure, of course, because rational adult people should plan for failure. Again, marrying someone who does not plan for failure is a looming disaster, because life is full of unplanned failures (death in the family, financial crisis, bad investment, serious illness etc). 

Besides, a prenup is for the safety and peace of mind of both, because it simplifies the possible divorce AND the marriage before it a great deal. Within a prenup, you can include a lot of stuff that you agree on when married (like a parenting plan, or parter expectations), not just finances, and it makes the definition of your marriage more clear cut. With a well written prenup, you know *precisely* what you are supposed and not supposed to do in the marriage, which nullifies 99% of future arguments.

Some things that prenuptial agreements can include:

- family plan and parenting plan

- your idea of faithfulness, expectations and consequences of infidelity

- your plans on contributing to the household, financially or otherwise

- even your weekly schedules or long term multi-year plans.

All of this makes both people feel safer, because they do not have to guess and worry constantly, or wrestle with their partner over details all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198367428.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>Many of the people in this thread have some idealized, fairy tale version of marriage where even mentioning the possibility of divorce is taboo to them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198394136.0" user="Freevoulous" delta="False">
    <text>and at the same time, most of them have some unrealistic Boogeyman version of what a prenup is.

Prenup is essentially everything *you already agree on as a couple*, just written down in a formalised language and notarially authenticated.

But Reddit believes a prenup is some kind of a Deal With the Devil signed in blood, with the evil husband cackling madly as he forces his would be wife to sing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198678005.0" user="Madplato" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Many of the people in this thread have some idealized, fairy tale version of marriage where even mentioning the possibility of divorce is taboo to them. 

There's a difference between knowing divorce is possible and entering marriage with contingencies in order to protect yourself and your assets in the event of it. I wouldn't agree to or request a prenup on principle, because it goes against my understanding of marriage. I don't think my motives are "corrupt". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198356419.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But if the other person loves them and wants to live with them forever, why is the idea of a pre-nup even crossing their mind?

If they want to be together forever, why is marriage crossing their minds? The whole point of marriage is to create a social contract/norm that makes it financially and socially costly to split up. You have a big party and make a big public commitment to stay together and divorce is very embarrassing. The legal and financial difficulties of divorce make it even less appealing. If people were able to stay with the people they said they would love forever, they wouldn't need marriage to coerce them, they would just stay together. But people are fickle and short sited, they often act impulsively and need checks on their behavior which is what a marriage provides. 

To me, a women who insists on marriage as the ultimate conclusion of a dating relationship is telegraphing major insecurity. She is saying that she doesn't believe a guy when he says he wants to be with her, she needs a financial/social/legal/ promise that he will, that seems pretty insecure to me. 

&amp;gt; It is like saying "I love you, and I want to marry you. Except I think there is a distinct and real possibility we may divorce and I want to make sure I get all my stuff back".    

People get married because they want an assurance someone will stay with them, they are implicitly acknowledging the possibility of breaking up when they use the tool that is marriage to try to ensure they will stay together, its just that we have interlined this norm and don't notice it anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198654500.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, because there is no legal or social benefits to marriage.

It's just a ploy for a woman protect herself and there certainly aren't any tax/inheritance/social benefits to being married.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30200187837.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>The social and legal benefits stem from identifying as a couple where the women/kids are protected if the man leaves. All this is in history books if you would open them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30198466667.0" user="DarkKnightRedux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Except the idea of a pre-nup can be insulting.

Not to a reasonable person.

&amp;gt;Like you say, if you love someone and intend to marry them then they should be willing to sign.

Unless they are gold digging, yes.

&amp;gt;But if the other person loves them and wants to live with them forever, why is the idea of a pre-nup even crossing their mind?

Intelligence. They're well aware even the best plans can fall through and are seeking to protect themselves.

&amp;gt;It is like saying "I love you, and I want to marry you. Except I think there is a distinct and real possibility we may divorce and I want to make sure I get all my stuff back".

Yes, it protects what they had before the marriage. Beyond being a good digger you should have no issue.

&amp;gt;It is planning for failure.

As all smart people do when they know it's a distinct possibility.

&amp;gt;A person may want to refuse because they don't think the person proposing the pre-nup is fully engaged so to speak.

An irrational or greedy person would refuse to sign a fair prenup but no one else would. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
