<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="491577396.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/84o7jo/cmv_the_godfather_iii_is_better_than_ii/">
    <title>CMV: The Godfather III is better than II.</title>
    <original_poster>meadowsopr</original_poster>
    <original_post>For me, The Godfather Part II only shines when Robert DeNiro is on screen. Whenever the film cuts back to Michael I hate it, because I think it's a melodramatic pause from the good story. Part III is a consistent movie IMO, with the only inconsistency being a bad performance from Sofia Coppola. I think the drama is intriguing and Andy Garcia does a great job. 

TL;DR Although the Vito storyline in II is probably my favorite plot in the trilogy, the other plot is boring, whereas III is more consistent.

p.s. Godfather I trumps both II and III by a mile IMO.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30218118678.0" user="paul_aka_paul" delta="False">
    <text>The whole point of the parallel storylines is to show how Michael fails to be like his father. We get to see how Vito rises to power through a combination of brilliance, ruthlessness and compassion. Michael has his brilliance and ruthlessness, but he has no heart. Sonny was ruthless and passionate, but he didn't think things through. And poor Fredo was all heart but lacked brains and courage.

All the sons had pieces of their father but none had the whole package. Vito built an empire that was rooted in love and respect. He was justifiably feared, but everyone knew he was reasonable and friendly to those who earned respect. Seeing that contrasted with Michael's robotic actions and empty words about family highlights his tragic character. He wins every battle he fights yet can't win the war. He has been programmed to win for his family but doesn't understand what that even means.

Part III isn't as terrible as everyone says. We do get to see Michael finally be vulnerable and emotional. He has figured it out, but the damage is done. He is trying to rebuild the family he destroyed in the name of protecting his family. But he is doing so in the face of the numerous enemies he made when he overplayed his ruthlessness in Part II.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30218300880.0" user="meadowsopr" delta="False">
    <text>Holy shit never thought about it that way. I was kind of close-minded I guess as I never compared the two subplots, just kinda fell asleep to one of them and was gripped to one of them. Might rewatch tonight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30218976368.0" user="Governor_Humphries" delta="False">
    <text>I have heard people say that Andy Garcia in III embodies the best aspects of the three Corleone brothers: Sonny's passion, Fredo's warmth, and Michael's brains. He is a more worthy heir to Vito than his father or uncles ever were.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
