<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="492422754.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/856btu/cmv_whaling_by_aboriginal_groups_is_perfectly/">
    <title>CMV: whaling by aboriginal groups is perfectly fine, sustainable, and in many cases necessary.</title>
    <original_poster>destroy233</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many anti-whaling groups attack not just the Japanese whaling industry (which I do not support as it is for commercial gain) but the aboriginal whaling of the Faroese islanders, Alaskan Inuits, and the Chukchi peoples etc. These whale hunts are necessary for the survival of the local people’s. These anti-whaling groups do not take into account the isolation of these areas which makes it impossible or impractical for a person to sustain themselves on a store bought diet. Speaking from experience ( I live and have been to rural Alaska) the cost of food and other goods is so ridiculously high that whaling and other subsistence hunting is absolutely necessary. I believe that these anti-whaling groups do not know this or ignore this fact. Change my view.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30226334087.0" user="TheRamiRocketMan" delta="False">
    <text>Based on historic whale population data, genetic evidence and population models, the historic whale population for most common species were in the 100,000's. In the North Atlantic alone, Humpbacks numbered around 240,000[source](http://palumbi.stanford.edu/manuscripts/Roman%20and%20Palumbi%202003.pdf) Recent population estimates are approximately [14,000 for Humpbacks in the North Atlantic](https://iwc.int/estimate). Global Blue Whale populations are even worse. There are now less than 20,000 left after whaling in the 20th century killed over [370,000 whales](https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/j.1748-7692.2004.tb01190). [This website](https://iwc.int/estimate) is great at listing all the recent(ish) whale population estimates. Every major whale species has had a population decrease compared to historic highs, most of them are dramatic.

Now indigenous populations DO NOT cause this much damage, we know this, you know this, but it does reveal an interesting point. Whales are incredibly reduced in numbers compared to their historic populations. Whales are mammals, and gestate one baby at a time. This means they cannot replenish their populations quickly when there is an abundance of food like some other animals. Whales also live long lives, and are relatively safe from predators once they reach maturity meaning that adult whales are good long-term producers of offspring. This means *every* fertile individual plays a critical role in the regeneration of the population, and killing *any* whale, especially adult, at this vital stage in their species recovery will have compounding effects on how quickly their population can return. Killing a single adult whale could potentially stop 10+ calves from being born. This is why we can't allowing whaling of any kind, at least until their populations swell to their previous highs.

Preserving whales is far more important that preserving traditions and values. Whales are vital links in the ecosystem that keeps our planet's food web running and we need their numbers to return to historic levels. Without whales, 7 billion people are screwed, compared to a few indigenous groups.

Edit: Other source - I'm a university biology student</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30227002408.0" user="destroy233" delta="False">
    <text>The species of whales that are hunted by indigenous groups are very closest monitored and endangered species such as humpbacks and blues are not allowed to be taken. These whale hunts by indigenous groups are  very closely monitored by the IWC and are halted if they believe a species or population is at risk. This isn’t like other hunting where there is an unlimited harvest, the amount allowed to be taken is very closely controlled to balance the survival of the species and the indigenous groups whaling practice. Since the 1986 moratorium on whaling the only groups allowed to whale are (mostly, looking at you japan) indigenous groups that take minuscule amounts compared to the large scale commercial whaling that took place before that. Secondly, one of the main points in the OP is that this is necessary for the survival of people in remote areas. Store bought food is ridiculously expensive, a gallon of milk costs upwards of 12 dollars and 2 hamburger patties can cost upwards of 23. It is not feasible to live in these areas without many kinds of subsistence hunting, including whaling. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
