<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="492422754.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/856btu/cmv_whaling_by_aboriginal_groups_is_perfectly/">
    <title>CMV: whaling by aboriginal groups is perfectly fine, sustainable, and in many cases necessary.</title>
    <original_poster>destroy233</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many anti-whaling groups attack not just the Japanese whaling industry (which I do not support as it is for commercial gain) but the aboriginal whaling of the Faroese islanders, Alaskan Inuits, and the Chukchi peoples etc. These whale hunts are necessary for the survival of the local people’s. These anti-whaling groups do not take into account the isolation of these areas which makes it impossible or impractical for a person to sustain themselves on a store bought diet. Speaking from experience ( I live and have been to rural Alaska) the cost of food and other goods is so ridiculously high that whaling and other subsistence hunting is absolutely necessary. I believe that these anti-whaling groups do not know this or ignore this fact. Change my view.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30224755761.0" user="Kringspier_Des_Heren" delta="False">
    <text>Well as far as I know a lot of people in Alaska don't whale.

What about living in the exact same area and not being part of an "aboriginal group"? Unless the prize of store-bought food is higher for aboriginal groups they are met with the same hardships and the rules should apply based on area you live in and not what aboriginal group you may or may not be part of right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30224850200.0" user="destroy233" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct most Alaskans don’t whale, and you have to be Inuit to be allowed to whale. The 9 specific communities that are allowed too are A mostly Inuit, and B the small number of non-Inuit in the community are allowed to be given whale meat by community members. I have met many non-Inuit people who lived in those communities who said it wasn’t an issue. Also the few high paying jobs in those communities are taken by the non-Inuits who can afford the very high priced store food. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30224858095.0" user="Kringspier_Des_Heren" delta="False">
    <text>Okay can't you just rephrase that to "poor people should be allowed to whale" then?

Basically I'm not seeing how the "aboriginal" part still factors into it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30224863938.0" user="destroy233" delta="False">
    <text>Aboriginal groups have practiced whaling for thousands of years and it is integral to their culture and survival. These isolated areas are almost all populated by these aboriginal cultures that have done this for thousands of years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30224880720.0" user="Kringspier_Des_Heren" delta="False">
    <text>Well it's clearly not more integral to their survival as that of any other poor person who can't afford food.

So we're left with the cultural which wasn't part of your original OP where you made it seem that it was about there being no other way to get food but now you're saying it's about tradition; basically you place people's rights to practice traditions above the preservation of biodiversity which is a weighing you can make but you originally phrased it like it was about that they have no other way to get food and I just don't see how that would apply; that has nothing to do with being aboriginal but with simple poverty: rich aboriginals can get food and poor non-aboriginals can't and apart from that I'm sure that if you need to hunt for your own food which I doubt is the most cost-efficient way there are other animals you can hunt that aren't endangered.

So really it's all about choosing cultural preservation over biodiversity preservation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30224919214.0" user="destroy233" delta="False">
    <text>It’s about tradition and survival. Food prices in the far north and other isolated places are ridiculously high. Job opportunities are also few and relatively low paying. So whaling is part of a long entrenched cultural tradition AND necessary for survival. For example a gallon of milk can cost upwards of 12 dollars. It’s not even. Every Inuit/inupiaq person who is allowed to whale at random, it is tightly controlled based on what area they live in and what species are hunted. Whaling of endangered species is not allowed, the most common species that is hunted is the bowhead whale which is listed as under least by the IUCN. Highly Endangered species aren’t allowed for aboriginal whaling. Addressing your other point, hunting one or 2 species of animals when your entire community is not feasible for the continuation of biodiversity. Yes it is partly about cultural diversity over biodiversity, but i believe they can both exist together. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
