<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30246401303.0" user="AngryCookedBeef" delta="False">
    <text>Not a change of view here but I wrote a research paper about this topic so I know a LOT about this particular touchy subject. Though it can be referred to as euthanasia, it's better to call it medical assistance in death(maid) or physician assisted death(pad),because euthanasia means "mercy killing" which makes it sound really negative. I've noticed that some of the comments mentioned how maid could be abused to potentially kill an unwilling patient or something. This really isn't a likely scenario but it's really hard to abuse it because aside from the patient's consent, there must be two physicians to confirm that the patient is terminally ill(has less than 6 months to live), is mentally capable of making the decision, and a handwritten note of consent. 
Also a majority of the people against this legislation base it on religious reasons and how suicide is a sin and all.
Uh brb I'm gonna go reread my paper bc I seem to have forgotten some things. Will edit this once I refresh my memory :/

Edit: Too lazy to summarize up my points so I'll just link a copy of the entire thing here. 
https://docs.google.com/document/d/11IXn_E2_DaV3rQj3GOK0WEOJadMDQjezmkGM5BEasZg/edit
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246450247.0" user="SirenitoDelFrio" delta="False">
    <text>I can’t wait to hear more about your paper. Do keep us updated!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
