<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30246208282.0" user="Sp4mDestroyer" delta="False">
    <text>I've had this discussion with my wife already. She once asked me what I would want her to do in the event I end up in the hospital in a coma, fighting for my life on life support or had to undergo this risky procedure to save my life. My answer was simple. I replied with "It depends." Then I continued with, no matter the situation or scenario, base your decision on the outlook of my quality of life afterwards. If there's a chance I can survive, but could or would end up braindead, a vegetable, someone that can't function on his own, or can't enjoy the little things I like doing (for example, if I had to have both my arms and legs cut off) then just pull the plug or don't waste any more money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246381180.0" user="SirenitoDelFrio" delta="False">
    <text>And that’s exactly where I’m coming from. If I wouldn’t get any enjoyment from living, whether due to an illness, or even being practically a vegetable, I’d want my family to pull the plug instead of forcing me to live. That would help the patient move on painlessly, and the family would finally accept the fact that the patient has moved on.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
