<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30246566934.0" user="FragileSound" delta="False">
    <text>I once read a paper/text on euthanasia where the author had a very interesting take on legalising euthanasia. This is how I remember what he/she said:

When giving someone an option, you change the possible outcomes. If you add an option to a situation you take away the possibility to have the status quo without choosing it.

To show this, consider I am having a dinner party at my house for friends. Let's say I don't invite you. In that case you have the status quo (not being at my dinner party) and you didn't have to choose the status quo. However, the moment I invite you, you can't have that anymore. Because then if you want the status quo you have to choose it. You can't have the status quo without choosing it.

This is important for two reasons: 1. By offering an option, you can imply an underlying meaning; and 2. You have to justify your choice.

1. If someone offers you a choice, there often is an underlying meaning or message in the choice/option. This might influence what the person thinks about an option. Short example: I say to you: "I have such a hard time practicing and playing piano", then you could respond: "Well, you could always stop playing piano". This could make me feel even worse, even though the option of quitting piano has always been there. Dying is always an option, but by allowing euthanasia you are telling me I could stop playing piano, with all its possible negative effects.

Now I can see why this argument is not a very good one. Obviously doctors won't go around telling people: "Hey, maybe dying is an option, cause I kind of want to go home." Which is why the second argument might be a bit stronger.

2. Let's get back to the dinner party scenario. If you want to stay home, then you'll have to have a reason for that (assuming you act rationally). This is the case for any option. But the difference when you allow euthanasia is that if you are lying in a hospital bed, you suddenly have to have a reason for your choice to stay alive (status quo) or not staying alive. This burdens those who qualify for euthanasia with having to justify not only the choice for death, but also for life.

To conclude this comment. I have to say that this view hasn't changed my view on euthanasia completely, as I am still in quite some cases of the opinion that euthanasia should be an option. I don't expect this to change your view, but I thought this was a very interesting view worthy of sharing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
