<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30245921297.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that I'm not supportive of euthanasia when other people do it for you. If you are in pain. If you are going to suffer until you die, just do it yourself. Don't put that on someone else. 

If the person is unresponsive, and no hope, then leave it up to the family. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30245944339.0" user="SirenitoDelFrio" delta="False">
    <text>But then you get into the case of whether or not suicide and assisted suicide is ethical. But you also say if the person is unresponsive, which would make it nonvoluntary euthanasia, which is illegal everywhere. You still have to weigh if the families decision is what the patient actually wants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30245956875.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>If I'm dying, but can still do things. Then I would get my affairs in order so my family wouldn't have to do anything, and then I'd off myself and give details as to why. Whether or not it's ethical is between myself and the Almighty. It would be my life and my responsibility. 

If a person is on life support or something, then that's the family's call. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30245961909.0" user="SirenitoDelFrio" delta="False">
    <text>But there’s still the case of the patient being in enough pain to want to die, but the family forces them to stay alive. If they’re hooked up to machines, they have no way to off themselves, and the doctors wouldn’t do anything because they could be charged with murder. No one would win in that situation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246469151.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>My point is, if you can express the will to die because you're dying of an incurable disease or something, just do it yourself. If the family isn't respecting wishes then have them written out before hand. But don't make a doctor or a loved one do it for you if you can help it. Go out while you still have a pair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30245984717.0" user="Ephemeral_Being" delta="False">
    <text>Stormlight Archives reference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246469755.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know what that is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246680843.0" user="Ephemeral_Being" delta="False">
    <text>Kick-ass series of books where the primary deity is named "The Almighty."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246886409.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>Ah</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246431950.0" user="angels_fan" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with "do it yourself" is that it has an extremely high risk of both pain and screwing it up so you don't actually die.

In a physician assisted suicide, the physician administers a painless chemical that makes you die.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246497521.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>Better not miss then. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246017529.0" user="Kfrr" delta="False">
    <text>God damn I hate this argument.  

JUST BECAUSE ITS LEGAL DOES NOT MEAN THAT ALL DOCTORS HAVE TO DO IT.  

You are not putting anything on anybody that hasn't already accepted what they're signing up for.  

You can't just stumble into an ER drunk and ask to be euthanized, as that doctor may not even ethically participate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246485610.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>If you have the capability to walk into a doctor's office you have the capability of walking off a cliff. Just do it yourself if you're gonna do it is my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246905693.0" user="Kfrr" delta="False">
    <text>You have no idea what you're talking about, and you've clearly never seen anyone quite literally *suffer* so that a hospital could continue to milk years and money out of cancer treatment, only to prolong someone's painful existence for another 8 months.  

Do you know why you're programmed to be so fearful of death? Do you know why people have giant funerals with flowers and caskets and expensive things?  

Because it makes. people. money.  

If your mother was diagnosed with inoperable and incurable cancer, and she was in extreme pain, the doctors would offer you multiple medications and ways to prolong her life for just a bit longer. You, being preprogrammed to say "Please try to fix her doctor, I am sympathetic and nothing is more important to me than my family", would probably empty your entire bank account and drown yourself in debt just to see her live a few extra days.  

You know what I wish we'd do? Ask the diagnosed individual what *THEY* want to do. Do you think for one second your mother wants you to spend every dollar you have trying to keep her alive? Fuck no. She's probably spent the last 10 years of her life thinking about death and what its consequences will be emotionally. Maybe she's spent thousands of dollars on life insurance and you'll be reimbursed, but guess what, Geico made hundreds of dollars a month from her while she should have been spending that money on a vacation in Bermuda for her last days.  

You know what the solution to ALL of these problems are? Allowing people to die peacefully, in an injection induced sleep.  

**I would have given anything... ANYTHING to not watch my grandmother suffer for the last year and a half of her life, and you're telling me that she should have just walked off a cliff.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246915647.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>I'm telling you that there's plenty of ways. And it's really your grandmother's choice and she doesn't need a doctor to help her. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246199335.0" user="Leocletus" delta="False">
    <text>Physician assisted suicide is when you do it yourself with the help of doctors (they give you the lethal injection etc.). Euthanasia is when another person does it for you. So it looks like you are against euthanasia, but for PAS. 

PAS is legal in 5 or 6 states. Euthanasia isn’t (but is legal in some places, like the Netherlands). 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246299974.0" user="Kylie061" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Don't put that on someone else.

But if another person voluntarily accepts that responsibility, what's wrong with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246488060.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's the person who wants to die' responsibility. Their life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246509657.0" user="Kylie061" delta="False">
    <text>But other people are allowed to accept responsibility for someone else's life especially if that person is voluntarily giving it up to them. Choice on the part of the dying person, choice on the part of the medical professional.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246536403.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>That's lazy living </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246557847.0" user="Kylie061" delta="False">
    <text>that's lazy arguing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246563531.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not. You can't just give responsibility of your life to someone while you're still capable of making  decisions as an adult.  Choose to die or choose to live. What a dishonest and dishonorable thing to let someone make those choices for you as if you're a child.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246571025.0" user="Kylie061" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would say that I'm not supportive of euthanasia when other people do it for you. If you are in pain. If you are going to suffer until you die, just do it yourself. Don't put that on someone else.

Maybe what I'm not getting is the "just do it yourself" part. By this, I'm interpreting just kill yourself, that's the only way to handle it. Why? Why can't you give someone else permission to kill you under a set of specific circumstances where you were going to die anyway and are experiencing significant pain?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246618971.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose if you're still capable, you should be the one to do it. If you're not capable, have it expressed before hand what you want to do. But probably it you can see the decline you should do it yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246632065.0" user="Kylie061" delta="False">
    <text>okay, but why? why can't a medical professional help?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246880352.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>Cause I believe it's undignified. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246590389.0" user="DDXF" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is lazy. You're only looking at the people who could do it themselves, not the brain dead people who aren't even alive, the only thing that's alive is their bodies, or the people in so much pain they can't even get out of a hospital bed to do anything about it. Saying you should just kill yourself if it's that bad, which risks failing and being in even more pain, is stupid. Why try killing yourself, which has a marginal failure factor, when you can be peacefully euthanized. And I again I raise my point, what about the people that can't even get out of bed, or are brain dead and just taking up hospital space with their beating corpses?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246615983.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>Then they need to tell people in some way that they wish to die before they get like that. Or do it themselves before they get like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246619816.0" user="DDXF" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think its on everyone's list of priorities to write down somewhere whether or not they want to die when they become unable to verbally confirm it. Nobody wants to think like that, and by not writing it, they're mentally denying that it would ever happen. Nobody expects this to happen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246882613.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>I've done it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246889967.0" user="DDXF" delta="False">
    <text>Good for you, but you aren't everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246893158.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>You used the term nobody. You mean to tell me you've not even talked about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30247286092.0" user="DDXF" delta="False">
    <text>In my experience, the majority of people don't want to believe that that could happen to them, so they don't think about it or acknowledge the risk. I haven't talked about it, personally. Not openly anyway. I've thought about it a few times, but never written it down anywhere</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246821032.0" user="BillieMadison" delta="False">
    <text>I will give you a counter-argument. When the gentleman who lived in the apartment adjacent to me wanted/needed to kill himself, the means he chose/was forced to choose was to jump from his 9th floor balcony. He clearly tried to be self-sufficient in his death by calling 911 before he jumped, and wrapping his face/head in a t-shirt to avoid a more horrific scene. I heard him hit the pavement, came to perform cpr, and now suffer from ptsd. Both of his feet broke off at the ankle when he landed. If he had a legal means to kill himself, neither myself nor the other people around would have to suffer from that experience. Same goes for family members and first responders who are forced to discover dead bodies in whichever way they died. Furthermore, it is horrific and tragic that that man, whoever he was, had to die in a moment of fear and shame instead of in a comfortable hospital bed with the respect and understanding of even a few close friends, family members or hospital staff. Do not deprive someone of that dignity. No physician can be forced to perform assisted suicide, but people are being deprived of a dignified death because of the romanticization of suicide, and the acts necessary to carry it out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246889576.0" user="Braegrmor" delta="False">
    <text>There's no dignity dying in a bed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30247191841.0" user="mitch-bittens" delta="False">
    <text>The assumption is that professionals are emotionally/mentally stable enough to do this. If they’re ok with it I don’t see the problem. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
