<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30249669482.0" user="ogy1" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct. I think one of the main reasons why euthanasia is not allowed in most first world countries is because of religious influence. Take catholicism in first world countries for example, it says in the bible if you commit suicide you have commited a sin and therefore you will go to hell. Because many of the 1st world nations have a catholic majority and have many religious people in positions of power this religious influence on their decision making prevents them from making something like euthanasia legal even though as you argued euthanasia is humane and could be regulated. A similar thing happens with abortion, religious people believe in a soul (which there is no scientific evidence for) and think if you terminate a foetus at any stage you murder this soul even though scientifically speaking for 12 weeks after conception the foetus has no brain function whatsoever and therefore has no consciousness or thoughts and is not considered intelligent life. Because again of people in powers religious beliefs, abortion something that makes logical and ethical sense in certain situations is not allowed in many countries. If you look will see a trend that the more secular countries make more logical based decisions in terms of legislation around these sorts of ethical issues eg scandinavian countries allow and regulate abortion and euthanasia etc. That#s why personally I think separating church and state and making politics secular is very beneficial for a countries people which has alot of evidence, there is a direct correlation between more secular countries and happier people in these nations. I think the only issue with just allowing euthanasia outright is people killing off elderly family members for will money. Therefore I think it is necessary to have a governmental board that assesses each case individually and makes a verdict.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
