<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30246865914.0" user="Escape-Carcass" delta="False">
    <text>You guys are so silly.  Euthanasia will never be an option for one reason.  Your body is not yours in most countries. Your body is the states property and you are not allowed to destroy or discard it.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30249705236.0" user="ogy1" delta="False">
    <text>Have you been to a nursing home before? I live in a country where euthanasia is illegal and I visit my grandmother sometimes who is cared for there. Some of the elderly people there have an absolutely shocking existance and its is actually quite upsetting when you see the state some of these people are trapped in. A lot of the people with dementia and alzheimer's are perpetually terrified and confused, there are others who are trapped unable to move or communicate and you can see that some of them are terrified. There are others who are either just straight up zombies who sit and stare into nothing all day or are stuck in a loop for example there is a woman at my grandmothers nursing home who just says 'up the window, down the window' every moment she is awake. It is completely unnatural to be alive when you get to a certain age, in the wild you would be dead a long time ago and these people are force-fed these small bullets of food that have crazy amounts of calories because their bodies refuse to eat or drink anymore and are often resuscitated from the point of death to keep them alive in a vegetative state even longer. I think if many people actually visited a nursing home they would have a different opinion. There are a number of countries who do have euthanasia already and have no issues eg scandinavian countries, so this idea that it will never be possible (i presume you mean in the usa) is not true</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
