<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495807671.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/876vnb/cmv_social_classes_are_pointless_things_like/">
    <title>CMV: Social classes are pointless. Things like feminism and racism end up becoming about power, instead of equality.</title>
    <original_poster>obkunu</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve seen so many people get their panties in a bunch over men’s rights or women’s rights or Black Pride or White Pride. 

I get the idea. To make the dominant class take themselves less seriously and make the oppressed class take themselves more seriously, until the playing field is even. 

So when Katy Perry basically forces a guy to kiss her, it’s okay because men are to take themselves less seriously. But if a man forces a girl to kiss him, it’s not okay because women are already taken too lightly. 

I get the idea I really do. But lately it seems as though women won’t stop until men are basically jokes and women are deities. 

Same goes for Blacks and Whites. Has there ever been, or is there currently any social class based issue that isn’t about reverse dominance in the name of evening the playing field?

Seems to me like social classes are just insecurities being raised to art forms until there is something else to band together and complain about. 

Edit - Someone brought my attention to the actual numbers and they basically make the idea of reverse-dominance moot. So topic closed folks. I’ve changed my view.  (Don’t know if I’m doing this right.)


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30251130785.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/obkunu (OP) has awarded 1 delta in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [**here**](/r/DeltaLog/comments/8779fz), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view [doesn't necessarily mean a reversal](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/index#wiki_what_is_a_.27view.27.3F), or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
