<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495807671.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/876vnb/cmv_social_classes_are_pointless_things_like/">
    <title>CMV: Social classes are pointless. Things like feminism and racism end up becoming about power, instead of equality.</title>
    <original_poster>obkunu</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve seen so many people get their panties in a bunch over men’s rights or women’s rights or Black Pride or White Pride. 

I get the idea. To make the dominant class take themselves less seriously and make the oppressed class take themselves more seriously, until the playing field is even. 

So when Katy Perry basically forces a guy to kiss her, it’s okay because men are to take themselves less seriously. But if a man forces a girl to kiss him, it’s not okay because women are already taken too lightly. 

I get the idea I really do. But lately it seems as though women won’t stop until men are basically jokes and women are deities. 

Same goes for Blacks and Whites. Has there ever been, or is there currently any social class based issue that isn’t about reverse dominance in the name of evening the playing field?

Seems to me like social classes are just insecurities being raised to art forms until there is something else to band together and complain about. 

Edit - Someone brought my attention to the actual numbers and they basically make the idea of reverse-dominance moot. So topic closed folks. I’ve changed my view.  (Don’t know if I’m doing this right.)


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30251159859.0" user="ThatOneEskimo" delta="False">
    <text>Well, yes. If you think about it from an equality point of view, feminism and racism are not topics that will be solved through equality measures. 

As an Australian I can't really talk for many cultures but at least here, the aboriginal population are statistically more likely to die earlier, more likely to drink in large amounts, more likely to smoke and more likely to have premature deaths across both genders. So what can we do to try and fix this?

As a white person is less likely to smoke than an aboriginal, treating them both equally with education on smoking is redundant, as it will result in a small improvement for the white population and a slightly larger but still small improvement from the aboriginal population. 

To fix the problem of aboriginals smoking more than white Australians, specialised support programs must be put in place to help them, as well as any other lifestyle factors that may influence their decision to smoke. Not including white people in this support is not an example of inequality for white Australians, but a case of more support for those who need it more. 

Fixing this gap is not going to be solved through equality, it must be solved through equity; providing those that are less fortunate with more so that all groups have the capacity to become equal. 

My example wasn't the best and my original meaning may have been lost in rambling so 

Tl;dr Equality isn't a solution to racism and sexism, and feminism resulting in more freedom for women when they have had less than men in the past is okay, provided that eventually it results in  equality, as equality alone will not help those who have had it worse in the past and have developed certain lifestyle factors that make it hard for them to integrate properly into society. Treating everyone as equal doesn't automatically make everyone equal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251761107.0" user="KoffiKhan" delta="False">
    <text>Equity not equality. Very much agree with this. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
