<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495807671.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/876vnb/cmv_social_classes_are_pointless_things_like/">
    <title>CMV: Social classes are pointless. Things like feminism and racism end up becoming about power, instead of equality.</title>
    <original_poster>obkunu</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve seen so many people get their panties in a bunch over men’s rights or women’s rights or Black Pride or White Pride. 

I get the idea. To make the dominant class take themselves less seriously and make the oppressed class take themselves more seriously, until the playing field is even. 

So when Katy Perry basically forces a guy to kiss her, it’s okay because men are to take themselves less seriously. But if a man forces a girl to kiss him, it’s not okay because women are already taken too lightly. 

I get the idea I really do. But lately it seems as though women won’t stop until men are basically jokes and women are deities. 

Same goes for Blacks and Whites. Has there ever been, or is there currently any social class based issue that isn’t about reverse dominance in the name of evening the playing field?

Seems to me like social classes are just insecurities being raised to art forms until there is something else to band together and complain about. 

Edit - Someone brought my attention to the actual numbers and they basically make the idea of reverse-dominance moot. So topic closed folks. I’ve changed my view.  (Don’t know if I’m doing this right.)


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30251148996.0" user="Bitchbasic" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think anyone supported Katy Perry. What she did was disgusting and wrong. However, that doesn’t change the fact that the majority of women are still underprivileged in comparison to men in modern society. Any celebrity/person of extreme wealth, ie. Katy Perry, is going to have power over an ordinary person, especially a contestant on their game show.

Even in the vocal minority, I very rarely see women advocating for the downfall of men. Yes, there is a tendency to call men “pigs”, but for the most part, no one is claiming that all men are below women or should be “jokes”.

It seems like you’re misunderstanding the history behind these movements. People in minority or typically oppressed groups (ie. women and African Americans) still do not have totally equal footing in America. It’s very easy for a man to look at the #MeToo movement and call it complaining, but the reality is that a majority of women live in fear. It’s scary to be a woman, even in America.

1 in 4 women (“claim”) to have been raped or sexually assaulted in their lifetimes. I’m a college student in a sorority — I’ve seen my friends get stalked and harassed by men and called horrible names and slapped when they don’t give them attention. I’ve seen a fraternity kicked off of my campus because the older brothers were passing our date rape drugs to the younger brothers for them to use at girls at one of their parties.

On the weekend before Halloween last year (2017), my lesbian friend (who is in a committed relationship) got black-out drunk at a bar, could not even stand up, and our male friends who had offered to DD there and back (and was totally sober) knowingly made out with her and tried to ditch the rest of our group and take her back to his place.

I walk home from work two blocks away with pepper spray. Ive been followed around a Kroger by catcalling men who wouldn’t leave me alone until I lied and said I was 16.

I’m not presenting anecdotal evidence for no reason. These are very real issues that the majority of women in America face. Men, who KNOW that they can easily overpower most women, take advantage of that fact to get attention and try to take what they want. I’m not saying all men are like this. I’m saying that a good number of men are like this, and that the majority of men allow this system to continue by claiming that modern sexism does not exist.

Feminism IS about equality. It’s about being seen as equal and not getting objectified by men. I can’t speak for every woman on Earth. I can speak for myself and every woman I’ve ever personally met. Women don’t want to hurt men. Women want men to stop mistreating them. It’s really not too much to ask for to not be sexually harassed at least once a month or to get called a bitch when you don’t response to some guy trying to take you out. Actual feminists just want respect.

Don’t confuse feminism with misandry.

Edit: just saw your edit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251162520.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>I’d like nothing better than for these men to face justice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251427028.0" user="HereWeGoAgainTakeTwo" delta="False">
    <text>"at least once a month" more like several times a week, or 20 times a night if you go out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251697210.0" user="Bitchbasic" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251464848.0" user="Zelthia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Yes, there is a tendency to call men “pigs”


And that’s fine and acceptable, judging by the content of your post. A tendency to call women whores would however be proof of how terrible women’s lives are and how much you have to put up with.

Not making it up. You say it yourself:

*I’ve seen my friends get stalked and harassed by men* **and called horrible names**

Sounds pretty hypocritical to me. 


&amp;gt;&amp;gt; I’m not presenting anecdotal evidence for no reason. These are very real issues that the majority of women in America face. Men, who KNOW that they can easily overpower most women, take advantage of that fact to get attention and try to take what they want.


Women, who know that society will be on their side, take advantage of the fact to get attention and try to take what they want.

It is absolutely no different. Women fear being attacked by random crazy man, men fear being taken to task over nothing by some crazy feminist.

This leads me to:

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;I’m not saying all men are like this. I’m saying that a good number of men are like this, and that the majority of men allow this system to continue


As a society, we despise the man that attacks you, but you want to justify pushing an agenda where your taking a man to task over perceived lack of respect is not being done often enough.

Feminism is the epitome of pot calling the kettle black. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251732788.0" user="Bitchbasic" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think that your first example is really a true display of inequality. When I say that men have a tendency to be called pigs, I mean that women in feminists groups will declare ALL men to be “pigs” online or at rallies, etc. When men call women names, it’s more like verbal abuse. Half the time a guy gets rejected, he’ll go on about how fat and ugly a woman is and call her crazy/a slut/clingy behind her back — just because she wouldn’t have sex with him or go out with him.

I don’t think this this is comparable, and they’re two totally different situations. If a guy sees a woman say “all men are pigs”, I’m sure it hurts, but it doesn’t hurt as much as targeted verbal abuse does.

Furthermore, your argument lies on the fact that I have a double standard in the first place. Of course I’m against women being verbally mocked; you quoted it yourself. I never said that I supported or was justifying men being called pigs, even as a group. In context, I said “Even in the vocal minority, I very rarely see women advocating for the downfall of men. Yes, there is a tendency to call men “pigs”, but for the most part, no one is claiming that all men are below women or should be “jokes”. (I don’t know how to do reddit quotes, sorry.) When I said that feminists tend to call all men pigs, I was conceding something *negative* that the group does while saying that the *majority* of feminists do not actively put men down aside from this.

I also don’t think it’s fair to compare a fear of being *physically attacked* to a fear of a woman calling a man out for something like “mansplaining”. Sure, a hyper-feminist going on a tangent is annoying, but it literally cannot compare to being sexually assaulted, raped, attacked, etc. It is absolutely different.

Your third point is entirely contingent on this fact, so I’ll include it in the following argument:

“Taking a man to task” is nowhere near comparable to being attacked. This is a fact. There is no law against telling a man he’s wrong for staring at your breast, etc. There are MANY laws against sexual harassment, sexual assault, rape, and other extremely common attacks against women that happen on a regularly basis. I’m sorry that some men feel like they’re being “taken to task” by a feminist. I feel much worse for the girls who are fearful to walk alone at night, suffer from PTSD, or are raising rape children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252270467.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251767496.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>If feminism is truly about equality then why is it anytime that I bring up something about men being treated unfairly, abused, or just not equal feminist laugh and disregard it as untrue? They victim blame the men. All I see is feminist fighting for women and having women marches and supporting women not men, but nothing for men? Me even asking that question I bet feminist were rolling their eyes.

 I literally saw a video the other day of a man passed out at what looked like a party. These two girls in bikinis were all grinding and humping on the man. When I brought up how disgusting it was and if this was reversed roles that video would be a violation of so many laws and rules and be in front page media, I received back lash saying I was gay and how any guy would dream of this. Absolute filth. 

If feminism is truly about equality they should be fighting this stuff too. Well but they're not. You even said yourself "it's about being seen as equal and not getting objectified by men" so its only for women? I thought it was equality? Equality means for both sides. So yes feminism isn't about true equality, it's about what you think equality is which isn't actually eequality. 

You can't fight for equality while only fighting for one side. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251810839.0" user="Bitchbasic" delta="False">
    <text>You *can* fight for equality by only fighting for one side. I’m not denying that men don’t experience injustice in society, but those occurrences are rare and seen as unusual. (Hence the false stereotype that “men don’t get raped.”) For women, the inequality is much worse and has spanned millennia; women have been systemically oppressed in nearly every historical civilization, and still are in many societies today.

Men should be treated fairly. The fact that you saw comments glorifying a man being sexually assaulted/raped is horrifying to me. However, I would argue that men’s rights aren’t as strongly fought for because these issues happen on a much smaller scale.

Furthermore, I believe that feminism and the advocating for female rights actually *helps* men. (Again, not misandry — I’m strictly talking about females fighting for their own equal rights.) Many of the people who promote the “men can’t be raped” lie and say that women grinding on an unconscious man would be “a dream” are men. The idea that men can’t be raped comes out of the stereotype that men are stronger and better than women, whereas women are weaker, more vulnerable, and are therefore the only sex able to be raped.

Yes, ideal feminism advocates for equality and justice for both sides. However, women have it much worse than men in every society on earth today, whether from prevalent rape or active human rights violations — that’s a fact. The reason why you see women only advocating for their own gender is because for women, these struggles are a very real and common occurrence.

If your house’s roof is leaking, but your children are starving, which are you going to prioritize a solution for? It’s not that you don’t want your roof to be fixed — but starvation is a much more pressing issue.

Until women are closer to standing on equal footing with men on the world scale, for most feminists, actively advocating for men’s rights is not a priority because the state of women’s rights is far worse. That said, I’m sure most feminists are outraged by injustices to men. When Katy Perry forcefully kissed a male contestant, feminists were some of the most vocal who said that the kiss was sexual assault and *wrong*.

Again, actual feminists don’t hate men, and actually do want them to not face injustices. But it’s important to prioritize women’s rights when [1 in 4 women experience rape (with 98% of women’s rapists being men and 93% of *men’s* rapists also being men)](http://www.oneinfourusa.org/statistics.php) in their lifetimes and women in some foreign countries are still married off to the highest bidder and have only recently gained rights such as driving or traveling alone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251885091.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>So why are you playing the compare game? Also its fine if feminism is fighting for women. I just want it to be known you aren't fighting for true equality and feminism should be labeled as such. It's not equality. Plain and simple. 

I'd also like to direct you to a post: https://www.reddit.com/r/MensRights/comments/873xqg/it_is_in_fact_males_not_females_that_suffer/?utm_source=reddit-android 
While the title is garbage and some wording is not the best, it's a good source some of the injustices that men face. There are more posts on the sub that go into good detail with sources on specifics. I suggest you do some of your own research that the big media won't show to you. I too once was a feminist. But even in this conversation you are trying to oppress male suffering as less than females. Which just further proves my point. You have also grouped men with a stereotype which is one thing feminist supposedly fight against which is a bit hypocritical and more double standards. 

Let it be known I'm not advocating to not get equality for women. Because I, from experience with my family, know they suffer in many ways and fight for my women counterparts, I just don't think the answer for equality is modern day feminism which is so one sided. I also don't think the Mens Right thing is the way. I just go there for some good information. I think equality is the answer where we fight for both sides. 

Using your analogy of leaking versus starving (which I think is a huge overstatement of the problems for each side) we have enough people to work on both simultaneously. It's not just one person living in that house, we're all a family that can work together. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251897183.0" user="Bitchbasic" delta="False">
    <text>I’ll definitely read over that thread later today, although I don’t have the time right now.

Just based on the title, which I know you said is “garbage”, do you honestly believe that women have the advantage in society despite women being systemically oppressed for centuries and only recently gaining the bare minimum of “equal” rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252017081.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>Definitely a tough question. In some areas yes, but in others no. In regards to child custody cases, decisions of abortion or not, divorce cases, in cases where women can falsely accuse a man of rape, the man not get a fair trial or his reputation ruined and the girl gets no repercussion, which leads to my next point the justice system in general is harder on men than women. But I am not ignorant enough to ignore that men have gotten the better side of the coin in lots of situations too which should not happen. 

But I mean in my own experience I didn't get a job at Google (who is now being sued for not hiring white males or Asian males to meet quota) because I am what I am and not a minority or woman. You can't fight fire with fire. While I think its great that companies are trying to solve the issues minorities face but I shouldn't suffer when I'm qualified or more qualified than others because you have a quota. If a women or minority is better qualified, great give them the job. If not? Don't be what we are fighting against. It doesn't help anyone. 

So your question is very situational that leads to another thing that is men and women are biologically different and will always be. So we will never be truly equal, but should definitely have equal opportunity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254367115.0" user="throwaway1239387" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the issue with quotas, and I get why they make you mad. I recently went through the college admission process, and am white and upper class. I get it. Personally, I'm not sure where I stand with quotas. They have their ups and downs.

But, I do want to address what you said about quotas not helping anyone. I'm a woman applying for I-Banking internships for next summer, and have begun going to recruiting events. If I go to an event and there is not a single woman on that panel, I cross it out in my mind as a **do not work here** place. While not always the case, if the vast majority of a company is male, and there is not a physical reason why (such as construction), I, and many women will assume the work environment is somewhat hostile to women. And then I, and many qualified women won't apply there, and the company loses out because of it. Maybe a lack of women doesn't necessarily mean a company is hostile to women, but a lot of people will assume so and then the company loses out. It's similar to the pressure many men feel against working in education when they see only women teaching at a school. I would absolutely be for a push to get more men involved in early childhood education, and if that meant lower standards to entry (ex. no babysitting experience as a teen, never was a camp counselor, etc) I would be for that. Yeah, a guy **can** be a babysitter as a teen. But he's going to get pressured not to, the same way a teen girl would feel pressured not to join the A/V club or robotics. 

Essentially, I think your assumption that the woman who did get your job is unqualified is unfounded and not based in proof. I also think your assumption that you would have gotten the job if you were a minority or a woman is unfounded -- is it possible that you just aren't that good? Did you go to an Ivy or top-20 school? Because I do, and even here people applying for jobs at Google don't think they have a chance in hell at getting it. Getting a job at Google is akin to getting into Harvard. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254955616.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>The thing with quotas is that there's a big possibility they aren't hiring based on what's best for company. If you hire someone who isn't as good you're hurting your company. You're also hurting everyone that applied. If more women and minorities are getting hired simply because they're meeting quota then it'll reduce the effort they put in themselves to better themselves over competitors since they'll just be more likely to get the job. The white men or Asian men will have to start going a whole extra nine yards to even be considered and you'll be right back where we landed with inequality in the workplace. 

Look I get the idea and the point of it and I think its great they want to try to fight inequality but you can't fight fire with fire. Not going to work. Quotas are the wrong way. Just encourage more diversity. Publish ads telling how you're trying to recruit more diverse people as long as they are on equal standing as the competition or better. Slowly and surely bring the change as you grow. Don't just flat out at the beginning say "NO MORE WHITE OR ASIAN MEN". And also don't hold diversity meetings where you don't allow them to come and help. Just because we aren't a minority or a woman doesn't mean we don't want to help or we aren't important to feel like we belong. So me as a white man who hasn't been in the work force for more than 3 years should suffer because of what some corrupt men have been doing for years when I had nothing to do with it? Fight those people, not the ones just trying to make their way like everyone else. 

As someone who is graduating in May and has almost 3 years experience in my field already along with good standing grades I see myself out there. I also did well on my interview so it came as a shock to me and when I asked why they wouldn't tell me. Which isn't uncommon but it was just wasn't right and then all these stories pop up about white men not getting treated equally and it just makes you think. No I don't 100% think it's why, but are you going to say its impossible? Still regardless if that's why I didn't get the job or not there's PROVEN in court evidence that it is happening along with many other accounts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30256670324.0" user="throwaway1239387" delta="False">
    <text>Listen, I understand your point about quotas -- they are unfair. My main point is that life is unfair. But, in general, life is more unfair to the people who need quotas. There have been multiple studies done that a recruiter will perceive the **same resume** as less qualified when it has a women's or a minorities name on top. Here is a link to a study done at Stanford proving that: http://gender.stanford.edu/news/2014/why-does-john-get-stem-job-rather-jennifer

Is that fair? No. Absolutely not. Women and minorities have an unconscious bias working against them and have to be more qualified to be perceived as equally competent. That's just the reality of the situation, and the fact that there are anti-discrimination laws doesn't fully get rid of unconscious bias. 

Is that your fault? No. And no ones saying it is. But the fact of the matter is that you benefit from this. Job applications are a numbers game, and when a significant segment of the application pool has to deal with this setback, the ones who don't have an inherent advantage. Again, not your fault, but it is something you benefit from. I benefit from something similar by being white, and I think it is important to recognize this. 

It might not be the best solution to fighting this unconscious bias, but we don't have a better solution. We can't change peoples unconscious biases, we can only account for them. Having quotas forces employers to more strongly consider the applications of historically disadvantaged groups. Does that give us an advantage? Absolutely. But recognize that you are given an advantage in that you are more likely to be perceived as competent simply because you are a white man. Your fault? Nope. But that's your advantage. Is it fair if no one else gets any advantages?

Yes, there is proven evidence that sometimes white men are at a disadvantage in some circumstances. But trust me, there's a hell of a lot more evidence that women and minorities are at a disadvantage. In certain circumstances, your gender and race will hurt you. But you are failing to recognize that this already happens much more often to women and minorities.

Also, as regards to diversity events. I was recently at a women in finance panel with a relatively prestigious MM firm. The point of it wasn't to exclude men just for the sake of excluding men. The point of it was that we could talk about the specific challenges these women faced due to their gender in such a heavily male-dominated industry. We talked about what to do if you were facing sexual harassment by a superior (and some men do deal with this, but it is much more common and a concern for women). We talked about how women in finance have to toe the line between being assertive and a bitch, in ways men don't. We talked about what it meant to be a working mother in a field where you're working 80+ hours a week. We talked about how dressing too feminine make you be percieved less seriously. Essentially, we talked about things we would have gotten professional backlash asking men. It was a place to discuss the specific challenges women face in finance. 

And you know what? There was a dude that showed up. He was allowed to stay and participated in the panel. I don't know how much he actually got out of it though -- because it was mostly about womens issues. These spaces aren't made to exclude men -- they are made to include women in a way they sometimes aren't. It's not like the panels are where they say "here women -- here are some internships just for being women!! yay diversity!!". They are meant to help us feel more comfortable entering an industry we are at an inherent disadvantage at. For me, this panel served to quell some of my fears about what it means to be a working mother in IB, and what to do when you feel excluded because of your gender. If you want to attend that panel, go ahead, but you aren't going to get much out of it. Again, not about excluding men/white people. They're about including people who often feel excluded. 

I get wanting to blame external forces when you fail. I had the same urge last year when I was rejected from Harvard Yale and Stanford. But over the year I've done a lot of thinking, and I've come to realize that while those accepted maybe didn't deserve it more than me, I surely didn't deserve it more than them. There are so many smart talented people out there. It can be hard to accept when we fail it might be because we just aren't enough. I get it. But my dude, Google is possibly the most selective job to get coming out of undergrad. I'm at a top 20 school, and I know people here who have near perfect grades who were rejected. One of them was a minority woman with near perfect grades, tons of related extracurriculars, and a scholarship student at my school. Rejected. Rejection is just a part of life. And I get wanting to blame it on external forces, but google hired *plenty* of white men to intern this summer. You just weren't one of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251984579.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>That thread is full of injustices against men that are cause by the patriarchy. Men cause the problems that face men, and men dominate political and economic power. Men have the ability to solve their own problems but they don’t. MRAs, who rarely deserve the title as all the vast majority of them do is bitch and whine about how feminism and women are ruining their lives rather than making any proposals to solve men’s issues, ignore that rather obvious fact that the issues they complain about are caused by the male dominated system we live in, not women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252050218.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>Ahhh. Feminist I take it? Blaming men for being oppressed. There are actually tons of proposals and men advocating for it, but people like you don't allow it. You shut them down and laugh. In case you didn't know not every man has the power to do it. If we did something would be done. Anytime a man would try to implement a law to help men he would be called misogynistic and a pig by feminist and scorned at by media to which he would lose all his "power" he had. But nice try. There's a stigma in trying to help men, and all we can do right now is speak and try to encourage others to understand because if we do anything as society stands right now, its torn apart. 

But yes keep your iconic man hating and hypocritical victim blaming on men mindset just as all extreme feminist do and continue to be a part of the problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252072715.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>Bullshit. Yes, I am a feminist, I am also a man. I advocate for both men's and women's issues, but I haven't heard a single decent propose from MRAs, I've heard many good proposals for solving both men's and women's issues from feminists. And the reason many MRA proposals get called misogynistic is that they are. Women are disadvantaged in our society, vastly more so then men are. 

All I really need to say to you though, and the single explanation for the whining done by most MRAs, is that when you're accustomed to privilege, equality feels like oppression. I won't stop fighting for women's rights until women are accurately represented in the highest level of political and economic life. Men dominate political and economic life, if MRAs want change, use that, and do so without once again limiting women's opportunities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252131170.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>"Do so without one again limiting women's opportunities" so doing the same to men is okay? Not equality. 

But I would love to hear those proposals then. Cause all I've heard is women this and women that. 

And tell me how they are so disadvantaged. Please. I know they have disadvantages but explain to me why its so much worse. 

Rape. Disgusting and I agree 100%. But the metoo movement is allowing innocent men to fall victim too easily so this needs to be addressed as well. Better investigations need to be done. 

Wage. Which depending on the source has been skewed. But yes has improved vastly in the last few decades. 

What else? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252205739.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>The simplest solution to the vast majority of men's issues is breaking down the patriarchy and gender roles. Get rid of toxic masculinity will massively help men. 

Can you cite any sources showing men are falsely convicted of rape at any significant rate, or if that rate has increased? A reckoning over sexual assault and harassment has been way overdue.

Wages. Women are paid less for the same work, as more women enter industries, salaries in those industries go down. Women's work is valued less than men's, that's an empirical observation.

And in the very end, men dominate political and economic life, women do not have the same power men do.

And once again, when you're accustomed to privilege, equality feels like oppression. Men's opportunities are only being limited in that their unjust advantages over women are being taken away. Until MRAs understand that, they won't make any progress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253466833.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Just a few corrections: first, gender only accounts for a very small % of the wage gap. Most of it is due to personal choice. It's not as simple as "men get paid more for working the same jobs because sexism." 

Second, women control about 80% of the consumer market. The general model is that money that women make, women spend, and money than men make, women spend. 

Third, women actually control *slightly* more of our political sphere than men, just because there are more women in the country. Most politicians are male, to be sure, but women have exerted more electoral power than men have in putting them there. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252038747.0" user="SituationSoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; why is it anytime that I bring up something about men being treated unfairly, abused, or just not equal feminist laugh and disregard it as untrue?

Probably because most of the shit you see on Men's Rights forums is actually untrue. You're getting information from a biased source, then you're concern trolling those same people when they're not taking that bias seriously.

&amp;gt; I received back lash saying I was gay and how any guy would dream of this

So, to be clear, you're upset at feminists because when you criticized women you received backlash from non-feminist men about your behavior?

The core of your problem here is that you're not thinking through who you're upset at or why you're upset about it.

&amp;gt; If feminism is truly about equality they should be fighting this stuff too.

Lots of feminists *do* fight this stuff. And the great thing about feminism is that it's a big tent, where your ideas are more important than who you are. You could contribute to making feminism more aware and more critical of sexual abuse against men, if you want.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252097944.0" user="miniibeast" delta="False">
    <text>Biased source? Well what other source am I going to go to? No other media outlet will publish it because the backlash they would get. I take everything with a grain of salt in feminist articles and the mens rights ones and if you see my history you would know I speak when i noticed the mens right becoming just like feminism is and not for equality but bashing and false claims. I'm not trolling anyone. I'm bringing light to a situation feminist won't think about sometimes and fail to listen to. 

I'm not upset at just feminist. I'm upset at the societal norm of allowing that stuff and feminist aren't helping. And it was the women who performed the act let me remind you. But yes lets focus on the "non feminist" men involved. I'm not pinning the blame on any one thing I was just stating how feminism isn't the answer because they aren't fighting or advocating against this stuff at all but say they are about equality. This video was on instagram. If that video was gender reversed instagram would have had the video down in minutes. I'm just showing you how feminism should be fighting for true equality and that it isn't. 

Yeah I tried that as a feminist and got called misogynistic by feminist. So I stopped associating myself with a fake equality movement. Not one feminist I know supports what I say or tries to help and just plays the "women have it worse" game. 

A women literally said thanks to men in a tweet and feminist were outraged. So no it's almost impossible to do that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252160976.0" user="SituationSoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well what other source am I going to go to?

Sources that print things that actually happen without a political agenda.

&amp;gt; No other media outlet will publish it because the backlash they would get.

No other media outlet will publish it *because it's not news*. "Two girls grind on a drunk guy and post the video on YouTube" is not news. It's not relevant to the lives of anyone. If the guy in question pressed charges, *that* would be news. Did the guy in question press charges?

&amp;gt; I take everything with a grain of salt in feminist articles and the mens rights ones

This is the equivalent of saying "I take everything in my high school history textbook and The Lord of the Rings with a grain of salt." One of those things is not like the other and comparing the two creates serious questions about your ability to be impartial on the topic.

&amp;gt; I'm bringing light to a situation feminist won't think about sometimes and fail to listen to.

Where are the examples of prominent feminists OK-ing the behavior in this YT videos? Of prominent feminists cheering for Katy Perry forcing a guy to kiss her? You're criticizing people who don't exist.

&amp;gt; I was just stating how feminism isn't the answer because they aren't fighting or advocating against this stuff at all

I think you're about a year's worth of feminist reading short of being able to credibly make this claim, because feminists in fact *do* argue against this stuff.

&amp;gt; If that video was gender reversed instagram would have had the video down in minutes.

Can you provide examples of equivalent videos that have been pulled from Instagram "in minutes?" Again, you're claiming this is a massive, society-wide problem. There should be dozens of videos like these.

&amp;gt; Yeah I tried that as a feminist and got called misogynistic by feminist.

You're spending a whole bunch of time right now trying to tell everyone who'll listen that feminism is bullshit and a harm to society. That's misogynistic. The way to not be called misogynistic is to not do things that are misogynistic. For instance, you could start by *listening* to people instead of having an opinion about their movement before having done even basic research about it and spewing MRA bullshit as a justification for your feelings.

&amp;gt; A women literally said thanks to men in a tweet and feminist were outraged.

Seriously, what are you talking about? I can't argue against anecdotes with no sources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252194627.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
