<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495807671.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/876vnb/cmv_social_classes_are_pointless_things_like/">
    <title>CMV: Social classes are pointless. Things like feminism and racism end up becoming about power, instead of equality.</title>
    <original_poster>obkunu</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve seen so many people get their panties in a bunch over men’s rights or women’s rights or Black Pride or White Pride. 

I get the idea. To make the dominant class take themselves less seriously and make the oppressed class take themselves more seriously, until the playing field is even. 

So when Katy Perry basically forces a guy to kiss her, it’s okay because men are to take themselves less seriously. But if a man forces a girl to kiss him, it’s not okay because women are already taken too lightly. 

I get the idea I really do. But lately it seems as though women won’t stop until men are basically jokes and women are deities. 

Same goes for Blacks and Whites. Has there ever been, or is there currently any social class based issue that isn’t about reverse dominance in the name of evening the playing field?

Seems to me like social classes are just insecurities being raised to art forms until there is something else to band together and complain about. 

Edit - Someone brought my attention to the actual numbers and they basically make the idea of reverse-dominance moot. So topic closed folks. I’ve changed my view.  (Don’t know if I’m doing this right.)


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30251691519.0" user="loewenheim" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have an example of a self-described feminist saying Katy Perry forcing a guy to kiss her is ok?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251710185.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not the point. I would think it’s ok if the idea was to take men less seriously and women more seriously. 

I just thought that this is no longer the idea. I thought the playing field is already even where both men and women are given equal consideration. So now, it’s about women being dominant over men. 

I said that this trend of reverse-dominance is apparent in all social class based issues such as sexism, feminism, racism. 

Somebody pointed out that despite my own observations, the worldwide numbers show that the oppressed class are still far from being on equal footing with the dominant class. 

Therefore, I edited the post to accept that the original idea of diminishing the dominant group and elevating the oppressed group is still the driving force, and not reverse-dominance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251775323.0" user="loewenheim" delta="False">
    <text>But this is not a matter of elevating women above men at all, least of all by feminists. I would be surprised to see feminists considering this a good thing, much less a victory.

I mean, the idea of "diminishing the dominant group and elevating the oppressed group" has some merit, but that doesn't mean that women get to disregard men's consent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251793868.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>No, you’re right. It doesn’t. But you get the idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251833287.0" user="Nylnin" delta="False">
    <text>[OP I think you might find this TedTalk interesting ](https://youtu.be/lrYx7HaUlMY) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30252044392.0" user="SituationSoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That’s not the point.

Of course it's the point. You're criticizing a group of people for being OK with something that none of them have actually come out and said they're OK with. 

&amp;gt; I said that this trend of reverse-dominance is apparent in all social class based issues such as sexism, feminism, racism.

But you have no examples of this trend, which is apparently so widespread it should be self-obvious to anyone looking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253535528.0" user="kellenthehun" delta="False">
    <text>Have you looked into the Evergreen College debacle, most notably what happened to Bert Weinstein?  Just curious of your thoughts on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254333612.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Of course it's the point. You're criticizing a group of people for being OK with something that none of them have actually come out and said they're OK with. 

I wasn’t criticizing anybody. I was using the Katy Perry incident as an example of a woman violating a man to support the idea that when feminism started, it was about diminishing men and elevating women, until they were both even, which would make what Katy Perry did acceptable, given that she was a celebrity trying to make someone’s day. 

I used a completely different set of examples to question the relevance of social class based movements to highlight how they seem to simply be dominance exchanges. Today there’s feminism. Tomorrow there’ll be masculinism and so forth. That’s the point. 

The Katy Perry incident was just an example. I never actually said anyone was OK with what she did, nor criticized anybody for it. Read the post and understand it before making snap judgments. Ask if you have questions. But don’t assume and shoot off baseless accusations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254791039.0" user="SituationSoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; which would make what Katy Perry did acceptable

My point is that what Katy Perry did *wasn't* acceptable and there isn't any evidence of feminists supporting her or saying it was acceptable. 

&amp;gt; I used a completely different set of examples to question the relevance of social class based movements to highlight how they seem to simply be dominance exchanges.

You didn't *actually* use examples. You invented some ideas then brought up vague trends to justify those without providing any examples of those trends actually happening.

&amp;gt; I never actually said anyone was OK with what she did

But your argument is premised on her doing that being "acceptable" which means people *have* to be OK with what she did. That's what acceptable means; it's accepted. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254957497.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My point is that what Katy Perry did *wasn't* acceptable and there isn't any evidence of feminists supporting her or saying it was acceptable. 

I never claimed that there was said evidence. Like I said, I used that as an example for a woman violating a man. I was trying to get across the perspective that when feminism started the idea was that it was okay that the concept of violation didn’t translate equally for men and women since the idea was to make men take themselves less seriously and make women take themselves more seriously. 

&amp;gt; But your argument is premised on her doing that being "acceptable" which means people *have* to be OK with what she did. That's what acceptable means; it's accepted. 

No. My argument isn’t premised on that particular incident being OK at all, just the idea that violations don’t translate equally for men and women because well, we’ve been over this. As I said previously, Katy Perry was just an example. 

&amp;gt; You didn't *actually* use examples. You invented some ideas then brought up vague trends to justify those without providing any examples of those trends actually happening.

My mistake. I didn’t provide the examples in the actual post. They’re in the comments. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30255016005.0" user="SituationSoap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I was trying to get across the perspective that when feminism started

When feminism started it was about voting rights. This is *really basic* feminist history. 

&amp;gt; it was okay that the concept of violation didn’t translate equally for men and women since the idea was to make men take themselves less seriously and make women take themselves more seriously.

This is word salad. It doesn't make any logical sense, and doesn't square with history. You might as well have said that feminism was about sending rockets to space because Barry Bonds once hit a home run. You're not making any sense.

&amp;gt; My argument isn’t premised on that particular incident being OK at all

Your argument was premised on the idea that it was "acceptable" which *by definition* means it's OK. 

&amp;gt; just the idea that violations don’t translate equally for men and women

Except you have not given *any evidence* that the violations don't translate, despite being called for that repeatedly. You're fundamentally misunderstanding the basic history of the topic you're talking about, the goals of the movement that build off that topic, counter-examples of that topic, and you're using non sequiturs to support your absurd perspectives.

Your viewpoint *is not connected to reality in any appreciable manner*. That's become *more* apparent as people have tried to challenge it. We cannot change your viewpoint because you believe things that don't exist provide evidence for a movement that isn't happening.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30255071419.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>The post clearly states that my viewpoint has already changed. I’ve awarded a delta for it. You’ll see the connections to reality if you go through the comments and the examples that caused me to “believe things that don’t exist” 

I haven’t formally studied the history. I get my ideas from feminists I know and that “word salad” is how they put it. They used parallels — specifically why Black Pride is ok but White Pride is not. 

I’ve been replying to you just to discuss your perspective regarding the post and to clarify certain gaps and misunderstandings. If changing my view is what you wanted, that’s already happened. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
