<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495807671.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/876vnb/cmv_social_classes_are_pointless_things_like/">
    <title>CMV: Social classes are pointless. Things like feminism and racism end up becoming about power, instead of equality.</title>
    <original_poster>obkunu</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve seen so many people get their panties in a bunch over men’s rights or women’s rights or Black Pride or White Pride. 

I get the idea. To make the dominant class take themselves less seriously and make the oppressed class take themselves more seriously, until the playing field is even. 

So when Katy Perry basically forces a guy to kiss her, it’s okay because men are to take themselves less seriously. But if a man forces a girl to kiss him, it’s not okay because women are already taken too lightly. 

I get the idea I really do. But lately it seems as though women won’t stop until men are basically jokes and women are deities. 

Same goes for Blacks and Whites. Has there ever been, or is there currently any social class based issue that isn’t about reverse dominance in the name of evening the playing field?

Seems to me like social classes are just insecurities being raised to art forms until there is something else to band together and complain about. 

Edit - Someone brought my attention to the actual numbers and they basically make the idea of reverse-dominance moot. So topic closed folks. I’ve changed my view.  (Don’t know if I’m doing this right.)


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30251142251.0" user="onesix16" delta="False">
    <text>When you discuss equality, you will inevitably have to talk about social classes, their conditions, and their dynamics. They're salient to the discussion of how to achieve equal opportunity, suffrage, and equal representation. Can you discuss equality without mentioning whose specific group is being treated unequally? Therefore, such classes are not pointless.

Moreover, I understand your argument as: contemporary class struggles are not struggles for equality but for the dominance of the minority (which is a misguided attempt to evening the playing field as you recognize) and therefore these "struggles" are no longer relevant and are now manifestations of "insecurities".

I posit a few questions concerning this view of yours:

1. Let's take your point about women not stopping until men are jokes and women become deities. This is obviously an example of dominance of the minority power against the majority power which you'd rightfully argued against. Therefore,

How are you sure that you are not arguing against an extreme and general example? Are women who demand domination over males *the only* representatives of women's rights? How do you therefore construe the less extreme versions who do not push for domination, such as feminists in Third-World countries who are still fighting for basic women rights?

And aren't the struggles minority classes in oppressive institutions such as those above valid and not pointless?

2. You argue that the line between fighting for equality and fighting for reverse dominance is blurring. Thus, when a group is pushing for power over the system, that is no longer a struggle for equality but a struggle for power. I think it is our responsibility to know what groups are validly struggling for equal rights and what groups are just looking to project their insecurities or looking to unfairly dominate the system.

But this also leads me to ask:

Are struggles for power and struggles for equality any different? Because if it is so, then things like feminism and racism have always been about power, just not *overpowering* everything else. 

Almost anyone will agree with you that such causes shouldn't be fronts to gain total domination over the system because that eliminates the point of equality, but the question then stands:

Does a group seeking to overpower the system instead of gaining equality invalidate the struggles of groups who have only sought equality? And if so, then are social classes therefore irrelevant?


 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251150394.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>I think the relevant issue here is fighting for what’s yours as an individual, not as a group. 

I get support groups, but as you said, due to susceptibility of these issues to platforms of dominance, it would only make sense for a support group to show support during particular incidents using the facts of that incident, instead of working to abstract themes that are likely to have no meaning in the end. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251160226.0" user="onesix16" delta="False">
    <text>I've read your edit and I agree with much of what you said in your reply. I won't argue any further and I appreciate your time being here. Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253478920.0" user="Nonplacebo" delta="False">
    <text>Damn, such civil discourse! Am I even on the internet? I wish every sub had the decency of this one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
