<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="496153887.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/87easf/cmv_most_modern_medical_advances_have_come_from/">
    <title>CMV most modern medical advances have come from companies looking to profit in the American medical system, and if America were to switch to a European style system then progress would slow worldwide</title>
    <original_poster>Extratydoncbicbslleb</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this without a ton of knowledge about the recent history of medical advances, but it seems to me that most modern medical companies don’t see much money to be made in socialist systems. While they will take the profits they can get there, if America were to switch as well medical advancement would stall (with the advantage that the current top quality of care would be widely available)

I am fully aware that there are numerous inefficiencies in our healthcare system unrelated to capitalist/socialist systems but that isn’t the subject here


Thanks </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30253799135.0" user="ThomasEdmund84" delta="False">
    <text>You are aware that other countries have private health-care right? And if anything there is more selection pressure on developing innovative technology that justifies expense because service completes with public healthcare. 

I do agree that public healthcare puts the focus on cheap mass production moreso than highly specific advancements but governments have to pay for healthcare just as much as individuals and insurance companies </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253936296.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn’t really address my question though- unless the profits are still large enough to fuel more medical innovation, which is what I’m looking for</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253946298.0" user="ThomasEdmund84" delta="False">
    <text>Are you looking for a change of view or just asking a really specific question?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253964709.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>Looking for a change of view, backed up with facts
Mutatron was the closest to convincing me so far, but I’m looking for something a bit more concrete and extrapolating by shrinking the whole us market seems like it could warp things too much 

Though I grant that the facts I want may not exist even if I’m ultimately wrong just due to the size of the us market distorting things.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
