<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="496153887.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/87easf/cmv_most_modern_medical_advances_have_come_from/">
    <title>CMV most modern medical advances have come from companies looking to profit in the American medical system, and if America were to switch to a European style system then progress would slow worldwide</title>
    <original_poster>Extratydoncbicbslleb</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this without a ton of knowledge about the recent history of medical advances, but it seems to me that most modern medical companies don’t see much money to be made in socialist systems. While they will take the profits they can get there, if America were to switch as well medical advancement would stall (with the advantage that the current top quality of care would be widely available)

I am fully aware that there are numerous inefficiencies in our healthcare system unrelated to capitalist/socialist systems but that isn’t the subject here


Thanks </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30254377575.0" user="TBOIOMATb_CYKA" delta="False">
    <text>You're assuming that America's high costs of medical care are driven by high costs of technology or medicine, which isn't exactly the case. The standard of medical care that we receive in most situations doesn't differ from what you'd get in a socialized European system. 

There are a lot of factors driving the costs, but as I understand, the biggest difference is our highly fragmented market. In a socialized system, where the state pays for everyone, the state has the bargaining power to say something like "we will need X quantity of hip replacements this year -- give us your best price for the parts". If a supplier wants access to that market, they have to make a competitive offer. In the states, we are fragmented into much smaller markets under insurers, state-by-state.

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254391448.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>You’ve actually got my view a bit mixed up- I’m mostly concerning myself with the high amount of investment in the medical sector.

The high costs of American healthcare are terrible for most involved, and there are likely many ways it could be improved without switching to single payer. 

My view is that a large factor is that most of our investment in healthcare comes from investors seeking to profit from those high costs, and that if USA switched to single payer then much of that investment would disappear (and from there fewer would want to enter the field etc)

I do think we could switch to a socialized system and give most/all citizens the best care currently available- but that research on the cure for cancer, Alzheimer’s etc would see much of their investment dry up and we wouldn’t see a solution there for much longer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254419549.0" user="TBOIOMATb_CYKA" delta="False">
    <text>What you're saying assumes that the margins of those high costs are being channeled efficiently to investors.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254430522.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>I am assuming that based on all the investors who choose to put their money there, yes</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
