<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="496153887.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/87easf/cmv_most_modern_medical_advances_have_come_from/">
    <title>CMV most modern medical advances have come from companies looking to profit in the American medical system, and if America were to switch to a European style system then progress would slow worldwide</title>
    <original_poster>Extratydoncbicbslleb</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this without a ton of knowledge about the recent history of medical advances, but it seems to me that most modern medical companies don’t see much money to be made in socialist systems. While they will take the profits they can get there, if America were to switch as well medical advancement would stall (with the advantage that the current top quality of care would be widely available)

I am fully aware that there are numerous inefficiencies in our healthcare system unrelated to capitalist/socialist systems but that isn’t the subject here


Thanks </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30253723993.0" user="BeansforHomerclese" delta="False">
    <text>The prices are still extremely good for the purposes of return on investment in countries with universal healthcare. 

Sure, you make 500% ROI when you sell a product or drug in America, but you still make 250% ROI when you sell it in Australia, Canada or France.

Your idea is that medical developments will stop if America switched, but other countries still pay for their healthcare services and they still pay a lot of money for them. 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253836145.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>If true great! I’m looking for examples or evidence though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253922631.0" user="BeansforHomerclese" delta="False">
    <text>Well the evidence would be in the profit margins of any company, American or otherwise, that sells pharmaceuticals or medical technologies abroad. 

Go look at any public companies financial statements, look at their international profits, if their return on investment is anything higher than say 20% (which, I guarantee you, as someone who works in the medical industry, it is), then you can safely assume that medical advances will continue at the same rate that it currently improves, because the return on investment will still be worth development. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
