<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="496153887.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/87easf/cmv_most_modern_medical_advances_have_come_from/">
    <title>CMV most modern medical advances have come from companies looking to profit in the American medical system, and if America were to switch to a European style system then progress would slow worldwide</title>
    <original_poster>Extratydoncbicbslleb</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this without a ton of knowledge about the recent history of medical advances, but it seems to me that most modern medical companies don’t see much money to be made in socialist systems. While they will take the profits they can get there, if America were to switch as well medical advancement would stall (with the advantage that the current top quality of care would be widely available)

I am fully aware that there are numerous inefficiencies in our healthcare system unrelated to capitalist/socialist systems but that isn’t the subject here


Thanks </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30253850310.0" user="mutatron" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; socialist systems

There aren't really any large socialist healthcare systems.

Of the [top ten world pharmaceutical companies](http://www.bbc.com/news/business-28212223), five are US-based and spend about $30 billion on R&amp;amp;D, while the five non-US-based companies spend $35 billion on R&amp;amp;D. 

Total US spending is about 47% of global spending. For [Novartis](https://www.novartis.com/sites/www.novartis.com/files/novartis-annual-report-2017-en.pdf), a Swiss company, the US market is 34% of their total revenues.

If US spending per capita were reduced to [Swiss levels](https://www.healthsystemtracker.org/chart-collection/health-spending-u-s-compare-countries/#item-relative-size-wealth-u-s-spends-disproportionate-amount-health), about 75% of current levels, US spending would drop to about 40% of global, and Novartis' US revenues might drop to about 30% of their total, so their total revenues might drop by about 8%.

[Sanofi's](https://www.sanofi.com/en/investors/financial-results-and-events/financial-results/Q4-results-2016/) documentation is not in a nice PDF presentation, but about 36% of their sales are to the US market.

I expect it's probably the same for the other non-US companies in the top ten of pharmaceuticals. For Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, US sales are about 52% of total, so a drop in US spending of 25% might cause a ~13% drop in revenues.

A drop in revenues of 8-13% is significant, but clearly the global market is large and rising, and the US share of that will be falling as less developed countries continue to rise out of poverty.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253939850.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not quite convinced yet, but of all the replies this is the closest I’ve gotten. Thanks for the sources and hard numbers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
