<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284315751.0" user="PandaDerZwote" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on your idea of "Love" and "First sight".  

If you define it in the strictest way possible, full blown love from the first moment you saw that person, than no, it probably doesn't exist or is very very rare.  
Most people don't refer to it that way though, but see it as sensing chemistry with another person very early on.  

That doesn't mean that you can know that a person is perfect for you and that you can know that person in and out from a glance, but that you can sense that you will be communicating greatly and will enjoy each others company. If you look at it like this, it makes a lot of sense, as everyone has things and people he or she will just "know" they will have great chemistry with.  
Doesn't matter if that will turn out to be true, but that isn't really implied anywhere.  

As always, phrases like this are useless when you take them at face value, you should rather look at what people actually try to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284397472.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>Well I mean if you define "love" as "saw the potential for a real relationship" and "first sight" as "after three or four dates", sure. But most people don't hear "I saw the potential for a real relationship after three or four dates" and assume is means "love at first sight." By the traditional definitions of love and first sight I just don't see it. Anything else is stretching it to fit a new meaning</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285958549.0" user="david-song" delta="False">
    <text>Falling in love is the pair bonding process in humans, love at first sight is the falling for someone part happening almost immediately. I don't see the controversy myself, it's a continuous process, who's to say where the beginning is?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
