<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284364754.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30287006779.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ElysiX – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+ElysiX&amp;amp;message=ElysiX+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/dwuj1ea/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
