<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284367190.0" user="Schnitzel8" delta="False">
    <text>You know how your gut can immediately tell when you meet someone you don’t like? Even before the open their mouth or do anything of substance you just kinda know this person is not someone you’ll get along with. 

If you’ve ever experienced this then it’s not a huge leap to accept that a similar phenomenon may be happening but in the opposite direction. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284386110.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>But the same thing can be wrong. You can get a really good impression of someone and then they turn out to be a jerk. Or vice versa. Just because you got a good impression and maybe it even worked out doesn't necessarily mean that what you felt that first moment was any more than attraction or infatuation </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284395644.0" user="Schnitzel8" delta="False">
    <text>I assume this has never happened to you, then. It’s only happened to me a few times but I just *knew* something was off with this person and it was right. 

There’s no chance of it being wrong when the feeling is that strong. It is something happening unconsciously so I don’t even know how to explain it. When it happens to you you’ll know. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284418693.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>It has, as far as feeling something was off. Sometimes it turns out to be true, sometimes you never get any evidence and possibly you were totally wrong. Same with thinking someone is awesome right off the bat. Maybe your instinct is correct, maybe you were wrong. I'm just saying that having a feeling that someone is a person you could love and then working on it and making it happen is different from actually loving them immediately.
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Like if most people had that feeling really strongly, if they just KNEW the was The One For Them, and the person walked up to them and said "You're a shithead," their "love" would die instantly. Whereas many if not most truly in love couples could work through an incident of name calling fairly easily and quickly *because they know each other*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284574180.0" user="Roflcaust" delta="False">
    <text>Playing devil’s advocate, but do you remember the times that you met someone and your gut feeling at that meeting turned out to be wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284589217.0" user="Schnitzel8" delta="False">
    <text>Like I say it’s only happened a few times. Maybe not more than thrice but it’s a very strong feeling that turned out right in each case. It’s not just a bad vibe it’s quite a thing actually. 

I’m just saying maybe love at first sight is something like this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284859026.0" user="Roflcaust" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the “gut feeling” is a real thing, and maybe love at first site can relate to that.  I just wanted to point out an area where human memory can fall prey to sampling bias.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284605975.0" user="UncomfortableNews" delta="False">
    <text>This is called self-fulfilling prophecy. :) 

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-fulfilling_prophecy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284630233.0" user="Schnitzel8" delta="False">
    <text>Possibly. 

But it’s a pretty strong emotional reaction to basically zero data and im not the only one who ended up disliking said person. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30287579644.0" user="vehementi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There’s no chance of it being wrong when the feeling is that strong

&amp;gt; When it happens to you you’ll know.

I really want to turn this around on you with respect to people being abused or hurt or murdered or scammed or whatever by charismatic individuals they "just knew for sure were trustworthy"... :(</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284835523.0" user="OneRFeris" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can get a really good impression of someone and then they turn out to be a jerk

Whether or not someone makes the wrong judgment "at first sight", you are basically admitting here that this phenomenon does happen- so it shouldn't be impossible to accept that sometimes it's right, even if you believe most of the time its wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284998544.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>I think my issue is that there's a difference between thinking you're in love and actually being in love. A fifth grader may think they are deeply in love with their crush and swear to the heavens that nothing will ever be truer. But when they grow up, they'll likely meet someone, fall in actual love and realize what they experienced before was misinterpreted. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285327965.0" user="OneRFeris" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who has been in love multiple times over the years, I must say love is different each time you experience it. Of course the love a fifth grader is capable of is different from a fully developed adult. 

Who among us is so omniscient, they can judge the "love" someone feels? Love is not a emotion that can be scientifically defined. Therefor, I believe it is impossible for an outsider to pass judgment on the love someone else feels.

Perhaps "love at first sight" is nonexistent for you, because you personally define love differently (I'm the same way). But we cannot presume to force our definition of love on others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30286356372.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But the same thing can be wrong.

And, also, it can be right.

If someone were arguing that "first sight" is *always* a reliable indicator of "love", pretty much everyone would laugh at them.

This term is almost always used in retrospect, by or about someone that actually has concluded over time that they are truly in love, **and** that their initial gut feel assessment turned out to be correct after all.

And, surely, that does sometimes happen. 

No one thinks that "love at first sight" is reliable or common... it's generally considered to be the exception rather than the rule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285423410.0" user="jgranite125" delta="False">
    <text>This is the case for me with my gf. She is staggeringly beautiful and I literally felt stunned when I met her and we started talking. Never had that happened before. I'd say the love feeling developed partially out of that original experience. Not love at first sight, but probably the closest I can attest to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
