<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284422161.0" user="Purple-Brain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.

I guess it depends on your definition of love. For example, I've known parents who miscarried or had children that died at a very young age, and even years later they remain full of love for that child and still consider them to be one of their own. It seems to me that this love formed in spite the fact that the child had presumably not yet developed thoughts, feelings, and a personality of their own. Though the mother is connected to the child by carrying it and caring for it for such a long time, any perception of who that child is and who they would have grown up to be is practically 100% an idealization or hypothetical, so under your view, on what basis could a mother continue to love her child after an early death?

Similarly, I find it acceptable to occasionally characterize love as stemming foremost from a profound yearning to love someone, with an added bonus if they love you back, or at the very least consent to being loved by you. I have experienced this myself at first sight, at least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284432419.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  love formed in spite the fact that the child had presumably not yet developed thoughts, feelings, and a personality of their own. 

That says to me that the would-be mother is imagining a child she wished for and mourning the loss of those hopes and dreams. Very real feelings and very real pain to be sure. But you can't really compare having an open slot as a parent who would love absolutely any child who filled it, no matter who they turned out to be with having an open slot like that for lovers. If a person swore they would love the next person who walked through the door at a party the way a mother swears she would love an unborn child, they would be clearly insane. Romantic love isn't that automatic and since it isn't genetically bonded it's actually much more about choice and commitment that magical "you exist, therefore I love you," logic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284512607.0" user="Purple-Brain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That says to me that the would-be mother is imagining a child she wished for and mourning the loss of those hopes and dreams. Very real feelings and very real pain to be sure. But you can't really compare having an open slot as a parent who love absolutely any child who filled it, no matter who they turned out to be with having an open slot like that for lovers.

Well, again, you'd have to specify or otherwise tighten your definition of love. Seems to me that "love at first sight" is possible for mothers. But I am now getting the sense that you are specifically referring to the love that exists between romantic partners.

At the same time, I don't necessarily see why one would agree that a mother who spiritually yearns for a child whom she has idealized a potential relationship with is accurately described as loving that child, and yet reject the idea that this same phenomenon could happen between two potential romantic partners. It seems to me that someone could see someone else and immediately recognize some shared quality or character about them that launches them into an immediate yearning for a relationship with them. Both scenarios are built on idealization and are stimulated by the mind, and in the case of romance, in which partners to a certain extent end up seeing each other as extensions of the other (e.g. feeling proud of their accomplishments, feeling embarrassed if they are rude in public, etc.), you can easily build up someone in your head by simply projecting onto them what you unconsciously want in yourself. Sure, you aren't (yet) loving them for who they *are*, but it seems to me that, insofar as enduring and stable love is often characterized as being a choice (as opposed to a response to one's hormones or lust), the stable love you are describing here could only really exist if it is constructed and then repeatedly fueled by the person, all wholly within their mind, with any outside shared experiences with that person only fueling the mental conception, but *not solely providing the basis for it.*

To that end, on what basis can we assert that so-and-so truly loves such-and-such on the basis of their mutually fun experiences and complementary personalities, most of which the enjoyment is derived by the mental redesigning of the event or person in a romantic light (otherwise we'd fall in romantic love with anyone we enjoyed spending time with), and yet deny so-and-so was capable of loving such-and-such on the basis of a similarly-constructed perception of that person that preexisted the actual occurrence of their relationship?

And furthermore, if you are postulating that being "genetically linked" provides a reasonable basis for loving someone at first sight, who is to say that the feeling of recognizing the potential for a relationship in other [is not genetically linked in its own right](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green-beard_effect)?

Edited to add the italicized text.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284532069.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>I think the reason why that yearning and then loving works for mothers but not for partners is that babies have nearly no personality for a year. They don't talk, they don't argue, they don't act aloof. They just need you in a way even simpler than a pet. If babies came out fully formed and mothers met them as adults, I don't think that genetics would even be enough to justify instant love for a large percentage of them. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

I, for instance, am adopted. Met my biological mother. Had nothing in common with her. She didn't love me, I didn't love her. We spoke for a while and lost touch. Loving someone before they have a personality and then being a part of their life as they grow into one (and *shaping* that personality as well) is demonstrably different from loving a fully formed adult human being without knowing them. As for the green beard effect, I don't think I would be any more likely to jump in front of a bus for my birth mom than any stranger, nor she for me. And actually, genetic *difference* is attractive and seeked out by partners (based on studies of scent and other traits), rather than genetic similarity, so genetic connection  isn't at all a factor in romantic love.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284621145.0" user="Purple-Brain" delta="False">
    <text>But during that time, the mother, who presumably loves her child upon its conception, needs to feel something that ignites and continuously fuels that feeling of love for the child. Given that the child doesn't yet have a personality, she isn't loving them for who they are, so what aspect of the child is she loving? In other words, from what source is this love being drawn?

You said it very well yourself when you pointed out that genetics doesn't seem to be enough to justify that instant love. I am not a mother yet, but in my view, it seems that loving a newborn child as a mother is very much a mental thing, or at least not a purely genetic thing. Otherwise, mothers around the world would likely be more consistent with the feelings they hold for their children, and the love for her child would likely occur more or less outside of one's internal jurisdiction, much like all men and women are forced to go through puberty. So if a mother is loving her child, it seems that she is loving any number of things that surround her role as a mother: the idea of having a child and creating life, the recognition of her own romantic partner (usually the husband) in the child, hypotheticals regarding who the child will grow up to be that are extrapolated from the child's limited temperament, the personal growth she is experiencing as a mother, the idea itself of being a mother, etc. I'm sure there are a number of factors that come into play. The idea here is that many of these things are comparatively one-sided and centered around the mother's perception of her role in the whole child-rearing affair. Once the child grows up, she could see the child's personality and character as further reasons to love them the way she always has been, but the child's personality and character don't completely replace the mother's old feelings of love as an altogether new foundation for loving the child, as one would expect to be the case if true love was based on intimately knowing a person.

By the same token, I see no reason why a person couldn't love an idea or projection of being the person's significant other before intimately knowing the person themselves. Love is enjoyable for reasons besides reciprocation and/or experience. You can feel centered, inspired, deeply moved, and oriented toward the world and your place in it, all by feeling confident in your love for a person. Experiences like these are what compel many people to turn toward God, spirituality, and nature. It isn't the ability to know intimately know the workings of these things that continuously fuels a person's love towards these things. Rather, it is has more to do with how compelling it is to feel limitless access to someone or something that they can aim love towards, and in the process gain perspective, decisiveness, and peace of mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284698977.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>Well I agree that genetics don't justify the love for a child. I think evolution does. Most of us have a natural instinct to protect and nurture any infant in need. That is part of how we survived as a species. On the other hand, evolution had a very specific reason for not giving us an instinct to instantly love someone without knowing their traits: so we could pick good partners suited to help us create and raise children, and whom we would be able to tolerate over time to help protect them. So, I suppose that you could argue that in a sense "love at first sight" exist as a genetic anomaly and those who suffer from it are similar to people with hereditary diseases making it difficult for them to bear children. In a biological sense, those people would have to be seen as defective or ill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284719596.0" user="Purple-Brain" delta="False">
    <text>My point isn’t the genetics aspect of it though. Do you have thoughts on the main parts of my view? My apologies if I’ve been too wordy with it. I’m ultimately trying to show how love at first sight isn’t necessarily unreasonable, because much of what we call love is simply how we’ve structured our minds to perceive another individual and our experience with them. This includes our perception of the other person’s personality, thoughts, and emotions (and how we reinterpret them in our own heads, which sometimes ends up looking very different from what they actually are).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284763189.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>Ultimately I think it boils down to this. When we were less evolved, yes we could go "oog. Pretty mate. Grooms good." And then basically get along. Now? We have thoughts that get us into love because otherwise our own thoughts "she doesn't listen anymore when I talk to her and I want her to take an interest in my hobbies..." will kill it before it gets to the level of real trust and commitment. Essentially we're too evolved to be calling lust and biological urges "love" in the same breath as calling commitment and understand and perseverance "love". I do appreciate your point of view, though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284835743.0" user="Purple-Brain" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but I still feel like I’m not doing a good job of getting my point across, because I can’t help but feel like you’re just restating your original view instead of responding to what I said in mine. I’ll be more direct: do you agree or disagree that you can love someone based on an idea of who they are (regardless of actual experience with that person)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284992145.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree because I think someone who believes they love a celebrity they've never met is not talking about *love* in the real sense but someone who loves their spouse is. It's not supposed to be the idea you love, it's supposed to be the person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285434060.0" user="Purple-Brain" delta="False">
    <text>Well, love for a celebrity is different from love for a romantic partner. Celebrities pretty much exist to receive admiration and make more money from that admiration.

What about going into the store to buy a puppy, sifting through the options for a bit, and ultimately seeing a cute little puppy that you immediately know is the one? Do you not truly love the puppy yet?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
