<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284829557.0" user="squidblankets" delta="False">
    <text>Sight plays only a partial role in love at first sight, just as it does in setting a basis for love that develops over time by establishing a mutual attraction.  My wife and I fell in love 16 years ago the moment we met.  We were in two separate groups of friends that ended up hanging out one evening, she was beautiful (sight) and made a joke that I just died laughing at (something else that told me immediately what kind of person I was dealing with) and knew immediately that I was going to marry this person one day.  That was all it took.  The amount of time that passed from when I physically saw her to when I realized my life would be different from that day on was at most 10 seconds.  Our first kid is on the way, and this remains the most profound moment of my life.  I'm not saying it's common, but it is real.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285010387.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>It just always seemed to me that people look back through love goggles and attribute a "knowing" that it was for life only when things worked out. I'm guessing if she'd blown you off she would blend in with other women you had a massive attraction to, but maybe I'm mistaken in that
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30286061450.0" user="squidblankets" delta="False">
    <text>But so what if it doesn't work out?  One can have that undeniable mutual experience and have a love that lasts only a decade. Or less. That initial experience still happened. Who says love is permanent?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
