<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30285064109.0" user="dbarj34" delta="False">
    <text>It's possible. Its not that you know it's specifically love, but it's something very special, something you've never felt up to that point.  Everything gets blurry other than her, everything goes quiet. Your heart pounds and you're in awe. She looks like a angel.  And you know that it's going to be a special relationship that last a while. Obviously love at first sight doesn't always mean perfect soul mates. Just my experience </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285081805.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>That's a chemical soup of dopamine being pumped into your brain. Doesn't mean it's *not* love per se, but that feeling doesn't last forever. Your wife of 30 years doesn't make things blurry or make your heart pound
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285089503.0" user="dbarj34" delta="False">
    <text>No of course it doesn't last nothing does </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285091522.0" user="dbarj34" delta="False">
    <text>Not to the same degree anyways </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
