<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284786814.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>I hate to be a hopeless romantic - but some people are just incredibly shallow. 

You argue that "real love, deep love requires that you know all parts of a person". 

Not everyone has that or wants that. For some people, Love is only skin deep. Some people only love $. Some people only love beauty. 

If your ideal Spouse is someone who is 1) Hot and 2) Willing to Fuck You and 3) Nothing else, a literal empty void personality-wise - then Love at first sight is obviously possible. 

I think your definition of Love is too strict and too personal. It is a very romantic version of the concept. For many, Love is simply - I find your nakedness tolerable and you have a job. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284797501.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like your argument boils down to "Some people *are* still unevolved enough to think 'oog. she's pretty. has moola." and that works because they're too stupid to evaluate further?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284831923.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't necessarily call these people stupid, but they do have a very different set of priorities than you. 

Some people are very cold, very detached, and don't want to bond emotionally. Some people highly value their independence and don't want to be overly shackled to another person. Some people value their social standing above their interpersonal relationships. 

There are reasons beyond "being unevolved" which might cause someone to only look skin deep when looking for love. 

If you constantly travel for work, and plan on seeing your spouse for only 1 hour a week, picking a "good lay" is not the worst plan, since their personality basically doesn't matter since you won't be spending much if any time with them. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
