<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="500473248.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/89yvmo/cmv_there_is_no_such_thing_as_love_at_first_sight/">
    <title>CMV: There is no such thing as "love at first sight"</title>
    <original_poster>BerryBrickle</original_poster>
    <original_post>So-called love at first sight is based on just that - sight. 
&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now I know some people are going to jump in with anecdotes about grandparents who married after three dates and were together for 70 years and whatnot. But that is a form of commitment and usually (in older people) a response to a society that did not really allow for divorce. Can two people make it work if they fall in love based on sight and quickly marry? Sure, sometimes. But that doesn't mean that real love, deep love like you have when you know all parts of a person can form immediately upon seeing them. You can't truly love someone without knowing about their personality, their thoughts and their feelings.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30284333085.0" user="teerre" delta="False">
    <text>Don't you think that if someone who is in love comes and says to you they fell in love at first sight is, at minimum, extremely presumptuous of you, someone who can have no idea how they feel, to question it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284391419.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>If someone came to me, for instance and said "I am in love with you," and I'd never met them, I'd absolutely question it. Like, what if I'm a serial killer and I killed their mother or something. *Anything* could be true about me but they claim to feel love. Love is something that is deep and is unique to the person you feel it towards. You can't love the unique person that is me without knowing me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284866522.0" user="Inelukie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can't love the unique person that is me without knowing me.

Why though? You say that in an axiomatic way without giving any reason for it. (There are people that do love the murderer of their mother btw.)

People hate spiders on an instinctual level. Even if that particular spider is not dangerous or problematic. They see a spider and go "waaahhh I hate spiders!". That is the reaction that can happen, just the other way around.

I actually had that "Love at first sight" moment myself. I walked into a room, looked at that girl and my heart skipped a beat. My mind only said "Wow!" and that's it.

I still remember that moment like few others in my life. I still feel like I love her, even though nothing ever happened between us and it happened 10 years ago. I got to know her better and the feeling got more nuanced, yet the initial reaction, the core of that feeling stayed exactly the same. Our friendship went down the drain in a not-so-good way, yet that appreciation and feeling has not changed at all. From the day I've met her to the day I die, that person was special to me for essentially no reason at all. I just feel that way for her. 

I've met hundreds, if not thousands of women (traveling around the world and so on) since then and nobody created a reaction that is even close to that one. She was my special someone and I'm pretty sure I'm not going to find any women that will ever get close to what I've felt for that random encounter. And it wasn't because she did something. It was just there. It clicked and never un-clicked. More and stronger than I've ever had with any other living being in this world.

It's just the way it is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284979759.0" user="caine269" delta="False">
    <text>Love at first sight is just lust. You get that feeling because you find the girl physically attractive. You know literally nothing else about her, so what else can you be reacting to?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285143480.0" user="Inelukie" delta="False">
    <text>Asking for a rational explanation for a feeling is absurd, sorry. That's like asking why your dick goes hard for a very specific fetish. It's just the way it is.

Lust feels very much different from "Omg, I want to marry this girl because my heart goes butterflies every time I think about her". I didn't even think about sleeping with her. At all. Which probably was the reason nothing ever came out of this. I was so overwhelmed by that emotion that I stopped functioning like a normal person. I just ...stared at her, unable to comprehend what is happening with me.

I knew nothing about her and still would have followed her to the end of the world without asking why. Can't explain it. Still would do it 10 years later if I could turn back time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285601977.0" user="SDK1176" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't much matter what you're reacting to. We classify emotions based on how they feel for the person having them, not by what caused them. I've personally fallen for two people in my life, the moment I met them. One went on to become a very good friend. The other is my wife. Love at first sight may be different from "true love", whatever that is to you, but *it feels pretty damn similar*. What it does NOT feel like is lust.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30284994060.0" user="teerre" delta="False">
    <text>That's not the situation I'm posing. I'm saying a couple comes to you and say they fell in love at first sight. Who are you to say otherwise? Even in your example, who are you to decide how the other person feels? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285047518.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure if you are the person I said this to before but: I think there is a difference between being in love and thinking you're in love. A 5th grader can be in love with her crush and swear it's true love. Later she will learn that she was incorrect. I'm not going to tell someone they're an idiot or anything but I am entitled to my opinion and I privately hold that someone who believes they are instantly in love with a stranger is mistaking infatuation and emotional overload for love.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285058127.0" user="teerre" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, but that's exactly the crux of the argument here. *You* have that **opinion**. Emphasis important. Other people have other opinions and, in this specific situation, it's impossible to check either way

At best, what you can reasonably say is that *you* will never fell in love at first sight 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285073947.0" user="BerryBrickle" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I suppose so. It's like people who claim they remember their own birth. I don't think that's possible because I don't think that's how the brain works. I think the very claim is crazy. But people can go ahead and claim it. Now if you showed me some new brain scans on newborns showing that they were capable of forming long term memory, I'd reevaluate my belief. I can't think of an equivalent in this case other than evidence that the brain of new love is similar to the brain of drug addiction, whereas the brain of mature love is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30285737535.0" user="thekrogg" delta="False">
    <text>I think the important issue here seems to be how (and by what metric) we define love. In your post you seemed to argue that love can only exist when you know everything about a person. (which I also think is not true, but that's a separate issue) Here though, you seem to be looking at love from a neurological perspective, as well as introducing the terms "new love" vs. "mature love". So what is your view? Are there certain levels of oxytocin and dopamine that you believe qualify as real love, and you believe that people who are in a long term relationship have higher levels of those neurotransmitters? Or are you arguing the philosophical point, that love exists out of respect and understanding of a person, which is impossible when you've just met someone? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
