<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503104193.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bj9oh/cmv_having_children_should_not_be_a_fundamental/">
    <title>CMV: Having Children Should not be a Fundamental Human Right</title>
    <original_poster>BioTheRaider</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've come across this interesting concept in some personal conversations, and I find myself continuously returning to it and thinking, "Huh, that might be something."

My view is that people should not be entitled to having children; that is people shouldn't automatically have the right to birth and raise a child. 

A quick disclaimer before the argument: I do not believe this is a view that can be effectively legislated for, and I am not advocating for any program to enable this. I am posing a more philosophical and ethical argument. I fully understand the dangers of giving a group of people the power to artificially select those who can and can't have children, and I don't pose to be any kind of expert in any area related to such things. I will not discuss selection processes, nor preventative processes, except in the broadest of possible senses.

Now, my points. It is immoral to force a conscious entity into existence. I think this is a principle many people feel in situations outside of human children. For example, I have asked several people a question along the lines of "Is it moral to, assuming they are conscious, farm instantiations of artificial intelligence?" Let's take this to a large real-world scale, and say we have a thousand servers each storing a thousand AI, and these AI are sufficiently intelligent that, while it is unknowable, there is a possibility that the AI are conscious entities. Imagine that a company is trying to create a specialized AI for some problem they're trying to solve, and so they set their servers to work evolutionarily testing the AI until they produce one which solves the problem sufficiently. In essence, a million possibly conscious entities are being evaluated on their ability to solve a problem, and then discarded for a newer, better generation of a million AI. These servers are creating and destroying millions of instantiations of an AI which is possibly conscious in some way. Is this morally acceptable? I think not. These entities are being forced into existence and, to a first degree approximation, somewhat arbitrarily destroyed. I think that is something equivalent to a digital Holocaust, and I am not using that phrase lightly. Were those AI human brains, there is no doubt that we would find some practice of subjecting humans to a similar process to be hugely immoral. The principle here is that we are, essentially, exerting control over the life and death of a conscious entity. We don't find slavery or murder acceptable, so why would this be?

We can take this principle and apply it to human babies. By having a child, you are creating a conscious entity; you've taken control of its life. 

I am aware that we have children in order to continue the species, we are biologically designed to have children. But just because it's the natural course of things does not make it moral. I'm not of the inclination that the perpetuation of the species is an inherently good goal.

Human life is frought with suffering and hardship. It is, until we somehow become all-powerful, unavoidable. Every new human life also means new suffering. We find that inflicting suffering upon someone is immoral, and even allowing someone to suffer is widely considered immoral. Why would it be alright to enable suffering through the creation of the capacity for suffering as having a child does? Why is it okay to force people to live? If someone is already alive, then of course we should allow them agency over their body and life, and provide alleviation of suffering, but why should we be allowed to force something into a position where it must encounter suffering?What right does anyone have to do this?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30305822461.0" user="zekfen" delta="False">
    <text>Is it immoral to let animals breed? Should we stop wolves from breeding because the wolf pups will have a life fraught with hardships and struggles? Should we stop geese from lay eggs and have chicks because they might be eaten by a predator?

Animals breeding and procreating is a natural thing, to not do so would be to go against the laws of nature. In the end, humans are animals, and as with all animals, they have a natural desire to breed. Do some people make bad parents? Absolutely! But so do some animals who lay eggs/birth and abandon their young. But that doesn’t invalidate the laws of nature. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305977891.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>The laws of nature are not moral arguments. What is and isn't natural isn't a good definition of morality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306107456.0" user="zekfen" delta="False">
    <text>Nature is neither good nor bad, thus nature holds the moral high ground. The laws of nature are what created you and has allowed to to live.  Weather you view that as good or bad is up to you, but you can’t make an argument that nature is immoral. Nature is life, and just because life is rough doesn’t make it immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
