<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503104193.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bj9oh/cmv_having_children_should_not_be_a_fundamental/">
    <title>CMV: Having Children Should not be a Fundamental Human Right</title>
    <original_poster>BioTheRaider</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've come across this interesting concept in some personal conversations, and I find myself continuously returning to it and thinking, "Huh, that might be something."

My view is that people should not be entitled to having children; that is people shouldn't automatically have the right to birth and raise a child. 

A quick disclaimer before the argument: I do not believe this is a view that can be effectively legislated for, and I am not advocating for any program to enable this. I am posing a more philosophical and ethical argument. I fully understand the dangers of giving a group of people the power to artificially select those who can and can't have children, and I don't pose to be any kind of expert in any area related to such things. I will not discuss selection processes, nor preventative processes, except in the broadest of possible senses.

Now, my points. It is immoral to force a conscious entity into existence. I think this is a principle many people feel in situations outside of human children. For example, I have asked several people a question along the lines of "Is it moral to, assuming they are conscious, farm instantiations of artificial intelligence?" Let's take this to a large real-world scale, and say we have a thousand servers each storing a thousand AI, and these AI are sufficiently intelligent that, while it is unknowable, there is a possibility that the AI are conscious entities. Imagine that a company is trying to create a specialized AI for some problem they're trying to solve, and so they set their servers to work evolutionarily testing the AI until they produce one which solves the problem sufficiently. In essence, a million possibly conscious entities are being evaluated on their ability to solve a problem, and then discarded for a newer, better generation of a million AI. These servers are creating and destroying millions of instantiations of an AI which is possibly conscious in some way. Is this morally acceptable? I think not. These entities are being forced into existence and, to a first degree approximation, somewhat arbitrarily destroyed. I think that is something equivalent to a digital Holocaust, and I am not using that phrase lightly. Were those AI human brains, there is no doubt that we would find some practice of subjecting humans to a similar process to be hugely immoral. The principle here is that we are, essentially, exerting control over the life and death of a conscious entity. We don't find slavery or murder acceptable, so why would this be?

We can take this principle and apply it to human babies. By having a child, you are creating a conscious entity; you've taken control of its life. 

I am aware that we have children in order to continue the species, we are biologically designed to have children. But just because it's the natural course of things does not make it moral. I'm not of the inclination that the perpetuation of the species is an inherently good goal.

Human life is frought with suffering and hardship. It is, until we somehow become all-powerful, unavoidable. Every new human life also means new suffering. We find that inflicting suffering upon someone is immoral, and even allowing someone to suffer is widely considered immoral. Why would it be alright to enable suffering through the creation of the capacity for suffering as having a child does? Why is it okay to force people to live? If someone is already alive, then of course we should allow them agency over their body and life, and provide alleviation of suffering, but why should we be allowed to force something into a position where it must encounter suffering?What right does anyone have to do this?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30305515854.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Your entire premise rests on the idea that existence is a net negative, that suffering outweighs whatever good that life can provide.  If it were the other way around, then surely one would say that we have a moral DUTY to bring as many people as possible into this great existence, and to DEPRIVE a life of existing is to take something away from them. 

Every new human life means some degree of suffering, but it also means some degree of enjoyment.  Your position only holds if the bad outweighs the good, and I don't believe that it does.  And I would argue that NO ONE ALIVE believes that it does, otherwise we'd all logically be killing ourselves.  Clearly every time you wake up in the morning, you have made the conscious decision that, despite that suffering, today is worth being around for.  Ergo, there is some amount of positivity in your life that is outweighing all of that suffering, or you'd just end it all today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305573878.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think this is a case where the reverse holds true. If everyone was always having children then there would be a lot of dead mothers (unless I'm wrong in assuming the great amount of stress would, as it has in the past, kill many people) and suffering on account of childbirth, but even if this weren't the case then you have a moral obligation to give each child food, water, shelter, clothing, etc.. In this situation resources would run thin and suddenly you have a situation that would rival the most impoverished of people at best, and thus there would be immense suffering. 

I don't necessarily agree that people are still alive because the good outweighs the bad. Having dealt very personally with suicide and suicidal ideation, I know well that such reasoning is a common general reason. However, I think most people's brains are capable of tricking them out of or simply throwing that reasoning away. It makes sense evolutionarily; someone who would kill themselves would be unlikely to pass their genes on, and one could easily see how brains would evolve "protections" of sorts against suicide.

 I'm not even stating that the bad in life outweighs the good, but that causing suffering is immoral, and by bringing a conscious entity capable of suffering into the world you have implicitly caused all potential suffering that entity endures. Of course, this chain of reasoning can go all the way back to the beginning of life, but I don't see that as making the argument invalid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305584472.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, I think most people's brains are capable of tricking them out of or simply throwing that reasoning away.

Well, that's just it.  You aren't necessarily **conscious** of the "math" that goes into determining that balance, but it's still happening.  For whatever reasons, your brain is deciding each day that life is worth living.  Just because you can't spell out all the pros and cons, and just because you didn't make the **conscious** decision, doesn't mean that your brain didn't work it out.  And this isn't without other examples.  Your brain constantly makes conclusions that you can't replicate on paper.  

When you reach out to catch a ball, it's because your brain just did a massive third-order physics problem in a split second to determine where that ball would be.  You couldn't ever explain it, and you couldn't do it on paper without a math degree, but your brain does it all the time.

Same thing here.  Your brain "tricking" you isn't tricking you at all.  It's just making decisions that you don't know it's making. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305614410.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>I will grant that as true, that the brain is constantly doing lots of processing without our conscious awareness, but you're assuming that the brain is making these decisions and carrying out these calculations perfectly. Brains are not perfect computation machines. They get a lot of stuff right, especially in areas like catching a ball, but we know they don't deal with more abstract concepts very well. Even with something like statistics, which because we live in a probabilistic universe one would expect brains to do quite well with, we can show that brains just do not carry out these processes with anywhere near 100% accuracy or even precision. If I remember correctly from Daniel Kahneman's book, people solve these "intuitive" problems at something like 30-40% accuracy. Brains only need to be good enough to get the *species* through, but that doesn't make them good enough to do most rigorous processes without a lot of effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305622098.0" user="scottevil110" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that's where my analogy sort of stops working, because where the ball is going to land is an objective truth.  Your brain can be "wrong" about that.  But in the case of life, we're talking about a subjective value conclusion.  It doesn't have a right or wrong answer.  It's coming to a subjective conclusion based on what it knows, and it's telling you that your life is worth living today.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305955678.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed, however I think that the brain may have evolved to come to that subjective conclusion because the alternative wouldn't produce offspring. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
