<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503104193.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bj9oh/cmv_having_children_should_not_be_a_fundamental/">
    <title>CMV: Having Children Should not be a Fundamental Human Right</title>
    <original_poster>BioTheRaider</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've come across this interesting concept in some personal conversations, and I find myself continuously returning to it and thinking, "Huh, that might be something."

My view is that people should not be entitled to having children; that is people shouldn't automatically have the right to birth and raise a child. 

A quick disclaimer before the argument: I do not believe this is a view that can be effectively legislated for, and I am not advocating for any program to enable this. I am posing a more philosophical and ethical argument. I fully understand the dangers of giving a group of people the power to artificially select those who can and can't have children, and I don't pose to be any kind of expert in any area related to such things. I will not discuss selection processes, nor preventative processes, except in the broadest of possible senses.

Now, my points. It is immoral to force a conscious entity into existence. I think this is a principle many people feel in situations outside of human children. For example, I have asked several people a question along the lines of "Is it moral to, assuming they are conscious, farm instantiations of artificial intelligence?" Let's take this to a large real-world scale, and say we have a thousand servers each storing a thousand AI, and these AI are sufficiently intelligent that, while it is unknowable, there is a possibility that the AI are conscious entities. Imagine that a company is trying to create a specialized AI for some problem they're trying to solve, and so they set their servers to work evolutionarily testing the AI until they produce one which solves the problem sufficiently. In essence, a million possibly conscious entities are being evaluated on their ability to solve a problem, and then discarded for a newer, better generation of a million AI. These servers are creating and destroying millions of instantiations of an AI which is possibly conscious in some way. Is this morally acceptable? I think not. These entities are being forced into existence and, to a first degree approximation, somewhat arbitrarily destroyed. I think that is something equivalent to a digital Holocaust, and I am not using that phrase lightly. Were those AI human brains, there is no doubt that we would find some practice of subjecting humans to a similar process to be hugely immoral. The principle here is that we are, essentially, exerting control over the life and death of a conscious entity. We don't find slavery or murder acceptable, so why would this be?

We can take this principle and apply it to human babies. By having a child, you are creating a conscious entity; you've taken control of its life. 

I am aware that we have children in order to continue the species, we are biologically designed to have children. But just because it's the natural course of things does not make it moral. I'm not of the inclination that the perpetuation of the species is an inherently good goal.

Human life is frought with suffering and hardship. It is, until we somehow become all-powerful, unavoidable. Every new human life also means new suffering. We find that inflicting suffering upon someone is immoral, and even allowing someone to suffer is widely considered immoral. Why would it be alright to enable suffering through the creation of the capacity for suffering as having a child does? Why is it okay to force people to live? If someone is already alive, then of course we should allow them agency over their body and life, and provide alleviation of suffering, but why should we be allowed to force something into a position where it must encounter suffering?What right does anyone have to do this?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30305603657.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I'll avoid the debate about suffering and whether life itself is a condition that should be avoided or not and focus on your title point.

&amp;gt;  that is people shouldn't automatically have the right to birth and raise a child.

It is, though. We naturally develop the ability to bear children. Taking this away would in fact be depriving people of an ability they naturally develop. That is more or less the definition of a human right. It is up to the individual whether or not to exercise that ability. If you want to discourage people from having children, that is one thing, but taking away that ability by force is the most authoritarian thing I can imagine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305688658.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  We naturally develop the ability to bear children. Taking this away would in fact be depriving people of an ability they naturally develop. That is more or less the definition of a human right. It is up to the individual whether or not to exercise that ability.

We have naturally developed the ability to kill other people, yet I don't see that as a human right. Whether or not a thing is natural does not factor into whether or not it is *moral*. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305708398.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Murder is not integral to the survival of the human race. In fact it serves the exact opposite purpose of giving birth. Birthing and raising children is literally the only thing keeping us going.

I understand being pessimistic, or someone not wanting to live, but taking the jump from pessimism to complete extinction of the human race because of the *possibility* that children might grow up to be depressed is a huge leap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305989130.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I did state that I don't believe the perpetuation of the human race is an inherently good thing. I also didn't state that it was bad, simply that it isn't inherently good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306091614.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>That's not up for you to decide, though. There has been enough effort to protect human life that we can assume perpetuating human life on earth is good and worthy of being protected.

If you're making the claim "it is immoral to force a human into existence" the other side of that coin is "it is moral to release a human from their existence." This is a huge can of worms you're opening with this claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306271455.0" user="descuidadojose" delta="False">
    <text>I like your argument, but I would posit to you the question of, what if artificial gestation of humans becomes just as costly/timeconsuming as natural brith in the future? It is not then in any sense necessary to procreate to further the human race. So in what way is this still a human right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306451821.0" user="MyUsernameIsJudge" delta="False">
    <text>"a right that is believed to belong justifiably to every person."

Even with alternatives, people would still be allowed to have children if they choose. Maybe they just want the experience of giving birth, maybe they want to do it "the natural way," maybe they want the attention of being pregnant, or the connection that comes from carrying a child. It's not up to us to deny anyone of that right.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
