<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503104193.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bj9oh/cmv_having_children_should_not_be_a_fundamental/">
    <title>CMV: Having Children Should not be a Fundamental Human Right</title>
    <original_poster>BioTheRaider</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've come across this interesting concept in some personal conversations, and I find myself continuously returning to it and thinking, "Huh, that might be something."

My view is that people should not be entitled to having children; that is people shouldn't automatically have the right to birth and raise a child. 

A quick disclaimer before the argument: I do not believe this is a view that can be effectively legislated for, and I am not advocating for any program to enable this. I am posing a more philosophical and ethical argument. I fully understand the dangers of giving a group of people the power to artificially select those who can and can't have children, and I don't pose to be any kind of expert in any area related to such things. I will not discuss selection processes, nor preventative processes, except in the broadest of possible senses.

Now, my points. It is immoral to force a conscious entity into existence. I think this is a principle many people feel in situations outside of human children. For example, I have asked several people a question along the lines of "Is it moral to, assuming they are conscious, farm instantiations of artificial intelligence?" Let's take this to a large real-world scale, and say we have a thousand servers each storing a thousand AI, and these AI are sufficiently intelligent that, while it is unknowable, there is a possibility that the AI are conscious entities. Imagine that a company is trying to create a specialized AI for some problem they're trying to solve, and so they set their servers to work evolutionarily testing the AI until they produce one which solves the problem sufficiently. In essence, a million possibly conscious entities are being evaluated on their ability to solve a problem, and then discarded for a newer, better generation of a million AI. These servers are creating and destroying millions of instantiations of an AI which is possibly conscious in some way. Is this morally acceptable? I think not. These entities are being forced into existence and, to a first degree approximation, somewhat arbitrarily destroyed. I think that is something equivalent to a digital Holocaust, and I am not using that phrase lightly. Were those AI human brains, there is no doubt that we would find some practice of subjecting humans to a similar process to be hugely immoral. The principle here is that we are, essentially, exerting control over the life and death of a conscious entity. We don't find slavery or murder acceptable, so why would this be?

We can take this principle and apply it to human babies. By having a child, you are creating a conscious entity; you've taken control of its life. 

I am aware that we have children in order to continue the species, we are biologically designed to have children. But just because it's the natural course of things does not make it moral. I'm not of the inclination that the perpetuation of the species is an inherently good goal.

Human life is frought with suffering and hardship. It is, until we somehow become all-powerful, unavoidable. Every new human life also means new suffering. We find that inflicting suffering upon someone is immoral, and even allowing someone to suffer is widely considered immoral. Why would it be alright to enable suffering through the creation of the capacity for suffering as having a child does? Why is it okay to force people to live? If someone is already alive, then of course we should allow them agency over their body and life, and provide alleviation of suffering, but why should we be allowed to force something into a position where it must encounter suffering?What right does anyone have to do this?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30305716418.0" user="boundbythecurve" delta="False">
    <text>First, I'd like to say I really like your argument. There's a lot of great points here that I think that average person never considers, and they are all the worse for it. This kind of discussion should be something that every educated, informed people should consider in order to truly get at the roots of their own values.

We have a few base assumptions here. Many of which I imagine we'll have lots of overlap in agreement. But some I don't think we will. I'd like to go over them to see where you might find a reason to change your view.

**Base assumption #1: "rights" exist.**

We're stripping away to some core concepts here. So we need to be very clear on what is a right. Obviously this is not a right as guaranteed by any government as you excluded practical legislation as a goal of this discussion. You're obviously not arguing for any legal rights here, and I agree with that. I hate most forms of eugenics (I'm Jewish by blood (not practice), so my family has a history with it).

What is a right then? I would very much like to here how you outline what a "right" is, before I outline some of what I consider to be core concepts of "rights".

**Base assumption #2: morality exists.**

This one was kind of funny to me. For this statement:

&amp;gt;  It is immoral to force a conscious entity into existence

to be true, you're essentially declaring all of human existence as immoral. Sure, individuals might not take that immoral leap into parenthood, but the species as a whole must reproduce to exist. And to reproduce requires creating consciousnesses that previously didn't exist. We can't obtain consent from beings that don't exist yet.

And since morality only exists because we invented the concept, then you're basically condemning our existence to be perpetually immoral (that's the part I found funny. Not wrong, just funny, because we can't be immoral without existing, but we can't be moral by existing, according to your statement).

I don't think there's anything explicitly wrong about that, but it just seems like a rather useless distinction. It's like defining two colors and then saying "but there's only 1 color in existence". What was the point of defining both colors if only one exists? What's the point of defining our existence as immoral if we literally cannot escape that immorality of existence.

I also don't like absolutes. I think we like to define our world in absolutes, and since reality resists simplicity, those absolutes end up being really unhelpful and destructive. For example: All [this group of people] like [something]. It's rarely helpful and just makes the person saying it look dumb. (There's a great book that has been helping me see the world differently that I highly recommend called [Finite and Infinite Games](https://www.amazon.com/Finite-Infinite-Games-James-Carse/dp/1476731713). There's also a free pdf if you just google it.)

My point for bringing this up is that I think it would be better stated to say: All existance of conscious entities *start* immoral, as they could not consent to being created, but *can* become moral through the value of their existence.

I don't think all conscious beings are inherently immoral, at least not forever. I see your point that you can't consent to being born, but that doesn't mean you can't retroactively consent. This kind of consent cannot and should not exist in other moral choices (for example, rape cannot be retroactively given consent, nor can that consent be retroactively removed). But I think the unique nature of consciousness could allow for my interpretation. 

**Base assumption #3: the importance of naturally occurring forces on morality.**

This one gets people tripped up all the time, but I don't think you're entirely tripped up on it. The classic (shitty) argument involving the extreme side of things is the banana argument seen here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2z-OLG0KyR4

It's also known as [The Watchmaker Analogy](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watchmaker_analogy). It is where significance or importance is placed upon the natural state of something. People have misused this argument for their own ends in all sorts of arguments. This banana fits my hand, therefore it was *designed* to fit my hand, therefore God exists. 

We're, obviously, biologically designed to make babies. But does the fact that making babies is naturally occurring mean it's moral? You seem to have taken the side of a definitive "no". Most people would probably say "yes", also definitively.

Again, I hate absolutes. I think we can find *some* morality in baby making, and we can find *some* immorality. You've definitely hit upon the immorality of baby making very clearly, and again, I want to applaud you for that, because I think this should be a more common discussion. But I don't think this one aspect of reproduction (the lack of consent from the consciousness being created) completely overwhelms all of the other aspects of reproduction. Not all of human existence is suffering. All human existence *has* suffering (I mean, we literally come into this world crying from the pain of taking our first breath), but most of human existence has joy too (I won't say "all" because I'm sure there's plenty of singleton cases we could point out where the human's existence was essentially nothing but pain and suffering. Some diseases really suck.).

And I only point to the continued improvement of human comfort as a sign that humanity *can* find joy, and prefers it to suffering. The quality of most human lives has improved greatly over the last few hundred years. Plenty new types of suffering has occurred, but I don't think you'd find any sane person that would prefer to live before the industrial revolution.

We strive for a better life. For ourselves. Sometimes for others. But we've found value in living because we have a desire to live longer than before. And in greater numbers. I propose that our strive for improvement shows two things:

1. Suffering exists (because we're trying to escape it).

2. We're willing to put up with the suffering long enough to try to reduce it.

This, to me, is a non-explicit form of consent to existence. While I agree with you that we cannot consent before we exist, and to be brought into existence is inherently without our consent, I propose that the consent can be earned through use of our existence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30305958342.0" user="BioTheRaider" delta="False">
    <text>Ah! I love this response! A big, precursory thank you to you good sir!

&amp;gt; What is a right then?

Obviously this is very hard to define. I don't imagine that I will do a better job than the thousands of years' worth of philosophical pondering greater and more rigorous minds have done, but I'll give it a shot. I'm going to work backwards here, from what I believe *are* rights and what I believe *aren't*. 

First off, I would say that nobody should have the right to deprive other people the ability to exercise their rights. I almost want to append "without explicit consent," to this statement, but I'm not aware of the ramifications of such an action yet. 

I believe in few very broad rights. You make your own decisions and nobody can force you into doing something you don't want to do. This includes things like taking recreational substances, moving to another country, getting a tattoo, changing your mind about the color for a room, free speech, privacy, suicide, etc.. I'm very much of a "live and let live," kind of mind. Of course, this only goes so far until it interferes with other people's rights.

I would also like to list as rights, the right to personal privacy and the right to the agreed ownership of property. 

I don't think this is enough to form a definition of what "rights" are, so I'm just going to try to pull one from my head. A right is an axiom that can be used to define instances of moral or immoral behavior.

I'd like to take a moment to define morality as well, as we can't have an undefined concept in our definition of a right, that's simply unrigorous! I think this is also easier to define, at least from my perspective.

An action that is immoral is an action which increases the amount of negative experiences in the universe, and decreases the amount of positive experiences. An action which is moral will increase the amount of positive experiences in the universe and decrease the amount of negative experiences. 

Rest assured I'll come back to answer the rest of your post, which is wonderful to read by the way. I have to go to work here soon, so I'll be thinking hard about your points. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306238137.0" user="boundbythecurve" delta="False">
    <text>I'm glad you liked my response! I liked yours as well.

Just as an aside, I would not classify *all* forms of suicide as a "right". Specifically because people who *were* suicidal due to mental health, survived suicide attempts, and lived on to lead happier lives, and are generally very happy they weren't successful in their attempt.

But merely having a better outcome is not what prevents suicide from being a right wholly. These people, in these situations, are not of their right minds. This is of course hard to define, and hyperbole has lead many to misuse that phrase, but I think it's relatively safe to say that suicidal thoughts caused by depression is not the sign of a fully healthy brain.

If their brain isn't fully healthy, then I don't trust them to make decisions like that. I don't believe the "healthy" version of themselves would trust their "unhealthy" selves either.

In other words: the right to commit suicide is for those in their right minds, and many suicidal people (where the suicidal thoughts are brought about by an unhealthy mind, namely depression) are not in their right minds. 

(side note: again, again, I hate absolutes. This is not a strict absolute for me. There are probably caveats and special cases where I would say someone has a specific right to suicide, despite not having a classically "healthy" mind, but I would evaluate those on an individual basis.)

This, of course, does not include cases of doctor assisted suicide for the terminally ill, and perpetually suffering. I'm very much for that, given the approval of a medical professional familiar with the patient. If the reasonable outlook on their lives is bleak, miserable, and generally painful, then I believe they have that right to end their own lives, for the same reasons I suspect you have. In these cases the people are *more* in their "right" minds. And if not their right minds, than in the minds of their loved ones, and their trusted healthcare professionals (for example, someone being brain dead).

I don't expect most people to entirely agree with me, but I just wanted to post that as an alternative view that you might want to mull over. But ultimately it doesn't have much to do with your original post.

&amp;gt; A right is an axiom that can be used to define instances of moral or immoral behavior.

I think this is a great general definition. 

But as I was looking over your examples and reasonings, something occurred to me: there are (at least) two types of rights, and one type isn't much of a right.

The first type is that born of nihilism. We're born free to act however we want. Nothing is intrinsically sacred. We can go eat, sleep, kill, steal, whatever we want. We'll suffer the consequences, but we're physically free to do whatever. It's a profoundly unhelpful type of right, because it makes literally every action a right. I imagine it's what [Diogenes](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diogenes) would define as a right.

In this view, the only thing you don't have a "right" to do is break the laws of physics. I have no right to fly because I can't physically fly (without an airplane).

The other type of rights are those that are given to us by others. And I believe that, in one way or another, all of your examples fit into this category. **Our rights are defined by what is acceptable to others.**

So when anyone lists out what they believe to be their "right", what they're really saying is "this is what all people should allow me to do". Of course, in your case, you're also having the forethought to apply this list of rights to all people, and not just yourself, just as Kant would have wanted.

And this aligns with your premise! Your title included the word "should", because you recognized that this was already a right provided by others.

So ultimately, they way we've navigated this discussion, it comes down to collective morality. What should people, as a species, protect as actions free to take by all of its individuals?

Since one cannot bring oneself into existence alone (unless you're God), being created is a right provided by ones parents. However, of course, this does not include the consent of the one being created, nor does this provided right extend past birth. Parents do not have the right to end your existence once you're born. 

(Of course there's all kinds of details we're glossing over, like the responsibility of parents to raise the child, as a human child cannot take care of itself)

Consent. The question is about consent.

And to answer that question, I point to my previous comment. Conception starts immoral because, due to the laws of time, consent cannot predate a being's existence. But it is up to the individual to understand the circumstances of their existence (and creation) and decide for themselves if consent deserves to be given, retroactively. 

And in many ways, this is the most profound right one can be given, and it's given by one's creators (parents). The right to choose to exist. But one must first exist to make that choice. And then once one makes the choice to choose to exist, it is a right only you have. It might be the only type of right that, once taken, is only provided by oneself, and not others. Parents start it. You reclaim it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
