<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306858038.0" user="throwaway_cmview" delta="False">
    <text>People should be able to choose what they want to believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306867020.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, when they're adults.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306885835.0" user="throwaway_cmview" delta="False">
    <text>*Children are also people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306936338.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Not mature ones. The age of adulthood exists for a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306939030.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't stop them from going to hell. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306956452.0" user="throwaway_cmview" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I don't know what you're asking for here. Do you think that people under the age of 18 should have their freedom of conscience suspended by the government? Should kids be prevented from accessing or professing a belief about politics or science too? There are sure a lot of children on League of Legends that I'd like to have arrested for professing thoughts about my mother without the required brain matter. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306886308.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>That point of view is only acceptable if there is no religion that is true. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307073270.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>That is the default state, since none are proven.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309913473.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>No its not, its a very narrow and unpopular viewpoint </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310263593.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; unpopular 

That happens to be because so many people believe in all of that stuff sans proof.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
