<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30307234770.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>So, elsewhere, you say you don't want kids to learn religion at home, and to report on parents for teaching religion. Don't you feel that this unfairly limits parents' ability to practice their own religion?

For example: 

* I pray before meals, aloud with my husband and kids.  I did this before we had kids.  What would you tell me to do? Not eat with my kids? Not answer questions? 

* I put up religious decor around holidays - things like an Advent wreath, nativity, etc. Again, I did this before I had kids.  Should this be disallowed? 

* Many faiths allow or encourage a small prayer area in the home - everything from a little Shinto shrine to a crucifix on the wall.

* Muslims, I believe, get out prayer mats and pray multiple times a day.  They also fast during Ramadan. Are they like... supposed to try to hide from their children while they do this? 

If you have faith, if you live your faith, those around you will see parts of that faith, without any pushiness on your part at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307452798.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>All those activities are going to be acceptable as part of their usual practice of religion.

Parents can answer questions, but no trying to bring the kid into the religion.

To counteract seeing this, the Kid as part of their education should go around and, for instance, visit a church one week, a temple the next, a mosque the next, etc.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307488079.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>"can answer questions, but no trying to bring the kid into their religion"

That seems an awfully fuzzy line. Do you... have kids? Kids want to be like their parents. Both of mine started mimicking my prayers before I'd made any explicit encouragement for them to. And, while I have encouraged it since (by correcting their mistakes and inviting them to join me) I don't really need to. My 2yo is often waiting with his food for me to carry mine in and severely tells me  as I set down my plate "Mommy,  you fowgot to say our pwayr."

My read on you is that you probably see that little tale as a horror story of awful indoctrination. But really, it's not.  If I don't invite my kids to pray with me, and just pray by myself,  there's a good chance they're gonna get upset and demand I pray again with them. They've never gotten in trouble for not praying (the severe words from my toddler are echoing a reminder from me to my husband, not me to my kids). 

They've asked me why we pray, and I tell them. I tell them all the reasons I personally find it helpful (a big one: people who take the time to appreciate and be grateful for what they have are happier). Now,  that's a true answer, but it's also a persuasive one - and I 100% do want to teach my kids gratitude. I do that in the framework of religion, because that's what I believe... but I'm having a hard time clearly seeing the line between OK/not OK from your perspective.


Separate point:
This didn't occur to me earlier... churches are often really big on  supporting families. My kids attend a mom's morning out thing at a nearby church for a few hours each week that's far cheaper than secular childcare for a comparable period of time. It's not actually even at my church, but a church of another Christian faith. My own church offers a nursery during a parenting support group that's on church premises, and regularly hosts pro-family activities on church property (Easter egg hunts, potluck dinners, family movie nights etc.) I'm assuming you'd ban all these things,  drastically reducing the amount of low-cost childcare, parental support communities, and free/cheap family entertainment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307737850.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I tell them all the reasons I personally find it helpful (a big one: people who take the time to appreciate and be grateful for what they have are happier). 

Let's start from here. See, I do think religion has its uses, like that quote. (otherwise I'd want to ban it outright). I mean, if that's what makes you happy, I'm not going to try to stop you, a presumably responsible adult. However, the thing is, I compare religion to something like marijuana, a *drug*.

Medical, and even Recreational Marijuana is something I support. 

However, and this is where I make the comparison: Religion, like drugs, require maturity in their use, and hence part of why I think that just like marijuana, actually practicing religion must be limited to adults only.

Now let's link this to kids. A kid can't handle something like marijuana. You know how dealers might provide the first hit free, thus starting the road to addiction? That's how I think religious indoctrination works with kids.

&amp;gt; "Mommy, you fowgot to say our pwayr."

That's the symptoms right there. 

&amp;gt; My read on you is that you probably see that little tale as a horror story of awful indoctrination.

That would be spot on.

And as for that line? I wouldn't want you inviting the kid to prayer. (Ie, bringing them into the faith)

Your church childcare point regarding costs? I'd like to have government subsidized childcare. In fact, it would be the perfect opportunity to organize the trips to different religious institutions every week I mentioned to balance what they see at home. Actually, the churches wouldn't need to stop holding their activities, they'd simply host a rotating different group of kids every time, fulfilling the goal of multi-denominational education. Again, your kids could go to a church (of different faith) for childcare one week, and then a temple the next.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308044092.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>Let's respond to the childcare idea first - it "sounds" good (and I have no issue with the idea of exposing kids to other faiths in general), but it does seem like an idea thought up by someone who doesn't have kids.  Before I first left my kids at childcare at the nearby church, I took my kids to two open houses to get to know the people I'd be leaving them with.  I filled out about 15 pages of info about my kids for their system and visited my kids' doctors so I could get a certified copy of immunization records to release to the church. And my kids STILL had anxiety about being left with the lovely women who care for them for the first few weeks. So... yeah. Sounds nice,  but logistically? I don't think your idea works at all.


On to the main topic: 

Okay, but did you read my post? I have zero confidence that we wouldn't end up in exactly the same situation if I'd *never* invited my kids to join me.  I didn't invite them to start with, it was just monkey - see,  monkey - do, just like when I do an exercise routine in the living room, scrub the floor,  or read a book. 

Would it be okay if things were exactly the same in our house if I'd never invited them? What if I felt the need to explain my strange and rude behavior (I invite my kids to join me in most activities they show an interest in, and encourage them to behave similarly to each other) and told them I was sorry I had to be rude and not see if they were ready to pray with me, but it was against the government's rules? Separately, what if I never encouraged them to pray, but they asked me to wait for them before beginning to pray, just like they want me to wait for them before starting my exercise routines - would I even be permitted to, or would the government require my rudeness on this topic? 

The point I was trying to make before, which I may not have made clear enough, is that the normal practice of faith WILL educate and invite children into it by the nature of how children ARE. If you want that not to happen I feel you have to place horrifyingly unfair burdens on the parents - either we must act anti-religious and actively push our children AWAY from what we believe deep in our hearts is best for them and us,  or we are forced to practice our own faith in secret. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308175146.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; monkey - see, monkey - do

I compared religion to Marijuana. If you did recreational Marijuana, and your kid tried to copy you - what would you do?

Or how about guns? Kid sees his dad go hunting, wants to copy him; do you just accept that monkey see - monkey do, or do you tell them it's too dangerous for their age.

Religion is the same. It's unhealthy for kids who don't know what it is they are really doing and can't make an informed decision. So what should you do with something like that? Keep them away from practicing it.

&amp;gt;  What if I felt the need to explain my strange and rude behavior (I invite my kids to join me in most activities they show an interest in, and encourage them to behave similarly to each other)

Behave like you would with any other topic considered 'adult' in regards to if the kid actually wants to copy you, like my 2 examples above. Answer questions if they ask, but this is how you get out of it if they want to actually participate.

&amp;gt; either we must act anti-religious

Not necessary, see my point above. You can practice your faith, pray as you like at home in full view, and tell your kids they aren't old enough, just like with something like driving.

I will not comment further on the logistical points as I am insufficiently experienced in that area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308333373.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>Wow,  haha... So much here.  Where to start?

Alright,  first off, your analogies to medical marijuana and hunting are not very useful. Maybe they make sense from your perspective, but not to most people. Hunting,  in particular... I'm not a hunter, but I know hunting families, and the kids are often involved from young ages - perhaps not firing a gun themselves, but they are being taught all sorts of things about hunting, they know they're eating hunted meat, they know gun safety and hunting safety tips before they ever touch a gun. 

Medical marijuana is just... there is basically no similarity there between how I view religion and this. I view medical marijuana as a minor harm to your average person, with no meaningful benefits to your average person, much like other prescription drugs. 

To me,  a more apt comparison to religion would be fluoridated toothpaste. It's possible to abuse or misuse toothpaste in ways that could be very harmful, but toothpaste also offers a multitude of benefits if used reasonably. Even if some people are irresponsible, my personal feeling is that the benefits to your average toothpaste-user make it worth encouraging responsible toothpaste-use.

You're looking at the cultists crazies and seeing the harm, the misuse. I'm looking at my day-to-day life with my family and others' families and seeing faith help teach wonderful lessons about gratitude, community support,  sharing, forgiveness, mercy, hope, love... 

The majority of religious upbringing is not "abusive brainwashing." I expose my kids to our friends of other faiths (and no faith) and talk about their beliefs respectfully with my kids ("Daddy and I believe... Miss Jalpa believes..."). I'm not an outlier.  The crazies are the outliers.

I also can't help but notice you haven't given actual examples of how I "should" respond in these situations. You say "like you'd respond to this or that" but those examples are nonsensical to me... and I really can't concretely envision a way to respond that is respectful of my own faith that I feel certain you would not find "overboard." I even gave specific examples to see if you would find them "overboard," but I did not get a specific response. 

If you can't clearly articulate in an unambiguous way what would be legal and illegal, this law seems completely unfeasible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309840631.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Medical marijuana is just... there is basically no similarity there between how I view religion and this. I view medical marijuana as a minor harm to your average person, with no meaningful benefits to your average person, much like other prescription drugs.

My analogy was to *Recreational* Marijuana, not medical (though it can still apply to medical in another way.)

I take it from your response you don't think well of recreational marijuana if that's how low your view is of medical.

&amp;gt; It's possible to abuse or misuse ~~toothpaste~~ Marijuana in ways that could be very harmful, but toothpaste also offers a multitude of benefits if used reasonably. Even if some people are irresponsible, my personal feeling is that the benefits to your average ~~toothpaste~~ Marijuana-user make it worth encouraging responsible ~~toothpaste~~ Marijuana-use.

But not to kids, where it'd be more harmful.


See, I see the benefits of recreational marijuana to be very similar to the benefits you have said that religion brings - it makes you happier, with the very same kinds of cons.

You also didn't answer my question either - What would you do if you were doing legal recreational Marijuana and your kid tried to copy you?

&amp;gt; perhaps not firing a gun themselves

Therein being the important part. They're kept away from the most dangerous part.

&amp;gt; The majority of religious upbringing is not "abusive brainwashing."

Purely raising your kid as your religion is brainwashing as I've already stated, as it can lock their belief system and they don't get a true informed choice later.
It's like giving your kid adult-legal drugs.

&amp;gt; I also can't help but notice you haven't given actual examples of how I "should" respond in these situations.

This basically fits everything.

&amp;gt; tell your kids they aren't old enough

That's all you need. hardly disrespectful.





As I've said before:

Legal: 

Praying as much you please in your home, in full view of your kids, if you wish.

Going to a church/mosque/temple/other religious institution.

Shines at home if your faith calls for it, but *not* allowing your kids to pray there.

Illegal: 

Sending your kids to religious schools

Inviting them to join you in religious activities.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309992889.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, see, you're asking me you act very differently on this topic than I would for anything else. Even on tough topics I always provide as much information as I feel my kids are developmentally able to understand and handle. That's just a matter of respecting them as people. 

You're acting like there IS no age-appropriate way to share your religion with your kids, and drastically oversimplifying - putting open dialogue on the same level as legit cult indoctrination. Putting voluntary emulation in the same bucket as forced worship. 

This lack of nuance is really harming your argument. Suggesting parents should punish kids to prevent them from praying at the prayer shrine they've seen other family members use? How is that reasonable? Kids get emotionally distraught too. They're  people too. They seek answers too. If Grandpa died and they see mom crying and praying for an hour, and they kneel down to join her... you want mom to tell them to go away? That they're too young to seek answers or comfort? Doesn't that seem... dehumanizing and abusive? At the very least they're going to feel alienated from their family members, and it's very hard to show the specific harm that wound be caused by allowing them to make their own choices. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310493024.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah, see, you're asking me you act very differently on this topic than I would for anything else

Again, if you did recreational Marijuana, would you actually let them emulate you?
How about if they accidentally saw you having sex? OK to copy?
Or any other Adult-only activity.

&amp;gt;  legit cult indoctrination

Know what the difference between a cult and a religion is? Numbers. That's it. A Cult with sufficient following becomes religion. This is true of Christianity's history as well - they were initially decried as a cult until they had sufficient converts, and suddenly pagans are the cultists. What you call cult indoctrination is little different from how parents bring their children into their religion.

&amp;gt;  Suggesting parents should punish kids to prevent them from praying at the prayer shrine they've seen other family members use?

Would you punish a kid you caught using some of your stash of Recreational Marijuana that he has seen you and other family members use?

Answer is the same.
Religion *is a drug*. Drugs can have useful benefits, including emotional comfort and happiness. But they are also dangerous.

Kid sees you crying and praying? Let them hug you for comfort. But don't let them pray.

&amp;gt; caused by allowing them to make their own choices.

They're not at an age where they realize that there is another choice. Can your toddler realize he has the real option to pray to Yama instead of copying you and praying to God? Praying to God becomes habit, the religion becomes addicting, and it becomes difficult to change to something else.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310615523.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>Most people would not agree with your definition of a cult, but would instead define a cult by the level of control it exerted over its members and the difficulty members have in leaving. 

You're arguing from a lot of base assumptions most people don't share. Most people do not equate Espiscopalianism with Scientology. Most people do not consider religion similar to a drug, and honestly you've made no strong case that they should. You just want people to blindly agree with your assumptions.

I'm out of this thread. There doesn't seem to be much chance of productive discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30311003623.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>I found that definition of cult way back in my college days in some social studies textbook. I didn't invent it. I no longer have that book, but here is something similar.

[Here's a link](https://aeon.co/essays/how-an-obscure-oriental-cult-converted-a-vast-pagan-roman-empire)

Christianity was a cult to start.

&amp;gt; religion similar to a drug

Karl Marx was not wrong on this issue.

&amp;gt; Most people do not consider religion similar to a drug

Because they are addicted to it. Do drug addicts admit it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308352070.0" user="Zifna" delta="False">
    <text>Another specific situation I'd want to know how your law would handle - music.  Would it become illegal to listen to or sing religious music where children might hear? If yes, how would you delineate what was religious music - Amazing Grace,  sure, but what if it was instrumental? What about Christian pop songs? What about country songs that talk about faith among other topics? What about secular Christmas carols?

And if music is okay, why is it okay?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309859548.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Another specific situation I'd want to know how your law would handle - music. Would it become illegal to listen to or sing religious music where children might hear? 

Given that I have specifically said organizing trips to various religious institutions is part of the multi-denominational education plan, this would not be an issue as part of that. It's part of learning about the various religions, and therefore fine.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
