<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306762546.0" user="radialomens" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

*Why*? I mean, if you want to worry about brainwashing that's one thing, but being baptized doesn't turn a person Christian. 

And does it matter to you at all that this would severely hinder religious expression? There are a lot of ceremonies that occur before adulthood. Having a bat mitzvah isn't going to hurt anyone, kid included.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306802574.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but being baptized doesn't turn a person Christian.

According to some, it officially does.

&amp;gt; And does it matter to you at all that this would severely hinder religious expression?

Of *children*. Who aren't mature enough to make decisions on it.

Religious rituals for children expose them to practices that become ingrained, preventing them from making properly as closed to unbiased as possible decisions when they are mature enough to do so.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306819087.0" user="radialomens" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;According to some, it officially does.

But it *doesn't*. They can change their mind. Many have and do.

My ex was baptized and it didn't turn him Christian. It got him wet.

&amp;gt;Of children. Who aren't mature enough to make decisions on it.

They're not making decisions, they're having parties. I mean, there's symbolism involved, like your entry into manhood, but it's not like they're signing a contract. 

&amp;gt;preventing them from making properly as closed to unbiased as possible decisions when they are mature enough to do so.

Then do you also believe that parents should not be allowed to discuss politics in front of their children until their children are old enough to vote? That would potentially include issues like civil rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306848471.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But it doesn't

according to you. Many religious people think otherwise.

&amp;gt; They can change their mind. Many have and do.

My point is that they should first make up their mind when they are an adult that hasn't been indoctrinated prior. Sure, people can change their mind later, but its harder to do so if brainwashed first.

&amp;gt; They're not making decisions,

They're getting decisions made for them.

As for politics, the voting age already prevents them from acting on it for all intents and purposes. there's no such age right now to prevent practicing a religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306870801.0" user="radialomens" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;according to you. Many religious people think otherwise.

Religion, like consent, must be ongoing. Do you or do you not accept that a person who has been baptized can be nonreligious?

&amp;gt;My point is that they should first make up their mind when they are an adult that hasn't been indoctrinated prior. Sure, people can change their mind later, but its harder to do so if brainwashed first.

But brainwashing and seeing your family for Easter dinner are two very different activities. 

&amp;gt;They're getting decisions made for them.

No, no decision is made for them when they have a baptism or bat mitzvah. They don't get put on some kind of national register, they don't get kept from learning alternative beliefs. They're having a party, not enlisting in the military.

&amp;gt;As for politics, the voting age already prevents them from acting on it for all intents and purposes. 

So those kids at the March for Our Lives are.... blank slates?

I feel like the very use of "for all intents and purposes" belies the very problem in your argument. For all intents and purposes, a youth's politics are instilled in them before they vote. They debate and they march and they listen to campaign ads and they talk to their parents about what this party and that party mean. *For all intents and purposes* a young person is politicized well before they can vote. I know I was. I went looking to argue about abortion and same-sex marriage back in high school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306826270.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>What makes religion different from other things you ingrain in your children from a young age, like political ideology, bigotry, racism, sexism, or even, *shudder* rooting for the Cleveland Browns?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306879351.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think choosing a religion is like picking out clothes to wear? Oh I'm going to try Buddhism today because it just "feels" right, oh I'm going to be Orthodox because I like the way it feels, oh, I'm going to go with Islam because I like their moral code. 

But that's an entirely wrong way of looking at things unless you're an atheist. 

Do you think that oh, I shouldn't tell my child not to run out in front of the street because they might not understand why? Or do you grab them to prevent them from getting hit by a truck? Do you worry about hurting their feelings by suddenly jerking them out of the way from oncoming traffic? Of course not. 

If Christianity is true, then that means there is a heaven and there is a hell, there will be judgement, if you were a Christian how in the world could you let your child go to everlasting torment simply because you were too afraid that it might somehow "damage" them or that they're "too young" to understand? 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
