<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306726838.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>None of this would prevent parents from educating their children in the comfort of their own home. Anything that would prevent that would be incredibly invasive and illegal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306838586.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Add it to the list of responsibilities of social workers to check for religious indoctrination.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306853497.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>How? It's a lot easier to lie about religion than anything else, especially since most religions already have instructions if you are being discriminated against. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307010543.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You don't actually believe this do you? You realize how ironic and dystopian that is hopefully? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307059136.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>brainwashing = abuse.

checking for abuse is part of a social worker's job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307078047.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You need to rethink your entire worldview. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307079555.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Tell me how brainwashing isn't abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
