<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306814562.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>From a sociological perspective the primary purpose of religion is to teach the values and morals that a specific society or subset of society holds to the next generation. By banning the teaching of religion to children you ban the standard established method teaching those values and morals. That means you have to replace them in some other manner very carefully crafted to not be a religion itself, which is very very difficult. 

Additionally for what you want to be done you would have to monitor everyone constantly in their homes. This is a violation of all principles of privacy (and the parts of the constitution that protect privacy in the US). 

And finally you are preventing parents from practicing their religion in their homes. That is a violation of their religious rights. (violation of the first amendment). 

What you are wanting is Orwellian levels of totalitarianism that would require a complete restructuring of society. It simply will not work, and in most countries would be highly illegal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306859039.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; From a sociological perspective the primary purpose of religion is to teach the values and morals that a specific society or subset of society holds to the next generation. By banning the teaching of religion to children you ban the standard established method teaching those values and morals. That means you have to replace them in some other manner very carefully crafted to not be a religion itself, which is very very difficult.

Difficult shouldn't prevent us from doing it.

&amp;gt; Additionally for what you want to be done you would have to monitor everyone constantly in their homes. This is a violation of all principles of privacy (and the parts of the constitution that protect privacy in the US).

I'd rather not home monitoring, but institute a system where social workers look out for indoctrination, as they do for abuse. Don't need orwell surveillance for that.

&amp;gt; And finally you are preventing parents from practicing their religion in their homes. That is a violation of their religious rights. (violation of the first amendment).

And teaching religion to kids is in my opinion violating their religious rights. Because they now don't get a truly free choice on it as they've been indoctrinated. The parents can practice, just don't involve the kids.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306906795.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>The damages to society, personal and religious freedoms are far too severe to tolerate. What you want is totalitarian bordering on fascist. You are wanting thought crime, and the government to dictate how everyone is raised and that is wrong. 

And all education is indoctrination. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
