<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306729787.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>How are you going to prevent a parent from talking to their children about their religious faith?

That seems like it would be a huge violation of both freedom of speech, and freedom of religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306771071.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>In my opinion parents teaching kids their religion violates the kid's rights to freedom of religion, because it may effectively lock them in when they see little else of other options, or that they even have the choice.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306777989.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't answer my question, though.  You might not like it, but how are you planning to prevent it under your plan?

Short of some massive Orwellian survellience network, how do you prevent parents from teaching their children the preferred religion in their home?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306812375.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, yes, the unfortunate practical hangups.

Getting Kids to report on if they learn this at home doesn't have massive privacy problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306816048.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Turning children into state informants against their parents is a massive privacy problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306823848.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>We ask children to report if they are abused. That's not a privacy problem.

It's the same deal here. Report if they're being indoctrinated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306831548.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Teaching religion is not abuse.  That's an absurd analogy to make.  It'd be no different than asking kids to report if their parents were secretly socialists or commies or libertarians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306872274.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Teaching religion is *indoctrination*.

Brainwashing is abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306882704.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Teaching religion is indoctrination.

Is teaching a kid not to run into the street after a ball indoctrination as well? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306899646.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>All education is indoctrination. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306822612.0" user="radialomens" delta="False">
    <text>You've literally taken a page out of 1984. I don't know how you think this isn't a privacy problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306903850.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see this as any different as getting a kid to report abuse, which brainwashing functionally is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306927286.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>How is religion any worse than you spouting your disbelief in any God?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306952222.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Irrelevant to this discussion.

Remember i said multi denominational education - they get to learn about as many religions as possible.

I'm not calling for teaching them to be atheists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306994015.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>You're calling for forcing them to live as atheists. Learning the tenets of Judaism is meaningless if you have to go, I don't know, somewhere else? every time your parents have a Seder. 

If your parents are religious, religion will be an important part of their lives. How can we reasonably expect families to divorce the way they live their religion (which are composed of practices, not simply beliefs) from the time they spend raising their children? What do you expect them to do with a six year old when they're at church? A six week old? Because leaving a child alone is also neglect. And if you expect the parents not to go to church, then you're prohibiting them (fully responsible adults) from expressing their faith, which even under your view is unacceptable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307107871.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>How about sending them to a church one week, a mosque the next, then a Hindu temple the next. A full, balanced education.

I expect them to make the same arrangement for their kids as with any other outing when they aren't home.

&amp;gt; And if you expect the parents not to go to church

They can go, I'm not trying to stop em.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307868533.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>Where on earth do you live? Where I grew up there wasn't a mosque for a hundred miles. Are you going to have a government campaign of mosque-building in every town to make sure people can still go to church? 

And yes, you are trying to stop them. You're raising the costs of religiosity unbearably high. Sending your young children unaccompanied to mosques when you are a Christian isn't tenable and you know it. Forcing them to visit a Hindu temple when there isn't one in their town isn't tenable. The entire situation is designed to make religious practice untenable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307959733.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sending your young children unaccompanied to mosques when you are a Christian isn't tenable and you know it.

You know, my proposed kind of multi-denominational education would breed something we call religious tolerance. You can trust sunday school with your kid but not a mosque? See, that kind of attitude is a product of that religious indoctrination.

I grew up mostly in Singapore btw. Which doesn't have any sort of religious tolerance problems. All sorts of religions jumbled in there with all the cultures, with all the accompanying religious buildings. They have both racial and religious harmony.

Really, leaving your kid with a sitter once a week when parents go to church is no different than for any other outing. Fund trips to different religious buildings under the education budget if neccessary, since thats what its for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307968235.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>It's not that they inherently don't trust the mosque, it's that when a child is at church sunday school her parents are in the same building! They're not going to be attending a mosque because they've chosen a different religion. Leaving your toddler with people you haven't vetted and probably don't know and driving across town is what's untenable. 

And what are you going to do when there *is* no mosque? Like where I grew up. Just no church at all for the kid because they can't also go to a buddhist temple? 

Also, some people can't afford regular childcare. They don't have sitters for other outings. Expecting them to pay for one to attend church is unfair. Also, plenty of religious rituals take place at home, like seders. Hell, every shabbat dinner on Friday is religious practice. Is the kid banished from their home every Friday?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308004983.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it's that when a child is at church sunday school her parents are in the same building!

We have different experiences with Sunday School then. Mine simply dropped me off and came back.

&amp;gt; Leaving your toddler with people you haven't vetted

You going to tell me parents vet Sunday School teachers?  They inherently trust them because they are the same religion, and don't trust those of the other. And that's part of the problem.

And like I said, if absolutely necessary, fund trips to other religious buildings under the education budget, or under the childcare budget, if you truly don't want to cost-burden parents.

If there's no other religious building nearby then it should be part of school trips to go to them, for the multidenominational education.

As for something like Shabbat, the Kid eats at home but doesn't participate otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308561220.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>No, that isn't part of the problem. They trust the teachers because theyre staff at *their church,* which they "vetted" in the same way we vet our friends and regular places we choose to do business. Good word of mouth, personal experience, standing in the community, etc. Parents would *not* leave their children with a random total stranger just because they happened to be the same religion, because it isn't the religion breeding inherent trust; it's familiarity with the specific institution. The mosque Sunday school is far more akin to the random total stranger. Unless people start posting yelp reviews of and state-accrediting daycares at temples, parents won't trust them with their kid unless they know them or the parents will be present. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310243025.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>[Religious people will trust those of their religion more *because of the shared religion*](https://www.researchgate.net/publication/300423613_Religion_Discrimination_and_Trust_Across_Three_Cultures)




&amp;gt; state-accrediting daycares at temples

Good idea, there's your solution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310394586.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>Again, the costs you are imposing on religion are exorbitant. They aren't for-profit institutions like actual daycares that can recoup these costs--they're part of nonprofit religious organizations. You are attempting to raise the cost of being religious--for all parties, from parents to churches to atheist taxpayers who have to fund these school field trips to every religious institution in the state--because you don't approve of religious practice. It is transparently unfair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310519629.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>Government is shouldering the cost of daycare/trips, or if counting taxpayers instead, then its fairly spread across everybody, even the atheists. 

And given the *educational value* of exposure to all these religions, and possibly increased religious tolerance that results, that money spent has value.

&amp;gt; because you don't approve of religious practice

If I disapproved of religious practice, I'd want it outright banned, not go planning trips to all their institutions. But I think it has benefits, comparable to drugs like Recreational Marijuana. Hence widespread multi-denominational education and restriction to adults.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306815292.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I would institute laws to make public education mandatory with statewide funding and ban homeschooling. Neither of these require things which don't exist already (just need legally mandated compulsory K-12 attendance for all children).

The parents could teach religion in their home but they wouldn't be able to indoctrinate to the same degree because their education would be secular and include critical thinking.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
