<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30306844184.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>You're coming at this question as an atheist. Sure, if there's no God, no Gods, no afterlife, etc. it doesn't matter so its fine to have this be a choice just like you choose your clothing or the car you drive or what you're going to eat. If all religion is pure fantasy, just made up BS no different than the world of Tolkien and the Gods told about from religion are no more real than the world of Final Fantasy then sure, your premise holds water. 

But what if you're wrong. 

What if there IS an afterlife, what if there IS a heaven and a hell. If that's true, wouldn't you want your child protected against hell? 

Your premise falls apart the moment you introduce the idea that religion could be based in reality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306898958.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>By default, as something must be proven once claimed, they are 'not true'.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306910594.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>So in other words your CMV can be explained as "atheist thinks religion is bad"? I fail to see how that's a convincing argument for anything. You don't believe in a God so thus you think its silly that someone would believe in a God. Since belief in a God is false (as per your inherent idea that there is no God) according to you there's probably not much that can be done to convince you that religion is good because in your mind its in inherent falsehood. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306943055.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that parents are brainwashing their kids and effectively taking away their freedom of choice.

Recall that i wanted multidenominational education of religion.

They can pick any of those when they grow up. I'm not asking them to pick non-religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30306971791.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My argument is that parents are brainwashing their kids and effectively taking away their freedom of choice.

Again, freedom of choice only makes sense in an atheistic world. Freedom of choice only effectively makes sense if all religions are equally right or equally wrong. 

You would not consider a parent who thought that their kid was running into traffic and didn't try to stop them was a good parent, correct? You wouldn't complain that the parent didn't sit down with their kid and explained the exact danger to the kid and asked them, ok, are you sure you want to run in the street. 

Rather, you'd expect that if a parent saw a danger or potential danger that would affect their kid that they would do everything in their power to prevent their kid from getting injured or killed. 

Let's say for the sake of argument that Christianity exists, would it not be considered just as irresponsible to do everything in their power to make sure their child does not go to hell as it would be to just let their child run in the street? 

Sure, let's have them wait until their an adult. But wait, the kid died of something and is now burning in hell for eternity. 

Is that a risk that's acceptable? 

Its certainly acceptable if you're an atheist, but if you're a Christian and believe that Christianity is true, that's absolutely unacceptable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307169728.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You would not consider a parent who thought that their kid was running into traffic and didn't try to stop them was a good parent, correct? You wouldn't complain that the parent didn't sit down with their kid and explained the exact danger to the kid and asked them, ok, are you sure you want to run in the street.

Danger from walking into traffic is proven. If you get hit by a car, you *will* get hurt.

Hell is not proven. Your hypothetical assumes the existence of what cannot be proven, it's not logical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309912568.0" user="Mozart_Sixth" delta="False">
    <text>Only if you view the world from an atheistic perspective </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310265907.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Only if you view the world from an ~~atheistic~~ Scientific perspective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307031744.0" user="jdylopa" delta="False">
    <text>Religion isn’t necessarily brainwashing. There are millions of people who leave the religion they were raised, either to convert or leave religion altogether. Why is it so hard to just say that once people are adults, they can form their own opinions and beliefs. Some people leave the religion they are raised with, some don’t.

Think about this: should it be illegal for parents to tell their children that the earth is flat? What about that vaccines cause autism? That climate change isn’t real? That people’s gender and sex aren’t necessarily the same? That GMOs are bad? That being a vegan is good? That the tooth fairy exists?

Religion or lack thereof is a belief, it’s an open question. People have different views. That doesn’t mean they’re all equally valid, but is it the role of the government to basically say “parents should only tell their children things that can 100% be proven or disproven and anything else should be somehow ignored until they turn 18?”

What about the practicality of it? Think about weekly religious services and holidays. Are children not allowed to go with their parents even if they want to? Young kids want to be around their parents and family all the time. How do you tell a kid they’re not allowed to spend time with their family?

What about when a parent is praying (as is their right) and their child asks a question. Or when a child sees a video on YouTube about religion and wants to talk about it? They’re just supposed to be told “sorry we can’t say the ‘G’ word till you’re older.”

I’m an atheist myself, and I do agree that some people only believe in god because it was how they are raised. But that isn’t anywhere near the same thing as abuse or neglect. For one it isn’t inherently detrimental. So what if they’re wrong? It doesn’t hurt them. In fact, religion does benefit many people. Whether God is real or not, having something to believe in can be mentally and emotionally comfortable for people. It’s been shown that religion objectively is a good thing for many people who struggle with addiction or are going through cancer. It’s a community. And for the people that religion doesn’t help, they have every opportunity to leave their religion and believe whatever they want. I was raised Jewish. It didn’t somehow prevent me from realizing I didn’t believe in god. Whereas my brother, who went through the same upbringing, still has some attachment to religion. And who does that hurt? Certainly not him, he’s happy as a clam.

The only reason to want this is to inflict your lack of belief onto others. If doesn’t matter whether it’s right or wrong, people should be allowed to believe what they want to believe and not have to censor their harmless beliefs just because they can’t be proven. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307147381.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Religion isn’t necessarily brainwashing. There are millions of people who leave the religion they were raised, either to convert or leave religion altogether. Why is it so hard to just say that once people are adults, they can form their own opinions and beliefs. Some people leave the religion they are raised with, some don’t.

It's harder to leave if you've been raised in it. That's the brainwashing effect. These people aren't getting a true free choice. This is why I want multi denominational religion education. They get to choose what suits them, leading to your below point. What they were raised in may not be the one for them, but being raised that way can lock them in. 

&amp;gt; having something to believe in can be mentally and emotionally comfortable for people.

I'm aware of the practical uses of religion (I consider it to be a drug.. but it can have practical use, Marijuana and all), which is why I'm not out to ban it. Pick and choose what suits you... as an adult. Btw, Legal Marijuana is also restricted to adults.

&amp;gt; harmless beliefs

Something that is inherently illogical, and teaching to believe in the illogical, is harmful. (See: climate change deniers). It may be counteracted by the beneficial drug-like effects, but harmless? no.


If a child asks a question i suppose they will have no choice but to respond honestly. Makes the public education angle even more important to provide information on everything.

As for services, for the purpose of the full education, I'd say church one week, Mosque the next, Temple the next, etc, etc, etc. So they see everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307153511.0" user="jdylopa" delta="False">
    <text>You still haven’t answered the main question:

How can you tell parents they can’t legally tell their child something unless it is 100% provable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307178702.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not asking for 100% proof requirement.

Religion doesn't even get to 1% level. Inherently, it can't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307187017.0" user="jdylopa" delta="False">
    <text>Neither does Santa Claus. Is telling kids about the tooth fairy abuse or neglect?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30307209627.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>I have never been a fan of the lies of Santa Claus or the tooth fairy to kids.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
