<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30308152101.0" user="kingado08" delta="False">
    <text>Ima blow your mind here just wait... it doesn't matter... because all the religions say the same thing in a different way with a different heaven and hell. Religion can be used to instill important values in children. About 98% of most all religious works (excluding scientology) have the same message. "Don't be a dick, don't steal and don't kill people". Almost all the stories in the Bible, Quran, even the Book of Mormon would be seen as valuable stories for children with good a morale if looked at anecdotally.  Also one can't "indoctrinate" someone with the value that truly matters which is what happens upon death. Everyone sees and experiences death different it's similar to fear there's no way to condition an exact response to it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30308215084.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; heaven and hell

Religions don't necessarily have to have a heaven or hell. Which values are emphasized also differs between religions. Hence choosing.

&amp;gt; Don't be a dick, don't steal and don't kill people

Then how about teaching that message... without the religion, what do you even need that part for then?

Clarify your last part as well as I am unsure of your meaning. Kids are indoctrinated by parents the same way cults indoctrinate any of their members.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
