<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503241477.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8bm7lx/cmv_people_should_not_be_able_to_choose_a/">
    <title>CMV: People should not be able to choose a religion until they reach the age of legal adulthood</title>
    <original_poster>PsychoticSoul</original_poster>
    <original_post>Children are about as impressionable as it gets, and getting religious instruction from their parents is, in my opinion, tantamount to brainwashing at the age where they are most susceptible.

Choosing a religion requires the same responsible, mature mind that allows one to vote, drive, drink, choose a political affiliation, etc - so why must those wait until adulthood, but religion can effectively be forced on the young?

By my suggestion I mean:

Instruction regarding religion in all schools must be multi-denominational and as wide as possible, such that a person can make as informed a decision as possible upon reaching adulthood on what path they wish to take.

Religious schools can only accept adults - those who have made the conscious decision to go there.

No religious rituals such as baptism until willingly chosen as an adult.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30308384201.0" user="kingado08" delta="False">
    <text>I think which values are emphasized is only even a circumstance of the time. I think all religions basically came to be in the same way with someone that truly believed they could help people live more fulfilling lives if they told one white lie and it snowballed. But I think ultimately religion was an evolutionary advantage that drew humans into bigger groups than they'd ever been in essentially starting history. So if those values could get us from the Stone Age to iPhones I'd say they're not too bad even with the white bearded guy. Because there's no denying before the 1800s the predominant belief and values system in the world was Judaism or Christianity. I'm not explaining myself well on the evolution thing. So before religion there's no reason not to eat your children or rape your mother. We were animals and we hunted and killed and raped and gathered. Now people were capable of critical thought but they had no basis for rules they did as the animals did. Until someone (likely a weaker or smaller person) thought of a way to live more peacefully. God says you can't rape or kill me and if you do when you die you'll live forever in fire. I'm not saying before that humans were running around killing eachother if they saw one another but much more anarchy. Which religion was truly the first I don't know but every ancient society has a temple and pyramids to protect the dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309851748.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>History of religion as peaceful for evolutionary advantage?

Really? you're going to go that route? With all of the religiously justified wars we've had? 

If anything those set us back, not advanced us.

&amp;gt; Because there's no denying before the 1800s the predominant belief and values system in the world was Judaism or Christianity

Forgetting Islam? Or the giant place that is China?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310273878.0" user="kingado08" delta="False">
    <text>Not peaceful there's nothing peaceful about humanity just more organized. I'm talking before Islam which is based on Christianity and I also said all religions are the same with the best ancient one being Buddhism because it instilled morals without necessitating a god. Also who were the first people to go to Africa and help people? The mission. Who feeds more poor people per day than UNICEF? The church. Do you blame JD Salinger for the death of Jon Lennon? Anything can be used for evil and war. Religion was just the least common denominator. People didn't die in the crusades because they were fighting a holy war. They died because the christians wanted Constantinople. Now patriotism has replaced that sentiment so it just shows how the ideal itself didn't cause the destruction it was merely an excuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30310434746.0" user="PsychoticSoul" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; all religions are the same

You're going to tell me that worship of the Greek Pantheon was the same as Islam?

&amp;gt;  I'm talking before Islam which is based on Christianity

You're lumping in Islam with Christianity and considering the Jews Separate? You're going to tell me the Islamic Caliphates had the same values as Christian europe?

&amp;gt; just more organized

Relatively non religious countries (such as the Netherlands, Denmark or South Korea) are no more disorganized than religious ones

Religious folks *exploited* Africa, Asia, and Latin America

&amp;gt; People didn't die in the crusades because they were fighting a holy war. They died because the christians wanted Constantinople

Dude, there was only a single crusade that targeted Constantinople, and it wasn't even the initial target at that.
Are you sure you have your history down? 

Crusades targeted places based on differing *religions*. And all of them were happily sanctioned by the Latin Church. Constantinople, in that time, also belonged to a different religion - an acceptable target.

&amp;gt; So before religion there's no reason not to eat your children

The Pragmatic reason would be propagation of your species. You don't need religion to tell you that. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
