<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503594194.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8btrrm/cmv_america_doesnt_need_more_stem_majors/">
    <title>CMV: America doesn't need more STEM majors.</title>
    <original_poster>brotherhood4232</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to follow the Reddit consensus that STEM = good and "basket weaving" majors = bad. I graduated with an electrical engineering degree myself. But after looking for a job myself, it doesn't seem like the job market could support a ton of more STEM majors.

I've seem very few job postings that said Entry Level. Most want 3\-5 years of experience and a host of qualifications that no new graduate will have. This means you are not only competing against other new graduates, but you are also competing against Mid\-Level STEM professionals. I think a flood of new STEM graduates would exacerbate this problem and a lot of those new engineers would be working at Starbucks. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30309635615.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>Every job these days (regardless of field) requires 3-5 years experience. 

Want to work in marketing, 3-5 years experience. Want to work in trucking, 3-5 years experience. Want to work in basket weaving, 3-5 years experience. 

In the 1960s every job required a high school diploma. In the 1980s every job required a college degree. In the 2010s every job requires a degree + 3-5 years experience. When the populous becomes more educated, job requirements go up, even when the requirements of the job don't go up. Edit: This is doubly true after a Recession. You are largely pin-down the moment when the economy shifted from College Degree -&amp;gt; College Degree +3-5 years to the 2007-2008 Recession when a lot of people went back to school (because they got laid off) and suddenly employers could afford to be extra stingy even though the jobs don't necessitate that level of experience. 

This issue has absolutely nothing to do with STEM jobs, its an issue with JOBS. 

As a secondary point - automation, robotics, mechanization, etc. is only going to continue to evolve. Once Uber perfects the self-driving car - the entire Transportation sector (10% of the economy) is going to be unemployed overnight. Retail/manufactoring/mining are also going to take major hits. 

In 15 years time, STEM jobs will literally be ALL JOBS. (maybe Hollywood is the exception, but that may literally be it). I don't think welding/carpentry/plumbing/driving/factory-working are going to continue to be occupations at all in 15 years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309641531.0" user="brotherhood4232" delta="False">
    <text>But how is anyone supposed to have that required experience, if no one is willing to provide it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309663411.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think all those "unpaid internships" are for?  (I'm only half being sarcastic, sadly, I'm also being half serious). Why pay entry level workers anything, when you can afford to pay only after the 3rd year?? Its 3 years of totally free labor. 

Edit: To seriously answer your question - if you get a PhD, typically those first 3 years experience are called a Post Doc position, not entry level. If you worked while going to school (say if you were a bio major and you worked in the bio lab whilst going to school) you can often spin this as work experience, at least to get into the door for an interview. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309694416.0" user="brotherhood4232" delta="False">
    <text>I did do a coop at the local power utility, but it doesn't seem like it was very useful experience for job applications. Honestly, I learned nothing from it. I was on Reddit most of the day because there simply wasn't enough work that I was allowed to do to fill up the day.

What I really wanted was an internship to improve my technical skills, but I didn't get one :/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309709166.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>You got what you needed though - you now get to check the magic box that says "I have worked 1 year" (or however long your internship was). Everyone applying for jobs has the same situation. Every recent grad applying for new jobs is fudging that 3-5 year thing with college/summer jobs. 

Anyone who has actually worked for 3-5 years is applying for jobs which require 5-10 years work experience. 

Isn't Life Fun? /s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309721437.0" user="brotherhood4232" delta="False">
    <text>I wish there was a  [Cursus honorum](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cursus_honorum)  for engineers...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309745209.0" user="Bizeran" delta="False">
    <text>I got something to note on his argument; I agree with it because creative jobs can’t reasonably be done with robots within the next couple decades.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309762801.0" user="Bl0bbydude" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not arguing the same point as OP, but I don’t take a strong issue with one thing you said. 

&amp;gt;I don’t think Welding/carpentry/plumbing/driving/factory working are going to continue to be occupations at all in 15 years. 

Technology is going to take a lot of jobs, AI is going to take a lot of jobs. But there’s still loads of jobs that just can’t be taken in the near timeframe. I mean seriously, in *15 years* you’re expecting robot plumbers and carpenters? Certainly things like driving and factory jobs will leave because they are fairly simple and repetitive, but a lot of jobs are either to unpredictable or too low paying to be replaced. (I mean, maybe in the far future, but 15 years is a fairly short timeframe.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
