<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503594194.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8btrrm/cmv_america_doesnt_need_more_stem_majors/">
    <title>CMV: America doesn't need more STEM majors.</title>
    <original_poster>brotherhood4232</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to follow the Reddit consensus that STEM = good and "basket weaving" majors = bad. I graduated with an electrical engineering degree myself. But after looking for a job myself, it doesn't seem like the job market could support a ton of more STEM majors.

I've seem very few job postings that said Entry Level. Most want 3\-5 years of experience and a host of qualifications that no new graduate will have. This means you are not only competing against other new graduates, but you are also competing against Mid\-Level STEM professionals. I think a flood of new STEM graduates would exacerbate this problem and a lot of those new engineers would be working at Starbucks. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30311143485.0" user="Special_Cattle" delta="False">
    <text>As a complete counterpoint, I got taken on as an experienced hire for a data analysis position at a major multinational straight out of my doctorate.  This is a position I knew nothing about, in a field I knew nothing about.  Companies, particularly large ones, will hire young talent and aged experience.

If you are not getting hired, you may be writing your CV in the wrong fashion, or you may be interviewing badly.  You should consider carefully how you come across both in person and on paper.

I appreciate that it is slightly different for a fresh university graduate, but perhaps that is a call for a Masters or PhD in your subject area.  The doctorate alone allowed me to skip my entire doctorate's worth of career progression without an issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30311159904.0" user="brotherhood4232" delta="False">
    <text>I would love to do grad school. Need some money first, haha. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30311164947.0" user="Special_Cattle" delta="False">
    <text>Then I highly recommend subsuming your desire for career progression and using that as a goal :)

While my PhD stressed me to hell and back, it has paid for itself five times over already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30311170360.0" user="brotherhood4232" delta="False">
    <text>I just need some money for living expenses. I’d like to work while finishing a masters. Then get a PhD if I still want to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
