<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326262038.0" user="justtogetridoflater" delta="False">
    <text>Activists should realise that playing the blame game altogether is turning people who would be allies in their cause. 

I think I'm going to have to disagree with this view on the basis that it doesn't go far enough. By the time the word privilege entered the conversation, it was already too late. 

If we stopped saying "White privilege" "Straight privilege" "Male privilege" an so on, I don't think that the argument would change fundamentally in any of these sections.

It seems to me that there is a certain group using these phrases because their argument goes like "You've been born into privilege, and we think you need to acknowledge that". And if it stopped there, we'd be alright. But it goes on. "You can't talk to us on this issue, you're straight. You've not had the same issues. You're white. You're cis. You're male". "These people are the enemy because they're possessing all the wealth and power, but aren't sharing it". Ok, great. Let me set up my torch stall. "These old straight white men have all this power". Now, let's be careful here. 

It's basically become like a mainstream conspiracy theory. You can't go around saying that Jews control the world, but old straight white men? 

And it's worth knowing that with identity politics in full force, some estimates say that the most left behind group is white, male, and working class. Because they don't get the support for being a girl. They don't get the support for being ethnic. But they didn't have anything to start with, so they have negative support. They're assumed to be alright for it, because white, and male, but in actual fact are being left behind by the assumption. 

And it's like that in universities. Men are outnumbered by quite a lot by women in university. But women are the oppressed ones, still. 

---

To some extent I think the biggest problem for these movements is a lack of a coherent vision of the utopia they want to head towards. And I think that lack of vision creates a lack of unity and hope for the movement, and then the anger and spite start to appear, and rather than talking about the big issues, it becomes privilege. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
