<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326206935.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>are you sure it's used to describe pure wealth disparities? I was under the impression it was used to describe things like the benefit of the doubt that cops and bank loan officers often give whites over blacks, which occur across all tax brackets. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326291022.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed that black people are disproportionately affected by those issues. But  plenty of white people have been the victim of police mistreatment and haven't even been rich enough to *try* to get a bank loan... so the phrase "white privilege" alienates them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326299291.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>but have they been the victim of police mistreatment *because they were white*? I very much doubt those are the circumstances surrounding any statistically significant amount of police mistreatment incidents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326379522.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>You would likely be wrong. Although on a per-capita basis, is might be lower the fact that 'white' makes up 73% percent of the US population. By pure numbers, there is more mistreatment of 'whites'.

I want to note, the source for 'whites' was the American Community Survey who defined whites as "A person having origins in any of the original peoples of Europe, North Africa (i.e. Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, Libya, and Egypt), and the Middle East (i.e. West/Southwest Asia, including Arabs, Assyrians, Bedouins, Jews, Kurds, Iranians; as well as Turkic peoples)." 

It is true of police shootings too. More 'Whites' are killed each year by police than others - again based on pure numbers.

The real problem with 'white privilege' is that some activists have taken a term from the academic environment, misused it and weaponized it. It is now 'acceptable' to dismiss arguments based solely on 'privilege' and to be told to 'check your privilege'. This 'privilege' concept is freely applied to individuals as if the concept really applied to that specific individual. 

When talking overarching social trends, it is perfectly sound and reasonable to talk about 'privilege'. When talking about individuals, it *is* derogatory. Individuals do NOT conform to the 'average' and do not have the 'average life experience'. You simply cannot treat individuals based on those 'averages' without applying racist stereotypes.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
