<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326231199.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. 

Do you believe that black and white persons with comparable backgrounds are always being treated equally? 

E.g. that when there are two job candidates (one black, one white) with similar experience and skills, employers are equally likely to hire the black candidate?

There have been tests that showed that resumes with "whitened" applicant names (and removal of other race indicators, like membership in organizations for black people) have a much higher chance of leading to an interview, than people with black sounding names and no race indicators.

This would be a counter-point to your claim that racism is  merely hardship from being rich or poor and that white privilege doesn't exist.

[Minorities Who 'Whiten' Job Resumes Get More Interviews](https://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/minorities-who-whiten-job-resumes-get-more-interviews)
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326338631.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; your claim that racism is merely hardship from being rich or poor

Clarifying question: what did I say that made you conclude that? I wasn't trying to say that at all. Racism can manifest in many ways, like when I mentioned police brutality and misconduct in my first paragraph.

And to address your point: yes, blacks do have a much harder time finding jobs. This is part of the racism I was talking about when I asserted that minority rights activists have legitimate concerns in their efforts. But I do not understand how this addresses my main point. There are plenty of white people out there who are un(der)employed in spite of this racism.

"Black disadvantage" would be a better term than "white privilege".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326623058.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Clarifying question: what did I say that made you conclude that?

When you said "There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white."

When you say that there is no privilege (solely) in being white, but in being rich, this suggests that you think that all else being equal, a black and a white person with comparable backgrounds, will face the same (dis)advantages.

&amp;gt;  There are plenty of white people out there who are un(der)employed in spite of this racism.

&amp;gt; "Black disadvantage" would be a better term than "white privilege".

The point of privilege is that even if you have black people and white people of similar backgrounds, black people are generally still going to have disadvantages.

Black disadvantage is equivalent to white privilege: all else being equal, white people don't face certain disadvantages (or to a lesser extent), which makes them privileged over black people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
