<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326367564.0" user="babygrenade" delta="False">
    <text>The term "white privilege" doesn't refer to financial means. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326374294.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry how does this challenge my view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326493719.0" user="babygrenade" delta="False">
    <text> Well, you assert that it alienates poor white people because out minimizes their struggles.

The term doesn't refer to white *financial* privilege though. It refers to differences in the way society treats whites and blacks. It describes implicit bias on a societal level.

&amp;gt; I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white

There is a privilege in being white. It's not having to deal with that societal implicit bias. 

The problem I think is that we often use the term privilege to refer to financial privilege, especially I  the context of saying someone "is privileged," but that's not the only manning.  Being tall is a privilege. Being smart is a privilege. 

You wouldn't say talking about the privilege of being tall, tall privilege if you will, minimizes the plight of poor tall people and alienates them. Being tall and being poor are separate issues. Sure being tall can help you earn more in the right circumstances, but it isn't going to pull you out of poverty by itself. 

White privilege doesn't really minimize the situation of poor whites because it's not strictly about poverty. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
