<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326341481.0" user="biggulpfiction" delta="False">
    <text>This is the most common misunderstanding of the notion of privilege. White privilege does not mean that bad things don't happen to white people. Many white people have horrific lives full of endless struggle and suffering -- that is not inconsistent with the concept of white privilege. The notion of white privilege is that many of the hardships non-white individuals face, they face BECAUSE they are not white. White people's hardships are not attributable to the fact that they are white, as opposed to some other race.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
