<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326215190.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>What would be a better term for the idea? Do you honestly believe that this new term would not aggravate anybody who is resistant to social activism?

This strikes me as a "climate change" kind of thing, where there was a deliberate attempt to shift the term to "climate change" and it hasn't made anything better but instead just given people who want to resist the research a means to say "see, you aren't even consistent".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326294049.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>I am not opposed to the term white privilege solely on the basis that it aggravates others; I am opposed because it aggravates others for no reason. If the term only aggravated people who were opposed to social change, I would support it; but the term aggravates poor white people whose plights are minimized by the term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326354752.0" user="Spaffin" delta="False">
    <text>Would “Minority disadvantage” be better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326373517.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. The term doesn't imply that whites have no disadvantage; it just brings up the specific issues disproportionately affecting minorities. Similar to the reason I support the phrase BLM; because it focuses on the plights of minorities rather than implicitly telling  white people they have no plights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326445895.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>But we've observed very clearly that "Black Lives Matter" is itself a divisive term. People have complained that the term focuses specifically on a minority group and ignores the broad picture. I absolutely guarantee that we'd see identical CMVs saying that activists should abandon the term "minority disadvantage" were we to use that term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30327180291.0" user="dpfw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What would be a better term for the idea?

Nothing. Don't argue privilege- argue policy. Argue for community policing and against the criminalization of homelessness. Argue for treatment over incarceration and argue against private prisons. Argue for a strong social safety net with universal healthcare and a welfare system that doesn't penalize work. Argue for education to be included in work requirements for welfare so that a poor person doesn't have to drop out of nursing school to qualify for food stamps. Argue for better schools funded based on the number of students and not property taxes- schools that can afford extracurricular activities that offer the sense of camaraderie that otherwise would have been provided by gangs, argue for easy access to contraception and abortion that is safe, legal, and rare. Take a strong stand against gang culture and in favor of marriage and the nuclear family. Argue in favor of offering training in skilled trades for low cost or no cost at all as a means to escape the cycle of poverty. 

The term "white privilege" is a losing issue, Drop it and fight for things that actually help minority communities. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
