<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326230044.0" user="Quint-V" delta="False">
    <text>I assume this is about the USA.

&amp;gt; There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

... while white privilege is perhaps a bad/vague term, it is used to point out the absence of discrimination against whites. It's nothing more than that.

"White privilege" per se is not an actual privilege. Rights are what everyone gets, but privileges are reserved to a handful few and given to those deemed sufficiently meritorious.

If we *compare* however, it certainly does seem like white people as a whole are privileged, though the proper conclusion is that non-whites are discriminated and often left on their own to deal with the systemic discrimination in place, with few representatives that work to solve their undeserved problems.

&amp;gt; while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

A typical argument people will resort to, is that there's an entire demographic that was oppressed. "Poor white people" is a subset of "white people". "Non-white" people **as a whole** have suffered massive amounts of discrimination and it is perfectly fair to point a big, black finger at that issue.

Black Lives Matter was met with responses like "All Lives Matter", but the problem with "All lives matter" is very similar to your own reservations against the term "white privilege". Yes, there are unfortunate people of all kinds, but you are not addressing the glaringly obvious issue that is far more prevalent. 

Imagine being the only one at the dinner table who hasn't been served yet, saying out loud "I deserve a warm meal", with the only reply being "Everyone deserves a warm meal". While it is true, such a statement implies a sentiment that willfully ignores the issue at hand, rather than addressing it and dealing with it; this is what infuriated the BLM movement and ultimately helped coin the term "white privilege".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326330529.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; he proper conclusion is that non-whites are discriminated and often left on their own to deal with the systemic discrimination in place, with few representatives that work to solve their undeserved problems.

Fully agreed. This is why I think "black disadvantage" or "minority disadvantage" would be a better term; because that term doesn't tell white people (at least explicitly) that they were privileged when they very well might not've been.

&amp;gt; Black Lives Matter was met with responses like "All Lives Matter", but the problem with "All lives matter" is very similar to your own reservations against the term "white privilege". Yes, there are unfortunate people of all kinds, but you are not addressing the glaringly obvious issue that is far more prevalent.

I don't blame you for the confusion, but I actually do support BLM &amp;gt; ALM. And here's why. BLM is not saying that "only black lives matter", or that "black lives matter more". The phrase and movement is designed to draw attention to the specific problems plaguing blacks; it is not designed to undermine the problems plaguing non-blacks. If we used the phrase "black disadvantage", that would be better and analogous to BLM in that sense.

&amp;gt; Imagine being the only one at the dinner table who hasn't been served yet, saying out loud "I deserve a warm meal", with the only reply being "Everyone deserves a warm meal". While it is true, such a statement implies a sentiment that willfully ignores the issue at hand, rather than addressing it and dealing with it; this is what infuriated the BLM movement and ultimately helped coin the term "white privilege".

Yes, you are right; shouting "everyone deserves a warm meal" is analogous to saying "all lives matter" in the sense that it ignores the issues the first person was bringing up. And BLM was right to be infuriated at the people who screamed ALM in response to them. But responding to that by shouting "white privilege" was unjustified, because while the term may accurately describe the ALMers who didn't understand what BLM was about, it doesn't describe all whites in America at all.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
