<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30355713938.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>Google already effectively serves as a filter towards the world. 

A few small changes to that filter - a few changes likely no one will see - and most of this problem goes away - its not like we'll notice. 

Google can do this - that is arguably the scary part. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355728071.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>im arguing that this is not a good thing.

that the solution to stupid speech is more speech. not just making other ideas go away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355906022.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>But our access to the world is already insanely heavily filtered. Millions of lines of code already block us from certain parts of the internet. 

Is there really a major difference between censoring 3 million websites relative to censoring 3.1 million websites?? 

If you use Google, you already are subjected to an insane about of censorship, what is 1 or 2 % more censorship at this point??? 

Its like trying to argue that 64 oz sodas are healthy but that 65 oz sodas are unhealthy - they are effectively indistinguishable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355915451.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>im not saying that is good either.

i do think many things should be regulated. just not speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355932129.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>But where is the harm??? 

You argue that fighting them causes more harm than good. If Google can fight them in an effectively invisible, undetectable way - where is the harm??? 

The only potential harm is allowing Google to effectively pick and choose which parts of the internet we see - but we already do that. There is no added harm. Thusly, its pure gain with minimal to no added harm. 

Edit: We've effectively already paid the price - at this point going up to the buffet a second time is effectively a free lunch, because we've already paid the piper. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355949132.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>the harm is 1984 style. a creeping restriction of thought. that we dont realize until it becomes extreme.

plus, just like this:
https://theintercept.com/2016/04/28/new-study-shows-mass-surveillance-breeds-meekness-fear-and-self-censorship/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355978735.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>And How did you find that article? Did you use Google?? Even if you went to theintercept.com and searched, their search (as is almost everyone else's) is powered by Google. 

If so, you've already bit the bullet. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355982807.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>i not saying that censorship doesnt exist, im saying i dont prefer it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
