<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30355800503.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confused about whether you think it's bad because you legit believe it'll cause bad outcomes, or if you think it's bad because you're ideologically opposed to what you see as threats to free speech, or both.

Whatever is the case, could you explain more?  Either say exactly what bad outcomes you perceive, or explain why you morally think it's bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355807437.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>sure. i think the threat to free speech is worse than the threat to the "objective" understanding of reality. i think a bad outcome is acceptable from time to time. and the best way is to address those bad outcomes is with other speech (rather than restricting speech).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355816190.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  i think the threat to free speech is worse than the threat to the "objective" understanding of reality.

OK, thanks for the clarification.

Could you explain what you believe free speech to be, and exactly what it means to violate it?  It doesn't match my idea of "threatening free speech" to label something untrue as untrue, or to set up an algorithm such that it shows up on the second page of results rather than the first.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
