<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30355739618.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>When Gutenberg's press first came out, democratized information was a nightmare. All of a sudden any literate person could potentially write a book. People had gotten so accustomed to books being so expensive (because it required an army of minks to make copies) that anything worth writing down was essentially guaranteed to be a respected source. 

People had to learn. We had to invent "authority". Not everyone that was an author was an authority. Certain people *earned* a reputation that their work held up to scrutiny and time and those people were more trusted than a relatively unknown source. 

We need to relearn this lesson with comments and "news" sources. The internet democratized news and we need to relearn the lesson of trust. 

Recognising probable sources of fake news is how this begins to happen. We absolutely need to know what is signal and what is noise. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355752320.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>i dont thin you are disagreeing with me. im not saying that we shouldnt know "trusted" sources, we absolutely should. even, it would be fine if there were efforts to provide credibility to sources, like apple news is trying to only provide trusted sources. but this is only a reasonable option because apple news isnt a major news source. i dont think there should be an effort to remove less trusted sources. or even sources that are nefarious. 

for example, i dont think there was anything wrong with wikileaks publishing the clinton emails.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355756776.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if we start picking what is fake and what is real we will have a slippery slope. 

I absolutely disagree with this. We definitely need to pick what is fake and what is real. That's our duty here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355767645.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>let me rephrase. as an individual, i think it's perfectly fine for you to decide which news you are interested in or not. and i think as humans, we seek truth, so we will discern "fake" from real news on our own. but i do not want a systematic effort by google or facebook to do that for me.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355769591.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>Facebook systematically prefers and promotes fake news. Is that a problem?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355771250.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>i should be neutral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355773539.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>So then we need to make an effort to correct for the natural tendency to [favor the spread of fake news](https://www.nbcnews.com/news/amp/ncna854896) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355788233.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>but of course lies spread faster. it's just sensational. like, if i said you were an ax murderer, that would be eye catching. and while stupid, it's acceptable to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355832414.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>So when you say it should be nuertral... Thay is in direct conflict with this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355836844.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>i mean, treat all info the same, regardless of the outcome. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30356424719.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>But we don't. Social networks are biased as to how they treat the info. They promote fake news. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
