<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30357639510.0" user="TheGumper29" delta="False">
    <text>To some degree this is what Russian trolls want. That essentially the fake news and real news become so inexplicably hard to separate that essentially nothing becomes true. We are forced to live in a reality with multiple conflicting things that are "true" that simultaneously cannot be fully believed. When that happens anything becomes possible. It is what is described as The Wilderness of Mirrors.

I am not for censoring things on account of their veracity and generally agree that trying to weed out real vs fake news has some serious issues. However, can't we just say that Russian intelligence services are acting with hostility towards us and we just block all of it as a form of self defense? Censor things based on the origin of the source rather than their ideas?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
