<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30355931533.0" user="helloitslouis" delta="False">
    <text>These trolls are organised, they‘re using multiple accounts on Twitter, YouTube, facebook etc where they brigade.

They push hashtags into trends, they brigade likes on facebook posts, they can make or break a video on YouTube.

Popular hashtags get picked up by the media as „people think that...“, a brigaded video on YouTube will end up in the popular algorithms and be recommended to a lot of people, your average Joe is going to be influenced by the most liked comment on that facebook post he cares about.

This is not just some randos posting shitty memes on t_d or 4chan, this is *active* influencing of what the media will see and report as the „public‘s opinion“.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355968013.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>but that's the price we have to pay.

stupid things can be popular. why not ban bullshit about the kardashians? that's more detrimental to society than even lies about politics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355991533.0" user="helloitslouis" delta="False">
    <text>The price for what, exactly?

Look, here‘s a little comparison:

Bullshit about the Kardashian gets popular because a lot of people seem to care about them.

Bullshit hashtags from the alt right get popular because *a few people with many accounts are pushing them into the most popular hashtags to give the impression that a lot of people care about these things*.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
