<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30355756245.0" user="sweetjeebs" delta="False">
    <text>We might have different definitions of "tolerating," "fighting," and "combat" because my definition of "not fighting fake news" would be to sit back and do nothing at all in response to fake news. Why not fight fake news by calling it out, discrediting it and posting counter points? You might have addressed that in some form with your last sentence about "more real news," but I dont think the mere existence of non-fake news does anything if fake news isnt adequately called out. 

  To me, "tolerance" means, "Well, yeah. Jimmy read online that Stanley Kubrick faked 9/11 under orders from Bush, but that's just his opinion and who am I to judge?" And a lack of tolerance toawrds fake news would be, "Jimmy, where the hell did you read that, because Kubrick was dead, 9/11 really happened and theres literally no evidence that Bush did it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355766408.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>let me rephrase. as an individual, i think it's perfectly fine for you to decide which news you are interested in or not. and i think as humans, we seek truth, so we will discern "fake" from real news on our own. but i do not want a systematic effort by google or facebook to do that for me.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
