<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="509235606.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8f6opi/cmv_for_the_most_part_fake_news_and_russian/">
    <title>CMV: for the most part, fake news and russian trolls should be tolerated, because the fighting them causes more harm than good.</title>
    <original_poster>shijfmxew</original_poster>
    <original_post>there are a lot of posts lately about fake news and russian trolls. I know this has a lot of impact on public opinion and causes many people to misunderstand the world, and even gets ping pong shops shot up by idiots.

That said, it is my view that any effort to combat fake news by edit it, or by censoring it, it worse than having it just exist. it is my contention that if we start picking what is "Fake" and what is real, we will get to a slippery slope that will inevitably restrict our discourse more than would happen if we just allowed idiots to say their piece (even if they dont have good intent)

*i do think the best way to fight fake news is with more real news, but that's not what this argument is.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30355896533.0" user="10twenty4" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever heard of the [Paradox of tolerance](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paradox_of_tolerance)? To be tolerant, one paradoxically has to be *intolerant* of those with intolerant views, as otherwise the intolerant will abuse the good faith of the tolerant to take over.

Free Speech is similar. Russian trolls and fake news are chipping away at the foundation of free speech, in an incredibly insidious way. Trollls don't argue in good faith. Their ultimate goal is to destroy faith in the very concept of discussion itself. Through their gish-gallops, contradictory and half-baked "arguments", and fake news, they seek to hide the truths they don't like in a deluge of shitposts.

So in a sense, trolls are abusing free speech in order to *censor* free speech. How can we possibly have a meaningful dialogue if we all suspect each other of spreading fake news? If we're all so weary of sifting through bullshit that we no longer even care about finding truth? 

And thus, like the paradox of tolerance, we cannot be tolerant towards them. If we have a way to reliably filter them out, we should take advantage of it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30355913301.0" user="shijfmxew" delta="False">
    <text>i could make the same argument about idiots or republicans (largely the same thing). They arent having meaningful discussion. they are too stupid to have good faith discussions. they believe incredibly stupid things.....

that said, it's just better to let them have their stupidity than to censor them. yes, they are destroying the country. yes, they are making us more sick, more poor, more intolerant...

well, maybe we should censor republicans. hmm

honestly though, it's just better to beat them at their own game. you cant make the concept of discussion worthless. that's just silly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30356313563.0" user="DakkaMuhammedJihad" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re misunderstanding what good faith and bad faith imply in this context. At some point, most American republicans belief in and support what they perceive to be the values of the Republican Party. Even if they make individual arguments in bad faith because they’re attempting to do something sly with their opponent, they still believe in *something* that they’re advocating for.

For the Russian troll farm, this could not be further from the truth. Everything they do is a performance. There are techniques, talking points, probably even scripts. This is not about the goals of a political party, their sole aim is to introduce absolute, unmitigated chaos to the point that nobody can believe anything anymore because there is so much noise nobody can find the signal anymore. Ridiculous, outlandish, obvious lies that play on the basest human emotions to land with outsized effects.

They just happen to have found the most support and amplification within the Republican Party. 

The same things are not being said about these two groups. Not at all. T</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30357089218.0" user="Swiss_Army_Cheese" delta="False">
    <text>If you can't beat a troll in an argument, then that just shows you suck at arguing or that you're position is in the wrong. Whether a troll genuinely believes in what they are saying is irrelevant, and if they don't then that should make things easy for you.

I used to think Gaddaffi must go just like the rest of the people, but one day I said "Silly Americans: Everyone knows tanks can't fly! So why are you destroying them", and "Silly NATO, flying in a no-flyzone", thinking that they were perfectly justified in doing so and I was simply ignorant of the legalities behind it. Didn't realise this was mission creep until I failed to get other people to explain how it wasn't.

They're not destroying the concept of discussion. They're demonstrating that you can't think criticly of the information you are reading and checking for any slants. The one damaging the discussion is the one saying that there can't possibly any other narrative or explanation for events.

Last time I checked the West is not at war with Russia, and Russia's not at war with the west.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30357548125.0" user="10twenty4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you can't beat a troll in an argument, then that just shows you suck at arguing or that you're position is in the wrong.

You can't 'beat' a troll in an argument. You're doomed from the start if you even try. Unlike someone with a legitimate viewpoint, they're not trying to win, they just want to makes things as confusing as possible. There's no actual win condition in that situation. For each well thought out source and point you can leverage, they'll throw out two dozen half-baked points, every single one of them bullshit. If you ever think you've won, they're perfectly happy to circle back around and try again, as often as you want. They want to make everyone so weary of trying to sort out the lies that no one cares anymore. 

And yes, I realize the irony of saying, "stop trying to argue with trolls, because they want to make everyone stop caring." All I mean is, learn to recognize when it's happening, because there's no possible benefit for you. Continue to think critically, seek out alternative views, and all that. Just don't feed the trolls.

And when it's possible to identify them, there's nothing wrong with taking trolls down. And it's very possible, as Russian trolls do often have recognizable patterns, plus there's information we're not privy to which a site's administration might have.

Let people learn about thinking critically from people who are actually acting in good faith.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
