<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="510392670.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8fvhi6/cmv_ocd_doesnt_have_to_be_debilitating/">
    <title>CMV: OCD doesn't have to be debilitating</title>
    <original_poster>lookslikeamirac</original_poster>
    <original_post>A lot of people get ticked off a bit when someone says something like "I'm OCD about _____" because they don't think it's legitimate and they see it as undermining what people with 'real' OCD go through.

I understand that maybe it seems insignificant to someone who has to wash his or her hands 20 times before bed, but it doesn't mean it's not some degree of OCD.

A hypothetical situation:

There's a guy who always leaves the volume on an even number when he changes it. When he turns on the TV though, he doesn't check to make sure it's an even number. So if it's already odd when he turns it on, then it's fine.

He changes the volume and sets it to an even number. Then, his friend changes it to odd and steals the remote. It doesn't prevent the man from watching TV, but it makes him slightly uncomfortable because he knows it's odd and he asks for the other guy to change the volume to an even number. The man refuses, and both men go on watching TV leaving the first man a little uneasy. After a while, the friend goes to the bathroom and forgets about the remote/volume, and the first guy steals the remote back to change it back to even.

My claim is that the guy may still have OCD since it makes him feel uncomfortable. It doesn't mean he *has to* change the volume back but he'd greatly prefer it be on an even number and gives some small anxiety when he knows that's not the case. It's enough that the friend forgot about it, but he remembered and immediately changed it on the first opportunity. 

To change my mind please provide evidence that my situation or a similar one *can't* be OCD. There may be no way around a semantic argument since we're dealing with medical terms, but try to avoid it if possible. 

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30365427595.0" user="Miguelinileugim" delta="False">
    <text>I have a not very severe, but not particularly mild either, case of OCD. And no it's not fun to wash your hands 20+ times a day, have to adjust things to perfection on occasion or having to deal with intrusive thoughts and a general sense of discomfort at random.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30365794760.0" user="wartoffevil" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not trying to diminish the pain you experience as part of this disorder, but do most people not wash their hands more than 20 times a day?

I had an interesting discussion with a psych one day about OCD, and what he said strikes a chord with what you are saying about the general discomfort. He said to me that I was suffering something similar, that people with OCD are afflicted by doubt, and that doubt can manifest itself in a form that allows for tangible control, like hand washing or checking locks, but that even if you resolved the supposed physical realities behind those decisions (removed hands, let’s say, and hired a doorman), the underlying painful condition would still remain. That is the disorder, not the manifestations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30365853835.0" user="lookslikeamirac" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ... the underlying painful condition would still remain. That is the disorder, not the manifestations.

I think this is the best description I've read so far to make a distinction between the feeling and the way it manifests itself in the behavior of a person with OCD.

However, I think this strengthens my particular argument.  If the feeling is present without a manifestation in a physical act which would make it debilitating, wouldn't that still be OCD?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30365872759.0" user="wartoffevil" delta="False">
    <text>I think others in this discussion have noted, and the same would hold true of many other issues like this, that it often comes down to a subjective assessment of feelings. I can expect to experience pain or sadness or fear similarly to you, but I can’t actually know that I do. So we use weak tools like language to try to gain at least a somewhat accepted frame of reference we can all operate from. At a certain point, OCD is only a disorder if and when the effect crosses a certain discomfort and pain threshold, and that can occur with no physical manifestations. Based on a subjective assessment of pain levels, the obsessive compulsive nature of the individual crosses into the disorder definition only if it brings pain. 

And that’s why some people find it inherently offensive to refer to non-painful compulsions as OCD. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
