<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="510392670.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8fvhi6/cmv_ocd_doesnt_have_to_be_debilitating/">
    <title>CMV: OCD doesn't have to be debilitating</title>
    <original_poster>lookslikeamirac</original_poster>
    <original_post>A lot of people get ticked off a bit when someone says something like "I'm OCD about _____" because they don't think it's legitimate and they see it as undermining what people with 'real' OCD go through.

I understand that maybe it seems insignificant to someone who has to wash his or her hands 20 times before bed, but it doesn't mean it's not some degree of OCD.

A hypothetical situation:

There's a guy who always leaves the volume on an even number when he changes it. When he turns on the TV though, he doesn't check to make sure it's an even number. So if it's already odd when he turns it on, then it's fine.

He changes the volume and sets it to an even number. Then, his friend changes it to odd and steals the remote. It doesn't prevent the man from watching TV, but it makes him slightly uncomfortable because he knows it's odd and he asks for the other guy to change the volume to an even number. The man refuses, and both men go on watching TV leaving the first man a little uneasy. After a while, the friend goes to the bathroom and forgets about the remote/volume, and the first guy steals the remote back to change it back to even.

My claim is that the guy may still have OCD since it makes him feel uncomfortable. It doesn't mean he *has to* change the volume back but he'd greatly prefer it be on an even number and gives some small anxiety when he knows that's not the case. It's enough that the friend forgot about it, but he remembered and immediately changed it on the first opportunity. 

To change my mind please provide evidence that my situation or a similar one *can't* be OCD. There may be no way around a semantic argument since we're dealing with medical terms, but try to avoid it if possible. 

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30366917255.0" user="Throwaway98709860" delta="False">
    <text>No psychiatric disorder is defined biologically. Conditions like OCD are hypothesized and specified entirely by subjective means (aggregating interviews with patients). Therefore, there is not a definitive way to determine which situations are certainly OCD and which certainly are not. There are general patterns and trends of symptomatolgy which a situation can be compared to, but no objective diagnostic criteria. There is actually debate about whether or not a variety of seemingly similar disorders (trichotillomania, body dysmorphic disorder, Tourette's syndrome etc) are actually forms of OCD - and if not, how they might be related. Therefore, there is really no way to say definitively whether or not the hypothetical situation you described is OCD - this stuff is just not hard science.

To the main point about OCD not being debilitating, I think my answer is just that it generally is. Sure, it probably doesn't have to be. You can probably find many subclinical cases in which a person has some symptoms but they are very modest. However, in most cases that are reported (and to be fair, the ones that are reported and treated are incidentally going to be the more severe ones) patients often have their lives ruined. For example, famed mathematician Kurt Godel is thought retrospectively to have had OCD. He had a constant fear of being poisoned (a pretty common OCD manifestation). His primarily compulsion was that he would only eat food that his wife prepared. At one point, his wife got very sick and was in the hospital for several months. Godel decided he just wouldn't eat - the fear of being poisoned was too horrifying to risk. He ended up dying of starvation. If you read the stories of people with OCD, while not often quite as severe as that of Godel, they are much more similar to his tragedy than the hypothetical example you gave.

I actually have OCD and it doesn't really bother me much when people say things like "I'm so OCD about cleaning my bathroom". It just indicates that they don't know much about the disorder. But, the reason people do find it offensive is that it depicts the disorder as something much more benign than it usually is. It's kind of like saying "Wow, I had four beers last night, I'm such a drug addict". </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
