<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="511944139.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8gsqmj/cmv_people_forgo_their_right_to_complain_if_they/">
    <title>CMV: People forgo their right to complain if they never do anything about it</title>
    <original_poster>ooselfie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a few friends that complain about their life ALL the time. I hear things like:

"My job sucks, I'm miserable here"

"God school sucks, I'm studying something so uninteresting"

I think they have total control - it comes down to laziness, or perhaps they don't even really want anything to happen. It is so easy to put in some extra effort in your day to make things happen for yourself. They complain and complain but never do anything to change. It's like the boy who cried wolf. 

If you constantly complain, but do nothing to mend the problem, then you shouldn't be allowed to complain. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30378046276.0" user="waycooladenu" delta="False">
    <text>I want to get a drivers license I can’t complain about how drivers ed sucks and taking the test sucks? What about taxes? I can not pay them but then I’ll be complaining about jail lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378059842.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>I guess the focus is more so on things that are in your control: like, losing weight, finding another job, finding an SO, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378114008.0" user="waycooladenu" delta="False">
    <text>Let’s take our school studies being boring for example I didn’t love every class I took in college but I graduated with the degree I wanted and now have the job I wanted and it was worth it. You can be damn sure I complained about the classes being boring and uninteresting as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378131057.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>Well how about we take your scenario and flip it a little?

What if it's a degree that you don't want and potentially in a market that you don't have interest in? Your complaints are the same: I hate these classes, I hate school, I don't even know why I'm studying this. 

-Why don't you...try some other classes?

-Why don't you...change majors?

-Why don't you...pursue some other skill set?

-Why don't you...a million other things?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
