<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="511944139.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8gsqmj/cmv_people_forgo_their_right_to_complain_if_they/">
    <title>CMV: People forgo their right to complain if they never do anything about it</title>
    <original_poster>ooselfie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a few friends that complain about their life ALL the time. I hear things like:

"My job sucks, I'm miserable here"

"God school sucks, I'm studying something so uninteresting"

I think they have total control - it comes down to laziness, or perhaps they don't even really want anything to happen. It is so easy to put in some extra effort in your day to make things happen for yourself. They complain and complain but never do anything to change. It's like the boy who cried wolf. 

If you constantly complain, but do nothing to mend the problem, then you shouldn't be allowed to complain. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30378024262.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>Complaining is healthy — it’s a release valve. If you can put your negative emotions into words they loose power. Often people complaining aren’t asking for a solution to their problem — they are just engaging in an activity that keeps them sane. All you have to do is listen to them, acknowledge their feelings, maybe complain a little about your own problems too. 

The people who don’t complain are the ones who should worry you — those are the people who suddenly snap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378031646.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that it's a release valve, but at what point do you draw the line? Constant complaining can feed a defeatist mindset, which is unhealthy.

Wouldn't it be much better energy spent funneling all the time you spend complaining, to doing something about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30379955932.0" user="deeman010" delta="False">
    <text>I sort of agree with the other guy cause the alternative would be people just doing what they wanted. If I wanted to quit, I would. If something upset me, I'd change it regardless of the effort required. If I was slightly inconvenienced by some random guy on the road and raged at him, I might actually kill him. 

Absorbing the emotions can be a better outcome for all than just acting on impulse. If I had less control, a lot of people would end up getting hurt. I imagine that it's the same for most people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
