<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="511944139.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8gsqmj/cmv_people_forgo_their_right_to_complain_if_they/">
    <title>CMV: People forgo their right to complain if they never do anything about it</title>
    <original_poster>ooselfie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a few friends that complain about their life ALL the time. I hear things like:

"My job sucks, I'm miserable here"

"God school sucks, I'm studying something so uninteresting"

I think they have total control - it comes down to laziness, or perhaps they don't even really want anything to happen. It is so easy to put in some extra effort in your day to make things happen for yourself. They complain and complain but never do anything to change. It's like the boy who cried wolf. 

If you constantly complain, but do nothing to mend the problem, then you shouldn't be allowed to complain. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30378107528.0" user="KittyHamilton" delta="False">
    <text>Complaining serves its own purpose: blowing off steam. It's a kind of social activity. You tell me about how incompetent your coworker is, I say, "Wow, what an idiot." I bitch about my cats ruining my blinds and you say, "That sucks."

It's also important to keep in mind that you rarely know everything about a person's life. Maybe you're only hearing the complaints and not the boring or positive bits, so you have a biased view, and the individual is satisfied overall with their place in life. (You see this sometimes on r/relationships, where someone complains to their friends/family about their SO, so they all have the impression the SO is an asshole, even when it's not the case) Maybe the person is stuck in their situation, at least temporarily. Then need to stay in their crappy job, or money is so tight they can't avoid to move out of their emotionally abusive parents' home yet. 

People have huge, complicated lives, involving money, family, friends, sex, hobbies, and  their own internal personal issues. They also have limited time and energy. It may well be that someone 'should' start addressing a particular problem, but if all their energy is being spent just keeping their head above water, acting might not be feasible at the moment.

More fundamentally, complaining in and of itself hurts no one, so why say people aren't allowed to complain?

Now, listening to someone complain is a kind of emotional labor. Complaining about the same problem excessively to a particular person, especially if one doesn't let the other vent about their own issues, is an unfair and exhausted situation most listeners.

When you empathize with a friend's problem, you take on a bit of their pain for yourself, and they have the relief of interacting with someone who sympathizes with their issue. When they keep complaining about the same thing to you, in a sense, their problem becomes your problem...but you have no way to fix it.

For some people, this is fine. For others, it's emotionally exhausting.

People have complicated lives, and there's nothing wrong with complaining about something without immediately trying to fix the problem. Sometimes complaining about those problems is what allows us to go face that same situation the next day.

_However_, because listening to someone complain is can be emotionally draining, people have a responsibility to make sure they are not draining their friends by constantly complaining about the same thing. Moderate how much you rant on a particular subject. 

And if a friend is constantly complaining about something and you're getting tired of hearing it, you have a right to express that hearing them talk about it so much is exhausting.

EDIT: Oh, and one more thing! There absolutely are people who complain constantly about their issues but make no attempts whatsoever to change their situation. People who refuse to take responsibility in life, or enjoy feeling like a victim, refusing any advice offered, etc. You may be dealing with some of these obnoxious people. I am only responding to the assertion that no one should complain if they aren't acting to mend the problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378155906.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It may well be that someone 'should' start addressing a particular problem, but if all their energy is being spent just keeping their head above water, acting might not be feasible at the moment.

I've always worked under the assumption that if you cared enough about something, you would do something about it. Almost regardless of your current situation. There's always a way to reasonably turn things around. 

&amp;gt;People have complicated lives, and there's nothing wrong with complaining about something without immediately trying to fix the problem. Sometimes complaining about those problems is what allowed us to go face that same situation the next day.

Why wouldn't people want to try and fix the problem if they feel so strongly to constantly complain about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378194723.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's always a way to reasonably turn things around.

Why do you believe that? Do you believe that there is no conceivable situation where someone can have such a horrible lack of agency that they aren't able to do anything to change their station? Like if I'm working 2 jobs and 90 hours a week to pay my bills because I have huge medical debt due to a health issue that popped up completely out of my control... there's no *good* option there that I can see. I could try to get a new job but in what spare time? I'm working almost every waking hour. I could go bankrupt but then good luck finding basically any housing should I have to move.

There are some people who get well and truly fucked, and even if a solution *exists*, they might be in too deep to *see it* and need to complain to someone who might be able to help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378512545.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Like if I'm working 2 jobs and 90 hours a week to pay my bills because I have huge medical debt due to a health issue that popped up completely out of my control... there's no good option there that I can see. I could try to get a new job but in what spare time? I'm working almost every waking hour. I could go bankrupt but then good luck finding basically any housing should I have to move.

Honestly...I don't. In your example, I feel like there are better ways to pay off a huge medical debt than just working 2 jobs @ 90 hours a week. It's all about working smarter not harder. Maybe you can refinance that debt into a low interest investment vehicle which can offset the aggressive fee schedule. There are also ways to make money off social media platforms like Instagram that don't require 90 hours a week, would most likely pay more, and at a lower barrier to entry. You can rebrand yourself quickly - perhaps work at a startup at lower pay and use that to build your portfolio or skillset, etc. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378521270.0" user="Qwerty_Resident" delta="False">
    <text>Working at a startup is awesome if you have a trust fund and a fallback. It's not great if you need money right now.

Refinancing debt is great if you can do it. Lenders are under no obligation to work with you if they want to be dicks.

If I don't have skills that pay well, gambling on making a name for myself on social media is just that: gambling. Many many more people fail to make a living on that than succeed.

Do you think that these ideas just *don't occur* to people in dire financial straits? Usually they do and there are circumstances that make it just unworkable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378258193.0" user="KittyHamilton" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've always worked under the assumption that if you cared enough about something, you would do something about it. Almost regardless of your current situation. There's always a way to reasonably turn things around.

That's a very optimistic attitude, but you have to remember you aren't these people. You don't know what is most important to them, in their heart of heart's.  Also, even if there is a reasonable way to turn things around, that doesn't mean it's easy. It may take a long time, and you may not be hearing about those attempts.

Complaining about something a lot doesn't necessarily mean they feel truly strongly about something. Many people won't speak about their biggest issues openly. I like to complain about tumblr fandom drama. I can go on long epic rants about it, but it's nothing I can fix, realistically, and it certainly isn't that important in my life. I just like ranting sometimes.

And again, limited time and energy. There may be reasons the person is not acting to try to solve a particular problem at this point in time. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
