<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="511944139.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8gsqmj/cmv_people_forgo_their_right_to_complain_if_they/">
    <title>CMV: People forgo their right to complain if they never do anything about it</title>
    <original_poster>ooselfie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a few friends that complain about their life ALL the time. I hear things like:

"My job sucks, I'm miserable here"

"God school sucks, I'm studying something so uninteresting"

I think they have total control - it comes down to laziness, or perhaps they don't even really want anything to happen. It is so easy to put in some extra effort in your day to make things happen for yourself. They complain and complain but never do anything to change. It's like the boy who cried wolf. 

If you constantly complain, but do nothing to mend the problem, then you shouldn't be allowed to complain. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30378016949.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>I'f I'm in a bad situation, but all my alternatives are worse, I shouldn't be allowed to verbally acknowledge my situation is bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378035672.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that ALL alternatives are worse. I don't think that definitive scenario truly exists, especially in a work type capacity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378052238.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>What alternatives reasonably exist?  If you just go "Oh yeah, stop being lazy and it'll work out!" then it's easy to "know" that good alternatives exist, but how much of this assumption of yours is based on knowing about job markets and contracts vs. your ideological position? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378078845.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>Well stop being lazy is definitely the first step. It's about putting in the effort to conduct that due-diligence - just to try. There's a market out there for most things if you're creative + hard working enough. You can brand and position yourself in anyway. 

Many of my conversations with my friends start and end with something like a complaint about their current situation, my probing and providing alternatives, them agreeing it's a good idea but admitting to those alternatives being too "difficult," me offering to help anyway, them never following up then complaining about the same exact situation weeks later. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378095809.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's a market out there for most things if you're creative + hard working enough. 

See, here's the problem.  *literally anything is possible* if you're creative and hard working *enough.*  Someone who's creative and hard working enough can invent a machine that lets them live forever.  There is no theoretical upper limit to creativity and hard workingness.

That's why this vague "creative enough" talk is meaningless.  What matters is the amount of creativity and hard work *that could be reasonably demonstrated* by *this individual* at *this time*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378135601.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What matters is the amount of creativity and hard work that could be reasonably demonstrated by this individual at this time.

And you're saying that the best that some individuals can "reasonably demonstrate" is literally nothing? No way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378334006.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>You just implied there is *nothing in between* "literally no creativity" and "enough creativity to succeed."

Do you really endorse this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378516960.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>Yes because it is not that hard to be reasonably successful IMO. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
