<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="511944139.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8gsqmj/cmv_people_forgo_their_right_to_complain_if_they/">
    <title>CMV: People forgo their right to complain if they never do anything about it</title>
    <original_poster>ooselfie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a few friends that complain about their life ALL the time. I hear things like:

"My job sucks, I'm miserable here"

"God school sucks, I'm studying something so uninteresting"

I think they have total control - it comes down to laziness, or perhaps they don't even really want anything to happen. It is so easy to put in some extra effort in your day to make things happen for yourself. They complain and complain but never do anything to change. It's like the boy who cried wolf. 

If you constantly complain, but do nothing to mend the problem, then you shouldn't be allowed to complain. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30379920234.0" user="HerbertWigglesworth" delta="False">
    <text>School curriculum is a difficult one, while there is a breadth in the later years to do your own research, you are generally bound by a pretty restrictive marking system, with more of  regurgitation approach to teaching / learning / demonstrating / working, as both a student and teacher.

Some people find what they are being taught dull, uninspiring and find it difficult to see the relevance of the work they are doing to the real world. 

Children can give feedback to teachers and to parents, but they rarely have any influence until they get older. Teachers are obliged to meet marking criteria, steer children down a specific route to optimise freedom of expression / curiosity, with ensuring the kids get a decent grade. When you are younger, learning the fundamentals is deemed more important, as it is consistent and standardised, indulging the personal considerations of each child in a class of X students, is extremely difficult.

Also, student experience outside of curriculum is not homogenous, some teachers are shit, some parents are uninspired and not caring, and yes some students are arseholes. However, the job of the system is to attempt to cater for as many students as possible, it's a flawed system, but one that is continuously developing, but is different in every single school in the world, for every teacher, and every student.

We complained a lot in school, our efforts only really had any weighting once we reached the age of 16, by this point most students have already established interests, or the lack thereof, and decided how they engage with school. It is not too late for change to occur, but kids are then in a very important phase of their life, of questioning their identity, shaping it, and expressing themselves and their concept of freedom and autonomy.

I think school is a bad example for your CMV, as everyone's experience is unique, and the level of capacity people have to make change varies.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
