<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="511944139.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8gsqmj/cmv_people_forgo_their_right_to_complain_if_they/">
    <title>CMV: People forgo their right to complain if they never do anything about it</title>
    <original_poster>ooselfie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have a few friends that complain about their life ALL the time. I hear things like:

"My job sucks, I'm miserable here"

"God school sucks, I'm studying something so uninteresting"

I think they have total control - it comes down to laziness, or perhaps they don't even really want anything to happen. It is so easy to put in some extra effort in your day to make things happen for yourself. They complain and complain but never do anything to change. It's like the boy who cried wolf. 

If you constantly complain, but do nothing to mend the problem, then you shouldn't be allowed to complain. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30378036622.0" user="jazzarchist" delta="False">
    <text>I have never understood this, like, what do you mean "not allowed?" Like, should I suffer a tangible penalty if I complain about the job I'm stuck in with no leverage to do "anything" about? Who organizes that system? Who enforces it?

This is such a weird, creepy, autocratic sentiment when you deconstruct it.

I'm not allowed to COMPLAIN!? I'm not allowed to SPEAK out LOUD to myself or other human beings? Like, who says?! YOU?!

I hear this view a lot and it honestly breaks my brain, like, the hubris here is outrageous. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378054827.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>Since you're focusing so heavily on diction, why don't you describe a *realistic* scenario where an individual has absolutely "no leverage" to do "anything" about it?

&amp;gt;I'm not allowed to COMPLAIN!? I'm not allowed to SPEAK out LOUD to myself or other human beings? Like, who says?! YOU?!

You are missing the point. It's not that people aren't allowed to complain, my contention is with people who constantly complain about the same thing, but don't enact any changes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378079020.0" user="jazzarchist" delta="False">
    <text>I think an underlying issue here is that a lot of effort people make in their lives are invisible couple with the fact people are more likely to say something like "ugh today sucked, i hate my job, it fucking sucks" rather than "ugh today sucked, i hate my job, it fucking sucks, good thing i applied to a few jobs last night, and i saw some other jobs today i might look into after work."

Sometimes, things are the way they are and they suck and it sucking can be "ok." 

Like, my job annoys the hell out of me and I complain about it daily, but honestly, my job is fine. I love the people I work with, it's not exactly difficult, etc. but good lord, I have some customer service responsibilities that drive me fucking crazy and sometimes they're as ridiculous and funny as they are maddening so when I'm with friends, I'll want to complain about it 1.) because it's therapeutic, 2.) my friends are gonna laugh their ass off when I tell them about the insane thing I dealt with today.

Complaining doesn't necessarily mean a huge change has to take place. Life is more complicated than that, even things I love I complain about. So there's also an issue of not WANTING to make a change, but goddamn sometimes you gotta vent about the things that stress you out.

So sometimes changes can't be enacted. There is nothing I can do about dealing with shitty customer service conflicts at work. They're going to happen, and I have to deal with them. But I don't want to quit or change jobs,  because that's just one piece of a whole in my working life, for example. So I guess we're getting down to "should be be allowed to complain AT ALL?" </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378106498.0" user="ooselfie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So sometimes changes can't be enacted. There is nothing I can do about dealing with shitty customer service conflicts at work. They're going to happen, and I have to deal with them. But I don't want to quit or change jobs, because that's just one piece of a whole in my working life, for example. So I guess we're getting down to "should be be allowed to complain AT ALL?"

yeah then I agree - the drivers behind what the complaint is about definitely matters. Again, my contention is with those who verbalize their desire of wanting something to change, complain about that specific thing, yet do absolutely nothing. In your case, it sounds like you have some inconveniences as a facet of your job, as we all do, but as you said "your job is fine."

What about if I am complaining about just being in the completely wrong industry, that it makes me depressed even being in this environment? Every time you see me, I share this exact same sentiment. You may offer advice, your perspective whatever, and I'll agree with you - you're probably right. Then next time I bring up the same thing, I actually didn't try anything you suggested or bothered with it, but my complaints are still the main focus of all our conversations. Wouldn't you feel like you...shouldn't complain if you're doing nothing about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378531962.0" user="tempaccount920123" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're missing a couple things of context:

1) For 90% of people, people don't mean what they say. 90% of the time. AKA talk is cheap.

2) People complain to others because "talking to yourself is weird". I'm guessing that you talk to yourself or think in your head a lot.

&amp;gt;Again, my contention is with those who verbalize their desire of wanting something to change, complain about that specific thing, yet do absolutely nothing.

I agree that it's a stupid verbal tic/stress dealing habit, but that's what it is. Those people are looking for empathy or using it as a conversation starter, but they wouldn't approach it like "Well, I meaningfully disliked hearing my boss ask me the same question today that he's asked me every week for the past month! How about you?".

Hell, most of the people that complain "Ughhhh my job succccccks" can't even remember what the hell happened last week. I run around with apparently one of the best memories of all time, or at least I pick up patterns that basically everyone else misses.

3) 

&amp;gt;What about if I am complaining about just being in the completely wrong industry, that it makes me depressed even being in this environment?

Woah, woah woah, that's not the same. This is *not* the same as complaining about the day to day. That's like "I think I want a divorce" kinda talk.

&amp;gt; I actually didn't try anything you suggested or bothered with it, but my complaints are still the main focus of all our conversations. Wouldn't you feel like you...shouldn't complain if you're doing nothing about it?

That's not what people are complaining about, or at least what they're trying to convey.

There's a joke from /r/talesfromtechsupport - "Go away or I'll replace you with a very small shell script.":

https://www.reddit.com/r/talesfromtechsupport/comments/32uzrk/my_first_day_on_the_job_and_i_accidentally_got/

***That's what you're talking about.***

But most people don't even *know* that the power to completely change a daily routine like that exists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378155106.0" user="ChicksLoveAJ1s" delta="False">
    <text>I think we both agree that these complainers should face no legal repercussions. Well the next best thing is social repercussions, and that comes down to YOU. Don't want them to complain to you, revoke your attention from them until they stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30378221367.0" user="caw81" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's not that people aren't allowed to complain, my contention is with people who constantly complain about the same thing, but don't enact any changes. 

If its not about preventing people from complaining, what do you want to happen if people complain and don't attempt any changes?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
