<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="514822279.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8iifev/cmv_history_would_have_largely_gone_better_if_the/">
    <title>CMV: History Would Have Largely Gone Better if the Nationalists had Won the Chinese Civil War</title>
    <original_poster>Kasunex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm aware that this is a tricky topic, so I'm sure the responses to this will be very interesting. Basically, I contend that, based on what we can assume, if the Nationalist Government of the Republic of China had put down the Communist Revolution, history would have gone better. Now "better" is a relative term, but I'll explain why I believe so.

First, the obvious. Mao Zedong's government killed around 45 million people. Some people put that number as high as 78 million, but either way, he's up there with Hitler and Stalin as one of the most brutal dictators and mass murderers in history. Chiang Kai\-Shek, on the other hand, was not exactly a benevolent ruler either; but the most excessive count I can find puts him as responsible for 18 million deaths. Still far too high, but far cry from Zedong. Let's also not forget that only about 2.8 million of those deaths were from corruption or political repression. The rest were the result of war. So; even if Chiang had continued corrupt and repressive policies in peacetime, that's still millions of lives saved right off the bat.

Secondly, there's the likelihood that the Republic of China would have reformed into a democracy. That's what it did on Taiwan after all, on top of becoming one of the "Four Asian Tigers". Let's not forget that, ideologically speaking, the Republic was only supposed to follow authoritarian policies until the country was stable and educated enough for democracy. Of course, there's no way of knowing whether or not the Kuomintang officials would have honored their pledge, and this also doesn't mean that the transition would have been smooth. But, it still seems likely that it would have happened eventually. Communist China is still a dictatorship today. I doubt the shallow, corrupt system that the Kuomintang perpetuated would have been so stable to the democratic wave of the late 80s and early 90s.

Third, there's the benefit for the rest of the world. With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently. North Korea would have been surrounded by American allies, and thus less likely to attack South Korea. But even if it had decided to do so, the only chance of victory it would have is if the West just didn't care enough to stop them. I'm aware that the only way America was able to get a coalition together from the UN was thanks to the Soviet Union boycotting over Taiwan, but let's be honest, it's not like America and South Korea couldn't have defeated North Korea on their own, especially if China was on their side. So, either no Korean War or a decisive Western victory. In a Western victory, Korea is united, all those killed by Kim Il\-Sung survive, and the united Korean Republic likely would be democratic as it became in our timeline. The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either not occur; or be a Western victory.

So there you have it. At the very worst case scenario, a few million would have survived. In the best case, millions would survive on top of two wars being prevented and China, Vietnam, and Korea becoming democratic. I am not saying that Chiang Kai\-shek was a good guy, or that he deserved to win, or that his wining would have suddenly turned Asia into a utopia. Just that, based on what evidence I have seen, a Nationalist China would have saved millions of lives and possibly spread democracy as well.

If you want a delta, remain respectful. Don't be condescending, don't try to claim that your argument is "just so obvious" or that anyone who disagrees is stupid, uneducated, etc etc. It annoys me enough when people do that in other arguments, and this is a very opinionated and complicated topic. Also, giving credit where credit is due and solid, concrete examples are huge pluses. That said; don't be upset if I don't give you delta; I don't always give them even when I like the points made.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30401255824.0" user="1standTWENTY" delta="False">
    <text>So. You make a solid argument but changing history is a very tricky subject. As one poster pointed out if China had gone nationalist war with Russia become a very distinct possibility.  There would be almost no chance America stays out and all of a sudden your “superior” future turns into WW3

Further that argument can be used in any direction, so perhaps if England had allowed Hitler to annex Poland, Hitler sticks with his original plan in Russia never goes to war with the west, Moscow capitulates and all of a sudden total WW2 deaths is 500,000 versus 73,000,000</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401269848.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if the only foreseeable benefit was less deaths than I would agree with you. However, in this case, the only *guaranteed* benefit is less deaths, but a likely benefit is the spread of democratic values across Asia. Would there be any such hypothetical additional positives in your WW2 scenario?

Besides, I also find it extremely difficult to believe that no country on Earth would eventually stand up to Hitler; at which point it becomes a bloodbath anyways. Plus, Jews would still be dying by the millions, so the death toll of the Holocaust would skyrocket. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401307821.0" user="1standTWENTY" delta="False">
    <text>I think your wrong. The reason hitler started the death camps was because the war was taking all of Germany’s resources and he wanted them gone   His original plan was always expulsion.  Further his war plans always ended at Russia.  He never wanted to be a warlord he simply wanted a strong Germany supported by Russian farms and oil fields.  I disagree there ever would have been a need to stand up to him</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401338496.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>I'm aware; I've written three college papers on the Holocaust.

It's true that Hitler's initial plans were initially towards expulsion and not extermination. However, considering how his plan was to round up all the Jews and send them to Madagascar, I can't imagine that would have ended much better. Besides, with Hitler at this point challenged only by the United States, I don't think he'd have any qualms about bullying the rest of the world; especially the Jews. 

Maybe there wouldn't be the Holocaust's sort of "iconic" death camps but it would be an extremely miserable world for anyone not German and I'm sure the Jewish death tolls would remain massive. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401332092.0" user="Waarivzrach" delta="False">
    <text>To get somewhat afield of the main point of discussion, I’m going to challenge that World War II hypothetical. Although by the time Hitler invaded Poland the Madagascar Plan (a plan to relocate all of the Jews in German territory to French Madagascar) was still on the table, it’s unlikely that the French would have made a decision different from the one they made in our timeline. This would mean the Final Solution is still likely to go forward in the occupied territory in Eastern Europe and even besides that, Nazi officials already had plans by 1939 to empty the eastern territories and turn the Slavic population into a slave race. So I think your proposal of 500,000 deaths is really not very much grounded in the history here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401429386.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't even think of the Slavs; great point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401546896.0" user="1standTWENTY" delta="False">
    <text>Ok this is point of debate. I will concede the point in Jews. However I will not concede the point about the overall war.  I repeat, he did not want to be a warlord, and with the exception of Russia he had no intent on other foreign territories.  Further  Stalin almost capitulated during the battle of Moscow.   He did not because he knew a lot of the Reich’s power was in France.  If hitler has most of his army I would strongly argue Stalin capitulates, Stalingrad never occurs, hitler overruns Russia and the war is basically over.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401578967.0" user="GarbledComms" delta="False">
    <text>One problem I have with this is that I believe that the Western opposition to Hitler wasn't just moral objection, but more importantly geopolitical.  The Western geopolitical opposition to Hitler was based on the concept of not letting any single power dominate Europe and Asia. A Germany that dominated everything between the Rhine and the Urals would be too powerful for the UK, France and USA to tolerate, Nazis or not.

For the same reason, if Chiang had managed to defeat the communists and hold China, I wouldn't be surprised to see the US suddenly start easing up on the Soviets.  Better to have the Eurasian land mass split between Europe, China, and a hemmed-in Russia than risk China swallowing up Siberia and becoming an Asian super-state.

Historically, Britain's #1 foreign policy goal was to prevent any continental power from dominating Europe because once a power no longer needed to fight adjacent land powers it could concentrate on building a navy that could directly threaten British soil. Likewise, the #1 US geopolitical goal is to prevent a power from dominating the Eurasian landmass such that it could marshal the resources to project transoceanic power that could threaten the US with invasion.  So long as the 'world island' is split between competing powers that have to worry about potential enemies on their borders, the US is safe.  Britain is in an analogous situation wrt Europe.  That's why those two countries have a "special relationship"- their geopolitical goals overlap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30402807050.0" user="1standTWENTY" delta="False">
    <text>That was a well thought out lengthy post, and I thank you for it, but unfortunately it is filled with your subjective opinion and is mostly a\-historical.  Much like WW1, England was dragged screaming into the war by the polish ambassador because they had a "Anglo\-Polish mutual defense alliance".  The English were terrified of how it would look to their allies is if they ignored their treaty.  Your grand theory is completely taken down when it is recalled the English themselves said that Hitler "could have Russia", so long as she left Poland alone.  

They were concerned about treaties, not who controlled Moscow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30403413635.0" user="GarbledComms" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they make the treaty in the first place?

And you criticizing me for being "subjective and a-historical" in an alt-history thread? Rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30403430378.0" user="1standTWENTY" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And you criticizing me for being "subjective and a\-historical" in an alt\-history thread? Rich. 

Fair point!

&amp;gt; Why would they make the treaty in the first place? 

Because Poland asked for it.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30403489687.0" user="GarbledComms" delta="False">
    <text>International relations ain't charity.  Britain and France aren't going to agree to a mutual defense pact with Poland just "because they asked".  They agreed because they had a goal in mind: to contain Germany.

As for overall historical context of my thesis concerning control of the continent and Britain's foreign policy, look at the Napoleonic Wars.  France was the most powerful continental power and was threatening invasion.  So what does Britain do? Put together a coalition of land powers to divert French efforts away from Britain directly.  When that coalition failed, they did it again for a total of 8 tries before finally permanently knocking out Napoleon.

In WW1, certain anti-French elements in Britain were indeed reluctant to commit to the Entente, but in the end they went anyway.  The overall reason the Entente was formed in the first place was to contain Germany, who were at the time (drum roll) the most powerful European power.

See the trend?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
