<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="514822279.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8iifev/cmv_history_would_have_largely_gone_better_if_the/">
    <title>CMV: History Would Have Largely Gone Better if the Nationalists had Won the Chinese Civil War</title>
    <original_poster>Kasunex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm aware that this is a tricky topic, so I'm sure the responses to this will be very interesting. Basically, I contend that, based on what we can assume, if the Nationalist Government of the Republic of China had put down the Communist Revolution, history would have gone better. Now "better" is a relative term, but I'll explain why I believe so.

First, the obvious. Mao Zedong's government killed around 45 million people. Some people put that number as high as 78 million, but either way, he's up there with Hitler and Stalin as one of the most brutal dictators and mass murderers in history. Chiang Kai\-Shek, on the other hand, was not exactly a benevolent ruler either; but the most excessive count I can find puts him as responsible for 18 million deaths. Still far too high, but far cry from Zedong. Let's also not forget that only about 2.8 million of those deaths were from corruption or political repression. The rest were the result of war. So; even if Chiang had continued corrupt and repressive policies in peacetime, that's still millions of lives saved right off the bat.

Secondly, there's the likelihood that the Republic of China would have reformed into a democracy. That's what it did on Taiwan after all, on top of becoming one of the "Four Asian Tigers". Let's not forget that, ideologically speaking, the Republic was only supposed to follow authoritarian policies until the country was stable and educated enough for democracy. Of course, there's no way of knowing whether or not the Kuomintang officials would have honored their pledge, and this also doesn't mean that the transition would have been smooth. But, it still seems likely that it would have happened eventually. Communist China is still a dictatorship today. I doubt the shallow, corrupt system that the Kuomintang perpetuated would have been so stable to the democratic wave of the late 80s and early 90s.

Third, there's the benefit for the rest of the world. With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently. North Korea would have been surrounded by American allies, and thus less likely to attack South Korea. But even if it had decided to do so, the only chance of victory it would have is if the West just didn't care enough to stop them. I'm aware that the only way America was able to get a coalition together from the UN was thanks to the Soviet Union boycotting over Taiwan, but let's be honest, it's not like America and South Korea couldn't have defeated North Korea on their own, especially if China was on their side. So, either no Korean War or a decisive Western victory. In a Western victory, Korea is united, all those killed by Kim Il\-Sung survive, and the united Korean Republic likely would be democratic as it became in our timeline. The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either not occur; or be a Western victory.

So there you have it. At the very worst case scenario, a few million would have survived. In the best case, millions would survive on top of two wars being prevented and China, Vietnam, and Korea becoming democratic. I am not saying that Chiang Kai\-shek was a good guy, or that he deserved to win, or that his wining would have suddenly turned Asia into a utopia. Just that, based on what evidence I have seen, a Nationalist China would have saved millions of lives and possibly spread democracy as well.

If you want a delta, remain respectful. Don't be condescending, don't try to claim that your argument is "just so obvious" or that anyone who disagrees is stupid, uneducated, etc etc. It annoys me enough when people do that in other arguments, and this is a very opinionated and complicated topic. Also, giving credit where credit is due and solid, concrete examples are huge pluses. That said; don't be upset if I don't give you delta; I don't always give them even when I like the points made.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30401844241.0" user="martqin" delta="False">
    <text>First I have a few problems with things you presented as facts. Mao did not kill 45 million people, 45 million people died in a famine. While you can attribute these deaths to Mao’s policies, it was caused by 3 years of bad weather. I’m not saying that Mao was not responsible for some people’s deaths through his poor political decisions, but if one looks historically at agrarian societies famines normally kill large swaths of the population. Even just in the 1690’s 10% of Scotland, ~8% of France, 20% of Estonia, and 30% of Finland all died in famines. While the almost 300 years looks significant, in practical terms China was very much in the same place agriculturally. Again, I’m not saying that Mao didn’t increase the severity of it, but it was a fairly normal thing for a pre-industrial society to have a famine that killed a lot of people, and if you are minimizing the short duration of the nationalist government and saying they really only killed 2.8 million, I feel as if I can do the same with Mao’s.

I agree on the democracy front, there is a greater chance that China would’ve remained democratic, although I’m not sure it would’ve been a great democracy. While this is entirely speculative, I think it would’ve largely ignored a lot of the rural populations (which was the vast majority of the country) and only really focused on the urban minority, as that is where most of the political leaders were from at the time. As much as people hate Mao’s policies, the cultural revolution led to a lot of positive results for the rural communities. If this interests you I’d recommend The Unknown Cultural Revolution (I can’t remember who wrote it... Dongpin something?), you can find a PDF of it online.

You also speak negatively about how China was communist aligned. Personally I see no problem with this and think most of the problems related to that are really related to American meddling. Speaking highly of Taiwan when (I believe that) China would be in the same place if the United States actually tried to help them, like they did Taiwan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401869971.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>The 45 million isn't my count. It was presented by a historian named Frank Dikötter. I am not him, nor am I a historian. So therefore I can't respond to your claim that the famine wasn't Mao's fault, except to point out that the suggestion that it wasn't doesn't seem to be a historical consensus. Besides; I do know from studying the Soviet Union that Communist policies can cause famines; look at the Holodomor for example. But again; I can't verify these facts because I am not the one who presented them. 

&amp;gt; You also speak negatively about how China was communist aligned. 

I'm not sure where I did that, except to point out that the Korean War and Vietnam War likely would have either not occurred or ended in a Western victory. This would have saved lives and possibly spread democracy as well. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401924289.0" user="martqin" delta="False">
    <text>I’m in no way arguing that 45 million people didn’t die, I’m saying that claiming Mao killed them is inaccurate. The Dikotter claim (although I haven’t read Mao’s Great Famine in ~4 years), which is one of the highest Great Leap estimates, is about starvation, unsafe working conditions, and government violence. His number for people killed by gouvernement violence was about 3 million (again if memory serves). I honestly can’t say anything that would redeem that, nor do I personally think it was a good choice. With respect to unsafe working conditions, they’re common in democratic countries. I have family from a small town in Quebec, where, suspiciously, a significant portion of men died of a cancer that has been tied to an unsafe mining operation. Seems like that happens (or at least used to during industrialization) here too. This leaves starvation, which I would argue was mainly caused by weather. Comparing it to a genocide in Ukraine caused by Stalin trying to keep Ukraine from leaving the Union is inaccurate. 

And you said it would’ve been beneficial to have an “anti-communist ally,” meaning that having a communist aligned China would be worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401938818.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I don't want to get bogged down in the Dikotter claim. I have no authority to defend it one way or the other. 48 million seems to be the average, run of the mill argument for historians on this topic, hence why I used it. Is it fair? That's not a conversation I'm capable of having.

&amp;gt;And you said it would’ve been beneficial to have an “anti\-communist ally,” meaning that having a communist aligned China would be worse.

"With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently."

In context, you'll see that this claim is not arguing China as anti\-communist is de\-facto better. The claim is that China allying with the anti\-communists would either prevent or lead to a swift and decisive end to the Korean War. Thus saving thousands of lives and possibly leading to a united, democratic Korea. The same could also occur with Vietnam, hypothetically. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30402473237.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Again, I don't want to get bogged down in the Dikotter claim. I have no authority to defend it one way or the other. 48 million seems to be the average, run of the mill argument for historians on this topic, hence why I used it. Is it fair? That's not a conversation I'm capable of having.

It's a pretty huge part of your indictment of Mao; if you're that unsure of it, are you sure about your premise in general?

Also, that may be the average among Western (*cough* making excuses for Western imperialism *cough*) historians, journalists and intelligentsia but not everyone sees it that way. As the other poster explained, famines happened through most of human history; we live in a very privileged time.

I think you might benefit from getting out of the western information bubble. I'm getting a vibe of, "communism is evil because it hurts people!" No political economic system we have tried hasn't had awful consequences. That's a human thing, not a communism thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30403047422.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>This isn’t a debate I am going to have. If we can’t agree that Mao killed 48 million then we’re not even on the same page. 

So as not to get bogged down in nitty-gritty details, I refuse to have debates about anything that I am not qualified to discuss. I trust the historians who have done massive amounts of research on this topic more than I trust some stranger on Reddit. I am aware some people disagree with these claims but I also know that people tend to be biased on this subject. 

As I can’t evaluate the truth for myself, I won’t discuss it. That’s all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404111275.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I trust the historians who have done massive amounts of research on this topic more than I trust some stranger on Reddit.

But not all historians agree.  Also, one could say the same about, say, Trump's corruption.  "I'm not qualified but I read 50 articles from Fox News saying Hillary is the real criminal so I won't talk about it!!"

Don't trust the random stranger on reddit but also don't blindly trust the western establishment, especially about something they have such a vested interest in being biased against.  You wanna have a whole conversation about how the world would be better off without Mao, expand your research.  I'm in the middle of [this](https://espressostalinist.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/battle-for-chinas-past.pdf) book, which gives a very different perspective.

&amp;gt;I am aware some people disagree with these claims but I also know that people tend to be biased on this subject.

Yes, people like those in the Western world, which has been having an ideological battle with communism for, like, 150 years.  Not only them, of course, but that's exactly my point.  That number is normal for the people explicitly supporting and arguing for the west and against communism.

If it's that important to your point (which I believe it is), you should balance your research with other sources.  As I've mentioned, I think you might have a tiny bit of a western bias.  It's cool; if you grew up in America, you basically can't help it.  But when you start throwing out numbers like 48 million kills for Mao, you need to check your sources thoroughly... and not regurgitate western propaganda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404201242.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Don't trust the random stranger on reddit but also don't blindly trust the western establishment, especially about something they have such a vested interest in being biased against.  

As you point out, better or for worse, I live in the West. Yes, the Western Establishment has a bias and agenda. So do you. So do the Communists. So does literally anyone we could possibly ask. We are going based off Western facts because a non-biased 3rd party does not exist and because I consider Western Historians living in countries where they can freely criticize their government more reliable than any Chinese Historian who is pressured against critiquing the Communist party. 

This whole line of thinking is a massive rabbit hole. I am basing my argument on the assumption that Western scholars are correct when they say Mao killed 48-70 Million. If that fact isn't true because of "Western Bias" than the entire conversation is derailed, and instead turns into a discussion over facts that nobody on reddit (outside of MAYBE askhistorians) is qualified to discuss fairly. 

I'm not really interested in discussing it anymore, since it's already gone too far off track. I want to keep the conversation focused on whether or not a Nationalist victory would have been better based on what we Westerners know and understand. Not transform it into one in which we argue pointlessly over the reliability of facts.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404429570.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So do you.

I have kind of a funny bias, though.  I happily voted for Hillary Clinton in 2016 and now am trying to figure out what's wrong with the world and what to do about it.  I'm not like some lifelong communist or something; I still find that word kind of icky (because of a lifetime of propaganda, I suppose).  I'm with Noam Chomsky; question mainstream thought because it is often wrong.

&amp;gt; I consider Western Historians living in countries where they can freely criticize their government more reliable than any Chinese Historian who is pressured against critiquing the Communist party. 

Oof, I would be really careful just taking the West's word for things they have a huge stake in.  It's kind of a big part of our narrative that people like Stalin, Mao and Castro were monsters.  I'm not saying ignore these figures, I'm saying if you're going to go to the trouble of formulating all these opinions, spend some more time with your facts.  Expand your research.  Do you understand why, in this particular situation, western thought is going to be so biased?  I think it would be intellectually dishonest to not take that into consideration and look hard at the facts you based your ideas on.

Also, Chinese politics is more complicated than that.  I'm no expert; I basically just started that book, but it's not nearly as simple as you can't talk bad about Mao or you'll risk losing your job.  There are trends in historical interpretation and saying that Mao made a lot of big mistakes was 'in' for a while.  Again, I just started that book.  If you'd like to know more, there are some very knowledgeable communists on the corresponding subreddits.

&amp;gt; I am basing my argument on the assumption that Western scholars are correct when they say Mao killed 48-70 Million. If that fact isn't true

Maybe you need to do some serious research into whether or not it is?  That's basically my point.

&amp;gt;I want to keep the conversation focused on whether or not a Nationalist victory would have been better based on what we Westerners know and understand.

And if we, as Westerners, have a flawed knowledge and understanding, your entire argument is flawed.  Exactly.  Couldn't have put it better myself, lol.

So before we make bold statements about Chinese history and even bolder statements about world history, we need to make sure the facts and perspective we're starting from are valid.  I assume this didn't change your view but hopefully it's convincing you that maybe it would be helpful to get outside mainstream western thought?  I can't stress this enough; if you're from America, you grew up with a lifetime of anti-communist propaganda.  So did almost any American journalist or historian you read.  In this of all situations, it is imperative that we question assumptions, perspective and facts.

For the record, I am yet to find almost any source I completely trust.  I trust certain sources most of the time on specific topics but that's about it.  Random example; you remember Elliot Broidy?  [Here's](http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2018/05/theory-playboy-model-had-affair-with-trump-not-broidy.html) an article laying out the theory that the media, including NYT, WSJ and CNN swallowed Trump's lie whole.  None of Broidy's actions make any sense, except if you assume that he was covering for an affair (and lovechild) of Trump's.  But three of our most trusted, respected, thorough media organizations (too generous to the WSJ?) were in too much of a hurry to publish some scandalous shiznit, none of them noticed.  Just a random example that was fresh on my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30402563981.0" user="martqin" delta="False">
    <text>While the Korean War would’ve probably ended in a unified Korea more similar to South Korea, given that China pushed back the South and the north likely wouldn’t have been able to keep up, I think the Vietnam war probably wouldn’t have been significantly different. The worst parts of that were what the Americans did to stop the guérilla warfare, which would’ve happened with or without Chinese support. I can’t say I know enough about the history of Vietnam and the Vietnam war to be able to comment on if it would’ve ended differently. Chomsky has something interesting to say about the war here: https://chomsky.info/reader02/

The other reply to this explains the importance of “getting bogged down in the numbers,” when your claim is partly a numerical one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
