<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="514822279.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8iifev/cmv_history_would_have_largely_gone_better_if_the/">
    <title>CMV: History Would Have Largely Gone Better if the Nationalists had Won the Chinese Civil War</title>
    <original_poster>Kasunex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm aware that this is a tricky topic, so I'm sure the responses to this will be very interesting. Basically, I contend that, based on what we can assume, if the Nationalist Government of the Republic of China had put down the Communist Revolution, history would have gone better. Now "better" is a relative term, but I'll explain why I believe so.

First, the obvious. Mao Zedong's government killed around 45 million people. Some people put that number as high as 78 million, but either way, he's up there with Hitler and Stalin as one of the most brutal dictators and mass murderers in history. Chiang Kai\-Shek, on the other hand, was not exactly a benevolent ruler either; but the most excessive count I can find puts him as responsible for 18 million deaths. Still far too high, but far cry from Zedong. Let's also not forget that only about 2.8 million of those deaths were from corruption or political repression. The rest were the result of war. So; even if Chiang had continued corrupt and repressive policies in peacetime, that's still millions of lives saved right off the bat.

Secondly, there's the likelihood that the Republic of China would have reformed into a democracy. That's what it did on Taiwan after all, on top of becoming one of the "Four Asian Tigers". Let's not forget that, ideologically speaking, the Republic was only supposed to follow authoritarian policies until the country was stable and educated enough for democracy. Of course, there's no way of knowing whether or not the Kuomintang officials would have honored their pledge, and this also doesn't mean that the transition would have been smooth. But, it still seems likely that it would have happened eventually. Communist China is still a dictatorship today. I doubt the shallow, corrupt system that the Kuomintang perpetuated would have been so stable to the democratic wave of the late 80s and early 90s.

Third, there's the benefit for the rest of the world. With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently. North Korea would have been surrounded by American allies, and thus less likely to attack South Korea. But even if it had decided to do so, the only chance of victory it would have is if the West just didn't care enough to stop them. I'm aware that the only way America was able to get a coalition together from the UN was thanks to the Soviet Union boycotting over Taiwan, but let's be honest, it's not like America and South Korea couldn't have defeated North Korea on their own, especially if China was on their side. So, either no Korean War or a decisive Western victory. In a Western victory, Korea is united, all those killed by Kim Il\-Sung survive, and the united Korean Republic likely would be democratic as it became in our timeline. The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either not occur; or be a Western victory.

So there you have it. At the very worst case scenario, a few million would have survived. In the best case, millions would survive on top of two wars being prevented and China, Vietnam, and Korea becoming democratic. I am not saying that Chiang Kai\-shek was a good guy, or that he deserved to win, or that his wining would have suddenly turned Asia into a utopia. Just that, based on what evidence I have seen, a Nationalist China would have saved millions of lives and possibly spread democracy as well.

If you want a delta, remain respectful. Don't be condescending, don't try to claim that your argument is "just so obvious" or that anyone who disagrees is stupid, uneducated, etc etc. It annoys me enough when people do that in other arguments, and this is a very opinionated and complicated topic. Also, giving credit where credit is due and solid, concrete examples are huge pluses. That said; don't be upset if I don't give you delta; I don't always give them even when I like the points made.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30405262781.0" user="pigmentosa" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is with Asia at least, absolutely NONE of the governments were any sense democratic except Japan until 1980s or so. It was more so a split between hardline communism/authoritarians aligned to the Soviets, and traditionalists/authoritarians aligned against them whatever spectrum they fall on.

Communism was more or less just used to organize among nationalistic lines against other nationalists who used nationalism to   organize among nationalistic lines. E.g. Indonesia had two factions of nationalists which were religious hardliners against communists that spilt out to open massacre. Korea had a brutal fascist dictatorship until 1980s, against a brutal communist-fascist dictatorship (arguments are made that both inherited the Japanese system of authoritarian brutality, which was largely true). Vietnam of course is well-known for it, although fascism was never in place given the country's elites on both sides were much more westernized than almost all others (the entire governments on both sides were French-educated and attended Sorbonne and french universities and so-on) and the country slipped from somewhat democratic to much more authoritarian as the course of the war progressed.

China as it currently is, or has been for a few decades now, has openly just replaced communism with authoritarian nationalism with communist themes. If the KMT were largely still to govern over the entirety of China its difficulty to see why or how they would see it logical to democratize given the size of the country. If anything it would go more or less the same route, albeit with greater friction towards the USSR. It may not even be true since the USSR supported the KMT during the war right up until Mao turned the whole thing around, and their friction was one of control over the "communist blocs" with the Chinese openly angered by Kruschev's anti-Stalinist speeches and views. 

You have to remember that the KMT accomodation with the West was largely due to necessity against the CCP, and they would given their size and strength pursue their own geopolitical imperatives.

tl;dr: geopolitics is the bigger factor, probably, and ideology isn't as important as you'd believe given the immense similiarity between alot of the ideological systems in place at the time. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
