<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="514822279.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8iifev/cmv_history_would_have_largely_gone_better_if_the/">
    <title>CMV: History Would Have Largely Gone Better if the Nationalists had Won the Chinese Civil War</title>
    <original_poster>Kasunex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm aware that this is a tricky topic, so I'm sure the responses to this will be very interesting. Basically, I contend that, based on what we can assume, if the Nationalist Government of the Republic of China had put down the Communist Revolution, history would have gone better. Now "better" is a relative term, but I'll explain why I believe so.

First, the obvious. Mao Zedong's government killed around 45 million people. Some people put that number as high as 78 million, but either way, he's up there with Hitler and Stalin as one of the most brutal dictators and mass murderers in history. Chiang Kai\-Shek, on the other hand, was not exactly a benevolent ruler either; but the most excessive count I can find puts him as responsible for 18 million deaths. Still far too high, but far cry from Zedong. Let's also not forget that only about 2.8 million of those deaths were from corruption or political repression. The rest were the result of war. So; even if Chiang had continued corrupt and repressive policies in peacetime, that's still millions of lives saved right off the bat.

Secondly, there's the likelihood that the Republic of China would have reformed into a democracy. That's what it did on Taiwan after all, on top of becoming one of the "Four Asian Tigers". Let's not forget that, ideologically speaking, the Republic was only supposed to follow authoritarian policies until the country was stable and educated enough for democracy. Of course, there's no way of knowing whether or not the Kuomintang officials would have honored their pledge, and this also doesn't mean that the transition would have been smooth. But, it still seems likely that it would have happened eventually. Communist China is still a dictatorship today. I doubt the shallow, corrupt system that the Kuomintang perpetuated would have been so stable to the democratic wave of the late 80s and early 90s.

Third, there's the benefit for the rest of the world. With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently. North Korea would have been surrounded by American allies, and thus less likely to attack South Korea. But even if it had decided to do so, the only chance of victory it would have is if the West just didn't care enough to stop them. I'm aware that the only way America was able to get a coalition together from the UN was thanks to the Soviet Union boycotting over Taiwan, but let's be honest, it's not like America and South Korea couldn't have defeated North Korea on their own, especially if China was on their side. So, either no Korean War or a decisive Western victory. In a Western victory, Korea is united, all those killed by Kim Il\-Sung survive, and the united Korean Republic likely would be democratic as it became in our timeline. The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either not occur; or be a Western victory.

So there you have it. At the very worst case scenario, a few million would have survived. In the best case, millions would survive on top of two wars being prevented and China, Vietnam, and Korea becoming democratic. I am not saying that Chiang Kai\-shek was a good guy, or that he deserved to win, or that his wining would have suddenly turned Asia into a utopia. Just that, based on what evidence I have seen, a Nationalist China would have saved millions of lives and possibly spread democracy as well.

If you want a delta, remain respectful. Don't be condescending, don't try to claim that your argument is "just so obvious" or that anyone who disagrees is stupid, uneducated, etc etc. It annoys me enough when people do that in other arguments, and this is a very opinionated and complicated topic. Also, giving credit where credit is due and solid, concrete examples are huge pluses. That said; don't be upset if I don't give you delta; I don't always give them even when I like the points made.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30402564975.0" user="Sophieven" delta="False">
    <text>Most of the time I don’t engage in counterfactual histories but since this proposition includes a range of topics I’m familiar with, I’ll point out some problems with the arguments; not saying that they are wrong — not fond of the dichotomy — but that there are more things to consider.

1) As mentioned above, the US’s position of power might be threatened if China transitioned to democracy and economic development (and with the liberalization of market recently, we’ve seen that the Chinese can develop rapidly). So maybe it’s not that easy for the US to stay an ally. But my main point here is how certain one can be that the Nationalist Party will later on democratizes because a huge reason for democratization of Taiwan was the oppression of Kuomintang (let aside the legitimacy of Kuomintang’s takeover of Taiwan and its oppression of the Taiwanese Independence movements in the 1950s). So if Nationalist Part had won and proceeded to rule China, why would you rule out the possibility of another revolution against the establishment or another civil war, like the one Communist Party led? The sense of connection between China and Western powers has been, historically speaking, pretty bad, so I doubt the US would willingly intervene either.

2) As pointed out above, the comparison of the number of casualty “caused” by Mao and Chiang can be contested. But I usually hold the position that “numbers don’t matter much in critical issues such as massive deaths”. So if the point is that Chiang would be “less murderous”, and therefore China would be “better”, I’d personally not take it. Nazi Germany isn’t evil for massacring “too many Jews” — the number shouldn’t matter. But this is perhaps considering philosophy and not aimed to change your view. Just noting a value difference and challenging the point of such an evidentiary argument.

3) Ok, it’s about world history. The Nationalist Party had been cozy with the US but I doubt that we can assume after it became the government of China, it would for sure stay that way. Alliance with the US doesn’t necessarily mean China would not be concerned about Japanese aggressions — basically, the US didn’t do much in China’s favor even before the Communist takeover (well, or before the large-scale Japanese invasions). Until the Pearl Harbor bombing, the US didn’t help out anybody at all. So China-US relations depend a lot on which neighboring countries are backed by the US — it still is. Now you’ve mentioned that Korea and Japan are US allies, how threatened do you think China would feel, regardless of the party in the government, due to historical hostilities among the three nations? If the neighboring countries are all US allies, I wouldn’t say for sure that China would stay out of USSR influence to form similar power dynamics of the Cold War.

4) Regarding the Korean War...did your conclusion draw from the premise that Cold War wouldn’t happen? Because USSR was also a sponsor to NK so even if China stayed out of it, it might still have happened as a proxy war. Also, I doubt that China would be unconcerned with a war that had a clear undertone of foreign influence happening at its border, especially because it’s historically averse to Western imperialism (and that was also what PRC believed what the US was doing in the Korea Peninsula). No matter the party in power, USSR could fairly easily point out the US expansion of influence in the Pacific and make China feel unease. Whether or not China would still have definitely gone to help with the Korean War I can’t say for sure, but as argued above, a proxy war would still be likely on the Korean Peninsula.

5) Someone above made the comment that a democratic China would be similar to India and then the discussion went into “I would rather live in X than Y”. Well, as someone who’s lived in both and studied on their political institutions, I’d say that China would have been very different because of its stable and efficient institutions, which India struggles with. Also...a case study of high functioning non-democracies that no one deserves is Singapore, if anybody is interested in institutions of different political systems.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
