<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="514822279.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8iifev/cmv_history_would_have_largely_gone_better_if_the/">
    <title>CMV: History Would Have Largely Gone Better if the Nationalists had Won the Chinese Civil War</title>
    <original_poster>Kasunex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm aware that this is a tricky topic, so I'm sure the responses to this will be very interesting. Basically, I contend that, based on what we can assume, if the Nationalist Government of the Republic of China had put down the Communist Revolution, history would have gone better. Now "better" is a relative term, but I'll explain why I believe so.

First, the obvious. Mao Zedong's government killed around 45 million people. Some people put that number as high as 78 million, but either way, he's up there with Hitler and Stalin as one of the most brutal dictators and mass murderers in history. Chiang Kai\-Shek, on the other hand, was not exactly a benevolent ruler either; but the most excessive count I can find puts him as responsible for 18 million deaths. Still far too high, but far cry from Zedong. Let's also not forget that only about 2.8 million of those deaths were from corruption or political repression. The rest were the result of war. So; even if Chiang had continued corrupt and repressive policies in peacetime, that's still millions of lives saved right off the bat.

Secondly, there's the likelihood that the Republic of China would have reformed into a democracy. That's what it did on Taiwan after all, on top of becoming one of the "Four Asian Tigers". Let's not forget that, ideologically speaking, the Republic was only supposed to follow authoritarian policies until the country was stable and educated enough for democracy. Of course, there's no way of knowing whether or not the Kuomintang officials would have honored their pledge, and this also doesn't mean that the transition would have been smooth. But, it still seems likely that it would have happened eventually. Communist China is still a dictatorship today. I doubt the shallow, corrupt system that the Kuomintang perpetuated would have been so stable to the democratic wave of the late 80s and early 90s.

Third, there's the benefit for the rest of the world. With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently. North Korea would have been surrounded by American allies, and thus less likely to attack South Korea. But even if it had decided to do so, the only chance of victory it would have is if the West just didn't care enough to stop them. I'm aware that the only way America was able to get a coalition together from the UN was thanks to the Soviet Union boycotting over Taiwan, but let's be honest, it's not like America and South Korea couldn't have defeated North Korea on their own, especially if China was on their side. So, either no Korean War or a decisive Western victory. In a Western victory, Korea is united, all those killed by Kim Il\-Sung survive, and the united Korean Republic likely would be democratic as it became in our timeline. The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either not occur; or be a Western victory.

So there you have it. At the very worst case scenario, a few million would have survived. In the best case, millions would survive on top of two wars being prevented and China, Vietnam, and Korea becoming democratic. I am not saying that Chiang Kai\-shek was a good guy, or that he deserved to win, or that his wining would have suddenly turned Asia into a utopia. Just that, based on what evidence I have seen, a Nationalist China would have saved millions of lives and possibly spread democracy as well.

If you want a delta, remain respectful. Don't be condescending, don't try to claim that your argument is "just so obvious" or that anyone who disagrees is stupid, uneducated, etc etc. It annoys me enough when people do that in other arguments, and this is a very opinionated and complicated topic. Also, giving credit where credit is due and solid, concrete examples are huge pluses. That said; don't be upset if I don't give you delta; I don't always give them even when I like the points made.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30401232845.0" user="tnorbosu" delta="False">
    <text>The rise of communist China led to the single biggest increase in standard of living in Human History. On top of Bringing 800 million people out of poverty; they are also almost entirely responsible for the decrease in extreme global poverty since 1990.

https://ourworldindata.org/extreme-poverty

China is also largely responsible for the amazing decrease in western power over the last couple of decades. Sure that sucks for Americans and Europeans, but the rest of the world couldn't be happier. 

China has arguably done more for Africa in the last 5 years than the entire west has done in the last 5 decades. Plus their new silk road will almost certainly result in massive wealth increases in East Africa and places like Pakistan.

&amp;gt;The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either have not occurred or been a Western victory. 

Things like this are even stronger cases for China. A western victory in Vietnam could have once more put them under the power of the French. Frances treatment of it's former colonies would almost certainly mean Vietnam would be much worse off than it is today

https://www.rt.com/op-ed/france-africa-neo-colonialism-675/

France's former colonies are almost universally among the poorest nations of the world. Adding Vietnam to that list would throw millions of people into poverty.

Also democracy is overrated; a democratic China would likely just be another India. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401244404.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're correct about the poverty angle. However, I also contend that you're opening a moral can of worms if you're arguing millions of deaths are justified if "for those who survived, things got better." I don't think it's an idea I agree with. 

&amp;gt;Also democracy is overrated; a democratic China would likely just be another India. 

Good enough for me. I'd rather live in India than China anyways. At least India grants civil liberties. But let's not make this a debate over democracy. Let's just assume that I disagree with this idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401331853.0" user="Narwhalbaconguy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Good enough for me. I'd rather live in India than China anyways. At least India grants civil liberties. But let's not make this a debate over democracy. Let's just assume that I disagree with this idea.

I highly doubt you'd be saying that if you actually went through with it. You wouldn't still be saying "at least this is a democracy" while poor, hungry, unsanitary, and living in fear.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30402488486.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, I also contend that you're opening a moral can of worms if you're arguing millions of deaths are justified if "for those who survived, things got better."

Not justified but you're the one arguing that communist China did so much that was bad. Here's some good. They took a country full of starving agrarian peasants and improved their standard of living. I think many Chinese people are happier with that than ending up as a western colony, for example.

Also I notice you didn't acknowledge the other argument /u/Narwhalbaconguy made; western colonialism has been a force of incredible cruelty for centuries. A strong China and generally a strong world socialism movement pushes back against colonialism, neocolonialism, imperialism, neoliberal capitalism... you know, the atrocious things our liberal democracies do to other countries.

Edit: sorry, it was /u/tnorbosu who made the excellent argument I was referring to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30403076731.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>And while I acknowledge that, I in turn counter that improving standards of living is not worth 40 million deaths. I said as much in the quote you hilighted. To me, that argument is tantamount to saying “it’s okay to break into someone’s house and kill them and steal their things because it increases your standard of living to take their stuff.” 

Especially since, as others have pointed out, the India comparison isn’t apt. Some have even argued a capitalist China would have done better economically than a Communist China. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404145698.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I in turn counter that improving standards of living is not worth 40 million deaths.

It's not a question of whether it's "worth" their deaths.  It is simply a fact that one of the consequences of communist China *was* an increase in standard of living for many.  Again, you're pointing out all the terrible things communist China did and the good things you think would have happened instead.  Well, here's some of the good that came from communist China.  Looking at America today, are you confident that standards of living would have risen nearly as much for as many without Mao?  Capitalism has a way of causing wealth inequality.

Also... you're still ignoring the anticolonialism thing.  I think /u/tnorbosu made a really great point there.  For all the terrible things East Asian workers go through, if China had ended up as basically a colony of the west after WWII (if only through economic subjugation through neoliberal foreign policy) it could be soooooo much worse.

&amp;gt;Some have even argued a capitalist China would have done better economically than a Communist China.

I mean, maybe their GDP would be higher?  Seriously, capitalism never would have bothered to increase standards of living in the same way.  Mao focused on getting technological development out to rural people.  It would not have been short-term profitable and therefore wouldn't have been worth doing.  Eventually we'd have factories moving out towards rural areas but they'd be even more exploitative than they are now.... most likely.  We can only guess based on things like trends in 20th century capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404175966.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's not a question of whether it's "worth" their deaths. It is simply a fact that one of the consequences of communist China *was* an increase in standard of living for many.  

My entire argument boils down to the idea that the positives of communist China are not worth the negatives. This is derailing it into a discussion about whether or not there were positives, which I've already agreed with. 

I don't care that the Communists increased the standard of living because they did so by killing millions of people. In a Nationalist victory, China *might* be poorer, but millions would have survived. That's a Nationalist plus for me.

&amp;gt;Also... you're still ignoring the anticolonialism thing.

I'm not ignoring it, I've just seen zero evidence that this is the case. China under Chiang would be Nationalist, not a colony. I don't even know where you get the idea of "loose western alliance = COLONY"

Honestly, you'd have a much easier time arguing that Chiang would have turned on the United States than that he would have been an American colonial puppet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404359482.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; because they did so by killing millions of people.

See there's the problem, though.  They weren't strictly linked like that; many people died just from regular ol' famine.  That's killed a lot of people in non-industrialized nations.  So it's not reasonable to invalidate all of the positives the Chinese communists achieved by lumping every person who died, so to speak, in with those positives as a 'package deal'.

&amp;gt;Honestly, you'd have a much easier time arguing that Chiang would have turned on the United States than that he would have been an American colonial puppet.

Literally part of why Mao felt such a need to industrialize was to avoid being railroaded by the West.  So not literally a colonial puppet but maybe a neoliberal outpost.  A place where the government serves the economic elite, who are closely entwined with western economic elite, who are closely entwined with western governments.  That's American neoliberal foreign policy.  I think we would have done it to China hard and it's pretty much never good for the people of the country we do it to.

Also, as the original arguer of the argument pointed out, world Communism losing out on China would have probably caused the west to expand, neoliberally speaking, even more.  Thus, more suffering.  I hate to admit it but America was sort of like the secret villain of the twentieth century.  Rewrite history with us having more power and we very well might have used it to cause more suffering, probably to increase our profits and deliver cheap goods to American consumers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404370088.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>More arguments about the reliability of facts, deflected my argument about Chiang to talk about Mao, accusing America of being a “secret villain”. 

Yeah, we’re done here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30404440805.0" user="Epistemic_Lily" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, do you really not understand any of the things that I'm saying?

You strike me as pretty intelligent; let me just say this about reliability of facts: question it.

As for America, we did some really horrendous stuff in the twentieth century.  We dropped napalm on children in Vietnam.  The more I read outside mainstream western thought, the less I trust mainstream western thought.  Stuff to think about for you, hopefully.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30403309103.0" user="En-Zu" delta="False">
    <text>I may be wrong about this but I was under the impression that the main economic gains came after Deng Xaoping de-nationalized the economy and made it essentially a free market corpratist state. 

Mao's reforms in particular seemed to actually cause famine if anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30408025479.0" user="thisisbasil" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; At least India grants civil liberties.

\* terms and conditions apply</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30409665521.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>If that’s the case, it calls into question whether India is actually a democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401359730.0" user="guitar_vigilante" delta="False">
    <text>That is an incredibly disingenuous argument to make. The reasons that China has slowly been enliminating poverty are due entirely to un-communist market reforms, which are still only half measures compared to what occurred in Taiwan and Hong Kong.

Your argument boils down to "it's better that the Communists won because after millions had died and they realized the horrible failures of communism, they adopted some of the things their enemies had been doing all along and things got better."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401485914.0" user="Waarivzrach" delta="False">
    <text>While the rise in the standard of living of so many people in a previously very poor China is certainly a positive result of the creation of communist China, as others have said, I think we’re really getting into a grey area considering the death toll that led up to that. Besides that though, there are other related issues like the annexation of Tibet (which admittedly maybe the Nationalist would have done too). Even regarding the rise in living standards, that seems to have been only for a very small subset of the population prior to the creation of the Special Economic Zones, which created a new flow of wealth that probably would have been available much earlier under a Western-friendly, non-communist government. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401907289.0" user="tnorbosu" delta="False">
    <text>the majority of the world is non-communist and western friendly; none of them grow like China. The things they have accomplished are literally unique in world history</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401768196.0" user="fakenate28" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder how much better Vietnam would have been If red China didn’t declare war on them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30416039094.0" user="renanqi001" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder how much more poor Chinese farmers Vietnam would slaughter and how much more resources Vietnam would steal from China if a retaliation was not put into place. For your information, Vietnam relied on Chinese subsides and China merely took away those supplies that were given out to them in the first place. Vietnam even used rice from China to fill up linen bags to use as sandbags to defend their post. Trust me, if you were living on the Yu\-Gui Frontier instead of in your air\-conditioned home, you would be supportive too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30416168575.0" user="fakenate28" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t have AC. 

I thought China declared war in Vietnam in the 70’s. Not the other way around. 

It’s crazy that a country that was so recently decolonized would declare war on China. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30416587820.0" user="renanqi001" delta="False">
    <text>Actually China did 'invade' Vietnam but that was more of a retaliation, or repulse, if you like, not unlike the allied 'invasion' of France in WWII. Vietnam started border conflicts but did not dare to go all out on China, and as China reached its breaking point on the matter, China declared war on Vietnam. 

As for your disbelief, your reason is perfectly legit, but if I may point out, Vietnam had just won not only several conquest wars against Cambonia and Burma, but also against one of two hegemons\-America. China, on the other hand, had suffered from famine and the instability known as the 'cultural revolution'. For their buffed\-up and victory\-intoxicated minds, China was just another weakling with plenty of loot ripe for the taking. War was hard for China, as it had lost most of its experienced veterans and officers to political chaos. There is a saying in Chinese that goes '\(in an army\) where the general does not know the soldiers and vice versa', depicting the horrid outcome of going to war without a well organised army. What was more, the Vietnamese Army was practically tutored by Chinese officers, making them so skilled in guerilla tatics and combat hardened. With experience gained from Vietnam War, they were ready and able to repell anyone who dared to come into their jungles.

However, China was smarter than the US, or at the very least in this case. The PLA only blitzed to Hanoi, scattered and utterly destoryed all resistance, though with a *very* heavy price, laid siege to the city, and then retreated without further conflict. This decision not only justified the Chinese casus belli, or cause of war, a retaliation against massacres on the Chinese\-Vietnamese border, but also did it help avoid dragging a nation still in turmoil into a bloody war like the Vietnam War. The US did not see through the blooded jungle of Vietnam and understand the consequences, continued their war until reaching the point of no return, and China learned from that.

I am sorry that I rambled on for so long, but I intend to show you and all those interested that China, or to be more specific, the People's Republic of China \(Communist China actually sounds a bit rude to a Chinese ear\) is not the monster depicted by western propaganda at all. We are people just like you, we have our troubles, we struggle to pay our loans and we enjoy pop music. But, in contrary to what your media might tell you, we also speak out against our government on a daily basis, but we appreciate what our government has done for us, we do not live like slaves under a dictatorship of proletariat, Taiwan is China, Tibet is China, and we would really like some activists \(nothing personal, some so\-called 'N'GOs\) to shut up about matters they don't know sh\*t about. We allow you to love your country, so why not let us be patriots as well? If someone still imagines China as a hellhole depicted by your propaganda, I heartly invite you to see 'hell on earth known as the evil dragon' that is the country China for yourselves. I promise you, there will only be tolerant, friendly people, and, if you might get into some troubles, a helpful, multilingual police force that await you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30416783534.0" user="fakenate28" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for taking the time to help me understand things :) 

What is the least rude way to differentiate The Republic of China in Taiwan from the PRC to a Chinese person? I understand that there is only one China, but sometimes we, in America, pretend that Taiwan is different. Is there a least worst way to do that? 

Also, Is Red China just as rude as communist China? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30416903500.0" user="renanqi001" delta="False">
    <text>No, Red China is actually *worse* than Communist China \(well, 'Red Menace', 'the Red Plague' in the 1920s just do not sound nicer now\).They always indicate China as an idealogical *foe* opposing the west, notwithstanding the 'subtle' implication that 'there is another China' or 'Taiwan is not China', thus bringing the need to seperate Taiwan from China. 

Things are complicated when it comes to Taiwan and China, however a well accepted way of seperating the two would be 'mainland China' and 'Taiwan'. It works for now, but there are still 1,5 billion people awaiting the day of reunifaction, when we, and the rest of the world would finally be able to refer to only one when someone says 'China'. :\)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30416909512.0" user="fakenate28" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks again. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401832735.0" user="Arkiasis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a democratic China would likely just be another India. 

India's economy is growing at 6% per year now. About the same as China. India is moving forward as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401897566.0" user="tnorbosu" delta="False">
    <text>oh trust me I wasn't trying to shit on India. I know all about the massive economic growth they're experiencing right now. My main point was China got to reap these benefits faster because they weren't burdened with the hassles of democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
