<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30455315006.0" user="smellslikebadussy" delta="False">
    <text>I think we’re speaking past each other in many ways regarding testimony and evidence and such, and I appreciate the discussion (and the formatting help!) I don’t know that either of us are C’ing the other’s V on this - which is fine! I’ll just make a couple of quick, evidence-independent points:

- Even if Wilson’s account were 100 percent, demonstrably true, we’d still be left with a half-assed, most likely intentionally negligent investigation into the incident led by Wilson’s closest friends, followed by one of the most bizarrely run grand juries I can think of.  That’s why this case remains incredibly relevant to the BLM movement. Just because Wilson didn’t head out that day wanting to kill black citizens - even if Brown caused all of this - those facts still show a deep disregard for the black community on behalf of the institutions that are supposed to serve and protect them. 
- To the racism point: Just because Wilson didn’t go hunting black people doesn’t mean it wasn’t a racist shooting. He has a history of racist behavior, was surrounded by others who did, and behaved and described his thought process in a way that dovetails completely with decades of racist imagery and description of black men. What exactly would prove racist thoughts on his part that day? Did he need to be wearing a white hood?
- Finally, I don’t understand how you’re putting such complete faith in Wilson here. You’ve repeatedly talked about (I’m on mobile here, so I’m paraphrasing) witnesses’ motivations - and therefore testimony - being suspect because the community would turn on them for not taking down the racist cop. Respectfully, you are inventing that out of whole cloth. But you disregard what people say based on this weird bit of armchair psychology, yet completely disregard the much more compelling motivation for Wilson to lie - to keep himself out of jail. He has a stronger reason to lie than literally anyone else involved. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
