<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30444577670.0" user="smellslikebadussy" delta="False">
    <text>You mention the pictures but don’t link them, so here they are. Are you saying [these](https://bloximages.newyork1.vip.townnews.com/stltoday.com/content/tncms/assets/v3/editorial/f/ca/fcaf331f-effe-59a8-81d8-1cce7a0ed4b8/54740885af5a5.image.jpg?resize=1200%2C797) are the injuries that caused a 6-4, 210-pound police officer to fear for his life? Do you think that’s a reasonable view?

As for the distance Brown ran, Wilson said it in his initial statement and his superiors (and the media) repeated it over and over again in interviews over a long period of time. Wilson himself doubled down on them a month later. Why does that not affect his credibility? Why are witnesses who contradicted Wilson’s account docked credibility in your mind, but the many inconsistencies in his own account waved away as him being shook up, even a month after the fact? How does it follow that “I’m not going to have credibility in the neighborhood” seems like a reason for dozens of witnesses to lie, but “Oh shit, I don’t want to go to jail” isn’t enough motivation for numerous issues with Wilson’s testimony to make you question anything he said?

And yes, the difference of more than 100 feet does matter to whether or not Wilson needed to fire at him more than a dozen times, whether or not Brown had activated his demonic ability to run through bullets. 

Furthermore, you say over and over again that forensic evidence corroborates Wilson’s account, but near as I can tell, have not elaborated in which evidence that is and how it supports Wilson. Can you be more specific?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30444657970.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You mention the pictures but don’t link them, so here they are. Are you saying these are the injuries that caused a 6-4, 210-pound police officer to fear for his life? Do you think that’s a reasonable view?

Yes. Have you ever been in a fist fight before? A grapple? Well nearly 80lbs, which is what Brown had on Wilson , is no small thing. In MMA terms, Wilson would have been a light heavyweight at best while Brown would've been a super heavyweight. There's a reason why the UFC wouldn't generally allow those two to fight: Brown would have a clear advantage over Wilson. Aside from MMA rules, Brown had, through his superior weight and strength, demonstrated his ability to manhandle Wilson and his firearm. 

Also, are you now walking back your allegations that Wilson wasn't injured/it wasn't a ME who examined him? It's clear, from witness and photo evidence, that Wilson *was* injured by Brown, and the ME (who usually deals with deaths) wasn't the one who examined him. So both of your claims are provably false. Do you admit to that?

&amp;gt;As for the distance Brown ran, Wilson said it over and over again in interviews over a long period of time.

Could you cite those instances? I ran three separate Google searches on it and checked the first 3-5 search results and never found Wilson stating the distance from the car. I did find [his grand jury testimony](https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/1370569-grand-jury-volume-5.html#document/p229/a189413) which didn't say shit about the distance. 

And, as I said, why would the distance matter, and why would you expect a shell-shocked Wilson to be able to detail the precise number of feet accurately?

&amp;gt;And yes, the difference of more than a football field

An inane comment, obviously, as a football field is 360ft in length and 160ft in width, both of which are larger numbers than the distance you're claiming, as of yet uncited, that Wilson stated was the distance between them. In any case, forensic evidence found that Brown was only some 20-40ft from Wilson, and advanced on Wilson some ~21ft as Wilson fired. 

&amp;gt;whether or not Wilson needed to fire at him more than a dozen times, whether or not Brown had activated his demonic ability to run through bullets.

Brown did *indeed* appear to have the ability to run through bullets; as three forensic investigations (and the DOJ report) found, he was shot by several volleys before a final shot (the last Wilson fired) to the head put him down. Idk about you, but for me if you shot my little toe off I'd be screaming on the ground like a bitch; Michael Brown, however, proved impervious to the effect of bullets until Wilson nailed one in his skull, which finally downed him. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30444703595.0" user="smellslikebadussy" delta="False">
    <text>Where did I say Wilson wasn't injured? I questioned Wilson's claim that one more punch from Brown would "end his life." And in another post, I actually cited the medical examiner, who said Wilson suffered "no bleeding, no laceration, no ecchymosis." So I don't know what posts of mine you're getting this from. I certainly don't admit that anything's false, because it's not, unless you're not in the habit of believing pictures and expert testimony.

The 30 feet claim can be found here: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/opa/press-releases/attachments/2015/03/04/doj_report_on_shooting_of_michael_brown_1.pdf

and later here: 

https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2014/nov/25/ferguson-darren-wilson-interview-abc-clear-conscience. That number came from Wilson's initial interview, and he didn't correct it and even doubled down on it in that Stephanopoulous interview. I'll edit to reflect that, as well as the football field comment, which was dumb on my part.

Can you cite your 20-40 feet comment? The DOJ report I linked above said that Brown ran "at least 180 feet away from the SUV," turned back, then died "approximately 21.6 feet west of the blood in the roadway." If I'm reading that right, he died about 160 feet from the car.

The claim that Brown "appeared to have the ability to run through bullets" is pure fantasy and is in line with two centuries of racist tropes about black men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447957491.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Where did I say Wilson wasn't injured? I questioned Wilson's claim that one more punch from Brown would "end his life." And in another post, I actually cited the medical examiner, who said Wilson suffered "no bleeding, no laceration, no ecchymosis."

Can you cite it again here? I went through the first few pages of your post history searching for it and found squat. 

As for the apparent swelling on his face: I ask again, have you ever been in a fistfight? Have you ever been in a fistfight with someone who has almost 100lbs on you? If they're knocking you in the face, any given punch might be lights out for you. And if you're getting punched while the person punching you is also struggling for control of your firearm, you might feel that the potential consequence of each blow has more gravity. 

&amp;gt;The 30 feet claim can be found here: https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/opa/press-releases/attachments/2015/03/04/doj_report_on_shooting_of_michael_brown_1.pdf

That was the same source for my original comment, which just stated Wilson followed Brown some distance from the vehicle before Brown stopped some tens of feet from Wilson and charged him. I searched the doc for keywords that would support your claim and found nothing. Can you please cite a specific page number for your claim Wilson said he chased Brown X number of feet?

&amp;gt;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2014/nov/25/ferguson-darren-wilson-interview-abc-clear-conscience. That number came from Wilson's initial interview, and he didn't correct it and even doubled down on it in that Stephanopoulous interview.

I listened to the video embeded in your source. It said nothing of distance. The only mention of distance in your second source was:

&amp;gt;When Brown was about 30 or 40 feet away down the road, he turned to face Wilson, the officer said.

First, that's not a direct quote. That's what the Guardian author is summarizing. 

Second, and more importantly, the ambiguous wording of that claim  renders it unclear if they're talking about 30-40ft away from the SUV, or if Brown and Wilson are 30-40ft away from one another. It's spotty, but given both his DOJ testimony and the later:

&amp;gt;The officer was not asked why it was that he should have feared for his own life when he was standing pointing a gun at an unarmed teenager 30 feet away.

We can surmise that quote was not talking about their distance from the car, but from one another. After all, if Brown ran away from the vehicle for 30-40ft, and Wilson gave chase before Brown turned to face him ~30ft away, what are we to make of the -10ft distance Brown was from Wilson? How could he have run only 40ft from the SUV and yet turned to face Wilson 30ft away, unless he ran further than 30-40ft? 

&amp;gt;Can you cite your 20-40 feet comment? The DOJ report I linked above said that Brown ran "at least 180 feet away from the SUV," turned back, then died "approximately 21.6 feet west of the blood in the roadway." If I'm reading that right, he died about 160 feet from the car.

I don't disagree with the latter part of that comment, I disagree with your claim Wilson claimed it was only (and I'm going from memory, here, since you edited parts into/out of your original comment since I replied to it) ~30ft that they ran from the vehicle. 

But I pulled from the same DOJ report you did which, unless searching those nearly 90 pages was bunk, says nothing about Wilson stating the distance they ran from the vehicle. The quote I cited was Wilson's, from section IIIA on the bottom of page 14, where Wilson says he chased Brown from the SUV, *doesn't state the distance they ran for,* and then says Brown turned to face him when 20-30ft away from Wilson (a slight correction to my 20-40ft, but a rather insignificant one, too). 

Between the DOJ report that we're both citing and the additional Guardian page you cited, I'm seeing nothing about Wilson making claims they were only some ~30ft from the SUV when the shooting started. Everything both you and I linked speaks to the distance from Brown to Wilson, not from the two of them to the SUV. If you disagree, please cite a specific source for your claim. Don't just say "well it's here somewhere in this 90pg report." Give me a specific page number and the location of the relevant quote on that page. 

Further, you haven't answered my question of why this difference *matters.* I was a first responder for many years. When shock and trauma sets in, people say all kinds of crazy shit, and give accounts wildly different from what actually happened. So why should Wilson be exempt from that trend? If Wilson said they were 1ft, or 30ft, or 300ft from the SUV, why would that matter? Forensic evidence + witness testimony still says Brown charged Wilson after assaulting Wilson and trying to gain control of his gun. Their distance from the SUV is irrelevant to Wilson's justified decision to shoot Brown. 

&amp;gt;The claim that Brown "appeared to have the ability to run through bullets" is pure fantasy and is in line with two centuries of racist tropes about black men.

First, nowhere have I asserted that it's a trait of all black men/people to be able to withstand firearms. 

Second, that said, Brown (and Brown alone - not "black men") *did* appear to be sufficiently engaged/strong enough to shrug off a rather spectacular amount of physical damage before going down. Like I said, if you shoot my little toe off I'll be writhing on the ground like a bitch. Fuck, if I *stub* my toe I'm out of commission for a good while. Brown, on the other hand, was shot eight times, and only the eighth shot actually downed him. He was shot in the hand, arm, chest, neck, *and fucking head* and he kept advancing on Wilson until a final shot to the head dropped him. We have no evidence Wilson continued to discharge his weapon longer than needed. He fired as many shots as it took to take Brown down, which happened to be most of a magazine in Brown's case. Seven shots wasn't enough - it took eight to bring down this particular guy. And we have no reason whatsoever to believe Wilson was at all influenced by some racist trope about black men being impervious to bullets, or that Wilson was racist at all, for that matter. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448201170.0" user="smellslikebadussy" delta="False">
    <text>Apologies for poor formatting - you are better at that than me. I hope this is clear.

Wilson injuries:

I did not cite, I quoted, but here's the citation. Page 6: "No bleeding, no laceration, no ecchymosis": http://www.documentcloud.org/documents/1371211-darren-wilson-medical-records.html

Also, I still don't see any post of mine where I said Wilson wasn't injured. 

30 feet reference is from page 14 of the link we both shared, in a section titled "Darren Wilson's Account": "Brown kept running, but when he was about 20 to 30 feet from Wilson, abruptly stopped..."

The distance matters because it's part of a pattern of misinformation from the Ferguson PD. Here's a story from a reputable outlet that has the chief saying that the entire incident happened in a space of 35 feet: https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2014/08/21/here-is-everything-police-and-witnesses-said-happened-when-michael-brown-was-killed/?utm_term=.7d01be78023d

That's the day after the shooting, after the police had investigated the scene. There's no reason for the chief to be putting out false information, but here he is doing it. Couple that with Wilson recanting major parts of his grand jury testimony during civil proceedings and it's enough to call his account into question.

The cite on that civil discovery is here: http://apps.washingtonpost.com/g/documents/national/us-district-court-document-including-officer-darren-wilsons-list-of-admissions/2371/. Specific discrepancies:

- Wilson reached through the window and grabbed Brown (questions 32-34)
- Brown never went for Wilson's gun (question 38)
- Brown had not gone for or displayed a weapon prior to the start of the shooting (question 41)

Also, I never said anything about how far Wilson chased Brown. Where are you getting this from? Please don't misrepresent my argument.

As to why the difference matters, is that not obvious? A Ferguson police officer shot and killed an unarmed citizen. The scene was secured and he was investigated by his friends and coworkers, who conducted a shoddy investigation, ruined evidence and lied about the incident from the very beginning. Wilson himself was caught in several provable falsehoods. This is exactly why this case is relevant to the national conversation about police brutality, which is what you wanted to discuss when you made the original post.

As for the part about the racist tropes, let me be very clear that I'm attributing those beliefs to Wilson, not you. Wilson's entire account is riddled with descriptions of Brown as having superhuman strength and abilities. This is right in line with a past rash of "giant negro" stories about black men with superhuman strength from the early part of the 20th century: undercoverblackman.blogspot.com/2007/07/attack-of-giant-negroes.html

Wilson stated that Brown "looked like a demon." He thought that Brown was so strong that he "felt like a five-year-old holding onto Hulk Hogan." (Source: https://www.christianexaminer.com/article/officer-darren-wilson-i-felt-like-a-5-year-old-holding-onto-hulk-hogan/47678.htm) He thought that Brown could run straight through gunfire for 10 feet despite having been hit multiple times already by "bulking up" and making "grunting noises." He insists that Brown was "reaching into his waistband" to grab a gun that wasn't there. These are the recollections of a man who, undoubtedly and provably through his own words, was under the influence of the racist cultural myth of the superhuman black thug.

That's relevant, by the way, because of the cover-up that was going on. Remember that we're not just talking about a general idea of a racist, brutal white police force. There's a long, documented history of that behavior in Ferguson, with Wilson's superiors (who were in charge of the scene) having been part of that culture for quite some time. Look at the list of admissions I linked above. Wilson admits to using racial slurs, and he admits the same on behalf of his colleagues. That's not evidence that he was influenced by racist thoughts when he killed Brown?

Finally, shock and trauma acknowledged, it's some kind of rhetorical trick to claim that Wilson wasn't lying, he was just wrong, but everyone who contradicted him was lying. Was Wilson still in shock at the grand jury testimony? When he was responding to the civil requests for admissions? Why was he contradicting himself at that point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30450730959.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>No worries on the formatting. And if you're interested, you can hyperlink citations by putting the [word] and (source) like that, only no spaces or "and." Just the ]( back to back. There's also a "formatting help" button on the bottom right of the text box which makes that a little more clear. Helps clean up your replies a bit. 

As for your initial claim about Wilson's injuries, you said it [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/dzfusw2/):

&amp;gt;Wilson: Brown was beating me so severely that I feared another punch might kill me. Medical examiner: Wilson suffered "no bleeding, no laceration, no ecchymosis [bruises]."

So... yeah. It kind of sounds like you were asserting Wilson wasn't injured. What was your point in saying a medical professional said that Wilson didn't have any of those injuries?

Also worth noting that the quote you listed from pg.6 (pg.8 of the overall document) only says that about certain areas of Wilson's body: it also says "right mid mandible and mid maxillary region with mild palpable pain, no swelling, deformity, or crepitus, **mild ecchymosis developing to area.**"

Also worth noting the overall diagnosis (pg.14 of the overall document) says: 

&amp;gt;Your diagnosis is

&amp;gt;Contusion of mandibular joint area (ED)

&amp;gt;Assault by other bodily force (ED)

So I'm not so sure the document you provided backs up your claim that Wilson wasn't showing bruising in the face... his whole diagnosis was bruising to the face. 

You're also being fairly uncharitable of your summary of what Wilson said in regards to his injuries might incapacitate him. If you've ever been knocked out, you know it can sometimes only take one good punch to the face to do the trick. Wilson being concerned that being repeatedly punched in the face might end up bad for him isn't unreasonable. 

For your next bit (emphasis mine):

&amp;gt;30 feet reference is from page 14 of the link we both shared, in a section titled "Darren Wilson's Account": "Brown kept running, but when he was about 20 to 30 feet **from Wilson,** abruptly stopped..."

"**from Wilson.**" *Not* "from the SUV." Your original claim of what *Wilson* said was (again, emphasis mine):

&amp;gt;Wilson: Brown ran 30-40 feet **from the car**, then charged at me, so I shot him.

As for your WaPo source, I'd never come across Chief Belmar's account since he wasn't one of the people who ever testified about any of this. Also "The overall scene spanned 35 feet, Belmar said" is a little vague. Which "scene?" The whole thing? The shooting incident that killed Brown? 

Still, at best you can claim that Belmar said *something* happened in a span of "35 feet." That *still* doesn't back up your original claim that Wilson said it, or that it was specifically referring to the distance from the SUV. 

&amp;gt;The distance matters because it's part of a pattern of misinformation from the Ferguson PD.

&amp;gt;There's no reason for the chief to be putting out false information, but here he is doing it.

Right. There's *no reason* for him to be doing that. The only thing that putting out provably false information (which I'm still not convinced even Balmar, much less Wilson, actually did) would do would be to hurt Wilson's case. Changing the distance doesn't actually *help* Wilson in any way, shape, or form. Why would Balmar do that, then? And why choose *that* bit of information to lie about? Like I said earlier, why does the distance matter *at all?* Why would it behoove Wilson to falsely shorten the distance from the SUV, especially when the distance itself is largely arbitrary? 

&amp;gt;Wilson reached through the window and grabbed Brown (questions 32-34)

First, worth noting that questions 32-34 chronologically happen *after* Brown rammed the door into Wilson and started assaulting him. 

Second, Wilson's DOJ testimony said (pg.14):

&amp;gt;Wilson used the opportunity to grab Brown’s right arm

So Wilson admitted to grabbing Brown both in his testimony and during the Request for Admissions. And Wilson never denied that his body breached the window threshold at any point during the scuffle. So no discrepancy there. 

&amp;gt;Brown never went for Wilson's gun (question 38)

So I should stop here and ask you if you know what a Request for Admissions is. Have you ever watched a lawyer TV show? Have you seen a scene where a lawyer is cross examining someone, and they only ask carefully crafted questions that have nothing to do with obtaining the objective truth per se, but rather extracting specific admissions that seem damning to the opposition and beneficial to their side? A Request is kind of like a written form of that passed between lawyers. There's no reason for the lawyers doing to questioning to ask any question that would paint Wilson in a favorable light. With that in mind, let's see what Wilson said in the DOJ report (pg.13)(emphasis mine):

&amp;gt;**Wilson withdrew his gun** and pointed it at Brown. Wilson warned Brown to stop or he was going to shoot him. Brown stated, “You are too much of a pussy to shoot,” and put his right hand over Wilson’s right hand, gaining control of the gun. 

Now, from the Request:

&amp;gt;38 Michael Brown never tried to remove your gun from your holster.

&amp;gt;RESPONSE: ADMITTED

And then... that's it. The Request doesn't ask any questions about Brown attempting to take control of the gun, since they knew Wilson would say yes (consistent with his DOJ statements) and it wouldn't look good for Brown. They asked if Brown attempted to take his weapon *from the holster,* which Wilson already said in his DOJ report that he did himself. *But* then the prosecution ends up with a nice little sound byte where they can truthfully say "As Wilson admits, Brown *never* attempted to take his gun from Wilson's holster!" while glazing over the fact Brown then gained control of it once drawn. 

So again, no discrepancy. 

&amp;gt;Brown had not gone for or displayed a weapon prior to the start of the shooting (question 41)

So I *think* the discrepancy that this is supposed to be showing is that when Brown turned and charged Wilson after they were both on foot, Wilson said Brown had his hand in his waistband (consistent crime scene evidence and credible wittiness testimony) indicating he *might* have had a weapon. But if Wilson ever claimed Brown displayed a weapon *prior* to Wilson drawing his gun in the SUV you'll have to point me to it, since that's all question 41 asks. 

So 0/3. No discrepancies. 

&amp;gt;Also, I never said anything about how far Wilson chased Brown. Where are you getting this from? Please don't misrepresent my argument.

We've spoken a lot about distances. What quote of mine are you referring to, here?

&amp;gt;As to why the difference matters, is that not obvious? A Ferguson police officer shot and killed an unarmed citizen. The scene was secured and he was investigated by his friends and coworkers, who conducted a shoddy investigation, ruined evidence and lied about the incident from the very beginning. Wilson himself was caught in several provable falsehoods. This is exactly why this case is relevant to the national conversation about police brutality, which is what you wanted to discuss when you made the original post.

Well first, you haven't proven that Wilson was caught in provable falsehoods. If you've read the DOJ report conclusions (or intro, for that matter) then you *know* that it was concluded after a *very* thorough federal (not "his friends and coworkers - this was a federal matter) investigation conducted over the course of nearly a year that Wilson's account was consistent with forensics, ballistics, the autopsy, crime scene analysis, and credible eyewitness testimonies. If you read the report you'd know that these independent, professional investigators were unable to find *any* credible witnesses who wholly inculpated Wilson, while every single one who did was shown to be inconsistent with hard evidence or not credible for other reasons. Seriously. Go double check the witness statements. There's a whole section for credible witnesses who inculpate Wilson, and it's *empty.* It also concluded that the shooting was reasonable and justified. 

Second, the one single area where you've been able to show even a single shred of vague evidence (the Chief's statement to the media) regarding the distance from the SUV has *nothing* to do with how justified or unjustified the shooting was. Even if it was shown that Wilson (not Belmar) was lying through his teeth and the shooting happened 1000ft from the SUV instead of the 10ft Wilson claimed, why would that matter one bit if all the other facts were the same?

&amp;gt;Wilson stated that Brown "looked like a demon."

Funny you should mention that, since more than one of the black witness who spoke out against Wilson (like 148) said similar things about Wilson, calling him not human or possessed. And some of the black witnesses who took Wilson's side said similar things in regards to how enraged Brown looked. 

&amp;gt;Finally, shock and trauma acknowledged, it's some kind of rhetorical trick to claim that Wilson wasn't lying, he was just wrong, but everyone who contradicted him was lying. Was Wilson still in shock at the grand jury testimony? When he was responding to the civil requests for admissions? Why was he contradicting himself at that point?

My reference to shock was talking about the distance thing. It doesn't apply to any of the other statements (which, again, you haven't proven to be inconsistent). 

As for the racism issue, I feel it's a somewhat lengthy issue that deserves more attention than I'll be able to give in my remaining ~500 characters in this reply. I'll leave a second since... y'know... I'm just *that* bad at concision. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30450845427.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Pt. 2 of 2:

Alright, so I'm not so churlish as to deny that racism exists. Any person of any race can be racist, and any person of any race can find themselves in a position to enact their racist beliefs to the detriment of others. 

We also know that, beyond more overt forms of racism, everyone has implicit biases. So in that sense, yes, Wilson and every other cop and every other person who has ever engaged with another person in any context has has their actions somewhat skewed by implicitly racist perceptions. . 

All that said, the current narrative is that the US is facing an epidemic of racist police brutality between white officers and unarmed black men. This is patently untrue for several reasons, the most glaring being that it's *not* an epidemic. [Another redditor did a breakdown of the scale of policing in this thread](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/dzfrh7q/), and while I'm not 100% on board with his numbers his point still stands: there are a gazillion police officers in the US engaged in a gazillion different interactions with civilians every year. Of these, only a vanishingly small number end in any kind of (even *questionable*) controversy. If you've been following this issue, as I have, you know that in the last decade or so you could tally up all of the controversial shootings of unarmed black men on your fingers and toes and still have a few digits to spare. 99.99% of the time, cops are just decent people doing their (quite difficult) job. Some tiny portion of the time shit goes south, and we ought to look at that, but it's also important to note that "we'll all white cops are horrible racists" *can't* be our first go-to response. 

And this is an uncomfortable truth, but there's also a reason why black people find themselves staring down the barrel of a cop's gun more often than whites: blacks top the leaderboards in all forms of violent crime. Now that, as it happens, actually *is* do to societal racism (and the legacy of it) putting more blacks in more positions where crime seems like a good idea compared to whites, but that's not the job of beat cops to be addressing. But I'm more in favor of preventing a future young black man like Brown thinking strongarm robbing a store and then assaulting the officer who confronts him from ever thinking either of those things are good ideas than I am in trying to assassinate the character of a cop who responds to a robbery or has to kill someone when his life is threatened by the robber. 

My old neighbor had a teenage daughter who suffered from mental illness. One day, off her meds, she was out on their lawn waving around a power drill. Other neighbors called the cops, who arrived and one cop (and Asian guy) shot her dead in seconds. This case *seemingly* has all the elements needed to stir up great controversy over police brutality. Young victim. Mental illness. Victim was unarmed (unless you're afraid of an unplugged power drill with no bit in it). Cops shot within seconds instead of using nonlethal means. And as a bonus, the victim was female, and women usually get more victim sympathy in the media compared to me. Now, why do you know Michael Brown's name and not hers? Why wasn't President Obama mentioning her death in speeches about police brutality (like Brown)? Why didn't Al Sharpton attend her funeral (also happened for Brown). Why does she not have a lengthy wiki, and why can't we access hundreds of documents and witness statements pertaining to the shooting online? Why did her death only get a cursory mention in our local paper? Why didn't trained federal investigators descend on my town to conduct a year long investigation into the shooting? Why weren't their months of violent riots protesting her death, and national outrage on the subject? Because it didn't fit the narrative. There is no national narrative about an epidemic of racist, trigger-happy Asian cops gunning down mentally ill white girls. It doesn't sell papers. It doesn't get clicks. *But,* "racist white cop guns down innocent, unarmed black man" provides media fodder for months, even years. It's sexy, in a morbid kind of way. 

But still, we have to acknowledge that of the vanishingly small number of unjustified police shootings that happen every year, not all of them are due to racism. They can't be. Some probably are, but that can't be the go-to explanation. The Gray incident in Baltimore was a great example of how it's a foolish go-to. Mainly black police force (50% of the officers involved in Gray's arrest and subsequent death being black), with a black police chief in a mainly black city in a country presided over by a black attorney general and a black President and yet "racism" was the cry on the lips of every rioter. 

Do you know that there are many cases where black police officers have shot unarmed black men and the shooting was deemed unjustified? Unless you've specifically dug for them, probably not. Like with my neighbor's daughter, that narrative just doesn't fit, and doesn't sell. 

All this to say that the bar on what we deem to be motivated by racism is quite low these days and there are vested powers who have a financial interest in pushing that potential reason, so I need rather extraordinary evidence of real racist influence before I'm willing to point that finger. That Wilson said Brown was stronger than him? Doesn't rise to that level. That Wilson said Brown was "grunting?" So? What does that prove? That Wilson has used at least one racial slur in his life? I mean, who hasn't? That he has heard his colleagues do the same? Okay. In what context? Were they making jokes? Quoting someone? Were they themselves black? Or were they saying something like "god how I hate these fucking niggers and want to kill them all" every time they passed a black dude on the street? I mean, I've called certain women "cunts" before. I've said "bitch" and "slut" too. If I was on trial for killing a woman and it was deemed justified but people wanted to try and peg me as a murderer influenced by sexism because I've said certain words, I'd like to think the context should matter a lot. 

And again with Wilson, I'm a little flummoxed how is racism is evident *in his actions.* Even if you can claim he said a racial slur at least once in his life, or that he has heard his fellow officers use them at least once, how has this "undoubted" and "proven" racism manifested in his behavior regarding Brown? If Wilson is really some brutal cop out to abuse power through killing black people in cold blood and then covering it up, why didn't he just pop Brown and Johnson on sight instead of politely asking them to stop walking in the middle of the street? Why didn't he shoot Brown in the back as Brown ran? Why didn't he empty his gun into Brown's corpse after bringing him down? Why is Johnson still alive? Might it have something to do with the fact Brown assaulted Wilson and repeatedly put him in fear for his life and Johnson didn't? But they're both black, aren't they? If their skin color, and not the assault and subsequent attempt to assault again, was the motivating factor, why did Johnson get off without a scratch on him? 

I'm also a little curious why you're not being a bit more incredulous of the narrative surrounding police brutality against black people. BLM, basically. While I disagree with most of your conclusions, you've clearly devoted a fair amount of time to researching this issue and others like it, and take *great* issue with practically every part of it. As such, you know that, for example, "hands up, don't shoot" is based on a lie, and yet it's a rallying cry for advocates against police brutality to this day. Since you've studied this stuff, you know perfectly well that riots over Michael Brown started *hours* after the incident, long before anyone had the facts... because the facts don't matter; the default assumption when a white cop kills a black man is the black man is innocent and the white cop is a racist piece of shit. Since you read the DOJ report, you're aware that those brave souls, primarily the black ones, who came out in defense of Wilson did so despite their great fear that their own community would turn on them for daring to speak the truth instead of follow the "Wilson is a racist cunt who murdered Brown, execution style" narrative. Since you've done your homework, you know that BLM turns a blind eye to virtually every instance where the cop isn't white; you know that BLM won't touch the issue of black on black street crime, which is responsible for like 99% of every innocent black person ever killed with a gun, both of which are quite strange choices for a movement titled "Black Lives Matter." "Black Lives Matter, But Only When White Cops Take Them, And Only When We Can Truthfully Or Falsely Claim Their Actions Are Solely Due To Racism" is a bit wordy, I'll grant you, but far more accurate. 

You can be skeptical and suspicious of police. Fine. Good, even. Any and everything deserves scrutiny. But for all your talk (and lengthy research) about how there's some implicit/explicit racist narrative governing the police forces of America, have you ever questioned your own implicit/explicit bias in that *perhaps* you've bought into the "racist white cop" narrative too thoroughly, and you're seeing signs of racism where it doesn't, perhaps, exist, certainly not as such a great, malignant, overriding force that it would drive someone to *murder* an innocent civilian for no good reason and then encourage the whole law enforcement apparatus, all the way up to independent federal investigators, to cover up this cold blooded killing because they just *all* really don't like black people? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
