<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30440252403.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source for your claims about the case? As you said, it's very old, and your explanation of what happened nearly exactly matches what I recall of the original police testimony, which was controversial at the time. It seems difficult to believe that controversial story has become fully proven with time given part of the controversy was eyewitness statements contradicting the police account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440306752.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Sure. And my apologies - I went back to edit my OP to include the wiki a little bit after posting, so you might've missed it. In addition to being a great summary of the incident, trial, and aftermath, the wiki also has 262 citations, many of them have citations of their own. Of course, not all of them deal directly with the claims of, say, the witnesses, but many do directly relate to Brown assaulting an officer, evading arrest, and charging Wilson later. Such as the [DOJ Report](https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/opa/press-releases/attachments/2015/03/04/doj_report_on_shooting_of_michael_brown_1.pdf) containing witness statements (starting on pg.26). Most corroborate Wilson's version of the events (and forensic evidence). Although, of course, eyewitness testimony is kind of shit at the best of times - witness 105, for example, claims Wilson was driving a car, not an SUV, something that's patently false. Also interesting to note that among a lot of the witnesses, even those who corroborated Wilson's version of events (and forensic evidence), there was a lot of animosity towards the authorities and an unwillingness to tell the truth or testify in any non-anonymous manner because they were afraid of the community backlash they would face if they told the truth that Brown assaulted a cop and charged him after trying to run away. Just to say that it's not too far-fetched to speculate that every account that contradicts Wilson's/forensic evidence might have an ulterior motive for wanting to make Wilson look bad and Brown look innocent, while every account that *does* corroborate Wilson/forensics could be seen as *extra* credible, since corroboration means allying with the cops and risking community backlash. There's nothing to gain and a lot to lose by corroborating Wilson/forensics, so the fact so many people did anyways makes that testimony even more compelling. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
