<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30440413527.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm still seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, real victims of (possibly racist) police brutality.

Don't you find it odd that white perpetrators, including armed and dangerous ones who have *just killed people*, manage to avoid death when being taken into custody at a much higher rate than black perpetrators? That includes white people who wave loaded guns around while begging to be killed when they finally make contact with police. I mean, sure, maybe police would have been justified in shooting, say, the Waffle House killer, given his recent actions and the fact that he was armed during their confrontation. But the police did not kill him. They figured it out and brought him in safely. The reason Brown is listed among the victims of police brutality is that his death was entirely preventable and totally unnecessary.

(Before you tell me that more white people are killed by police than black people every year, black people are still killed at a much higher than expected rate given their representation in the population.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440491308.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. 

My longtime neighbor has a schizophrenic (white) teenage daughter. One day, off her meds, she was out in their front yard dicking around with a power drill. Other neighbors thought it was a gun, called the cops, the cops arrived and shot her (Asian cop did the firing) to death within seconds of arriving. Since I know her family, I know her name. If you happened to read our local newspaper, you might vaguely remember reading the story on the third page or whatever. But lets change just two, maybe three factors: lets say she was black, the cop was white, and perhaps she was a he. If those 2-3 things were changed, *you* would know his/her name, too. Al Sharpton would have been at his/her funeral. Obama would have been dropping his/her name in speeches about police brutality. I would have seen *his/her* name alongside other victims of police brutality on Reddit twice just today, as we all have for years. But that's not the case. Asian cops shooting innocent white girls isn't a buzz issue. 

Look, cops deal with a gazillion different people in a gazillion different interactions each year. We can both point to individual instances where a white guy got off easy or got unjustifiably killed, and we can do the same for black folks. Regardless, out of those countless police interactions every year, you can tally up every controversial police shooting of an unarmed black man in the last decade using just your ten fingers, or less. Unjustified police shootings of black men might be more likely, but hardly at an epidemic rate. 

And yes, black people are killed at higher rates *per capita,* true. They also represent far more criminals *per capita.* Black males, for instance, make up only ~7% of the population but ~50% of the murder perps, for example. For most all other crimes (robbery, rape, assault, car-jacking, etc.) that 7% of black men top the leaderboards in committing *way* more crime than their population representation would suggest. Naturally, this means they end up dealing with adversarial cops far more than other demographics. When someone tosses out a stat that blacks are 2.5x more likely than whites to be killed by police, that sounds shocking... but blacks are almost 8x more likely to be homicide offenders, among other things. 

As for "entirely preventable and totally unnecessary," what would *you* have done if you were officer Wilson? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440619263.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Asian cops shooting innocent white girls isn't a buzz issue.

Maybe it should be. I was surprised when Justine Damond's case didn't get more attention. That was the white woman who got shot by a cop in Minneapolis while she was wearing her pajamas and was just approaching a cop vehicle after calling 911. Of course, unlike most police involved shootings of black people, the cop who shot Justine has been charged with murder.

&amp;gt;They also represent far more criminals per capita.

White people commit crimes at about the same rate as black people, they just pay for it less. [The vast majority of violent crimes are committed by a person who is the same race as the victim. The rate of white-on-white violent crime is 4x the rate of black-on-black violent crime.](https://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/rhovo1215.pdf)

But while we're on the topic of statistics, let's talk about cops. [Cops are statistically more likely to be violent than the general population, perpetrating family violence against intimate partners and children at a rate of 40% while the regular population only has a family violence rate of 10%.](https://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2014/09/police-officers-who-hit-their-wives-or-girlfriends/380329/)

&amp;gt;As for "entirely preventable and totally unnecessary," what would you have done if you were officer Wilson?

I would have continued to follow the suspect in my vehicle and called for backup, since apparently Wilson found his size intimidating and concerning. Yelling at a suspect out the window is an unnecessarily escalating action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440962790.0" user="nowthatsucks" delta="False">
    <text>1,000,000 cops do 10,000,000 arrests per year [not including traffic violations arrests] from which 1,000,000 are for violent crime.

There are 4500 reports for alleged police misconduct

And police have shot only 60 unarmed people per year

So even if you found 100 cops who were truly abusers they account for 0.001% of all cops. 99.999% of cops did they jobs like they should

It's disingenuous if you generalize a 99.999% group based on the actions of the 0.001%

&amp;gt; White people commit crimes at about the same rate as black people, they just pay for it less. 

That's just not factually true, 

For 2016:

https://ucr.fbi.gov/crime-in-the-u.s/2016/crime-in-the-u.s.-2016/topic-pages/tables/table-21

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Race_and_crime_in_the_United_States</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30441814241.0" user="smellslikebadussy" delta="False">
    <text>It's a problem whenever police officers kill anyone of any race. It's a problem that we give them complete authority to do so, with the only oversight being their closest coworkers and friends. I'm much more interested in seeing police reforms, in Ferguson and elsewhere, than I am in seeing Wilson brought to any sort of justice. Convicting him (which would have been extremely difficult the way the law is written) and leaving in place the system that created him does nothing. We need reform on how police are trained, equipped and authorized to use deadly force, and in communities like Ferguson, we need massive changes in how local government in general, and the police specifically, deal with the black community.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
