<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30440400176.0" user="roolf31" delta="False">
    <text>Let's assume for a moment that he was guilty of theft \(not clear at all imo\). He was accused of stealing a box of Swisher Sweet Cigarillos which look like they are about $3.26 for a pack of 5. Maybe he was stealing a whole case of 20 boxes that was worth $50.

Do you think that crime deserves the death penalty? Do you think that fleeing the police deserves the death penalty?  They could have simply let him run away. Maybe they could have done some actual police work and found him later. Or maybe the $3 box of cigars was not really worth the effort. I'm struggling to find the angle where he "deserved every bullet he got."

Do the police in Ferguson not have a vehicle they can get inside to protect themselves from the terrifying threat of an unarmed black man running toward them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440448668.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I mean, [here's the video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mkOfqIXkBRE) of the robbery. The description of the perp was "He’s got a red Cardinals hat, white t-shirt, yellow socks, and khaki shorts." Michael Brown was wearing a red Cardinals hat, white t-shirt, yellow socks, and khaki shorts. The guy robbing the store in the video is wearing a red Cardinals hat, white t-shirt, yellow socks, and khaki shorts. 

And of course I don't think stealing anything from a convenience store deserves the death penalty. That's nonsense. But that's also not what this case is about. When a convenience store workers calls the cops and says "I've just been assaulted and robbed, he's what the perp looks like," I *do* think the police ought to respond and try to arrest that person, which is exactly what Wilson did. When he tried to apprehend the suspect (Brown), Brown responded not by complying with the officer's orders, but by assaulting Wilson and trying to disarm him. Now, just to pause for a second, if *anyone* of *any* race does that, they've got a deathwish. There's a long list of things you can do to avoid getting gunned down by the cops, but "don't hit them" and "don't try to take their gun" are probably the first and second things on that list. 

And what do you mean "do some actual police work" and find him later? If the dude went home and changed he'd be in the wind. Nobody would ever find him, regardless of any policework. 

I mean, have you ever worked in any kind of retail store? Someplace that sells something? Are you really asserting that any random person should be allowed to show up to your work, assault you, and steal something and the cops should just say "eh, not really worth the effort to respond to that?" No! 

And Wilson didn't even gun the guy down while he was running away *after* assaulting Wilson and attempting to disarm him. He only shot when Brown ignored commands to get on the ground and instead put his hand in his waistband (like he was reaching for a weapon) and charged Wilson. This is the Michael Brown who just demonstrated his ability to manhandle a police officer. This is the Michael Brown who just demonstrated his desire to take a cops gun. And no, they were like 100+ft from the car at this point. And you make it sound like an unarmed person (who is much larger and demonstratively stronger than you) can't possibly be a threat. You ever get your ass beat by someone bigger and stronger than you? Not fun. *Especially* not fun if you know that person wants to take your weapon and do god knows what to you with it. So what would you have done? Would you just have kept calling out "stop" as this dude who just beat your face in and appears to be reaching for a weapon charges you? I mean, *maybe* he just wants to hug it out. But probably not. Maybe you'd take that bet, but I wouldn't. I'd pull the trigger. And worth noting that Wilson had to pull that trigger like 10 times and only when he scored a headshot did Brown finally go down. Idk about you, but if you shot my pinkie toe I'd be screaming on the ground like a bitch, but not Michael Brown - this dude took have a mag to the chest and arms and *kept coming.* Fuck that, man. I'm going to keep shooting until he's down. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30445674908.0" user="throwing_in_2_cents" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; responded not by complying with the officer's orders, but by assaulting Wilson and trying to disarm him. Now, just to pause for a second, if anyone of any race does that, they've got a deathwish. 

I would agree that this is true in today's America, but do you think this is the way things should be? 

Obviously assault of an officer and trying to get their weapon escalates a situation and is both morally wrong and a bad idea, but should we expect the response to immediately jump to deadly force? After all, the suspect is still unarmed and, while violent, neither of those crimes seem worthy of the death penalty nor do they directly put anyone not being paid to risk their lives at risk. I'm not saying deadly force is wrong in all circumstances, but against an unarmed suspect the bar should be pretty darned high and I'm not sure the Brown case qualifies. 

I might be convinced that the Michael Brown case should not be used as an example in the Black Lives Matter movement, but the very fact that you argue what happened to Brown would be a predictable outcome for anyone taking the same actions shows exactly why this case is critically important in a discussion of police brutality. The only reason I see to disagree is if you define 'discussions about police brutality' differently. Out of curiosity, what is your definition? To me, that phrase would certainly include examination of the militarization of our police force, a lack of prioritizing deescalation techniques, insufficient training and practice with non-deadly restraint techniques, and where the lines of acceptable force should be drawn in addition to the important questions of implicit bias.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447372696.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would agree that this is true in today's America, but do you think this is the way things should be?

&amp;gt;Obviously assault of an officer and trying to get their weapon escalates a situation and is both morally wrong and a bad idea, but should we expect the response to immediately jump to deadly force?

Well I'd point out that the specifics of Brown's case are somewhat different from the hypothetical I just posed: in Brown's case the use of deadly force wasn't immidiate or without reason, as Brown demonstrated an ability to overpower Wilson and a desire to disarm him, while in the hypothetical I'm just saying that by ignoring orders, assaulting an officer, and trying to take their weapon you're doing quite a lot to needlessly increase the probability of you getting shot. 

I do believe that when someone is violent with the police, police should have the ability to defend themselves. Tasers, mace, and hand-to-hand methods of subduing violent aggressors shouldn't be out of the question, but they all have their own upsides and downsides as well. Tasers are less reliable than firearms in terms of stopping power, and by choosing to spend time discharging one you've wasted time for your aggressor to advance on you or fire back with something of their own. Mace can blow back at the person spraying it. You might be very well trained in hand-to-hand methods, but the other guy might be better, or he might have a knife, or two buddies nearby who will jump you the second you engage. Considering, I do believe police should be armed and should see their gun as one of several different methods they have to protect themselves. What I meant by the bit of mine you quoted was just that, given that cops *are* armed, assaulting one (as is true for assaulting any armed person, really) just cranks your chances of getting shot up to eleven. 

&amp;gt;I'm not saying deadly force is wrong in all circumstances, but against an unarmed suspect the bar should be pretty darned high and I'm not sure the Brown case qualifies.

If Wilson didn't exit his vehicle to pursue on foot and/or Brown didn't turn around to charge him, I would agree. But given that those things both happened, the most likely outcome had Wilson *not* fired would be that Brown would have assaulted him again, almost certainly overpowered him, and either taken his gun during the struggle or rendered him unconscious, after which Brown would be in full control of Wilson's life. 

I also dislike the hype around "unarmed" perps. [This](https://www.reddit.com/r/dashcamgifs/comments/4j12i9/man_brutally_beats_female_cop_during_traffic_stop/) man was unarmed, too, but it didn't do much to prevent him from easily overpowering the officer. In addition to the fucked up face and probably a good deal of brain damage, that perp could've easily just taken her gun and killed her on the spot. Just saying unarmed =/= still potentially incredibly dangerous, and unarmed =/= can't become armed at some point. 

&amp;gt;shows exactly why this case is critically important in a discussion of police brutality. The only reason I see to disagree is if you define 'discussions about police brutality' differently. Out of curiosity, what is your definition? 

I'd say it doesn't, just because a cop defending himself from someone insane enough to assault and quite possibly try to kill the cop isn't the cop being "brutal." It's a reasonable use of force, which is like the opposite of brutality. 

As for my definition, it'd be more or less consistent with [this one](https://thelawdictionary.org/article/what-is-police-brutality/); excessive or unnecessary force, beyond what's reasonably needed to control the situation. 

&amp;gt;To me, that phrase would certainly include examination of the militarization of our police force, a lack of prioritizing deescalation techniques, insufficient training and practice with non-deadly restraint techniques, and where the lines of acceptable force should be drawn in addition to the important questions of implicit bias.

That's certainly true in regards to discussing police brutality more generally, but I don't think any of those things were at play here:

- Militarization. I'm actually not too opposed to this concept in general. There have been many instances in US history, such as the North Hollywood shootout, that have shown there are times when 9mm handguns/.38 revolvers/12 gauge shotguns aren't sufficient for the kind of work police sometimes need to do. But in any case, Wilson wasn't shooting at Brown with an AR while lobbing grenades; he was just using standard issue, non-military-type gun. 

- Deescalation. Big fan of this one, generally speaking. And it's a little hard to tell how applicable it'd be to this discussion, given that only Wilson and Brown's friend heard the initial verbal exchanges, and are basically polar opposites of one another in regards to how rude or polite Brown and Wilson were to one another. And both have ulterior motives for framing things the way they did: Wilson didn't want to seem like a dick, and Wilson killed 101's friend. 
 
That said, virtually everything in 101's account was proven false by physical evidence/credible witness accounts, while the opposite is true for Wilson. Just based on the precedents of reliability, Wilson probably didn't escalate the situation at all. At best we don't know. At very *worst* Brown responded to Wilson dropping an f-bomb by leaping onto his vehicle and punching him in the face. 

- Insufficient training. Probably the most relevant one in this case; as I said elsewhere, Wilson probably could've taken some steps to prevent being in a situation where shooting Brown was the only viable option. But, as always, hindsight is 20/20 and it's hard to know if extra training would have prevented him from making these "mistakes."

- Non-deadly restraint techniques. I'd argue this isn't relevant here. Brown had almost 100lbs on Wilson. In MMA, for example, those two would have never been allowed to fight. Expecting Wilson to engage in a hand-to-hand confrontation in hopes of subduing Brown seems a bit much. 

- Implicit bias. Well, everyone has it. That's about as much as we know in this case. We don't know how racist Wilson is or isn't. There really isn't any evidence of it either way, nor evidence that all the implicit bias training in the world would've altered the outcome of this incident. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30443663568.0" user="IambicPentakill" delta="False">
    <text>"Do you think that crime deserves the death penalty?"

Nice strawman you got there.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
