<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30440281052.0" user="acidpaan" delta="False">
    <text>He was an innocent unarmed man.  He was murdered by a police officer. The officer was acquitted of all crimes.  You say the shooting was justified, but we don't have the same view. Michael Brown deserved a fair trial, but he was served a death sentence amid an altercation that had many conflicting variables. Some of the witness accounts leading to the acquittal were extremely fishy and the way the trial was carried out seemed to be stacked in favor of the police department, as many are (this phrase "We investigated ourselves and found no wrong doing") Upon hearing about the trial of the cop it certainly seemed as though the focus was more upon whether MB was a criminal and less about if deadly force was necessary. The fact that the public had such vocal and conflicting opinions on the matter only added fuel to the fire. I do agree that police should have a right to use deadly force in extreme circumstances, but respectfully ask that you change your view in the case of Michael Brown because after all the evidence provided I don't think deadly force was necessary in this case. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440358481.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;He was an innocent unarmed man.

I mean, you are aware that Brown had just assaulted a convencince store worker while robbing that same store like 5min prior, right? "Innocent" seems to be a bit of a strong word for that. 

And he was unarmed, yes. But not for lack of trying. When Wilson attempted to apprehend Brown for his recent crime, Brown responded by assaulting Wilson and trying to take his weapon. 

&amp;gt;Some of the witness accounts leading to the acquittal were extremely fishy

The fishy ones were mainly those who were trying to make Brown look innocent and Wilson look like a murderer. This happened in a predominantly black area of Ferguson where not a lot of folks had a fond view of police. The fact the majority of the witnesses corroborated Wilson's version of events (and forensic evidence/autopsy reports, which are far more credible than either Wilson *or* any witnesses) should really say something. Many of the witnesses who corroborated Wilson/forensic/autopsy findings were outspoken about their distaste for law enforcement and their fear that telling the cops the truth of what happened would make their community turn on them, but they did it anyways. 

&amp;gt;"We investigated ourselves and found no wrong doing"

You do know that the Ferguson PD didn't put themselves on trial, right? 

&amp;gt;Upon hearing about the trial of the cop it certainly seemed as though the focus was more upon whether MB was a criminal and less about if deadly force was necessary.

Hardly. If you go through the reports there are whole sections where it's discussed at great length how Brown had clearly demonstrated his ability to ragdoll Wilson, had demonstrated a desire to take Wilson's gun, and when Wilson caught up with Brown, Brown decided to ignore Wilson's repeated commands to stand down (you notice Wilson didn't just shoot him in the back or gun him down for complying) and charge at Wilson with his hand in his waistband, instead. The perp kicked the shit out of a convenience store worker for a pack of shitty cigars. He evaded arrest. He assaulted a cop. He tried to take a cops gun. He evaded arrest again. And then when a second attempt to apprehend him was made, he made like he was reaching for a weapon and charged the cop. What do you think would have happened if Wilson *hadn't* fired and allowed Brown to advance on him? Think Brown was in the mood for high-fives or a big hug? Probably not. Brown would have kicked the shit out of Wilson, probably taken his weapon, and then who knows if Wilson would be alive or dead? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440601394.0" user="acidpaan" delta="False">
    <text>"Brown had just assaulted a convencince store after robbing"

ALLEGEDLY - remember he never got a fair trial

"The fishy ones were mainly those who were trying to make Brown look innocent"

Not by my recollection.   Witness 40 should have never been included but helped create the false narrative https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2014/dec/19/ferguson-prosecutor-witnesses-darren-wilson-michael-brown


"You do know that the Ferguson PD didn't put themselves on trial, right?"

No but the DA that they work in partnership alongside with every day did

And from your last paragraph: "Brown had clearly demonstrated" "Brown decided to" "he evaded" "he assaulted" etc... 

If you're familiar with law this is the most shocking part as they should've been Looking at Wilson's actions, as it was Wilson on trial and not Michael Brown.  Like i said before Brown never had a fair trial and was executed that day with a death penalty! He was shot (i forget? 12 Times!?!) Dead.  Couldn't wilson have used a non-lethal shot to the foot or knee?  We will never know because we only concluded that Michael Brown was a guilty man and never really asked the question of if Wilson could've taken a non-lethal alternative to defend himself against an unarmed man. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440669477.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;ALLEGEDLY - remember he never got a fair trial

It's on video. Unless Brown has a twin who likes to dress exactly like he does, this allegation isn't exactly a contested one. 

&amp;gt;Not by my recollection. Witness 40 should have never been included but helped create the false narrative https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2014/dec/19/ferguson-prosecutor-witnesses-darren-wilson-michael-brown

Check out the DOJ report, cited numerous times on this CMV. Most of the credible witnesses supported Wilson, while most of the fishy ones were against him. 

&amp;gt;No but the DA that they work in partnership alongside with every day did

Well that's counter to your original statement. "Investigating ourselves" and "investigated by a separate organization" are two different things. 

&amp;gt;If you're familiar with law this is the most shocking part as they should've been Looking at Wilson's actions, as it was Wilson on trial and not Michael Brown.

Browns actions would have been the thing (and the only thing) that rendered Wilson's actions justified or unjustified. It's not for no reason that they investigated Brown's actions. 

&amp;gt;Like i said before Brown never had a fair trial and was executed that day with a death penalty!

True. And if you kick the shit out of a cop, try and take their weapon, and then charge them, you should probably expect you won't get your day in court, either. 

&amp;gt;He was shot (i forget? 12 Times!?!) Dead.

Something like that. Although it was only the final shot that actually downed him. The dude received nearly a dozen shots to the chest and arms and just kept coming - it was only when Wilson scored a headshot that Brown went down. Scary stuff, indeed. It was like Brown was on PCP, only he wasn't. I wouldn't want someone like that getting ahold of me. 

&amp;gt;Couldn't wilson have used a non-lethal shot to the foot or knee? We will never know because we only concluded that Michael Brown was a guilty man and never really asked the question of if Wilson could've taken a non-lethal alternative to defend himself against an unarmed man.

If you've had any firearm training whatsoever you'd know that "trick shots" targeting certain nonvital areas (feet, hands, knees, etc.) are ill advised. This isn't the movies. Even an expert marksman would have difficulty capping someone's kneecaps while they're moving, and such shots won't necessarily incapacitate them.  There's a reason why all those paper cutouts just display the head and torso: those are the areas you should be aiming for if you want to stop your target. And that's what Wilson did: several in the chest before one in the head finally stopped him. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440702504.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440722949.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/acidpaan – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+acidpaan&amp;amp;message=acidpaan+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/-/dzflwdk/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440733668.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>Your former comment was deleted, but I wrote up a reply, so here:

In reverse order, if I may...

&amp;gt;Either way if you're not willing to change your view you might have posted this in the wrong sub...

First of all, accusing OP of being unwilling to change their view on CMV is actually a rule violation. I'm not about to report you, but just FYI.

Second, as you'll note, I've actually awarded a delta in this CMV, as I have for most of my CMV posts. So accusing me of being unwilling to CMV is not only rule-breaking, it's factually incorrect. The fact I've found your counterpoints unconvincing might be just that - they're unconvincing. 

&amp;gt;No i probably wouldn't, but if I was protecting myself or from a "bad cop" or if I had been suffering a mental illness at the time i would hope that justice would be served in the end, unlike in this case.

What "bad cop?" Wilson gave Brown *several* chances and warnings and Brown spit in the face of all of them. And what "mental illness" are we dealing with, here?

&amp;gt;If you were willing to look at the situation from the opposite side of the spectrum you would see that justice had not been served and MB didn't deserve to die

I am. And I don't see any alternative. Either Wilson allows Brown to rush him, kick the shit out of him, and take his gun, or he shoots him. Not a lot of grey, there. I'd opt for the latter 10 times out of 10. 

&amp;gt;For all we really know MB could've been trying apologize or turn himself in before officer Wilson decided to slaughter him like a cow for his own sadistic racist motives.

Firstly, do you have any evidence that Wilson was a sadistic racist?

Secondly, turning to face and then charging a cop with your hand in your waistband while refusing repeated orders to stop and drop is a rather odd way to "apologize" or "turn himself in," wouldn't you agree? I, for one, would comply with every order the officer gave me. Brown did the opposite, and presented himself as a threat. 

&amp;gt;Maybe if you can see yourself as Brown's lawyer you could see a differing picture?

What the hell would I argue? "Yes, your honor, criminals should be able to assault police officers and take their guns. Tis only the law... right?"

&amp;gt;The DA that works in tandem with the PD should never be the ones investigating these types of crimes. Agree? I believe after this case many politicians started to call for the DOJ to get involved when a civilian dies in police custody.

The DOJ *were* the ones who investigates this case. The DOJ report (i.e. the federal investigation conducted by independent agents far removed from the influence of a specific PD in fucking Missouri) is the thing I've been citing all up and down this CMV. The Ferguson PD didn't conduct this investigation, nor did local attorneys; this was a *federal* investigation that concluded Brown was guilty as sin. 

In claiming that Brown was innocent and Wilson is a murder you're not just going against Wilson's statement. You're not just going against the majority of eyewitness testimony. You're not just going against the forensic evidence. You're not just going against the autopsy findings. You're going against the *fucking DOJ report* on the subject. If you really feel your scantly (rather nonexistantly) cited evidence is more compelling than that considered by these several bodies of arbitration that concluded Wilson was innocent and Brown was a criminal begging to be shot, fine. But at least acknowledge that you're in some fringe minority group that willingly discounts the evidence. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
