<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447489548.0" user="4trezz" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace

I don't think that hardly anyone actually thinks it is illegal for the NFL to do this because of the first amendment. People talking about free speech or 1A are mostly talking about the values represented therein, not that it is literally illegal.

The big problem I have with this move is that it was an intentional end-run around the union. You want to treat NFL players like the guy punching the clock in a supermarket wearing a smock, but they are highly skilled professionals in a monopolized market. Unions are a big deal for these reasons and player discipline is supposed to be collectively bargained. 

Now, this particular rule was implemented without an owner vote and without union input. The NFL typically cannot enforce any rules they want, as you say. Player discipline from the league office is supposed to be subject to the collectively bargained deal. Knowing this, they used a loophole-- teams have more leeway in disciplining players, so they decide to fine teams instead. Teams are not subject to a CBA with the league. From a corporate governance stand-point, this is absolute shenanigans, even if it is technically legal. It is certainly putting more stress on already strained labor relations.

And how this got implemented without an owner vote, I have no idea. I would expect owners to be able to vote on the league taking money from them. I will look into the bylaws tomorrow, but this part also stinks of shenanigans for now.

But the bottom line is that the NFL cannot just make whatever rules they want and this particular solution was intentionally crafty shenanigans which showed no regard for regular procedure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447510194.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>That definitely sounds shady, although I guess it's allowed. 

I also think the players have an incredible amount of leverage and if they actually care about this issue can certainly band together and make a change. That would assume most players agree with the point of the protest though, and I'm unsure if this is the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447526601.0" user="4trezz" delta="False">
    <text>I think that the fact that the league had to implement this without the input of many owners shows me that they don't have much support either. The league office is largely just a mouthpiece for the owners. I suspect that they didn't vote because, even if they had a small majority, they didn't want there to be a voting record on which individual owners could be held to account for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30449019119.0" user="Doodoointhepeepants" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn’t have to do with players being disciplined though.  It will be up to each individual team if they want to discipline the player or not.  This is imposing fines on the teams, not the player, if they kneel during the anthem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30449268245.0" user="carter1984" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  You want to treat NFL players like the guy punching the clock in a supermarket wearing a smock,

Making and average of $2.1million per season. 

To play a game.

Because a bunch of filthy rich owners pay them an average of $2.1 million per season...to play a game.

Last I checked no one was forced to play in the NFL. They play because someone else is willing to pay them an average of $2.1 million per season...to play a game.

Context matters</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30452826153.0" user="BlackRobedMage" delta="False">
    <text>His point wasn't that people were forced to play in the NFL, it was that it's a highly specialized market with a very limited talent pool.

If you disagree with that, then you should definitely go get yourself paid $2.1 million a year to play a game.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
