<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447433206.0" user="Armadeo" delta="False">
    <text>I agree legally or but how do you feel about it ethically? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447468922.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>If I was the NFL I don't think I would have made this decision, but I don't think it's unethical for them to make a decision in their own financial interest. The athletes can use their own platforms to outlet these beliefs, nobody should be forced to give you their platform.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447475656.0" user="Armadeo" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's unethical to not allow an extremely peaceful protest. I find it amusing that respect is something that you have to hold a financial gun to someone's head to enforce. That shit is comical in a supposed free country. 

Also, you don't think an athlete's platforms is a sporting arena? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447492199.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>How about this: The NFL sees these protests during their contests which make their consumers angry, which causes them to lose money. People likely do not want to think about police brutality during their Sunday reprieve from their every day lives which is stressful enough. The NFL would prefer not to take a political stance one way or the other on this issue, they want this out of their product completely. 

No, I don't think the athletes are entitled to this platform. The platform clearly belongs to the NFL and they can share it or not share with whomever they please. If you worked in an office do you think it would be appropriate to spend company time protesting during the workday in the work building?

And how would you feel about other political agendas being represented? Do you also fight for the right for Nazi, free market, free healthcare, libertarian, socialist, feminist, etc. ideas to be represented during the anthem without giving the NFL the ability to restrict them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447557913.0" user="Armadeo" delta="False">
    <text>I don't envy the NFL's position here. Saying that, I think they backing the wrong horse when it comes to their stance here. I saw the NY Jets owner say that the organisation would pay any fines that they received for players kneeling. This in my opinion is much more virtuous route and I would hope they would be viewed positively for this move in 50 years. 

I don't buy the Athletes = Office Worker comparison. They are not the same nor should be treated the same. They are personalities with incredible influence over the league and it's consumers. As i said before, this is an extremely peaceful method of protest that highlights an important issue. It is not like these players are supposed to be doing paperwork or training while this is happening so the below assertion is pretty silly. 
&amp;gt; If you worked in an office do you think it would be appropriate to spend company time protesting during the workday in the work building?

The company I work for is a big proponent of marriage equality, gender equality in the workplace, placements for disabled people and lots of others. If these troubled me to the point where I needed to leave then I guess I would leave....
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448782713.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't envy the NFL's position here. Saying that, I think they backing the wrong horse when it comes to their stance here. I saw the NY Jets owner say that the organisation would pay any fines that they received for players kneeling. This in my opinion is much more virtuous route and I would hope they would be viewed positively for this move in 50 years.

Completely agree. However, I think it is absolutely their right to do so.

&amp;gt; The company I work for is a big proponent of marriage equality, gender equality in the workplace, placements for disabled people and lots of others. If these troubled me to the point where I needed to leave then I guess I would leave....

Exactly. However, in the case of the players I think they have some better choices than we would including banding together for a lockout if this is a big issue to them. In fact, whether they agree with this particular cause or not it would probably be advantageous to set a precedent. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447662283.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; do you think it would be appropriate to spend company time protesting during the workday in the work building?

During my general work duties, I might say no, on the other hand, my job doesn't have me perform speech (ie, the flag ceremony) in the first place. I'm not sure it's a fair comparison.

It's already a political act in the first place (granted, a relatively uncontroversial one in the past), that's a large part of the appeal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30449405093.0" user="Anon6376" delta="False">
    <text>They are not "not allowing" it. The players face zero consequences for kneeling. If a owner doesn't mind paying the fine the players can kneel all they want. This isn't a players rules, it's an owners rule.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
