<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447444854.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to hate the idea of football being used to push a political agenda. How do you feel about the US Government spending millions of dollars and having government officials, up to the President of the United States, weighing in on how the NFL should conduct business in order to promote a political pregame show?

If you think all of that is acceptable, why do you specifically object to the idea of these athletes bringing politics into football? Is there a reason that's particularly bad? I'm not talking about whether the NFL is legally allowed to do this, mind; I'm asking why you seem to think it's unethical or immoral for specifically the players to be political.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447466784.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think the US Government should be attempting to influence private businesses by outwardly describing their wishes. I also don't think the NFL particularly cares what Trump tweets, they are attempting to stop actions by employees that they feel are harming the image of their business and losing them money.

I personally do not object to the idea of athletes bringing politics into football, I apologize if that's what my post seemed to imply. But I believe a private company has every right to create their own rules and expectations that employees are expected to comply with. I do not fault the NFL for a decision that they believe is in their financial interest. 

I originally created the post due to reading and watching several viewpoints that seemed to think it is completely unacceptable for the NFL to do this and they are violating the 1st amendment, free speech, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447558441.0" user="SurprisedPotato" delta="False">
    <text>Whilst they are not violating the first amendment, they are certainly violating free speech. The constitutional amendment only restrains the government from restricting free speech. 

The only question is whether the NFL is right to violate free speech in this manner.

NB - do note that while the NFL is a money-making enterprise, they are heavily subsidised by the government in the form of payouts and tax exemptions. Analogies with other private enterprises may falter on that point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447620800.0" user="isoldasballs" delta="False">
    <text>Football is already “pushing a political agenda” through the anthem. It’s just a non-controversial one. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
