<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447906448.0" user="ryarger" delta="False">
    <text>The part of your view that I’d like to change is the last part where you suggest that if a person is Ok with the current protests they should also be Ok with swastika’s or other political messages being used.

I think that you are actually spot on here and that you **should** be Ok with that BUT you should also be aware of importance of the current protests.

These are people who love their country. By refusing to stand for the anthem they are sending out a distress signal. They feel that the country they love so much is deeply broken in a way that directly threatens the life of their friends and family.

This isn’t a minor thing. This is an SOS.

If someone felt the same way about another topic - say a neo-Nazi feeling that the minorities are killing this country - I would absolutely want them to make that publicly clear. I’d want to know that someone who I’m paying for entertainment has that view so I can make a choice whether I want to support that.

That’s what irks me the most about people against the protests. Nearly universally, it’s people that - when pushed - don’t believe that the protesters are right. When it comes down it, it’s not about “respecting the flag”, it’s about not really believing that Blacks in America are in imminent and continual danger from public authority.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
