<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447604831.0" user="john_gee" delta="False">
    <text>I might be behind the curve on this, but I haven't seen many serious suggestions that the NFL *lacks the right* to enforce this decision. They are, of course, a private organization. Most criticism I've read (and heard) on their decision here deals with their lack of moral courage as an organization: failing to adequately address concussions, traumatic brain injuries, abuse, rape, etc., yet drawing a line in the sand over black people refusing to stand for the anthem. Just because you have the right to do a thing doesn't mean you deserve praise for doing it. The decision-makers at the NFL have every right to be bigots. They can ban kneeling and allow swastikas if they really want to, but the portions of their audience that they offend also have the right to hate them, criticize them, and refuse to watch them based on their decisions. 

In this case, it appears that the NFL is making a play for the angry white people who changed the channel last season and hoping it doesn't cost them too much in terms of black and/or liberal viewership in the coming season. Maybe that will turn out to be a smart business choice; maybe not. But the people who see it as a cowardly choice have every right to be critical. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
