<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447417327.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447492876.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Codyiswin – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+Codyiswin&amp;amp;message=Codyiswin+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/-/dzjltkf/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
