<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447491524.0" user="ithomasina" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. 

Likewise, employees of a private business should not be forced by their employer to make political statements that have nothing to do with football.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447513552.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>My guess is that they agreed to this in some form (knowingly or unknowingly, would have required quite a bit of foresight) in signing their contracts, otherwise they would have easily deflected this issue in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447915623.0" user="DjangoUBlackBastard" delta="False">
    <text>They didn't which is why the player's union is looking to get this new rule ruled illegal. The NFL's only anthem rule prior to this was that players had to be on the field and the league office supported Kaepernick taking a knee for over a year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448723395.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>My assumption is that there is something in their contract like "employee agrees to follow current and future guidelines of conduct as described by the league office etc. etc." otherwise you're right and this isn't even an issue, the players will simply continue to do as they please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448849092.0" user="DjangoUBlackBastard" delta="False">
    <text>Your assumption is wrong. They agree to rules at the time of the antitrust agreement being signed. Standing for the pledge wasn't in that antitrust agreement. That's why the player's union is taking action. They're only allowed to add rules the league front office hasn't agreed on and the league supported player's rights to kneel for over a year (basically up until Trump called them out).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447724996.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>A football player's job is to attract fans.  

Overt disrespect for America repels football fans.  

Therefore, the league has every right to require outward respect be shown, and it is part of their job to comply.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30449014416.0" user="Doodoointhepeepants" delta="False">
    <text>They don’t have to, the rule allows players to stay in the locker room.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
