<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447488070.0" user="Trotlife" delta="False">
    <text>First of all the players aren't employees like Steve in accounting is an employee. They're literally what people are paying for. They're athletes of a quality so good they're almost impossible to replace. So pushing them around and telling them what to do is just not a smart move. 

Also kneeling to the flag is really a negative form of speech, it's refusing to act or say things that you don't believe in. It's basically handing out fines for not being patriotic, which is an ugly road to go down. What if a player voices concern about the state of the government? What if a player doesn't love the military enough? This forceful form of nationalism creates a really bad atmosphere to express oneself.

If a player starts wearing a swastika then he's gonna face a ton of backlash from society at large, and the business would have every right to fire that player because their unpopularity is hurting business. But handing out fines for expressing yourself is not within an employers rights unless a contract says otherwise. What I think will happen is that the players won't sign contracts that says that they need to be patriotic or lose money.

Further more, I'm not American, but NFL is often used as patriotic propaganda. It's not very subtle. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447503608.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, the players do have a significant amount of leverage.

I'm not sure it's all about "patriotism". If the consumers of the NFL's product supported these protests and they did not incur a financial loss for the company (perhaps even a gain?) do you think the NFL would have reacted this way? I don't.

I don't think it's fair to say "fire the neo nazi because it's obviously bad and there's backlash" but say that this is completely different and the players should not be subject to repercussions, when there is also significant backlash. The ideology does not matter, what matters is the NFL feels it is hurting its product. 

I think it is most likely in the contracts as well. I agree that most likely the players will not agree to these restrictions anymore, but for now they have agreed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447735017.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They're literally what people are paying for.

Ticket sales have gone down in the wake of these protests.  Protesting the anthem is what they're literally refusing to pay for.  

&amp;gt; If a player starts wearing a swastika then he's gonna face a ton of backlash from society at large, and the business would have every right to fire that player because their unpopularity is hurting business

What they're doing now is hurting the business through unpopularity.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447779833.0" user="Trotlife" delta="False">
    <text>It'll hurt their business a lot more when the black players (so most of the players) actually do something to oppose these rules. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30447782745.0" user="foot_kisser" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they do that?  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
