<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447684504.0" user="timoth3y" delta="False">
    <text>It's a bit more complicated than that.

You say that the players do not have a right to protest on their employer's dime and against their wishes. I agree with that.

However, let's consider his *original* protest -- remaining seated during the national anthem. He wasn't doing anything. It was a lack of action. A refusal to participate in (what he considered) a forced political statement of support for something he disagreed with.


Now that's a lot less clear. Should an employee have the right to compel political speech from their employees? Should they be able to force someone to make a statement supporting a candidate or a cause that they find abhorrent?  US courts have generally held that compelling speech in this way is a violation of freedom of conscience, and it is often prohibited even when not done by the government.


His original position was that he did not want to be compelled to state his support for something he did not believe in, so he took no action and remained seated.  He changed this to kneeling when he wanted to make it clear that he was not disrespecting veterans.


To be clear, the NFL is being very careful in their new rules. They are allowing players to stay in the locker room, so they are not compelling speech.


There is a lot lot more subtlety here than most people want to see.








</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448766143.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly a good point, and they would absolutely not get away with it if they were forcing everybody to salute Trump or something. But the protest is already convoluted in itself, as the kneeling during the anthem objectively has nothing to do with police brutality which muddies the subject even further; it is completely subjective and means different things to different people. 

Hypothetically, if they forced everybody to stand it would be uncertain what "speech" or meaning they are even compelling. Support for the military? Support for police brutality? Support for Trump? Solidarity with the American people? I would imagine something so unclear would be difficult to prosecute.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30450019656.0" user="timoth3y" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the meaning of this "speech" is unclear, but that does not change the basic rights in question.  We agree that an employer should not be able to force employees to salute Trump. But an employer could also argue that the meaning was not really clear. Are they showing respect for Trump personally? The office of the president, or the nation itself?  Maybe people are showing they are a proud Republican

As far as political statements go, saluting the president is not that different from standing for the national anthem. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
