<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447815005.0" user="AvoidingMyToDoList" delta="False">
    <text>They do not have the right to punish UNLESS they make every single team re\-write all player and coach contracts and resign their entire team with these rules drafted. It needs to be in each player's contract in order to be a stipulation that each player/coach on each team must uphold. That's like your boss coming to you and saying "you need to work 65 hours each week or you will be punished" when your contract specifically states that you are to work 40 hours a week. People think because these players are in the spotlight that they don't have a right to be protected by their contract. From a business standpoint it's complete bullshit IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
