<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447505795.0" user="KokonutMonkey" delta="False">
    <text> From the NFLPA:

&amp;gt;a statement, the union said it would review the new policy and "challenge any aspect of it that is inconsistent with the collective bargaining agreement. 

The NFL is bound to act within the constraints of this agreement. As this rule pertains to discipline, pre-game player behavior, and subsequent fines. It's reasonable to assume that there are certain processes that must be followed before such a change takes place (e.g., mandatory consultation with union reps, period of notice, etc).

Unless you have a strong working knowledge of the NFL's own bylaws and collective bargaining agreement, it's simply too early to assert what the league can/can't do with certainty. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448787554.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>Good point. My guess is they consulted a few lawyers though, I doubt this will be quickly crumpled up and thrown away.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
