<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="520648489.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lzay1/cmv_the_nfl_has_every_right_to_punish_kneeling/">
    <title>CMV: The NFL has every right to punish kneeling</title>
    <original_poster>Swaguuuu</original_poster>
    <original_post>The NFL is a private business. They should not be forced to yield their national platform and allow their employees to make political statements during work time that have nothing to do with football. This is not a free speech issue because it is not the government legislating the restrictions. They do not have to allow their employees, who agreed to follow their rules when they signed contracts, to use the NFL's access to millions of Americans to further their political agendas. And if you are going to say they must do this, then you better be okay with players displaying KKK hoods, swastika sleeves, #FreeHealthCareForAll signs, or whatever else they're feeling frisky about that day during the anthem too. 

If the players believe this is unreasonable, then stage a lockout or something because the NFL has every right to make rules and enforce them in their own workplace. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30447725174.0" user="lawtonj" delta="False">
    <text>Playing the anthem and forcing all your employees to stand and "respect" the flag or face suppension to audience of millions is propaganda and force all the players to be political if you are happy with this you should not be able to complain if Target forced all of its employees to say america sucks after they talk to a customer. 

Businesses should not be allowed to force their views on to you as that violets freedom of speech. It should not be legal for NFL to write their politics in to a contract.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30448810174.0" user="Swaguuuu" delta="False">
    <text>Imagining my trip to Target ending in this way made me lol, so thanks. As was stated elsewhere, this is where the subtlety comes in of what the NFL policy actually says. Players are allowed to stay in the locker room, so there isn't necessarily compelled speech.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
