<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="522076006.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8mtwfa/cmv_parrots_dont_make_good_pets/">
    <title>CMV: Parrots don't make good pets.</title>
    <original_poster>KnightWhoSaysNi1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Just to be clear, I'm not in a place in my life to get a parrot, nor do I want one, as you can tell from the title of my post. But I want to find out why people find them to be good pets.

Here's why I don't think they make good pets:

1. From what I've read about them, they're on the emotional level of toddlers. And while human children are toddlers for a few years, parrots can live around eighty years. So you're dealing with a toddler for eighty years.

2. To add onto the previous point, they can live eighty to ninety effing years! Cats and dogs can live around twenty years, and that's a reasonable time commitment, but for a pet with the kind of lifespan that a parrot has, even if they have the very best outcome and have an owner who makes a lifelong commitment to them, there's still a good chance that they'll be uprooted from their home at the very end of their life.

3. From everything I hear and read, they require a ton of work! They seem to be messier and more expensive to take care of than dogs and cats, and after all that work, you can't cuddle them like dogs and cats. It also seems like it's hard to find a vet for them, and I'm guessing it would be way more expensive once you do find a vet.

4. They're loud and neurotic. If you don't devote a huge amount of attention to them, they screech all the time, pluck their feathers out, and attack people. I've heard a cockatoo screech, and I think I'd go insane if I had to listen to that sound in my house constantly.

With all this out of the way, I'm not going to pretend that I don't think that they're cool animals. They're really beautiful and seem pretty intelligent. It's neat that they can talk, and maybe for people who are not me, the novelty of them talking wouldn't wear off after ten minutes. I just think they'd be better off at zoos or wildlife sanctuaries where they have enough space to fly around and have a team of dedicated people than as pets in people's homes. Change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30464941533.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't want a pet parrot and I don't think they are appropriate for a lot of people but my neighbors had a parrot. They never had children so the qualities of the parrot \(being smart, living a long time, being extremely loyal\) made it the perfect companion for them. It didn't live in a cage, it's wings were clipped but it had several open air play pens throughout the house. The parrot died \(I think they had it for 20 or 30 years\) and they were devastated, they really had an emotional connection to the parrot on the same level as one might have for a child. 

So parrots can make great pets, while also not being ideal for the average person. But this is true of any pet from a horse to a hamster. Each has a varying level of commitment that must be considered or else you risk having a bad situation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
