<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483258471.0" user="decker_42" delta="False">
    <text>Pride is about sexual preferences isn't it? While I think you are right there is more to LGBT than sex, I'm not surprised it's a bit of a sexy event.

Possibly it's like saying an art gallery should explore the culinary skills of the artist....yes he can whip up a great omelette but it's kind of not the point.

Edit: But I do think you're right, I'm just not sure it'll happen. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483286321.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about the sexual preferences. There's just as much romantic preferences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483299556.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>At a base level I disagree with that.  Gay aren’t gay because they think men are better life partners or they enjoy male culture. The basis of being gay is an attraction to a member of the same sex. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483312672.0" user="2074red2074" delta="False">
    <text>But most of the current issues aren't about gay sex. That's legal, and for the most part very few people think it should be illegal. The problem comes from acceptance of gay relationships, gay marriage, gay child adoption, etc. And a massive public display of sexually-explicit acts and imagery is not helping that case at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483319830.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Gay pride is not supposed to make straight people accept gay people its meant to help gay people accept themselves. And the fact that people are more uncomfortable with the sexual aspect of gay pride kind of disproves your assertion that gay sex has been accepted before gay relationships</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483327915.0" user="2074red2074" delta="False">
    <text>It really doesn't. People are uncomfortable with public displays of sexuality. You think it would be accepted if *women* were on the giant float shaped like an erect penis instead of men?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483340084.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>I would accept it. But I find it odd that you assuming we should conform to society and not have society be more accepting. The fact that society wont accept something so harmless shows that it is an important current issue.  Society would have everyone homogenize and despite the first four letters, that is not what gay pride is about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483351408.0" user="2074red2074" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe gay pride should be about gay issues and not issues that affect the general public more-or-less equally? You don't see women's advocates groups campaigning against global warming, for example. Usually the group members just join up with an actual global warming group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483364558.0" user="quaintquincidence" delta="False">
    <text>I've been following up to that point and then suddenly were lost. Can you elaborate on which issues do you pertain to the LGBT+ community and which bear no relation to it, but are nonetheless mixed in? The women's advocate :: global warming analogy throws me completely off balance, I don't even understand it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483373429.0" user="2074red2074" delta="False">
    <text>A major portion of the hate pride receives is because of rampant public displays of sexuality. This isn't because the sex is gay, it's because a large portion of society doesn't like talking about sex. The gay movement would benefit itself by separating its advocacy for freedom of sexual expression from its advocacy for acceptance of gay relationships. Demonstrating that gay people aren't sex-crazed perverts would do wonders for convincing old Republicans that gay people can raise a child in a healthy environment, and that they can express real love instead of just lust in a marriage. If a gay person really wants to advocate for the acceptance of sexual expression, he or she can join or create another group that welcomes straight people with the same cause.

It's like if women's advocates started a global warming campaign. A lot of the people who disagree with women's rights also don't believe in climate change, so it could damage their point by association. Instead, a women's advocacy group should focus strictly on women's advocacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483403679.0" user="quaintquincidence" delta="False">
    <text>Hm, now I see better where you come from. But I *do* think Pride parades are about freedom of sexual expression. They are about accepting and removing shame from yours and others' sexuality. While I can see and agree (to a degree) on your point about the detriment of conflating goals, I think you are approaching this from the wrong side. One reason a large proportion of society has a hard time accepting LGBT people is precisely that it doesn't like talking about sex. Coming to it from another angle, you generally don't see the same extent of sexual displays at pro-gay marriage rallies. Because *then* it is the case that the goal is rather different.

In any case, however, I find your analogy very misguided. LGBT is much, *much* closer linked to sexual expression (even in the most charitable reading possible) than is women's rights to global warming. A closer analogy (though still not a good one, as I cannot think of one that is on the point atm) would be global warming :: oil dependency or women's rights :: sexual harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483390684.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>The point he is making is that gay groups should focus on gay issues, not issues that affect everyone. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483410179.0" user="quaintquincidence" delta="False">
    <text>But this is somewhat at the heart of gay issues, isn't it? What am I missing here? This sounds to me like someone saying to the Black Lives Matter movement to focus on black issues, not police brutality that affects everyone. Hold on...this is *exactly* what some people were saying!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483428379.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>It's not at the heart of gay issues. People don't like it, regardless of them being gay. The gay bit is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483475746.0" user="quaintquincidence" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that some people don't like witnessing expressive sexuality, regardless orientation, but I just cannot agree it is not part of gay issues. Saying that sounds almost as if you're being dim on purpose. To quote from the Wikipedia article on LGBT community:

*These communities generally celebrate pride, diversity, individuality, and sexuality. LGBT activists and sociologists see LGBT community-building as a counterbalance to heterosexism, homophobia, biphobia, transphobia, sexualism, and conformist pressures that exist in the larger society.*

I would say this is very much at the heart of that community and it's issues. You can try and argue that sexuality *shouldn't* be part of the gay issues. I don't exactly see how or why you can manage that, but you can try. But it is a fact, that it is a part of the gay issues. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483350255.0" user="busmans" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People are uncomfortable with public displays of sexuality. 

They must not be that uncomfortable. Pride parades are huge, and they're everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483352760.0" user="2074red2074" delta="False">
    <text>I should say the people who are uncomfortable with pride parades tend to be uncomfortable with public displays of sexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483388816.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>So they are trading off intentionally making nornal people think they are weird, for having some people come out of their shell. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483415801.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and I find it extremely odd how you think looking normal is more important than being comfortable with yourself. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483427037.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't make a single claim of that. Please don't put words in my mouth. In fact I made no claims at all, just tried to summarise what you said so I can understand</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483444912.0" user="decker_42" delta="False">
    <text>That's a very good point and strongly backs OP's view - overly gratuitous public displays of sex aren't going to do any good when it comes to proving family stability and adoption.

I believe your are very right sir. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483577124.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Gay are gay, for those reasons. They find men as better life partners, and enjoy male culture. You aren't gay for just sex. That's not how it works for most people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
