<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="36" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483634098.0" user="pupeno" delta="False">
    <text>I think pride parades have been a celebration of weird and extravagant and from that point of view, by themselves, don't do a lot for gay people. I've been attacked for saying this, but I don't think we have information that confirms or denies that pride parades have been a positive force for the acceptance of homosexuality. From that point of view, you are right, because the NSFW content, and weirdness would actually detract from the cause. It would not normalize homosexuality, it would make it even weirder for the person that's prejudiced or neutral.

There would be one case in which you are wrong though. Pride helps normalize edgy, weird behavior. If it succeeds at doing that, it will help people accept homosexuality when they feel it is a weird, edgy behavior.

You also need to take into consideration at which state in the evolution of a society the pride parade is happening. A pride parade in parts of middle east, Africa, etc. is a protest, it's a battle cry. I don't think those should have a lot of NSFW content and I think they generally don't. The pride parades in NYC and London are more like celebrations than protests. I think the festiveness there makes more sense.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
