<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483372991.0" user="xaedala" delta="False">
    <text>I understand what you're saying in regards to wanting to bring your family. You want them to see the community you now identify with and you don't want them to see that community negatively. However, it's important to understand the reason for this over-sexualisation here. 

As members of the LGBTQ+ community we don't necessarily have many places to express our sexuality, as even in places we aren't discriminated against it can feel uncomfortable to partake in a PDA or even dress in a sexy way, especially if people can 'tell' that you're part of the LGBTQ+ community. 

Pride takes this away for a lot of people, here they're able to dress in any way they want, they can feel sexual if they want to and they feel at home around others who are accepting of them. 

Whilst full nudity may be inappropriate for young audiences I feel it may not be the fault of the pride parade here. Ask yourself how receptive your family are towards pride, and also towards nudity/partial nudity. Explain this to them, how your community needs an outlet, and more importantly a SAFE outlet, where they feel comfortable in themselves. 

Not every member of the community is lucky enough to pass for straight, or lucky enough to live somewhere accepting, or with an accepting family. Remember that asking people to change themselves in a pride parade goes against the acceptance of our fellow LGBTQ+ family.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483468946.0" user="Renzolol" delta="False">
    <text>Where do you think straight people are expressing their sexuality? Do you think being able to see a straight sex scene in a TV is the only thing stopping me from whipping my dick out in the street and claiming to be proud of my sexuality? I don't do it because I'm not a degenerate, not because there are sex scenes on TV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483484944.0" user="quaintquincidence" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any reason to feel ashamed of your sexuality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483685154.0" user="Renzolol" delta="False">
    <text>I have been made to feel ashamed of my sexuality, yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483751997.0" user="quaintquincidence" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't you have liked a way to counterbalance that?

I am not trying to plant some sort of a polemical trick on you or "win" an argument. It's just that I know this can sometimes be a driving factor and wanted to see where do you diverge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483707688.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As members of the LGBTQ+ community we don't necessarily have many places to express our sexuality,

Genuine question, what are some places that a normal (by which I mean not famous or in any way special) straight person can express their sexuality in day to day life? The only one I can really think of is nightclubs, and there are also gay nightclubs, so that is a non starter as far as the comparison goes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484873867.0" user="alyjiahalyjiah" delta="False">
    <text>Idk I don’t think anybody likes pda from anybody </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
