<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483257418.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who is also bisexual and who is also not a big fan of pride parades I will push back from a different angle.  I think that the identification of lgtbq as a unique cultural group is misunderstanding, it is different from a group like African Americans who can live their whole lives together and in many cases are separate from the rest of society.  Most of Lgtbq stuff is about topics that are sexual in nature, so it would seem strange to not emphasize the part of the group that is shared in common amongst the people.  It’s would be like an NRA rally trying to tone down  the guns so that people are too intimidated to show up.  It’s the reason why this group exists in the first place so why pretend that it isn’t an extremely important part of it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483290822.0" user="darkforcedisco" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it is different from a group like African Americans who live their whole lives together and in many cases are separate from the rest of society

Wait, what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483294781.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>Poorly worded attempt to say people are born into the African American community and some people spend their whole lives living mostly arround other black people.  Very few people are born into the lgtb community and it’s a community formed arround a specific subject.  It isn’t a generalized community that something like White Suburbia is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483306707.0" user="darkforcedisco" delta="False">
    <text>I kiiiinda get what you're saying, but would argue that being born LGBT makes you a part of the community as well. Your association with said community is how we usually associate people with being "in," no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483312729.0" user="LusoAustralian" delta="False">
    <text>That's not the point he's making. You're using community as a generic collective noun instead of as a descriptor of the people who you surround yourself with and see every day. While black people might live and interact with 90% black people all their life the same is categorically not true for LGBT people. It's extremely unlikely to live in a local community where almost everyone is LGBT. As such the very concept of an LGBT community has to be centred around sexuality and sexual themes, it's inherent to a collective based on sexual orientation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483328680.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>I actually probably couldn’t have said it better myself.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485808349.0" user="darkforcedisco" delta="False">
    <text>Ah ok, now I understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483313094.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>No there is a difference between, being born gay bi etc and being a member of the lgtb community.  There are many gay people who are not members because they don’t like the culture and don’t want to be associated with it.  The community itself if different that a term used to describe an orreintation.  For example a Chinese kid raised by Kenyan migrants in Norway is not really a part of the Chinese community in any meaningful way, but he is Chinese. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483301278.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>America is more segregated now than it was in the 1940s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483380401.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>You know full well that's nonsense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483410952.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>shoot. I did a research project on reparations and I swear i came across that. I probably got 1940s confused with "40 years ago". Segregation is still perhaps one of the biggest issues facing the US education system however and US housing policy in the post war era trapped blacks into poor neighborhoods through redlining and suburbanization. 

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/answer-sheet/wp/2013/08/29/report-public-schools-more-segregated-now-than-40-years-ago/?utm_term=.4916c6ffaa15</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
