<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483344379.0" user="gavriloe" delta="False">
    <text>There are two schools of thought on this issue (probably many more, but that's besides the point). Some people believe that the LGBT community should try to conform to traditional, heterosexual standards and strive to be accepted as equal citizens. Others believe (the radical/ radical feminist viewpoint) that traditional monogamous relationships and the obsession over the nuclear family is oppressive. They feel that just as gays and lesbians challenged straight notions of decency by demanding equality, they must also challenge the straight ideal of monogamous relationships. They believe that society has an expectation of people looking for and staying in permanent relationships. It's not to say that everyone should be polyamorous; people certainly have a right to be monogamous if they wish. However, society still judges people for sleeping around, and this is precisely what (some) of the people you are talking about are pushing back against.

&amp;gt; In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible


On the other hand, people would say that you need to be more inclusive of their sexuality. I went to pride parades growing up, when I was like 4 or 5 years, and I don't think it's really an issue at all for children. 



Everything I've said here is all fine, and well, but there is still the nuts and bolts of the matter to talk about. Maybe people in pride parades "should" tone down the explicit content, but how are you going to make them do that? If you force them out then you've completely undermined the point of a *pride* parade in the first place. The whole idea is to accept and celebrate people not matter what. I would say that it is societal expectations that prevents pride from being fully inclusive. The members of pride are not out to include society, but to be included by it (if that makes sense).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
