<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483289845.0" user="joshrichardsonsson" delta="False">
    <text>Why? 

I’m a straight guy and I always saw it as a celebration of your sexuality. 

A sexuality that has been historically oppressed by the same dipshits telling you that you can’t whip your flamboyant dick out and wave it around with pride. Fuck that.

What better way to celebrate sexuality than with sexual demonstrations? 

You think tucking your balls in and dressing like an amish person to the parade will make the homophobic dumbasses suddenly stop caring about what two men do in the privacy of their bedroom?

Bigotry goes deeper than that. 

At the end of the day what unites you guys isn’t your talent, or your intelligence or anything. It’s the fact that you are LGBTQ+
Obviously you’re talented. Obviously you have every other great or horrible trait anyone else has. That’s not what the celebration is about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484206534.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>I think toning it down would definitely convince people on the fence that LGBT community aren't a bunch of sexual deviants. As someone who's part of the community, it's not how I like to see myself represented to the rest of society </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484936105.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484959893.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/do_meth – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+do_meth&amp;amp;message=do_meth+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05xz8p/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488114864.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>What's wrong with being a sexual deviant? (assuming consenting adults and all)  Wouldn't it be better to convince people on the fence that sexual deviance is okay?  That's certainly a broader and more inclusive goal. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
