<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483259353.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Is it wrong to celebrate sex? It’s something everyone does and sexual attraction is the single thing that bonds every gay man. Gay sex wasn’t universally legal in the US until the early 2000s. PRIDE is a celebration of all aspects of gayness and it would be ridiculous to censor it to make people more comfortable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483272410.0" user="SlawPJoe" delta="False">
    <text>Hetero married dude. I think people express themselves differently. You could call me repressed or anything you like but other than generalities I don't really wanna talk about sex with a buddy, a stranger, or anyone but my wife.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483286393.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>Comepletely fine and I honestly agree with you.  I you on a personal level, but I fail to see the harm is asking others to be less expressive of themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483289176.0" user="darkforcedisco" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of gay people don't either. But the ones that want to should be able to.

You can't ignore that for a long time, talking about gay *kissing* out loud was taboo, and in some cases, would get you locked up at best. There are some places where it still happens. 

Compare it, for example, with Mardi Gras. If you don't want to enjoy it, don't. But there are a lot of people that enjoy that type of partying. For a long time, the thought of anything like that featuring homosexuals was super taboo. Now, if people want to be too PDA and enjoy being risque in public while gay, they can do that, and should be judged the same way heterosexuals that do it are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483382163.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>And hetero people who do it are judged poorly too....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485803835.0" user="darkforcedisco" delta="False">
    <text>So basically exactly what my last sentence says then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487386566.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but the difference is it's a far larger proportion of the gay community. That's why it reflects poorly on the gay community as a whole.



I'm not saying it should. We should treat weirdos individually. But when a "gay pride" parade is filled with the "weirdos" it's hard not to associate weirdo with gay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483291904.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Great! But almost every member of LGBT will tell you stories of being shamed or forced to repress their sexuality. Pride parades are for gay people to express every aspect of their sexuality without social consequence. You don’t have to watch it or talk to them just understand that despite the hilariousness and flamboyance there’s a genuine reason for them to be so over the top.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483279715.0" user="HeadsOfLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>Being proud of your sexuality is one thing of course, it’s another thing to walk along waving 10 inch dildos around...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483285677.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>How so? It’s sexual expression that is meant to challenge people’s prejudices. There is no logical reason for people to hide sexuality in the way that they do besides being shameful or uncomfortable. Pride is about the opposite of that. It’s about expressing unconventional sexuality and people’s willingness to accept themselves and to accept others for it. Sure it’s silly but that’s kind of required to make it genuine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483288712.0" user="HeadsOfLeviathan" delta="False">
    <text>Some people aren’t comfortable with having to explain to their three year old child what a dildo is. There is a reason to hide sexuality, gay or straight, and it’s called public decency. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483295515.0" user="Inz0mbiac" delta="False">
    <text>Then dont bring your 3 year old to the parade. I miss several parades every year. It's very easy to avoid a parade</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483383075.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>They are big and in public. Can exactly just avoid them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483566465.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>Uhhh, yeah, you can. Just don't go out that day, or don't take a route that brings you in contact with the parade? It not like the route is some big secret to trap unsuspecting homophobes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483586193.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>The pist above said how it was super easy to avoid them, and it won't impact anyone. You have suggested not going out. That's a big impact</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483596066.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then dont bring your 3 year old to the parade. I miss several parades every year. It's very easy to avoid a parade

Exactly when did it say that?

&amp;gt; or don't take a route that brings you in contact with the parade? 

And you ignored this completely. I haven't been to a parade in years *without trying*. They're not some massive all-encompassing thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483620295.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>In London, the parades are big and very much in places that people go on a regular day out. Can't avoid them unless you replan your day</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483644979.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>[Yeah, I'm not seeing this as a problem still](https://www.pinknews.co.uk/images/2017/07/Screen-Shot-2017-07-06-at-09.20.39.jpg). It's not a massive inconvenience to avoid that parade route for a day. There's no shortage of things to do in London off of the parade route.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488897907.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>That goes through A LOT of central london.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488909288.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>And doesn't go through A LOT more of it.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488926733.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, So i would have to avoid some of the best parts of london I visit on most weekends. 


To avoid it, I would have to completely change my schedule. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488931396.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>Poor you? If you're trying to garner sympathy because of the horror of having to go to a pub a couple blocks down you're getting nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488935152.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I never asked for sympathy. It was stated it would be super easy to avoid and I wouldnt have to change my plans. I have factually shown thats not true, helped by the route map you kindly supplied. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488936471.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>Literally no one stated you wouldn't have to change your plans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488947739.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>" I miss several parades every year. It's very easy to avoid a parade"

That was up the comment chain I replied to. 


"Just don't go out that day, or don't take a route that brings you in contact with the parade?"


And this was you. 



So, what you are now saying is that yes, the parade is indeed a material hinderance on my life. You agree. Excelelnt. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488959841.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>Uh huh, again, no one ever said you wouldn't have to change plans. Yeah, if you want to avoid something, you have to avoid it. I do agree that it may cause a minor inconvenience to you, yeah, but there was never any disagreement there. The only thing we've stated that you've chosen to argue against is that is very easy to avoid a parade. And it still is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30489024947.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>OK, we just disagree that having to fundamnetally change my plans counts as "easy to avoid"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30489030776.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>If you really want to consider a change of plans to be this difficult feat, be my guest, but its as easy as sending a text dude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30489062587.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, its completely changing the plans for the day. e.g. cant go to yautcha, a restaurant i go to a lot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30489070963.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>"Hey I forgot theres a parade going on lets go to X instead"

Wow. So hard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484894830.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484907093.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>u/do_meth – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+do_meth&amp;amp;message=do_meth+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05x3e6/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484916478.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484924628.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/do_meth – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+do_meth&amp;amp;message=do_meth+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05xk3i/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484925522.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484925540.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488360087.0" user="dang1010" delta="False">
    <text>Ahh yes, thats a great way to build a unified front and instill in the minds of children that it's perfectly okay and normal to be gay.  "Sorry kids, we can't go out today because of the Pride parade because it's too inappropriate." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488400100.0" user="Alteffor" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not about to avoid pride I'm just saying acting like its some massive inconvenience to avoid if you want to is just garbage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485920952.0" user="Inz0mbiac" delta="False">
    <text>Yes you can. I work in a major downtown and I wanted to go to the pride parade last year, and I still missed it. The parades happen on Saturday mornings. The parties are usually contained to the gay bars. It's really easy to miss a pride parade</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483300595.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>I’m fine with people being uncomfortable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483319486.0" user="pensivegargoyle" delta="False">
    <text>So they don't explain it. A weird costume is just a weird costume until someone explains the context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483368382.0" user="blazershorts" delta="False">
    <text>If these events are going to be as explicitly sexual as this thread is making them out to be, then there needs to be a better effort to keep minors away from them.  Maybe require advisory warnings for any advertisements or press statements from parade organizers.  

I mean, even the most liberal of cities have decency laws, so there has to be a balance between protecting that public interest and the interest of those participating in the parade.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483291006.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>Which is actually hilarious.  I see your point, but I also think we are a little too sensitive about sex.  It’s not something dirty or evil.  It’s an enjoyable part of life and honestly as long as you are involved in a task that is consenting, not involving children, and not dangerous to your or your partners health I don’t really care. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483283906.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>"Sexual attraction is the single thing that bonds every gay man." That is just... not true. Is sex the only thing that keeps a hetero relationship going? No. Love, trust, communcation, mutual respect and interest. Those are some of the biggest factors in any relationship, gay or not. Second, he's not saying to censor it, he's just saying to tone it down a little.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483298325.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Im not saying being gay is only about sex I’m saying that sexual attraction is the only single thing besides gender that EVERY gay man has in common. Also sex is deeply connected to love or else gay men would fall in love with women.
And asking someone to tone it down is asking for someone to censor themselves which just brings back feelings of being in the closet. The ultimate act of “toning it down”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483574844.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Sex is not what "every gay man has in common." Being gay isn't just sexual attraction! You can be gay without wanting to have sex.  And what's your logic around that part where sex is deeply connected to love, or else gay people would fall in love with women? Men arent just attracted to other men because they have a dick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484406249.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Of course they are. Your assertion is ridiculous. Yes I find other things attractive about men beyond their dicks but being gay is a sexual preference and if you aren’t sexually attracted to men you aren’t gay </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484822695.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>I... what is your logic here? Gay isnt strictly a sexual attraction. I am sexually attracted to men, but what i'm saying is that it isn't everything. Its a tiny part of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484833868.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>It all comes from a sexual attraction to the same sex. What else is there to being gay? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485266489.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Is the only thing to being hetero the sex? No, of course it's not. It's about enjoying your partners personality and being comfortable around someone you love. I'm not saying that's how you feel in your relationship. Maybe you're in it for the sex, i don't know, and i don't judge. But don't say that sex is the only reason people are gay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485273402.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>There’s more to a gay relationship than sex but being sexually attracted to men is the only qualification for being gay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485277072.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Or romantically attracted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485436577.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>Sexual attraction is a prerequisite</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486164202.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>It is most definetly not. I can be gay and asexual (though i'm not.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486177621.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>No you fucking can’t</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487303499.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe i got something wrong. I can't be homoSEXUAL and asexual. I can still be gay and asexual, since gay works for either homosexual or homoromantic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483317692.0" user="LucasOIntoxicado" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever fell in love with someone from your own gender? Sexual attraction is directly related to those things you mentioned; if it weren't, 90% of teenage boys would date their male best friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483583886.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, i'm queer myself, and no, i judge my sexuality upon whether i enjoy the quality of their personality and behavings, rather than their genitals. Gay sex isn't only what's differentiating gay and hetero relationships. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484887983.0" user="Neetoburrito33" delta="False">
    <text>YES IT IS! Why dont you fall in love with women? Do they have unattractive personalities or behaviors? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485275115.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>Yea, they do. I'm not appealed by their fashion, general behaviours, personalities, general feministic tendencies. I like men, but not only for the sex!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488127717.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>And they say gay men don't have a misogyny problem! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488602219.0" user="Cassycasuist" delta="False">
    <text>I... don't. I'm not oppresing women. I fight for equal rights, equal pay, i believe that everyone is equal. But i'm just not attracted to them, relationship-wise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483671864.0" user="Joe_Baker_bakealot" delta="False">
    <text>Every single argument for sexual pride parades revolves around this idea that America as a whole and has a fucked up culture around sex. Fair enough. But *nobody* outside of the gay community sees pride parades this way. Pride parades aren't percieved as being held for some sexual revolution for everyone. It looks like a bunch of gay people being way too sexual for comfort in public for the current sexual atmosphere in America. If pride parades are either portrayed or percieved as how they've been described in most of the conversations, then that'd be great, but in my experience none of them have been.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
