<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483441913.0" user="business-of-ferrets" delta="False">
    <text>This is actually situated within a larger debate. Any social minority (which, in Western society basically means anyone apart from white straight men) has two possible paths towards acceptance. 

The first is taking a hard stance on the issues that you find are important to the group you identify with even if they are in conflict with general societal norms (depending on the country: abortion, gender neutral bathrooms, etc. etc.). These people are often labeled as 'feminazis' or more general as 'SJWs' as people that are 'just trying to live their lives' do not understand why anyone would contest current social norms. 

The whole point of social norms is that they should be followed. Even if you are aware of these norms, they are ingrained in us: Americans have an aversion to nudity, Brits to awkward social situations and many Northern Europeans to physical contact. That's why the second path of acceptance has a more neutral stance on the issue. People following the second path are more hesitant towards being hard-liners as they feel it is counter-productive towards their goal. They want to be seen as 'normal' and, following your example, parading in the nude in the USA will not get you accepted as 'normal'. 
(for a good visual example of this debate see this video from contrapoints. It's about transsexuality but the general idea is the same: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j1dJ8whOM8E)

The thing is (and this is where I finally get to my point) is that the second path doesn't really lead to acceptance. Homosexual people are not completely accepted in Western societies. Woman aren't even really accepted. You are accepted in this society when you act like a white straight man. Being a career woman is okay, but wanting maternity leave is not. Being a homosexual is fine and having a boyfriend as a man is fine but you can't talk about homosexual sex. 

The only true way of getting taken seriously and accepted is to provoke and shift the window of what we find normal. This goes for race, gender, sexuality and much more. The NSFW content is therefore crucial to pride. If it wasn't a thorn in the eye of the 'normal' person, it wouldn't change anything. Just think about this: how often did a quiet, peaceful (not promoting violence here!) and uncontroversial protest really change anything?

Additionally, as said, your aversion to nudity is cultural. The puritanical roots of the USA is exactly why nudity is used in pride. It is used to provoke and to make people that are ashamed of being homosexual realise that they are not alone and that it is nothing to be ashamed of. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483530864.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The only true way of getting taken seriously and accepted is to provoke and shift the window of what we find normal. This goes for race, gender, sexuality and much more. The NSFW content is therefore crucial to pride. If it wasn't a thorn in the eye of the 'normal' person, it wouldn't change anything. Just think about this: how often did a quiet, peaceful (not promoting violence here!) and uncontroversial protest really change anything?

Not uncontroversial, per se, but a lot of the protests during the civil rights era accomplished quite a lot through modest, peaceful, demure protesting. It was more like "we're going to sit in this diner where you don't want us," not "we're going to get raunchy with white women (willingly, of course) on the diner counter."

In other words, you can be "in your face" without being depraved and raunchy. Pride, though I'm a huge fan and go as often as I can, too often falls into the latter category. 

And I also have to wonder if this is really particularly effective in changing people's views. If you're a bigoted homophobe who hates the idea of men being with one another, which is more likely to make you more accepting of the concept: a bunch of guys who look just like you holding a rainbow banner marching down mainstreet, or seeing dudes dressed like butterflies in assless chaps next to the dudes blowing one another in the middle of the street? Maybe neither, but I find it hard to imagine that the latter is *more* convincing. If someone doesn't like homosexuality, practicing homosexual acts in public in front of their face is likely a poor way to go about gaining their acceptance. 

Idk man, I just feel that if your goal is to win over the bigots there *has* to be some middle ground between "fitting in" and "practicing your deepthroating skills on a hogtied man in the street" that might be a better way to ease the bigots into it. 

Finally, can I get you to expand on your "Woman aren't even really accepted" point? It seems to me that women are practically *revered* in Western society. For example, I'm planning to ask my LTR GF to marry me. This will involve me taking her out someplace nice, all on my dime and where I'll probably be pulling out the chair for her, to present her with a stone-laden ring that accounts for a significant portion of my yearly salary which will be used as currency in my bid that she *might* accept my proposal to be lifelong partners. As Joe Rogan joked in his early standup, the allure of pussy is *so powerful* that dudes are literally willing to *blow themselves up* in the *hope* that they might score some in another dimension. It just seems to me that the plight of women in our society is being over-lionized, not "aren't even really accepted." They're not just accepted, but loved on, lusted over, pursued, cherished, valued, and revered. Ours is a society that teaches men that if they're in a situation involving limited lifeboats and a sinking ship, spots ought to go to the children (which makes sense) and women (which really doesn't) first. That's not just "accepted," that's "seen as more valuable than men." So how can you make that point is what I'm wondering, in not so many words. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
