<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="48" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30484346135.0" user="turtlecage" delta="False">
    <text>I live in a big city and therefore our pride parade is a huge party, and yes with lots of skimpy outfits and nods to the kink community, etc., 
My mom took me to the pride parade every summer starting when I was a toddler. She essentially was trying to make an association in my mind of LGBT = Happy, good, smiling people having a great time. I remember being handed some candy by a giant beautiful drag queen. It was fun. 

Later on in life this association was important for me because it turns out I am a member of the LGBT. In addition to being very queer positive my mom was always sex positive. Sex was never a shameful discussion in my household. I don’t see nudity or sexuality and feel uncomfortable. I’m not uncomfortable with my own body. I have an awesomely healthy relationship to sexuality in general. 

TL;DR bring your kids to pride because it won’t hurt them. It’s fun. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
