<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483545537.0" user="OhNoMellon" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're a little to focused on pride being an event that has to be right for you. Though I understand if you want more representation of your beliefs.


Pride has a different view on sexuality than you do, but they (as well as many 
other influences) are still pushing to make being gay normal and accepted. Maybe they push some away but they draw others near, and those who are drawn near are a voice that draws even some that were pushed away.

I do understand that you want your version of the culture to have more representation. This would be great but you don't need to replace one with the other as long as they're both beneficial which I think they are. Maybe pride might not be for you, but it is a good thing for many which others in this thread show better than I could.


I think maybe the view that you could shift towards is, "I wish there was an event as popular as pride that would appeal to more conventional values and represents my culture more." </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
