<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483266884.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483274434.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>This isn’t a disagreement, and there a difference between reductionism and emphasis.  Very few people would say that being gay or bi is just about sex, but is sex not one of the key defining features that separates these group from the rest of society.  There is nothing wrong with sex it isn’t evil and it’s fun.  I say this as someone in a long distance monogamous relationship.  It’s ok to embrace sex as part of your life it needed be something to be ashamed of or feared.  I may have overreacted to your comment I understand.

Also mods I would make a request if we don’t delete the posts that don’t necessarily follow the rules in this post.  The lgtb community has big internal discussion about this and a lot people get very depressed and upset about these things.  So I would ask if you let them vent and not get deleted. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483333662.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>We will be removing all comments that break our rules. If that is a concern other subs may be better suited for the purpose but on this sub, our rules will apply and we will enforce them. 

If you have any further questions or requests please message the mods by messaging r/changemyview.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483290182.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Loktharion – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+Loktharion&amp;amp;message=Loktharion+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e04y79g/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
