<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483289794.0" user="Nuthead77" delta="False">
    <text>Hi I'm new to this sub, but here's my take.  You can look at it from two angles.

1 by your description you know that PRIDE tends to be very open and sexualized.  That is the standard so your proposition would be something different than what is the current PRIDE events, a change.  Would everyone else who the event represents feel the same?  How difficult would this be for everyone who is liberated and feels free by the event?  For a lot of people this can be a highly therapeutic event that they look forward to every time to just be open and themselves, or even purposefully "extra" as a healthy outlet due to the repressed feeling that many in the LGBTQ+ community feel in their everyday lives in a heteronormative society.  After all it is about the members of the community and not necessarily those outside, or am I wrong on that?  So with that said I think it's great that you have a vision for a different type of celebration and I'm sure many others would love to join.  Shouldn't that be up to you and those who espouse your beliefs to start?  Maybe call it Pride Family and encourage as much crossover as possible.  This could even be combined with the current events on the day before and after.  Set a goal of inclusion and make it clear that everyone , including children, is welcome.  You could even try to turn it into a community outreach and encourage those who would never consider going to the current event to attend.

2 Since it is based upon sexual and romantic preferences, gender, sexual curiosities and discovery it will by nature be more sexually open then events based on other things.  Would a simple parade and event draw as many visitors?  Would the tradition continue?  Would straight people still go to Mardi Gras if it weren't for all of the NSFW activity there?  And that's not even an event specifically based upon something that has a sexual component by nature. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483397424.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Your post is unreadable. Please edit out the bold and size</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483588608.0" user="Nuthead77" delta="False">
    <text>I posted on mobile and it looks completely normal to me.  I'm not sure how it happened, how do I change it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483617360.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I have no idea :(</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486174186.0" user="Nuthead77" delta="False">
    <text>I figured it out, I put the number sign before the 1 and 2 and it changed the font size to header, thanks for the heads up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487235976.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Ah great to know thanks</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
