<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483428139.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as

What about acceptance and understanding of the human body? About not being ashamed of what we are? Maybe those are not values you personally hold, but enough people apparently do.

&amp;gt;However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride.

I cant speak for the community, but isnt at least a big part of the intent to promote a social shift to make things no longer be inappropriate? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483434466.0" user="Joe_Rogan_is_bae" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What about acceptance and understanding of the human body? 

Just because I don't want my kids to see grown men penetrating themselves in the street doesn't mean I don't accept the human body. Jesus christ.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483449516.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>Sex is a normal part of the human body, if not even the entire point of it. What is inacceptance if not trying to exclude something from public/social life? If not thinking of something as "this should not be seen"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484218407.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not ashamed of the human body or my sexuality, but that doesn't mean i would go to a strip club with my kids. Some things are not age appropriate for young children, and there's a time and place to learn about it all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484372837.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Some things are not age appropriate

Why sex though? To keep the children "pure"? For one, thats a lost cause with the internet anyway, but more importantly, why is purity a good thing to promote? Are you for abstinence only sex ed too? If children were likely to be traumatised at the sight of other people having sex, psychologists would be overrun by those cases, but theyre not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484640634.0" user="MythDestructor" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you consider it inappropriate? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484658076.0" user="CrabStarShip" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't you want your kids to see that? It most likely has to do with puritanical views that society has forced on you and your children. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
