<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483297601.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>Dan Savage has consistently said two things on this topic, either of which might at least give you another perspective.

First can be found in this [column from 2012](https://www.thestranger.com/seattle/SavageLove?oid=14850048), where Dan notes that these types of parades clearly haven't set the LGBT community back too much, considering that they've been occurring in major cities for many years and these communities have never been stronger. Cities with the biggest parades are often the most accepting, although granted this may be flipping correlation and causation.

The other point Dan has made is pretty simple: the "freaks" were the ones that supported the gay and trans community from day one. Straight swingers, sadists, and masochists were among the first to rally behind the gay cause, even though it probably hurt their own political cause in doing so. To an extent, the LGBT community "owes" some support and some gratitude for people who stuck with them in removing sodomy laws and eventually legalizing gay marriage in the US. The crazy stuff in some parades is sort of a salute to this past, a way to let that freak flag fly and be accepting of all, even if it's quite offensive to even fairly accepting people. If you drop the allies from the parade, you're sort of turning your back on your staunchest advocates.

I sort of agree with you, personally: I have a lot of conservative family members who would be freaked out by some sections of the parade and I'm a bit of a prude myself. In my mind though, it sort of sets a new benchmark for what's "freaky" and suddenly a person who likes to swing both ways doesn't seem so weird. Consider the ["door-in-the-face technique"](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Door-in-the-face_technique) which you sometimes see in sales. When you ask someone to accept something really crazy, which they'll recoil from or clearly reject, you can then more readily present them another option, which is less extreme, and they'll be more likely to accept it. It's a little underhanded in a way, but it's not really a trick, just an argumentative technique.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483379188.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>It may not set them.back, but it gives people like me pause. I am left wing on almost all social issues, and don't understand why anyone would have a problem with gay people. However these type of parades make it hard to not associate gay with "weird".


I know it's a small subset, but that's the message it's sending.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483458187.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>I've always seen the flamboyancy as being a positive part of the message. The freedom to confidently express one's sexuality can only be a good thing. 

It's empowering for people whose sexuality has been historically, culturally condemned. It's probably also empowering for the rest of us (hetero, cis, etc.) to be more open about our own sexuality (and maybe try new things that we otherwise wouldn't have tried for fear of being labeled?).

Just like you "don't understand why anyone would have a problem with gay people," so do the rest of us not understand why you'd label sexual liberty as "weird." That word has a negative connotation to it despite there being nothing wrong with sexuality, or the expression of one's sexuality.

In fact, I think it's safe to say that sex is just about everybody's favorite thing to do with each other. Why should there be any negative connotation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483536881.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>The same reason why I dont think you should be able to jack it in the middle of the road. Being sexual is great, and you should be able to have sex with every other consenting adult in every way possible, but you dont have to let everybody see. Other people aren't consenting to see you having sex and people shouldnt be expected to be confronted with things of an overtly sexual nature when crossing a road.


I happen to think nudity and sex is something special you should share with just loved ones. I mean I'm from Amsterdam and I just dont go to Pride events for that reason, but I also dont really care if they do it in a manner I disagree with, but I do think it's counterproductive if you want to be treaten equally to everyone else. Most people think the heterosexual guy rubbing up on a girl in public is weird. Same for the two gay guys on a boat during a Canal Pride event.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483557908.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>So your objection is based on the fact that you're... offended... but you can't really say why, or why that matters...? And then you go on to appeal to the status quo... 

What's so sacred about a naked human body that it should only exist in private? Obviously, masturbating in the middle of the street would be a distraction and a dangerous road hazard, but is there any legitimate objection to public sexuality other than "it's gross?"

Western culture is so weird in the way it deems certain rituals to be necessarily private affairs. These archaic rules are residual of religious fundamentalism, I think. 

Pushing the boundaries of what's "appropriate" public sexuality is a great, and very productive, part of the LGBTQ movement. It's definitely a part of the movement that benefits heteros quite a lot. I don't understand how you could object to it beyond "it's yucky."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483634824.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So your objection is based on the fact that you're... offended...


I didnt say I was offended or that it was offensive. So no. I disagree with it. And I dont like it.

&amp;gt;but you can't really say why, or why that matters...? 


I did say why. I think nudity/sex should be reserved to your loved ones. I dont force anyone to adhere to my view, but that is what I believe.


&amp;gt;And then you go on to appeal to the status quo... 


Did you forget the point of the original post? It said that the Pride events are counterproductive to its goals since people are less likely to accept your sexuality if you bring it in a way people abhore. The status quo is a central point of that argument so hugely relevant.


&amp;gt;What's so sacred about a naked human body that it should only exist in private?


I think it makes it more special to be intimate with each other if you only share it together. Again: I'm not the one trying to delegitimize the other person's point of view or asking anyone to conform to mine. That's what you are doing.


&amp;gt;Obviously, masturbating in the middle of the street would be a distraction and a dangerous road hazard, but is there any legitimate objection to public sexuality other than "it's gross?"


So people should be able to flash to women and children at their own discretion? Masturbating in full vorw of a preschool? Before I can answer your question I must know the depths of your opinion on what public sexuality is okay and what isnt.


&amp;gt;Western culture is so weird in the way it deems certain rituals to be necessarily private affairs. These archaic rules are residual of religious fundamentalism, I think. 


This isn't unique to Western culture. Islamic culture forces women to cover themselves as to not arouse possible male suitors. If anything Western culture has a lot more freedom in nudity and sexuality than every other culture in the world except maybe some primitive tribes.


&amp;gt;Pushing the boundaries of what's "appropriate" public sexuality is a great, and very productive, part of the LGBTQ movement. It's definitely a part of the movement that benefits heteros quite a lot. I don't understand how you could object to it beyond "it's yucky."



Explain how? I thought the point of the movement was to be how being a certain sexuality is okay, not that you should be able to ejaculate in front of a bus full of kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483669809.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>The point is you're sharing your hetero-normative rules for how people ought to behave, based on... your feelings. It's literally a matter of you being offended. You don't have a reason beyond "I just don't like it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483682577.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>It's only a "hetero normative" rule because there is no such thing as a straight pride event. It doesn't really make any more sense for gay people to be overtly sexual in public than straight people. It's part of the contract of society that we try not to expose people to actions they don't want to be exposed to, if possible and reasonable. Many people don't wish to be confronted with unconsensual nudity, so we try to keep that sort of thing to people who have consented and are willing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483692180.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>It'd be more accurate to say that we have a social obligation to not encroach upon each others' autonomy when it doesn't hurt us. Gays, straights, whatever, should be able to be as sexually expressive in public as they desire to be, so long as that expression doesn't violate others' rights or autonomy.

However, you're not protected from "being offended" by the sight of a person who's more comfortable with their body and their sexuality than you are. If you are offended by that, that's your problem. It's not up to others to behave in ways that conform to your hetero-normative rules.

The reason for y(our) fixation on the censorship of nudity is an archaic residual of religious fundamentalism. Get over it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483738516.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; as that expression doesn't violate others' rights or autonomy

I guess the argument is these parades can get very close to that fuzzy border, and it doesn't do gay acceptance any favours.

And I would never say I was offended about anything, for the record. It's just sub optimal if your true goal is acceptance, at least these days when there is far less overt bigotry to actually fight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483741384.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>The civil rights movement in the 60s had people like you too. "You negroes would get a lot more support if you weren't such an inconvenience." Every movement will have tone police like you I guess–telling the oppressed how to protest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483778602.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>It's not tone policing as we aren't telling people what to say, we are telling people how we feel and how it changes us when they behave the way they do. We are not saying not to do a thing, we are telling you the consequence that will have on our opinions of you, as is our right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483789827.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>Just like the 1960s civil rights "ally" warned blacks, 

"I'd support you negroes if you didn't hog all the chairs at my favorite diner. It's my right to tell you the consequence that will have on our opinions of you"

Yep. You're tone policing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483879048.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>OK, lets flip it. If you are a movement, what rights are you trying to attain? The problem is there is no defined end goal, so you are continuing with the tantrum long after the thing you were fighting against has gone away. It looks no different to me than a teenager shouting "YOU JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND ME" while slamming their bedroom door. It's laughable, petulant, and drives people away.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483942953.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>I said the same thing about the negroes in the 1960s and nobody listened. They carried on with their sit-ins. Amen, brother.

No, wait. You  just made a terrible analogy.

It'd be more like, you're born a teenager, and society had historically, and presently, condemned people like you for being a teenager. You grow up your whole life suppressing your totally valid feelings, because you've been conditioned to repress those feelings, because you, and billions of others, have been told those feelings are wrong, and that having those feelings makes you a bad person. Then, you finally accept yourself because you're part of a society that at least "lets" people be teenagers "as long as they don't shove it in muh face" (hocks phlegm, aims for spittoon). And, to celebrate your pride in being a member of a group that has overcome historical, and present, marginalization, beating, bullying, rape, torture, lynching, etc., you confidently do something that represents your experience as a teenager. You motorboat another consenting teenager's thonged asscheeks.

And then the camera pans back to /u/mancubus314159 who has a sour look of disgust, because being a teenager is icky, and he doesn't want other people to be exposed to the icky thing. If he accepted the icky thing, then maybe he is actually icky, and that just wouldn't do. No, not at all. I'm not icky, because, as I am part of the society that has been conditioned to believe, being icky makes me a bad person. So, again, trust me, I am not icky.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483953527.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand people doing pride parades as a celebration of the rights they have won. That's totally valid. But people in that situation thinking they are misunderstood and the only gay in the village nowadays is just silly, because nobody cares what gender you want to fuck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483966520.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483988215.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/iSunMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+iSunMonkey&amp;amp;message=iSunMonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05d73s/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483990042.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483991504.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>If you want to appeal, use the link.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483997944.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484380877.0" user="Hero17" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; nobody cares what gender you want to fuck.

Except for bakers

https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/04/us/politics/supreme-court-sides-with-baker-who-turned-away-gay-couple.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484559241.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>Fair point!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483692464.0" user="refreshx2" delta="False">
    <text>S/he does have a reason beyond "I just don't like it" -- that they think that nudity should be reserved for loved ones. Maybe you disagree and are interpretting that as they just don't like it, but that's an incorrect interpretation.

They make some good points and it would be worth thinking about them in the future to see if you can understand where they are coming from. I think it's an important perspective to understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483696256.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>That's not a reason. That's just a deeper hole into 'because I don't like it.' It doesn't explain anything beyond personal preference... beyond being offended.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483749592.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>You sound like a child who keeps asking 'why' on any answer you give. I've given you the reason why I dont like it, which is a perfectly valid reason to not like something and is much deeper than 'I dont like it', I've given you examples of public sexuality that I hope you agree are over the line (but refuse to answer), I've touched on the subject of consent for bystanders and I've explained to you why it's counterproductive to the stated goal of it being okay to be a certain sexuality. 


You have given nothing but straw men, personal attacks, argumentums ab absurdum and a general whine out of a limited paradigm of it being a remnant of religious institutions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483753693.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>I could take you down an endless rabbit hole of 'whys', and they would all ultimately reveal that it's "just personal preference." It's you being offended. It's not hard to see. Nor would it be hard for you to investigate introspectively.

&amp;gt; consent for bystanders

Imagine the audacity of that woman to show her thighs in public. Whore! What happened to all the decent women? It's the 1950s after all! 

Don't appeal to the status quo. Nobody is hurt by others' sexuality. They, like you, are just offended. Get over yourself.

&amp;gt; straw man

l'eddit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483761992.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>It's not up to you what harms other people. Women are hurt all the time by guys like you who think they have the right to expose themselves to others because of your own personal sexual preference. You are on par with sexual offenders.


Edit: by the way. You can 'l'eddit' all you want, but that doesnt make your fallacies any less fallacious. You are really bad at making logically sound arguments. I'm done here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483763137.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483772801.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>u/iSunMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+iSunMonkey&amp;amp;message=iSunMonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e058u69/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483783905.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>Assaulting someone is a threat. The mischievous pervert who exposes himself to people is a perceived threat to that person's safety. That's why this is considered wrong.

Seeing gay dudes lubed up and motorboating each other in thongs on a gay pride float is not a threat to anyone's safety. That's why this is you being offended.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484398965.0" user="lilbill952" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't see how that level of extreme sexual behavior being presented in public hurts the LGBT movement from garnering the respect of more sexually conservative people then you are dense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484491274.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>The point of pride is we don't care how sexually conservative people see us. We're taking one day a year to express ourselves how we want to and if someone doesn't like that I'm sure they can find something else to do over the weekend. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484794216.0" user="farnix12" delta="False">
    <text>That seems like a sentiment that straight people might share, something not something intrinsically linked with being LGBT. 

If you want to have a parade celebrating open sexuallity, that's fine, but that's not something inherit to being gay and the fact the Pride seems to conflate the two is what makes me personally uncomfortable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485767690.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you think pride conflates being sexual with being gay? 90% of the people there are dressed perfectly normal with an emphasis on rainbow gear. It's no more sexual than a music festival, fourth of July parade, or watching a random tv channel for four hours. The only reason people are uncomfortable is because being gay is still seen as icky by an unfortunate part of our population. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485908429.0" user="farnix12" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The only reason people are uncomfortable is because being gay is still seen as icky by an unfortunate part of our population.

No the "amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness" is definitely a factor.  That's the whole point of this post, OP wanting Pride to be less overtly sexual.  If it was just the 90% of the people dressed perfectly normal, there wouldn't be these complaints.

You can take children to a fourth of July parade, or watch a random tv channel for four hours and you probably won't see a guy in leather waving a dildo around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485971365.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>So many things wrong in your comment... 

You want to explain to us all how exactly a "normal" person dresses? As a trans-woman I'm very interested in what you think I should be wearing. [This](https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/rethinking-mental-health/201111/what-do-we-mean-normal) is a psychology today article about why you're using normal wrong. 

Second you clearly have never been to pride. [Here](https://www.advocate.com/pride/2017/6/07/104-photos-sacramento-pride-golden-state#slide-26) is the one I attended last year. Sure looks like tons of people brought kids to me. 

Lastly there is no difference in the amount of sexualization you see in a holiday like Fourth of July or on tv and pride parade. Literally the only reason you notice is because queer relationships are still stigmatized. There are plenty of women in bikinis, sexualized ads, and double entendre in day to day society. Pride is the one day that the tables are turned and the majority of it is aimed at queer folk </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486066472.0" user="farnix12" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You want to explain to us all how exactly a "normal" person dresses?

I'm literally just quoting you saying:

&amp;gt; 90% of the people there are dressed perfectly normal with an emphasis on rainbow gear.

so you presumably knew what you meant by normal 

I have admittedly never been to Pride, [but given the other comments in](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/e04xgyk/) [this thread defending nudity at Pride](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/e04yvzz/), it seems disingenuous to claim that Pride is just as sexual as any other holiday.  

This whole comment section is filled with people defending why Pride is uniquely sexual.  The Pride you attended may have been tame, clearly a lot of people have had a different experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487268985.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, have you ever been to a pride event? I'm almost positive that these days, the only events where you'd see a guy in leather waving a dildo around are events in big cities like NYC or Chicago, and in big cities that's already something you might see regardless of whether it's pride or not.

The vast majority of pride events are exactly as you describe above, 95&amp;amp;#37; of people dressed in rainbow t shirts or maybe a cute costume, just milling around the street getting drunk and watching the floats (if there are any, I've never actually been to a pride event big enough to have floats).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487467329.0" user="farnix12" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The vast majority of pride events are exactly as you describe above, 95&amp;amp;#37; of people dressed in rainbow t shirts or maybe a cute costume, just milling around the street getting drunk and watching the floats

That's great.  That's what I would hope for.  That's sounds like what OP was hoping for.  

But this whole comments section is full of people disagreeing with OP, not on the grounds the Pride is actually SFW and he's overreacting, but on the grounds that nudity and sexual content is an essential part of Pride and should not be toned down.  And I'm disagreeing with those people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485325190.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>Big surprise when the public perceives you as sexual deviants. Don't go crying when you get treated like a deviant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485747394.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>Why would I be crying? I'm not ashamed of how I dress for pride and I'm certainly not bothered by how anyone else chooses to present themselves. The only people crying are those too prudish to mind their own business </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487263654.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>"These people don't act how I want them to act, therefore they deserve to have their rights taken away."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487454950.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>Straw man. What "rights" are being denied by asking for pride parades to be a little more family oriented and less sexual. OH the humanity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30495298482.0" user="lilbill952" delta="False">
    <text>In public though? On streets where everyone deserves to be comfortable and not be subjected to sexually explicit behavior?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30495319379.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>Do you even have a source on this sexually explicit behavior? Seriously have you actually been to pride and been offended? I'm not arguing this point anymore because the only sexually explicit things I've seen at pride were behind a tent that you needed to be carded to get into. There's nothing in the parade that is any more lewd than you would see during a fourth of July parade or watching a few hours of tv and the only reason people are offended is because queer relationships are still "icky" for too many people </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484569517.0" user="Bujeebus" delta="False">
    <text>Women wearing pants are not the reason they're raped.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484589438.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>What.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484627100.0" user="Bujeebus" delta="False">
    <text>The argument that women should not be able to wear pants in the 1900 was that it was too revealing and would put women in danger of men who wouldn't be able to control themselves.

Woman aren't raped because of what they wear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484658268.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>Okay... What I'm saying is that men shouldnt be allowed to expose themselves to women at their own discretion. Or vica versa for that matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484501766.0" user="cgi_bin_laden" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you're intentionally misinterpreting his/her comment to fit your own biases. You're not even listening at this point, you're just emoting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485088511.0" user="kwantsu-dudes" delta="False">
    <text>Of course it's personal preference. But that's precisely the point. Others have different preferences. **So when the entire discussion is about trying to garner acceptance from those that hold different ideals**, we need to **acknowledge** the personal preferences of others and tailor a message that does it's best to not be offensive.

You keep mentioning how it's personal preference and yet you seem to think there is some objective truth that people should not be offended by sexuality. No, that's just your own personal preference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485099894.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487271841.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like this has been stated 1,000 times in this thread, but pride events are absolutely NOT about garnering support from those that hold different ideals. Non\-queer people's feelings don't really matter for pride.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487452525.0" user="kwantsu-dudes" delta="False">
    <text>I acknowledge that. But focusing on that, doesn't actually address OP's CMV.

&amp;gt; In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance.

So OP set a goal. For pride parades to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible.

Saying "Well pride parades were never about achieving that goal", doesn't actually attempt to change OPs mind. It may cause OP to drop his view as being impractical to accomplish, but it doesn't address "to do *this*, *that* needs to happen". A statement of "*This* is not the current goal" points out a reality, but doesnt address the view. An accurate challenge of the view is "to do *this*, *that* doesn't work. Or this other thing would be more effective".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483724316.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>You cant change somebody's view if you are attacking a straw man and if you refuse to answer questions relevant to your view on the argument at hand. You are a bad advocate for Pride culture because you are only interested in attacking the people with a different view than yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483743171.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484152754.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/iSunMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+iSunMonkey&amp;amp;message=iSunMonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e058ern/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484356000.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it's fair of you to accuse iSunMonkey of being a bad faith debater when you haven't addressed his/her criticism. I'm trying to understand what you think you're communicating, but I have to agree with iSunMonkey that the only thing coming across in what you wrote is "I don't like it, just because." Of course we all have things we don't like and that's fine, but if there's more substance to your argument, it isn't coming through and you should try to revise your statements to better reflect your thoughts. I don't see how Sun Monkey has attacked you at all -- s/he has (correctly in my opinion) summarized your argument as a heteronormative worldview based on your personal tastes, and you have not clarified them as being anything else. You are the only one attacking someone personally here. I understand how we can be swept away by frustration, but I hope you'll try again to communicate what your thoughts are if you feel there's more we should get from your argument. I know I'm interested in hearing what you have to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484394590.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>It is fair in all regards to call him a bad faith debater, because he doesnt respond to my questions which are very relevant to the points he makes, keeps painting me as being offended, which I am not, and that he claims that I '**just** dont like it', which implies I have not thought it through enough to have a legitimate personal preference.


Further down his comment has been removed because of being hostile.


I cant debate someone who sticks to their preconceived notions about me, my motivations and my reasonings even in the face of further elaborations. My personal preferences arent even relevant to the whole discussion. He is the one that is saying public sexuality is a good thing and we should allow it, but he doesnt respond to how far the limits of that go. So how am I able to further the discussion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484444564.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  So how am I able to further the discussion?

Forget about your beef with that user and talk to me instead, then. I would like to understand what you're saying, please help me to do so.

"I just don't like it" IS a legitimate personal preference, which is the point -- the only thing coming through in your argument is "that is my personal preference" in different words. However, you keep saying this isn't about your preferences. If there is more to your objection, it isn't coming across at all. What, besides "this is my personal preference," is your argument?

If your only objection is that these acts go against your personal preferences for how people behave in public, that's okay -- I respect your right to have your preferences. But you keep insisting that it isn't about preference, so if there's something else, please tell us.

I'm about to head out so I can't reply right away but I'll be back tonight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484521175.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>You misunderstand me. Go back to my first comment on this subject, before I was backed into a corner to defend my personal preference. I said that I want to avoid these things, so I just dont go to these kind of events. I think, unless they are breaking laws, that they should do what they want, but that it is **counterproductive** to the goal of the movement, if they want to be accepted by society at large. There's a lot of sexually conservative people out there, and if you act in an outrageous manner, they are less likely to accept you, because what you're doing makes them feel uncomfortable and uneasy.


What ended up being the focal point of the discussion was that the other user said that public sexuality is good and that the boundaries of that should be pushed more, and he even elaborated on my example of masturbating in public, implying that it's fine to do so. That's where it ceases just being a personal preference. People are hurt by people who do things like that. That would make it okay to expose yourself to everyone, including unsuspecting women and children. Children could grow up with unhealthy sexual relationships because of being forced into a sexual situation without being able to understand it yet. Furthermore most people dont want to see you have sex or pleasure yourself, regardless of sexual orientation, and without society's consent, there's a high chance of harming people by doing these things. In essence I believe public sexuality can turn harmful. Laws in nearly all of the world currently reflect that sentiment. Pride events mostly arent harmful, even though they can get really sexual assault-y, which is why I say they can do whatever they want.


But the reason why I think it's counterproductive to be overtly sexual and why that is a dumb thing to persist on doing, is that the movement wants people to accept their sexual orientation, right? But you're acting in a way people wouldnt accept a heterosexual either. That runs counter to the goal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484954302.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the reason why I think it's counterproductive to be overtly sexual and why that is a dumb thing to persist on doing, is that the movement wants people to accept their sexual orientation, right? But you're acting in a way people wouldnt accept a heterosexual either. That runs counter to the goal.

I can understand why you feel that way. A lot of people agree with you. Of course LGBT want acceptance AS PEOPLE. But that means acceptance of their sexuality and sexual practices. The thing that people don't accept about them is this one part of their personality -- their sexuality. If the only way to gain acceptance is by repressing their expressions of their sexuality -- for instance, not holding hands or sharing an affectionate kiss in public even when heterosexual couples can do so -- then they are not accepted. If acceptance means hiding, that is not acceptance. 

I don't feel comfortable with innocent displays of my sexuality 364 days of the year. I am accepted as a person because I don't look "too homosexual" for society's tastes -- in other words, I am not accepted. I don't really want or need the right to finger another girl while you watch me in the street, but after repressing my sexuality for the sake of "acceptance" I can understand the impulse to let it out on the 365th day. So I can see why you find it distasteful, but I don't think it's counter to the goal -- the point is to draw attention to the "deviant" and unacceptable sexual preferences because we are all tired of hiding from the rest of you.* To accept me is to acknowledge and accept that I want to finger another girl and I'm not interested in covering that up.

*I can't speak for everybody, but in general

Editing to add what I wrote in another comment:

&amp;gt;I understand the desire to have a family friendly pride event or an event that honors other experiences that LGBT people typically share, but my opinion is that this isn't what pride parades are usually for. They're about asserting the right to experience sexuality however a person wants without discrimination or criminal action against them.

So of course I want to be accepted, and 364 days I understand that means "don't look like an icky gay person" and I can toe that line. But I want the acceptance of my sexual practices as well, I want to be accepted as a whole human, not just 95% of me. Pride is a time where that part is not just accepted, but celebrated. If I deal with the rest of you for most of the time, you can deal with me for one day.

So I think your understanding of the focus and goal of these events, or of what it means to get acceptance, is a little off perhaps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485962748.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I can understand why you feel that way. A lot of people agree with you. Of course LGBT want acceptance AS PEOPLE. But that means acceptance of their sexuality and sexual practices. The thing that people don't accept about them is this one part of their personality -- their sexuality. If the only way to gain acceptance is by repressing their expressions of their sexuality -- for instance, not holding hands or sharing an affectionate kiss in public even when heterosexual couples can do so -- then they are not accepted. If acceptance means hiding, that is not acceptance. 


That wasnt what this discussion was about. Obviously you should be able to express your sexuality in a manner that is socially acceptable for heterosexuals as well. The discussion was about overtly public sexual behavior and how it negatively affects the movement's goals. Kissing and holding hands arent overtly sexual behavior.



&amp;gt;I don't feel comfortable with innocent displays of my sexuality 364 days of the year. I am accepted as a person because I don't look "too homosexual" for society's tastes -- in other words, I am not accepted. I don't really want or need the right to finger another girl while you watch me in the street, but after repressing my sexuality for the sake of "acceptance" I can understand the impulse to let it out on the 365th day. So I can see why you find it distasteful, but I don't think it's counter to the goal -- the point is to draw attention to the "deviant" and unacceptable sexual preferences because we are all tired of hiding from the rest of you.* To accept me is to acknowledge and accept that I want to finger another girl and I'm not interested in covering that up.



'Hey I want to finger another girl' is something quite crass. If your point is to draw attention to the 'deviant' sexual preferences just for the sake of drawing attention to it, then you're doing a great job. But thats not the message that you seem to want to get across or that the movement wants to get across. It seems to be 'accept me as a person including my sexual orientation'. And you're alienating a huge part of the population if you do it in this manner. People dont want to know about what you stick in where. A much nicer message, that most people could rally around, is that you want to love another girl without being judged.


While I get that you want to 'act out', it doesnt change the practical outcome this will have on the large amount of people who think sex is something private.





&amp;gt;So of course I want to be accepted, and 364 days I understand that means "don't look like an icky gay person" and I can toe that line. But I want the acceptance of my sexual practices as well, I want to be accepted as a whole human, not just 95% of me. Pride is a time where that part is not just accepted, but celebrated. If I deal with the rest of you for most of the time, you can deal with me for one day.

&amp;gt;So I think your understanding of the focus and goal of these events, or of what it means to get acceptance, is a little off perhaps.


Why do you conflate being overtly sexual in public with having a certain sexual orientation? Do you need to be able to finger a girl in public to be accepted as a gay person? I dont need to fuck a girl in public to be accepted as a straight dude. I'm all for: 'Hey I want to have sex with a girl in the comforts of my home' or 'I want to be able to hold hands and kiss my girlfriend in public without being judged', but why do you insist on defending having to be able to fingerblast a girl in public? This is something that isnt accepted by society no matter your sexuality, so why should accepting your sexuality include something like this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486055257.0" user="Answermancer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is something that isnt accepted by society no matter your sexuality, so why should accepting your sexuality include something like this?

I agree with the other two posters that you're coming off as mostly defensive and your argument seems to boil down to "I don't like it" or more specifically "Society traditionally doesn't like it, and I share that dislike."

You act like blatent sexually in public (ignore the gay angle for a moment) is somehow objectively "wrong", but that's just an opinion.

It happens to be one shared by many people (in what I would describe as a prudish culture), but it's still just an opinion. That's what the other two posters were getting at.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486963752.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>Then you also seem to misunderstand the point of the post. The original post said that people are going to be turned away from your movement because of the sexual undertones. Acceptance by society is at the central point of the argument. I've also given so many arguments at this point, I am quite sick of people not addressing it and reducing the argument to the most base bull they can think of.



&amp;gt;You act like blatent sexually in public (ignore the gay angle for a moment) is somehow objectively "wrong", but that's just an opinion.


Surely you can agree that there is sexual behavior that is objectively unacceptable? I dont know why you posters insist that I'm saying that every blatant sexual behavior is objectively wrong, when I specifically said it was just my opinion (and that of society's) and that people dont have to adhere to my norms. The only thing I said is that a) it can turn objectively wrong when it hurts people (like masturbating in view of a preschool or exposing yourself to an unconsenting woman) and that b) in the context of seeking acceptance for your sexual orientation by society, it is counterproductive to display behavior society doesnt accept from any sexual orientation (and that overtly sexual behavior =/= sexual orientation).


Edit: I also dont get why you feel the need to call me defensive. Stick to arguments. I dont attack posters unless they attack me. If you and other people wouldnt feel the need to attack me, this would be a nicer place and discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488108267.0" user="dang1010" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You act like blatent sexually in public (ignore the gay angle for a moment) is somehow objectively "wrong", but that's just an opinion.

Except it is though.  Children don't have the capacity to understand sex, and exposure to it at that young of an age can hinder and damage their development.  And this is regardless of if they're witnessing heterosexual or honosexual acts.  So depending in what extent of blatant public sexuality you're talking about, it is objectively wrong and harmful to the public.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30492482235.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>I'm starting to understand why the other user got frustrated with you. You don't seem to have understood what I wrote at all, and are now engaging in hostile stereotyping. Let me try again:

First of all, I have explained a point of view to you, I have never stated that I engage in public sex. Automatically grouping me with this behavior and referring to me as part of a collective-you is quite presumptuous and I would like you to stop. You are ascribing motives and behaviors to me that I have never indicated as my own based on your preconceived ideas about LGBT individuals -- despite my specific statement that I don't engage in those behaviors -- simply because I identified myself as LGBT. I can't respond to those parts of your argument because, in addition to being personally insulting, they are non-substantive.

&amp;gt;That wasnt what this discussion was about.

This discussion is about whether sexual behavior at pride parades is furthering the goals of pride parades. I contend that being allowed to engage in "deviant" behavior without fear of reprisal is an integral goal of pride parades. I explain to you why many people feel this is so important by providing background information on some common LGBT experiences.

&amp;gt;People dont want to know about what you stick in where.

You seem to be under the assumption that the general public are equally uncomfortable with any kind of display of sexuality. This may be true for you personally, but it is painfully obvious that this is not the case in general society. The open, unimpeded expression of sexual preference is often not available for individual LGBT people (or other "deviant" desires) in the same way that it is available for heterosexual/vanilla people. People are perfectly fine with the concept of heterosexual vanilla encounters. Representations of "normal" sex are very common, in the media, in public displays of affection, etc. The public is perfectly fine with me as long as they can assume I'm straight. They *should* be equally fine with me if they discover I like something other than heterosexual vanilla encounters, and representations of such sexual practices that are on par with representations of "normal" sex should not be stigmatized (such as the hand-holding example I gave you in the previous post). The fact that this is not the case is why we have pride. 

The concept that SOME kinds of sex are okay to hint at in public and OTHER kinds of sex are not acceptable -- and the people who engage in it are not acceptable -- needs to be dismantled. This is the goal of pride. All kinds of consensual sex (and the people who engage in it) should be destigmatized on an equal footing.

Sexual displays at pride events further that goal by creating an environment where deviant sex is not hidden, secret, shameful, or stigmatized. It is placed on par with "normal" sex, as it should ALWAYS be. Some people use these events as a safe space to express themselves in a way that they feel they cannot during their daily lives, as I have explained to you. In other words, that part of pride events is not FOR you. It is not to convince you that gay sex is so cool and you should be all for it. It is to allow people who fear holding hands with their loved ones on the bus to assert and celebrate their whole selves, including their sexual preferences.

I have never insisted on publicly fingerblasting anyone, so I'd appreciate it if you keep your personal prejudices against LGBT individuals out of your next reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30493318014.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485333221.0" user="stayphrosty" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't you doing exactly what you're accusing them of? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485545245.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>I am responding to someone continuously arguing in bad faith in an appropriate manner. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484250977.0" user="CPUSolLeks" delta="False">
    <text>I think we all have the right not to be included unwillingly in another person's sex life no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484493978.0" user="cgi_bin_laden" delta="False">
    <text>You're intentionally misinterpreting his comment to fit your own biases. Please focus on the comment, not on your own prejudices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484630173.0" user="BrianNowhere" delta="False">
    <text>I'm the least prude person I know but there are good reasons for having public decency laws so that everyone's wishes are respected. 

If the sight of nudity doesn't bother you, you lose nothing in an environment where nudity isn't allowed except you can't get naked and you don't get to see nudity. On the other hand, If nudity was to be allowed, the people who don't want to see it or have their kids see it do get their rights disrespected.  
Therefore public decently laws are the best way to make sure everyone's rights are respected. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484718023.0" user="BryceTheBrisket" delta="False">
    <text>Listen, it's not just that. As with the previous point, would you want your children being exposed and flashed in public? Sexuality is a good thing, I'm not arguing with you on the point, but it is something reserved for responsible and consenting *adults*. Using terms like "hetero-normative" only weaken your argument. I just want to understand why just being openly sexual to non-consenting viewers is a good thing.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484398546.0" user="gloomy_Novelist" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;So people should be able to flash to women and children at their own discretion? Masturbating in full vorw of a preschool? Before I can answer your question I must know the depths of your opinion on what public sexuality is okay and what isnt.

Not him, but in an ideal world, yeah, that'd mostly be fine.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484408347.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>Why mostly? Do you believe that masturbating in view of a preschool is fine or not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485487881.0" user="gloomy_Novelist" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, it's mostly flashing that could still be an issue as a prelude to assault.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484367397.0" user="electronics12345" delta="False">
    <text>Its an issue of consent. 

Sex should only occur between consenting parties. 

Witnessing a sexual act - is itself a sexual act. 

If I'm in public, and I turn a corner, and there you are - I have not consented to anything that is about to happen. Therefore, I did not consent to the sexual activity - of watching sexual activity. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484486875.0" user="cgi_bin_laden" delta="False">
    <text>You're misreading his comment. He/she isn't offended by the naked human body (at least that's not how I'm reading it).

Would you be fine if my wife and I rolled out a blanket in your local park while your kid's birthday party was going on and just started screwing right there? You'd be perfectly okay with that?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485546874.0" user="zharth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I happen to think nudity and sex is something special you should share with just loved ones.

You have every right and freedom to live your life by this principle. What you do not have is the right to force anyone else to live by this principle. The decisions you make in your own life are your own responsibility. The decisions other people make in their lives are their responsibility. We don't all have to be the same, and we don't all have to lead lifestyles that the rest of us support and agree with. Being *exposed* to other people's lifestyles is not a violation of your rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485658125.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>I did not claim so. I said I disagree with it, I stated why, then I said that I dont really care if they do what they want I just avoid Pride events, but that I do think it's counterproductive to the LGBT+ movement's goals. If you read further in the thread you'd read I specifically said I dont force people to adhere to my norms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483605256.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>But why can't people just be gay and normal? Why does it have to be gay and over the top flamboyant.


Surely the ideal situation is that you can't even tell people are gay. That's when it's normal, part of the culture, and no one cares about it.


Why do gays have to stand out? Just be gay, cool, i don't care. Don't throw it on my face. Same with if it was women riding big dildos. I don't care, but when You start making it a big show I start to dislike it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483620839.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>"Why can't people just stick to the status quo?"

Nobody *has to do or be* anything. The point is that people should be free to express themselves, even in sexual expression. 

"Normal" is a meaningless word. 50 years ago, it was "normal" to call women who wore clothing that revealed their legs "whores." It was "normal" before that to call interracial couples "race traitors." Appealing to the status quo is a primitive emotional bias.

The purpose of flamboyancy could be to normalize the acceptance and understanding of sexuality that isn't hetero, cis, etc. The fact that it makes you "feel icky" isn't a very good objection to anything. Try coming up with something other than ["I was offended."](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ceS_jkKjIgo)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483685252.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; people should be free to express themselves

They *are* free to. The point of the OP is, you are allowed to do it, but know that many people will take you and your cause less seriously if you do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483697482.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>No, they're not. People are shamed, arrested, beaten, exiled, excommunicated, harassed, bullied, lynched, and executed for expressing non-hetero-normative sexuality. People are not free to express themselves.

Pride parades are a celebration of how far we've come while pushing the envelope for what's "acceptable." Pride parades are not places for heteros to project their weird rules. It's a break from that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483733860.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I haven't seen that behaviour in the past 20 years. Perhaps America is less tolerant than England, but I don't really read stories like that online about America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483742007.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>...kids don't bully in your schools?

You don't have access to internet where people are harassed and hated?

Didn't the UK just have a big Neo Nazi demonstration last year?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483775509.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>When was the last lynching? The last execution? The last excommunication? Links please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483779912.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>Google it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483870908.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>Lazy non answer. I'm just going to take it as given that your prior statement was hyperbolic and not grounded in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483961370.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484050240.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/iSunMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+iSunMonkey&amp;amp;message=iSunMonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05d34q/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484386629.0" user="Hero17" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-40643461</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484553689.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>Those were horrible, but they weren't any of the above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483809262.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>We literally bully gingers more than gays. No one cares if you are gay. 


There will always be some idiots, but just like there are some people who don't like short people. They are idiots most people agree. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483900478.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484027671.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484033412.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484041988.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>u/iSunMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+iSunMonkey&amp;amp;message=iSunMonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05bs5a/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484043281.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483806478.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>That's not really the case anymore, at least in the civilised world. For reference I live in London.


Basically no one here cares if people are gay. It's  just part of life. 


However people do get annoyed with overt sexual displays. Both gay and straight. But it's almost ALWAYS gay, which is why this conversation is happening.



If you want to be treated as just another person, act like one. If you want to act differently, fine, but you will be treated differently</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483902452.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484026540.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Can you tell me at least which part is wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484032488.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Basically no one here cares if people are gay. It's just part of life. 

"Faggot" "gay" "homo" "trap" are not part of your society's vernacular?

People objectively care whether other people are gay. This is still mainstream thought almost everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484086511.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, not really. Never heard of trap.


And even when I have heard them, it's almost never actually with reference to a gay person. The words have evolved in the same way dumb and lame have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484051470.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/iSunMonkey – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+iSunMonkey&amp;amp;message=iSunMonkey+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05bto4/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485047448.0" user="Banankartong" delta="False">
    <text>You are wrong.

"More than one in five LGBT people verbally or physically attacked due to their sexual orientation or gender identity in last 12 months, figures show. Attacks on LGBT people surge almost 80&amp;amp;#37; in UK over last four years." [https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home\-news/gay\-lgbt\-hate\-crimes\-stats\-rise\-four\-year\-physical\-verbal\-homophobic\-abuse\-community\-a7933126.html](https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/gay-lgbt-hate-crimes-stats-rise-four-year-physical-verbal-homophobic-abuse-community-a7933126.html)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485605658.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Nowhere in there does it define a "hate crime". For all I know then"attack" could be a sideways glance.

That article has also only 5000 sample size.


Can you provide an actual source? I am very open to being processed wrong :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485555550.0" user="zharth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The point of the OP is, you are allowed to do it, but know that many people will take you and your cause less seriously if you do.

To be fair, the thrust of this argument usually runs along the lines of, "...but they *shouldn't* be allowed to, because I don't like it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485906176.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't really heard that argument in the wild for at least 10 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483626899.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>No one is saying you can't be gay and "normal". Plenty of queer people are and they still attend the pride parades.  But why should you have to? Why is abiding to the rules of what straight people find acceptable what gay people should strive for? 

The whole point of pride is letting people express who they are without shame. Following the rules of opressors should never be the goal.

As someone who is queer and pretty conservative in my expression of sexuality, i am so inspired by sexual liberated people who dont give a fuck. That is how queer people got rights to begin with and to limit that freedom in order to appeal to the larger straight masses, ie you, would be going backwards in time. 

Tldr: we dont care of you are offended by overt  queerness. If it bothers you that it is being thrown in your face, dont come to the pride parades. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483637909.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>You have misunderstood. I don't care that it's queer. At all. In any way. I can't make that clearer.


What I am saying is that why can't queer people just act like everyone else with regard to expression.


You can have one of the following. "Be treated just like any other person regardless of your sexuality" or "want to be loud, proud and in my face about being queer."



You cannot have both. I think option 1 is better. I'd rather being gay just be something like being left handed, something I just accept and isn't a big deal. You can't want being gay to not be a big deal, AND act like people do at gay pride.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483661536.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>I did respond to that a lot. Queer people do not need to abide by the social norms that straight people find acceptable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483794059.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Of course they don't. Fair enough. However they then cannot ask to be treated just like everyone else. That's the trade.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483808996.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>"Treated just like everyone else" is interesting. Do you mean in regards to the law? Or being tolerated or respected? 

Queer people should be treated with respect without having to conform. I dont think it is asking too much. There are plenty of straight people who already do this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483814115.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I don't mean legally, sorry! Just by people.


Someone being queer does not change my level of respect for them. People doing overt public sexual displays does.


Straight person overt display: not respect.

Gay person no display: respect.



The factor is NOT sexuality. It doesn't matter to me. Couldn't care less.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483829489.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>Cool. I don't think we will ever agree if  being "over the top flamboyant" is a reason for you to not respect someone. 

However, I can understand you being offended by dildos and nudity. To that I say, it is a big part of gay pride- and always has been. There are family friendly alternatives to gay pride in some cities that you can look into if you want a way to show support without seeing those things that offend you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483842760.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>As a general rule, if someone takes one part of what they are, and makes it a huge deal, that's an issue for me.


I don't like people who have a massive group mentality. I like people to be individuals. 


E.g. in London, if you are 20 and gay, it's likely you have faced almost no discrimination at any point. Almost certainly less than even a ginger person. Therefore if you make being gay a big deal, that's am issue. Just be gay, and love your life. It's like me going around shouting how I'm left handed and that's ok. People aren't saying otherwise.


I don't "support" gays, like I don't "support" gingers. That feature of the person simply doesn't matter to me. If an individual is having hardship due to it, I will 100% support them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483860524.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>Well my biggest issue is people thinking they understand things they have never experinced instead of just listening to the people who have- yet that still happens regularly.

A lot of gay people still face issues coming out to their families regardless of whether they are super religious or not. A ginger would never.

You would be surprised that it is still nervewracking to come out to coworkers even if they are open minded people because they assumed you were straight. A ginger would never face this.

Many gay people still face discrimination even in london- or chicago where i live. But many of us are just living our lives. Sometimes straight people think that gay people are making a big deal out of something when they are just being themselves.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484117516.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you need to come out to coworker? If it comes up just mention it, if not, don't. 


Maybe this is just a London thing, but no one gives a shit if their co-workers are gay.


This feels like a UK US divide. America is super religious so maybe more anti gay. We aren't.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484193115.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>Because coworkers share their personal lives with eachother often. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484262375.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>The it will come up in conversation. It's not an"hey I'm gay" it's a "me and my husband did this" (assuming they are a man)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484535297.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>It is still coming out and it still is not easy especially if you are not in a relationship and people make assumptions. You have to correct them. As a straight person you would not know that feeling. But also this is only one example we are arguing about. I think in general you are over estimating how easy it is just because you do not experience the discrimmimation. 

But i have several clients whom i would never want to know my sexuality because of their beliefs and i work in downtown chicago. I also dont think i make a big deal out of being queer- but i definitely think we deserve a pride parade once a year. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488896877.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It is still coming out and it still is not easy especially if you are not in a relationship and people make assumptions. You have to correct them.


Oh no, the horror. 

Steve: "Hey John, look at that girl, shes super hot" 
John: "Not really my thing mate, im gay"
Steve: "Ah neato, didnt know that"


What exactly is the concern over "coming out" to coworkers? What is the root cause of it being a worry? Are you concerned they wont like it?



&amp;gt; But i have several clients whom i would never want to know my sexuality because of their beliefs and i work in downtown chicago.

I know nothing of Chicago, I can only talk for London. 



&amp;gt; I also dont think i make a big deal out of being queer- but i definitely think we deserve a pride parade once a year.

I dont make a big deal over being left handed, where is my parade? 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483670668.0" user="EGDF" delta="False">
    <text>You understand how you sound, I hope. If not, here's the point you are parroting that the LGBT community has heard for years from supposed "allies" : "I don't care if you're gay as long as I can't see it." 

This is the opposite of what pride is about. It isn't about conforming to cishet sensibilities, it is about celebrating the differences we have as humans, especially those who have been cast aside from what society considers "normal". Liberation comes when the structures of heteronormativity are broken down, not when we force everyone to hide underneath it to avoid offending. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483693966.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>You can't ask to be treat the same while going out of your way to act as differently as possible. It makes no sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483711960.0" user="EGDF" delta="False">
    <text>Why? Why can't you just treat everyone with respect without trying to police some part of their lives? It hurts no one. "Think of the children!" there's nothing at a pride parade that can't be displayed on cable television.

Why do you get to say who deserves rights and respect when there's no such litmus test for heterosexuals? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483723969.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>Respect is earned, I will treat someone relatively neutrally until they prove themselves otherwise. I don't get to say who deserves respect, but I *do* get to say who *I* respect, and I draw the line somewhere before people being deliberately extremely overtly sexual in public places where there are likely to be young children who will ask awkward questions. And I would have the exact same judgement of a bunch of straight people marching down the highstreet waving dildos in the air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483780643.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I'm fairly confident he (and I) would treat heterosexuals the same if they behaveD the same.


It's NOT ABOUT being gay. It's about how people are acting. Straight/gay/whatever I would treat the same if they behaved like this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485399321.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>OMG enough with the "you wouldn't treat heteros the same" straw man. OP has repeatedly said he would treat them the same. If heteros were out having mock sex on parade floats and waving sex toys around, they would judge the heteros the same way.  

Why is your overt sexuality something society has to "tolerate"? Why can't you just follow decency laws and such. Please show me the equivalent of a hetero parade and I'll shut up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483760908.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I can't tell if you are intentionally misunderstanding. We both know that is not what I am saying.


Be gay. Be straight. Be whatever, I DON'T CARE.


However, if you want to throw it in my face, I will treat you the same way I would treat a straight person who did, poorly.



If you want to be treated just like everyone else, act like everyone else. If you don't then dont. Completely your choice 


However what you cannot have it "I'm going to act in a way massively different to others, but want to be treated the same."


As I said, you can either "be gay, get on with your life, it's not a big deal" OR you can scream and shout about it.


If you do the latter, you CANNOT be treated as just Normal, becuase you are acting massively out of line with the norm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483644822.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>There's a strange zeitgeist around sexuality in the west. It's so natural for people to scoff in disgust at the idea of gay dudes, for example. Straight guys act like they're trying not to stare at the sun when they accidentally open gay porn.

People really need to get over it. People fuck. Your parents fuck. Your sister fucks. Gays fuck. Trans people fuck. We all know sex can be a wonderful experience. It's weird that we have revolted by the idea of someone doing it and enjoying it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485267997.0" user="Turtle_78" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody chooses their feelings, whether those feelings be attraction or disgust. "Just get over it" is as useless for removing attraction as it is for removing disgust. Your desire for expression is no more valid than another's desire to avoid. You must learn to respect that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485647357.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>You're making a huge false equivalence between disgust at public behavior and intimate/personal sexual attraction.  

There's also pretty good evidence that disgust in general is learned, not innate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485897970.0" user="Turtle_78" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe there is any false equivalence in what I have written. Nobody chooses their feelings. No matter what those feelings are, no matter how ordinary, or strange or even self-destructive those feelings may be, whether they be learned or innate, nobody chooses how they feel. Telling someone to simply "get over" their feelings is unhelpful regardless of what those feelings may be. Where do you think I have made a false equivalence?

That isn't to say that feelings can never change, of course. Perhaps society would be better if we were more open about sex. Telling someone to "get over it" will harm any attempts towards this, however. Hostility is more likely to turn someone against an idea than towards it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487294936.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>I used to actually feel revulsion at the sight of two men kissing. Now I'm in a stable, loving relationship with another dude. 

Some things you can get over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487333347.0" user="Turtle_78" delta="False">
    <text>Equally, some people aren't comfortable with public displays of affection regardless of gender, and that's ok. We should respect those people rather than forcing them to change. That doesn't mean you can't publicly display affection, just don't tell others to do as you do. It really isn't much to ask.

TL;DR: Asexual people exist, and it is inappropriate to tell them to just "get over it".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483687708.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; abiding to the rules of what straight people find acceptable 

It's got nothing to do with what straight people find acceptable. Straight people aren't inherently less sexual. We just don't have a straight pride parade with dildos and inflatable animals.

&amp;gt; we dont care of you are offended by overt queerness.

You keep conflating sexual expression with being gay. They aren't related, gay or straight is the direction, the level to which you express it is the magnitude of that vector.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483706256.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>Actually it was. I was directly responding to a straight person saying how they felt queer people should express their sexuality. 

I understand that sexual expression and being gay is not the same thing. I already said i was a queer person who was conservative in my sexual expression. I also stated that many gay people who come to pride are the same way. I am saying that those who are not do not need to hold back so that the masses can feel more comfortable. 

I included striaght masses bc there is a correlation with queer identity and being sexual free/liberated- whether that correlation is exclusive or not. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483730076.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; to a straight person saying how they felt queer people should express their sexuality.

No they weren't, they were saying how they personally feel about people being overtly sexual in public, not how anyone should express it, just how they feel about it when people do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483748387.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree, but I think it is my mistake for not distinguishing the between the words sexuality and sexual identity. 

Regardless, complaining about gay people being "over the top flamboyant" is 100% a straight person telling queer people how they should express themselves. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483773356.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen gay people complain about this too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483816557.0" user="improcrastin8ing" delta="False">
    <text>Same. And I think that is often internalized homophobia but that is a whole different conversation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483875544.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>Anything can fall into "bad think" or "internalised bad think". It doesn't leave any scope for falsifiability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483800276.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I think you were replying to me orginally and have misunderstood. If a gay person wants to be over the top flamboyant, fine. That's their choice.


However they then CANNOT ask to be treated just like everyone else.


That's the trade. Act normal, be treated normal. Don't, and you won't. That's how it works for everything, not just sexual stuff</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484689744.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Basic human rights are not supposed to be and should not be contingent upon "normal" \(i.e. "respectable", "appropriate", etc.\) behavior.  

The gay rights movement was not about asking to be treated "just like everyone else".  It was about asking for basic rights and freedoms. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484905427.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Rights and freedoms they now have, as they should. (At least in UK where I live).


We aren't talking about rights. That battle is over and won.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484910670.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>This doesn't really seem relevant to this conversational thread. Nobody was talking about denying anyone human rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484952292.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so what do you mean by being treated "just like everybody else"?  You want to reserve the right to treat people whose behavior you disapprove of in what way exactly? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485000559.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I think the point of the OP was that the OTT sexual nature can make the parades themselves hard for normies to swallow.

And I'm not reserving anything. I'm leaving all possibilities open for all kinds of behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485590173.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I mean if you don't want to be treated differently to a generic person, don't act so massively out of line with the norm.


I'm not saying how you should act. Just saying if you act unusually I will treat you unusually. E.g. if you have a face tattoo</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485672596.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>You're the one who brought this idea of "being treated exactly the same as a generic (i.e. normal, i.e straight) person" into the conversation.  What does being treated that way mean?  Basic politeness? Respect and courtesy? Lack of violence and mocking and derision?   Access to the basic institutions necessary to have a safe and comfortable life? If so, then behaving exactly like a generic/normal/straight person is way too high a bar.  Everyone should get those things, even people you personally don't like. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487335352.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>It means if you act that way I'll treat you the same type of way I treat someone with a face tattoo. Basically "huh, they are a weird dude. If possible would likely avoid them".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487785248.0" user="mancubus314159" delta="False">
    <text>For me, it's somewhere between indifference and basic politeness, until proven otherwise, of course.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485381550.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>Go get a tattoo on your face, or piercings throughout your face. You will be treated differently, this is commonly known. It's not "right" per se but it's the way it is. You want to work a fortune 500 job but only don tee shirt and jeans, well, you aren't gonna work that job. Want to be treated like anyone else but go out and wave dildos in peoples faces and be overtly flamboyant, people gonna people and treat you differently. It is such a simple concept young children understand it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485367740.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>Why is abiding to the rules of what straight people find acceptable what gay people should strive for?

So ALL gays are into overt sexuality? That...sounds.....homophobic......</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483843827.0" user="Accountforthis35" delta="False">
    <text>I agree mostly with what you say, yet what do you mean when you say 'dont throw it in my face'? Usually when people say that they also mean general PDA that dont seem to invite the same vitriol that heterosexuals get when displaying PDA and I disagree with that. Gays should be able to kiss and hold hands and hug the same as everyone else imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483864271.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Ah that's fair. For clarity, my line for acceptable PDA does not change if you are gay or not. The sex of people doing the pda doesn't matter to me 


If I dislike it for gays, I'd also dislike it for straights</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483854433.0" user="TrueLazuli" delta="False">
    <text>The big show was a reaction against a culture that was constantly heaping shame and reproach on people just for being who they were. 

It was a response saying "I know you don't like my lifestyle, but get over it, because I don't fuckin care what you think."

Continuing the flamboyant attitude of Pride is remembering and honoring and celebrating that response and the people who were willing to not care whether you disliked them, and in so doing brought us to a place where much of the time, we *can* "just be normal."

Pride started with "we're here, we're queer — get over it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484024496.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and in that time it made some sense. Now it doesn't.


Either you want to be treated the same or you don't (you plural, not you). If you want to be treated normal, act it.


It's a choice. And I am not saying which to make, it's 100% up to them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484048099.0" user="TrueLazuli" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, and in that time it made some sense. Now it doesn't.

To repeat myself: 

Continuing the flamboyant attitude of Pride is remembering and honoring and celebrating that response and the people who were willing to not care whether you disliked them, and in so doing brought us to a place where much of the time, we can "just be normal."

364 days out of the year, I don't wear my BDSM gear on the street. 

This one day, I look at you and your attitude that I have to act in a way that makes you comfortable in order to be treated like a person, and I tell you to stuff it up your be-hind, sir, cuz I don't give a flying frick when I'm at Pride. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484097299.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>You are free to do that. However it makes people like me, who have no issue with your sexuality, dislike you.


When enough of a certain group do actions which I dislike, it becomes hard not to associate that with a group. I make sure to compartmentalise bit it's not easy, and a lot of people don't even try.


Again, you are free to act this way. However it makes many people like gay people less. 



You don't need to care about that. But you acting this way hurts the gay community.



You may not care about what people think of you. But you arent just affecting yourself. You need to be ok with making people like gays as a whole less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484294128.0" user="TrueLazuli" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But you acting this way hurts the gay community.

I disagree. Every movement has to balance its own needs against public perception. In some cases it is more important for the base to be reminded of its freedom to be who they are, and to remember those who pushed for that right, than for them to appear likeable to people who disagree. In this case I think that being polite and discreet about it 99.7% of the time (364 days out of 365 days of the year) is a fair compromise. To say that a group asserting its weirdness on that .3% of days—on a tiny fraction of the year when they celebrate the heritage of their movement—is a reasonable excuse for dismissing them is unfair.  This is a space specifically set aside for asserting themselves against social norms. 

So yes, it may have a cost in terms of public perception. But to say that cost outweighs the benefits, to say that it *hurts* the gay movement on the whole and should be stopped, is inaccurate. (And IMO pretty self centered on the part of straight folks.) Yes, the opinions of straight people do matter on a social level.  But they're not the only thing that matters.  The gratification and liberation of self-assertion against contrary social norms is important, too. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484508340.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>How about with straight people start acting normal and stop shitting all over us? 
It's not normal to police what other people wear or who they date. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484883668.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Normal is defined as the usual behaviour.  By DEFINITION the norm is his most of society acts. It isn't necessarily better, but it IS THE NORM.

Also, please point to a single place where I mentioned wanting to change how people act. I am saying act how you want, but these will be the consequences</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485789753.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>Frankly there have been millions of words written about why describing hetero relationships as normal as a problem so I'm not even going to bother touching on that. Here's a psychology today article about why you're using normal wrong https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/rethinking-mental-health/201111/what-do-we-mean-normal 

And as for consequences, what consequences? That prudes don't show up to the pride parade? That doesn't seem like a bad thing. Literally everyone is welcome at pride including the many churches that march in the parades across the country. If a bit of skin is keeping somebody away that's on them. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487358182.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>The consequences are that even left winged moderates like me, who are fully backing all gay rights etc, find it hard to seperate "normal" gay people from the bonkers gay pride ones.



When there is a part of a community who behaves poorly (to the view of most it IS poorly, not saying it's a fact that it is), it reflects poorly on the entire community.



So you get people like me. Super moderate. Super left wing on social issues like homosexuality. however my view of gay people is tainted by these parades. And there are TONS of people like me.


The gay pride stuff makes the overall view of gay people worse to SO MANY people. You don't have to care. That's fine. But that's the result.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487387412.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>And we don't! Perfect! You're welcome to hold whatever beliefs you choose and were going to have a blast at our family friendly event. The whole point of pride is we don't care how other people see us. We're taking one day where we don't have to try and hide who are and celebrating it. 

Are you just as uncomfortable with a fourth of July parade or a day at the beach? There's the same amount of specialization that happens at either of those places but it's directed towards straight people so no one cares. What about tv or movies? Does all the sex make you uncomfortable there? The only reason pride is seen as deviant is because queer relationships are still gross for far too many people </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487599476.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>You seem very happy to talk for the entire gay community. I expect a lot of gay people want to be seen just as a regular person who happens to be gay. You seem to want to be seen as a "Gay person".


Why can't gay just be a feature like being left handed, where it doesn't really matter. Surely that's the goal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487864402.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm just speaking for those who attend Pride and like it the way it is. We're not going to stop celebrating our one day a year because a few people are offended. This whole month is Pride Month and if the actual parade is too flamboyant for you there are many other ways to show your support. 

Lol you really think the goal of Pride is to not stand out? Really? Maybe we should all go back in the closet so as not to offend anyone that way either. Do you also support forcing left handed kids to use their right in middle school "just to be normal like everyone else?"
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488304969.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>So to sum your point up "I don't care of I hurt other gay people because I wanna party"?


That's clearly a crude summary but it seems to be what you are saying.


Your actions ARE leading to people who have always supported gay people starting to sway (e.g. me). I am 100% for all gay rights. I don't at all care about you being gay, literally doesn't matter to me. however due to the absurd pride nonsense I find myself accidentally putting those traits on all gays, which clearly isn't fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488434409.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>Sure that's a good summary for entirely missing the point I'm making. 

Pride isn't a party. It's about expressing yourself however you want with an emphasis on the lgbt community but all allies are welcome too. It is NOT a 
recruitment festival to bring moderates in or cater to them in any way. If you don't like what Pride is (have you even attended one before condemning it as wrong?) that's fine but it's not for you then. 

I don't like Veterans Day but instead of complaining it focuses too much on glorifying violence I just stay home and play with my dog . Not every event is meant to include everyone. When has appealing to the mainstream ever made something better? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488884758.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Pride isn't a party.

You cant be serious. Its a huge party. 


&amp;gt;  It is NOT a recruitment festival to bring moderates in or cater to them in any way.

AGAIN. for like the hundredth time. That is NOT WHAT I AM SAYING. I do not want I have to repeat myself again, so please stop saying this. 


I am saying you are pushing people away. I am not even saying thats bad. I am telling you the FACT that you are. Thats it. Can you please just acknowledge that the way people act at pride pushes at least SOME people away. 


&amp;gt; I don't like Veterans Day but instead of complaining it focuses too much on glorifying violence I just stay home and play with my dog . 


Are there veterans riding giant gun shaped dildos? If so, I kinda think you have a point. If not, it isnt really comparable. 


I am going to simplify this for you, as it clearly isnt taking. I am going to lay out a logical trail, and you will either agree, or point out where SPECIFICALLY its wrong. 


1. At Pride parades there is often quite lude flamboyant displays. 

2. This puts off a lot of people. 

3. People start to associate this behaviour with all gays, not jsut the crazy ones at the parade. 

4. This can have negative effects on all gays. 



Again, please point to exactly where you disagree. If you just ignore that, you are not debating in good faith and I simply wont reply. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30489227586.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao a logic trail? 

1: a pride parade is no more lewd than literally any other parade. There is an adult section but it's behind a tent you have to be carded to get into. If you're going to keep claiming it's a bastion of depravity you need to source it. 

2-4: are all the same complaint. You keep saying it puts people off like that's some kind of terrible thing. Are you seriously telling me that because you might see a vaguely penis shaped float you no longer support my right to be married? Be employed equally? Really? If so you were never an ally to begin with and WE DON'T WANT YOU. If you just don't like the atmosphere of pride don't go. Why should we cater to you? You're giving me literally no reason to change other than "I don't like it." sorry, not compelling enough. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30490487272.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>So you are okay with taking a large group of people whom support you, and turning them against you, because you like a good party.


I am not saying that's right or wrong. But that IS the outcome of your actions.


And as I have said a hundred times now, and I DO NOt want to have to repeat myself again, this is NOT about rights. That's argument is over. Gay rights are not an issue, we've won, gays have rights.


It's about being treated as "weird". Like someone with a face tattoo.



If you really okay with being thought of as weird by most people, fine.



You are also starting to make ALL gay people seem weird, and that's just not fair to the normal ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30490961606.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>Lol! I didn't know the gay rights movement was over! Thank you for telling me! Do you also tell black people that racism has been solved since Obama was president too? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30490988529.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>What rights do gay people not have (in the UK, I'm not sure about America).


Feel free to add American things if you want, as I'm always open to learning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30490999351.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30491078071.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>As with everyone I have asked, becuase you can't name one you have got agressive. 


If you could name some, you would. By deflecting you have implicitly told me that you agree there are no rights they don't have.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30491102040.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Veloqu – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+Veloqu&amp;amp;message=Veloqu+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e09jxo7/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30494461732.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Can you please provide me with any legal rights gay people don't have?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30495339758.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>You can't be serious. Let's see, I personally have been denied my name change, am no longer allowed to re-enlist in the Marines, won't go to the prison that matches my gender identity, am in fear of using public bathrooms, and constantly have to deal with harassment at the VA hospital I have to go to. But sure, I don't face any discrimination. 

Plus you're ignoring pride isn't just for legal protections. It's about social acceptance which we clearly don't have since you are trying to shove us back in the closet. We're not interested in pandering to you. Pride is for us. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30495709138.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I'll go point by point.

Name change denial is weird. How would that even notice that you are gay? Chuck to Steve could be done gay or non gay. If it's chuck to Sally that's a trans issue, not a gay issue.



The marines is odd. Maybe I've misunderstood but being gay can stop you from being on marines? I did not think that was true.


The prison one is about gender identity. Not relevant to a discussion on homosexuality


Harassment is not a legal problem.


I .very happy to talk about gay social issues or trans legal issues. However that's not what I asked into this question



Can you provide any legal rights gay people don't have?



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30495945392.0" user="Veloqu" delta="False">
    <text>No I refuse to entertain you shifting the goalposts. Do you not think trans people have a place at pride? Your question doesn't matter at all because pride is for everyone on the queer spectrum myself included. 

Honestly I can't even fathom why you keep bringing up legal issues anyway. The US has legally been its own country for a couple hundred years now and we still celebrate Independence Day. Gay marriage just got legalized a few decades ago and we still get shit on from everyone. 

I'm done with this conversation because you don't care about being an ally, just telling people what they should or should not wear at an even that isn't even meant for you. I don't like jerseys and tailgating but I'm not about to ask for the culture at football game to change because I can't handle public drunkenness or whatever. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30495976273.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No I refuse to entertain you shifting the goalposts. 

I have not shifted the goal posts once. We have been talking about gay people. If you would like to change the conversation, thats ok. 



So to be clear, you cant provide a SINGLE legal right that gay people dont have? Cool, sounds like the gay rights movement is over. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30497714886.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Please stop downvoting. This sub is not a place where downvoting is disagreeing.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484510376.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484664815.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>What? How? Seriously, if you are gonna slur someone spell it out. 


I have been nothing but supportive this entire conversation. Surely not caring if someone is gay is the goal!!??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485658862.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Who said that was the goal?  Not caring about something that is so intimately wrapped up in someone's life is like not caring about them as a person.  If you told someone about some piece of your identity or personality that you valued and derived pleasure and meaning from, and they replied "whatever." or "don't care." might that not seem rude and dismissive? 

Celebrating that someone is gay; loving that someone is gay; feeling fucking joyful that someone is gay = all better goals.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487348047.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Do you care that I am left handed? No. 


Why the fuck would I care that someone is gay? I don't love it or hate it. Do you love that I am straight,? Are you joyful that I'm straight,?



The goal should be to treat people equally regardless of sexuality. Now I don't care if someone is straight, so I won't care if they are gay.


Gay is NOT better. It is NOT worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487454105.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>If you love being left handed, and being left handed brings you joy and meaning, then yes I care about that. 

Treating people equally, yes, but equally \*well\* is better than equally dismissively. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487535805.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Why on earth would being gay bring someone joy. That's part of the problem. Don't have happy or sad about being gay. Just be gay.


Being gay should not be a big deal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484796760.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>u/freeside_till_i_die – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+freeside_till_i_die&amp;amp;message=freeside_till_i_die+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05ouqw/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484568182.0" user="CJGibson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; when You start making it a big show I start to dislike it

Maybe it's not by, for, or about you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484660824.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>And as I have now stated about 100 times, sure. I am not telling people how to act. I am simply informing them the consequences of their actions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485615783.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think they don't know?  That's pretty condescending! 

Or else you're making a threat...that \*you'll\* be the source of those 'consequences'.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487340657.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Mate, calm it down a tad.


As I have said, it's literally a polite discussion. They are saying they'd like to behave like this. I am saying this will be the outcome.


That's it. Nothing more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487449543.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>You're being consistently vague about \*what\* that outcome is.  In what way will people suffer if they behave in a manner that you don't find normal?  Who will be the cause of that suffering?  

If you're saying it's okay to not treat people like human beings with the basic amounts of respect, dignity, freedoms, and rights, just because they behave in ways you disapprove of, then that's not okay. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487613831.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't been vague. I have spelled it out many many times in this thread. However in summary here is an example.


Take face tattoos. If I am at work and have to choose someone to do a project with, I will have very conscious bias against the tattoos guy. This can clearly hurt them as they could be passed to for great pieces of work etc.


.why would I pass them over? Becuase being face tattooed very likely means you are kinda weird. For instance if I was hiring, it would be a massive negative against them.

This isn't just me. It's the standard approach to face tattoos in finance jobs.



Now if being gay starts to be seen as "weird" because people associate it with the pride craziness the same can happen to them.



Not saying it's right or wrong, just a likely outcome</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485363044.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>90&amp;amp;#37; of society is cis and hetero. If you cannot see how overt sexual displays at "pride" celebrations makes even the gays(hence this thread) uncomfortable than maybe the problem lies with you? It's not like OP is saying pride should stop. He's just saying if it was more accommodating to everyday people it would achieve its goal better. I hear from my gay friends every day is hetero cis day, yet I don't see overt sexual displays at any parades unless they are for porno.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485900198.0" user="CJGibson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; He's just saying if it was more accommodating to everyday people it would achieve its goal better.

If you think eliminating portions of the LGBT community from the celebration of Pride in order for it to be more well received by the 90% of the world that isn't LGBT would help it achieve it's goals, then it seems like maybe you don't really understand the goals of Pride.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488000138.0" user="zuesk134" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  it would achieve its goal better

so whats the "goal" of pride parades? why do people think a celebration for the LGBT by the LGBT has a goal that is anything beyond "lets have fun and celebrate!!!!"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488116435.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>The "goal' is to show that being gay isn't your entire identity. That being gay is the same as heterosexual "love" and isn't any different or outside the norm. It's like being left handed, it's an aspect of your person hood but doesn't define you. Hence the whole "we're here, we're queer, get used to it" mantra. It's not we are sexual deviants and love bondage and strap'ons and outward sexuality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488303150.0" user="oldmanjoe" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt;In fact, I think it's safe to say that sex is just about everybody's favorite thing to do with each other. Why should there be any negative connotation?

Sex is something for adults / mature people. We protect minors from all sorts of "adult" content. I don't think that's wrong. 

I have no problem teaching my 5 year old child about love between two people. I am not interested in a conversation about dildos with my 5 year old.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484587378.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>Understandable and I guess it's not persuading you the way that it did for me. I was completely on your side on this issue (the parade just freaks people out and confirms their worst assumptions about these groups), but this experience of having witnessed these displays, particularly in person, made me realize that if so many people are willing to make fools of themselves in public, they must really care about these other issues like civil equality and mistreatment by the police. My views have evolved in other ways for other reasons since then, but I guess that's what hearing Mr. Savage's thoughts did to my delicate sensibility. Maybe my mind was just open enough to accept it at the time, but there was a point where I didn't think I'd budge on the issue.

I hope you get to a point where telling your family and friends about who you are is as comfortable as telling your family about your new dog or about your cool friend from Ecuador. The leather-clad daddies and bois are rooting for you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487993792.0" user="zuesk134" delta="False">
    <text>the purpose of pride is not to convince "people like you" of anything. it's for gay people by gay people. the comfort of the straight "left wing on almost all social issues" people is not of concern. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488280036.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>So you wouldn't care if a very large group of society started to dislike gay people due to actions you did?
That affects all gay people, not just pride goers.


Here is the thing. It's not about being gay. I don't care. Most people (at least where I live) don't care. We are passed being gay being an important thing, which is great.


It's about acting like a wanker. When a large enough section of a group act like wankers, it's hard not to associate the group with being wankers.



Your actions affect OTHER gay people negatively. You don't need to case about me. You seem rather heterophobic, sure. But you surely care about them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488284380.0" user="zuesk134" delta="False">
    <text>pride has been pride for many many years. a "very large group" of people already hate the LGBT, and it's not because of the parades. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488287791.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't address the point. You are turning people who are "on your side" against you with your actions. 


That hurts everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488294755.0" user="zuesk134" delta="False">
    <text>no, i'm not ignoring the point because i disagree with your entire sentiment so what is there to talk about? pride is not to win anyone over. and the end result isnt new homophobia </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488311865.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. You clearly aren't listening. The point of pride doesn't matter.


There IS the effect of turning some people who previously supported gays against. That's a fact. 


Regardless of the intent, pride DOES have negative effects on gays.


Sure, it may have positive ones, and you can argue it's net positive. But you CANNOT ignore the clear negative effects, which is what you are trying to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483644917.0" user="jwg529" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;The other point Dan has made is pretty simple: the "freaks" were the ones that supported the gay and trans community from day one. Straight swingers, sadists, and masochists were among the first to rally behind the gay cause, even though it probably hurt their own political cause in doing so. To an extent, the LGBT community "owes" some support and some gratitude for people who stuck with them in removing sodomy laws and eventually legalizing gay marriage in the US. The crazy stuff in some parades is sort of a salute to this past, a way to let that freak flag fly and be accepting of all, even if it's quite offensive to even fairly accepting people. If you drop the allies from the parade, you're sort of turning your back on your staunchest advocates.


Are your suggesting the "freaks" of the parade are not gay or trans but instead are straight swingers, sadists, and masochists? To clarify.. not meaning freaks as in a bad connotation, but as in the most flamboyant and obscene with their outfits and behavior during the parade. Because I agree with OP that Pride would be better if it were a family friendly event instead of a "freak" show as you put it. And I think you can't put the blame on other groups as you seem to have done IMO. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484512542.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>I used the term "freak" in quotes because it's not a term I'd normally use or I believe to be literally accurate, but it has been reclaimed by the BDSM and other communities much as "queer" has. I also understand that this portion of these parades isn't the only one with nudity or defiant sexual displays. However in my experience I'd seen it as odd that these folks were involved in a "gay pride" event and their sole purpose appeared to be to freak me out, unlike the kindly local high school gay-straight alliance chapter's salute to Stonewall. Mr. Savage had enlightened me. It made me view all of the gimp gear, simulated gay sex, and dildo waving with a strange wistfulness (and sinfulness as my autocorrect first suggested). Sorry if I sounded sex-negative or opposed to being inclusive to all brothers, sisters, and others who want to have fun in the privacy of their bedroom or dungeon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483682737.0" user="Traveledfarwestward" delta="False">
    <text>And regular ol’ American families *who just want to have a nice time in town with their kids* should just know ahead of time to stay away from these things and LGBTQ people, I take it?

***Doesn’t seem very inclusive to me.*** Y'all are about as tolerant as the people you complain about, imho.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484549710.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>Bring everyone. If you're offended, you can leave. Or you can stay, like I normally do even though some of the candy they throw is too phallic for my liking. I hope you give it a shot and enjoy it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484554901.0" user="Traveledfarwestward" delta="False">
    <text>Kids?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484624496.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. The parts that I would deem completely inappropriate for kids in parades I've attended are fairly small and are easily seen in advance. Kids can be shielded from those. If the parade is more intense than expected for whatever reason, you can pack up and get some ice cream instead. It's a lot of work, so it's a bit easier to relax and have fun without the kids. But that's the case for a grocery store or cinema as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483693822.0" user="UberSeoul" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting points. As to your mention of the door-in-the-face technique, the [overton window](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overton_window) theory likewise confirms exactly that line of reasoning. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484540811.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, although the "Overton Window" concept has been sort of co-opted by the fringe right-wing in the US, the idea rings very true to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484092406.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>There's more to being gay than sex and nudity. I feel it boils all of our struggles down to one day of being freaky and inappropriate, rather than commemorating everything the community has been through. The fact that the parade still occurs doesn't mean it doesn't set the cause back; young adults with no families are abundant in large cities and can make it out to these events. Parents on the other hand are more likely to look at them with discomfort and displeasure. Since pride is so heavily associated with the community, the image we paint of ourselves is sex depraved maniacs rather than actual multifaceted people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484308281.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's more to being gay than sex and nudity.

Not sure what you mean by this. There's more to being human than sexuality, but a person's sexuality is what makes a person gay. The pride parades are there for acceptance of "deviant" sexual practices, as they always have been. I understand your feelings about a family-friendly acceptance event, but these have always been about sexuality and imo probably always will be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484789567.0" user="Maple_jack" delta="False">
    <text>Being gay is not just about liking dick. Being gay is wanting to cuddle with your boyfriend or hug them and kiss them on the cheek after they achieve something. Its about caring and loving someone who is the same sex as you. Being gay does not have to focus around the sexuality of it. the sexuality is just the loudest and most captivating part and tbh most peoples first experience of seeing anything gay was seeing a gay category in porn. 

I do think the gay community needs to show the world they are about more than just sex because a lot of people who enter the gay community whose main experiences of gayness have been hook ups now seem to think that's all there is. The about of cheating and fuck boy behaviour is honestly insane . </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484833695.0" user="memester_supremester" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The about of cheating and fuck boy behaviour is honestly insane . 

this is true of hetero guys too though lets be honest</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484970276.0" user="Maple_jack" delta="False">
    <text>Good point i guess i should not have expected anything different </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484888235.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>I agree and disagree. Being in a relationship includes a lot of experiences besides sex. Being in a community as you put it, or a  marginalized group, subculture, or however a person would like to define their own experiences -- includes a lot of experiences besides just the Thing that it is about. So yeah, gay people experience gayness is a lot of ways besides having gay sex. But what does it mean to be gay? It means you are attracted to the same sex. It is a sexuality. So yep, it IS just about liking dick. That's the only barrier to entry here.

I think what you mean is that, by asserting and celebrating their rights to engage in whatever sexual practices they want, pride parades somehow reduce gay people and all that they experience -- who as human beings are more than sexuality -- into just sexual practices. I don't think that makes sense unless you see gay people as somehow not human.

I understand the desire to have a family friendly pride event or an event that honors other experiences that LGBT people typically share, but my opinion is that this isn't what pride parades are usually for. They're about asserting the right to experience sexually however a person wants without discrimination or criminal action against them. I don't think that's reductive anymore than going to a birthday party would make you think that person celebrates no other holidays. That just isn't the focus of the event.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485013606.0" user="Maple_jack" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So yep, it IS just about liking dick. That's the only barrier to entry here.

The only barrier to entry here is liking guys not necessarily dick. A gay guy might not like trans men despite them having a dick. Additionally it is possible to want a romantic relationship and not really desire sex for gay people as well as straight people. 

I want to be clear i am not against the sexual side i just wish people would see past it. i see no problem with pride having sexual elements the problem comes from the media and people only focusing on that part. its like thousands of openly gay people happy and walking together yet the only thing the media focuses on is the 100 people who have a sexual outfit and then that gets exaggerated in to people thinking that is all pride is.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485041934.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;then that gets exaggerated in to people thinking that is all pride is.

I think that's a problem with those people, not a problem with pride. Not to state the obvious, but the open, unimpeded expression of sexual preference is often not available for individual LGBT people (or other "deviant" desires) in the same way that it is available for heterosexual/vanilla people. I think being able to temporarily let go of that self-censorship is an integral part of the event. I don't like to be sexual in public so I don't participate in it, but I can definitely understand why it's important to some people.

As for your first point, I'm aware. I chose to use your words for stylistic reasons, I guess that's what I get for being cute.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485446873.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's a problem with those people, not a problem with pride.

\[Totally\]([https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=https&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;#37;2Fimg.4plebs.org&amp;amp;#37;2Fboards&amp;amp;#37;2Fpol&amp;amp;#37;2Fimage&amp;amp;#37;2F1386&amp;amp;#37;2F49&amp;amp;#37;2F1386490428677.jpg&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;#37;2Fwww.ign.com&amp;amp;#37;2Fboards&amp;amp;#37;2Fthreads&amp;amp;#37;2Fi\-dont\-hate\-gay\-people\-but\-i\-hate\-the\-gay\-pride\-social\-movement.454033915&amp;amp;#37;2Fpage\-8&amp;amp;docid=Ohwn4DrM\-6PdkM&amp;amp;tbnid=N\_MKIoohFf6jDM&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;vet=10ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwgyKAAwAA..i&amp;amp;w=635&amp;amp;h=500&amp;amp;client=firefox\-b\-1\-ab&amp;amp;bih=873&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;q=overt&amp;amp;#37;20sexuality&amp;amp;#37;20at&amp;amp;#37;20pride&amp;amp;#37;20parades&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwgyKAAwAA&amp;amp;iact=mrc&amp;amp;uact=8](https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=https%3A%2F%2Fimg.4plebs.org%2Fboards%2Fpol%2Fimage%2F1386%2F49%2F1386490428677.jpg&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ign.com%2Fboards%2Fthreads%2Fi-dont-hate-gay-people-but-i-hate-the-gay-pride-social-movement.454033915%2Fpage-8&amp;amp;docid=Ohwn4DrM-6PdkM&amp;amp;tbnid=N_MKIoohFf6jDM%3A&amp;amp;vet=10ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwgyKAAwAA..i&amp;amp;w=635&amp;amp;h=500&amp;amp;client=firefox-b-1-ab&amp;amp;bih=873&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;q=overt%20sexuality%20at%20pride%20parades&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwgyKAAwAA&amp;amp;iact=mrc&amp;amp;uact=8)) \[in\]([https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;#37;2Fwww.cypheravenue.com&amp;amp;#37;2Fuploads&amp;amp;#37;2F8&amp;amp;#37;2F5&amp;amp;#37;2F6&amp;amp;#37;2F8&amp;amp;#37;2F8568420&amp;amp;#37;2F9600828\_orig.png&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;#37;2Fcypheravenue.com&amp;amp;#37;2Flacking\-standards\-at\-pride\-parades&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;docid=LLY\-oYH7\_WRviM&amp;amp;tbnid=okxzO7rfJMlOYM&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;vet=10ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg4KAYwBg..i&amp;amp;w=684&amp;amp;h=187&amp;amp;client=firefox\-b\-1\-ab&amp;amp;bih=873&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;q=overt&amp;amp;#37;20sexuality&amp;amp;#37;20at&amp;amp;#37;20pride&amp;amp;#37;20parades&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg4KAYwBg&amp;amp;iact=mrc&amp;amp;uact=8](https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cypheravenue.com%2Fuploads%2F8%2F5%2F6%2F8%2F8568420%2F9600828_orig.png&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcypheravenue.com%2Flacking-standards-at-pride-parades%2F&amp;amp;docid=LLY-oYH7_WRviM&amp;amp;tbnid=okxzO7rfJMlOYM%3A&amp;amp;vet=10ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg4KAYwBg..i&amp;amp;w=684&amp;amp;h=187&amp;amp;client=firefox-b-1-ab&amp;amp;bih=873&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;q=overt%20sexuality%20at%20pride%20parades&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg4KAYwBg&amp;amp;iact=mrc&amp;amp;uact=8))\[heads\]([https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=https&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;#37;2Fimgoat.com&amp;amp;#37;2Fuploads&amp;amp;#37;2F16a5320fa4&amp;amp;#37;2F30846.jpg&amp;amp;imgrefurl=https&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;#37;2Fwww.reddit.com&amp;amp;#37;2Fr&amp;amp;#37;2Fnews&amp;amp;#37;2Fcomments&amp;amp;#37;2F805jwb&amp;amp;#37;2Fmississippi\_town\_rejects\_gay\_pride\_parade\_lawsuit&amp;amp;#37;2F&amp;amp;docid=NiIKGh6dhtalcM&amp;amp;tbnid=PPjoNVyr36dWwM&amp;amp;#37;3A&amp;amp;vet=10ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg\-KAwwDA..i&amp;amp;w=720&amp;amp;h=540&amp;amp;client=firefox\-b\-1\-ab&amp;amp;bih=873&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;q=overt&amp;amp;#37;20sexuality&amp;amp;#37;20at&amp;amp;#37;20pride&amp;amp;#37;20parades&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg\-KAwwDA&amp;amp;iact=mrc&amp;amp;uact=8](https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=https%3A%2F%2Fimgoat.com%2Fuploads%2F16a5320fa4%2F30846.jpg&amp;amp;imgrefurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.reddit.com%2Fr%2Fnews%2Fcomments%2F805jwb%2Fmississippi_town_rejects_gay_pride_parade_lawsuit%2F&amp;amp;docid=NiIKGh6dhtalcM&amp;amp;tbnid=PPjoNVyr36dWwM%3A&amp;amp;vet=10ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg-KAwwDA..i&amp;amp;w=720&amp;amp;h=540&amp;amp;client=firefox-b-1-ab&amp;amp;bih=873&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;q=overt%20sexuality%20at%20pride%20parades&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwizzJ3wu73bAhUIxVQKHcLMCJoQMwg-KAwwDA&amp;amp;iact=mrc&amp;amp;uact=8))</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487196715.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>You know, I've been on multiple naked bike ride events where literally hundreds of people cycle through the streets of a downtown area naked on a bright Saturday afternoon. There were kids, old people, families, everyone saw us with our floppy bits in the breeze. And no one seemed to care. 

But of course, you show off your queerness, and suddenly it's "save the kids" and "this is indecent". So why is a literal horde of naked people riding around the capital so much more palatable than a bunch of gay dudes dressed funny doing the same?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487489528.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And no one seemed to care. 

Or so you thought, because people aren't always assholes and don't need to tell everyone how they feel. You probly offended a lot of people, while possibly breaking decency laws. You just don't know cause people weren't vocal about it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484883977.0" user="TMac1128" delta="False">
    <text>So gay relationships are *only* about the sex, eh? Sounds incomplete.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484912560.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how you could possibly conclude that from what I said.

&amp;gt;There's more to being human than sexuality, but a person's sexuality is what makes a person gay.

What is the bare minimum you have to do to be a homosexual? What is the definition of homosexuality? Being attracted to your own sex. It is a sexual preference. That in no way means your relationship is built on sex, any more than a heterosexual relationship is built on sex. Please don't be disingenuous in your interpretation of my words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485096983.0" user="TMac1128" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but a person's sexuality is what makes a person gay.

Your own words that limited the scope of being gay to their sexuality. Neither of us truly believe being gay is *only* about sex so why fight someone when they suggest a parade should focus less on the *sexuality and general inappropriateness* of pride parades?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485102263.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>Sexuality as in sexual preferences, not sexuality as in the act of sex. "Neither of us truly believe that," you say. In other words, you know exactly what I meant, and you know I used a common word to express my meaning, so why the disingenuous nit-picking? Spare me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485110351.0" user="TMac1128" delta="False">
    <text>You should have spared the other guy when all he commented was that a pride parade should be more than sexuality... which you then doubled down "well its all about sexuality". Should have spared all of us, in fact. Goodbye</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485053799.0" user="kwantsu-dudes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Not sure what you mean by this.

Because these pride parades are creating a negative association in many peoples mind that "gay = flamboyantly sexual". So if people dislike flamboyantly sexual people, they should dislike gays as well. And vis versa, to slow our progression to a more sexually accepting society. 

OP wants "gay = just another normal relationship" that should be attempting to shed it's "deviant" label. These pride parades do the opposite. They try embrace it. And that may be nice for those people, but it's not the best at garnering acceptance from others.

So I think you're right about what the pride parades are, but OP wants them to be a tool for acceptance of homosexual individuals and relationships. And I'd have to agree with OP that they currently aren't a tool for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485084908.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're not giving homophobes enough intellectual credit. They're not morons. They can look around and easily realize the streets are not full of flamboyantly sexual sodomites. They may see a few homosexual couples holding hands or sharing a quick kiss, just as couples do all around them. I don't think a good-faith actor could come away with the conclusion of LGBT being exhibitionist in general based on pride parades.

I guess OP and I disagree on what it means for LGBT to be accepted. THE thing about LGBT people that is unacceptable is sexual preference. I can walk around looking like a heterosexual person without discrimination or molestation. That doesn't mean I am accepted as a WHOLE PERSON, because my sexual preferences are still considered unacceptable by many. If acceptance means "don't look too gay" "pretend you don't like to have deviant sex and we're cool" etc, that's no acceptance at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485259553.0" user="kwantsu-dudes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; They can look around and easily realize the streets are not full of flamboyantly sexual sodomites.

No, they can't. Because they aren't in the streets. They don't go to the pride parades. What they see is what the media focuses on. And the media will focus on the aspects that creat controversy. So if you are attempting a message of acceptance, you should limit your expressions so that they can't be used to offend others.

If it is just an event to have fun and do whatever, fine. But it certainly isn't being used to make people more accepting of homosexual relationships.

&amp;gt; If acceptance means "don't look too gay" "pretend you don't like to have deviant sex and we're cool" etc, that's no acceptance at all.

What does "looking gay" consist of? If feminine, isn't that a distaste for feminine men, and not homosexuality? I think it's important we make the distinction. Because now you're trying to create an association between fashion and sexuality. We need to tear down these association if we want acceptance, not build them up.

Plenty of people enjoy "deviant" sexuality, (bdsm, underage, rape play, anal, sex out of wedlock, all sorts of other fetishes) and pretend to not like them in the society they live. Most people don't really care to know other's sexual preferences. Yes, the "norm" of hetereosexual relationships helps to take our focus away from what it actually means. So when something abnormal is displayed, homosexuality, it's an actual mention of sexuality. And that's tough for progress.

But "normal" behavior will always be viewed as more acceptable. Thus the best think homosexual people can do, is attempt to normalize their sexuality. And I don't think these parades are an active step in that direction. Normal people don't have parades for being normal. 

People need to decide. Do they want to be viewed as different, unique, and special? Or do they want to be viewed as normal? Being special comes with some privileges, but it also comes with some costs. They need to be willing to accept both.

And that social lesson applies to more than just homosexuality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485529257.0" user="zharth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; isn't that a distaste for feminine men, and not homosexuality?

We're talking about homophobic morons, right? They make this mistake readily and enthusiastically. I've been shouted down on the street for being a "fag" despite the fact that I don't identify as gay. But because I'm trans, I threaten straight culture's expectations of what a "man" is supposed to look and act like. These morons don't care about the details - that's part of the problem. They just don't like whatever is different from what they're familiar with, and they're not afraid to say something about it.

&amp;gt;Thus the best think homosexual people can do, is attempt to normalize their sexuality.

Aw, hell no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485701580.0" user="kwantsu-dudes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I've been shouted down on the street for being a "fag" despite the fact that I don't identify as gay.

Thus why I want to break the association, not build it up.

&amp;gt; But because I'm trans, I threaten straight culture's expectations of what a "man" is supposed to look and act like.

No. It's not straight culture. It's a gender norm/roles "culture". (I don't really know what makes up these different sub-"cultures" people continue to come up with. Can you describe straight and gay culture for me?)  Sexuality is part of the more wide designarions of gender norms/roles. It doesn't take a straight man to believe men should be "tough, rugged, etc.". Again, you're conflating two different things even if they have some strong associations.

&amp;gt; These morons don't care about the details - that's part of the problem. They just don't like whatever is different from what they're familiar with, and they're not afraid to say something about it.

And why don't people like things they are not familar with? Because they don't understand it? Because they believe what they think is "right" and everything else is "wrong"? 

People can change. Minds can be changed. But it requires the correct message. You seem unwilling to even attempt to discover one. Fine. That's not your duty. But you better not expect change to occur then.

&amp;gt; Aw, hell no.

Why not? What makes being gay *more* special than being straight? Why the focus on standing out? If the effort is for inclusivity, that will **require** normaliziting the behavior. If you instead want your sexuality to be sometime of a badge so you can be different from others, then so be it. But being different, comes with negatives as well. And if you're complaining about how your desire to be special is resulting in special treatment, then I don't really care.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485690803.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Homophobia has always been partially about gender deviance.  Having sex with men, after all, is supposedly feminine behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485725919.0" user="kwantsu-dudes" delta="False">
    <text>I actually brought up that in reply I made to someone else. That opposition to homosexuality (and acceptance of hetereosexuality) has to do with certain views on gender norms/roles.

And I'm all for redefining those roles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30492287089.0" user="batterycrayon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No, they can't. Because they aren't in the streets.

Are you arguing that homophobes never leave their houses, and the only information they get about the world around them comes from the news? Any given person can, through their daily lives, observe that the streets are not regularly full of homosexual sexcapades.

&amp;gt;Because now you're trying to create an association between fashion and sexuality. 

No, I'm not. "Looking gay" is in the eye of the beholder -- as another comment mentioned, a man dressed femininely might "look gay" to a given person -- but what I was referring to are normal behaviors that would give away a person's sexual preference. For instance if I hold hands with another girl and give her a kiss on the cheek when we end the night, a casual observer could easily deduce my sexuality.

The whole point here, which I think you missed, is that many LGBT individuals only feel accepted when they are passing as a straight person. "As long as I don't have to know you exist, we're cool" is not acceptance.

&amp;gt;Plenty of people enjoy "deviant" sexuality ... and pretend to not like them in the society they live. 

Yes, that's the exact point. Non-"deviant" behavior doesn't have to hide. I can walk down the street holding hands with a man and kiss him goodbye without any worry. If I do it with a woman, there is less acceptance. The premise of the pride parade is that the concept of consensual sex being deemed "deviant" and necessarily secret is a problem society needs to solve. The stigma around unusual consensual sex needs to go, that is the point. Displaying them at pride IS a step in that direction, because it removes the element of secrecy en mass for a day. Nobody is asking you to like gay sex. We're asking you to stop stigmatizing it.

&amp;gt;People need to decide. Do they want to be viewed as different, unique, and special? Or do they want to be viewed as normal?

This is a weird perspective to force on the issue. I suppose it depends on what you mean by "normal." LGBT is a small portion of the population, therefore it could be considered unusual. However, the job of insurance salesman is also a small percent of the population -- you don't consider insurance salesmen abnormal, do you? Certainly, you wouldn't expect an insurance salesman to try hard not to look like an insurance salesman or keep their job duties a secret in normal daily activities. If this person talked about selling insurance during a discussion about job duties where everyone shared, you wouldn't say "why do you insist on being special!" Similarly, sexual preferences are just a difference people have. It is not about being on a special/normal spectrum. It is about equitable treatment. The average person doesn't walk around trying not to look straight or pretending not to like straight missionary sex or hide their straight romantic relationships. People who like "deviant" sex don't want to be subject to discrimination due to this fact. It is that simple.

As for your point about social costs: there is a difference between natural consequences and unreasonable discrimination. If you don't shower, people will stop wanting to hang out with you until you bathe. If you talk about your sexual encounters in a loud voice at a church luncheon, you will be asked to leave whether you're describing "deviant" sex or basic, married, procreation sex. Yelling at all the fags about how gross they are is not a social consequence, it is a hate act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484344222.0" user="paintvulgarpicture" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's more to being gay than sex and nudity.

Is there? What more is there to being gay than attraction to the same sex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484667183.0" user="potato1" delta="False">
    <text>Being attracted to someone isn't just about sex. There's also romance, non-sexual affection, etc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484772495.0" user="RosieBunny" delta="False">
    <text>It’s also about the social and societal impact that being gay has on you and the experiences that are common to the group. Like, are you able to bring your significant other home to meet your parents? Are you worried you’ll be fired or kicked out of your church or disowned by your father? Have you spent half your live believing that there’s something deeply flawed about your inherent being? 

It’s like saying being black is only about the color of your skin, or being a woman is only about your chromosomes. It’s also about the shared history and current atmosphere in which a member of a group experiences their world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485634279.0" user="Dont____Panic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Every straight guy is only with his wife so he can ram her in the pussy.  What more is there?

Sorry, I took that lewd and inflated tone to make it clear how it comes across.

Yes, sexual attraction is...  at its root, about "fucking", but it's not ***that simple*** in human relationships.  It's a complex tapestry of social expectations, interpersonal relationships, romance, politics and so many other things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484380125.0" user="anokrs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;sex depraved maniacs rather than actual multifaceted people. 

These two aren't mutually exclusive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484385161.0" user="hashtagdrogas" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe most parade focus solely on nudity? A lot of it is just normal people in normal clothes celebrating lgbt. I've never personally been to one but a quick search on Google images will show alot of that got the most part</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484426673.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>I've been to two in smaller cities and they were like any other festival. Just instead of Irish flags for St. Patrick's Day or Greek flags for Greek Fest, there were rainbow and trans flags everywhere. The ones I went to were super chill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484671136.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484671869.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/airstrike – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+airstrike&amp;amp;message=airstrike+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05sasg/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484701956.0" user="jedwards55" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly right. I was in NOLA a day or two after a pride event. I was walking down Bourbon street in the middle of the day (families and kids all around) and rounded a corner to see a man trying to catch beads on his erect penis adorned in his pride regalia. Granted this location is known for its nudity, but this seemed like it was above and beyond the norm. 
I’m from a pretty conservative background, but have become more progressive in adulthood. I’m also not a stranger to male nudity (sports team showers, etc), but this did not reflect well upon the movement. I know this doesn’t by any means represent the whole group, but a lot of people who are uncomfortable about LGBT+ feel that way because they equate that form of sexuality with sexually delinquency. These kind of actions only cement those ideas, however wrong they may be. 
So I guess the question is: who is this behavior for? Is it to express oneself in whatever way he/she wants? Is it to win over the fence-sitters? the entrenched, staunch conservatives? These are questions I don’t have answers to but might illuminate why this behavior is common at these events. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484874381.0" user="thisdude415" delta="False">
    <text>I have never been made fun of for kissing men, and no one one but my sex partners have ever even seen me have sex. 

When I get hate from homophobes, it’s about how I dress, or talk, or walk. 

Pride is when I *lean the fuck in* to the things I do in my every day life that get me hate from hateful people. 

So, I normally wear shorts a couple inches shorter than a straight man would, and sometimes I get shit for it. So during pride, expect me to be wearing really really short shorts. 

I’ve been made of for having little symbols of pride on my bag or what have you, so during pride, I’m going to rainbow all the things. 

And at the end of the day... pride isn’t for straight people. Pride is for me. The rest of the year, I’m a great employee and colleague, a generous family member and community member, etc. 

During pride? I don’t really care about those things. I shouldn’t have to be a model citizen to deserve human decency. I spent at least a decade of my life with an existential fear of spiraling into loneliness, depression, shame. And pride is when we say fuck all of that, and celebrate all the ways that tbh gay life is better than straight life. 

TL;DR: if straight people are offended by gay pride they shouldn’t come to the parade. It’s for us, not them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485253321.0" user="Lego_My_Alter_Eggo" delta="False">
    <text>I completely respect your position regarding this, I don't think anyone should force you to behave a certain way. However, We have to ask what the point of pride parades are. If they're just for non-straight people, that's fine, you don't have to try to make them more palatable to straight people. However, if the goal is integration and acceptance into the larger community (of majority straight people), then overt displays of sexuality don't make sense at these parades, because such displays actively work against the goal of integration by intentionally trying to combat the people you're trying to gain acceptance from. People dislike what they are unfamiliar with. By flaunting overtly sexual behavior in people's faces who already are not likely to be comfortable with that, it just comes off to them as a reflection of true nature. It makes the gay community look like a bunch of sexual deviants; it lowers your relatibility with the general public.

However, like I said, if that's not the goal, then it doesn't matter. Just don't expect people to like it - it's hard to have it both ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485392575.0" user="thisdude415" delta="False">
    <text>Pride is different things to different people. But the last thing I’m going to worry about during fucking gay pride is straight people’s feelings. 

Pride isn’t a call for equal rights. It’s a celebration of who we are, regardless of what society says. 

Pride parades are older than gay marriage. They’re older than the hiv epidemic. They predate consensual gay sex in private even being legal nationwide (2003, by the way). 

Pride parades started the year after the Stonewall riots. That was when police, yet again, decided to harass queer people for having the audacity to congregate in private, and wanted to ruin their lives with mugshots at a time when such a thing would actually ruin their lives. 

So, when you tell someone who knows gay history that we should act more respectable (for whom?) during gay pride, it’s actually incredibly offensive. 

For decades LGBT people kept to ourselves, sneaking around in the shadows. Guess what? Times were worse then than ever. Even after “liberation,” we still have to navigate coming out, still face disproportionate bullying, and globally most of us still don’t have equal rights. 

So no, I won’t act respectable to make the straights happy or whatever. My people tried that and got arrested. My people tried that and had the American president laugh as we died by the hundreds of AIDS. My people tried that and we lived under unequal rights for most of this country’s history. Even today, we can be fired in a lot of states for being gay. Just yesterday, there was a fucking Supreme Court case about whether you can legally decide not to sell a fucking cake to a gay couple. That case was just about Colorado—in tons of other states, it’s *perfectly* legal to discriminate against gay people like this. 

So. 

We’re here, we’re queer, get used to it. ❤️🏳️‍🌈✌️

Ps y’all stop worrying about gay people being freaky in the sheets and y’all start worrying about straight men shooting people </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485431535.0" user="Lego_My_Alter_Eggo" delta="False">
    <text>I don't care about gay people being g freaky in the sheets. I don't enjoy people being freaky in the *streets*, irrespective of gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485475371.0" user="thisdude415" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but why should I care? It’s gay pride. Not glitter parade for straight audiences </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485540630.0" user="Lego_My_Alter_Eggo" delta="False">
    <text>because it makes the movement look bad, and negatively impacts it's ability to successfully win victories for LGBT both culturally and politically. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485578916.0" user="thisdude415" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not convinced that’s true though. The earliest Gay Pride parades and the ones most raucous today (San Francisco, Chicago, New York City) are some of the cuties that have been the most progressive on these issues. 

Sure, some part of this is self sorting, but maybe there really is no such thing as bad publicity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485494740.0" user="slowtasker222" delta="False">
    <text>All I’m going to say is if you don’t care about straight peoples feelings why the hell would they ever come around to caring how you feel and how your oppressed. I’m all for gay pride parades I don’t care what you guys do but if you don’t care how people feel than why should I have any inclination to care how you feel or how your people feel. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485681087.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Because caring about oppression is basic morality?! 

Are you really conflating having to look at a dude in short shorts or a leather harness with basic civil rights and freedom from oppression and violence? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487181534.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>"Unless these gay people act how *I* say they should act, I'll fight against equal rights!"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487441033.0" user="slowtasker222" delta="False">
    <text>To bad that’s not what I said </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485381269.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485434366.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/almightySapling – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+almightySapling&amp;amp;message=almightySapling+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e067iqd/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485494847.0" user="zharth" delta="False">
    <text>Well said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485676497.0" user="DovBerele" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, well put. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486815044.0" user="TheHatOnTheCat" delta="False">
    <text>OP is part of your "us" but reading her comments she it sounds like she is also one of the people who are uncomfortable with these displays at pride parades. Not everyone who will be offended by overtly sexual behavior and nudity is straight. 

Likewise, not everyone who has a family they'd like to bring is straight. Also, not all children are straight. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30579834389.0" user="ggghhhhhh" delta="False">
    <text>I know this is super late, but i thought this comment was both beautiful &amp;amp; eye opening. Thanks for sharing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30579855912.0" user="thisdude415" delta="False">
    <text>Thank ya! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485018021.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>Sex-depraved maniacs isn't a stereotype we made for ourselves. It's one that dogs us across society. It's in the "I don't want to see that" when someone would be perfectly comfortable seeing the same affection between straight people. It's in the idea that it's somehow "anti-family" or "anti-children" to present gay relationships on TV or in movies, even if it's sexless (for chrissake, Disney's Han Solo features a kind of romance between a robot and a human, yet needed to make that robot female somehow, because male-male is more scandalous than biological-robotic). It persists when school boards fire teachers for giving any hint that they're not straight. The conception of gayness as being sexually deviant, and/or hypersexual, was created and is still empowered by the rest of society.

So how do you combat that? Chaste kisses between two men somehow become perversion in the eyes of some. There is no level of respectability that will win over a true homophobe. Keeping sex in pride, present and forefront, combats the idea that our sex is wrong. It does say "fuck you," but more importantly, it says "I am a human and okay" far better than kowtowing to social standards established by straight society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485434317.0" user="Childmonoxide" delta="False">
    <text>Chaste kisses between my wife and I in public can become perverse in the eyes of some. I've been told to "knock it off" just showing PDA's with my wife. Stop acting like sexual conservatism only affects gays. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485534491.0" user="haikuandhoney" delta="False">
    <text>He’s arguing that sexual conservatism affects gays more, which it does, and it can lead to public verbal abuse and physical violence. Where I grew up gay people were afraid to hold hands in public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486340887.0" user="Kramereng" delta="False">
    <text>This exact issue was addressed on reddit not to long ago.  See[ this writeup about why the kink community is integral to LGBQ communities and are part of pride parades.](https://np.reddit.com/r/CringeAnarchy/comments/7oanin/what_exactly_are_the_children_being_taught_here/ds87f0w/?con=)  It changed my view on the matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484316248.0" user="notmyrealnam3" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The other point Dan has made is pretty simple: the "freaks" were the ones that supported the gay and trans community from day one. Straight swingers, sadists, and masochists were among the first to rally behind the gay cause, even though it probably hurt their own political cause in doing so. To an extent, the LGBT community "owes" some support and some gratitude for people who stuck with them in removing sodomy laws and eventually legalizing gay marriage in the US. The crazy stuff in some parades is sort of a salute to this past, a way to let that freak flag fly and be accepting of all, even if it's quite offensive to even fairly accepting people. If you drop the allies from the parade, you're sort of turning your back on your staunchest advocates.

   WOW!  I'm a parent, a big supporter of gay rights and yet up until this moment I've always found it strange that the gay community , after spending 364 days since the last one wanting to be seen as equal/not freaks etc has a parade that seems to be all about tits and cock, and quite frankly it is not something my kids have been exposed to (the parades) 

   Until this moment that bothered me.  Thanks Mr. Savage (and guy above me for posting), a very interesting perspective </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486856608.0" user="TheHatOnTheCat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Dan notes that these types of parades clearly haven't set the LGBT community back too much, considering that they've been occurring in major cities for many years and these communities have never been stronger. Cities with the biggest parades are often the most accepting, although granted this may be flipping correlation and causation.

I still remember a middle school math lesson where we did a class graph of shoe size and height. Then the teacher said "so shoe size predicts height". Correlation does not prove causation and even when there is a casual relationship it may only work in one direction. 

Cities with the biggest parades are often the most accepting is exactly what one would expect and really does not tell us anything about the impact of parades. Unless it tells us parades aren't so harmful they make everyone who already accepted the lgbtq community switch to intolerance. But I don't think that is anyone's argument? So really it proves nothing?

The same can be said for the communities have never been stronger. The issue is we don't know how strong the support would be if they were cultivating a different impression. So we have no way of knowing if it is impacting things "much" or not. 

Say you had a flower in a pot of poor quality soil. It has grown and is now a blooming plant. Maybe you would look at it and say the poor soil must not have impacted it much? But you don't know that. Not unless you have seen the same type of flower growing in good soil to compare to. Maybe the same flower in better soil would be taller, have more blossoms, ect. Basically, without some sort of control (which we obviously don't have) these comments seem really empty to me. 

I'd also argue that people who already are genuinely accepting of the lgbtq community aren't going to be swayed by this behavior anyway. So for example I am straight but have zero issue with people of other orientations. Because I don't stereotype "gay people" it doesn't affect me to see some gay people being overly sexual since I will attribute it to them as individuals rather then gays in general. 

I think it is the fence sitters or people who have fully negative or partially negative views that may be impacted. People like OP's family she is concerned about being accepting. There are many people in our country who think gays are less moral and more wanton then "normal" people. They believe in a "gay lifestyle" and have certain stereotypes by which gay people are more sexual and less meaningful then people in "normal" loving relationships. If you believe this, or if you just have been exposed to this view and it is even an implicit bias you have, these actions play into that. I think what OP is saying is she wishes there was a big event where a bunch of people came out into the street and showed they were just normal people who love and live like other normal people. That is the message she wishes they were sending to people like her family. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486866738.0" user="sflerb" delta="False">
    <text>Some good points. I think we can probably agree that the influence of parades, whether it be positive or negative, has not been enough to stem the tide of acceptance overall, which I think is what I take from Mr. Savage's article.

I'll say that a parade of normal people sounds incredibly dull. I want to see a fireman, a few Shriners, and some naked painted bicylists. Some tootsie rolls wouldn't hurt. :D</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487947428.0" user="TheHatOnTheCat" delta="False">
    <text>I have been town/city parades that had fun things in them and people who looked weird, colorful, ect in nonsexual ways. I think it is perfectly possible to have a fun, colorful, strange, exciting parade without it involving people being naked or sexual themes. I've actually personally only attended "family friendly" parades. 

That said, I personally don't care. But in OP's shoes, if I felt it was my already judged group being represented to the outside world, I think I might care more. I also for example am fine just not bringing my child to pride. But if I was lgbtq I might wish it was appropriate for my family so I could share it with them like OP does. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
