<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483562728.0" user="internetboyfriend666" delta="False">
    <text>I don't entirely disagree with you in that I think certain aspects of pride can be family friendly, but almost all pride celebrations already  have some aspects that are. Remember that the very first pride parade wasn't a parade at all; it was a riot. It was an act of courageous self defense against one vicious and brutal assault in a long line of vicious and brutal assaults. We can't be complacent and think that because things are somewhat better now that it means we're equal, because we're not. There are tons of people out there, many of them in power right now, who want to shove us all back in the closet or even in our graves, and I can't think of a better way to celebrate our resilience AND to honor the people who started the very first pride riot than to say "we're here, we're queer, and fuck you because you're never getting rid of us". 

So much of mainstream gay culture today is focused on assimilating into hetero society to fit *their* norms and *their* expectations of what "acceptable" LGBTQ people should be like. If self-censor pride , we risk losing the very thing we fought so hard for in the first place, which is acceptance and equality **as we are**, and not how "polite hetero society" thinks we should be. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
