<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="58" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485057059.0" user="GoldenEst82" delta="False">
    <text>I am a mother of 3 sons. 
I have not brought them to pride events, as very young children, because I feel it is age inapropriate. Little children learning social rules might... have interesting interpretations of what they have seen, because they have no framework to understand it. (IMO, and experience)

When my children and I started having conversations about sexuality, I made a point to "swing through" a pride event with them, and see what their unbiased feedback was. 

They thought it was a riot of fun. They loved how crazy and colorful it was, and even the tiny uncomfortable-ness you feel when someone is being "socially innapropriate" in public. 

We went home and had a *conversation* about what they saw. 

Along with gay history and the purpose of pride events, and we talked about the pride event's level of sexuality. About how that made them feel. 

It is valuable to young people to have experiences with their families that allow for these conversations. 

I also consider those children who cannot go home and talk to anyone honestly about their feelings about sexuality, period. They need to know there are people out there who *will* talk to them about it.
 And if your a 6' man in full drag and glitter beard- clearly you are not embarrassed nor threatening to have that conversation with. Everyone needs to "find their people" in life- and while it might not be drag level- knowing that the sexuality spectrum exists in wild swings- is comforting. It's wholesome. 
It's why I am a straight ally. 


Just my .02, and how the *overt sexuality* pride embraces *does* have value to cis gendered young people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
