<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483331706.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>Gay guy here.  In North America, we are born into a culture founded, in part, on puritan values. We have fairly oppressed views of sexuality. And homophobia is partly, driven by those oppressed views. So part of acceptance is shifting people's attitudes about sexuality.

We are never going to detangle sexual orientation from sexuality. It's right in the name. It's about the gender of the person we fuck and fall in love with. We can't have that conversation if people are going to tiptoe around the subject. We have to tackle it straight on.

More over, some issues like HIV prevention are a MSM conversation that the LGBT community drives. So, where do we draw the line? is Sexually Transmitted Infections a "NSFW" conversation?

Lastly, when you come out the other side of internalized homophobia and reconciling the homophobia you face on the day to do day to be who you are. Everything about sexual expression is pedestrian. Nudity is pedestrian. Fetishes are pedestrian.

Our whole culture is screwed up about sex. We can't talk about penises, vaginas, menstration, erectile disfunction, STIs, unexpected/unwanted pregnancies, abortion, sexual orientation, gender identity because there's a stranglehold on our culture of attitudes that have to change.

I fuck guys. Some people see that as a sexual fetish, if I am at all going to try and differentiate sexual orientation from sexual fetishes, I have to have a frank discussion about both subjects.

Pride isn't celebrating being gay or bi. It's about celebrating our right to not be oppressed for being sexually attracted to other consenting adults and possibly wanting to pursue romantic relationships with them about it. Sexuality is an inherent part of that celebration. We are advocates for anyone who isn't a monogamous, cisgender, heterosexual who only does it missionary in the dark with the minimal amount of clothing removal under blankets.

Part of being a part of this community is embracing the NSFW aspect of it… besides what is NSFW isn't necessarily NSFL. They are different standards applied in contexts. Like Pride.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483399638.0" user="DudeWtfusayin" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt; Our whole culture is screwed up about sex. We can't talk about penises,  vaginas, menstration, erectile disfunction, STIs, unexpected/unwanted  pregnancies, abortion, sexual orientation, gender identity because  there's a stranglehold on our culture of attitudes that have to change. 

Yes, we can. There's 0 issues with it. It's all over Television. Doesn't mean you have to go around half naked tongue kissing and bathing in champaign while dressed like a cartoon character. Specially since you people bring your kids to that shit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483469153.0" user="nonsense_factory" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; "you people"

Stay classy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483640914.0" user="xyifer12" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, "you people" applies to countries that have these events. People need to stop acting like this automatically is an insult or phobia whenever it's not impossible to use that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484375211.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>It’s an othering statement that leads to an unfounded generalization about a group of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484072226.0" user="DudeWtfusayin" delta="False">
    <text>What's unclassy? If you want me to say "you gays".. that sounds more offensive. I don't care about gays. To each their own. Just behave like acual people. Did you know that domestic violence and child abuse is way higher in homosexual households? Don't bring kids into something that isn't normal and behave like people. Whatever else you do i don't care about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484368763.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>That is a complete and utter lie. Religious propaganda. 

https://www.google.com/amp/amp.health.com/mind-body/more-evidence-gay-parents-raise-well-adjusted-kids</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484429686.0" user="DudeWtfusayin" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not religious. And this is a fact. Kids raised in a nuclear family are 70% less likely to end up criminals, drug addicts and other shit. The abuse is also true. Which even if it wasn't, still not a good outcome for kids. So yeah.

And someone who publishes for CNN and NYT has very little credibility for me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484544237.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>If CNN or NYT, two highly established and well\-respected news outlets, aren't good for you, what would qualify as "credible" for you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484753603.0" user="DudeWtfusayin" delta="False">
    <text>Anything that isn't straight up owned by jews.

EDIT: Also you're gonna tell me CNN doesn't have a clear agenda and publishes skewed studies and bullshit that suits their agenda? I'd trust 0 MSM.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485139214.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485150384.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485185638.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485194006.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485234783.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>u/DudeWtfusayin – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+DudeWtfusayin&amp;amp;message=DudeWtfusayin+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e063i8m/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485244273.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485277839.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>u/thatoneguy54 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+thatoneguy54&amp;amp;message=thatoneguy54+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e063bs6/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485279925.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>u/thatoneguy54 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+thatoneguy54&amp;amp;message=thatoneguy54+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e062bym/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485469337.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486699059.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>Great. You're antisemitic too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486688575.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>You have very little credibility because you are offering *NO* evidence. You have offered *no* facts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483650909.0" user="filawigger" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;all over Television.

No it's not. Compared to most of the developed world we have a much higher ratio of violence to sex in out media than others. Did you know that gay sec scenes (male or female) are almost guaranteed to give a movie an R rating as apposed to a straight sex scene usually only requiring pg-13 unless nudity is revealed? We, as a society, still stigmatize homosexuality and it's relationship. Sexual or not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484068034.0" user="DudeWtfusayin" delta="False">
    <text>If you mean the states, maybe. 

&amp;gt;Did you know that gay sec scenes (male or female) are almost guaranteed to give a movie an R rating as apposed to a straight sex scene usually only requiring pg-13 unless nudity is revealed?

Good? Do you *want* kids to be more gay? Is being gay something that should be encouraged? Not saying is should be treated as something bad.. but definitely not normal, because by definition it's not. 

Tell me what would happen if we had more and more gays? Ah yeah.. We'd die out. 

EDIT: Also, how is showing gays fuck on screen "talking" about television? Gays are super overrepresented in TV shows and series, specialy daily talk shows and game shows. "Talking" is definitely not the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484539930.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>What the flip?

First of all, if the media you consumed influenced your sexuality, then there wouldn't have been any queer people at all until like 2017 because everything has always been exclusively cis and hetero. Any time queer people did show up, they were either villains or cowards or killed for being who they were. 

Secondly, why the hell not encourage more queerness? We've spent a millenia drilling heterosexuality into everyone's skulls and literally murdering people who didn't want to. I wanna see gay people everywhere in the media in every possible way because maybe then ignorant fucks will get a clue and realize that we're just like them, something we've known since the beginning of the time.

Thirdly, there's more to the LGBT community than just gays and lesbians. Bi and pan people exist, and there are trans and ace people who are heterosexual. Heterosexuality has always been included in the LGBT community, but because it's not your specific type of heterosexuality, it's weird and icky and you don't wanna see it.

Fourthly, gays are far, far from overrepresented on television. [Only 18.4&amp;amp;#37; of movies in 2016 had a queer character in it](https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/25/15690404/glaad-lgbtq-representation-film-not-getting-better), and you're probably thinking, "But LGBT people only make up like 5&amp;amp;#37; of the population, of course they'd only appear in that many films!" but what you're not thinking about is the fact that queer people are literally everywhere in life, we're just invisible to you because we're just normal people. I can guarantee you work or interact with at least 3 gay people in your daily life, knowingly or not. Why is this not shown in movies? Why are less than 1/5 of movies not even thinking about queer people? 

In conclusion, 

&amp;gt; Not saying is should be treated as something bad.. but definitely not normal, because by definition it's not. 

Fuck that noise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484780776.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485059917.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>u/DudeWtfusayin – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+DudeWtfusayin&amp;amp;message=DudeWtfusayin+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e05une0/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485067096.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485075218.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>Use the link if you want to appeal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485078805.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486456238.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486472202.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>u/we_are_compromised – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+we_are_compromised&amp;amp;message=we_are_compromised+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/-/e06uk6m/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30487057141.0" user="we_are_compromised" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First of all, if the media you consumed influenced your sexuality, then there wouldn't have been any queer people at all until like 2017 because everything has always been exclusively cis and hetero.

That's a perfect showcase of the danger of reductive logic.

&amp;gt;Secondly, why the hell not encourage more queerness?

Maybe because queer people have been historically persecuted across all cultures?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488447016.0" user="dang1010" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Secondly, why the hell not encourage more queerness?

I hope you mean we should encourage people to embrace and accept their sexuality, and not that we should encourage people to be gay. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483652919.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>You are to sexuality what the Amish are to technology. Get with the times.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484062096.0" user="DudeWtfusayin" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that you think running around half naked and fucking whatever moves is progressive is just degenerate. Wake up, it's not healthy, makes 0 people happy and destroys our culture. Be gay, bi, whatever the hell you want, don't be a freaking animal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483629721.0" user="Ganjiste" delta="False">
    <text>Why arent you advocate for cisgenders ? Why cant certain group be part of this celebration ?

edit: dont need to be that sensitive and downvote my ass, I was just trying to figure out something I misunderstood.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483651855.0" user="iSunMonkey" delta="False">
    <text>The entire definition of 'queer' is the antithesis of 'straight, cis, hetero, religious, etc.,' Of course sexual advocacy is for everybody, but it's especially mean to empower marginalized people, as is every social justice movement. You can be part of it, instead of whining that you're not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485227263.0" user="Ganjiste" delta="False">
    <text>Yes my bad I misunderstood the word "advocate" and basicaly the whole statement, it makes sense now</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483660642.0" user="stephwinchester" delta="False">
    <text>Because you won't find a single place on earth where being cisgender will put your life at risk. It takes *zero* effort to go out and be proud to be a cisgender person. Being cisgender in and of itself doesn't put you in the position of needing someone to advocate for you. You can celebrate queer people and their rights during pride as much as anybody else, but needing an advocate? Why? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485224645.0" user="Ganjiste" delta="False">
    <text>I misunderstood the word "advocate" yes it makes sense, cisgenders dont need that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484189601.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>Cisgendered people aren't discriminated against or marginalized. No one is going to hate you for being cis, and the cis "community" hasn't been through any struggles on account of their gender orientation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484293299.0" user="Rs90" delta="False">
    <text>I won't pretend like this is a huge thing but there's been a rise of hatred toward cis people in younger people. I've noticed it and even been told I was "so cis it made them sick". Which is funny because I'm not, I just don't express that personal side of myself openly. So I chalk it up to angst. Still, it's become more acceptable in small groups recently. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484299724.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>That's a very small portion of people who are likely sick of being oppressed by cis people and take it out on you like that. Certainly not the majority of cis people are treated that way </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484585507.0" user="SirMrGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Except that's a tiny minority who have no effect on society as a whole. Anti-lgbt people have largely controlled the government for centuries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485092406.0" user="Saikou0taku" delta="False">
    <text>Can you expand on what you mean about cis hate? 

All I'm imagining is poorly landed jokes. You prefer neutral colors and conservatives clothes? "That's so cis it makes me sick!" type of thing.

Kind of similar to the racial jokes like "Black people like watermelon and Chicken, hur de hur". It's not so much hate as it is naivety and immaturity. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485212184.0" user="Ganjiste" delta="False">
    <text>I know that, I just misunderstood the previous statement. I also misunderstood the word "to advocate". Because yeah cisgender dont need that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484360789.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>You misunderstand that part of my statement. It am not saying all cisgender people. My gay ass is cisgender after all...

I am saying Pride is not people who are cisgender AND straight AND monogamous AND sex in missionary...  gah... this is a basic logic statement where all of these characteristics overlap.  It’s an attempt to say that anyone who’s a little different with regards to their sexuality, sexual orientation or gender identity is welcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485213977.0" user="Ganjiste" delta="False">
    <text>My bad, it makes sense now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484115171.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>Conversation is different than actual physical nudity, giant penises, etc. I wouldn't want my younger brother to be exposed to that kind of vulgar and obscenity, but I wouldn't mind letting him listen to someone advocating for better sexual education in schools. Sexual orientation doesn't necessarily tie in heavily with the act of having sex itself. There's more to the LGBT+ community than sex. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484322109.0" user="majeric" delta="False">
    <text>The [Japanese have a fertility festival where they carry around large penises](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanamara_Matsuri).... 

Mardi Gras has nudity. 

Yes, there is more to our community than sex and sexuality but sex and sexuality is an integral part of our community.  It shouldn’t be dictated by the lowest common denominator of comfort of sexual expression.

Pride is an event that happens one day a year in one part of the city. If it personally offends you, you can avoid it for the few hours that it happens. It’s like a nude beach, there’s a reasonable expectation of nudity and its avoidable. 

The reality is that in recent years, my city has “toned it down”  but there are other people who are offended by men dressed in drag because to them it’s offensive and vulgar.

Pride is what it is and should be reduced to not offend every individual’s sensibilities but people’s sensibilities should be suspended for one after noon of celebrating sexuality. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484664691.0" user="rainbowsforall" delta="False">
    <text>May I ask *why* you don't want your you her brother exposed to these things? Do you believe it would do some sort of harm? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
