<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483308566.0" user="AnorhiDemarche" delta="False">
    <text>Bi/pan here. 

For a lot of people being out and proud includes being able to show the sex side, which is portrayed in the general media (without being a joke) as being a thing much less than "gay people exist" is. A pride event where you have to hide your sexuality, even a little, just wouldn't feel like pride to many. 

I think it's unfortunate that we have so few family friendly lgbt pride events In my country as we have a growing number of lgbt inclusive families (eg, lgbt couples with kids) that wish to introduce their children to the celebration of what and how they are, but may feel they can't due to the nature of the events.   

Edit: it got a little ranty so I removed the necessary bits.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
