<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483537106.0" user="xxruruxx" delta="False">
    <text>I think your complaints are a little privileged. 

Pride parades began when being gay meant that you could lose your job or face real violence--or even be killed--for being gay. 

The first pride marches weren't as flamboyant. It was an arduous struggle to even just get the permit in LA, and required the help of the ACLU. Organizers received death threats up until the parade, and tensions were high. 

As the years went on, pride became about occupying a public space, forcing people to acknowledge gay people and to say "Here I am!" It's one day of the year where you can feel liberated from the daily oppression of societal homophobia. Early pride marches were called "Gay Liberation Parades" for a reason. **Nudity, bondage gear, and sexually prurient behavior is put on display in public space because that's what being gay was synonymous with.**
Being gay, at one point in our country's history meant that you were *dirty, diseased, immoral, a criminal, and undeserving of happiness.* The flamuoyance you see at pride is a way to reclaim power and identity from oppression. If grown adults are offended by the sight of a natural human body  at pride, maybe that in itself is proof that we need parades of this nature. 

Sure, you might not feel the threat of violence today for being bi. This is a great thing. Maybe you still think that pride should be more conservative. But understand the struggles that gay people faced in order for us to get to this point, and you should honor that history. 

Besides, there are different ways to introduce your family to the LGBT community other than pride. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
