<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483298943.0" user="mystriddlery" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe you're right, maybe the nudity turns people away and lowers the chances of people warming up to pride parades. 

You could also argue that bodily expression is healthy and demonizing or sexualizing the people who choose to be themselves on Pride day can lead people to continue to be offended by the human form.  

Do you hate the fact that gore filled movies can be rated PG but things with nudity shoot straight to R?  Do you hate how over-sexualized commercials and movies have been lately?

The best way to combat this (peoples issues with the naked body) would be to normalize it in a way that people can appreciate it for what it is, without over-sexualizing it.

Telling them to repress themselves continues the idea that human bodies should be shamed and covered. 

Maybe families won't want their kids to see naked people, but then again maybe families are teaching their kids the wrong ideals and we should collectively remove the stigma against the human body. 

I wouldn't say public nudity should be legal all the time, but during a parade when it's relevant I think it is fine.  You may not have heard about this but some bike races and running events are held in the nude.  

I know this post is all over the place, but what I'm getting at is: you're right about nudity probably turning away families, but just because it does, doesn't mean nudity is a bad thing.  Maybe the families who won't let their kids see something because it's nude are in the wrong and creating a society where we are ashamed of our own skin. 

What if allowing nudity during the parade actually helps people appreciate and normalize the human body?  If thats the case then I think it's better to keep it than remove it. 

Added point: Many of the people who support (or hate) the LGBT community aren't going to change their view just because some people were in the nude.  Maybe some people won't watch the parade, but nobody is switching from gay friendly to hating gays solely because of some nudity during a parade. 

Obligatory "this isn't my actual view, but this is CMV so I had to try". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483396655.0" user="Perite" delta="False">
    <text>I think the op is drawing a distinction though between nudity and sexualised nudity.

From my perspective, I’ve got no problem taking my kid somewhere where people might be naked (it’s not so uncommon here in Europe), but I’m not taking him somewhere people are overtly sexualised.

That said, I don’t really know how big an issue it is anyway. I don’t personally believe that going to a going to a pride parade will stop a kid being a bigot. I think there parents that teach openness and respect will do so regardless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484105372.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>People can certainly switch between not supporting gay marriage to supporting it if they see that gay people are just as kind, compassionate, and functioning members of society. I believe my family would probably change their mind if pride wasn't what it's like currently. 

I don't think nudity is relevant to the parade. There's more to being gay than just having sex. In my opinion, having sex is a very small part of being bi. I'd rather see more LGBT music, poetry, art, dance, etc to portray our community rather than sexual deviance on live television. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484232298.0" user="CPUSolLeks" delta="False">
    <text>Personally, I don't care what you do in your spare time.

However, I hate people who wear their sexuality as their personality.

its like [this keane and peele skit](http://www.cc.com/video-clips/stelsi/key-and-peele-office-homophobe)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484265526.0" user="moochs" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, how many people do you know that are like that? I have many gay friends, and have met many of their gay friends, and live in an extremely liberal city, and in my lifetime, I've only ever met maybe one person like that.

(BTW, love that clip!)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484274533.0" user="Narwhalbaconguy" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP but I actually know a TON who are like that</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484293474.0" user="moochs" delta="False">
    <text>Tell me more! How do you know so many? How do/did you meet them? The only place I would even guess to look for them is at the clubs.

EDIT: BTW, I know way too many hetero males that love to spend most of their day in "locker room talk" mode. I find that equally annoying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484331842.0" user="Narwhalbaconguy" delta="False">
    <text>My ex was friends with almost entirely  people from the LGBT community, and I have a few of my own. I'd say around 30-40% of them acted like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484503284.0" user="thatoneguy54" delta="False">
    <text>I've met a lot of people who appear to be like that when you first meet them, but as you get to know them they open up and you learn they do more than think about how gay they are all day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485039989.0" user="Narwhalbaconguy" delta="False">
    <text>Same here, it seems that they just wanna get that fact out in the open first before they continue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484386032.0" user="Daibakuha" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People can certainly switch between not supporting gay marriage to supporting it if they see that gay people are just as kind, compassionate, and functioning members of society. I believe my family would probably change their mind if pride wasn't what it's like currently.

Pride isn't about convincing people of anything. Pride is about celebrating who you are. It's about openly flaunting all the things society tells you not to.

We shouldn't let people who don't even support Pride dictate the type of content at Pride. Pride is about openly flaunting your sexuality, gender and orientation because those are the things society tells us to hide away.

That's my take on it as a straight white cis-dude, who supports the movement. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488010470.0" user="zuesk134" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Pride isn't about convincing people of anything. Pride is about celebrating who you are. It's about openly flaunting all the things society tells you not to.

thank you! this seems to be the most missed point in this post. pride is a celebration, not assimilation activism. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484485960.0" user="redviper187" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem with this line of thinking is that conforming the LGBT community to what cis-het people want it to be is that it defeats what I see as the purpose of pride in some ways. Pride isn’t just about gay marriage or getting cis-het people to support LGBT people it’s about openly displaying and being proud of the things we’ve been told our whole lives we should be ashamed of. Sex is obviously not the only aspect of that (nor is it the only aspect of pride) but it is an aspect of it and removing that would reinforce the message to some that sex (or possibly to some that certain kinds of sex) is shameful and is something to hide.

I think that in general conforming LGBT events and community standards to fit the cis-het norm is not ideal because while you may get people like your parents to accept “normal” queer people like the gay couple who behaves exactly like a straight couple but is gay but will they accept the non-binary pansexual kid who doesn’t want a monogamous relationship? While it may foster acceptance of certain aspects of the LGBT community it no longer, in my opinion works towards the message “it’s okay to be different” instead it says “gay people aren’t that different” which is true for many of them, but not true for many others.

So I think, in conclusion, it is great to use pride as an introduction to the LGBT community for folks, but at the end of the day, the celebration is by LGBT people, for LGBT people of all varieties and I think starting to change it to make cis-het people more comfortable is not necessarily the right direction to go. 

I will say though it would be nice to have some aspects of pride by non-sexualized and include more things like music and poetry because not all queer people like sex! And I personally include asexual people in LGBT+ and they should feel welcome at pride as well.

Source: am that non-binary pansexual kid who doesn’t want to be in a monogamous relationship </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488694254.0" user="dang1010" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;because while you may get people like your parents to accept “normal” queer people like the gay couple who behaves exactly like a straight couple but is gay

I'm sorry, what?  How exactly does a straight couple act?  There are plenty of straight couples that are open with their sexuality and don't act the "norm."  I don't think what gender you prefer dictates how you and your partner act as a couple.  Also, there are plenty of straight people that are in non-monoganous and open relationships as well.  It's not something specific to the LBGT community at all.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488705132.0" user="redviper187" delta="False">
    <text>Very true! I was over generalizing a bit for sure, thank you for pointing that out. What I meant was behaving like a stereotypical reserved “proper” (according to some folks) couple. One that follows societal norms about what is and isn’t appropriate regarding sexual expression, style, etc. in most people’s minds, that stereotypical couple is straight, but I certainly wasn’t trying to throw all straight people in with that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488753836.0" user="dang1010" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so with that being said; how is this an LGBT issue and not just a kink shaming issue?  The same people that would judge you poorly because you're non-monoganous would also judge a straight couple poorly for being non-monoganous as well. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30488814521.0" user="redviper187" delta="False">
    <text>Well first of all, polyamory is not a kink. So facing discrimination or chastisement about being non-monogamous is not kink shaming. But I’m more importantly I was using non-monogamy as an example. The central point of my comment was that I don’t think it’s the best idea to tailor an LGBT event made by LGBT people, for LGBT people to straight people (I’m sure there are some LGBT people who are also made uncomfortable by the sexuality aspect of pride, which is why in my original post I said we should make sure to add parts of pride that are sex free, my point about tailoring the event to straight people is not simple related to OPs issue, but a general statement about the celebration). I think sexual freedom and expression has a long history of association with the LGBT community and that since pride is a celebration of all aspects of that community, those things should be included. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484740093.0" user="nashife" delta="False">
    <text>I think that you're looking at Pride as if it's supposed to be persuasive or meant to convince cishet people of something.

It's not. 

Pride is not an "argument" for anything. It's not "for" cishet or conservative folks. 

Pride is "for" the LGBTQ+ people ourselves to have a small chunk of time where we can just be visibly "ourselves" without stigma and to remember and support those who died or who are harmed by the majority culture and institutions just for existing as who we are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486414231.0" user="we_are_compromised" delta="False">
    <text>The inappropriate sexual behavior at Pride events often hurts members of their own community. I have a gay friend who attended a Pride event at 16 and was leered at, groped, and made very uncomfortable. Myself, as a bisexual person, would never be caught dead at one of those things. Outright indecency and harassment isn't called out by the other attendees. The ones paying for the permits don't seem to bother laying down basic conduct guidelines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486466031.0" user="nashife" delta="False">
    <text>Consent violations are not okay under any circumstance and I am sorry that your friend experienced this. That's awful and unacceptable. These sorts of assaults are not the kind of behavior that should be okay at any sort of event, and it's not what OP is talking about. Your friend should never have been assaulted in this way, and people of all flavors need to do better.

Things like that happening are not okay and the organizers and the community need to do better for victims of such assaults.

That said, that's not the same thing that's being discussed here. This thread that I replied to here is suggesting that the nudity and sexual behavior has a kind of rhetorical effect on an outside audience.

OP said the following:

&amp;gt;  I believe my family would probably change their mind if pride wasn't what it's like currently.

Which suggests they believe that Pride is somehow meant to be persuasive and we're undermining our "argument" by having content that is repulsive to our audience.

If it were true that Pride was meant to be a kind of "persuasive argument" to convince a certain conservative audience of our merit, then sure. That would be a valid criticism. 

The conservative majority audience sees the kind of behavior displayed at Pride and goes "wtf is this?"

But that's the thing: Pride is NOT a persuasive argument. It's for us. It's for us to express ourselves as we actually are rather than hiding ourselves or altering ourselves for the comfort of the people around us. If that means being nude, lewd, and colorful, that's what it means. (But again, assault is NEVER OKAY. Ever. I'm sorry your friend experienced that.)

To change how we behave at pride because it's not "appealing to an outside audience" is to erase ourselves, which is something we have to do on a daily basis at work, at home, in public, and in church just on a daily basis. Pride is a respite from the other 360 or so days where many LGBTQ folks feel like they have to pretend to be someone else just to be accepted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484228224.0" user="asharkey3" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you hate the fact that gore filled movies can be rated PG

Can you give an example of this? I can't say I have ever come across a movie with *gore* that wasn't a high rating. Some blood or injury in a PG-13, sure, but I don't think that's the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484822786.0" user="PointMeAtTheSky_" delta="False">
    <text>Jaws.

But I think that was before PG-13 was a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30484859255.0" user="asharkey3" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah when that movie came out, PG was the only rating under R. 

Although in today's standards that certainly would have been a R rating. Interesting, I had no idea Jaws was only PG lol</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
