<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483298753.0" user="CLIFFORDRight" delta="False">
    <text>Read something similar and relevant on here a little while ago regarding why BDSM communities take part in pride. I’m paraphrasing here, but the answer was somewhat relevant so I’ll do my best. 

The basic idea was that originally, when homosexuality first came into the view of the mainstream, most societal subsets turned their backs or responded with outright aggression in most of North America. The BDSM community, which had been operating in a similarly clandestinely way was the first group to openly support gay individuals. In fact, a lot of BDSM hang outs and meetings became also partly dedicated to gay individuals.

So now, when homosexuality is widely accepted (in the western world, important distinction in this context) the argument is that the broader community owe something to the BDSM community. The BDSM helped the gay community garner support, so the gay community should repay the favour. 

This is why BDSM and other less child friendly individuals show up at pride, and at least from this historical perspective makes perfect sense to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483396696.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>BDSM is a choice. We don't need parades for all fetishes. 

A gay parade should be about gay rights. Which they now have. Or gay acceptance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483457702.0" user="CLIFFORDRight" delta="False">
    <text>Find me one peer reviewed source that proves sexuality is a choice. Just because something is confronting doesn’t mean it’s the persons fault. Think about it logically, why would anyone choose to be attracted to children ?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483584393.0" user="Neutrino_gambit" delta="False">
    <text>I never said something is someone's fault. Also your child example is odd. That's a sexuality like being gay, not a fetish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483682038.0" user="Joe_Baker_bakealot" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't fetishes inherently tied to your sexuality? If you took away someone's fetishes their sexuality would now have to be different.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
