<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525423033.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/cmv_we_shouldnt_have_a_minimum_unit_price_of/">
    <title>CMV: We shouldn't have a minimum unit price of alcohol.</title>
    <original_poster>uk85cp</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

I hope this finds you well!

Legislation was recently passed in Scotland to have a 50p minimum unit price of alcohol.  

Their Health Minister said that the driving reason for this is to cut alcohol-related deaths by 392 in the first 5 years and hospital admissions by 8,254 cases.

Having the minimum unit price will significantly raise the price of cheap, high-alcohol drinks, which heavy drinkers tend to buy. 

My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation. 

Thanks for your time either way!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485046350.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Deterrence doesn't work through an either "it worked" or "it didn't" kind of binary relationship.  Almost anything you make more expensive will reduce consumption.  Yes, this single measure won't solve alcoholism, but it certainly doesn't do nothing.

&amp;gt; Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation.

That doesn't really describe people who are buying the cheapest and most potent alcohol possible, which are the only alcohols that hit the pretty low minimum threshold.  People drinking in moderation generally aren't drinking everclear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485182741.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your reply!

Regarding your first point, my (minimal) understanding of prohibition in the US, was that although official statistics may have suggested that there was a complete reduction of alcohol sales, the reality was that alcohol would have been readily available and possibly even more dangerous as manufactured at home.

Completely take on board your point regarding the fact that it's not binary. Maybe it is part of a wider plan to tackle alcohol abuse, however, if they do have a wider plan then it certainly isn't getting the same media coverage.  

If you go out in the U.K on a weekend, it's not uncommon to see people extremely drunk and it just appears to be accepted as a norm. 

Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485270927.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think prohibition is a fair comparison.  Selling alcohol in the US usually requires a fairly difficult to obtain alcohol license (usually dictated by your local government).  That hasn't created a huge market for blackmarket alcohol or people making alcohol at home, just like this moderate and reasonable restriction wouldn't either.  Also, the easier alcohols to make usually don't have that high of alcohol content.  And distilling spirits requires a special license and is illegal otherwise.

Just because we have a history of snubbing our noses at a complete alcohol restriction doesn't mean the response to moderate alcohol restrictions would be remotely the same.

&amp;gt; if they do have a wider plan then it certainly isn't getting the same media coverage.

I'm not suggesting it is necessarily part of a wider plan, but it is a relatively small measure, so I think it is perfectly acceptable if the benefits are only moderate.

&amp;gt; If you go out in the U.K on a weekend, it's not uncommon to see people extremely drunk and it just appears to be accepted as a norm.

There are lots of alcoholics/college students that go to the bar with the mentality "I have $20 bucks, what is the most drunk I can get with that" and there are certain types of alcohols that are mostly purchased by people with that mentality because they are the outright cheapest per unit alcohol.  This reduces how drunk that person can get on $20.  And those alcohols aren't really purchased nearly as much by casual consumers who are drinking in moderation, so I don't really see the minimum price restricting moderate drinkers.  Nobody stops at 1/2 shot of everclear, for example.  By the time you've finished a shot of everclear, you've consumed about 2.5 shots worth of normal hard liquor, so even if that is the only drink you have at the bar all night, you're really pushing the concept of "moderate drinker".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485428336.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>I think the analogy is fair as I believe it is all relative. With prohibition people used extreme means to avoid an extreme piece of legislation, and in turn, I feel people will use moderate means to avoid a moderate piece of legislation. 

So true, it won't lead to a huge black-market, but I suspect it will just lead people taking reasonable steps to navigate their way around the moderate alcohol restrictions, making it all a bit pointless.  

It may not affect moderate drinkers if looked at in isolation, but I see this as a further squeeze, another example of a raise in the cost of living:

https://www.theguardian.com/business/2017/dec/12/uk-inflation-rises-uk-cost-of-living-squeeze

I'm guessing a root cause for why people end up abusing alcohol is stress. In seeing laws that chisel away at all the minor things we enjoy, may even lead to more stress in those of us that can enjoy moderation. In turn, leading us to get so stressed with life that we end up abusing substances like alcohol.  

If the Government is serious about the issue, then I suspect to convince people like myself, it needs to package up raising the price of alcohol with a number of others strategies. 

Thanks for your thoughts btw. Most appreciated!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485511734.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm guessing a root cause for why people end up abusing alcohol is stress.

I'm with you there.  Stress as well as other untreated mental disorders that they are self medicating for.  Along with a strong genetic predisposition to alcohol abuse which has a 50% heredity rate (which very well could overlap with susceptibility to stress/mental disorders being what was heritable, so isn't necessarily a distinct source from the other sources).

&amp;gt; In seeing laws that chisel away at all the minor things we enjoy, may even lead to more stress in those of us that can enjoy moderation. 

Even if I were to grant you that alcoholism is 100% stress and not the other things like mental disorders and genetic predispositions, the argument doesn't follow that allowing them the alcohol is actually beneficial to them.  If we were to just make all alcohol 100% free, we'd certainly have more alcoholics and I don't really see how you could argue that would be a benefit to either those individuals or the greater society.

I also don't think you can argue that putting a minimum price on alcohol is going to cause significant financial stress to anyone but alcoholics.  I still don't buy the fact that this will have much impact on non-alcoholics (because it generally isn't going to affect the types of alcohol they are buying), and even if it did, its not going to have a significant impact on them because they are just not buying enough alcohol for this slight increase to be a significant burden on their overall finances.

Again, who are these people who "enjoy alcohol in moderation" and are buying UV Blue or other cheap and highly alcoholic beverages that would hit the threshold?  People "enjoying alcohol in moderation" aren't going to really even be doing shots in the first place.

&amp;gt; it needs to package up raising the price of alcohol with a number of others strategies.

If it is a good and sensible strategy that has a small, but positive affect, the only reason why it would NEED to be packaged with other strategies is if those other strategies have multiplicative benefits that are necessary to make this have a positive outcome.  I see this program having a small but noticeable benefit by itself, so I don't see a reason to not pass it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30494575725.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>"Even if I were to grant you that alcoholism is 100% stress and not the other things like mental disorders and genetic predispositions"

Yeah, totally, there are a number of causes. So let's say stress, mental health disorders, genetic predispositions and I'm going to throw in social norms/culture as well. So we have ourselves 'the why' I guess, unless there are things we've missed out!

"... the argument doesn't follow that allowing them the alcohol is actually beneficial to them".

Right, so maybe we need to clarify the who?

So, let's stratify the population in terms of alcohol consumption. I'm guessing it would look like a triangle, in that you'd have a tiny proportion of the population at the top of the triangle, that are going to be the most seriously addicted to alcohol and probably cost the health services the most money. 

This group, with the most severe addictions, are probably going to need a pretty comprehensive package of support to address their issues and a hike in prices isn't going to change that imo. 

The next couple of tiers down you are going to have a greater proportion of the population who are drinking over the recommended number of alcohol units a week, who might be influenced to change their behaviour due to a hike in price. These tiers might be drinking over the recommended guidelines, but it is arguable, that it is their choice to do that. They may choose to live a life, in which they drink socially with friends and smoke, and end up with a shorter life expectancy. But that's their choice. Maybe they have a mundane job, no career possibilities, little to do for fun and actually enjoy getting drunk on a Friday with friends. 

Instead of making that decision for them by raising the prices so they can't afford the drink, wouldn't it be better to focus on education so that they can make an informed decision? Then, if they are fully aware of all the risk implications, but still choose to drink over the recommended units, then that's their choice.

Maybe this boils down to your view of Government and what its role should be in managing people's lives. So no one is necessarily right or wrong, just depends where you sit ideologically. 

"If you made alcohol free, then we'd certainly have more alcoholics".

Not necessarily. I guess you'd work towards having a society where even if alcohol was free, people would have enough going on and informed  enough to choose not to drink.

"If it is a good and sensible strategy that has a small, but positive affect, the only reason why it would need to be packaged with other strategies is if those other strategies have multiplicative benefits that are necessary to make this have a positive outcome."

I guess this kind of view, is why some people who could be persuaded to support the legislation, are turning against it. It feels like a change that is being done to them, instead of being done in partnership with them (If that makes sense).

My little understanding of change management, is that it's better to bring people along with you instead of imposing it on them. 

The former approach will just (rightly or wrongly) make people skeptical as to why that change is happening. Even if you are doing it for the right reasons!

Maybe thats why people's trust in political institutions is lower than ever.

Instead of reactionary laws that make a small dent, do we need more of a wider rethink in how the public engage with some of these issues? So that if legislation to raise the price of alcohol does come into being, then at least people will have felt some involvement and ownership over that decision.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
