<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525423033.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/cmv_we_shouldnt_have_a_minimum_unit_price_of/">
    <title>CMV: We shouldn't have a minimum unit price of alcohol.</title>
    <original_poster>uk85cp</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

I hope this finds you well!

Legislation was recently passed in Scotland to have a 50p minimum unit price of alcohol.  

Their Health Minister said that the driving reason for this is to cut alcohol-related deaths by 392 in the first 5 years and hospital admissions by 8,254 cases.

Having the minimum unit price will significantly raise the price of cheap, high-alcohol drinks, which heavy drinkers tend to buy. 

My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation. 

Thanks for your time either way!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485032774.0" user="EternalPropagation" delta="False">
    <text>How would cheap alcohol affect Peoples of Native Americans who suffer from alcoholism and diabetes? If we whites allow those Peoples to buy as much alcohol as they wish then the Peoples of Native Colors will just end up harming themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485035767.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485042924.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MasBlanketo – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+MasBlanketo&amp;amp;message=MasBlanketo+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/-/e060453/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
