<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525423033.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/cmv_we_shouldnt_have_a_minimum_unit_price_of/">
    <title>CMV: We shouldn't have a minimum unit price of alcohol.</title>
    <original_poster>uk85cp</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

I hope this finds you well!

Legislation was recently passed in Scotland to have a 50p minimum unit price of alcohol.  

Their Health Minister said that the driving reason for this is to cut alcohol-related deaths by 392 in the first 5 years and hospital admissions by 8,254 cases.

Having the minimum unit price will significantly raise the price of cheap, high-alcohol drinks, which heavy drinkers tend to buy. 

My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation. 

Thanks for your time either way!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485040452.0" user="figsbar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation.

If you just enjoy alcohol in moderation, are you really going for the drinks that this law actually changes?

Edit, some calculations:

* 6 pack for ~£3

* 750ml wine for ~£5

* 750ml spirits for £15

The only times I've bought cheaper than that were a couple bottles of rose for £3 and some vodka I now severely regret buying for £10. And that was definitely not during a time where I "enjoyed alcohol in moderation"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485071884.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the response!

No, but my understanding of the law, although it's focused specifically on these kind of drinks, it will also have the wider affect of raising the price of alcohol as a whole. 

The Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS) said a floor of 50p per unit would raise the cost of 70% of alcohol bought in shops

http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-42362028

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485136486.0" user="figsbar" delta="False">
    <text>Apparently the main story for me is that I should have shopped around more as a student. (also that I just didn't know how many units are in a beer/cider and apparently drank a lot more than I thought I did)

But that's not my point. 

You said:

&amp;gt;Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation.

I'm saying those people will barely be affected. Does it matter if "70% of alcohol bought in shops" increases in price for your "moderate drinker" if they're not buying those drinks in the first place? I can see it having an effect on both alcoholics and teenagers going binging, but not much on people drinking moderately.

Especially since adults are recommended to drink no more than 14 units a week, even if a "moderate drinker" drinks twice that and all his drinks now *double* in price to hit the 50p minimum. He's now spending £7 a week extra. (And I'm hardly describing a "moderate drinker" at this point)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485284821.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your reply Figsbar! Most helpful.

Sure, if you look at it in complete isolation it doesn't seem much, but when writing 'further financial squeeze', I'm looking at it as a further hike in the cost of living:

https://www.theguardian.com/business/2017/dec/12/uk-inflation-rises-uk-cost-of-living-squeeze

For this reason I think I am justified in having a view on it, even if is only affecting me on the face value minimally. It just feels like a further infringement on the things we enjoy!

Thanks again!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30486308588.0" user="zacker150" delta="False">
    <text>Setting a price floor doesn't just affect the process of the bottom of the barrel drinks originally priced below the floor. It raises prices of poetry much everything but the top shelf liquor. 

For an example, consider a company which makes 4 tiers of drinks.

Level 1 (the worst drink) costs a $1.
Level 2 costs $1.50.
Level 3 costs $2.50.
Level 4 (the top shelf stuff) costs $10.

 Suppose the government institutes a price floor of $1.50. Naturally, level 1 will increase in price to $1.50. However, now level 1 and level 2 are the same price, so everyone will buy level 2 instead of level 1. Therefore, the price of level 2 will also go up. This in turn causes the price of level 3 to go up as well. Since level 4 is already super expensive, the price of level 4 remains roughly the same. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
