<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525423033.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/cmv_we_shouldnt_have_a_minimum_unit_price_of/">
    <title>CMV: We shouldn't have a minimum unit price of alcohol.</title>
    <original_poster>uk85cp</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

I hope this finds you well!

Legislation was recently passed in Scotland to have a 50p minimum unit price of alcohol.  

Their Health Minister said that the driving reason for this is to cut alcohol-related deaths by 392 in the first 5 years and hospital admissions by 8,254 cases.

Having the minimum unit price will significantly raise the price of cheap, high-alcohol drinks, which heavy drinkers tend to buy. 

My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation. 

Thanks for your time either way!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485049847.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>At least in the U.S. (I'm sure it's comparable) the top 10% of alcohol drinkers account for over half of all alcohol consumed, which is about 10 drinks per day.

I'm not sure what the current minimum price you can get a drink for in Scotland, but even a change of a little bit could easily add up and strongly deter people from drinking so much.

There's evidence that these 'sin taxes' work on the assumption you can't easily drive to a neighboring state or country and buy it without the tax. I'm not sure if that's the case for Scotland though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485193703.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks Rehcsel! Don't suppose you know the names of these States that have pushed through similar legislation and are now seeing some positive outcomes?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485319693.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>[Here's](https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1471-2458-13-1072) a meta-analysis that shows there's a correlation.

However I'm unsure of any specific states that imposed a tax, I understand that most of these come from a specific city and thus people just drive to a neighboring town to get soda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485430486.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks Rehcsel. I'll give it a read!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
