<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525423033.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/cmv_we_shouldnt_have_a_minimum_unit_price_of/">
    <title>CMV: We shouldn't have a minimum unit price of alcohol.</title>
    <original_poster>uk85cp</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

I hope this finds you well!

Legislation was recently passed in Scotland to have a 50p minimum unit price of alcohol.  

Their Health Minister said that the driving reason for this is to cut alcohol-related deaths by 392 in the first 5 years and hospital admissions by 8,254 cases.

Having the minimum unit price will significantly raise the price of cheap, high-alcohol drinks, which heavy drinkers tend to buy. 

My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation. 

Thanks for your time either way!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485039430.0" user="Gimmedat_chicken" delta="False">
    <text>So before we start, I totally agree with you. But, for the sake of CMV I’ll play devils advocate. 

Maybe what the health minister is hoping is that this will deter people from beginning to go down a bad road. I totally agree that for the most extreme alcoholics a higher price probably won’t stop them. But maybe this could help with people who aren’t really alcoholics but also aren’t super responsible with their drinking. Maybe that guy who’s on the edge will only have two drinks instead of three and that could make the difference. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485101251.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the response!

My suspicion is (and this isn't based on anything other than my thoughts) that it doesn't address the root cause of why some individuals are drawn to over drink.  

If prices are raised, I suspect that whatever drives them to drink in the first place, will just make them turn to other illegal highs, or  others will see an opportunity in the new law and make the same products available on the black market. 

(I appreciate you're playing devils advocate!)

Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485218289.0" user="Gimmedat_chicken" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if definitely doesn’t get to the root cause. I don’t think I could tell you exactly what the root cause is but it’s certainly not cheap alcohol. Otherwise everyone would be alcoholics. 

What it might do though is deter someone who’s less extreme on the scale. I’m picturing the guy who isn’t really an alcoholic but does tend to drink too much when he’s out having fun. Not so much the guy stealing wallets for cash to buy his gutter alcohol with. For the first sort of guy, he might think “Man, alcohol is so expensive these days. Maybe we should have a party at my place instead of going to a bar”. And perhaps that’s the decision that saves a life since he won’t have the risk of driving home that night. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485304300.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your reply Gimmedat_chicken!

Yeah, possibly, although I guess that guy could easily also say ''Man alcohol is so expensive these days, I might go get [insert substitute substance that gets him high] instead!

Haha, although I'm rooting for this guy to say what you said!

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485684730.0" user="gyroda" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I’m picturing the guy who isn’t really an alcoholic but does tend to drink too much when he’s out having fun. 

Worth noting that the minimum prices effectivelyv don't do anything to bars because they're already charging above the minimum. It only hits the dirt cheap stuff in the supermarkets and off licenses. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485722734.0" user="Gimmedat_chicken" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I didn’t know that - I’m not from Scotland</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30485749694.0" user="gyroda" delta="False">
    <text>It's some incredibly important context for the topic. This doesn't even affect buying a multipack of Fosters, it's targeted at the stuff that's "the most alcohol for the least amount".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
