<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525423033.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8otn09/cmv_we_shouldnt_have_a_minimum_unit_price_of/">
    <title>CMV: We shouldn't have a minimum unit price of alcohol.</title>
    <original_poster>uk85cp</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

I hope this finds you well!

Legislation was recently passed in Scotland to have a 50p minimum unit price of alcohol.  

Their Health Minister said that the driving reason for this is to cut alcohol-related deaths by 392 in the first 5 years and hospital admissions by 8,254 cases.

Having the minimum unit price will significantly raise the price of cheap, high-alcohol drinks, which heavy drinkers tend to buy. 

My opinion is that this won't change the behaviour of those individuals that abuse alcohol, as their craving will be too strong to deter them.

Instead this will just result in a further financial squeeze to those people that can enjoy alcohol in moderation. 

Thanks for your time either way!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30485789993.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Moderate drinkers are not going to feel much of any effect for the slight increase in cost. They do not consume enough for it to be an issue. The only people who will be affected by this to any significant degree are those who are heavy drinkers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30489098763.0" user="uk85cp" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks!

That's fine if you are looking at it in isolation, but I see this as another example of a rise in the cost of living:

https://www.theguardian.com/business/2017/dec/12/uk-inflation-rises-uk-cost-of-living-squeeze

So even if I am a moderate drink who is not feeling much of an affect of this one piece of legislation, I can see it as another example of a series of costs which I can feel an affect of. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
