<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="530658087.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8rxuef/cmv_leave_stray_animals_be_esspecially_sick_ones/">
    <title>CMV: leave stray animals be, esspecially sick ones. death is not the end of the world</title>
    <original_poster>enshem</original_poster>
    <original_post>\*english is a second language to me.

animal shelters/activists tend to pick up stray animals in order to rescue them from the streets. they claim to save them from hunger, poor hygiene and loneliness. sometimes it will suffer from hurtful medical condition which is costly to treat.

animals feel pain but they are not humans in the sense that they do not have the same metaphysic needs, such as excelling at work, philantroping or refining there eloquent thoughts about doing better as a being...

i think it's safe to assume that their conception of death is more like ancient humans who were sad but not alianited by it, opposite to our society which hides its deaths in hospitals and bursts with grief for celebrities that undergo the most common thing there is. that's why i feel  saving as much (urban) animal lives as possible is pointless.

sometimes the animal has some medical condition, which means it'll die sooner. treating wilk be a waste of money and sometimes cause painful recovery process. if the animal suffers its best, i think, to put it down.

i see on social media a lot of people who ask for emergency money to support their adopted pets, often more then few,  whom they took out of will to help the animal. like family planning, i think taking an animal with no means to treat it is selfish and irresponsible, while the better option is leaving it in the ecosystem it originally came from.

i love animals and act by it - veganism, owning adopted dog, keeping beauty cruelty free. but i theorize that adopting because of the "animal needs" is actually more selfish, done by people who wants to feel good with themselves when actually doing more harm.

im totally for adopting and not buying, as long as you have the means to treat it. if a stray animal look like it's in major pain - if you can't afford a vet, human painkillers can get queted and brought out of context, or become the empathic solution in this situation.

thank you for reading this far,

looking forward to read your thoughts in return and broaden my point of view :)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30527074190.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>None of it is really for the animals though.

 &amp;gt; it's safe to assume that their conception of death is more like ancient humans who were sad but not alianited by it

Not really, just like it's not safe to assume anything about animal cognition. Animals as "advanced" as cats lack (to some extent at least)
 basic notions of [object permanence](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object_permanence#In_animals) and [self awareness](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mirror_test) that suggest that they are incapable of perceiving death in a manner similar to anything humans do.

When people adopt pets, volunteer in shelters or go vegan, they ultimately do it because it makes them feel better about themselves, helping strays is exactly the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527321918.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>Does something need to have a concept of object permanence, or a concept of death that is like ours, to warrant ethical consideration? Human babies below a certain age lack those capacities as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527373595.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>Something needs to be able to understand death for you to be concerned with how it grieves death... That includes babies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527407894.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>What does grieving death have to do with ethical consideration?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527538377.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>OP writes:

 &amp;gt; i think it's safe to assume that their conception of death is more like ancient humans who were sad but not alianited by it, opposite to our society which hides its deaths in hospitals and bursts with grief for celebrities that undergo the most common thing there is. that's why i feel saving as much (urban) animal lives as possible is pointless.

I point out that this anthropomorphized version of animals "being okay with death" is as incorrect as the notion that they grieve over it, because they simply lack the capacity to understand death in a way intelligible to us, so this shouldn't be a factor in whether or not you let strays die.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527797473.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>I'm speaking to you. You stated "When people adopt pets, volunteer in shelters or go vegan, they ultimately do it because it makes them feel better about themselves, helping strays is exactly the same." You are implicitly disregarding any ethical arguments for doing these things. I'm asking you why. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527917209.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not disregarding ethical considerations, or claiming that these ethics somehow have to revolve around whether the animal can understand death.

What I am saying is that the motivation for helping animals is personal, and a person will only do it to the extent that they think it's the ethical / moral / socially expected / fun thing to do, which makes the subjective experience of animals irrelevant to the question of how people in general engage with them, even if many of the people who do do it because of some perceived subjective animal experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30529374128.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>I'm asking you what ethical framework you use as an individual that leads you to the conclusion that the well-being of another life form should warrant consideration only if it makes you feel nice inside. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30529392746.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>None. Read the thread again... I'm not personally commenting on the ethics of dealing with animals at all.

I conclude, based on my experience with people, that people generally act based on what feels right or nice to them. Do you disagree with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30529865606.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>I'm asking what makes anything right/wrong with regards to killing or not killing anything. You have no framework for ethics whatsoever? You have no argument for why a baby should or should not be killed? Just feelings? Really, it's a personal choice as to whether you should murder a human? There's no conversation to have here if nothing means anything or has any value. Why even bother with this thread if you really believe that? The whole question is about whether something should or should not be killed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30530485084.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>And I'm asking you, why do you think it's okay to kill babies? Do you think babies are worthless? Do you think they can't grow up into adults with feelings, families and lives? Do you think people don't grieve their dead babies? If you follow such a skewed moral code, how can you even reason about morality towards animals?..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30530486948.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>Unsubscribing from this worthless sub. Thanks for making it clear what a colossal waste of time this place is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30530510822.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>See, when you have a conversation, the most important part is actually listening to what the other side says. When you try to attack something that the person you're talking to is not claiming, that's a [straw man fallacy](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Straw_man), and it makes conversation impossible because I can't keep defending whatever extreme position you feel comfortable going against, just the one I express myself.

If logical argument structure is worthless to you, then this sub really isn't for you; I'm not very good at arguing with pathos-filled demagogy, you'll find the rest of the internet much more accommodating for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30530782432.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't attacked a single thing, because not a single one of my straightforward questions has been answered. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30531180190.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>But I have answered every question until the very last time you asked the same thing. Here they are in context:

 &amp;gt; You stated "When people adopt pets, volunteer in shelters or go vegan, they ultimately do it because it makes them feel better about themselves, helping strays is exactly the same." You are implicitly disregarding any ethical arguments for doing these things. I'm asking you why.

To which I replied

 &amp;gt; I'm not disregarding ethical considerations, or claiming that these ethics somehow have to revolve around whether the animal can understand death.

I haven't answered the "why", because I can't explain to you why I'm stating something that I'm not actually stating.

 &amp;gt; I'm asking you what ethical framework you use as an individual that leads you to the conclusion that the well-being of another life form should warrant consideration only if it makes you feel nice inside.

Which I answered:

 &amp;gt; None.

I haven't stated, and don't agree with the strawman conclusion you present, so I can't tell you what ethical framework leads to it.

As to the question I haven't answered:

 &amp;gt; I'm asking what makes anything right/wrong with regards to killing or not killing anything.

I personally hold beliefs regarding this, and I'll be happy do list some of them if you're interested. I'll stress, however, that this is completely irrelevant to my response to OP.

 &amp;gt; You have no framework for ethics whatsoever?

I do. 

 &amp;gt; You have no argument for why a baby should or should not be killed?

I do, within the moral framework I follow.

 &amp;gt; Just feelings?

Yes. Whatever moral code you believe in is ultimately based on axiomatic statements that you believe in because you feel they're true. Morality cannot be proven mathematically.

 &amp;gt; Really, it's a personal choice as to whether you should murder a human?

Ultimately, yes. There is not true divine command or law of nature that mandates that killing is wrong. In many cultures, what we'd consider to be heinous murder is or was completely acceptable common practice, and I don't think we have any objective grounds to declare our morality superior to theirs.

 &amp;gt; The whole question is about whether something should or should not be killed.

But it's not. That's *your* angle. OP's view was that actively saving strays is inconsistent with generally caring for animals because of the ways animals experience death and because of logistics and impracticality of actually helping some of these animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30530792727.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>But I understand now that people on this subject would prefer to make minor pointless quibbles that skirt the edges of what the conversation is actually about instead of digging into any real conversation of consequence, so that was enlightening. Its a more reliable way to get internet points, so it makes sense. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30528117600.0" user="hameleona" delta="False">
    <text>In a place without laws and societal norms:  
Why wouldn't you kill a baby? Because of how *you* would feel.  
In the end while ethics are often times formed by society the way they work is by providing a positive or negative feedback to certain actions to *you*. There is some biological part in it by empathy but a lot of it is entrenched to us by outside forces (the old nature vs nurture debate is still ongoing).  
So in the end - going vegan is doing it for yourself. So that you would feel good. Or so that you can be judgmental to others. :)  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30529364982.0" user="whenigrowup356" delta="False">
    <text>You're talking about laws and customs, not ethics. Ethics are a framework to use to decide whether one SHOULD take or not take an action, whether it is legal or not. If you think the only ethical reason to do or not do something is that it is illegal and that will cause negative consequences for you, there is no further conversation to have here. If the only thing stopping you from murdering babies is laws, please stay far away from other humans. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
