<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="530658087.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8rxuef/cmv_leave_stray_animals_be_esspecially_sick_ones/">
    <title>CMV: leave stray animals be, esspecially sick ones. death is not the end of the world</title>
    <original_poster>enshem</original_poster>
    <original_post>\*english is a second language to me.

animal shelters/activists tend to pick up stray animals in order to rescue them from the streets. they claim to save them from hunger, poor hygiene and loneliness. sometimes it will suffer from hurtful medical condition which is costly to treat.

animals feel pain but they are not humans in the sense that they do not have the same metaphysic needs, such as excelling at work, philantroping or refining there eloquent thoughts about doing better as a being...

i think it's safe to assume that their conception of death is more like ancient humans who were sad but not alianited by it, opposite to our society which hides its deaths in hospitals and bursts with grief for celebrities that undergo the most common thing there is. that's why i feel  saving as much (urban) animal lives as possible is pointless.

sometimes the animal has some medical condition, which means it'll die sooner. treating wilk be a waste of money and sometimes cause painful recovery process. if the animal suffers its best, i think, to put it down.

i see on social media a lot of people who ask for emergency money to support their adopted pets, often more then few,  whom they took out of will to help the animal. like family planning, i think taking an animal with no means to treat it is selfish and irresponsible, while the better option is leaving it in the ecosystem it originally came from.

i love animals and act by it - veganism, owning adopted dog, keeping beauty cruelty free. but i theorize that adopting because of the "animal needs" is actually more selfish, done by people who wants to feel good with themselves when actually doing more harm.

im totally for adopting and not buying, as long as you have the means to treat it. if a stray animal look like it's in major pain - if you can't afford a vet, human painkillers can get queted and brought out of context, or become the empathic solution in this situation.

thank you for reading this far,

looking forward to read your thoughts in return and broaden my point of view :)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30527079955.0" user="RoToR44" delta="False">
    <text>When you say:

&amp;gt; leave stray animals be, esspecially sick ones. death is not the end of the world

are you reffering to people who can support a stray animal and nurture it back to health, or to those:

&amp;gt; i see on social media a lot of people who ask for emergency money to support their adopted pets, often more then few, whom they took out of will to help the animal. like family planning, i think taking an animal with no means to treat it is selfish and irresponsible, while the better option is leaving it in the ecosystem it originally came from.

who can't support one, and need money to do so? If someone is well funded, why shouldn't they attempt to on their own money nurture a stray animal back to its health, groom it and then send it to shelte for adoption. You have said that adoption is nice, but where are the adopted animals coming from? I would argue that most of them were stray animals originally. Once attempted, if it turns out that animal can't recover, it is humane to put it down, so still, attempting to save an animal is still a reasonable choice for those who can afford it.

There are instances, such as with stray cubs,(baby dogs/cats) where taking them in should be the recommended option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527140865.0" user="enshem" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point and agree.let me rephrase- Adopting an animal that you can take care of is fine. I am criticisizing two things: 1.  systematic rescuing, often done serially by activists who can't take good care of them and from, in my opinion, confusion between  animal life value and animal care value.
2. Putting money into curing animals when there are a lot of other animals that won't recuire it to be maintained.

Did I get what you are saying?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30527154226.0" user="RoToR44" delta="False">
    <text>But, when you pick up an animal from the streets, you can't really tell whether it is healthy or not. Are you saying that once medical examinations are done, we should not take care of the sick ones, and return them to streets? I would agree if they were terminally ill, but sick ones... well, if you put them up for adoption, and a financialy capable owner agrees to adopt them, I don't see any problem here. If animals do turn out to be terminally ill, you should put them down peacefully then. 

&amp;gt; animal shelters/activists tend to pick up stray animals in order to rescue them from the streets. they claim to save them from hunger, poor hygiene and loneliness. sometimes it will suffer from hurtful medical condition which is costly to treat.

I disagree, and say that animal shelters should do this. This is the most ethical way of getting stray animals off the streets. Finally, every action costs money, if it serves a pourpose, money isn't wasted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
