<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="530658087.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8rxuef/cmv_leave_stray_animals_be_esspecially_sick_ones/">
    <title>CMV: leave stray animals be, esspecially sick ones. death is not the end of the world</title>
    <original_poster>enshem</original_poster>
    <original_post>\*english is a second language to me.

animal shelters/activists tend to pick up stray animals in order to rescue them from the streets. they claim to save them from hunger, poor hygiene and loneliness. sometimes it will suffer from hurtful medical condition which is costly to treat.

animals feel pain but they are not humans in the sense that they do not have the same metaphysic needs, such as excelling at work, philantroping or refining there eloquent thoughts about doing better as a being...

i think it's safe to assume that their conception of death is more like ancient humans who were sad but not alianited by it, opposite to our society which hides its deaths in hospitals and bursts with grief for celebrities that undergo the most common thing there is. that's why i feel  saving as much (urban) animal lives as possible is pointless.

sometimes the animal has some medical condition, which means it'll die sooner. treating wilk be a waste of money and sometimes cause painful recovery process. if the animal suffers its best, i think, to put it down.

i see on social media a lot of people who ask for emergency money to support their adopted pets, often more then few,  whom they took out of will to help the animal. like family planning, i think taking an animal with no means to treat it is selfish and irresponsible, while the better option is leaving it in the ecosystem it originally came from.

i love animals and act by it - veganism, owning adopted dog, keeping beauty cruelty free. but i theorize that adopting because of the "animal needs" is actually more selfish, done by people who wants to feel good with themselves when actually doing more harm.

im totally for adopting and not buying, as long as you have the means to treat it. if a stray animal look like it's in major pain - if you can't afford a vet, human painkillers can get queted and brought out of context, or become the empathic solution in this situation.

thank you for reading this far,

looking forward to read your thoughts in return and broaden my point of view :)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30534123749.0" user="goodforthepsyche" delta="False">
    <text>Except we *are* the ecosystem they came from. When we domesticated the dog, we made it harder for them to survive the wild, as we deliberately evolved them to be at our sides in a mutually beneficial partnership. They have a need for human companionship just as badly as we have a need for it. Same for cats. Not to mention, as they were bred for human needs and not the ecosystem's needs, stray cats and dogs can do serious damage to the environment around it. Even the ill ones are going to do more damage on the way out than if someone let them fade in a human household. Stray cats can destroy native bird and rodent populations, stray dogs can do the same and can move up to pets like cats since they have such bigger size ranges--and if a dog is big enough to take down a cat, they're going to go for the slow pampered pets before the feral ones. We created them, we're responsible for them, so us taking them in at great personal expense *is* the right thing to do for them--and if we feel we've chosen an animal, they're family, so we're going to stick by them to the end.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
