<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="530658087.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8rxuef/cmv_leave_stray_animals_be_esspecially_sick_ones/">
    <title>CMV: leave stray animals be, esspecially sick ones. death is not the end of the world</title>
    <original_poster>enshem</original_poster>
    <original_post>\*english is a second language to me.

animal shelters/activists tend to pick up stray animals in order to rescue them from the streets. they claim to save them from hunger, poor hygiene and loneliness. sometimes it will suffer from hurtful medical condition which is costly to treat.

animals feel pain but they are not humans in the sense that they do not have the same metaphysic needs, such as excelling at work, philantroping or refining there eloquent thoughts about doing better as a being...

i think it's safe to assume that their conception of death is more like ancient humans who were sad but not alianited by it, opposite to our society which hides its deaths in hospitals and bursts with grief for celebrities that undergo the most common thing there is. that's why i feel  saving as much (urban) animal lives as possible is pointless.

sometimes the animal has some medical condition, which means it'll die sooner. treating wilk be a waste of money and sometimes cause painful recovery process. if the animal suffers its best, i think, to put it down.

i see on social media a lot of people who ask for emergency money to support their adopted pets, often more then few,  whom they took out of will to help the animal. like family planning, i think taking an animal with no means to treat it is selfish and irresponsible, while the better option is leaving it in the ecosystem it originally came from.

i love animals and act by it - veganism, owning adopted dog, keeping beauty cruelty free. but i theorize that adopting because of the "animal needs" is actually more selfish, done by people who wants to feel good with themselves when actually doing more harm.

im totally for adopting and not buying, as long as you have the means to treat it. if a stray animal look like it's in major pain - if you can't afford a vet, human painkillers can get queted and brought out of context, or become the empathic solution in this situation.

thank you for reading this far,

looking forward to read your thoughts in return and broaden my point of view :)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30530325349.0" user="cloudypeak" delta="False">
    <text>I can try to answer this in the context of the United States. Outside of simply wanting the animal to have a better life, there are other reasons to take domesticated animals off the streets (though I do believe the wellbeing of the animal is a major driving factor, but anyway) that are beneficial for humans.  
  
First, taking them off the street can reduce the danger to humans. Dogs are very territorial and stray dogs that are not socialized (raised by humans) can be aggressive to humans; aggressive large dogs that are trying to defend their territory may bite someone and could cause serious harm. If a stray animal wanders into the street where there are cars, many drivers will probably swerve to avoid the animal (especially dogs and cats--because many see them as pets and have their own at home, and I would guess they would be more reluctant to hit them than deer, raccoons, and other animals) and this could cause an accident.  
  
"The ecosystem where the animals come from" does not exist. Cats and dogs are not part of the ecosystem. They did not originally come from "outside" and do not have a place in the system and are invasive species. Cats especially have negative affects on the surrounding environment, killing millions of native animals per year. One bird species even went extinct because of cats. Now you may be wondering something like, "Why should it matter if a species go extinct?" There are reasons for this as well. The environment has balances; removing a species could have an affect we never anticipated. For example: remove a predator and suddenly the former prey species has nothing to keep it in check, allowing them to grow to unintended sizes. Birds eat small bugs and some species are even specialized to eat a specific type of bug that others can't; removing a bird species could allow these pests to grow more freely. Birds are also important pollinators. They eat a plant's seed, fly a few miles, then poop out the seed, allowing for the new plant to grow in an area it couldn't get to by itself. There doesn't always have to be negative impacts, though; a new species could take up the extinct one's role in their absence. But point is, we usually can't tell what will happen. So, we should try and keep native species around (though fun fact I'm pretty sure researchers determined we can remove mosquitoes without devastating impacts, but I have to read up on that more).  
  
Many shelters have TNR programs (Trap, Neuter, Release) instead of taking every animal off the street, simply because there is not enough space/money. They take the animal, spay/neuter them (prevent them from having offspring), then put them back on the streets (though if the animal appears friendly, some will refrain from returning it). Preventing animals from breeding will eventually cause the population to die out (new animals aren't being added to the family, and the older ones are dying). Cats and dogs can breed a LOT; if you don't take the animals off the streets or fix them, the populations will grow to be huge. This stops more animals from being born, which is good for reasons above and also for animal welfare reasons because then there will be less animals to take in! 
  
I agree with you that it is irresponsible to adopt a pet you cannot pay for, just like how it's irresponsible to adopt/have a child that you know you cannot pay for. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
