<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="534422853.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8u6jb9/cmv_alexandra_ocasiocortez_victory_over_queens/">
    <title>CMV: Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez victory over Queens Democratic Chairman and 4th in Congressional Dem Leadership, Rep Joe Crowley is a harbinger that Cuomo losing in his September primary to Cynthia Nixon.</title>
    <original_poster>SeanFromQueens</original_poster>
    <original_post>A month ago I offered the possibility that Ocasio-Cortez without much money or name recognition would spell danger to Cuomo’s chances of being renominated for governor. I based this on the surprising primary results in 2014 that had an unknown Zephyr Teachout get 34%, mostly from upstate, winning nearly every county upstate while Cuomo got 80% of the vote in the five boroughs. Such a lopsided victory for Cuomo in the five boroughs depends on the primary voters continuing to support Establishment candidates, rather than any upstart candidates like Ocasio-Cortez and Cynthia Nixon.
  
Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez winning by  nearly 20%, means that actress and education activist Cynthia Nixon will likely receive the same voters that voted for Teachout plus those primary voters who would vote against the Establishment like Crowley and Cuomo. I would like to add that State Senator Jose Peralta is also very much in danger if there’s a primary challenge due to his involvement in the IDC (Cuomo’s useful excuse to not implement more progressive policies) which had a fake resolution mediated by Joe Crowley and is nearly entirely within Crowley/Ocasio-Cortez’s 14th district.
  
On the state primary night in September, I will likely repost this CMV to brag, but maybe there’s something I’m not seeing.
  
CMV: As goes the 14th of NY congressional district, so goes the gubernatorial Democratic primary. 
  
https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8m3qxa/cmv_representative_joe_crowley_nyd_losing_his/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30558109874.0" user="rejaded_jade" delta="False">
    <text>Cynthia Nixon will have to pull off a miracle to take anything other than New York City.  I would prefer more liberal policies, but she doesn't even know the geography of the state she wishes to be in charge of. 

I'm sure that NYC people are appreciating the whole subway thing being focused on, but I want to know what she plans on doing about farmers committing suicide over milk prices bankrupting them.  For Pete's sake, she think upstate starts in Ithaca and she can't even spell that!

I believe that most upstate people like myself are not going to go with a celebrity who doesn't understand the process of government and no experience. We've seen the damage that has done on the federal level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30558438163.0" user="doublediamondz" delta="False">
    <text>Has Cuomo been good to upstate?

I’m not a NY resident and he seems like he’s been terrible in general from afar, so I’m just trying to understand what makes her worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30558642833.0" user="rejaded_jade" delta="False">
    <text>He's got a so-so track record for upstate. His Upstate Revitalization Initiative and the Buffalo Billions have been steps in the right direction.  Problem is Cynthia Nixon has been almost completely absent in her positions for anything other than NYC.

Google her policy positions and you can't even find them.  Plenty of articles and interviews with platitudes.  "Supporting good jobs" is a soundbite, nothing more.  She has not had real events that are open to the public and spent  her little time in the richest parts of upstate.

Cuomo at least acknowledges that there is more to New York State than the city and that our needs are different.  

As someone in a same-sex marriage I greatly appreciate the work she did for marriage equality here. I appreciate her stance on public school funding, but she doesn't seen to have a real grasp of what is within the governor's purview and how one would be able to use that office to advance the positions she has very broadly outlined with no specifics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30558691414.0" user="doublediamondz" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for the insightful response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30558654064.0" user="SeanFromQueens" delta="False">
    <text>He rammed through a cosmetic gun control bill (NY SAFE Act) and the teacher's union hates him, his loss of nearly every upstate county in the primary in 2014 was not due to wild support of Teachout. Cuomo's victory in that primary was entirely due to winning in the city (and the city's huge vote total). That's why an upset victory for a grassroots candidate who was outspent 10 to 1 is a **HUGE** red flag that Cuomo is endangered in the state primary in September. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30558687104.0" user="SeanFromQueens" delta="False">
    <text>Teachout without campaigning (largely due to a lack of capacity) upstate other than a single 1 week bus tour won almost every upstate county. Cynthia Nixon winning NYC basically guarantees her the nomination since there are so many more votes in the city than upstate. Ocasio-Cortez's victory, as improbable as it was, indicates that the same voters who will largely determine the gubernatorial nomination is open to an upstart candidate like Cynthia Nixon.
 
I worked on Teachout's campaign in 2014, and we would've been thrilled to have a public poll mention Teachout in April, having more than single digits would've been amazing. Nixon prior to announcing had a public poll giving her 21%. There is no doubt in my mind that Nixon will outperform Teachout, and she will likely win/lose in September by a very narrow margin. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
