<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="534422853.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8u6jb9/cmv_alexandra_ocasiocortez_victory_over_queens/">
    <title>CMV: Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez victory over Queens Democratic Chairman and 4th in Congressional Dem Leadership, Rep Joe Crowley is a harbinger that Cuomo losing in his September primary to Cynthia Nixon.</title>
    <original_poster>SeanFromQueens</original_poster>
    <original_post>A month ago I offered the possibility that Ocasio-Cortez without much money or name recognition would spell danger to Cuomo’s chances of being renominated for governor. I based this on the surprising primary results in 2014 that had an unknown Zephyr Teachout get 34%, mostly from upstate, winning nearly every county upstate while Cuomo got 80% of the vote in the five boroughs. Such a lopsided victory for Cuomo in the five boroughs depends on the primary voters continuing to support Establishment candidates, rather than any upstart candidates like Ocasio-Cortez and Cynthia Nixon.
  
Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez winning by  nearly 20%, means that actress and education activist Cynthia Nixon will likely receive the same voters that voted for Teachout plus those primary voters who would vote against the Establishment like Crowley and Cuomo. I would like to add that State Senator Jose Peralta is also very much in danger if there’s a primary challenge due to his involvement in the IDC (Cuomo’s useful excuse to not implement more progressive policies) which had a fake resolution mediated by Joe Crowley and is nearly entirely within Crowley/Ocasio-Cortez’s 14th district.
  
On the state primary night in September, I will likely repost this CMV to brag, but maybe there’s something I’m not seeing.
  
CMV: As goes the 14th of NY congressional district, so goes the gubernatorial Democratic primary. 
  
https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8m3qxa/cmv_representative_joe_crowley_nyd_losing_his/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30559402095.0" user="Jim631" delta="False">
    <text>I think you might be seeing what you want to see here. 

I think it's more accurate to say Joe Crowley lost because he barely ran. Heck, he even skipped MULTIPLE debates and sent a proxy in his place earning him a rare rebuke of a Democrat from The New York Times.  

The last poll I saw showed Cuomo with a huge lead over Nixon.  It's hard for me to see this not ending in a Cuomo landslide.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
