<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="534422853.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8u6jb9/cmv_alexandra_ocasiocortez_victory_over_queens/">
    <title>CMV: Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez victory over Queens Democratic Chairman and 4th in Congressional Dem Leadership, Rep Joe Crowley is a harbinger that Cuomo losing in his September primary to Cynthia Nixon.</title>
    <original_poster>SeanFromQueens</original_poster>
    <original_post>A month ago I offered the possibility that Ocasio-Cortez without much money or name recognition would spell danger to Cuomo’s chances of being renominated for governor. I based this on the surprising primary results in 2014 that had an unknown Zephyr Teachout get 34%, mostly from upstate, winning nearly every county upstate while Cuomo got 80% of the vote in the five boroughs. Such a lopsided victory for Cuomo in the five boroughs depends on the primary voters continuing to support Establishment candidates, rather than any upstart candidates like Ocasio-Cortez and Cynthia Nixon.
  
Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez winning by  nearly 20%, means that actress and education activist Cynthia Nixon will likely receive the same voters that voted for Teachout plus those primary voters who would vote against the Establishment like Crowley and Cuomo. I would like to add that State Senator Jose Peralta is also very much in danger if there’s a primary challenge due to his involvement in the IDC (Cuomo’s useful excuse to not implement more progressive policies) which had a fake resolution mediated by Joe Crowley and is nearly entirely within Crowley/Ocasio-Cortez’s 14th district.
  
On the state primary night in September, I will likely repost this CMV to brag, but maybe there’s something I’m not seeing.
  
CMV: As goes the 14th of NY congressional district, so goes the gubernatorial Democratic primary. 
  
https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8m3qxa/cmv_representative_joe_crowley_nyd_losing_his/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30557556521.0" user="ReOsIr10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;actress and education activist Cynthia Nixon will likely receive the same voters that voted for Teachout plus those primary voters who would vote against the Establishment like Crowley and Cuomo.

Aren't those two groups the same? Isn't voting for some unknown challenger the epitome of voting against the establishment? Furthermore, [polls of the Cuomo/Nixon race are showing a similar 60/30-ish margin as the 2014 race](https://www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2018/governor/ny/new_york_governor_democratic_primary-6526.html). This suggests that the anti-establishment wing of the NY Democrat party is about one third of the vote. It's difficult to see how Nixon makes up that 30% margin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30558721482.0" user="SeanFromQueens" delta="False">
    <text>Polls narrowing and months still to go means that Nixon could win. Teachout got most of her votes from upstate and lost downstate by large margins (losing the Bronx by 60%), 4 years later and after IDC (breakaway Democrats in the State Senate) and Bernie's campaign awaking voters to the concept that not all Democrats are progressive or working on their behalf. Cuomo is bought DINO beholden to the NYC real estate industry and Wall Street, caring zilch for average New Yorkers, similar to Joe Crowley. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
