<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537030374.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vqfae/cmv_the_future_has_a_bigger_change_to_go_worse/">
    <title>CMV The future has a bigger change to go worse off than not.</title>
    <original_poster>jojowoodo</original_poster>
    <original_post>Now i dont think that it *has* to go this way but one has to wonder, and this is what I've come up with so far:

- Political extremism becoming common politics, and politicians encouraging this to secure votes.

- An older generation who actively wants life to be harder for incoming generations, it seems to have moved beyond "oh those kids are a bit lazy" to active hatred. 

-The accumulation of wealth into small blocks, and also the acceleration of that accumulation, which implies it will keep getting worse until something explosively collapses. 

The fact that the spread of "good" cultures by western standards has stopped, and corrupt and totalitarian regimes are moving into positions of power in the world. 

- The increased ability to kill massive numbers of people, coupled with a more aggressive stance on actually using that power (the decay of nuclear nonproliferation and No first use policies). 

- The reemergence of nationalism, not an issue of political left vs right, but of the link between nationalism and war. 

- The fact that the current world model of outsourcing production to poor countries is inevitably on a clock, and we'll need something to replace it by the time poor countries run out, the only solutions I can see require the suspension of human greed, which I think is impossible. 

- The trend of privatizing infrastructure humans need to live, I can't say if this is an issue in all countries, but it is in NZ. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30578316067.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The increased ability to kill massive numbers of people, coupled with a more aggressive stance on actually using that power (the decay of nuclear nonproliferation and No first use policies).

The ability has not increased, we have had the ability to sterilize this planet for a number of decades now.

And the willingness to use them has dropped since the cold war. Do you have any idea how bad things got back then? The USSR said to the US "we will burry you" and the US called them an "empire of evil", hardly a friendly relationship. Then you add in the numerous proxy war where the US payed islamists to shoot russians and riussians payed vietnamese farms to shoot americans and things like the cuban missile crisis and you see how good we have it now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30610937066.0" user="Smaaaaaash" delta="False">
    <text>Incredibly late to the thread, but agree; if we’re supposedly in another cold war, it’s a lot colder and a lot more subtle (if not sterile) than the last one. Americans and Russians can still fly to each other’s places as opposed to the relationship between the US/USSR, and the closest thing we’ve had to a proxy conflict are the bombings in Syria (which aren’t even related to Russia; their response is the only thing we take out of it). The only two major things that have similarity to the Cold War at the moment are that we both have powerful nukes (although not nearly as many) and we don’t like Russia that much (which varies from person to elected official).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
