<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537285091.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vvvtv/cmv_not_all_gay_people_are_born_that_way/">
    <title>CMV: Not all gay people are born that way.</title>
    <original_poster>eltonjohnelway</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I should make it known that I am not anti-LGBT and I believe that everyone should have equal rights and be treated fairly. I am straight but I do have a few gay and lesbian friends, coworkers, and family members. 

The common belief nowadays is that gay people are "born this way" and I can't find myself to completely believe this. I want to, as I want to be fully supportive of my gay friends. However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". I think that this expands to sexuality. I don't think there is anything wrong with this or that it is some sort of a mistake if you end up being gay. However, I do believe there is some alternate timeline/universe/ course of events ( whatever you want to call it) where certain people end up with different sexualities. In my opinion, my life could have been drastically different and I could have ended up being gay, but my cousin could have ended up straight. 

I am not trying to offend here, and I hope that it doesn't come off that way. I would truly like to have my view changed. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30581019189.0" user="Mockfury" delta="False">
    <text>Gay and straight brains are physically different.  Every older brother he has increases the chance of a man being gay by 33%.  And in studies, people were surprisingly accurate in determining if someone was gay just by looking at their face.

I would argue that these points lend themselves more toward 'born this way' instead of environmental effects.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30581882850.0" user="Apokolyptyk" delta="False">
    <text>You got a source for that? I'm not trying to be rude, but that sounds like bullshit.

The only gay guys I've known besides one have either been the oldest brother or an only child. Most of them being an only child. And 33% sounds like a made up number and is extremely high. You telling me that if someone has 4 older brothers they are 132% gay? By your logic, every 5th boy would be gay. Also, explain lesbians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30582017180.0" user="fyi1183" delta="False">
    <text>I can't answer all your questions, but that's not how probabilities work.

&amp;gt; The only gay guys I've known besides one have either been the oldest brother or an only child.

Given how small families are these days, it's possible that only children and only sons are more frequent than younger brothers, so given different base frequencies you'd encounter more only children gays even if only children are slightly less likely to be gay than younger brothers.

&amp;gt; You telling me that if someone has 4 older brothers they are 132% gay?

The statement was almost certainly meant in relative terms. That is, if the base probability for an oldest son being gay is 10%, then the probability for a second son being gay would be 13.3%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30582629367.0" user="Apokolyptyk" delta="False">
    <text>I was being fecetious, atleast partially, with the numbers. This guys claim is absolute bullshit though and makes no sense whatsoever.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
