<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537285091.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vvvtv/cmv_not_all_gay_people_are_born_that_way/">
    <title>CMV: Not all gay people are born that way.</title>
    <original_poster>eltonjohnelway</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I should make it known that I am not anti-LGBT and I believe that everyone should have equal rights and be treated fairly. I am straight but I do have a few gay and lesbian friends, coworkers, and family members. 

The common belief nowadays is that gay people are "born this way" and I can't find myself to completely believe this. I want to, as I want to be fully supportive of my gay friends. However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". I think that this expands to sexuality. I don't think there is anything wrong with this or that it is some sort of a mistake if you end up being gay. However, I do believe there is some alternate timeline/universe/ course of events ( whatever you want to call it) where certain people end up with different sexualities. In my opinion, my life could have been drastically different and I could have ended up being gay, but my cousin could have ended up straight. 

I am not trying to offend here, and I hope that it doesn't come off that way. I would truly like to have my view changed. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30582777973.0" user="AffectionateTop" delta="False">
    <text>According to twin studies, what shapes us is divided into heredity, shared environment and unique environment. Generally speaking, 50% of our variance in various traits come from heredity, a tiny portion of mayyybe 5% is shared environment, and the rest is unique environment. Unique environment is the things you go through yourself, including asphyxiation at birth, your own decisions, various environmental effects, and the randomness that built your body and brain. Everything except stuff shared during upbringing.

So, no, we most certainly are not entirely shaped by how we are raised and our experiences as children.

Most people feel upbringing should be so very important to our personalities. The data isn't there to support that. Rather, we have vibrant personalities at birth, and those don't really change much. And that is okay, and beautiful.

Given this, yes, homosexual people are born that way. Though of course, not every one of them is exclusively homosexual.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
