<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537285091.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vvvtv/cmv_not_all_gay_people_are_born_that_way/">
    <title>CMV: Not all gay people are born that way.</title>
    <original_poster>eltonjohnelway</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I should make it known that I am not anti-LGBT and I believe that everyone should have equal rights and be treated fairly. I am straight but I do have a few gay and lesbian friends, coworkers, and family members. 

The common belief nowadays is that gay people are "born this way" and I can't find myself to completely believe this. I want to, as I want to be fully supportive of my gay friends. However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". I think that this expands to sexuality. I don't think there is anything wrong with this or that it is some sort of a mistake if you end up being gay. However, I do believe there is some alternate timeline/universe/ course of events ( whatever you want to call it) where certain people end up with different sexualities. In my opinion, my life could have been drastically different and I could have ended up being gay, but my cousin could have ended up straight. 

I am not trying to offend here, and I hope that it doesn't come off that way. I would truly like to have my view changed. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30581296098.0" user="contro-versy" delta="False">
    <text>The prevailing explanations for the causes of homosexuality are all genetic, or focus on events that occur during embryonic development. For example, homosexuality is matrilineal--heritable on the mother's side. Gay men have a smaller INAH3-- a region of the brain that governs sexuality. When you shrink the INAH3 of a male rat, the rat is more likely to mount other male rats. You can verify all this for yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
