<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537285091.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vvvtv/cmv_not_all_gay_people_are_born_that_way/">
    <title>CMV: Not all gay people are born that way.</title>
    <original_poster>eltonjohnelway</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I should make it known that I am not anti-LGBT and I believe that everyone should have equal rights and be treated fairly. I am straight but I do have a few gay and lesbian friends, coworkers, and family members. 

The common belief nowadays is that gay people are "born this way" and I can't find myself to completely believe this. I want to, as I want to be fully supportive of my gay friends. However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". I think that this expands to sexuality. I don't think there is anything wrong with this or that it is some sort of a mistake if you end up being gay. However, I do believe there is some alternate timeline/universe/ course of events ( whatever you want to call it) where certain people end up with different sexualities. In my opinion, my life could have been drastically different and I could have ended up being gay, but my cousin could have ended up straight. 

I am not trying to offend here, and I hope that it doesn't come off that way. I would truly like to have my view changed. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30582625633.0" user="PokemonHI2" delta="False">
    <text>I think you might just be arguing semantics. 

"Born this way" is a great phrase to use in a lot of circumstances because it gives a sense that straight is not the default. The ambiguity of the phrase also blurs the line between nature vs nurture, so it is about love and acceptance instead.

However, I disagree with your different timeline argument. It's like saying to a straight person that they could have been gay if something shifted their timeline. That's not always the case, because you're treading into fictionality and theoretical ideas, a lot of which do not have enough scientific evidence to back that up. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
