<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537285091.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vvvtv/cmv_not_all_gay_people_are_born_that_way/">
    <title>CMV: Not all gay people are born that way.</title>
    <original_poster>eltonjohnelway</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I should make it known that I am not anti-LGBT and I believe that everyone should have equal rights and be treated fairly. I am straight but I do have a few gay and lesbian friends, coworkers, and family members. 

The common belief nowadays is that gay people are "born this way" and I can't find myself to completely believe this. I want to, as I want to be fully supportive of my gay friends. However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". I think that this expands to sexuality. I don't think there is anything wrong with this or that it is some sort of a mistake if you end up being gay. However, I do believe there is some alternate timeline/universe/ course of events ( whatever you want to call it) where certain people end up with different sexualities. In my opinion, my life could have been drastically different and I could have ended up being gay, but my cousin could have ended up straight. 

I am not trying to offend here, and I hope that it doesn't come off that way. I would truly like to have my view changed. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30580343475.0" user="MrSnrub28" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". 

So, I prefer chocolate ice cream to vanilla. Are you suggesting that I was not born with this taste but rather it was the manner in which I was raised and my experiences that account for this preference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30580375441.0" user="eltonjohnelway" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, that is what I am suggesting. I don't think you were born liking chocolate, but instead developed that preference in one way or another. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30580389784.0" user="MrSnrub28" delta="False">
    <text>How would you know, and more importantly, what is the difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30580405267.0" user="ghostlonefight" delta="False">
    <text>Well there are a variety of ways to test nature vs nurture. Tests using twins are a common one. The point would be accuracy on terms and the potential acknowledgement that it doesn't matter what origin of homosexuality is because it's fine either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30580418022.0" user="MrSnrub28" delta="False">
    <text>Twin studies are imperfect, but if you can prove nature or nurture then publish your work and collect your world-shattering noble prize. You’ve just made history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30581015568.0" user="ghostlonefight" delta="False">
    <text>? There are a lot of studies about this. All the ones I'm aware of say that many things are a combination of both. Some things like physical features definitely have genetic components. Preferences for most things have both. There have even been identical twin studies about being gay, and despite having the same DNA, many twins aren't both gay.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
