<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611260899.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>Your arguments for the niqab always refers to "not mandatory by law",

while your argument for high heels always refers to "socially mandatory".

To have an honest conversation we must choose to either talk about social norms or laws for both of them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611286435.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>2 inch heels were the dress code in an office job I used to work at so they were "mandatory" in that sense. They are also most definitely a social norm. I don't think the niqab is a social norm even in muslim countries besides maybe Saudi Arabia and even there the majority of women do not where it. I will concede some people may be forced by their strict families to where it but I do not think that this is the majority of people who where it, especially in the West. And like I said the niqab does not physical harm to health in the way heels do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611410626.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>So social norms, good I think this is the most interesting of the two choices.

How much do you know about the social norms in countries where the niqab is worn? What are your sources? 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611444812.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>My uncle and cousin lived in Saudi Arabia for 2 years where he was a professor at a university there.  Although the country is obviously oppressive to women,  and she hated living there, the niqab in particular  is not mandatory or socially expected. The hijab is however mostly mandatory (although foreigners don't HAVE to wear it)  Many people who where the niqab actually do it just because they feel safer from men who sneer at them for just existing or because they are very religious and want to hide their bodies. These thoughts are oppressive in nature but it is something that has been engrained in them since birth. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611463954.0" user="Skallywagwindorr" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Many people who where the niqab actually do it just because they feel safer from men who sneer at them for just existing or because they are very religious.

Doesn't this mean there is way more social pressure among the general public to wear a niqab then there is social pressure here to wear high heels? I have never heard anyone say they do not feel 'socially' safe if they don't wear high heels nor did I ever feel unsafe. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30614233533.0" user="Abdul_Fattah" delta="False">
    <text>It's a different type of pressure. KSA is more concerned with religiosity and traditions. So women wear them to be seen as religious/traditional. In some countries professionalism is important and one way for women to show it is to wear heels.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
