<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611356673.0" user="swearrengen" delta="False">
    <text>The real questions are - what is oppressive and what is oppression? What is freedom? There must be a freedom being oppressed for there to be oppression.

You are free if you can say "no" to others. 

Freedom is having the right of refusal without the threat of retaliatory coercion.

Your freedom is protected when saying "no" to someone doesn't result in them physically forcing you or intimidating you with the threat of force. The degree of that threat determines how oppressive it is. If they physically force you, it's oppression.

I don't know the niqab situation. But in western countries, all woman are free to say "no" to high heels. 

So, for women who *do* wear the niqab around the world - what happens if they all decided not to? How would their society react? The answer determines if the niqab is oppressive or not.

Forgive my ignorance, but I would imagine varies place to place around the world, many would be "completely fine" with it, and some small percent would want them "put to death"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611376831.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>See the argument about the niqab is that if people don't wear it they are sentenced to death which I don't think is true. I did quick research on it and it worn by them minority of muslim women and most muslim scholars agree it is not obligatory.  I'm sure there is pressure by some extremely religious families to wear the niqab though but there is also a lot of societal pressure to where heels. That was my main argument. I conceded that someone posted an article about someone who beat their wife for not where the niqab but they were also sent to jail. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611902981.0" user="Rufus_Reddit" delta="False">
    <text>An Iranian woman was just sentenced to 20 years in jail for taking off her face veil.

https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-43329896</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611915528.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611959692.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>u/ban1o – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+ban1o&amp;amp;message=ban1o+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/-/e29jl6w/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
