<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30612793454.0" user="EmpRupus" delta="False">
    <text>High heels are like make up or hair. It is simply a sign of grooming and professional standards - while unfair, it is more a matter of uniform. High heels do cause damage the same way corsets did. However, not wearing high-heels is not a safety issue.

On the other hand, a Niqab is viewed as a sign of personal character, moral values and devotion to God, in other words, your very essence of womanhood and value to men. In many places, a woman in a hijab is considered a candy inside a wrapper, whereas a woman without a hijab is considered an unwrapped candy, with ants all over it.Such a woman is considered unworthy of the privilege of sexual respect, and also unworthy of being a wife or a mother. She is considered a "street woman" and thus "up for grabs".

Not wearing naqab is a safety issue.

&amp;gt; I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.

Translation : I don't want to be raped by men. I don't want men to pick me out from the group and sexually harass me, because they thought I am a street prostitute. And then report me to my family for being out and about in streets, enticing men with my sexuality, which will lead to me being blacklisted from all prospective marriage alliances, since the whole neighborhood will know me as "that woman" and warn men against marrying me. I will probabley end up a spinster.

There is of course no legal mandate for niqab, in the same way there is no legal mandate against men wearing skirts and lipstick in America.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30613136619.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think not wearing high heels can affect how professional one looks thus affecting how far they progress in their career? You said yourelf it a sign of grooming and professional standards. 

&amp;gt;Translation : I don't want to be raped by men. I don't want men to pick me out from the group and sexually harass me, because they thought I am a street prostitute. And then report me to my family for being out and about in streets, enticing men with my sexuality, which will lead to me being blacklisted from all prospective marriage alliances, since the whole neighborhood will know me as "that woman" and warn men against marrying me. I will probabley end up a spinster.

lmao I'm sorry this just made me laugh. I'm not saying this never happens but this just seems to be based on western stereotypes of muslims. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30645518299.0" user="EmpRupus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I'm not saying this never happens but this just seems to be based on western stereotypes of muslims.

No. It is based on testimony of women themselves. 

What you are doing is called "White Feminism" aka, a wealthy white woman prioritizing her complaints (such as heels and lipsticks) and trivializing the more serious priorities of minority women (such as being victims of physical and sexual abuse).

Feminism and woman's liberation applies to all women, not just white women, so please don't defend rape and abuse in non-white communities. Minorities don't exist to make you feel charitable, they are actual human beings. 

As a white person from a first-world-country, you might think the biggest problem facing women are the discomfort of heels. But it is not so.

You might talk about heels as a separate conversation. But don't bring in the more serious issues of minority women in that. Problems faced by minority women are not benchmarks for your walking discomforts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
