<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611338253.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>The niqab has the unique property of covering a person's face, which is where we tend to ascribe people's personality and emotion. In any media critique, calling someone faceless means that they lack humanization. It's usually the default way to mark someone as either a villain or an acceptable target for consequence-free violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611346638.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>i guess this argument just depends on whether you think covering someone's face is more oppressive than a footware that can damage someone's back, joints and feet. I do agree that the niqab is oppressive my argument it that heels and the niqab were equally as oppressive and are both the result of societal pressure. 

I guess I can understand you argument about how it removes their humanization and since it is solely worn by women you are dehumanizing women. My main thing is that it is only worn by a minority of women and muslim scholars agree that is is not mandated which makes me thing most women who wear it chose to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30614201040.0" user="Abdul_Fattah" delta="False">
    <text>Some Muslim men actually do cover their faces (the tagelmust for example). Historically it wasn't that uncommon in Muslim areas as well. We don't see it as dehumanizing someone, because we don't think the face defines a person. We also have our ideas of negative types of dress that you'd find odd. For example, wearing pants that go past your ankles is a negative in Muslim societies as it represents pride. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
