<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611228986.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>High heels are worn to be more prevalent in society, making the user taller and more attractive. They are there to attract attention to the wearer. 

The niqab diminishes someone's viewability and makes them part of the background. It allows the wearer to be ignored which is key when oppressing someone.

It's hard to actually oppress someone with something that calls more attention to them rather than less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611241473.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>a piece of footwear that can cause long term damage to your feet, back and joints is not as oppressive as a piece of clothes that hides your face? 

https://www.seeker.com/high-heels-cause-long-term-damage-1765087339.html </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611253542.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't respond to my point just reiterated one of yours.

I don't know anyone that wears high heels every day, so it's weak argument. Additionally just because it's damaging doesn't mean it's oppressive, alcohol is literally poison but me drinking it every once in a while doesn't make it oppressive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611261032.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>high heels with minimum of 2 inch heel were mandatory in a place I used to work at. It was an office job so yes I had to wear them everyday.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611278914.0" user="rehcsel" delta="False">
    <text>Ok but what about my original point?

To your point in the U.S. specifically it's illegal to have different dress codes for men and women. [Source](http://fortune.com/2016/05/12/high-heels-dress-code/) Many other countries are also following suit. So it's a non issue these days.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611303293.0" user="trikstersire" delta="False">
    <text>That's a problem with your work place and your specific situation and not a societal norm. 

The whole point of HIDING your face is to prevent you from being able to show parts of your body. To shame your appearance. The point of high heels is to *accentuate* your body, to show it off in a more attractive way. 

Look I get your idea here - you are upset that high heels are a large part of society and it's something that objectifies women more. But comparing it to oppression is pretty horrible for you to do. Because you're saying that you suffer as much as they do. And you are grossly overplaying your own suffering while also invalidating their oppression. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611363274.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how something that damages one's feet, back and joints is not oppressive. I think the are both oppressive. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
