<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611134831.0" user="PersonWithARealName" delta="False">
    <text>Is there any country with laws dictating you *have* to wear high-heels? 

That would be the difference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611143532.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>Like I said in the post, there are no countries dictating someone where the niqab. Can you please name which country you are referring to? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611147353.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Women in Iran have been arrested and imprisoned for removing the veil in public

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/07/iranian-woman-who-removed-headscarf-sentenced-to-two-years](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/07/iranian-woman-who-removed-headscarf-sentenced-to-two-years)

see also here

[https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/feb/02/tehran-hijab-protest-iranian-police-arrest-29-women](https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/feb/02/tehran-hijab-protest-iranian-police-arrest-29-women)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611150101.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>So are we mixing up the hijab and the niqab. The post is clearly about the face viel that covers the face besides the eyes which i not mandated in Iran or even  commonly worn. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611154835.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>Why is the distinction relevant to your argument?  You used the generic term "veil" in your title.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611166177.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about the niqab...this is clear in my post. Since it's being banned in many countries and many people arguing it's oppressive to women. I am not talking about the hijab That is a completely different argument. There is a difference. "face viel" refers to a veil that covers the face which the hijab doesn't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611189223.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>If Iran and other countries  mandated all women wear 2 inch heels, its disingenuous to argue that no country mandate women wear 4 inch heels.  While technically correct, I feel it misses the argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611235204.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>this is a fair argument</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611264275.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>If the argument changed your view, you should award a delta for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611273378.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>how do you do this lol </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611275546.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>No worries.

Just reply to u/cacheflow's comment with a short explanation why you feel it is a fair argument and include the following text, without quotes:

&amp;gt; !delta</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611303541.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>!delta 

This is a fair argument. It has at least partially made me rethink about it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611160540.0" user="PersonWithARealName" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Muslim women are legally required to wear hijab in public in Saudi Arabia [1] and the Indonesian Aceh province,[2] and all women are required to do so in Iran.[3]

I had a moment of confusion and was thinking about the hijab, not the niqab. 

The fact that the hijab is legally required in some areas does still pertain to the difference between high heels and the niqab. In the western world, the niqab is seen as an extension of the hijab. A more extreme version of the same thing. So while the niqab itself isn't mandatory, the fact that Westerners consider it to be an extreme version of the hijab which is required puts those two on similar ground. 

I'd also argue that high-heels have literally no religious connotation, which cannot be said for the niqab. Another difference. Also, one is footwear and the other obscures the face. There's plenty of differences between the two.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611176443.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I am not saying there are n differences between the two I am arguing that the niqab is no more "oppressive" than high heels. I don't see how the niqab being viewed by the west as a more extreme version of the hijab has to do with it not being  any more oppressive than heels.  Most people in the West do not view the hijab as that oppressive but view the niqab as more oppressive which is why it is being banned in many places and argues against. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611184788.0" user="PersonWithARealName" delta="False">
    <text>One covers the face and one goes on the feet. That's the argument for it being more oppressive. It's oppressive to cover someone's entire face in the name of modesty. 

And the reason they see it as an extreme hijab is relevant is because the hijab *is* required by law in some places. This means they think the niqab could *also* be required by law some day. They ban it because of the potential for forced use. Because if it is seen as an extreme version of the hijab, the idea is that they think some women who use it are forced to wear it against their will. While no woman is forced to wear heels against her will. 

That said, I don't agree with banning the niqab. If someone wants to wear it, who am I to stop them? But I do think that the niqab is in no way comparable to high heels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611207911.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>so it's not oppressive to intentionally do damage to your back and joints? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611220286.0" user="PersonWithARealName" delta="False">
    <text>If you choose to do that? No. 

Is football oppressive because you're intentionally doing damage to your back and joints? Are factory jobs oppressive because you're intentionally doing damage to your joints? 

It's not oppressive to choose to do something that hurts you. It's oppressive to be forced to. And while the niqab isn't legally enforced, the hijab is. And with the niqab seen as an extension of the hijab, it's not unrealistic to think that some women are forced to wear a niqab against their will. 

Do you think that the women living in Saudi Arabia amongst people who do use the niqab would be culturally accepted if they chose not to wear it? Is it possible that there's even *one* woman forced to wear her niqab? Meanwhile no women are forced to wear heels. That's a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611248214.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I used to work at a place where it was mandatory to where heels. Heels are a cultural expectation for formal where and they serve no purpose besides making the legs look longer and the women's legs appear sexier. 

The majority of women in saudi Arabia do not where the niqab and it is not mandated. It is a cultural garment similar to heels. I believe most women wear it as some form of extreme devotion to their religion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611274221.0" user="PersonWithARealName" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but you don't have to work at those places. So heels aren't mandatory. 

You didn't answer my question about football and factory jobs? If heels are oppressive because they intentionally harm your back and joints, are those professions I listed also oppressive? 

&amp;gt; The majority of women in saudi Arabia do not where the niqab and it is not mandated. It is a cultural garment similar to heels. I believe most women wear it as some form of extreme devotion to their religion.

And any deviation from devotion to the religion can result in serious consequences. Even if it isn't legally mandatory, the niqab is viewed even by Muslims as a result of conservative fundamentalism. The exact type of people who demand subservience from their women. I suspect that if they wanted to break from their small societal norm, there would be consequences.

&amp;gt; It is a cultural garment similar to heels.

Except one covers the entire face in the name of modesty, and one is footwear. Even if your argument is that both are oppressive, you have to see that covering your entire face is more oppressive than footwear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611431795.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You didn't answer my question about football and factory jobs? If heels are oppressive because they intentionally harm your back and joints, are those professions I listed also oppressive?

There are jobs/sports/professions. - that technically either gender can participate in.  I am talking about oppressive clothing on women. I personally think football is whack and dangerous and should be banned but that's a completely other argument maybe for another CMV lol. 

&amp;gt;And any deviation from devotion to the religion can result in serious consequences. Even if it isn't legally mandatory, the niqab is viewed even by Muslims as a result of conservative fundamentalism. The exact type of people who demand subservience from their women. I suspect that if they wanted to break from their small societal norm, there would be consequences.

I guess people just view things that are religiously associated as inherently more oppressive than things that are socially expected? Like I said most religious scholars agree the niqab is not obligatory and there isn't examples  of people being arrested or beaten if they do not wear the niqab. There was an argument about it being an extension of the hijab which is mandatory in some places which I think it a good argument though. 

&amp;gt;Except one covers the entire face in the name of modesty, and one is footwear. Even if your argument is that both are oppressive, you have to see that covering your entire face is more oppressive than footwear.

The definition of oppressive that I use is 

1. unjustly inflicting hardship and constraint, especially on a minority or other subordinate group.

I just personally ting shoes that can do damage to your feet and back fit this definition as much as something that hides your face but does no physical harm. I know you disagree with that argument but I guess that's where we agree to disagree. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
