<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611209675.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think anyone is arguing that the niqab itself is oppressing women. It's a piece of cloth. It's the social expectation of wearing a niqab that is oppressive, and certainly more so than the social expectation of high heels.

Under Salafi Islam, of which Wahhabi Islam is effectively the state religion of Saudi Arabia, a woman's face is considered [awrah](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intimate_parts_in_Islam), and therefore it's religiously forbidden for a woman not to cover her face (with a niqab or otherwise). Whether or not there's a law and how lenient Saudis would be towards a woman refusing to wear one is irrelevant - it's the social and religious expectation that a woman wear a niqab or equivalent.

There's no social or religious law in the West requiring women to wear high heels, and many women choose not to wear them most of the time without appearing odd. You could argue that whatever social expectation of high heels still exists is oppressing women, but certainly not as much as the social expectation of wearing a niqab.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611229703.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>Heels are mandatory in many work places. They were mandatory in a place I used to work. It is most definitely a social expectation for women. 

The niqab is not mandated in Saudi Arabia and the majority of women there do not wear the niqab. 

Just because something as religious associations does not make it more oppressive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611272045.0" user="Sugarleaps" delta="False">
    <text>No one forced you to take that job. You made a conscious choice. Society didn't enforce it, you did. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611275812.0" user="47ca05e6209a317a8fb3" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about it being religious per se, just like it's not about it being legal/illegal. It's about it being socially expected and enforced. [Wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niq%C4%81b#Saudi_Arabia) says:

 &amp;gt; the niqab is an important part of Saudi culture and in most Saudi cities (including Riyadh, Mecca, Medina, Abha, etc.) the vast majority of women cover their faces

Maybe where you live heels are treated in a similarly oppressive capacity to niqabs in Saudi Arabia, but everywhere I've lived or worked they weren't, and any requirement to wear them at work would come as part of a broader overall costume or uniform you're committed to, like for a waitress at a bar or similar, which you could say is oppressive, but it's part of the job and restricted to work only, so not as much as the niqab, which you're expected to wear wherever there are men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30614224230.0" user="Abdul_Fattah" delta="False">
    <text>And men in KSA are expected to wear the thawb and the multi-part headdress. I don't see why this is oppressive? Social expectations seem completely reasonable to me. This notion that choices shouldn't have consequences is unrealistic and naive. Most people who make the argument that niqab is oppressive also believe in some concept of freedom. In these societies people call oppressive women/men are free to wear what they want, and other people are free to react negatively due to the dress those people wear. It seems antithetical to the notion of freedom to want an end to social expectations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30612151924.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It is most definitely a social expectation for women.

No it isn't. I have never worn a pair of heels in my entire life. I have never had anybody say anything about it ever. I've never gotten glaring looks when out in public. It's never been brought up or mentioned ever in my life that I'm wearing flats instead of heels. 

I'm not sure that a woman in a country that has a lot of women wearing hijabs could say the same thing about not once having it ever brought up to her or not once experiencing any glares or comments about never having ever worn a hijab. 

I would agree with you if heels were actually mandatory - be that socially or legally. I agree that high heels themselves are oppressive. But they're optional, not required (socially or legally), and therefore they are not on par with the hijab. It isn't just "Western values" that makes Westerners frown on the hijab while ignoring high heels - rather, it's the fact that hijabs are often mandatory (socially or legally) while heels are not. 

Your one job that required heels is an exception, not the norm, and I bet that if you sued them you could win the lawsuit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30612157313.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about the niqab... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30612161591.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>Okay well even worse for your argument, but so just replace "hijab" with "niqab" in my comment and the comment still applies. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
