<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611242107.0" user="justtogetridoflater" delta="False">
    <text>There is no dictation that high heels are necessary. 

Practitioners of Islam do insist on their women wearing the hijab or niqab. It's a choice in so much as they're told that they should wear them to be a good muslim woman from a very young age and that a god is watching them so they must do it. With this comes this message that women are inherently sexual beings that lead men to desire and that they're in danger if they show themselves to men, even in a non sexual way. It's genuinely believed that men must avert their eyes so as not to feel sexually interested in this. It's not a choice, because from the get go, it's been an insistence. You see kids wearing a niqab. You occasionally see them wearing a hijab. 

Whereas high heels admittedly do carry a negative message, but it's worth considering that it's a negative message largely created by the market for high heels. It started out being a thing that men did. Now it's a thing that women do. And it's largely now a problem that women do it, rather than an insistence by men that women do it. It's like makeup. If women were to refuse to wear makeup, then it's quite likely that there would not be serious consequences for it from men. But the issue is that an individual woman is caught in this system whereby women wear makeup and judge others who do not wear makeup. 

I don't know of men that insist that women must wear makeup or wear heels or whatever. And to some extent, my parents refuse to give my sisters makeup and let them wear heels and indeed shun social media until such time as it's judged appropriate and when that is exactly, I don't know. The idea that they're sexual beings is explained to girls when it's appropriate and is done so in a more honest way.  And to some extent everyone's parents do this. There are a few parents that have not done that, but that doesn't usually have good results, and I think the revulsion you feel when you see a kid with high heels and ears pierced and makeup is a sign that we know that this is wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611249772.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There is no dictation that high heels are necessary.

High Heels were mandatory in my work place </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611257651.0" user="justtogetridoflater" delta="False">
    <text>Well, that's a fair contrast. I think that's wrong, and is oppressive.

I would argue that it's less oppressive than the niqab/hijab with Islam, however, because you can always avoid working there. You could find somewhere where high heels were not mandatory. Of course, workplace uniforms are traditionally quite oppressive in general, because any semblance of personality in clothing is to be squished out in favour of people looking as if they're working here. However, with Islam, you're raised from a very young age to believe that this is the only way a woman should be. High heels don't carry ideological religious weight. The only message I think you take from high heels is that women are sexierr if they're taller than they really are. They're based around a woman being decidely kind of sexual and that's ultimately a choice. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611332789.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I can agree with the argument that there is probably more pressure to wear the niqab for those that do. However the majority of muslims women don't wear it and most muslim schoalrs agree it's not mandatory. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611366701.0" user="justtogetridoflater" delta="False">
    <text>The majority of workplaces don't demand high heels either.

The difference is that you can ditch a shitty workplace but you can't ditch Islam quite so easily. It's indoctrinated into you. It's forced on you by your parents, your moral authority figures, your spouse probably. And there are entire countries that force the hijab onto women. 

The niqab and hijab stem from the idea that you are naturally a source of evil essentially. Your very body is an immoral thing, that you can't allow men to see in case you tempt them and they rape you. This is literally an argument put forward by someone a couple of days ago on here when he was trying to defend it. They basically teach you to be fearful. They're there to teach you that you're not allowed to be a sexual being, except with your husband.

High heels are there to make you sexy. That's the point. You put these heels on and make the decision to be a sexual being. But we don't force it on kids. We try not to teach kids that they are sexual beings, mostly. We try not to teach kids that this is what we ultimately desire to be. We want our daughters to be accountants and lawyers not strippers and porn stars. Heels are not considered a thing of social morals. There is pressure to put them on but I would suggest that it's a pressure that is competitive and jealous over and above being oppressive. I don't think we find it fair that a man should dictate his wife/gfs outfit, for example. I think men barely notice half of this alleged oppression in terms of clothing, because they don't perpetrate it. A man can wear a suit all year and nobody know. There was that newscaster who did. I would find it interesting to find that a man is suddenly so much more arsed about this when women are wearing the clothes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611403581.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>see I can understand this but I think people have a misunderstanding of the niqab. I did a bit of research in it and although I believe the beliefs behind it are  definitely patriarchal  since the religion is patriarchal to begin with it seems that women who where it mostly want to either to maintain anyoniminity or as some sort deep devotion to their religion. 

Just because High heels are meant to make you look sexy or more sexual instead of hiding yourself doesn't mean in my opinion that they aren't oppressive in nature. Oppressive means "unjustly inflicting hardship and constraint, especially on a minority or other subordinate group." Heels are worn almost worn exclusively by women and objectively can damage one's physical health which is why I consider it "oppressive" 

I know many women chose to where heels but also many women where them due to societal pressure or social norms t that they've had since birth especially for formal events which is similar to the niqab imo. 

I will concede from arguments for families where they do where the niqab it is probably more pressured to do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611424055.0" user="justtogetridoflater" delta="False">
    <text>The question is, (oppressive job excluded), could you avoid wearing high heels? If you got backlash from this, who would it be from? What the hell are you doing wearing high heels? You know what they are, but you're wearing them? What made you take a job where high heels are compulsory?  What messages are you taking from the high heels?

The niqab has far more pressure on it. But it also has more ideological pressure on it too.

I have not seen an argument that high heels are seriously being forced on women by men. They're being worn by women at this point because women want to wear them because they feel pressured by women, mostly. It's peer pressure mostly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30615706664.0" user="NewbombTurk" delta="False">
    <text>I get that you're trying to defend you culture, and possibly your faith, but your equivocation on this thread is embarrassing. 

Wearing heels, and wearing the niqab and not comparable in any way. Heels are almost never required. Ever. I've been in the corporate space for thirty years and has never even heard of this requirement. But, even if it was, is not the same as the religious requirement to cover you face/hair from the view of men. It's not even the same ballpark. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30623180674.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not a muslim lmao. That's a weird assumption to make </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30623195117.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30623203185.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I get that you're trying to defend you culture, and possibly your faith, but your equivocation on this thread is embarrassing.

how is this not making an assumption? You didn't make any new points so yes, that's all I got from your response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30623230355.0" user="NewbombTurk" delta="False">
    <text>Because I said "possibly", admitting in my post that I don't know. What you should have taken from my post was that you are guilty of some hardcore equivocation. Let me be clear; the "oppression" of mandatory heels (I find your story dubious) is not the same thing as the concept of a deity who deems a woman's body parts should be hidden from the sight of men. Are they both oppressive? Yes. Are they even close to the same thing? No fucking way. 

You are wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30623300304.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>u/NewbombTurk – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+NewbombTurk&amp;amp;message=NewbombTurk+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/-/e2g9ckt/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30614236646.0" user="Abdul_Fattah" delta="False">
    <text>Except men have an awrah as well, and women are required to not look at men as well. So guess men are sexual beings as well?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
