<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="541274287.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8y9dwv/cmvhigh_heeled_shoes_are_just_as_oppressive_as/">
    <title>CMV:High Heeled shoes are just as "oppressive" as the face veil/niqab</title>
    <original_poster>ban1o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently there has been a lot of objection to the niqab in western countries based on the premise that they are oppressive to women. I am ignoring the aspect of social security and focusing on the aspect that I feel is repeated over and over again on reddit and social media that the niqab is oppressive to women and thus should be banned.

In Western Society high heels are part of the culture. High heels make the wearer taller, accentuating the calf muscle and the length of the leg overall and often to make women appear sexier. However they are objectively bad for your health and can cause back ad joint pain and vein swelling. High Heels, despite being damaging to ones health are often mandatory in work environments or a cultural expectation as part of formal wear for women. Despite high heels being objectively ad for ones feet though many women choose to wear them as part of their fashion choices, but one could say some are being condition due to societal expectations for women. 

The niqab on the other is a cultural garment often used in some arab countries that conceals the face aside from the eyes. There are no countries where the niqab is mandated  (no it is not mandated in Saudi Arabia). I was reading reasons people where it and a lot of people where it because it makes them feel more comfortable and they like the anonymity.   Yes this might be due to oppressive ideology about a women needing to "hide herself" from men but again most of these women choose it. I think it's rare that a husband or father is forcing someone to wear the niqab since the hijab is much more practiced. Also the niqab  is not objectively bad for one's physical health like high heels are and does not arm to the women wearing it besides perhaps in western society getting weird stares from people

So I argue that high heels are just as oppressive if not more oppressive than the niqab but western society doesn't view it that way since the niqab is associated with islam and arab countries in a way high heels are not.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30611183959.0" user="Tarron" delta="False">
    <text>Stop it.

Just stop it.

You have the choice whether to wear heeled shoes or not. A choice you don’t have in a lot of circumstances with a niqab.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611205190.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>do you know anybody that is forced to wear the niqab? It's not mandatory in any countries and is owrn by a small minority of muslim women. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611225420.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text> If Iran and other countries mandated all women wear 2 inch heels, its disingenuous to argue that no country mandate women wear 4 inch heels. While technically correct, I feel it misses the argument.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611317609.0" user="trikstersire" delta="False">
    <text>You do realize that people have been fucking ***KILLED*** for not wearing a niqab right? Like cool, it's not required by law. It's required by religion. But aside from losing your job at some weirdass company that requires 2 inch high heels, your life isn't in danger because you opted out. 

This is a very very incredible case of first world self-centered pity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611321251.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>do you have examples of being  people killed for not wearing the niqab? The vast majority of islam scholars do not think that it is mandatory. so it is not "required by religion" I don't really take arguments like this seriously. They seem more emotional. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611338996.0" user="trikstersire" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.google.com/search?q=woman+killed+for+not+wearing+niqab&amp;amp;nirf=woman+killed+for+not+wearing+hijab&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiK676z3ZncAhVRn-AKHZ9LBqIQ8BYIJygB&amp;amp;biw=1280&amp;amp;bih=628&amp;amp;dpr=1.25

Sounds like you're in denial...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611354313.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not in denial. These articles all reference the hijab and not the niqab. The niqab is worn by a  minority of mulsim women. 

I did however see some merit to the argument that the niqab is seen as a more extreme version of the hijab  especially in the west and since the hijab is mandatory in some places then it's disingenuous to say that the niqab is completely up to one's choice. However you re not arguing this. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611352712.0" user="turned_into_a_newt" delta="False">
    <text>[This](https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/middle-east/iran-woman-hijab-protest-arrest-jailed-prison-shapark-shajarizadeh-headscarf-white-wednesdays-a8439816.html) woman was sentenced to 20 years for not wearing a hijab. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30611355683.0" user="ban1o" delta="False">
    <text>Sigh. I understand what you guys are doing but y'all aren't making good arguments when you ignore what my original statement even was. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30614242261.0" user="Abdul_Fattah" delta="False">
    <text>That women was sentenced for standing against the government.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
