<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="546995725.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/91o0lp/cmv_but_president_pense_is_not_a_good_argument/">
    <title>CMV: "-but president Pense!" is not a good argument against impeachment.</title>
    <original_poster>Dr_Scientist_</original_poster>
    <original_post>This post assumes that Donald Trump has been found guilty of committing an impeachable offense. **A standard which hasn't been reached**. This is a purely hypothetical universe, different from our own, one in which Trump is conclusively guilty of committing crimes which would normally eject a person from being the president. 

I only bring this up because I often see people bemoaning, 'Oh but then *Pense* would be president' as if that would not be a dramatic upgrade from a convicted criminal. Pense seems to have no spine, abhorrent views, and his tenure as vice-president seriously undermines his credibility as a moral thinking person. His willingness to fly out to a football game, *just to leave it*, is hardly better than a humping lapdog. I don't think he belongs anywhere near the office.

However Trump has proven himself to be so disastrous, it seems inconceivable to me that Pense could be worse. It just doesn't seem plausible that Pense would surround himself family members as top advisers, pull dumbass stunts like a travel-ban without consulting legal council, resort to playground bullying like trying to illegally withhold federal dollars from sanctuary cities, get himself caught up in some Russian scandal, or some pornstar scandal, golf at his own resort every weekend, suggest doing away with due process, start a trade war, make asinine tweets threatening world war at 3am, fight illegal immigration with baby cages, or open his administration to the likes of Scott Pruitt and the whole goddamn swamp of lowlifes Trump has brought with him.

I totally get that he would likely appoint ultra-conservative supreme court picks, push back LGBT rights to the stone age, and may have chosen to abandon the Paris Accord /  Iran Nuclear deal all on his own. Again, he's not someone I would vote for. 

**BUT** *if* Trump ever were on the verge of being impeached, "-but what about Pense????" is not a good argument for tolerating a known criminal in office. 

This is something I feel pretty strongly about but whenever I try talk about it, I don't feel like I get much/any support for my view. 'Oh but what about Pense' is something I hear often from people whose opinions I respect. **Is there something to that argument?** Should I be more concerned about Pense maybe being a bad president if it's known that Trump already is one? 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30655514759.0" user="iWinterRS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;pull dumbass stunts like a travel-ban without consulting legal council,

He doesn't need to that's why it was upheld in the scotus.

&amp;gt;resort to playground bullying like trying to illegally withhold federal dollars from sanctuary cities

HR 3003, called "No Sanctuary for Criminals Act," passed largely along party lines 228-195 on June 29, 2017

While its temporary preventive measure [In April, A California judge granted a nationwide preliminary injunction that temporarily blocked a section of an executive order signed by Trump to withhold federal funds from "sanctuary cities."] it will go to the senate to be made a law, assuming they agree, so it would be legal, but currently he is within the law by following the judges orders.

Those two weaken your argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30655543264.0" user="Dr_Scientist_" delta="False">
    <text>The version of the travel ban upheld by the scotus was *NOT* the one thrown out by a completely inexperienced doofus in the first month of his presidency. The one upheld by the scotus was at least the third iteration, *after* it had been altered by white house council.

The sanctuary cities is another example where I believe Pense would have gone through the correct channels from the start, rather than shit the bed and work from there like Trump. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30655576789.0" user="iWinterRS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The version of the travel ban upheld by the SCOTUS was NOT the one thrown out by a completely inexperienced doofus in the first month of his presidency

 There's clarity you were talking about eo 13769 where I was referring to eo 13780

&amp;gt;The sanctuary cities is another example where I believe Pense would have gone through the correct channels 

Did Trump try through an eo? Otherwise, he is with the house bill HR 3003 like I stated above which you didn't really address. 

Also the trump shit the bed makes it hard to believe you are wanting your view changed in conjunction with calling him a doofus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30655612931.0" user="Dr_Scientist_" delta="False">
    <text>If my CMV were 'Trump is a garbage person' you're right. I don't think my view can be changed on that subject. On the topic of, I shouldn't want Trump impeached knowing he's guilty of committing crimes because *PENSE!* I'm willing to hear and consider arguments. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30657271603.0" user="Apprehensive_Clock" delta="False">
    <text>Impeachment != to removal. It is only a formal statement of charges against a head of state. Once an individual is impeached, he or she must then face the possibility of conviction via legislative vote, which then entails the removal of the individual from office.

Bill Clinton and Andrew Johnson were both impeached and both were acquitted. No president has been impeached which lead to their conviction and removal from office.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
