<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="548728073.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/92p5ah/cmv_there_is_no_reasonable_or_practical_way_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reasonable or practical way to actually enforce an abortion ban</title>
    <original_poster>captainporcupine3</original_poster>
    <original_post>My apologies if I'm hopelessly naive about U.S. law. A better title for this post might be, "I can't think of any reasonable or practical way to enforce an abortion ban, please enlighten me."

I often hear people arguing the merits of an abortion ban without grappling with the real and practical challenges of actually enforcing the ban. It seems to me that there are some pretty glaring issues that would arise if we tried to actually enforce a ban. I'm starting from the premise that we all agree that it's permissible to terminate a pregnancy if necessary to save the life of the mother. So here are some potential issues I am wondering about:

1) How does the state determine that you had an abortion in the first place? It's my understanding that the government can legally subpoena your medical records by obtaining a search warrant if necessary for a criminal investigation. But on what grounds could the state receive such a warrant in the first place? How would the state know that you as an individual were ever pregnant in the first place, let alone suspect that the pregnancy was terminated? I'm not aware of any registry of individual pregnant women that could be checked over. 

2) If the state did have some suspicion that a specific pregnancy was terminated, on what grounds would it suspect that the termination was unlawful? Particularly if abortion is lawful when necessary to save the life of the mother. Not to mention the fact that pregnancies are terminated when the fetus has died in the womb. Assuming the state had some mechanism for determining what pregnancies were terminated, would it be given carte blanche to review to the medical records of any individual who fell into that category in order to determine if each individual case was legal? Is it reasonable or practical for the state to launch an investigation into the private medical history of every woman whose pregnancy is lawfully terminated to root out the individuals whose pregnancies were terminated unlawfully? 

3) Assuming you granted the state those rights and were willing to support the bureaucracy necessary to enact them, what next? When reviewing individual medical histories, what criteria does the state use to determine that an individual termination was unlawful? Surely there are plenty of borderline decisions where the mother's life is at substantial and even imminent risk but she still has the right to continue the pregnancy if she chooses? What metric does the state use to determine that a specific pregnancy was risky enough that termination is deemed legal or illegal in that instance? Isn't it true that in many cases different doctors would reasonably disagree on the risk to the mother's life?

4) Once the state determines that a particular termination is deemed unlawful, how do you prosecute? Does the state pursue murder charges in a jury trial? Are the individual's private medical records made available to a jury so that they can make the ultimate ruling on whether the termination was indeed unlawful? And based on what -- the reasonable person metric? Can non experts make a reasonable determination on the merits of a medical diagnosis like the need to terminate a pregnancy?

Again, my apologies if some of these questions are naive. From my humble position these seem like reasonable questions, but if I am wrong that they are serious or noteworthy issues then please change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30668959916.0" user="warlocktx" delta="False">
    <text>Abortions take place in doctor's offices.  Doctors offices have employees.  All it takes is one disgruntled employee to report a doctor.  Or a husband or boyfriend who doesn't support the woman's choice to abort.  Or her best friend's husband who overheard them talking on the phone.

Doctors have a LOT to lose - their medical license, their livelihood, their reputation, not to mention the possibility of jail.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30669149273.0" user="captainporcupine3" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're not wrong. It was already pointed out in this thread that the way to actually enforce this ban is to crack down on the provider, which is what I think you are saying. I will say that my questions were raised under the assumption that it's not reasonable for the state to review a patient's private medical history without good reason to suspect that someone has broken the law. I am not sure that a mere claim from an associate of the pregnant woman would clear the legal bar for a search warrant to be granted. Would that mean that law-abiding individuals who received a medically necessary abortion would be subject to a criminal investigation, with their private medical history opened up to the state, based on any anonymous tip? Maybe this is already how it works, I don't know. If it is I think it is unreasonable.

Regardless, another poster already convinced me that a tipster could still do the trick without any need to spy on citizens. All the state needs to do is to crack down on the provider with a claim that they are breaking the law and the abortion ban can be easily enforced.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
