<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="550658674.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/93uiya/cmv_the_ddlg_lifestyle_is_unhealthydestructivenot/">
    <title>CMV: The DDLG lifestyle is unhealthy/destructive/not good</title>
    <original_poster>chakalakawhat</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Super Important Thing:** I will always defend any consenting adult's right to participate in DDLG.

**First reason (applies to non-sexual ddlg and other dom/subs):** I think that an able-minded person relying on someone else to make personal decisions for them is psychologically unhealthy because it means refusing to develop psychologically and handle their adult responsibilities/take care of themselves and puts those responsibilities on someone else.

I think that someone making personal decisions for someone who is mentally able is like the super-ultra version of a codependent relationship.

So it hurts everybody.

**Second reason:** Sexualizing adults acting like children sexualizes children.

I'll compare to how a vlogger transitioning FTM answers the question, “Why transition to be gay?”\*

He says that before he transitioned, men he would date would respond to him as if he were a female when he really wasn’t. Transitioning allows him to be with people who are attracted to the person he actually is and who he is as a man.

My point about ddlg is that daddies are relating to littles as if they were children when they are actually adults. The part of the little that attracts them is the child part. If it wasn’t the child part that attracted them, I don’t see why they wouldn’t just do dom/sub without the age play/regression.

**I'm totally open to other perspectives on this!**

\*Video link: [https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk](https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk) (this person does not endorse my opinion!).

**TL;DR: ddlg is unhealthy because it keeps people in super-ultra codependent relationships instead of growing up and it sexualizes children.**

edited for clarity</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30683473424.0" user="NearEmu" delta="False">
    <text>Do you hold the same logical stance on every type of bdsm?

For instance, you say "sexualizing adults acting like children - &amp;gt; sexualizing children"

So does "sexualizing adults being violent to one another - &amp;gt; sexualizing violence in general"

If you have a dom/sub and one is a "slave" and the other is a "master" does that also  end up being a statement on ones belief in slavery or sexual slavery?

The difference in all these things boils down to one thing, are the people consenting, and do they understand what they are consenting to, and is it done thoughtfully and safely between the people consenting?

Nobody would ever defend violent BDSM where one person beats the other to the point they are coming to work with black eyes and cuts on their face and things of that nature. That isn't safe.

Nobody would defend DDLG where one person is treated to the point of full mental regression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30683602707.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you hold the same logical stance on every type of bdsm? 

No, because "sexualizing A = sexualizing B" is not my logical stance. The logic would be: What makes something a sexualization of children is sexualizing something that is distinctly child-like, not adult-like. Sexualizing adults acting like children is sexualizing something distinctly child-like. Ergo, sexualizing adults acting like children is sexualizing children. 

That logic is specific to ddlg, not bdsm.    

&amp;gt;The difference in all these things boils down to one thing . . .

No, I don't think consent is justification for doing something. I will defend the *right* of any consenting adults to practice ddlg. But that doesn't mean I think it's a good idea. In fact, I think it's an unhealthy one. And because I think it's an unhealthy one, two people can think through it as carefully as they can, decide it's unhealthy but consent to it anyway, and do it as safely as they possibly can and I will still think it's destructive.  

&amp;gt;Nobody would ever defend violent BDSM where one person beats the other  to the point they are coming to work with black eyes and cuts on their  face and things of that nature. That isn't safe. 

I have heard that defended as safe if the dom knows what he is doing. I only bring that up because diff people have a different understanding of safe. Because I think ddlg is psychologically unhealthy, I think it's psychologically harmful and not safe.

Going to work with cuts is definitely not discreet, though. 

&amp;gt;Nobody would defend DDLG where one person is treated to the point of full mental regression. 

I *have* heard full regression defended. Not acting like they're 7 every single second, but a person wouldn't stop calling a drinker a drinker if they had a few hours or days of sobriety between drinking. So if ddlg embraces regression in the place of healthy ways of coping, then yes, I think it's unhealthy, destructive, and all-around not good. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30683611183.0" user="NearEmu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No, because "sexualizing A = sexualizing B" is not my logical stance. The logic would be: What makes something a sexualization of children is sexualizing something that is distinctly child-like, not adult-like. Sexualizing adults acting like children is sexualizing something distinctly child-like. Ergo, sexualizing adults acting like children is sexualizing children. 

So sexualizing violence like behavior is sexualizing something violence - like, and sexualizing slavery like behavior is sexualizing slavery.

&amp;gt;No, I don't think consent is justification for doing something. 

I didn't say only consent, the point is about much more than that one sentence, you have to read the entire thing as the full point otherwise picking one bit here and one bit there makes no sense.

It's about the distinction between reality and fakery. Movies and Real life, Imagination and Reality, Play and Not-Play. Consent is one specific portion, safety is another.

&amp;gt;I have heard that defended as safe if the dom knows what he is doing. I only bring that up because diff people have a different understanding of safe. Because I think ddlg is psychologically unhealthy, I think it's psychologically harmful and not safe.

You heard that from bad people. 

The entire concept of BDSM is based upon the foundational idea that BDSM will not negatively affect your life outside of the "allotted time".

&amp;gt;I have heard full regression defended. 

I have heard murder defended, but we don't base our ideas on people that defend extremist minority opinions right?


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30683670444.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So sexualizing violence like behavior is sexualizing something violence -  like, and sexualizing slavery like behavior is sexualizing slavery.

If you want to talk about whether BDSM is unhealthy, there might be another thread for that or we can start one. I only say that to keep this particular thread focused. Regardless, I don't see an issue with the logic.

&amp;gt;I didn't say only consent

That's right, you didn't. You said:

&amp;gt;The difference in all these things boils down to one thing, are the people consenting, and do they understand what they are  consenting to, and is it done thoughtfully and safely between the people  consenting.

To which my response is:

&amp;gt;And because I think it's an unhealthy \[idea\], two people can think through  it as carefully as they can, decide it's unhealthy but consent to it  anyway, and do it as safely as they possibly can and I will still think  it's destructive.

And what I mean by that is that if a behavior is inherently harmful, then no amount of consenting, understanding, thinking, planning, or acting will make it not harmful.

I think that not taking responsibility for oneself is psychologically harmful. Like, understanding the consequences and not taking responsibility anyway doesn't make it any less harmful.

&amp;gt;You heard that from bad people.

But *why?*

&amp;gt;The entire concept of BDSM is based upon the foundational idea that BDSM  will not negatively affect your life outside of the "allotted time".  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;I have heard murder defended, but we don't base our ideas on people that defend extremist minority opinions right?

This is getting off-track, but I want to mention it anyway because it's something that I see in every conversation about bdsm that I've ever been part of. Solely from reading your last post, all I know is that you believe that BDSM is founded on the idea that it will not negatively affect your life outside of the "allotted time" and that you think the destructive thing of full on regression is only practiced by a minority. I have no way of knowing if that's true.

And it doesn't matter because I'm talking about an able-minded person handing over personal decisions to someone else that are part of their responsibilities as an adult to take care of themselves.  That could mean embracing regression but it might not. That's the idea that is such a problem for me. That and child fetishes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30683711482.0" user="NearEmu" delta="False">
    <text>I'll just focus on the last part since it seems like the crux of this will be "you decided it's unhealthy based on reasons that if I question, you say *but why*", if you have decided it's unhealthy based on reasons that I can't argue or you say "I think it's unhealthy" then I don't think i can argue much in that direction.

The idea that BDSM isn't supposed to actually cause true harm is based on every respectable BDSM community that has ever existed. You will find *zero* respectable communities that are okay with actual mental harm being done to people, and you will find *zero* respectable communities that are not strictly in favor of having *alotted* times for play, and full acknowledgement of reality.

You do have a way of knowing that, you can go find the largest and oldest communities, and read what they have to say about it. 

It does matter, because you are basically doing the equivalent of arguing against the Catholic Church, by upholding the Westboro Baptist church as your examples of why it's shitty and harmful.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30683804519.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>I'll tell you why I think ddlg (not bdsm, that's another conversation) is unhealthy. 

Because taking responsibility for personal decisions in one's life is part of psychologically developing into a healthy adult. If you have a partner who makes those decisions for you, you're stunting your psychological growth. If you don't work out that mental muscle, it atrophies. 

I will give you a quotation in the morning from a psychologist that talks about it more so you don't have to take my word for it. I have one in mind, but I need to go to bed. I have some other resources from the field of childhood development, too. That entire field is based on the idea that children go through stages and *eventually grow up*. Going back to an earlier stage of development is like some Benjamin Button-level psychological stuff. 

Freud (who put this idea of age regression into words) thought of it as pathological and part of forming a neurosis (I'll type that citation for you tomorrow, too, but for now the book titles are *A General Introduction to Psychoanalysis* and *New Introductory Lectures on Psycho-Analysis*, both by Freud). Freud was wrong in a lot of ways, but I bring him up because the person who disagreed with him, Jung, valued regression *as long as it was helpful in moving development forward again*. I don't see anything about ddlg that is about moving forward past ddlg to a more adult level of development. 

Again, I'm moving past bdsm to focus on ddlg. 

My question for you is: **why is my view wrong?**</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
