<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="550658674.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/93uiya/cmv_the_ddlg_lifestyle_is_unhealthydestructivenot/">
    <title>CMV: The DDLG lifestyle is unhealthy/destructive/not good</title>
    <original_poster>chakalakawhat</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Super Important Thing:** I will always defend any consenting adult's right to participate in DDLG.

**First reason (applies to non-sexual ddlg and other dom/subs):** I think that an able-minded person relying on someone else to make personal decisions for them is psychologically unhealthy because it means refusing to develop psychologically and handle their adult responsibilities/take care of themselves and puts those responsibilities on someone else.

I think that someone making personal decisions for someone who is mentally able is like the super-ultra version of a codependent relationship.

So it hurts everybody.

**Second reason:** Sexualizing adults acting like children sexualizes children.

I'll compare to how a vlogger transitioning FTM answers the question, “Why transition to be gay?”\*

He says that before he transitioned, men he would date would respond to him as if he were a female when he really wasn’t. Transitioning allows him to be with people who are attracted to the person he actually is and who he is as a man.

My point about ddlg is that daddies are relating to littles as if they were children when they are actually adults. The part of the little that attracts them is the child part. If it wasn’t the child part that attracted them, I don’t see why they wouldn’t just do dom/sub without the age play/regression.

**I'm totally open to other perspectives on this!**

\*Video link: [https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk](https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk) (this person does not endorse my opinion!).

**TL;DR: ddlg is unhealthy because it keeps people in super-ultra codependent relationships instead of growing up and it sexualizes children.**

edited for clarity</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30712775651.0" user="ReedCrawford" delta="False">
    <text>The DDLG subset of BDSM is disgusting. Fetishizing acting like a child or abusing someone like you’re their parents is no different than having a fetish for actual kids. 

I’ve always thought this but it wasn’t until recently that I actually saw it happen this way. I knew someone that was heavily into a DDLG relationship with a guy that always gave me a creepy vibe. Found out in the news he had been arrested for pimping out and selling pictures of his partner’s young daughters to a group of other DDLG people. She disappeared from social media when people that knew them, including me, tried to ask what happened. A few months later she was arrested and convicted for the same crimes. I had no idea those kids were being abused. If you want proof you can Google the name Nicholas White in Cincinnati. 

Then I found out that three kids my aunt and uncle adopted were also sold by their biological mother, who was also into calling her own pimp/boyfriends “Daddy”. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
