<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="550658674.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/93uiya/cmv_the_ddlg_lifestyle_is_unhealthydestructivenot/">
    <title>CMV: The DDLG lifestyle is unhealthy/destructive/not good</title>
    <original_poster>chakalakawhat</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Super Important Thing:** I will always defend any consenting adult's right to participate in DDLG.

**First reason (applies to non-sexual ddlg and other dom/subs):** I think that an able-minded person relying on someone else to make personal decisions for them is psychologically unhealthy because it means refusing to develop psychologically and handle their adult responsibilities/take care of themselves and puts those responsibilities on someone else.

I think that someone making personal decisions for someone who is mentally able is like the super-ultra version of a codependent relationship.

So it hurts everybody.

**Second reason:** Sexualizing adults acting like children sexualizes children.

I'll compare to how a vlogger transitioning FTM answers the question, “Why transition to be gay?”\*

He says that before he transitioned, men he would date would respond to him as if he were a female when he really wasn’t. Transitioning allows him to be with people who are attracted to the person he actually is and who he is as a man.

My point about ddlg is that daddies are relating to littles as if they were children when they are actually adults. The part of the little that attracts them is the child part. If it wasn’t the child part that attracted them, I don’t see why they wouldn’t just do dom/sub without the age play/regression.

**I'm totally open to other perspectives on this!**

\*Video link: [https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk](https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk) (this person does not endorse my opinion!).

**TL;DR: ddlg is unhealthy because it keeps people in super-ultra codependent relationships instead of growing up and it sexualizes children.**

edited for clarity</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30683445282.0" user="Bladefall" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think that an able-minded person relying on someone else to make personal decisions for them is psychologically unhealthy because it means refusing to develop psychologically and handle their adult responsibilities/take care of themselves and puts those responsibilities on someone else.

I get the sense here that you have in mind 24/7-style relationships, where one person always makes all the decisions for their partner. This does not describe all, or even most, DDLG relationships. Most people who are into it tend to only engage in it in the proverbial bedroom, and live most of their lives as two adults in an adult relationship. 

&amp;gt;Sexualizing adults acting like children -&amp;gt; sexualizes children.

There is a fetish called forniphilia; it's when a person is treated like furniture. For example, the submissive will kneel on the ground and the dominant will put her feet on him, using him like a footstool. 

Do you think that this leads to sexualizing furniture?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30683538560.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>Talking about your first point: There is no official entity that decides what is or is not a certain label so I've notice these labels have wonky, constantly changing boundaries. But the relationships I've described do exist and those are the ones I'm interested in talking about. 

I can't take anybody's word for it that the majority of bdsm relationships are like *x* and not like *y* because everyone's experience is different. I don't believe that the majority of ddlg aren't 24/7 relationships because of my own experience. I've never *ever* heard a person talk about their own ddlg relationship as bedroom only, and I'm not new to this scene. 

If a ddlg only exists in the bedroom, then I take "bedroom" to mean "sex." In that case, see reason number 2 for thinking it's unhealthy. 

\------------------------

Just to clarify: I don't think sexualizing adults acting like children **leads to** sexualizing children. I think that sexualizing adults acting like children **actually** sexualizes children. I put the symbol there to avoid confusion from grammar, but I'll go change it lol. 

Your second point: It *could* be sexualizing furniture. 

I'm assuming the reason the person is into treating a person like a footstool is not because the person is furniture-like. They're not sexually attracted to the furniture-ish qualities in someone. Or the complete lack of sentience in their partner. Not attracted to the way their partner is making furniture-ish decisions. 

I assume they're sexually attracted to dehumanizing someone. Which I also think is bad, but in which case would not be sexualizing furniture. 

But let's say that, yes, a person likes to treat their partner like furniture because their partner's spine curves in a certain way that's just like a beautiful vase, etc. That would be sexualizing furniture. Sexualizing furniture is not outlandish. All sorts of created things that fill up space have sexual themes and innuendos.  

But I don't see a problem with sexualizing furniture. Sexualizing children, though--with that, I have a big problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30684011512.0" user="iwillcorrectyou" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I assume they're sexually attracted to dehumanizing someone.

So, if we can draw the distinction between sexualizing furniture and specializing dehumanization, can we not also differentiate between sexualizing children and sexualizing dependence? Because I see DDlg as more about the dependence than the child. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30686664621.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I think distinguishing between the two is good. There are a lot of ways to sexualize dependence. What I don't understand is why someone would choose to sexualize dependence by sleeping with an adult acting like a child when they could do something that doesn't involve anything childish. If a person is sexualizing dependence by sexualizing an adult acting like a child instead of doing something else to fit that purpose, it makes me think that they chose sexualizing an adult acting as a child because they are uniquely attracted to the child part. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687004037.0" user="iwillcorrectyou" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It makes me think that they chose sexualizing an adult acting as a child because they are uniquely attracted to the child part. 

I can totally see where you are coming from here. No matter how you cut it, I believe DDlg can be problematic, but not that it is always problematic. 

There is not that many avenues in mainstream BDSM to achieve that same state of sexualized dependence (or just power play) found in DDlg. Petplay is common enough, but it does not fill the same role as DDlg (it is more dehumanizing). Neither does Master/slave (it is *too* submissive). Often times it is simply easier to adopt the precut roles found in DDlg than to have to work through creating your own unique narrative for why the sub is playing in this manner (sweet+bratty+tease+loving) with the Dom(me). 

So, to make a long post short: I agree that, like in all BDSM, participants need to examine their motivations with a critical eye, but disagree that simply opting for the easy, predefined path of DDlg is always due to being “uniquely attracted to the child part.” </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
