<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="550658674.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/93uiya/cmv_the_ddlg_lifestyle_is_unhealthydestructivenot/">
    <title>CMV: The DDLG lifestyle is unhealthy/destructive/not good</title>
    <original_poster>chakalakawhat</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Super Important Thing:** I will always defend any consenting adult's right to participate in DDLG.

**First reason (applies to non-sexual ddlg and other dom/subs):** I think that an able-minded person relying on someone else to make personal decisions for them is psychologically unhealthy because it means refusing to develop psychologically and handle their adult responsibilities/take care of themselves and puts those responsibilities on someone else.

I think that someone making personal decisions for someone who is mentally able is like the super-ultra version of a codependent relationship.

So it hurts everybody.

**Second reason:** Sexualizing adults acting like children sexualizes children.

I'll compare to how a vlogger transitioning FTM answers the question, “Why transition to be gay?”\*

He says that before he transitioned, men he would date would respond to him as if he were a female when he really wasn’t. Transitioning allows him to be with people who are attracted to the person he actually is and who he is as a man.

My point about ddlg is that daddies are relating to littles as if they were children when they are actually adults. The part of the little that attracts them is the child part. If it wasn’t the child part that attracted them, I don’t see why they wouldn’t just do dom/sub without the age play/regression.

**I'm totally open to other perspectives on this!**

\*Video link: [https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk](https://youtu.be/B-Ty5lok0tk) (this person does not endorse my opinion!).

**TL;DR: ddlg is unhealthy because it keeps people in super-ultra codependent relationships instead of growing up and it sexualizes children.**

edited for clarity</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30685797801.0" user="eadala" delta="False">
    <text>First thing, you need to define what you mean by "DDLG lifestyle." Within your **first reason** section you make some discussion about how adults need to make their own decisions and attend to their own responsibilities, which I think most other well-adjusted adults would agree with you on. *However*, this is imposing an assumption that the DDLG lifestyle includes having the "daddy" make these decisions, e.g. financial, medical, social decisions, and so-on. But to assume that a DDLG lifestyle includes these features by definition is absolutely dead wrong. For instance, the nonsexual aspects of even a 24/7 DDLG lifestyle may include simple things like - say you're the daddy - sitting with your girlfriend while she colors or eats applesauce and watches cartoons to detox from a stressful day of work. There are some very benign forms that DDLG can take, and I think in this way it isn't fair to say that DDLG lifestyle *in general* is unhealthy / destructive, and thus why I think you should change your view.

I also think it's an oversimplification to say that DDLG is a manifestation of co-dependency. I understand the imagery behind a "helpless" little empowering the daddy and making them feel in control, and the imagery behind a stern daddy implying attentiveness and love and how unhealthy the connection between sternness and love can be. But I think it is also wrong to assume that every DDLG couple derives these feelings, or at least seriously cares about them. Many DDLG couples do their thing as a form of multiple-day / week / month long roleplay building to some extremely strong sexual encounters. Many others don't derive sexual pleasure from it. I was with a girl who spent 12 hours a day dealing with pissy customers all the time (ironically, other adults who act like children :P). When she got home, she loved to color or watch kid's cartoons to detox. She liked to suck her thumb, be carried to bed and tucked in. It's in fact because she was *so* responsible, productive, and independent during her day, that she grew to enjoy just having a some hours at night to act like a kid (we play video games, don't we?) and forget all of the trouble. Some couples go much further than this of course, but there are many different forms roleplay can take, not just ageplay, so comparing a 24/7 DDLG arrangement where the daddy controls a bunch of shit... it'd only be fair to compare that to other roleplay themes taken this far like sexy french maid who literally has to clean 8 hours a day. Are either of them unhealthy? Probably. But DDLG isn't the problem; shitty people are the problem. And shitty people have many different kinks.

It would be unhealthy if somebody uses DDLG to escape from actual problems, just like it'd be unhealthy to use working out, video games, drugs, or eating to escape those same problems. It would be unhealthy if somebody used their position in a DDLG role to impart actual control over the other that they did not consent to giving up. Knowing where this line is drawn is tricky, but to say that DDLG is a guaranteed unhealthy or destructive lifestyle is not only an oversimplification, but usually just incorrect. It's basically saying that romantic relationships in general are guaranteed unhealthy or destructive; no, it depends on the nature of that arrangement.

As for your **second reason**, I'm not sure how to reply to this. Obviously if somebody is sexually attracted to children, that is not right. But being attracted to an adult who roleplays as a child is totally different. You said:

&amp;gt;My point about ddlg is that daddies are relating to littles as if they were children when they are actually adults. The part of the little that attracts them is the child part. If it wasn’t the child part that attracted them, I don’t see why they wouldn’t just do dom/sub without the age play/regression. 

You are making a **gigantic** assumption in saying that "the part of the little that attracts them is the child part." Anybody in the community who comes remotely close to outwardly showing signs of pedophilic tendencies are shunned and usually reported. Tons of lingerie comes in the pinkest of pinks, or the tamest baby blues. Ton of lingerie is lacy beyond belief with frills and ruffles and all kinds of stuff going on. It is entirely possible, and quite often the case, that they just like hyper-feminized clothing, hairstyles, makeup, etc., rather than actually being envious of a child's wardrobe. And as for the daddy involved, they may like hyper feminine women.

Essentially you ended the above quote with the following question: If they're not attracted to the child part, why don't they just do dom/sub without the ageplay?

Consider this: ageplay is probably seen as humiliating to most. You would be mortified if you were caught doing it. So the sub can magnify their submission-based sexual pleasure by feeling humiliated as it takes away more power, and in many submissive's brains, the emotion of *embarassment*, which causes deep-ventilated breathing, increased heartrate, and adrenaline, feels very similar to the emotion of *arousal*. In the same way that ropes and blindfolds take away a sub's physical power, humiliation, degredation, and teasing take away their emotional power. Of course this is only right if it's pleasurable and consented upon by both the dom and the sub. As you know a dom/sub relationship often involves controlling the sub in sexual ways. It could be another source of humiliation (read: sexual pleasure) for the sub to have their daddy tell them when they can go to bed. The couple can establish boundaries and say "daddy can send me to bed any time after 10pm", something the sub has to do anyway because she has work at 6am. Boundaries are key.

I'm sorry if you are only interested in talking about the extreme 24/7 "daddy controls literally everything" subcategory of the DDLG lifestyle. But to say that the DDLG lifestyle is bad because of what the extreme 24/7 "daddy controls literally everything" lifestyle *might mean* for either of their mental wellbeings is just not fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30685959574.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>Wow this is a lot of great material, thank you (and everyone) for taking the time to type it out. 

I have to run but I wanted to acknowledge your message. I’ll be back later. 

One thing I do want to clarify, though, is that I’m not only interested in talking about 24/7 relationships. I would love to talk about other relationships that people call ddlg. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30685970608.0" user="eadala" delta="False">
    <text>Sure thing. When you're free, if you reply again it'll ping me and I can respond and answer questions / respond to comments :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30686583116.0" user="chakalakawhat" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, back 😊

This is a lot of good stuff to respond to, so I’ll probably respond in more than one post. 

But the biggest question I’m thinking about as we talk about this is how to talk about something like ddlg that doesn’t have a universally agreed-upon definition.

Convos about ddlg (and bdsm) that I have been part of/have witnessed tend to digress into arguments over what counts as real ddlg. 

Does anybody else struggle with having these conversations?

My opinion on ddlg has way less to do with defining it and way more to do with talking about the relationships that other people label ddlg. So for example if someone says their relationship is ddlg and they want to talk about why they think it’s healthy or unhealthy (and a few ppl have done that already), then I would love to talk about that experience rather than whether it counts as real ddlg. 

But just so we don’t start talking about sharks or something, maybe a loose definition of ddlg could be a relationship between two consenting adults in which one person takes on a caregiving role and the other person takes on a child-like or childish role. 

Just a side note: I used the words “ddlg lifestyle” in my main post because I thought it would be a broad term, not a term that is talking about 24/7-only relationships. Is saying “ddlg lifestyle” misleading and if so, do you know of a different phrase that works? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30686753285.0" user="eadala" delta="False">
    <text>People dispute the definitions of things with absolute definitions as well. It's hopeless hahaha no worries you're in the norm for struggling with these talks.

One of the problems is, exactly as you alluded to, people can get very defensive or authoritative about what their kink means, just like they can get elitist about video games, politics, etc. It's just another part of life that we put way too much effort into fighting over.

The way I try to work around this, and tried with you, is asking you what *you* meant by DDLG lifestyle. At the end of my first post I noted that the 24/7 style is a "subcategory" of what most would consider the "lifestyle." When you say the BDSM lifestyle, we know that can take many distinct forms and has no concrete definition. Usually, as with most other things, the trick is to keep an open mind. If they're talking about why their thing is right or some other thing is wrong, always try to frame it with them. Constructively discuss what details in particular they are confused / grossed out / interested in; for example, if someone says, "I don't know, all of that little kid shit just grosses me out", one can very carefully reply with something like "what about it grosses you out?" Then they can elaborate and say things like: the roleplaying, the coloring, the spanking, and so-on, and you can point-by-point better reply and understand what's upsetting them.

I didn't mean to get us caught up in definitions; I would be a hypocrite to try to tell *you* what a DDLG lifestyle means. I just wanted to make a point that there are some very harmless, and some harmful, variants of the lifestyle just as there are with any other kink-based lifestyle. It isn't misleading to say DDLG lifestyle, but the word "lifestyle" *usually* implies some form of long-term or continuing embracing of it. But if you are trying to refer to an individual who only does ageplay for 30 minutes at night as a conduit for sexual play, it might be more accurate to refer to them as having DDLG kinks or moods (e.g. "I'm in a DDLG mood tonight"). Either way I don't think you're really upsetting anybody, but it can get confusing!

Your definition works in the same sense that a definition of "run" in the dictionary works. It's certainly *a* definition of it, but as I've been droning on about, DDLG in and of itself is a huge category that serves as an identifier like meat or vegetables, rather than beef or broccoli.

If you were to ask me, I would say DDLG is a type of either sexual or nonsexual roleplay that involves a man (or woman roleplaying as a man) behaving like a paternal figure in some manner of ways, and the woman (or man roleplaying as a woman) behaving like a child in some manner of ways - summarized succinctly by the term "ageplay." The exact nature of how these paternal and childlike behaviors manifest is as varied as each individual, but the uniting factor is that the paternal figure is the dom and the child is the sub. And of course, not only the means, but the frequency and extremity to which the couple exercises their DDLG kinks / moods / lifestyle is also incredibly varied. And so as to not pigeonhole, if my memory serves me right, MDLB = Mommy Dom / Little Boy, which is the gender-flipped version. Of course there's DDLB and MDLG but I hope nobody feels left out when I simplify to the most commonly used abbreviation (other fun fact: if both parties prefer to act like children, just throw around LB / LG as many times as makes sense).

There are a few distinct ways DDLGs do their thing. One common theme is that the DD is stern and forceful. From here, it's a question of whether the DD is also mean / demeaning, or loving and caring. Some like to just have sexual encounters as usual, but the woman enjoys saying "daddy" and being spanked and that's it. Perhaps this is the lightest version of DDLG you see, but it is insanely common. Some like to roleplay breaking the 4th wall - that the DD and the LG are aware that they are adults and that the LG is humiliating herself with her kink, or alternatively that the DD is forcing the LG to humiliate herself when they both know she's a grown woman. This is very popular and yet another reason why I want to emphasize that there is absolutely zero explicit connection between ageplay and pedophilia. The couple could just really be into humiliation, and ageplay is a damn good way to go about that. Or they could just really be into cute clothes. Also a fun thing to consider: women in pop culture have been roleplaying the "innocent girl" since the dawn of TV. Men and women just love this dynamic, where the sexy librarian or cheerleader isn't aware that she's sexy, or the "virgin" is acting innocent and confused. A twist that popped up in the 80s and 90s all the time was the teenage boy doesn't know that the hot mom is hitting on him until the end of the episode. Of course I don't mean to exclude other couples here - just trying to draw some connections to the conventional DDLG setup and pop culture. Having the LG act innocent and cute is a turn-on for some.

The DDLG community is one of the most fascinating and refreshing. Their tumblrs are often crowded with long-winded messages about how wearing a goofy little dress or sucking on a pacifier makes being alone after a breakup give them peace and confidence. They often send out posts discussing what is and is not okay behavior from your DD, and tips on how a DD can be a more engaging and understanding partner for their LG. Of course there are extremes and jerks everywhere, but on average I see nothing but positivity and consent from this group of people. Be warned: there are also a lot of pages dedicated to roleplaying an extreme lifestyle, and here you will find pretty shocking captions about control, humiliation, etc. But those are typed by the fingers of a horny person and hopefully not to be taken seriously.

Little anecdote here. Any time someone brings up a kink with me, of course I try to keep an open mind. If the ageplay is happening because the man or woman had a damaged childhood or whathaveyou, provided they are not actively trying to hide from an adult life, this is perfectly fine. I know one woman who as a toddler had the pacifier smacked out of her mouth by having her cheek slapped because her mother wanted her to "grow out of it." Later in therapy she was told it's basically harmless (but watch out for your teeth!), and the fact that she has stable employment, is pursuing an education, has an active and positive group of friends, and isn't physiologically addicted to the pacifier, and it isn't getting in the way of her professional life - these are all bits of reasoning to support the idea that it doesn't matter if DDLG is used as escapism or therapy, so long as both parties understand, and both parties aren't using it for unhealthy reasons. She uses a pacifier when she's getting nervous. Maybe she never grew out of it, but she is a grown up :)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
