<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30688063868.0" user="baconaran" delta="False">
    <text>As someone with a geology degree and someone who recently purchased a diamond ring to propose, I was also sceptical about over paying into an artificially created diamond market.

I am well aware of how De Beers has manipulated the market for diamonds, and pushed their desire into our society through very clever marketing tactics. "diamonds are forever" "diamonds are a girl's best friend" even the tradition of proposing with a diamond ring which is a very young tradition. 

But here is why I choose to go with a diamond.

First of all anything only has the value that we put on it, even currency. There are a limited amount of natural diamonds on Earth. In fact the youngest diamond is over 900 million years old, with most being much older than that. The necessary conditions for diamonds to rapidly rise to the surface while staying at stable pressures and temperatures likely do not exist anymore. Of these diamonds very few are of gem quality and many go onto industrial uses. When you get them certified you can see the inclusion color clarity gradings and if it is flourcent. There is a non linear relationship for these scales, so there are exponentially fewer high grade diamonds than average ones which is why the price rises non-linearly with size and grade.

In a sense when you buy a diamond you are investing in a part of that market. De Beers will do everything they can to keep this market stable, including investing in technology to flood the market with lab made diamonds to keep the value of natural diamonds high and limiting the supply of natural diamonds. It's kind of like investing in these diamond companies because they have a gigantic interest in keeping the market where it is. With any scarce resource, there is a demand and a limited supply leading to their value. But unlike commodities like gold, not all diamonds are made the same. A perfectly clear flawless diamond is far more valuable than the average diamond with yellow hints and inclusions. While you may not be able to tell from a distance, the nicer diamond will always be more valuable than the average ones. Now of course you don't want to tie all you money up in diamonds, but owning one isn't such a bad idea, it will always have value, just like other scarce commodities.

My fiance also said she was fine with diamond "substitutes" but it is just not the same. I can tell she is much happier that I went with a diamond and not something else and I think this would be the case for most women (though I'm sure she would have been happy either way). In fact if you are not getting a diamond I would highly recommend you don't try and get something that looks like a diamond, get another gemstone if you go that route, because any other substitutes trying to be a diamond will never measure up or be the real thing (and what message does that send). They reflect light in a very unique way. Take a hand lense to a shop (or ask for one at the shop) and really spend some time looking at the diamonds for inclusions and color. You can get a good deal if you are patient and educate yourself about the market. It's not completely made up, or it wouldn't exist. Most diamonds pushed in mall stores (even the big name chains) are total scams and rely on uninformed consumers not knowing the difference between a good diamond and a bad one. I would highly recommend getting a certified diamond, and buying the diamond by itself and then having it set into a ring. You can find better deals online or through diamond suppliers than in any brick and mortar jewelry store.

 It would take some major social upheaval to to ruin the diamond market and if you are really worried about that then you might be better off proposing with a rifle and a kilo of coke because those things will never lose their value. I know that I want to be with my fiance forever and I know that a diamond is a timeless classic (and a gem that I didn't have in my rock/mineral collection) that will hold it's sentimental value even if it doesn't completely hold it's monetary value. Most women don't want to replace or upgrade their engagemnet ring so think about what you want on your wife's finger in 10 years or 20 years or 30 years.  When i bought my diamond I actually made money on the purchase (it was appraised for much higher than I paid). You just need to know what to look for and be patient. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688703779.0" user="Gefilte_Fish" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In a sense when you buy a diamond you are investing in a part of that market.

How will you make money or even break even on reselling a diamond? If you sell to the industry, you are only selling one diamond, and they will need to turn a profit to make it worthwhile. So they won't give you what you paid. If you sell to a private party, they will most likely be looking for a deal. If you sell via a 3rd party, they will take a sizable commission. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688851972.0" user="xR3B3Lx" delta="False">
    <text>Not only that, but you don't *make money* in the act of spending money. The purchased diamond would need to be *resold* at a higher price after accounting for inflation and other factors (such as investing that same money elsewhere and receiving interest or dividends), and based on what's been said it certainly doesn't sound like that diamond is going anywhere anytime soon. So, I'm also confused about how money has been made simply by purchasing it for less than its appraised value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688896989.0" user="AtomAndAether" delta="False">
    <text>They have a geology degree, not economics. Its a praise of the rock and the justification all hobbyists use when spending way too much on something.

The idea is that its a veblen good - an item whose demand raises with its price simply because people buy it as a status symbol because exclusivity. Watches, pens, cars, gems, etc.

Everyone buys in at ridiculous price points, and the non-elite justify it by talking about re-sell value. Then they hold it their entire life instead of, say, just investing the money. Then they die. Then their children pawn it for a third what they originally paid, losing the third they did get to inflation.

The only people who make money on veblen reselling to any significant degree are serious collectors.

Additional edit: On a more positive side, there is a range in all of these fields of some seriously good quality, and while reselling for profit is not to be expected you can resell for a lot less depreciation than other fields no problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689025871.0" user="xR3B3Lx" delta="False">
    <text>Nor do I have an economics degree, but that is irrelevant to the conversation, as an appeal to authority or lack of it. However, I should note that the reference to a geology degree was meant to increase the original commenter's authority discussing the topic. The person provided reasons from personal experience that moved him to make a diamond purchase *and* provided such reasons as a potential way of convincing OP that buying a diamond can be worthwhile. Had it simply been an anecdotal explanation, fine, but when it veers into the realm of argumentation for a product (and it clearly did), then counter-arguments can be expected, especially on a subreddit devoted to argumentation.

Therefore, it's entirely appropriate to point out that no money was made by the person purchasing a diamond, since the only flow of money was to the seller; as well, his description of keeping a particular gemstone for "10, 20, 30 years" makes it seem that he doesn't even have resale in mind, thus invalidating his claim that he made money as well as the implication that purchasing a diamond could be seen as a money-making investment.

The original commenter did not mention resell value; it would be a different story if he had. He said that he "made money" *on the purchase* because it was under the appraisal price. Simply paying less does not equate to receiving money, regardless of whether we're discussing Veblen goods or those that follow more standard supply-and-demand practices. Even if this is passed off as simply a form of rationalization, that doesn't mean the rationalization is actually correct, only that it causes the buyer to feel happier with and more confident in his purchase.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689086031.0" user="AtomAndAether" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't intending for the degree thing to sound like such a jab, just that his view would be great for talking about how great diamonds are versus non-diamonds but then transition to why I disagree on it being an investment in the market it exists.

To the point, "making money" on a purchase by holding it for 10, 20, 30 years is exactly what entails veblen reselling or the hobbyist "its an investment". I'm not talking about the flipping type of reselling where you'd buy an Xbox on a big sale and then sell it for just under original price, or early investment reselling where you might back a kickstarter and resell for higher. I'm talking buying a $400 Montblanc fountain pen in 1994, using it your entire life, and then trying to sell it for $800 in 2084 because it is no longer made and those 2084 pens are "just no good" compared to those sweet pre-2000 pens or whatever.

Under the idea that you could resell in this way, due to it being a zero-sum thing and demand will rise as it becomes more exclusive and a status symbol, then you did essentially "make" $400 by spending $400 following sub-thread OP's phrasing.

I was just jumping in to bolster your argument. In that, you're right, its a bad move to think you're making money purely on speculation of resell.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689233278.0" user="xR3B3Lx" delta="False">
    <text>I see; I see! Now I feel like a fool for misunderstanding what you communicated. Thanks for reiterating your thoughts! I think we're in agreement for the most part.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689404429.0" user="AtomAndAether" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, we are in agreement. I was just adding against the idea of diamonds being better than non-diamonds on the basis of investment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690144825.0" user="baconaran" delta="False">
    <text>Diamonds have actually increased about 4-6% a year for several decades now, while at the same time De Beers has gone from 90% market control to \~30% market control in the last 40 or so years. As I said in the original post as well, diamonds are a finite resource, and the conditions for natural diamond formation in the earth that we can technically recover (read kimberlite formations) likely don't exist anymore. Every diamond can be put on a scale from industrial grade to museum quality, and evaluated as such. So if you buy a high quality diamond, there will only be so many other diamonds that can compare to it.  


The diamond supply output has actually been dropping in recent years, and demand has been increasing as more countries and peoples acquire a taste for luxury goods. This combined with the quality relationship between diamonds that make it hard to compare a J SI2 diamond to a D VS1 diamond, slightly breaks the description of a diamond as a veblen good (though an argument could be made both ways imo) Just as not all cars are veblen goods but a Ferrari would be considered one, or not every handbag is veblen but a Hermes Birkin is almost the gold standard of veblen, not every diamond falls into this category.   


Obviously I didn't buy my engagement ring as an investment to make money off of and I have no intention of selling it, but if you buy a good quality diamond at the right price, it isn't actually the worst investment. Most diamonds are just sold at extremely marked up rates and rely on consumers not being informed enough about the diamond market to know that they are getting ripped off. Most people see carat size and price and don't look much further. Even the GIA/AGS grading system doesn't tell the entire story, you really need to look at and inspect it to make sure you are getting a good deal.  
some links:  
[De Beers market control](http://www.kitco.com/ind/Zimnisky/2013-06-06-A-Diamond-Market-No-Longer-Controlled-By-De-Beers.html)  
 [historic diamond prices](https://www.petragems.com/education/diamond-prices-and-trends-over-the-years/)  
 [graph](https://www.statista.com/statistics/279053/worldwide-sales-of-polished-diamonds/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690070417.0" user="baconaran" delta="False">
    <text>"make money on the buy" is an expression not to be taken literally. I've heard it mostly used in the context of real estate when you buy a house well below market value. Even if the market takes a downturn, you could get out of your investment ahead, as opposed to buying something with the prospect of it eventually increasing in value. In a similar vein, my fiance bought an authentic Tiffany's necklace for 5$ at a garage sale and "made money on the buy" even though she never sold it because she wares it, and in reality all we did was spend 5$ on it. That said if I were to insure my ring, and my fiance were to lose it, I would get back more money then I paid for it originally. (ignoring the price of insurance)  


I clearly have no intention of selling the diamond or the ring, and certainly did not buy it with the intention of making money on it. The social and personal value that the ring has, outweighs the monetary investment I put into it imo. I don't think the value of diamonds in our society will take a big dip any time soon, and I don't think my fiance will value her ring any less in the future, so it retains its investment through non monetary means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690130991.0" user="xR3B3Lx" delta="False">
    <text>You know, that's completely fair. Knowing that you meant it like that is helpful; as well, I was previously unaware of the term *making money on the buy*, though the concept is easy enough to handle and fairly self-evident, so thanks for teaching that term to me.

The reason I responded as I did is because there are a number of instances anecdotally in which people have rationalized purchases because of a sale or special offer (e.g., clothing sales, limited-time offers on phones, etc.), when they in fact regretted that purchase afterward or otherwise maintained a habit of unhealthy expense. When it comes to people spending money in general, I don't usually care how others spend their money; I don't control others' personal expenditures, and they don't control mine. I recognize that people have different values, and that's fine. It's when people rationalize a purchase in ways that don't make sense that I tend to get more antsy, though I  now understand better where you're coming from due to your helpful follow-up.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
