<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30690168769.0" user="trunks111" delta="False">
    <text>I think your argument is more "in my case a diamond is a waste of money" and you'd probably be right. If you're just starting a life with someone and aren't already well off, then save every buck you can, you'll need it. And if she truly loves you she shouldn't care all that much whether you spent $1900 or $700 so much as that you spent the time and thought trying to pick something you think she'll like and wear. 

To adress the argument as a whole, one mans trash is another mans treasure. If you're well off or have connections (my dad has been in pawn for 20+ years for example and I could probably get a discount if I *really* wanted to), or if you really just like the look of something more, then it isn't a waste of money bc it's not a burden and you/your partner like whatever it is you're getting. I personally love sapphire and amethyst which are relatively cheap. Some people might like white gold or platinum, some might like diamond or pearl or opal. To each their own</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
