<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687605675.0" user="xiipaoc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

Try about a century ago.

But to answer your main point, diamonds are *not* a complete waste of money.  Maybe they're not worth it for *you*, but the hardness of diamonds is actually very useful in certain kinds of drills, for example.  For diamonds in jewelry, yeah, they're only expensive as a status symbol, but... people *like* status symbols.  Some of them do, anyway.  The idea is that you wear the ring with the diamond or whatever and brag about how rich you are.  Some people care about that sort of thing.  It's not a waste of money for them.  Now, I think this is stupid.  But I guess I'm not the target audience.

The fake diamond gem you mentioned, the moisanitte, is also problematic.  What's the point of *that*?  Diamonds are worth a lot of money not because of how they look but because diamond companies have decided that they should be, so if you have a fake diamond, you're essentially lying, at least unless you explain what the stone is.  The diamond, as a status symbol, communicates something that isn't true here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687707368.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding the status symbols, I get it. Hell, if I was stupidly rich this wouldn't even be a consideration (although if I spent all my money on overly expensive diamonds I'd have a hard time ever being rich). The fact is that they only have value while we believe they have value. As soon as that belief falters they will plummet. 

Regarding your second point though, it's a common misconception that a moissanite is a "fake diamond". It's actually a completely different gem that just looks almost identical. This is an important definition, because I do not plan to ever try to pass it off as a fake diamond. The reason I would get one is because it's still pretty and an engagement ring is still a bit of a staple. If I thought that another gem would look better in the engagement ring, I would buy that one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687718887.0" user="xiipaoc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's actually a completely different gem that just looks almost identical.

That's the definition of a fake diamond, is it not?  Completely different but looks almost identical?  But if all you care about is the aesthetics, then sure.  I mean, I don't think *anyone* should be buying diamonds at those hyper-inflated prices, but the people who do have reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687786103.0" user="ixanonyousxi" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The fact is that they only have value while we believe they have value. As soon as that belief falters they will plummet. 
  
  
You can say this about most things in our economy.  Paper money is utilitarianly useless, its only valuable because we as a society agree that its valuable.

Facebook lost over billions of dollars in value,  not because it was broken, damaged, or useless, but because we agreed as a society that its worth less. Heck nothing really changed about the site in the time period it dropped. 

A house can be worth 300k one day and if the market crashes itll be worth only 100k, even though nothing about the materials or layout has changed.

As with most things in society,  things are worth not what you can use them for but how much someone is willing to pay for it. Diamonds arent exempt from that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
