<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30688106851.0" user="geniice" delta="False">
    <text>"moissonite" is as much of a marketing thing as diamonds. 

The catch is that Moissanite strictly refers to natural silicon carbide crystals. They are rare, small and unless you are prepared to pay on a level that makes diamonds look cheap your girlfriend isn't getting one.

What you are refering to is Charles &amp;amp; Colvard Moissanite. A 4H polymorph of silicon carbide.

Why does this matter? By preferring the marketing term rather than a simple description (say crystaline silicon carbide) it shows you attach value to marketing. By chosing a misleading marketing term (instead of say Amora Gem) is shows you value misleading marketing over more direct branding. 

As for why diamonds are valuable the core reasons are that they have been a popular gem for a long time and were one of the hardest to synthesise. Commercial production of Ruby goes back to the first decade of the 19th century. Competitively priced production of jewellery grade diamonds has only been around for a few years. De beers marketing has of course added to that but there are some fairly solid issues behind it.

Of course I'm an advocate for Gimmal rings rather than using stones at all so meh. Get some synthetic ekanite and be somewhat original (may make going through airports tricky mind).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
