<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687913569.0" user="btrner" delta="False">
    <text>I’m going to preface this by saying I got a moissanite ring for my soon to be fiancé. We talked about it a lot and decided the price of a Diamond was not worth it as the quality of the moissanite we found far exceed any diamond. We felt much better spending that money on a custom platinum setting. 

That being said, I think anything can be deemed a complete waste of money. Go to r/frugal and they’ll tell you to buy a nice commuter car cuz why would you ever need anything else. 

As for diamonds, their value is inherently integrated in US society (Thanks DeBeers) and that’s what justifies the price. Diamonds value comes from the clout bestowed upon it in society. 

You’re 100% right that if society flipped on its head, a lot of people would have lost substantial value in their diamonds, but since that is unlikely to happen, diamonds retain a level of valuation that is quite frankly ridiculous. 

Another example, US currency has no backing other than the US government. If the US were to fall, then all the paper would be worth nothing (just like Greece’s debt crisis a year ago) however, US currency is valued because of the clout bestowed upon the nation. (Not the greatest example, as it vastly over simplifies international currency but a gist)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
