<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687504209.0" user="Chronic_Apathy1" delta="False">
    <text>You're right that from any objective standpoint, diamonds aren't really worth anything. In fact, between the ability to create artificial diamonds and the artificially shortage that diamond companies create, any logical observer would conclude that spending so much money on a diamond is absurd. Except, we aren't really logical creatures, and whether it's because of clever marketing or some other influence, the fact of the matter is we as a society place a lot of value on diamonds.

So let me ask you a question: If you do decide to buy a moissanite ring, are you going to tell your girlfriend (hopefully fiance!) what it is, or are you going to let her believe it's a real diamond? Is there any kind of worry on your part that if you do tell her, she'll react negatively, even if she understands?

Things are worth what we believe they're worth. We put immense value on "real" jewelry made of pearls, silver, gold, and the like, even though it offers very little advantage to convincing fakes, because we *like* that it's genuine. Even if the value is ultimately artificial, there's an argument to be made that you can't put a price on that, even if it's not logical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687515841.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>Why would she feel any different if it was real or not? It’s a token of his love. Unless it’s not really about that right? 

Don’t listen to these ppl OP. Go with the fake. They make really good ones that won’t wear out. 


If she checks it out, she wasn’t the one anyway. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687533229.0" user="Chronic_Apathy1" delta="False">
    <text>That logic works both ways. If he isn't willing to buy an expensive ring, he isn't the one anyway.

She's going to wear this ring on her finger for the rest of her life. He's not even talking about buying a better ring at the same cost, he's talking about spending less than half of what he was already prepared to spend. It is very likely that she has been told from a very young age that the engagement ring matters. That it is the ultimate symbol of his love and devotion for her. I've known a lot of very thrifty, down-to-earth women who believe that engagement/marriage is the time to spend big. We can bitch and moan about it being a bullshit cultural thing all we want, but the point remains that for some women, it's a very important thing they've been dreaming about for their entire lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687545959.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>If he doesn’t tell her, how will she know?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687552163.0" user="not_vichyssoise" delta="False">
    <text>That's not exactly a great reason lie to your fiance/spouse.

If it's a token of love, why would you misrepresent what it is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687560326.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>You’re not, it’s a token. You aren’t misrepresenting because you actually love her. You are lying because it saves you real money on something that only costs so much because it’s been artificially inflated to be that way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687573918.0" user="not_vichyssoise" delta="False">
    <text>So if it doesn't matter what the token is since it's only a token, why the deception regarding the material it is made of?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687611927.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Just for reference, I'm definitely going to tell her :)

I wouldn't want to start out on a lie.

In answer to your question though, most jewellers (store-fronts) would not be able to tell the difference. Apparently it is almost instantly obvious to anyone that actually deals with gems regularly (gemologist?). I think it has something to do with the way the light is refracted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687568313.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>I do agree with you on that, it could go both ways. Foe reference, yes I will proudly tell my partner that I bought her a Moissanite ring. I didn't mention it in the original post but I'm trying to stick to a budget. In order to do this, I can buy a basic ring with an actual diamond or have a custom made ring with a Moissanite.

I much prefer the idea of putting actual thought and care into what I choose to give her and making it something that only she has, rather than just being about how much I spent on the diamond.

If she was the type to say "you didn't buy an expensive ring, you're not the one" then I wouldn't love her as much as I do. On the other hand, if I thought that her checking out the ring makes her "not the one" then that would be hypocritical. As I said, I will proudly tell her that I made a decision based on what is best for our future, while still providing her with a gorgeous, custom piece of jewellery.

Thanks for the reply!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687605104.0" user="ImmortalBach" delta="False">
    <text>You can buy vintage, that way its real and you can ensure it's not a blood diamond</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687539063.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>OP should NOT try to trick her. Starting your marriage off on a lie, a lie that she will wear on her finger every single day of their marriage, is a horrible idea. If, as you say, for her to be the right women for OP then she shouldn't care about the gemstone, then on the same token he should be able to tell her the truth about what stone it is up front and she wouldn't care rather than OP trying to sneak a lie by her. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687543311.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>Ok then just don’t ever proclaim that it’s real OP. Then it’s not a lie. Win-win right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687547023.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>A lie by omission is still dishonest and sneaky. It does not make for a healthy relationship. Why are you so opposed to OP just telling her what kind of ring it is? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687568555.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>Because he can use the money somewhere else on something that isn’t artificially expensive (a vacation for him and his new fiancé?) and even if it’s not a real diamond, his love for her is real, and that’s what the ring is supposed to represent right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687626380.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Spot on here, although I don't have to lie about it so it's still a win-win.

I'd much rather spend the money on a holiday for the two of us, a house deposit or something that will be more meaningful</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687679125.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>There you go man. Don’t let them change your mind. You can do a lot with the money. 

If anything maybe rethink the whole engagement thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687726868.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Hahahahahahahahaha

I love the tenacity! Still gonna get engaged, but your heart is in the right place haha

Mostly because it'll just be easier to tell people she's my wife, rather than my partner. It makes things like joint bank accounts and wills and stuff heaps easier too. Oh, and it's important for her ;)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687734288.0" user="ElBlancoDiablo22" delta="False">
    <text>Haha It’s just a bad contract man. That’s all I’m saying. 

Good luck to you and your new fiancé though :) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687543523.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>OP, just talk to your girlfriend about this. If you are about to spend the rest of your life with her you should be able to have conversations about these things. Many couples pay for engagement rings together. If diamonds mean that much to her maybe she'll be willing to pitch in and pay for some of it and/or use your combined wedding fund to pay for some of it. It doesn't have to fall all on you. It's her ring to wear for the rest of her life so it should be the ring she wants, and there's no reason she shouldn't help pay for it too. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687579240.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>First off, thanks for your reply!

We have discussed it and she is fine without a diamond. It's just that the way the store was talking made it sound like her ring was going to look like something from wallmart if it didn't have a real diamond.

My research led me to understand that diamonds are massively over-priced and there is no real reason for this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687595409.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>Well those sales representatives are of course paid to sell the most expensive ring they can squeeze out of you. And beyond that, they probably do genuinely believe that they are saying because they are the type of people who like jewelry so much that they got a job at a jewelry store. Shallowness and wedding traditions are their bread and butter. They're probably super traditional people who really do value that stuff. But their values don't necessarily reflect your values.

As for myself, I think diamonds are unethical. They pretty much can't be sources ethically unless they come from Canada, which makes them double in cost than diamonds that come from Africa, which are already double in cost from non diamond rings. However, when my husband and I announced our engagement we were given a family heirloom diamond ring that we didn't realize was coming our way. So I do have diamonds, which were undoubtedly blood diamonds when they were new, but by reusing it we have figuratively washed the blood from them. Be sure to ask around both families if there are any family heirloom pieces of jewelry that you could melt down and redesign into a new custom ring. Ours was a total and very welcome surprise. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687622599.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, the history of diamonds is another good reason not to buy them. It's just not something I wanted to debate in this thread because I'm sure we all agree on that, so I left it out of the original post.

I had considered melting down jewellery but for reasons I'd rather not discuss it's definitely not an option for us from either side of the family.

I do have some jewellery that was bought for me when I was born that I never wear, I thought it would be very meaningful for me to get that added to it. I'll have to see how I go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687680478.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>It's probably cheaper to get an antique diamond on eBay if it's a loose diamond rather than a ring. You could then take that antique loose diamond and meld it with your own old jewelry (assuming it's gold jewelry or something like that) and make a great meaningful ring that way! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687574178.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the reply.

I probably should have mentioned in the post that I will \*not\* be tricking her. I would never do that. I'll tell her straight up that it's not a diamond.

The point of the post was more about the value of diamonds themselves, as opposed to whether or not I should buy one. A strong argument could change my view though, hence CMV :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687738401.0" user="smellinawin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Go with the fake.

This is the only reason not to buy the moissanite stone. If you or your wife think of it as fake. This devalues it in your own mind and would make a special ring become less special.

But if you can view it not as a fake ring, but in fact as a superior version of a crappy diamond ring you would have otherwise had, then the value increases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687823541.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I've mentioned in other areas of this thread that it's not a fake diamond, it's a different gem that looks almost exactly like a diamond but doesn't cost anywhere near as much. Very different to a fake diamond in my mind.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688065765.0" user="QuinnLord" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Things are worth what we believe they're worth.


Exactly, and the belief that diamonds are worth anything was conjured up by Browns - the engagement ring company. People buy martinis that have had a diamond "steep" in them... Advertising, idiocy and too much money does not equal value </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689015933.0" user="Chronic_Apathy1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Advertising, idiocy and too much money does not equal value

They literally do, though.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
