<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687496842.0" user="Zeknichov" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about how logical you can make this. It's about how your girlfriend feels. You are buying her a gift afterall because you like her and want to make her happy so what is important is how she will feel over having received the gift. Some women do like diamonds more than any other gemstone for X reason and while X reason might very well be a bad reason trying to convince her that it's a bad reason and she should like the gemstone you bought her more instead because your reasons are better than hers isn't really going to go over very well. In life, when dealing with people and emotions it's not always about being right.

Bring her shopping at a mall and just happen to stop by a jewelry store then lead her into a few questions about gemstones. She'll tell you how she feels and if she's smart she'll realize you're feeling her out for a gift so she'll lead you in the right direction. If you listen to her carefully and select something you know she'll like it will go a lot further than trying to rationalize what you think she should like based on some logic you've posted on Reddit </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687587184.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the response! 

To clarify, we've had a discussion about it and she's happy with a Moissanite. This post is more about the cost of diamonds compared to the quality when compared with other gems.

I'm also really curious to hear what reasoning people have for the preference as I just can't work it out in my head.

Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687598587.0" user="Zeknichov" delta="False">
    <text>Now apply my answer to if she wanted a diamond. Now the price might actually be worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687656118.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>I still only partly agree. The actual worth of a diamond is over-inflated because people have been tricked into thinking that "diamonds are forever" and all that. So if she was set on a diamond, I would buy one for her because I want her to be happy. However I would still see them as a waste of money.

Generally, if you spend a lot more, you expect to get a lot more. In this case, I really just dont feel that you do. I guess I'm just really lucky that my partner and I share the same values.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687820401.0" user="beartankguy" delta="False">
    <text>I guess it's how people will pay a lot for branded clothes while the actual quality of the fabric won't be worth the exorbitant price increase. Diamonds are basically a 'brand' but the difference is somehow they've convinced many women (and men) that there are no alternatives to diamonds and you must have one. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687939986.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>I actually struggle there as well. I will only buy name brand clothing if it is actually better than the rest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30705758159.0" user="jisusdonmov" delta="False">
    <text>In most cases it actually is. Though as I replied to this guy below, “better” is a wrong term. So is “branded”, to be fair, as *every* piece of clothing is branded. You’d have to be more specific 😊. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688533881.0" user="dopkick" delta="False">
    <text>Some brands do have better weaves of cloth for their clothing. How much that’s worth is subjective and personal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30705646268.0" user="jisusdonmov" delta="False">
    <text>Please don’t make comments about things you don’t really have good experience with. 

This is not the place for me to expand, but I’ll just let you consider these four things: 

* serious branded clothes are often very expensive to produce, at least more expensive than you’d think it is

* it is very expensive to sell (from design and marketing, to rent, to creating experience)

* it is undeniably of a better quality than cheap clothing

* cheap clothing manufacturers make considerably larger profits than luxury brands (see Inditex, Fast Retailing Group, H&amp;amp;M). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30705714990.0" user="beartankguy" delta="False">
    <text>You know why it is very expensive to sell? Because they have to convince you to spend too much on clothes. 

The quality will be higher but not 5x or 20x or 50x better than low grade stuff in 99% of cases. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30705754173.0" user="jisusdonmov" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I know why, and you don’t. So again, I don’t see you actually willing to learn from your comments, so just stop talking in an authoritative tone about things you have very little understanding of. 

“Better” is not the right term, as it means different things to different people. But there absolutely are items that are produced with 50x more effort than others. 

And that’s without even opening a can of worms about why the stuff that’s 50x cheaper is so cheap, that’s a conversation you’d really be smart to avoid unless you want to feel pretty miserable about boasting to make certain choices you do when it comes to clothing (at least if you consider yourself a somewhat empathetic, considerate human being). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30706033487.0" user="beartankguy" delta="False">
    <text>50x more effort put into it does not equal 50x "higher quality"

I'm aware of third world exploitation but that is an entirely separate topic. 

In my opinion very cheap clothing is good enough quality for most people and people place higher value on branding and marketing than they do about quality of fabric or the piece. I'd exclude some things like shoes that you use heavily but generally that is my opinion. 

But i'll take what you say in mind, I would have assumed the fancier brands were just ripping people off more but they seem to have fair reason to be that way based off your comment and I'll believe that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30706167757.0" user="jisusdonmov" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t say it does. It reflects the pricing point to an extent, but if effort and craft is valuable to you - that’s up to you. But to say there’s no difference (“exorbitantly” overpriced) is disingenuous. 

And very cheap clothing, mostly, is good enough if all you want is to cover your body, no doubt about it. 

But your original post was something else completely. 

It is also true that people put a lot of value in the brand, but bare in mind that in order for the brand to be worth that value it cannot let people down in quality, even if it’s not something people care about themselves. In a way, a brand has to earn that trust before it can “overprice”. 

There are no luxury brands that came out and made a big name for themselves through marketing alone while making cheap uninspired goods.

I’m glad you’re keeping an open mind, luxury goods (fashion in particular) have so much misinformed and prejudiced opinion amongst “normal” people, it’s often hard to discuss 😄. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687891270.0" user="BommbVoyage" delta="False">
    <text>Are you familiar with the concept of a veblen good? Your girlfriend (and other women) want diamonds *because* they are expensive and make them feel like you are really interested in them if your willing to waste that much cash just to make them happy. If you think spending thousands on a shiny rock just to prove to your girlfriend you really like her is silly and a bad idea your right, but it's going to be an uphill battle to convince her of that unless she's super cool.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Veblen_good</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688033688.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>Fortunately for me, she is super cool.

Thanks for the article, I'll check it out as soon as I can! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688686805.0" user="LittleWing0802" delta="False">
    <text>FWIW, I asked my now-husband for a sapphire, and we split the cost (it was soon to be shared money anyway, right?). He still surprised me with a proposal.
I don’t give a damn about diamonds, and additionally they’re not always ethically sourced. 

Not a comment to change your view but to provide balance for the comments.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687935768.0" user="Zeknichov" delta="False">
    <text>People are programmed to value certain things differently. While it is true that diamond value is a fabricated reality orchastrated by a corporation in order to extract money from people, it doesn't change the fact that this fabricated reality brings people who buy into the reality a sense of worth. To these people diamonds have value and they get a sense of satisfaction from owning them. That feeling is real even if the reality created to program people in a manner to feel that emotion by owning diamonds is fake. To you, people are being tricked by a corporation but another way to look at it is that people are paying a corporation to provide them with those emotions. People are getting something of value in exchange for their money.

Yes, there are other programs that are cheaper and thus arguably better. If you can get behind the program that the significance of the gift is in the act of someone special giving you something and the actual item doesn't matter such that any gemstone at any price or even a rock would have the same meaning (and same emotional impact) then that would be cheaper while having the same effect. Not everyone can trick themselves into feeling this though because this reality isn't something a corporation goes around trying to program.

So here's where I'm going with this... A corporation does something for people. The corporation creates a reality for people much easier than it is for people to create a reality for themselves. That reality allows people the ability to feel a strong emotion from receiving a diamond. If it weren't for this corporation people wouldn't feel a strong emotion from receiving a diamond. In fact it is questionable that people would ever feel a strong emotion from any gemstone if not for the corporations that try to create the reality that enhances the emotions one feels from receiving a gemstone. That emotion has value and that value is worth something. It is worth the price of a diamond.

Again, I agree with you that it is possible to get as much satisfaction from something else much cheaper but it isn't necessarily easy for people to get the same satisfaction because no corporation is selling such a reality to people. You're paying for the ease of having such a reality that provides such an emotional reaction being provided to you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688004380.0" user="katrinac490" delta="False">
    <text>That’s the reason I won’t ever buy a diamond. I’d rather something more original and sentimental, and it’d probably be way cheaper too!! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687789904.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>Diamonds are worth so much mostly because of the efforts of De Beers. It was way more than a decade ago BTW, more like a century. Gucci handbags are also worth so much primarily because of marketing too.

If you look back in the past, it's the same kinda deal as a dowry. It's a gift of commitment and of value. That the actual thing almost has no value is pretty much irrelevant, the fact that you're willing to lay out a big chunk of income makes you feel more committed, and your future wife feel like you're committed, and this is more than words can say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687832531.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>But doesn't that imply that the richer you are, the more committed you are? I know that it's "two months salary" or whatever, so it scales. But honestly, 2 months salary for a poorer person is life or death, diamond or food/rent. 2 months salary for Bill Gates is a lot more money, but I doubt he would struggle without it. 

I would rather prove my committment by my actions, than through my wallet. Those actions being: considering our future together and not making a poor financial decision to signify our union.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687874330.0" user="anarchistprince" delta="False">
    <text>"Two months salary" also comes from an advertising gimmick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687906479.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely. The whole thing is silly. But it is in the public consciousness so what are you gonna do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688140574.0" user="compounding" delta="False">
    <text>The value of “2 months salary” isn’t meant to directly measure your commitment, but to *demonstrate* your monetary value as a mating partner. Both to that partner, but more importantly to her social group and family.

By this admittedly archaic standard, Bill Gates is objectively a more “fit” partner as demonstrated by his 1.9 Billion dollar 2-month salary engagement gift vs. whatever you “can” spend on an engagement ring.

You may wish that your actions define your fitness as a mate, but the original intent and purpose that led the culture to latch onto the use of “transparent conspicuous consumption as demonstration of value” was excellently fulfilled by buying expensive veblin goods (i.e., diamonds) to show off.

Now, you may expect that your fiancée (to be) doesn’t care about that sort of thing... and she may even feel pressured to agree because being attached to such historical anachronisms aren’t currently in “fashion”.... BUT... you should be really really really sure that not fulfilling that cultural expectation among *her friend group* doesn’t diminish (even in a subconscious and/or irrational way) her appreciation for the actual intention.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689031595.0" user="ThetamingoftheMew" delta="False">
    <text>If an expensive and useless Veblen good like a diamond is a value signal, then why can't an expensive and *useful* good like a house or a car be? Is it just meant to demonstrate that you have excess wealth to burn?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689068171.0" user="sarcasticorange" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If an expensive and useless Veblen good like a diamond is a value signal, then why can't an expensive and useful good like a house or a car be? 

Because a good number of people you meet will never see your house or car.

&amp;gt; Is it just meant to demonstrate that you have excess wealth to burn?

One could argue about the phrasing, but basically, yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689082496.0" user="sarcasticorange" delta="False">
    <text>Which is fine. Just remember that most people do things which are not practical all the time for the sake of social constructs. A t-shirt and sweats are much more comfortable and versatile than the outfits most of us wear to work, but we don't because of the judgement (and possible accompanying repercussions from said judgement) we would receive from others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689698201.0" user="PhosBringer" delta="False">
    <text>Work is a bad example, as dress code in every place I've worked at was enforced. It's about following police, not judgement. If you're at work you're expected to follow a guideline. They're implemented for a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690038927.0" user="lalafriday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A t-shirt and sweats are much more comfortable and versatile than the outfits most of us wear to work, but we don't because of the judgement (and possible accompanying repercussions from said judgement) we would receive from others.

Speak for yourself...I work from home :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688392864.0" user="NathanielGarro-" delta="False">
    <text>Just a quick FYI OP, if she wanted (and you were willing) there are some good lab grown options as well which can serve as a compromise. They have the same composition and look of a diamond (because they are diamonds) but are a tad pricier than moissanite. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688837761.0" user="angelindisguise" delta="False">
    <text>My diamond in my engagement ring is fake as fuck. We spent the money saved on an epic honeymoon. Worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689215262.0" user="shuzuko" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't even want a diamond, I wanted a purple spinel. But we got a diamond ring free as a gift from a family member and free ring of any kind &amp;gt; "perfect" ring that costs money we could use on our honeymoon. So now I have a diamond ring 🤷</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689529651.0" user="angelindisguise" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.jewlr.co.uk/products/JWL0267/14k-white-gold-organic-leaf-ring?e0=&amp;amp;s1=04CZIR&amp;amp;s2=SWKRed&amp;amp;s3=SWKRed&amp;amp;sku=14KW my ring</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689261284.0" user="Demosthenes96" delta="False">
    <text>I think being able to say this as a comeback to any antiquated person who thinks you should only have genuine diamonds is all you need, really. “So that’s . . . Not a really diamond?” “Nope- check out the vacation pics of us in an awesome place we could afford to go to because we didn’t waste money on a diamond” *crickets* </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689503418.0" user="angelindisguise" delta="False">
    <text>Cuba was amazing. I got to captain a speedboat and I got air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688879324.0" user="exosequitur" delta="False">
    <text>What I would look at is the aftermarket value of the stones. That is probably the best metric of value you will find.

Diamonds fail miserably on this point, with high quality rubies and emeralds basically being depreciation free (aside from markup), and it's not too hard to buy a used piece with the gem you want, then use the gold and stone and still come out ahead of buying "new" (as if any stone is new lol) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689000391.0" user="Lonewolfdies" delta="False">
    <text>Just to add another voice to the conversation, my fiancé and I went with moissanite and couldn’t be happier, I think you and your girl will be really happy with your decision :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689236659.0" user="ffn" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm also really curious to hear what reasoning people have for the preference as I just can't work it out in my head.

I think this is really the point. It's about personal preferences.

You're talking a lot about Moissanite in this thread. But isn't your argument against diamonds just as legitimate against buying Moissanite over some other gemstone?

You'll give me reasons why Moissanite is worth it to you, and whatever you say will be correct, because those are your personal preferences. Other people might think "pfft /u/DarkPhoenix07 is thinking about spending $700 on a ring, what a waste of money", but who cares what they think? What's important when you're buying a ring is what *you* think is important.

For some people, whatever the reason, diamonds are preferable and worth the money. And whatever you think is completely irrelevant to their decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690792173.0" user="Diesel1donna" delta="False">
    <text>My engagement ring cost £18! I chose it,I love it. I would be horrified if my lovely husband had spent £1000+ even if we had that kind of money.
My favourite necklace is one my son made by choosing individual beads (he was three). I wear pretty stones from the beach on a leather thong, my boy,now 20 buys me Vintage (charity shop) jewellery and I love the effort and thought. Stones and other gems are so much more interesting than diamonds and don't even start me on people who ' upgrade' their engagement ring....? Mine means so much to me, as does the man who gave it to me. 
I hope your girlfriend appreciate s whatever you choose and understands it was chosen with love.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30705731075.0" user="jisusdonmov" delta="False">
    <text>It’s cool that you have an outlook that leads you to enjoy these things just as much as someone who enjoys more expensive things, it’s commendable. 

However I often see this line of thinking in threads such as this, and it’s kind of disingenuous, and betrays a bit of jealousy (or lack of understanding/experience), amongst other things, on your part (and people with similar opinions). 

Before you feel like you need to defend yourself and I’m telling rubbish, consider a few things. 

You really *wouldn’t* be horrified if your husband spent £1000+ on a ring if you’d have the money for it. And by “having money for it” I don’t mean getting into debt to afford it. I mean being comfortably able to afford it and not having it make a difference to your other needs. The only reason you *think* you’d be horrified is because you’re not able to afford it at the moment.

The necklace is cool, however you’d be surprised how many people that wear expensive jewellery also wear sentimental things like this. Wearing monetarily “worthless” sentimental items is not something exclusive to people who don’t possess luxury goods. But it’s often talked about in a way like it is. This betrays unfamiliarity with being able to afford luxury goods and/or having experience with people who can. 

Vintage/charity shop jewellery doesn’t actually take any more effort or thought to buy than a carefully considered expensive piece (just ask men who buy expensive watches). People who say that often have a scenario in mind where their vintage piece was hunted down in some romantic way from some place that’s off the beaten track and is one of a kind, but somewhat pricey gifts are thoughtlessly bought at the mall. 

However there are plenty of people that buy vintage things from bog standard tourist markets or their local Oxfam, and rarely stray from “oohhh this looks cute/interesting” level of consideration while making a choice. Just because it’s used and old doesn’t necessarily make it special. 

Conversely, luxury jewellery market is actually enormous, and hunting down just the right piece for someone can take enormous effort. And it doesn’t even have to be a diamond, there’s plenty  of other stones used, in plenty of styles. Expensive jewellery doesn’t start and end at Tiffany. I can show some pretty cool (to my taste at least) examples if you’re curious. 

All in all, as I said in the beginning, none of this is to knock you down, or your choices. I think it’s cool of you to appreciate simple things, some people can’t, often for shallow reasons. 

But please consider that the other side is not actually as simplistic, shallow, unoriginal, and uncreative as these threads and comments similar to yours often imply. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30708627519.0" user="Diesel1donna" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you, I see your points , I really do. However in MY case I genuinely would be horrified. Having had very little money, and my beloved having very poor health, it would upset me to feel he knew me so little that even if we could easily afford the money, I would prefer to have Victorian books, or WW1 ephemera. 
I would never deign to think that people with money find less pleasure in simpler,cheaper items. People are different whether rich or poor. Some are impressed in spite of a jewels cost, some only because of it, we all have our passions, 
My passions are hiking, rock pooling, messing about on the farm, or in the woods with the dogs. If by any miracle I ever become rich I can imagine the dogs we could rescue, or the children we could help, however much money I had, rather than a piece of jewellery around my neck, or on my finger.
I am simply not materialistic, shopping fills me with dread ( unless for books or strange antiques) and a shopping centre is the Devil's own invention!! 
So your points are valid, apart from the charity shop ones. For a ( from the age of 15) year old boy to visit several charity shops in search of something,rather than just popping into a store where a whole section of jewellery is laid out DOES show more care. It DOES show more effort, and it certainly means more to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30773021321.0" user="jisusdonmov" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry about your troubles, and apologies for a delayed reply. Thing is, you only think that now, but when people better their situation they get used to different standards *very* quickly, and so would you. Doesn’t mean you wouldn’t be more aware of it, but you certainly wouldn’t be terrified to spend £500 or more on a ring. 

It’s not about knowing you so little. Again you make the judgement that people who spend money put no thought in their gifts. See the pattern? Some memorabilia and Victorian books can get pretty pricey, unique and rare. Would make a great gift. Antiques cost too. Some more, some less. Again, having money doesn’t make you an idiot who spends thoughtlessly.

It’s just a different scale. Some people would see having pets as a luxury, like your dogs. It’s all just a matter of perspective, yet you always seem to be just a tad judgemental.

Hiking in distant regions of the planet is also way more interesting than in Wales or something 😉. 

Spending own money doesn’t have to mean that you’re “materialistic” and/or thoughtless. 

Regarding charity shops - I don’t think it does. His choice is just limited, but he literally goes into a charity shop instead of a store, no super thought required. It seems you have a very narrow understanding of luxury goods in general, if you think people who care about their gifts just shop at department stores at the first jewellery counter they see. 

In any case, this is an easy and popular generalisation to make, just be aware that it’s often not very true, and I wish your loved one all the good health in the world. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688805695.0" user="auradog" delta="False">
    <text>This is how a lot of people think but it predicates on the idea that women arent able to think rationally. If her X reason is a bad reason and you just accept that you are establishing a dynamic where she can be irrational and be rewarded for it, ( which will obviously lead to more of it). If you give her something heartfelt and symbolic, but cheap, like a wood ring carved in borneo when you went there on your first trip together or something, that should be more meaningful than a rock that's only expensive because it is. Might as well put "supreme" on the ring too and quadruple the price while you're at it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
