<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687622211.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>Diamonds (in a jewelry context)  are worth what they  are worth for the same reason Moisanitte are valuable - people are willing  to  pay a certain amount for them.

So...if Diamonds are a waste of money, then so are other gemstones. What is undeniably true is that cheaper things that are a waste of money result in _wasting less money_ when  you purchase them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687715558.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>This is exactly right. Either way it's just a pretty little rock right? Why not "waste" less money on something that is almost identical. I guess I'm lucky that Diamonds are still the preference for most people, otherwise the cost of a Moissanite might be a lot higher!

Just to clarify, I don't see buying my parter jewellery as a waste of money, but buying something particular \* just because it's expensive\* compared to buying something that is almost exacltly the same for a third of the price just makes little to no sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688338434.0" user="GrandmaBogus" delta="False">
    <text>I felt the same about gold rings. Check out tungsten carbide - It's dirt cheap, looks and feels like a nice metal (similar density to gold) and will last forever due to the extreme hardness. I've had my $20 ring for three years and there isn't a scratch on it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689009413.0" user="hucifer" delta="False">
    <text>The main advantage that a gold ring has over tungsten is that it can be resized, which might prove useful at some point down the line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689651208.0" user="GrandmaBogus" delta="False">
    <text>With a $20 ring there's no need to ever get it resized, you just get a new one with the same engraving. No reason to sink tons of sentimental (and monetary) value into the ring – the ring isn't important at all, it's just a *symbol* for what's important. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690276810.0" user="hucifer" delta="False">
    <text>Well that's fine; each to their own.

I think a lot of people like the idea of a ring which ages gracefully along with the wearer, though. Particularly for wedding rings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30692027694.0" user="GrandmaBogus" delta="False">
    <text>Ok then, stainless steel and silver wears with time. Sinking $2000 into *metal* at the time in your life *when you need money the most* just sounds insane to me. I realize that's the culture we have but from an outside perspective it's bizarre. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30698377787.0" user="solanaceaeroot" delta="False">
    <text>Stainless Steel is hard to resize and silver is too soft for long term wear. 

But I agree with your overall point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688914158.0" user="PizzaIsItsOwnReward" delta="False">
    <text>"Waste" is too subjective in this context, because it depends on value, which, again, in this context, is in the eye of the beholder. Practically everything subjective is a waste, technically. But diamonds do have industrial and technological value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689112659.0" user="TheExter" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; just because it's expensive* compared to buying something that is almost exacltly the same for a third of the price just makes little to no sense.

why buy really expensive clothes when something cheaper gets the work done? why buy a really expensive car when a cheaper one gets you to a destination? why eat at a really expensive restaurant when you can get full from the cheap one (and tastes better!)? 

all of those you could say it "makes no sense" but they all do, fancy jewelry/clothes/accessories all come with an invisible value of social status. 

this might not matter on your social circles but there are people who depend on having the most expensive everything. so for example the big big diamond it's not to say "Look how pretty it is!" is to say "look how much i can spend, therefore you can be sure i have a lot of money and you can trust me for future opportunities" because i sure as hell am not trusting the couple using fake/cheap knock offs

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689253433.0" user="swaffel_me_zachtjes" delta="False">
    <text>Actually the market does not work in the normal way it does for jewelry; jewelry actually subverts the normal supply-and-demand mechanic that drives the market; diamonds are actually sold to by jewelers for about 10 times the industrial prize and basically how it is that there is still a surplus; basically they offer what the jewelers can't sell to the industrial market for a far lower price where actual supply-and-demand takes effect.

So basically as far as jewelers go there is as surplus and the price is still high. Why? because people buy diamonds in and jewelry in general in the inverted way; people don't go to a jeweler and say "I want this product—how much does it cost?" but "I have this much money to spend on jewelry; what can I get for it?" the entire point of jewelry is basically to show how much wealth you have so normal underbidding doesn't work. With phones if two places offer the exact same phone but one offers it for 90% of the price of the other one people will go for the cheaper one but that's not how it works with jewelry at all. In theory people would just buy a larger diamond for the same price then but in practice people can't even see the difference. Most people who buy diamonds don't know anything about the quality of a diamond and are really just looking to lose a set amount of money.

So the result is that normal underbidding is not an effective strategy to gain customers in the jewelry industry and that jewelry is sold well above the actual normal market price as a result.

It's in the end not a lot dissimilar from a lot of branded clothing which is sold well above the actual production cost and its actual material worth because people buy it to show off their wealth but the difference is that these things actually have a hidden "production cost" which is the massive advertisement campaign that was needed to establish it as a luxury brand and that's not the case with jewelry which rarely have a brand to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689735690.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>It works _exactly_ like the  normal market.  It just happens  that supply and  distribution are  tightly controlled.

That doesn't change that value is  imparted by _consumer's willingness to pay_.  That there are "forces" on supply is no different then  any product, it's just we like to talk about the particulars of diamonds  because they  are  an interesting case.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
