<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30688447049.0" user="UniversalTruths" delta="False">
    <text>I completely agree, but with one caveat explained well by evolutionary psychology. 

Diamonds as a product are in fact a very clever way invented by DeBeers to extract monetary value out of a powerfully emotional ritual that humans developed in their mating process: the promise of long-term companionship, fidelity, support and sacrifice that men make to their mates. The reverse promise is inherent in women's agreement to bear children with their partner. In terms of evolutionary psychology women sacrifice huge part of their lives, youth, fertile years, ease of finding another mate, or "matrimonial market value" when they become pregnant.

Having a tangible token of a reciprocal offer from the male partner is a real need in this dynamic. That's what behind the asset-sharing principle in divorce law. Proposing marriage is *supposed* not to be easy on the man's part. It's meant not to be *cheap,* but it doesn't necessarily mean monetary value. What is important is the *promise and transmitting this promise to others.*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
