<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="35" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30689034080.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>Diamonds are cool from a hardness perspective, and are fantastic. However, there is indeed little difference between a natural diamond and an artificial one. This is perhaps a slight modification to your viewpoint, but I hold that diamonds are a fine choice if you don't bother with the whole natural business. You can get modestly sized diamonds inexpensively from chinese sellers if you don't mind them being artificial. Hell, the whole business will probably come crashing down eventually because of the improving ability to make artificial ones look like natural ones.

TLDR: The premium is mostly surrounding "natural" diamonds.

Moisanitte will be slightly more reflective than a diamond, which from a pure asthetics standpoint, isn't at all bad, but does mean it can be differentiated from true diamonds, if that's important to you two.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
