<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687724977.0" user="Balthazar_rising" delta="False">
    <text>Whilst the price of diamonds are artifically inflated (they deliberately control the scarcity of them, and have created a market by making diamonds the 'traditional' wedding stone), the value of the diamond isn't actually in the cost of the stone, or the ring.

The value of the ring is actually representative of how much you value your partner. For example, if you have a large budget (say, $1000), but only spend a few hundred on the ring, your partner may percieve that as how much you value her.

However, if you have to sacrifice your own desires to save for a ring, and your partner knows it, they know that you value them above your own desires.

This is not a universal fact, and some partners are willing to compromise on cost, especially if you already show your love in other ways. Many couples believe in "marrying the man, not the ring".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687914848.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>I would personally much prefer my partner marry me based on my merits as a partner rather than how much I can spend on a ring.

Technically anything I spend comes at a sacrifice as we are working very hard to save everything we can to get a home deposit and afford a holiday that we both sorely need. I'm working full-time while studying also full-time and she's working two jobs. Spending $700 on a moissanite is still quite a sacrifice as it pulls us away from our goals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687974465.0" user="Balthazar_rising" delta="False">
    <text>You're preaching to the choir here... I recently got engaged with a very cheap ring, but I'm saying there are some couples that would put value on a ring based on the amount of sacrifice. If you sacrificed for a ring, and $700 is your price, is that better or worse than a multimillionaire buying a $1000 ring?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688638391.0" user="woofiedude" delta="False">
    <text>More than 20 years ago, my husband and I deliberately chose a fake diamond. I got the the cut, size and style I wanted for less than $400. No one has ever known it’s fake. I really didn’t care to spend thousands of dollars on it. Since then we’ve bought a house, traveled overseas multiple times and saved up to pay in full  for our kid’s college education. Never once did I want to replace the ring. 

If you and your girlfriend are ok with it, go for it. Do your thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688666294.0" user="introvertabrate" delta="False">
    <text>I dated a woman for 2 years and we were talking about getting married. Then she told me what I had to spend to make her ring important to her.  That was the beginning of the end of the relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688685612.0" user="TheManWhoPanders" delta="False">
    <text>It's not an either-or thing.  She can still like you for your merits but still have an expectation that you care so much about her that you're willing to spend a lot of money on her.  That's ultimately what the diamond symbolizes. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
