<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687519044.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Diamonds like anything else are a resource. They are used in manufacturing because they are effective at mechanical sharpening of softer things like steel. In particular scalpels and cooking knives. Because of this there is an impact on the price of diamonds, that is not insubstantial since owning a rock for a piece of jewelry means it's not being put to work in a factory. Granted more recent techniques have made it possible to manufacture diamonds, you still need tertiary resources to produce those diamonds.

It's the same reason gold is a de facto currency, because it's rare and has properties that are valued for reasons unrelated to vanity. Yet people have their wedding bands made out of gold.

So they're not a waste of money *more* than anything else is a waste of money. You are just paying a premium price due to the inherent valuation of the material for other purposes.

When you consider that something like Moisanitte probably doesn't have the same properties and is thus more useless, you don't carry the same premium. That's an actual waste of money, because you are over valuing a worthless rock. At least a diamond has uses.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687606339.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>I do see your point, but then where does the huge increase in cost due to colour and clarity come from?

A majority of the diamond cutting tools use manufactured diamonds that look like garbage but have the same hardness value. This means that where the value comes from is seperate to where the money is spent.

Also Moissanite is used in jewellers cutting tools. It can cut anything other than diamonds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687625511.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I do see your point, but then where does the huge increase in cost due to colour and clarity come from?

That's the premium you pay. That valuation, is the value of the diamond as a piece of jewelry.

 &amp;gt;A majority of the diamond cutting tools use manufactured diamonds that look like garbage but have the same hardness value. This means that where the value comes from is seperate to where the money is spent.

It's still an opprotunity cost because manufacturing fake diamonds is an operation unto itself. Whereas just mining diamonds to manufacture with instead of selling them to consumers would be more efficient. That's another aspect of the premium, these companies have to give something up to make money but the only reason to give that up is if it's worth *more money* than the alternative. That adds to the value of diamond jewelry because you need to incent people to continue to produce authentic diamonds.

&amp;gt;Also Moissanite is used in jewellers cutting tools. It can cut anything other than diamonds.

That's a substantially more niche application than the numerous ones for diamonds.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687666781.0" user="regulatorDonCarl" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think OP’s fiancé intends on cutting concrete or stone with her ring?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687688171.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>That's irrelevant.

Market forces act on the value of the diamond independent of what the diamond is used for.

A diamond on someones ring finger is a diamond that is not being used to cut cement elsewhere. That demand adds a premium value to the stone.

That's why per ounce, popcorn is worth more than crude oil. Because the flat rate of popcorn at the movie theater is thousands of times higher than it's worth. Yet without oil society as we know it crumbles into nothing.

Market forces don't care about what you do with your goods.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687690873.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>No but durability matters when you wear a ring all day every day. Bumping your hand against walls or hand railings is infuriatingly common. You don't realize it until you start wearing your most prized possession on your hand every day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687852781.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>This is why I mentioned the Mohs scale of hardness. Diamond is a 10 but Moissanite is a 9.6 (or 9.5 I don't remember). Still pretty good in the scheme of things</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688517890.0" user="Shellbyvillian" delta="False">
    <text>Are you willing to concede that "still pretty good" is a sufficient gap that diamonds should be priced higher than moissonite? If so, it's just a matter of how much a premium is reasonable, not that diamonds are completely useless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688126225.0" user="ronpaulfan69" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Unlike hardness, which denotes only resistance to scratching, diamond's toughness or tenacity is only fair to good. Toughness relates to the ability to resist breakage from falls or impacts. Because of diamond's perfect and easy cleavage, it is vulnerable to breakage. **A diamond will shatter if hit with an ordinary hammer**. The toughness of natural diamond has been measured as 2.0 MPa m1/2, which is good compared to other gemstones, but poor compared to most engineering materials.

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Material_properties_of_diamond</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30689094582.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; The toughness of natural diamond has been measured as 2.0 MPa m1/2, **which is good compared to other gemstones,** but poor compared to most engineering materials.

Why the heck would you be smashing it with a hammer??? I said you bump it into walls and stuff as you walk around. Not that you expect it to be as strong as engineering materials. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30690807290.0" user="ronpaulfan69" delta="False">
    <text>Something as simple as dropping the ring onto a ceramic tile floor or into a steel sink could cause a diamond to chip or crack.

They're not very durable compared to other materials rings are commonly made of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688655346.0" user="IotaCandle" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure there are many factories left using anything but industrial diamonds...

The real reason for their cost is that a cartel controls most of the production, and maintains an artificial scarcity while advertising their product.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688892483.0" user="DianaWinters" delta="False">
    <text>Diamonds aren't even rare. In some cases you can literally dig them out of the ground with a shovel. The reason why diamond jewelry is expensive is because of marketing and artificial scarcity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30688953419.0" user="Acewolff" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Diamonds like anything else are a resource. They are used in manufacturing because they are effective at mechanical sharpening of softer things like steel. In particular scalpels and cooking knives. Because of this there is an impact on the price of diamonds, that is not insubstantial since owning a rock for a piece of jewelry means it's not being put to work in a factory. Granted more recent techniques have made it possible to manufacture diamonds, you still need tertiary resources to produce those diamonds.

No, the diamonds used in jewelery can only be used for visual effect. That lack certain stregths that you would need to use then for industrial purposes.

&amp;gt;It's the same reason gold is a de facto currency, because it's rare and has properties that are valued for reasons unrelated to vanity. Yet people have their wedding bands made out of gold.

Partially correct, it was until people realized they could better grow and/control a market if they used a currency based off what other people says it's worth. The reason gold was so popular is because of it's ability to be struck into coins, and doesn't tarnish. Now we know gold has a plethora of uses and is traded on all markets as a commodity.

&amp;gt;So they're not a waste of money more than anything else is a waste of money. You are just paying a premium price due to the inherent valuation of the material for other purposes.

True, can't really argue otherwise. But it isn't as if all of the diamonds we're once owned by someone famous and all other equally useless gemstones we're not. There is even a place in Arkansas where you can go sift through the dirty and find a diamond. It's regualted by the state, is free, and they even higher professional geologists to tell you what rocks you have.

&amp;gt;When you consider that something like Moisanitte probably doesn't have the same properties and is thus more useless, you don't carry the same premium. That's an actual waste of money, because you are over valuing a worthless rock. At least a diamond has uses.

What? A diamond's hardness compared to Moisanitte is negligable, especially since it's only use is to look good. Also Moisanitte has a high refractivity index so it literally sparkles more than a diamond of equal size.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
