<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="551186699.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/945udn/cmv_diamonds_are_a_complete_waste_of_money/">
    <title>CMV: Diamonds are a complete waste of money</title>
    <original_poster>DarkPhoenix07</original_poster>
    <original_post>So, I recently went into a store to look at having a piece of jewellery made. While I was there, the staff were making out like anything other than a diamond will basically be a piece of garbage.

Having no knowledge of these things, I almost agreed to purchase quite a sizeable diamond which would have blown my budget. In my mind, why buy the jewellery at all of it's just going to look like cheap trash...

Luckily, I didn't. I've now done some research into moisanitte and white sapphires and I'm really struggling to understand why diamonds are worth anything at all.

Moisanitte gems are rated on the same colour and clarity scale as diamonds so visually they conform to the same standards. Yes, a diamond is a 10 on the mohs scale, but a moisanitte is a 9.6.

Regarding the price, I was offered a visibly yellow diamond, uncertified, enhanced (has had silicone injected) 0.8ct for $1900. I can buy a 1.25ct moisanitte, perfect clarity, same cut for $700.

When trying to find out why diamonds are worth more it appears to be for two reasons:

1. About a decade ago, a diamond company (de beers I think it was) spent millions on an advertising campaign to promote them then raised the prices.

2. As a status symbol. Literally just so that people can say that "their ring cost $17,000"

Based on that, the value of a diamond is only what we percieve it to be. If that were ever to change a lot of people will have worthless, albeit pretty, rocks on their hands that cost them the same as a house deposit. 

So please, change my mind. If you can't my girlfriend is getting a moissonite ring 😉</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30687510915.0" user="TheMothHour" delta="False">
    <text>Not knowing much about moissanite, I can’t give you a comparison in quality. The one thing about diamonds, that make them so desirable, is their ability to sparkle different colors.

As for the cost, I think the cost of rings are ridiculous too. But I have heard that man made diamonds are very good and half the cost. My coworker bought his wife a man made diamond - and he said it was at the 3rd of the cost. Have you checked those out? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30687596392.0" user="DarkPhoenix07" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is actually a problem with marketing. Some of the earlier companies called them "moissanite diamonds", implying that they were artificial diamonds. They definitely aren't they just look almost identical.

I've watched a lot of videos and read a lot from jewellers and such and they all say the same thing. Moissanite is actually higher on the fire and brilliance scale that diamonds.

So I'm reasonably sure they're the ones I've looked at. The other option is a white sapphire, although these are reasonably softer so will scuff easier.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
