<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="553674122.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/95n5oq/cmv_cable_channels_should_be_individually_priced/">
    <title>CMV: Cable channels should be individually priced and available for purchase rather than lumped into cable packages.</title>
    <original_poster>upstairsboys</original_poster>
    <original_post>This isn't really an argument for my proposed "business model" existing. It already does, in the form of HBO, SHOWTIME, or other premium, subscription-based television networks. My argument is that this model of paying for only the channels/networks you want to watch should be applied to all cable companies across the board. It's a flawed system, and one worth briefly explaining in case some Redditors are unfamiliar with how this works in the United States. Essentially, cable providers offer packages that bundle together a certain number of standard channels (ESPN, Discovery, HGTV, etc.) for a flat monthly rate. For example: DIRECTV's  Select Package offers 155+ channels for $35 per month (please don't r/HailCorporate me, I just wanted to pick a well-known, nationally-available provider). This means that the cost of providing each of those 155 channels is (to some degree) incorporated into this $35 per month rate. I assume that because the next package available offers 160+ channels for $40 per month. So the amount of channels and the cost of service is directly related (though I don't imagine it costs DIRECTV a whole dollar to add one channel to their service).

It's ridiculous that a consumer has to pay for the cost of providing 155+ channels when (and this is the primary reason for my argument) NOBODY watches 155 different television channels. I looked it up and found that, on average, people cycle between 15-20 channels. That means there are 135-140 channels included in your package that are raising your rate while going completely unused. And while you can technically take advantage of the access you're paying for, you were not in anyway involved in determining what channels you wanted access to in the first place. 

It should be up to the consumer to decide what channels they receive access to and therefore pay for. Everyone has different interests, and should be able to shape their TV payments around those interests. The channels should be individually priced based on the production costs of each network (i.e. truTV would likely cost less than, say, NBC). The cable providers are still responsible for providing cable, they just don't get to heap together a bunch of extraneous channels and tell you how much you have to pay to access the few channels from the heap that you like to watch.

I understand that this is an argument regarding the actions of companies whose sole motivator is generating as much value for shareholders as possible, and that as a result they don't behave in a way that is logical that contributes to the common good. So I suppose I'm looking for responses that in some way invalidate my proposed model, provide a better alternative to the one I layed out, or somehow influence me to prefer cable packages to a pay-for-what-you-use system. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30706711158.0" user="HanniballRun" delta="False">
    <text>Can you tell us how many individual (non-packaged, like HBOGO) subscription channels you currently pay for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30706916321.0" user="upstairsboys" delta="False">
    <text>I pay for HBOGo, and I also pay for a Netflix subscription</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30706926078.0" user="HanniballRun" delta="False">
    <text>I should have asked earlier, but do you also pay for subscription cable/satellite package?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
