<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="60" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721186284.0" user="DukeofDixieland" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you to  a large extent, but I will try to modify your view with two points of consideration.

1) Political thinkers have known for all time that most people can't understand the complexities of political economy. As we move through time, we give people a little more voice one piece at a time. We've moved from Monarchies to Aristocratic parliamentary governments and on to the representative democracies we have today.

Not only can most people not understand political economy's intricacies, they don't *want* to.  We would all much rather elect someone who dedicates their life to studying these things and represents us so that we can specialize for our career and focus our energy on our own lives.

2. You mentioned that you have been studying economics.  I'm not an economist, but I have a BS in Finance and an MBA in International Business, so I've taken more econ classes than most econ majors (I just don't have the math background to run the extremely complicated regressions needed for leading edge econometrics).  The primary function of academic economics is to build economic models. Then, we must know which model to use in a given circumstance to forecast correctly. The are thousands of models in todays arsenal.

Most of the core tenets of economics aren't actually up for debate among the professional class, but many folks on Reddit will argue them anyways.  For example, there's no economic model in existence that would produce the outcomes that proponents of a $xx minimum wage claim.  

If you are interested in debating Austrian vs Keynesianism, well, they are both just theories with different sets of economic models.  The EU has used austerity models from the Austrian school recently in Greece.  In the US, we are moving toward a progressive NeoKeynsianism plan with big government spending and higher inflation targets.  

In other words, they are all "right," so the debate is which policy is the most useful to implement out of the entire collection in the economic toolbox at a particular moment in time to acheive a specific outcome.  Professionals may get things wrong, but it's because they chose the wrong model - it doesn't mean the models don't work.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721236920.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the comment! 

Do we elect people who make it their lives work to study these issues, or do we elect those that play the game of politics the best? 

It's true that the core tenets are largely agreed upon in all of economics, as long as you exclude the marxists. 

While I think the rest of what you write is reasonable, I also think that there is enough difference between the schools of thought that one might see a hammer where another sees a saw. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721263567.0" user="DukeofDixieland" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that there is a certain population of people who dedicate their lives to politics and the ones who play the game the best are the ones who win elections.  There is a large number of policy wonks working at NGOs, too, or career positions in govt - most aren't elected at all (thank God).

I would even say that many Marxists are "correct." The Labor Theory of Value, for example, is a very real metric. It just doesn't have much use post industrialization or in larger economic zones.

The differences in schools of thought are really minimal, though.  The ideas on 100% of microeconomics are the same and most of macro also has consensus accross the board. The differences that emerge are limited to monetary and fiscal policy tactics and specifically *when* to use them - they actually agree on the short run outcomes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721293560.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I don't think it's quite a 100%. I'm reminded by Bryan Caplan's "[Why I'm not an Austrian](http://econfaculty.gmu.edu/bcaplan/whyaust.htm)"

I do agree though, that there are many topics especially in micro, but also macro where there's a strong consensus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721380128.0" user="DukeofDixieland" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting example.  I guess I would say 99%, then.  But in the real world, we don't use Ordinal  Utility.  That isn't split between Keynesian vs Austrian.  It's  actually ubiquitous across both. It's rarely useful to use ordinal because there isn't an actual number associated with utility.

There may be some rare cases where Ordinal  works well, such as looking at different types of public transport or peoples' preference for different versions of equal utility (budweiser vs Miller or pizza vs Mexican food) but from my experience its generally ignored.  It goes back to the notion of picking the right model for the right task rather than debating on whether or not models "work."



</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
