<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="91" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30722019274.0" user="Claytertot" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with your premise, including the fact that even the experts don't agree on their own political areas of expertise.

A fundamental flaw with Democracies is that some percentage of voters will not be responsible or competent citizens. But the alternative is to cede power in a single unelected person or ruling body. One glance at a history book can tell you that, while imperfect, democracies are better for their people than totalitarian states, because, like you said, even the experts aren't always right or in agreement about what should be done. No single person or group will do a better job of running a society than the democratic will of the people. While plenty of people hold bad, ignorant, or immoral views, the will of 300 million people is generally going to average out to be pretty good.

I sometimes feel the same anger that you do. I try my best to fully understand an issue before I start making claims about it and I know that lots of people dont do this. But there isnt much you can do about that except engaging in conversation and doing your best to present educated arguments, and being willing to adjust your view if someone presents a better argument.

So my point is that, while you are generally correct, this is a necessary downside to a democracy. Democracies aren't perfect, but they are certainly better than any other option that has ever been tried, even when a large portion of the population isn't educated on every political and economic issue.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
