<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720803889.0" user="ViewerofFewer" delta="False">
    <text>First off, I think your standard for how one gains knowledge is a bit singular in that I don't think people necessarily need to read the theoretical work others have done, right, wrong, or neutral, to know that a particular system is flawed, ineffective, or unjust. This might be an odd example but, during slavery for instance, I don't think slaves needed to read the works of, say, Frederick Douglas, or William Lloyd Garrison to know that the situation they were in, as a result of slavery, was wrong.

In the same way, I think that by insisting that the only way one can be qualified to speak on political/economic issues is by reading certain texts, which first of all, require them to have access to those texts. Many of which exist behind paywalls, and/or are written in inaccessible language. 

What I'm saying is, you are setting a very high bar for entry that I think denies the voices that might be the most useful when discussing the shortcomings of particular policies, be they economic, political, or both.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
