<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="38" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720868837.0" user="Sitnalta" delta="False">
    <text>I feel you have countered your own point by pointing out that experts disagree with each other as much as normal people. This shows that increasing knowledge, while desirable, is no route to some sort of utopia. It may be impossible for humans to ever know enough because you can't really set the standard; how much does someone have to read before they are qualified to advocate for change? We are the species we are and we can only conduct our policies as that species. Saying that humans aren't qualified to advocate for political change is like saying giraffes' necks are too long. You are probably right, but there isn't anything thing that can be done. No matter the level of education, people will advocate for change, often based on their own experiences. Which leads me to my second point:     
     
Why is reading more valuable than experience? As someone who has lived the life of a very poor person in London, who has survived on low wages and high rents for years, who has seen, spoken with and worked with the underclass extensively, who has held two jobs to make ends meet I may well have a much better understanding of the reality of English society than some banker's child who went to private school and then straight in to parliament, no matter how many books he read on the way to his degree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720938767.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I want to push back against this notion that experience is somehow interchangeable with actual arguments. Yes, you will probably have a better overview of many problems, but that does not come with novel insights that will lead to policy that actually achieves whatever goals you have. Someone working a minimum wage job does not somehow achieve insights that the literature on the subject is ignorant to, or even unable to comprehend. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
