<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="66" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721330984.0" user="TheK1ngsW1t" delta="False">
    <text>I've heard "The more you know, the less you know," but the Socrates one is good too.

People don't have to know every minute detail of every part of their beliefs and have the ability to defend them to anyone and everyone in order to hold to a belief. I can't even begin to read Calculus, but that doesn't mean I can't ever do Math. I'm a decently smart Christian who can theology your ear off, but no way am I ever going to try and debate Bill Nye.

Many big issues of life really have simple answers. Then you get another question branching off of the first one and another simple answer, and then another question that's only loosely related comes up and yet another answer that can be boiled down to a certain degree of simplicity. Add enough simple answers and you start getting some complex answers, but you built up to them. If John Doe knows that Y happens shortly after X, or that A causes B which generally gets in the way of X, then that's all John Doe *absolutely* has to know in order to hold a reasonably logical belief. He doesn't have to be able to explain the exact math and work out the taxes for a nationwide healthcare plan, just that it would be pretty expensive with lots of bureaucracy that either would likely bankrupt the country and change the cost of living nationwide. He doesn't have to know all the ins and outs of the American immigration system to know that there are hurting people trying to escape hardship at any cost and that we can and should help them. (trying to do an issue on both sides of the aisle, don't y'all go getting in debates with me, that's not today's issue) Mr. Doe then catches bits and pieces of more detail of the topic and more in-depth math throughout his life from talking to people, watching the news, listening to talk show hosts, and catching the occasional article for or against his viewpoint and refines or even changes his views as time goes on and as he gets input from smarter, trusted sources.

I will completely agree with you that sometimes--lots of times--it can get out of hand, and I've recently been trying my hardest to avoid getting into extended debates (or sometimes even responding at all) unless it looks like we'll both be able to stay civil and at least try to understand if not completely agree. I'm competitive and opinionated. It's hard XD</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721367384.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People don't have to know every minute detail of every part of their beliefs and have the ability to defend them to anyone and everyone in order to hold to a belief. I can't even begin to read Calculus, but that doesn't mean I can't ever do Math.

I agree, but I do believe that if you attempt to test and defend your position without mercy, then you will struggle to hold that position for long. The nice thing about math is that it's all decided, and it's all provable, replicable and always consistent. Philosophy is (or should be) the same. Slavery was never moral, but our uncovering of moral truth is slow and arduous. 

&amp;gt; I'm a decently smart Christian who can theology your ear off, but no way am I ever going to try and debate Bill Nye.

I've actually started to approach religion again. I figure my edgy 13 year old selfs rejection of religion probably didn't give it a fair shake. I also discovered Jung, which has some great insights about religion. 

There's another quote from some 13th century Persian guy that goes something like “Yesterday I was clever, so I wanted to change the world. Today I am wise, so I am changing myself.” It's been stuck in my mind, and keeps seeming more true than ever. And even though I'm not religious, I can't help but feel that religion will have some part in that. 

&amp;gt;I will completely agree with you that sometimes--lots of times--it can get out of hand, and I've recently been trying my hardest to avoid getting into extended debates (or sometimes even responding at all) unless it looks like we'll both be able to stay civil and at least try to understand if not completely agree. I'm competitive and opinionated. It's hard XD

I'm the same way. Even now I find myself leaping at every chance to prove someone wrong, which is really all I can do at this point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721385794.0" user="TheK1ngsW1t" delta="False">
    <text>I've really been feeling the stress. Although I don't *actually* think I am, a quick look at my post history would make you believe that I'm on a personal crusade to single-handedly turn Reddit from their Leftist, Atheist ways with just a little bit of D&amp;amp;D and Brandon Sanderson on the side XD

I need to get a reliable job and for school to hurry up and start so I'm busy enough to do not-Reddit things...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
