<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720931861.0" user="Taco_Wrangler" delta="False">
    <text>What Socrates really said is in Plato's Apology:

"what I do not know I do not think I know either"

The context is that Socrates was looking for a man wiser than himself because he doubted the oracle's claim that he himself was the wisest of men. 

http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Perseus%3Atext%3A1999.01.0170%3Atext%3DApol.%3Asection%3D21c

http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Perseus%3Atext%3A1999.01.0170%3Atext%3DApol.%3Asection%3D21d

The gist of the story about Socrates searching for a man wiser than himself is that becoming more wise does not come with certainty and certainty seems to be more common where there is less wisdom.

So your view is accurate to a point, but the Socrates story illustrates it was also true ~2500 years ago. It's been true for essentially all of human history, and is arguably an integral element of human societies.

Political and economical discourse also persists and is an integral element of human societies. There is no objective solution to the situation. Being sure of yourself but wrong has as much social / political currency as being wise. You can witness this happening in every kind of human organization. 

The question is really how to proceed given that by all evidence this situation is not likely to change. You could become a better advocate yourself or you could force everyone else to refrain from participating in politics or society. Both have been tried.


TL;DR if this is too long for you to read you are part of the problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720975055.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, I had a feeling I might be misusing that quote, or quoting it inaccurately. I also like how you frame the situation at the end, and I think you're correct. But instead of advocating for something I'm not even sure I can believe in, I'd rather just bother other advocates with doubt and nuance.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
