<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="55" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721074950.0" user="lifelonglearner27" delta="False">
    <text>You mentioned you get angry that you are unsure of your views, while many people who are less well read are so sure of theirs. I don't see why this is something to be angry about, but rather something that will always be a truth of life. However, there is something to do about it on a micro level.

People are always looking for ways to declare their superiority over others because of pride. I would say people prefer black &amp;amp; whites in politics than grays, and thus have the ability to say "my view is better than yours". 

I would try to use whatever energy you have from this and channel it to educating others around you about how much they don't know in the "I only know what I don't know" way. When I talk politics with people, I never intend to persuade, only to share a perspective and gain another from the other person. I do believe that if you can find the source of someone's suffering, and then discover the source of suffering of many people from many different backgrounds, that will give you valuable insights on what needs to be fixed in society. A change of political opinion rarely ever happens at the table, but rather at night as they toss and turn and think about the conversations from the day.

It doesn't make the general apathy/pride/superiority complexes/lack of knowledge of the general okay. But it will always be like this. I think it is better to advocate for better ways to communicate about politics that I outlined above so that information can actually spread person to person without heated feelings and hurt pride. A cultural shift needs to occur, and as someone like yourself who is knowledgeable you could continue to contribute to the change. That's nothing to be angry about. Perhaps more fuel to boost the education system, but not anger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721094960.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks! I'm not exactly sure I get angry. It's probably a childish "I spent so much time on this, and you get to sit there and confidently say thing, and confidently believe in them, and you get the social utility of sharing the views of those you want to fit in with, while I either stay silent, or speak and have both sides annoyed at me."

I do interjet in conversations, more on reddit than in real life, trying to stress the importance of nuance, or to tell someone why they're probably wrong. If nothing else, I ended up with a pretty good intuition that leads me to identify missteps and the like in arguments. And I think there's value in having people in the middle trying to foster good faith discussion and steel manning the arguments of those you disagree with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
