<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720622007.0" user="Hans_Brickface" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to segway here and talk about something seemingly unrelated for a moment, but I'll get back to the point.

If you've ever worked, say, a retail job, you often see processes that are very inefficient and could be improved upon. Of course, you don't have an MBA from Harvord and probably know jack shit about the expertise needed to run a successful large business, but you don't have to be a genius to see that shit ain't working as well as it could.

And I feel the same way about politics. Perhaps somebody won't know what the best way forward to solve a problem is, but it's not hard to spot problems that need fixing, especially if they happen to directly affect you.

IMO, I think your CMV would be much harder to challenge if you'd said something like people who don't know as much as they think they do are way too arrogant about their political views.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
