<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720679648.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>Life, in itself, is inherently political, inherently economic. I don't need to have read Marx or Adam Smith to understand my own economic reality. I don't need to be a political science major to know how various policies impact my life and the lives of those around me. I understand these things because they happen in my life.

People will always advocate for change that benefits them and theirs. Will they always advocate for the "correct" policies? The ones that help the greatest number of people? Most likely not. But they can be relied upon to advocate for policies that make their lives better, and everyone is an expert on their own life.

That's the premise that democracy is built on: that people can be relied upon to vote in their own best interest. And if the majority of people do that, the resulting policy should, in theory, help the most people. Now that doesn't always happen, but that's more the product of other factors.

Edit: (Taken from a comment I posted somewhere in this thread) "My original comment was for sure not as nuanced or well thought out as I intended it to be (and my thinking has changed somewhat through the course of this discussion), but it's got waaaaay too many replies at this point to change it without looking like an asshole.

My point was that we shouldn't be ignoring the input of people who aren't well-read (think poor folks, people who lack access to adequate education, etc.) simply on the grounds that they aren't experts in a given field. Especially when, oftentimes they are the ones a proposed policy will impact most."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720744617.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But they can be relied upon to advocate for policies that make their lives better, and everyone is an expert on their own life.

That's just not true though, is it? What about antivaxers? Because they might truly believe that their kids got autism from the vaccines they were given. I mean it fits. The anti-vaxers say vaccine-&amp;gt;autism, and that's exactly what happened.

Now, that is an obvious case. But what about rent control? What exactly should the minimum wage be? What about immigration policy, debates about funding. 

Even things that seem simple and good, like foreign aid, have unintended consequences. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720772740.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>You're absolutely right about the antivaxx thing and the foreign aid thing, I didn't think about that aspect. This is a complex issue. I don't know if I'm allowed to give you a delta for changing my mind a little, but my view is definitely more nuanced now.

As for rent control and minimum wage, I would argue that my point still holds. There will always be more tenants than landlords, more employees than bosses. In a perfect democracy, rent control would reflect the interests of tenants, minimum wage would reflect the interests of workers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720792852.0" user="amazondrone" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't know if I'm allowed to give you a delta for changing my mind a little

You're not. ~~Only OP can award deltas in a given thread.~~ Anyone can award a delta, but not to OP.

Edit: I stand corrected, seems I remembered the rule the wrong way around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720868461.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>[Actually](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_4), anyone can award a delta.  It’s not limited to the OP exclusively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721200807.0" user="amazondrone" delta="False">
    <text>Oops, thanks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720805380.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks!

As for the rent control and minimum wage issue. It's not landlords on one side and tenants on the other here. The same with minimum wage. There are bosses that think it should be higher, and there are employees that wish it lower, or gone. You're left with the same issues, and there are studies on both to arm arguments with. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720839456.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>Sure there may be outliers, but I would be willing to bet that most people working at minimum wage jobs would like to be paid more, even if the concept of raising the minimum wage seems bad to them - and that kind of mentality probably has a lot more to do with a flawed political system. In the U.S. at least,  both parties have spent decades convincing people to vote against their best interests. But that doesn't change the reality that most people want to make more money at work and, if given the chance (without political affiliation, of course), would absolutely vote to give themselves a raise.

I've never met a landlord in my life who didn't want to get the most out of their property. That's just supply and demand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720997342.0" user="epelle9" delta="False">
    <text>I think your point right here sort of shows why OP has a point. Everyone wants to be paid more, and everyone wants more jobs. In the simple mind of some people they would go and without doubts say the minimum wage should be higher and they should be paid more, without realizing that with a higher price for paid labor, there will be less supply willing to pay them hay price, and many of them will lose jobs. They know enough about economics to make decisions that impact their daily lives right now, but not enough to know the other possible side effects. This doesn’t mean that they shouldn’t be able to chose having less jobs but being paid more if they do have one, it just means that knowing the right choice for everyone is extremely hard even for people who dedicate their lives to it, so of course there are people that will stick with some beliefs (many of which will be wrong since they don’t know enough to know that they don’t know how it works) , without even knowing the full repercussions of their belief, or why it should or shouldn’t be that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721049956.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>Your point (and to an extent the OP) is based on the idea that potential future harm is worse than current actual harm, and because people can't always see potential future harm, they aren't informed enough to speak on their current actual harm. Which is not a great way to run a society imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721104950.0" user="epelle9" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it’s definitely not a great way to run a society, and in a utopia everyone would be informed enough to make proper decisions, which would impact the most people possible is the best possible way. Thing is the world is not an ideal society, and people failing to view the potential future harm of their uninformed decision has caused their own problems to become bigger. Look into Venezuela for definite proof of that, or Trump for a more debatable (but still real) example of people not knowing what they are doing or how it will affect them and ending up worse. Actually, almost any populist leader will be a good example of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721142944.0" user="ABOBer" delta="False">
    <text>Tbf they're pointing out the problem and saying 'isnt this a problem?' as it isn't being addressed in their eyes, rather than offering the solution which OP provided

The best solution is educating the public to a basic level to understand government, economics and personal development that provides them enough information to make an informed decision and the skills to be able to find and analyse information on their own</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721385605.0" user="Android_Obesity" delta="False">
    <text>That’s pretty much the ELI5 tag line of economics:  a system for trying to balance infinite wants with finite resources.  People often know what they *want* (seems that they’re often wrong about knowing what will actually make them happy but that’s another issue).  That doesn’t mean that they know what the ramifications of that would be on a societal level.  Other times, they simply don’t care how it will impact someone else and are only concerned about how things will impact them and maybe small family/social circles that they care about.


So it’s on people with more expertise and their eye on the bigger picture to balance that out for everyone, IMO.  I can’t help but think that a pure democracy where we all voted on everything with our smartphones would produce an absolute nightmare of a society.


Perhaps, as OP said, I lack the expertise to say and people would surprise me because I don’t know enough about politics and demographics.  But some quick online searches about the US say about a tenth of people never finished high school or got a GED, only about a third have a Bachelor’s degree or higher, the mean IQ is about 98, about 20% have a mental illness (in the broadest sense) and about 5% are severely cognitively impaired, about 1/6 are in poverty and 1/3 in near-poverty or worse, etc.


Sorry if it comes off elitist but the average person knows fuck-all about running a country with 325+ million people in it, the world’s biggest military, and one of the top two economies in the world (US vs China gets subjective for “largest,” IMO).  I know a good bit more than average and still couldn’t come close to doing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720894752.0" user="PeteWenzel" delta="False">
    <text>If there are studies out their to confirm any belief (anti vaccine propaganda not so much - but for and against most economic policies that’s certainly true) then who is entitled to a political view on an issue, anyway?

You explained that even many experts worry that they are not certain what a “right” policy would look like - even concerning their field of knowledge and expertise. That may just serve to show that a technocratic government isn’t necessarily the best idea.

But we as a society have to make decisions on how to organize ourselves and how to deal with a myriad of issues. It seams to me that we should make them in a democratic manner - ideally with a halfway educated and informed electorate. This puts power and responsibility into the hands of all of us and involves us in forming, holding (and revising) strong political beliefs.

Now one might argue that it is hubris to do so but I would argue that it is necessitated by our political system - at least if it is to function as it is supposed to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720985090.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You explained that even many experts worry that they are not certain what a “right” policy would look like - even concerning their field of knowledge and expertise. That may just serve to show that a technocratic government isn’t necessarily the best idea.

Good point, though I didn't advocate for technocracy. 

&amp;gt;But we as a society have to make decisions on how to organize ourselves and how to deal with a myriad of issues. It seams to me that we should make them in a democratic manner - 

I also agree with this. I realize how amazing our societies and living conditions are now, especially seen in the context of history. And also because I think it's much easier to make something worse than it is to make something better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721117065.0" user="WorldOfTrouble" delta="False">
    <text>Not just anti-vaxxers. But the American south comes to mind, people constantly voting against their own interests with Planned parenthood and sex education are unarguably fucking over their own children and making lifemore difficult for themselves. 

Also, not trying to get too political but its hard to avoid it, but republican policy especially in the last two years is in stark opposition to the benefit of his base. 

People often do not vote in their own best interests at all, they vote with feeling and what they want to be true. 

Regardless of whether it benefits them or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721133322.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>Oh absolutely. My original comment was for sure not as nuanced or well thought out as I intended it to be (and my thinking has changed somewhat through the course of this discussion), but it's got waaaaay too many replies at this point to change it without looking like an asshole. 

My point was that we shouldn't be ignoring the input of people who aren't well-read (think poor folks, people who lack access to adequate education, etc.) simply on the grounds that they aren't experts in a given field. Especially when, oftentimes they are the ones a proposed policy will impact most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721436081.0" user="WorldOfTrouble" delta="False">
    <text>Well let me start by saying i dont disagree to an extent. 

Morally, we shouldn't be taking away peoples votes.

However, the question lies with is it more moral to take away someones vote and make the decision for them that will improve their life. 

Or do you give them the choice but then accept everyones life might be worse because of it?

Its a difficult choice, and personally mine would be shovelling money into education to try and get a more educated populous. 

But that probably wouldnt work perfectly either. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722097818.0" user="E36wheelman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As for rent control and minimum wage, I would argue that my point still holds. There will always be more tenants than landlords, more employees than bosses. In a perfect democracy, rent control would reflect the interests of tenants, minimum wage would reflect the interests of workers.

That’s not true- it’s a balance. If only tenants and workers had control over rent and wages no one would be a business owner or a landlord. It takes capital to build buildings and business and that’s what they bring to the table in market equilibrium. Sure, a bunch of tenants could get together and contract into building a condo but it would be a massive undertaking to make even a small complex. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722143720.0" user="RyanKretschmer" delta="False">
    <text>I just want to point out with rent control, the lower it is, the the quicker buildings and facilities fall into disrepair, and this is where slumlords come from. So even trying to help common renters, the policy hurts. So just by looking out for the interests of the masses, it may just hurt them more. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723201554.0" user="draw_it_now" delta="False">
    <text>I would say /u/cats_and_bad_ideas' point is more subtle than that. I think people understand their own economic reality, but there is still a fear of the unknown in everyone.  

People will know that their rent is too high. They will know their wages are too small. They will know their free time is too fleeting. But they may not be able to express why they're afraid of vaccinations, or brown people.  

Both of these things, economic and cultural policies, come from fear, it's just that the "economic fear" is based more in reality, with a more realistic response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723630394.0" user="MasterKaen" delta="False">
    <text>The majority of people aren't antivaxxers though</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723642750.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I know, but it's enough to prove that the guy I responded to was wrong, because the implication is that people can make the same kind of mistake with every belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723661957.0" user="MasterKaen" delta="False">
    <text>The idea with democracy is that people may be wrong sometimes, but the majority is usually right. This is not always true, but the antivaxxers movement isn't people of it being wrong. A lot of problems in American democracy can be explained by flaws in our political system too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720794068.0" user="hexane360" delta="False">
    <text>This is completely not the point of democracy. It's not "capitalism with one vote", where everyone votes in their own self interest and we see where the chips fall. It only works if most people try to vote in *society's* best interest. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720815873.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>Let's look at minimum wage as an example. In a perfect democracy, one in which everyone's vote counted equally and everyone voted, the question of raising minimum wage comes up. There are more people working minimum wage jobs than there are people who would benefit from keeping the wage low. If, in this perfect system, the votes were tallied, minimum wage would go up because the majority of people voted in their own best interest. It doesn't work like that in reality, but in theory it should. It does definitely get more complicated with broader societal policies, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720848587.0" user="hexane360" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but that doesn't mean it works for all policies. Look at environmental regulations. Any one individual doesn't have much effect on the environment, so it's a net negative for them to be regulated. But it's a net positive for everyone if they're regulated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720880296.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>I'm bad at Reddit, so i can't figure out how to quote it, but my comment literally ended with "It does definitely get more complicated with broader societal policies, though."

That said, I live in Colorado, and fracking is a big issue here. The number of people fracking benefits is small compared to the number of people it harms. Put it to a vote, it would definitely be more regulated than it is. The only people who want fracking to happen within 1000 feet of a school are oil executives, literally no one else wants that. Of course it has more complicated repercussions, but in theory, those repercussions would be handled in the same way as the initial problem, and eventually an equilibrium would be reached.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720849088.0" user="Otherones5" delta="False">
    <text>Society's best interest is itself part of one's own best interest to many people, probably including you.  So by voting in your own best interest you are probably in part voting for society's best interest as well.  Plus people generally understand that when they cast a vote, they're affecting change that will impact more than just themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720897191.0" user="hexane360" delta="False">
    <text>There are still edge cases where the sum of individual interests is diggerent from the collective interest. See the Tragedy of the Commons.

&amp;gt;people generally understand that when they cast a vote, they're affecting change that will impact more than just themselves.

I agree, but the OP I replied to contradicted this, arguing that only self interest is necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721195575.0" user="Otherones5" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose what I'm claiming is that self interest is societal interest to a certain extent due to our communal culture.  As you've said there are divergences, and these divergences indicate a failure in democracy.  Is this an area that could be improved?  Sure, if you cultivate even more societal awareness and social responsibility in people.  Is this an area that causes democracy to fail fundamentally as a system?  I don't think so.  We're doing okay as far as treating society with the same respect we treat ourselves.  Seems like the fact that we are having this discussion on its own lends credence to this notion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720912666.0" user="Scary_Llama" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;you are probably in part voting for society's best interest as well.

This is just false. A minority ethnic/ideological bloc could easily rally to push their interests at the expense of society as a whole. And societal degradation is a slow process, so the effects won't be felt until possibly years/decades down the line. Most people are not responsible or informed enough to vote on domestic problems that don't affect them directly, let alone foreign affairs or economic policies. But we let them do it anyway.

People literally voted for Hillary because "it was her turn" and Trump to own the libtards. That's the voter base in this country. Democracy will always create voting blocs and party loyalty, policy be damned. That's the end result, and we're starting to see the cracks in the system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721154002.0" user="Otherones5" delta="False">
    <text>My claim was not so strong as to deny the existence of issues on which people vote, thinking they are voting the right way, but are actually misinformed and are voting against society.  My point is that, in general people are not so self centered that they vote only with themselves in mind.  I think you're coming from a perspective that exaggerates the importance of the issues on which many people disagree, when in reality there are many issues we take agreement for granted on, and this agreement opens the opportunity for aligned belief in societal benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721163823.0" user="Pl0OnReddit" delta="False">
    <text>That's not a mistake..  Our political system was built to divide numerous interests and have them compete, thus diminishing their individual power.  People vote for lots of stupid reasons and some don't vote and some vote for "correct" reasons.  BUT, that's not an unforseen outcome of democracy.

Madison calls them factions and writes abou them in Federalist 10.

As an aside, there is a reason suffrage was initially linked to property ownership.   The original concept isn't that any joker with two feet and maybe a brain can vote,  but that those invested in society should have a voice in society.  Universal suffrage exacerbates problems but the system of scattering various competing interests across the country does seem to work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720932900.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>As u/hexane360 pointed out above, this isn’t always the case.  One example is a large number of companies that all rely on clean water from the same lake, but would individually have to pay money for a filter if they wanted to stop their companies from polluting the lake.  Individually, the best thing to do is to not buy a filter—each company will only slightly impact the water quality overall—but this naturally results in an equilibrium where nobody buys filters, the lake is disgusting, and everybody is worse off.  The same goes for the situation where 51% of a population votes to keep the other 49% in brutal slavery.  And another possibility is that almost everybody favors a simple, intuitive (and wrong) solution, and a few people favor a more complicated, counterintuitive (correct) solution.  There are certainly lots of situations where everybody voting in their own perceived best interest will achieve the best outcome, but in general, voting can be relied on as an optimization process.  (Although it’s usually pretty good at eliminating very bad solutions.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721239386.0" user="Otherones5" delta="False">
    <text>Welllll if we were seeing something so radical as 51% of society enslaving the other 49% I would not give my claim any credence.  I don't think there's anything that even comes close to being able to be described in such radical terms.  It is possible for what you describe to happen in democracy, and we see it happening on a micro scale or at low levels of significance, but this observation does not mean democracy is a failure (unless, as OP suggested, people vote only in the interest of society).  And this is probably not what OP or you mean.  I just wanted to underscore the idea that self interest on its own is not generally a term that discludes the interest of society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721390981.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I agree with that.  My point was that although voting plus self interest can work (it’s certainly better than guessing randomly), it’s not an efficient system.  I do think that it’s good at pruning out the worst outcomes and allowing a moderate amount of flexibility when it comes to changing societal views, but in terms of passing good policies, like private vs public healthcare, it’s not very efficient.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720948992.0" user="dysGOPia" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But they can be relied upon to advocate for policies that make their lives better, and everyone is an expert on their own life.

No they can't and no they aren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720965221.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that, for example, LGBTQ folks can't be relied upon to vote in their best interests? That they don't know what those interests are? That they should trust politicians to decide what those interests are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721043330.0" user="dysGOPia" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm saying that religious fundamentalists vote based on fairy tales and poor racists unwittingly vote against their own interests.

https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/2018/06/06/trade-war-ruin-donald-trump-voters-american-economy-column/674058002/

http://time.com/5266409/donald-trump-elections-farmers-rural-voters/

https://thinkprogress.org/trump-climate-policies-will-hurt-red-states-economic-growth-1af84ee6a2d5/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723509428.0" user="bleahdeebleah" delta="False">
    <text>I suspect they define 'interests' differently</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721847972.0" user="Voted_Quimby" delta="False">
    <text>Can they be relied upon to vote in their best interest on LGBTQ issues, sure probably. Those usually boil down to a simple choice between having rights or not having them.

Can they be relied upon to vote in their best interest when it comes to tax policy or healthcare or something else complex, probably not. Just like everyone else. I would assume most LGBTQ people are not single-issue voters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720983913.0" user="KingMelray" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's the premise that democracy is built on: that people can be relied upon to vote in their own best interest. And if the majority of people do that, the resulting policy should, in theory, help the most people.

This might be a decent starter, but it can lead down a dark path.  If 75% of people decide their lives will be far easier if we made the other 25% of people slaves more people's lives would technically be better off.  It would just be at the radical expense of the minority. 

I am aware this is an extreme example to make a point, but many countries in history pillage their own citizens at the benefit of others.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721085168.0" user="eyebrows360" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't need to have read Marx or Adam Smith to understand my own economic reality.

To some very general meaning of "understand" then sure. But also no; you *do* need to be well read if you want to have a chance at understanding the reasons behind it, and to proof yourself against being bamboozled by charismatic nefarious actors telling you the causes are things that'll ultimately turn you in to a pawn of theirs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721106782.0" user="cats_and_bad_ideas" delta="False">
    <text>I think people are a lot smarter than this comment gives them credit for. As an example, during the early war in Iraq, I was a child (read: not very smart or well-read), but I still understood that there was a link between the war and the cost of gasoline, even if i couldn't put my finger on exactly what it was.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721189590.0" user="eyebrows360" delta="False">
    <text>The two bits of knowledge "wars get fought for oil due to oil being the basis of the developed world" and "this war is one of these wars despite the official narrative trying to bamboozle us with 'freedom' BS" don't just happen inside the heads of children apropos of nothing. For child-you to know these things implies that you *were* well-read, or let's say well-enough-read, by the mere fact you knew them.

I don't think it's a great analogy anyway; politics &amp;amp; economics are *vastly* different ball games to war. Wars such as the one you cite happen usually for a singular claimed reason, and a singular actual reason that the government try to hide - but there's at most usually two. Economical and political systems within a nation state are *vastly* more complex things, with actors left and right claiming many different causes and factors for every single issue. It's a literal minefield that even people who *enjoy* looking in to these topics struggle to keep up with, let alone your average Joe who just wants his rent to stop being so high.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721216757.0" user="sfurbo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't need to be a political science major to know how various policies impact my life and the lives of those around me. I understand these things because they happen in my life.

Yes, you do. Just like you need to study medicine to know what the effects of various treatments are, or need to study engineering to know how to determine the carrying capacity of a bridge.

Society is a complicated construction, and complicated construction often have unintuitive reactions to changing conditions. Rent control might make your rent lower, but could also reduce the amount of holese for rent. You can't tell which of those effects is going to have the bigger impact on your life simply by living your life. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721221880.0" user="zacker150" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People will always advocate for change that benefits them and theirs.

I disagree. People will always advocate for the policies that *they think* will benefit them. Whether or not these policies will *actually* benefit them requires a decent background in economics. 

So while it would be a good idea to listen to people about what our goals (full unemployment, low  inflation, high economic growth, etc), we should not listen to them about how to accomplish said goals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721224537.0" user="MasterPsyduck" delta="False">
    <text>There are issues with this logic, people think they are experts on everything in their life but the gaps in knowledge lead to things like being misled by politicians and finding an easy scape goat to target instead of the true source of their problems. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721241611.0" user="Ambrosita" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But they can be relied upon to advocate for policies that make their lives better, and everyone is an expert on their own life.  

This is the thing that always gets me.  People like to pretend like their ideals are noble and true, but they're always just campaigning for themselves and rarely anybody else.  Its okay that it works like this, but please stop claiming the moral high ground about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721347875.0" user="wolfkeeper" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People will always advocate for change that benefits them and theirs.

I simply don't think that's true. Many, many people vote for nationalist causes, irrespective of whether they themselves benefit, or racist causes that may harm another group, but will also harm themselves to some extent.

In other cases, people have been systematically exposed to propaganda that causes them to vote against their best interests; for example Brexit, and the election of Donald Trump are likely examples of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721395787.0" user="TheNoize" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't need to have read Marx or Adam Smith to understand my own economic reality

You sure about that? I REEEALLY beg to differ.   


You don't need to read Marx or Adam Smith to have an uninformed OPINION about your economic reality.  


As for understanding your economic reality - you better crack open the Marx and start studying</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721449909.0" user="taosaur" delta="False">
    <text>Self-interest, specifically short-sighted and ill-informed self-interest, is also the foundation stone on which any con is built. Believing you are acting in your own self-interest is a great way to get conscripted into someone else's army without even knowing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721511581.0" user="Zephos65" delta="False">
    <text>My one problem with this is that they may realize short term effects of different policies ("my taxes got lowered so I don't have to pay as much yay!") But may not have the foresight to see long term effects ("now I don't get free healthcare, free education, et cetera").

Most policies and economic actions are to complex for *anyone*, let alone the layman, to be able to tell if it will have a net benefit to society </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721735916.0" user="zzzztopportal" delta="False">
    <text>They’ll advocate for the policy that they think makes them better off.  See: trumples voting for less welfare</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722661651.0" user="I_love_Coco" delta="False">
    <text>Well put - essentially the invisible hand at work in our democracy.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723191362.0" user="myrthe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People will always advocate for change that benefits them and theirs. Will they always advocate for the "correct" policies? The ones that help the greatest number of people? Most likely not. But they can be relied upon to advocate for policies that make their lives better, and everyone is an expert on their own life.

You've gotten a lot of pushback on this para, but I like what you were going for here. After pondering the same problem for a bit here's what I came to: People won't reliably vote the best for society, or the policy that will be best for them, or even policy they perceive to be best for them... but - they are the one person who can best be relied on to make decisions with their own perceived interests at heart. Anyone else we empower to make decisions will or may have competing priorities.

That isn't much of a claim left, but it's all Democracy has going for it... and it's better than any other system I know.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
