<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720561631.0" user="justtogetridoflater" delta="False">
    <text>That's kind of not how society works. You don't expect this of anyone else in any field. You don't expect 1 engineer to design the whole product from scratch most of the time. It's a collaboration often relying upon basic foundations of other people's work before it even gets to the drawing board. And before it gets to the drawing board you often have a guy with no knowledge, a chequebook, and a list of demands of the product. You then pass that to sales people and they don't need to know necessarily how it works or why it's actually better. They'll produce the best narrative they can given a limited understanding. And then you drop it into the shops with a dozen others all claiming to be the best to people who don't know about the product. And that person buys it and they need nothing except how to use it. And if you think about how your average man uses a washing machine, not even to a particularly large extent. Nonetheless that person will develop a feel for what works. That washing machine worked so that brand works. That car broke down so you don't buy another. And so on.

The job of politicians is to set out a list of aims. They have to take it to experts who will work out what can be done. And having received that information they have to persuade people that their way is the best. People don't need to know everything to vote on the plan. They just need to understand a framework of the ideas conveyed. 

And if they can understand the frame work they can argue on an issue by issue basis updating themselves as they go.. Is that subject to bias and ignorance? Of course. But as long as things work overall, we don't end up in a situation that makes that so disastrous.

I think what truly matters here is that information is conveyed in an easy to understand way and that there is a bare minimum understanding of these issues.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
