<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="107" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30723542928.0" user="JohnnyFlan" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for this thread, it is by far one of the most interesting ones I've read in a while. 

I would like to argue that reaching an expert consensus is sometimes a very hard, costly and long process which would be incompatible with the speed at which decisions have to be made in today's society. Moreover, expert consensus is also different from science-based decision-making, take medicine for example, it's not uncommon for guidelines to be drawn based on expert consensus, however this is the lowest form of recommendation possible (the weakest form of guideline recommendation). Why? Well because the simple need to use the expert consensus points out the lack of hard factual evidence provided by randomised control trials or meta-analysis. (And this sort of evidence strength would even be more difficult/impossible to achieve in other areas such as social security, law or economics). So in my opinion an expert consensus based society (technocratic) would be unrealistic and unachievable. 

What I would propose as an alternative solution was an "informed democratic society" meaning that more and more decisions would be made by the public (either by referendum/electronic referendum, or other sorts of direct voting), but, to be able to vote you would have to show a basic knowledge of the question and the consequences of either decision. I'll give two examples. 

-Local level: population decides whether to build a new hospital or not. In order to qualify you for the town hall meeting you have to show (through a questionnaire) that you understand that building the hospital would lead to a cost-sparing closure of two schools or an increase in x% of the municipal tax.

-national level: building 3 new aircraft carries would lead to shortening the health budget and therefore end the free distribution of contraceptive pills nationwide. (With all the increase in unwanted births that would come out of that)

Now I know that not every decision can be boiled down to a "a+b = c" question, but I would argue that that is not the point, because since you actually had to seek some knowledge about the question, the voting-population in general would understand the nuances of the policies and be directly involved in the decision making. (Hence no " I'll vote yes because the democrat guy wants me to vote no and I've been a republican whole my life" kind of voting)

Moreover, the experts would be responsible (through some sort of imparcial government backed institution) for making the "basic information" package available for the whole population clearly stating the facts and general currents of thought about the issue, this way making sure everyone would have access to the basic knowledge required to vote on the issue.

Please note that the politicians would still be involved in advocating for one solution over the other according to their ideology and personal interests of course. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
