<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720873147.0" user="JamesDevitt" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going make sort of a counterclaim. A lot of well-read people don't have the proper kind of life experiences for properly formed views of politics or economics. I can think of my own life. I came out of university with a philosophy degree and all sorts of interesting ideas about how a society might be governed. Then I moved to Baltimore and saw how people really lived and my views changed completely. Then I started my own reading of Anthropology which has an advantage over more navel-gazing subjects as economics and philosophy of actually empirically looking at how people live. (Did you know that no society actually ever bartered for their daily needs?! Economist made up that grognard from their easy chairs!!!) So really, I think often we need a lot more less-well-read people entering the conversation.

I will definitely agree with you that the state of discourse is terrible. One thing I do hold dear from my study of philosophy is the principle of charity. Where you should assume (until proven otherwise) that other people are arguing in good faith and trying to work out the truth. If you can interpret something two ways, one that has a point and one that doesn't make any sense; to always interpret it in their favor.  But I think the source of the poor level of discourse isn't uneducated people, but the ad-driven media. Anger sells. Fear sells. If people were given a proper room in meat-space to encounter the other with snacks and comfortable chairs, I think people could work more stuff out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
