<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720727720.0" user="froggerslogger" delta="False">
    <text>I think that you are correct that most people cannot possibly understand the complexity of most issues.  I definitely changed a lot of my views about this when I went to grad school.  Surrounded by lots of people with more knowledge than me, who still didn’t fully understand specific issues.  Even the professors would sometimes be open about this.  

But I think that advocation and politics are essentially separate from actual issue understanding.  They are foundationally moral issues, not issues of pragmatic optimized decision making.  You might be correct that the optimization is desireable, but our system is set up to decide between moral systems and not practical systems. 

I’d suggest something like Lakoff’s Moral Politics for a more in depth examination of this dynamic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720857148.0" user="Tinac4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But I think that advocation and politics are essentially separate from actual issue understanding. They are foundationally moral issues, not issues of pragmatic optimized decision making. You might be correct that the optimization is desireable, but our system is set up to decide between moral systems and not practical systems.

I think that you’re not entirely wrong, but aren’t correct either.  Not all political disagreements are purely moral ones.  Of course, some are.  For instance, some people may think that taxation is a form of theft and is morally wrong regardless of its benefits, and other people may think that anything less than pure communism and perfect redistribution of wages is morally wrong.

But most examples of disagreement are not entirely the result of differing moral views.  It’s usually some combination of different moral views *and* different beliefs about what the facts are.  (The proportion of each may vary widely.)  Sometimes it’s just the latter:  I think that raising the minimum wage slightly will probably make people better off on the whole without affecting the economy strongly, but someone else might think that it will harm the economy and lead to poor people getting laid off, making people worse off.  A third person might think that any damage done to the economy by raising the minimum wage to $13 will be outweighed by the employees’ benefits, and that layoffs will be relatively minor.  Everyone in this example may hold the same moral view—that it’s best to make as many people as well off as possible—but they disagree on the consequences of each policy, and consequently have different overall positions.

A large number of issues may involve a mix of both moral and factual disagreements.  And in many cases, it’s difficult to separate the two.  I’m largely in agreement with [this blog post](http://slatestarcodex.com/2018/07/18/fundamental-value-differences-are-not-that-fundamental/), which expresses my view better than I can.  We appear to disagree primarily about the extent to which moral or factual disagreements influence positions, but in my experience, both are commonplace.  You can’t discard one of the two caused altogether, and even that binary can be an oversimplification.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
