<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720673734.0" user="Dr_Scientist_" delta="False">
    <text>One way to help explain the collapse of the Soviet Union is the inefficiencies baked into the system by far-away central authority bureaucrats micro-managing on-the-ground operations. 

It doesn't help when your country's leader is a murderous totalitarian strongman, the central bureaucrats are just whoever's left after purges have hollowed out the country's effective leadership, etc. There's a lot of things wrong with Soviet Russia. 

But it was also partly this inability to trust locals with their own self-governance that led to it's collapse. The manager of a shoe factory can't be allowed to determine how many shoes they can produce, the central authority will decide! The disconnect between the on-the-ground experience and even someone diligently trying to come up with the right number from a thousand miles away in Moscow is going to produce unfavorable results.

People who live and work in an area are those **MOST KNOWLEDGEABLE** about what sort of economic and political reform they need. It would be a huge mistake to think that just because a group of people don't have a strong education, that they would mis-identify political or economic grievances important to them. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
