<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="93" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30722260552.0" user="ray07110" delta="False">
    <text>If you feel that being well-read is important to make political or economic decisions then you have to define what being well read is. There so many books out there and history is so long that not one person is a master of all facts, except maybe god. Socrates, according to Plato, understood that he was not a supreme holder of knowledge. Knowledge comes from life experiences and our interaction with the world around us, not books. Books are just records of knowledge not a producer of it. Life is a learning experience. Reading can help with decisions you make in it but it is not the be all and end all of making a choice. That is why you have well-educated people with different political and economic views. All these educated people in government and we are still in more than 8 trillion dollars of debt, I think. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722272233.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Books are just records of knowledge not a producer of it

Right, but the book still needs to be read for you to acquire it's knowledge. They produce knowledge in someone lacking it. I know older people that do nothing but bide their time, and they're not growing knowledgeable. 

But yes, "well read" is a poor choice of words for what I wanted to say. Doctor Oz is well read, and yet a quack.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722954885.0" user="ray07110" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so let me ask you this: What would be included in you criteria as to the amount and type of knowledge that is necessary to engage in a political or economic action or decision?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723306566.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I've never said that we should make such a divide. It would be pretty hypocritical to do so based on what I said in my OP, no? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30727782827.0" user="ray07110" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that everyone who comments on politics wants to set the standard on who can and cannot have commentary on any issue having to deal with public policy. We all have an opinion on how the government should act in order to solve an issue or set a convention. We should not base the criteria of running for office or debating issues on education or level of due diligence, but on the facts stated.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
