<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="48" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720979667.0" user="Saranoya" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that uncertainty is a mark of intelligence. 

People who don’t know what they don’t know (and we’ve all been there, at some point or on some issue) will indeed often assert their opinions with great conviction, no matter how nonsensical those opinions may be. When you know enough to understand that most things are far more complex than they seem, it can become difficult to form an opinion that satisfies your own standards of rigor on anything. I don’t think you should consider this a reason to get frustrated or angry with the people who form their opinions more easily than you do, although I recognize that frustration or anger are rarely the result of a conscious decision to get frustrated or angry. When you have more difficulty than someone else forming a ‘quick and dirty’ opinion on any given issue, consider that a sign that you may well be much better informed on that issue than that other person.

That being said ... does this mean that people who are less informed cannot express their opinions anymore? I say answering yes to that question is a recipe for disaster. When someone is advocating for a certain kind of change, and you know that what they’re proposing is unlikely to work the way they think it will, because it’s been tried before, it doesn’t help to say to them: “That thing you’re proposing makes no sense, so shut up and come back when you’ve read and understood these ten books on the subject.” It makes sense to listen to their concerns and start a conversation. “OK, it seems to me that you’re concerned about X. It’s good that you’re speaking up so we, as a society, can start thinking about solutions to your problem. Would you like to tell me a bit more about what your core problem is, and what you think might help you?”

If you do the latter, the person will feel heard. That is a first step of monumental importance. If handled well, it may prevent the situation from escalating further. And it encourages the person to speak up next time they have a problem — even if they don’t know the solution. 

You don’t have to know exactly what the best way to handle any given situation is before you’re allowed to speak up. If you don’t speak up (and nobody else with your problem does), then the people who do know how to handle your problem, or who might be reasonably equipped to figure something out, won’t know that they should be working on your particular issue.

Not everyone can (or should) be an expert on everything. But there are enough people out there who are experts on one thing in particular. And if they don’t get input from non-experts, they might be solving the wrong problems.        </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
