<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="95" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30722368528.0" user="GingerJack76" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're right, but I think there does need to be some form of clarification.

Yes, most people aren't well-read enough on their history, their philosophy, their economic theory, political ideology, and so on and so forth. And many times people will advocate for things that they don't understand, they're not very well read on, and they don't know the consequences of. Although I'd say that it's not something that you would need to spend thousands of hours of doing in order to become sufficient to make a reasonable decision on the matter, it's just that you need to read a broad range of things rather than a specific thing.

But there's really nothing that we can do about it, and we have to treat people as though they are capable of making informed decisions on the matter.

Let's assume that people aren't generally well-read enough to advocate for the change that they want to see, mainly because they just don't know what the consequences of what they're advocating for are. The logic leads us down to a technocracy, we're select individuals of certain amounts of intelligence, or in this case more wisdom, are able to vote on issues for the rest of the country. The problem with this is that it's an oligarchy by nature, and because it's an oligarchy it will inevitably oppress the people that do not have the decision to vote. And it's not like the people at the top or anything special, they're just more well-read than the rest of the populace and can make informed decisions, but that doesn't necessarily mean that they're moral decisions.

So yes, people need to be more diligent with what they advocate for, everyone could stand to read more about what their ideology promotes and to go about engaging with politics with high amounts of skepticism and conservatism, and I mean that not in a political sense but in a "changing things is very hard and you will most likely fuck it up if you aren't careful" mentality.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
