<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="104" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30723178517.0" user="Bismar7" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a bit late to this, but this was something I addressed for myself, given my own due diligence in all three of those subjects. 

If we view economics as a function of time, and politics as the system of time management then the only question becomes why we allow for those who lack comprehension of political science and economics to determine those who create the system of time management? 

We have people who invest that time to become professionals. I want a licensed pilot to fly my plane, an expert PhD holding surgeon to perform surgeries, an engineer to create the foundation of a skyscraper. I do not expect an 18 adult to do these things. Why then are they expected to hold the expertise of someone wise enough to lead politically? Why then are they expected to be well enough informed of the premise? 

I don't exactly disagree with your premise, but I disagree with stopping where you have. The answer does not lie in presuming the end reasoning is that there won't be, or shouldn't be, sociopolitical advocation. The end reasoning is that the goal of those dealing with the function of time should hold those managing the system of time management accountable, instead of choosing them worthy. 

In essence, people should not vote to put others in office. There should only be democratic votes of no confidence in order to kick people out of office. Beyond which the determination of choosing those worthy to lead should be left to lovers of wisdom. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
