<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720516824.0" user="Priddee" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that people without degrees in Economics or Philosophy shouldn't talk about it within their circles? Or that they shouldn't be taken seriously in Academia? Because I promise they're not taken seriously in Academia, and I encourage people to talk about Economics and Philosophy, that's how you get more people in the field. As someone in both of the fields, the more the merrier. 

When people advocate for economic positions through politics, they are usually pushing for some result they want. They don't really understand the how or why past maybe the big details. The left generally says we have all these poor people we need to help, and we need to do something to help them. The right generally says free markets create the opportunity for everyone to get richer. So people pick what fits their beliefs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720644038.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that they can't reasonably hold the views that they do, for the reasons stated in my OP. 

I'm pretty sure that's true. But obviously the prescription is not for people to just not talk about these subjects. I'm also not really talking about academia. I love to discuss these politics, economics and philosophy, and I think people so do more of it even if I've been reduced to simply argue why people are probably wrong, because that's all I know. 

I'm not sure what I'm saying myself, or what the implications of my assertion is. Maybe I'm just disillusioned by the current state of the discourse. Though, I'm not sure how much it matters. I remember reading some letters between Bastiat and Proudhon, and I was shocked that they were having the exact same debates that I were having at the time, making the same points that I saw on reddit every day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720677471.0" user="Priddee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm that they can't reasonably hold the views that they do

There's a difference between being rationally justified in holding a position, and it being right. Someone who has someone who is informed in the subject describes and explains a view is enough for people to latch on to it. The issue is that there are always the more intricate details that laypeople don't know or sometimes even care to know that hide the flaws in the view. This is where being someone informed on the subject, and talking to someone who isn't, gets frustrating. That's why you argue why people are wrong or probably wrong. 

But if the goal of all of this is to find the best answers to the questions we have, discourse is good period. It gets people excited about the subjects, and into the field. Heck, that's why I got my degrees, it started with late-night conversations with friends who equally had no idea what we were talking about. But that's okay, there is no requirement of knowledge to talk about these issues. 

But back to the original point, People hate the idea of saying "I don't have an opinion" about any given topic. The honest thing is to jump into the literature or field and absorb information before you hold a position, but people don't do that. They usually latch on to what they hear last, or what fits their current worldview. But their at least in a loose sense 'justified' in holding the view. Even if it's for bad reasons. Because they don't know they're bad reasons. I know that's a weird concept and seems counterintuitive, but it's how it works. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
