<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="49" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720991949.0" user="tyrannicalblade" delta="False">
    <text>I think your main point is wrong ,as people do not need to be well read on a specific subject to be able to express themselves or how things affect them or how they simply seem to be... I think your issue here is that you do not feel like knowledge has given you the power you seeked for, but instead just more questions, and that is true as far as any science, the more you know, the more the universe expands on it.  


What you do need is to have some reasonable logical mind, patience, and open mind to accept new ideas or that the ones you held were wrong, On that part if "that" what you meant by  well read, then perhaps you are right... But i do not think the issue here is that for example, people advocate for policy 1 (that has a not fully concensus study backing it up) or policy 2 that has more backing from the science community... Its more that you see both policies and only see at the studies, but fail to see the other issues surrounding them, for example, you can be unsure which of 2 studies is wrong on a economic level, but more likely, 1 study has a much higher impact on other grounds, for example nothing to do with economy, but since you made an example of anti vaxers and stuff, there are economic studies to support that lifting enviriomental regulations on several markets would help the economy, and then there others that say, going fully green is just better economily because of a longer term mentality... My point is, you can make a case for both things on a purely economical level, but the issue here is treating it as an only economic thing, there is moral grounds, and logical grounds that need to be ignored to support those things, for example, thinking that you can pour chemicals on oceans or rivers, and have no impact on enviroment, animal wild life, and even human life, is just stupid, and you do not need any kind of studies backing that up, is like, you do not need a study to tell you a knife wound might make you bleed... you just know...   


I don't know if i have made my point across but this is what i meant to say, im not sure what exactly are those things where you sit uncertain unable to articulate why , but i think, in lack of knowledge, a set of values and logical view is where things come in together, sadly a lot of people use that lack of knowledge or those blind spots on science to push in their harmful agenda that normally is to either fill their pockets of fast money disregarding any consequences, or to opress the people they do not like. And here is where you should come to defend the other side of that blind spot even in lack of full knowledge, because even if you are not sure, you do know the effects on other values you have, or grounds...at least logically </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721013255.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think your main point is wrong ,as people do not need to be well read on a specific subject to be able to express themselves or how things affect them or how they simply seem to be... I think your issue here is that you do not feel like knowledge has given you the power you seeked for, but instead just more questions, and that is true as far as any science, the more you know, the more the universe expands on it.

I think you're right to an extent, in that part of what motivated this post was an immature sense of "it's not fair". I also think my choice of words was poor, as some heterodox quack can also be very well read. 

&amp;gt;What you do need is to have some reasonable logical mind, patience, and open mind to accept new ideas or that the ones you held were wrong

That what I did. I went out looking for answers, not just within the framework of democracy, but also, maybe especially more radical schools of thought. And the deeper I got, the less clear things became. At one point I was a little well read, but also relatively certain of the truth, and I advocated for it, wrongly. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721075005.0" user="tyrannicalblade" delta="False">
    <text>Well the thing is that, science and politics, are never meant to be something that we as people ever get wrong, we always will be wrong until we find out how we were wrong, we'll support chemicals, and policies that unbeknownst to us, harm us in the long term, our understanding in anything and everything is doom to be flawed, for our understanding only begins when we feel its at its peak, its ever changing and evolving, thing we do now and we advocate daily, might be proven wrong later on, but you shouldn't let that discourage you from taking a stand, and if you are standing on moral grounds and common decency, chances are, even if studies do not follow you fully, they will... Sadly if we all took a scientific aproach, and said, well, we do not know enough to really know anything, then we would never do anything or progress... Innovation would crumble, and we'd be stuck in past practices until proven without a shade of doubt to be wrong, and by then it will be too late, taking risks and taking sides will always be important to human progress even if we have to get through some shit talkers that will try to manipulate the uncertainty into selfish made harmful agendas.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
