<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="75" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721539690.0" user="poorfolkbows" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn't follow that because the truth has been elusive to you that it has therefore been elusive to everybody else. It could be that some people have an easier time discovering the truth than others. Or it could be that some people have stumbled on the truth by accident.

I'm with you on economics. It's voodoo to me.

But let me give you a philosophical issue in which I know with 100% certain that I am correct even though there are people who are a gazillion times smarter than me who disagree with me. I know with certainty that the basic laws of logic (law of excluded middle, non-contradiction, etc.) are absolutely true in all possible worlds under all possible circumstances and that it does not depend on what anybody actually thinks or believes. But I had a philosophy professor who disagree with that, and there are lots of professional philosophers who disagree with it. I know with certainty that they are absolutely wrong.

So the mere fact that experts disagree on something is no reason to conclude that nobody knows the right answer or that you can't figure out the right answer.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721661660.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;t doesn't follow that because the truth has been elusive to you that it has therefore been elusive to everybody else. It could be that some people have an easier time discovering the truth than others. Or it could be that some people have stumbled on the truth by accident.

And what, they're hiding it from the rest of us? The truth I mean.

It's not that I didn't understand economics. It's that when faced with all of these schools, and having learned enough to see the nuance, and the depth, I couldn't reasonably say that the school I liked the best, and agreed with, was correct. I would spend days debating economics. I loved it. I've also taken 4-5 classes economics in the past couple of years. But agreeing with something doesn't make it true. And I read some criticism about the school I thought was true, that put some of that into question. But of course, I had also spent years critiquing every other school, because they were wrong, and I was right. 

&amp;gt;I know with certainty that they are absolutely wrong.

&amp;gt;So the mere fact that experts disagree on something is no reason to conclude that nobody knows the right answer or that you can't figure out the right answer.

I actually agree with you on the logic thing, and the sentiment in general. But, philosophy has no real consensus. So there's nothing to lean on. But that's not the case in economics, or medicine. Medicine is perhaps the best example, given how much misinformation and nonsense is out there, that people actually believe. Do you agree that it's unreasonable to disagree with the consensus there? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721684360.0" user="poorfolkbows" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you agree that it's unreasonable to disagree with the consensus there?

I think in most cases where there are experts that you should lean in favour of the consensus unless you have really good reason to think the consensus of experts are wrong. And that's usually how most of us know anything at all when it comes to history or science. We ourselves haven't done the math or the experiments or made the observations. We simply believe what the experts have said, and I think it's rational for us to do so.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
