<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="42" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720882098.0" user="ChineseTradeWar" delta="False">
    <text>You don't need to produce air tight arguments to advocate for change, you just need to convince somebody else to change their mind. Most voters aren't well informed and may not listed to the even the most well articulated stance. If you can convince your dumbass friends and family to vote differently, you're more successful than 99% of activists who march in the streets and scream at strangers. 

You seem to be talking about analysis paralysis and believing there's some kind of ultimate answer out there that you're on the path to and others aren't. In reality, nobody is going to find that ultimate truth so we stick with utility. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720924482.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>That's why I used to word "reasonably". I know that change is possible, but that doesn't mean that it's reasonable. It's not so much paralysis as it is discovering how weak my positions were, when confronted with all of the uncertainty. 

You are right in that I'm assuming that truth exists. But even when it come to achieving utility, the same problems exist to a lesser degree. Ask a Keynesian and a monetarist on how to maximize it, they will give different answers, both having devoted their lives to the question.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
