<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720691664.0" user="hoolahoopmolly" delta="False">
    <text>What you claim is only true if there exists only one objective truth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720703588.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Or if people tend to have similar goals, but many roads there. It is true that given a goal, there will be *a* best way to get there. A straight line between to points, and all that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720737094.0" user="hoolahoopmolly" delta="False">
    <text>No I’ll be able to find tons of example where this is not true.
The most obvious since you mention politics: I think it would be easy to agree that most people want a society where people are happy, healthy and prosper. But how to achieve this, you’ll find thousands of contradictory opinions all of which would be true depending on perspective.

If I took your claim and brought it to the most extreme then we should have a technocrat society where a council of the best read scholars run the show.
I think many people would agree this is not very appealing.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720793989.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Not every perspective will allow you to see the world clearly. Someone mistaking screams for laughter and saying "hey, we should do more of what lead to that" is not operating on anything true. If you want to achieve something, then the number of legitimate perspectives and opinions will very quickly fall. 

The consequences of what I'm saying don't have an effect of whether it's true or not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720864529.0" user="hoolahoopmolly" delta="False">
    <text>There can easily be many true perspectives. 
Imagine if what you said was true, every median income family would drive the same car because that car is objectively the best car.
Only they don’t because people have different focus, experience, vantage points, aspirations etc etc.

It’s very rare that there is only one truth. The more complex your goal is the more true that is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720882867.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Holding an opinion about the kind of music you prefer is not the same as holding an opinion about the minimum wage, or the morality of abortion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720988425.0" user="hoolahoopmolly" delta="False">
    <text>I haven’t mentioned music, my example was a car, very different.

Now you start to stray, you mentioned goals, there’s always a best way to a goal.
Now you talk morality, abortion y/n.

I support the idea of a US minimum wage (which should be significantly higher) because there are working poor in that country, yet I live in a country with no minimum wage and that’s fine because we don’t have poverty here. So my position shifts depending on circumstances.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
