<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="100" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30722744565.0" user="accelaboy" delta="False">
    <text>People who are not being served by their government will advocate for change because they are suffering. They do not need understand the finer points of economic policy to recognize when they are being oppressed and exploited.

The actual policies that address these problems may indeed come from highly educated thinker-types. In fact, if you take any one of the world's problems as an example, you will find plenty of solutions in the form of theories and proposed policies coming form the world's most educated people.

But when you look for implementation of these policies, you'll find that honest attempts to improve the lives of the lowest classes are pretty rare. For example, all of the world's leading scientists are screaming that we need to take drastic action or face ecological disaster at the hands of global warming. Very few countries have adopted appropriately aggressive policies to face this threat. You can blame the highly educated ruling class who choose to ignore the facts because they have their own priorities.

When conditions are bad enough, people will protest in the streets because there are food shortages, not because they read the latest edition of a climate science journal. **Here are your "uneducated" people advocating for political and economic change.** History shows us that these movements (or the threat of these movements) are what actually drives social progress.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
