<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="90" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721995564.0" user="ILikeNeurons" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing.

I'm going to focus on this point, because I think you're suffering from a misconception that there are significant differences between these schools of thought. 

[Economists tend to form a consensus based on the strength of the evidence, regardless of the school of thought](http://econweb.ucsd.edu/~gdahl/papers/views-among-economists-wp.pdf). What that means is that when the evidence on a topic is strong, economists of all stripes coalesce around the view that the evidence supports. This should be reassuring, as it means 1) They're not just making it up as they go along, and 2) They're not so attached to an ideology that they can't be swayed by evidence. 

To really drive this point home, [there are a  number of policy changes that economists from every political background can agree on](https://www.npr.org/sections/money/2012/07/19/157047211/six-policies-economists-love-and-politicians-hate). If *the public* 1) had knowledge of the consensus among economists on those topics, and 2) had respect for the fact that the consensus is reached by way of evidence, politicians may enact those policy changes to the great benefit of society at large. 

For those areas where the evidence is weak, you are right that no one can really say what's right, and it's important that we keep an open mind and keep collecting evidence (and maybe, in the meantime, if we have to make a decision, that we come down on the side on which the bulk of evidence points towards). 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722008205.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I agree to an extent. I've mentioned that there are several areas of economics where there is consensus across schools of thought elsewhere here. I might have been overly generic in my descriptions of disagreement within economics, making it sound like every school is wildly different. I wrote the post quickly, as used economics as something to drive the point home. I'm not sure getting bogged down in the nuances of economic schools of thought would have helped. Plus, I'm rusty, it's been years since I've seriously thought about economics. I kind of checked out after I started realizing just how little command I really had of it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
