<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="97" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30722387539.0" user="Busenfreund" delta="False">
    <text>The real question is: can the well-read, educated, knowledge people be objective and consider the interest of others just as important as their own interest?  

If *yes*, then I would agree 100% and I’d prefer we rely on only those educated people to make policies, because people with a greater level of understanding will, on average, advocate better policies than those with less understanding. 

If *no*, then the knowledge of the well-read people can’t really be utilized, because they can’t be trusted to help anyone but themselves.  If they are selfish, then giving them more influence would only lead them to help them selves at the expense of others.  So in this scenario, it’s important to spread the influence evenly amongst the people to make sure everyone’s interests are being considered.

As for my opinion: a true democracy will theoretically fall in the 2nd category, but it should be clear that our democracy has been undermined by opportunists in many ways.  Most people have been manipulated or marginalized to the point that their right to vote is more or less worthless. So I would like to see it move further in the direction of the first category.  IMO the average voter has very little knowledge or understanding behind their voting choices—many of them are just voting within party lines, many others are simply voting in line with their family or friends, and many others will just vote based off rhetoric they see in campaign advertising.  

I can’t go into anymore detail than that because, like OP, all I know is that I know nothing, and the more I think about it the more baseless I realize my opinion is haha. 

Great post OP</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
