<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720591339.0" user="zh1K476tt9pq" delta="False">
    <text>I generally agree with your point but I think you ignore that most democracies have somewhat of a "filtering" system and essentially use trial and error.

In practice people aren't really making decision based on their own views but they are simply following "opinion leaders". E.g. I grew up in Switzerland, probably the most direct democratic country on the planet as people can vote around on 20 or so referendums each year. Some topics are really complex and obviously there is no way you can actually understand everything even with a background in economics, e.g. health economics, as you might know, is an own branch within economics with its own experts. And that's just one topic.

How it works in pratice is that all parties have their own experts and journalists look into the topic, interview scientists and experts and essentially try to boil down topics to its core points. If you think about it, many topics are actually somewhat simple. E.g. do we want to pay a bit more for healthcare and help poor people or should it be cheaper but some people will be worse off? The parliament essentially already works out a solution, which is usually based on expert inputs too. So the decision people make already includes at least a decent solution.

Also really often things simply get figured out over time and is basically some kind of action/reaction/improvement process. E.g. people see reports about horrible wars on TV, so they want to help refugees. But then many people are allowed in, this creates tension and some parties abuse this pushing an anti immigration agenda, so the people want harder rules. The government makes more restriction and stricter rules, which leads to less problems and better integration. So all of a sudden people side with immigrants again if e.g. the government tells immigrants to leave after a decade even though they integrated very well.

It's obviously not perfect but ultimately people will judge by the results.

Also maybe a bit offtopic, but personally I think "direct technocracy" would be the best system. Basically make the government very technocratic and remove politics as much as possible but ultimately let people vote on whatever the technocrats worked out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
