<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="58" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721146177.0" user="Buckabuckaw" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for bringing this issue up.

I'd like to point out two assumptions that you appear to make that might require some re-thinking. 

First of all, I think the phrase "well-read enough" suggests that political convictions are arrived at by reading or, more broadly, learning the systems created by others. I would argue that a political position grows in response to problems in life created by some other group of people. For instance, the political value of "equal under the law" arises from inequality under certain existing laws. When such a dilemma arises, it *helps* to be well-read in history, psychology, sociology, etc. But such academic knowledge is neither necessary nor sufficient to form a considered political opinion.

Secondly, in a related point, choosing from a menu of different existing political.positions or parties is unlikely to be completely satisfying. For most Americans, for instance, voting "straight Democratic" or "straight Republican" is not the only choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721163644.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I've said it a couple of times now, but I think "well read" was a poor choice of words. I wrote the post quickly, and honestly I expected a couple of comments calling me an elitist idiot, and little more. 

I agree that you don't need academics or much at all to form a political opinion. But I will stand by the statement that this political opinion is likely based on things that cannot reasonably be believed if examined thoroughly. 

I also agree with you last point, but I would also say that there is such a wealth of different political philosophies out there, and so many sub-categories within each of them, that you'll likely find something to that will satisfy you. At least before you become so uncertain and nuanced that you end up forced to look at every issue independently, or to simply drop ideology alltogether.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
