<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="79" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721729100.0" user="BobartTheCreator2" delta="False">
    <text>Only half of politics is political theory. The other half is lived experience.

I'm someone with the money and resources to get an education, who had the guidance to read up on political ideas. Not everyone has those things, but everyone lives within this system. 

Someone who is homeless and impoverished may not have read up on the issues, but they may have a far more intimate understanding of the problems with our political/governmental system than you or I might.

It's an extreme example, but to imply that individuals lacking the educational guidance and resources to understand issues from a theoretical perspective is, IMO, an elitist implication. It ignores the lived experiences of people whose struggles with "the system" impede them from attaining those resources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721762114.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand the lived experience arguments. I grew up in a house with insulation so poor that the condensation from my breath would freeze my pillow to the wall. I didn't know if it was okay for me to eat breakfast for years. I grew up dirt poor. 

What lessons was I supposed to learn there? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722518621.0" user="BobartTheCreator2" delta="False">
    <text>Well, what were the circumstances surrounding your poverty? No one chooses to be poor, and in a good system, people would not have to live through those kinds of conditions. So, just asking yourself why your family was poor can uncover flaws in the world around you.

The flaws are more obvious when examining minorities with histories of legal discrimination in their respective countries. In the US, for instance, 100 years of segragation and housing discrimination prevented black Americans from leaving poor areas until around 40-50 years ago. Even though these individuals often lacked educational opportunities, it was obvious to them that they were being denied economic prosperity on the basis of their race.

Idk what country you're in, or what race you are, or what the circumstances surrounding your poverty were. But it's fucked up that you were put through that as a kid, and it's a systemic failure that a person can be born into that situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723317698.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I knew enough about pride, and too little about socioeconomics to ask my dad at the time. Could have been pride. Could have been addiction.

I never said that you can't advocate for change, or that we should stop people. It would be hypocritical for me to go "I don't know anything, but we should definitively create a two tiered system were only smartypants like myself get to do anything". You're also right with the slavery example. I do think though, that it would be relatively simple to examine the moral beliefs of the people at the time, and illustrate how slavery cannot exist consistently with it. Philosophy didn't take some insane detour in the US at the time. It was just applied inconsistently or not at all. 

I'm not saying that you can't prove people wrong, even if you're uncertain of most things. That's when you're in the best place to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
