<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="73" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721485882.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change

What is a logical conclusion of this belief? Should people be prevented from advocating something unless tested for book knowledge?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721638781.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>That is my conclusion. Though well read was a poor choice of words. I don't have some ultimate conclusion I'm trying to trojan horse in here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721715369.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>That's fine. I'm just trying to figure out what you believe, rather than what is contained in the one sentence in order to mount a proper argument. So here I go.

Who decides how much knowledge you should have, and what kind of knowledge?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721772602.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not trying to split people into groups here. 

&amp;gt;Who decides how much knowledge you should have

I think people should have enough knowledge to be able to see the scope and depth of what they're trying to learn. 

&amp;gt; and what kind of knowledge?

The kind that makes you humble, and willing to engage in good faith discussion with those that you disagree with. The kind of knowledge that drives you to steel man their positions for the benefit of both of you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722240864.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I'm not trying to split people into groups here.

You by definition do by your own admission.

&amp;gt;I think people should have enough knowledge to be able to see the scope and depth of what they're trying to learn.

So who decides what knowledge is sufficient? A member of a party? A scientist? A chosen profesor from that field?

&amp;gt;The kind that makes you humble, and willing to engage in good faith discussion with those that you disagree with. The kind of knowledge that drives you to steel man their positions for the benefit of both of you.

But when I asked you, you confimed that your logical conclusion of this belief would be for people to be prevented from advocating a position, unless they are adequately "well read".

If you want to be logically consistent. It means you aren't willing to engage in discussion with people who aren't "adequately well read".

Wanting both sides of the issue to be seen and heard, and for discussion to ensue is a mutually exclusive position not compatible with your CMV.

Unless you want to go back on your word, and to the general "Most people are too dumb to adequately champion an issue", but that doesn't mean they should be prevented from doing so. In which case I agree, but the discussion is kinda pointless as this is a common knowledge and pretty much self evident.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722256060.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I use the word reasonable for a reason. I'm not talking about preventing anyone from anything. I'm only saying that they might advocate something unreasonably, or hold unreasonable views. Or even hold reasonable views unreasonably. 

I haven't said anything that implies some governing body grouping people, or any other thing you'd find in a dystopian YA novel. 

&amp;gt;'m not trying to split people into groups here.

Should have clarified. I'm not advocating that we produce some actual list of people classified or unclassified to hold views. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722301627.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Should have clarified. I'm not advocating that we produce some actual list of people classified or unclassified to hold views.

So what are you advocating?

That people should be allowed to do anything they want, but they probably shouldn't because they aren't experts? 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722353204.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I keep saying that I'm not advocating anything. I'm pointing out a problem. That's it. Something that gnaws at me and fill my mind constantly. 

I'm not even saying that they shouldn't. As I think I said in my OP, you also reasonably can't expect them to do anything else. I wish that people would be a little more humble in their beliefs, and to treat each other better and more fairly in their discussions. But other than that I have no prescriptions. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723339390.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>How would you try to change's one's mind on a platitude?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723345672.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>It's only a platitude when it's summarized. You can take the time to explain how the discussion has become toxic, and the things that happen when it is toxic, and go over the benefits of taking steps to avoid that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723366292.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>Well the core of your CMV seems to be.

&amp;gt; I wish that people would be a little more humble in their beliefs, and to treat each other better and more fairly in their discussions.

If I say something along the line "The world is a dangerous place". How would you try to change my mind? That can be almost anything and everything. A concept so vague  it is nearly useless.

Saying : "The world is dangerous place, therefore we need to secure our border" is on the other hand a very specific claim, that could be attacked via evidence, or other means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723375985.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I'd probably refer you to the work of Hans Rosling, and tell you that the world is much less dangerous than it used to be. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723417085.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>And I offer my rando evidence supporting my view and on we go, debating a concept so broad, it could be argued every which way.

Or I can move my goalpost (as I don't actually had any in the first place) and say, altho the world is not as dangerous as previously. It's still a dangerous place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723434089.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I've forgotten what you were trying to say among all of the other commenters. 

If you want to talk seriously to someone then it will require work.

If you're someone who will only argue their own point, no matter how they will do it, and no matter what is said, then you move on. 

To the second response I'd probably have them look at the rates of people dying from these dangerous things, and have them really think about the percentage. Or I'd just concede, happy that they moved closer to a reasonable place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723962866.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I've forgotten what you were trying to say among all of the other commenters.

I ask question. You agreed with the statement. I tried to attack that statement. You flipped your position about that statement. I asked further questions. You got confused.

&amp;gt;If you're someone who will only argue their own point, no matter how they will do it, and no matter what is said, then you move on.

I'm not. Which is why I asked questions, which will allow me to better accomplish the point of this subreddit. It was you, who aren't consistent.

&amp;gt;To the second response I'd probably have them look at the rates of people dying from these dangerous things, and have them really think about the percentage.

I argue that no matter how much the amounts of deaths are decreased. The world is still dangerous place, because no matter how low you go in the amount of danger. The incredibly vague language  used allows me to automatically confirm my statement. Because any danger at all, allows me to say that world is a dangerous place.

See any problem?

Tldr of this discussion. Your CMV is incredibly generic, so it can be argued whatever which way with no evidence at all. It's a platitude. There is no possible way I can convince you that most people are well red enough to champion position. And there is no way you can confirm it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
