<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720555998.0" user="tunaonrye" delta="False">
    <text>There is a difference between advocating for *change* and advocating for this or that policy solution. An American who is relatively ill informed about economic theory can still know whether she is impoverished or not. And they don't need to understand Gini coefficients to see rampant inequality. People in such a position might reasonably say "I wish we were more like the Nordic democracies, when it comes to economics." or "I wish people in my country didn't go bankrupt from medical expenses." Those are political views! I don't see why that is annoying or unjustified. It is clearly not the same as having a legislative solution (or an understanding of theory), but no individual is going to know everything that would be pertinent to reforming economic policy or social policy. Most legislators in Democracies are not theoretical experts on economic policy, they are politicians trying to accomplish political goals. But advocating for change does not require perfect knowledge, it just requires a reasonable complaint.

The problems with individual beliefs is really a problem of political coordination. And there are some views that are reasonable but underdetermined (like macroeconomic theory, ethics, etc.) and there are some views that seem patently unreasonable... like conspiracy theories, scientific denialism, etc. There is no hard and fast rule for separating the reasonable from the unreasonable that everyone accepts. That is a deep problem for individuals, but does not (yet) seem to be a complete indictment of democratic institutions. The world would be vastly better if people were more humble about how certain they could be and did not think that expertise about X translated to expertise about Y... but this is the problem that we live with if we want to work together. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720690634.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>Because your perspective sort of puts all ideas and wishes on the same line. 

What about someone walking around, without a job, seeing immigrants with jobs, coming to the conclusion that immigrants should stop making us all poorer by stealing our jobs. 

You can reasonably say "I wish something were so", but some wishes are detestable. And in my conversations, there are rarely just wishes. 

I agree with your reasonable/unreasonable divide. But even within reason, it is difficult to have a conclusion, and to then track that down to it's epistemological and metaphysical roots and having the conclusion survive. 

I think the most reasonable thing would be to assume that the experts likely knows more than you, and to go with the consensus. Sort of like the "97% of scientists!" but applied to everything that you cant reasonably master yourself, while recognizing that the experts themselves are often divided. 

I also agree that people being more humble would be great. Actually, I think that's the key to what annoys me. These things are so difficult and confusing, and they should be treated as such. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720820982.0" user="tunaonrye" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not quite sure what you are after, but maybe this will help:

Much of politics is not just factual dispute but also about normative values. Same-sex marriage, abortion, even immigration all have more or less ethical content within the debate. Sometimes we just have "culture war" disputes, as in the case of abortion, and sometimes those issues are (often) buried, as in immigration. Obviously the economics of immigration are pretty much in favor of much more immigration if you ask (most) economists. And then you explain the economics to a person who is anti-immigration for economic reasons and there is no change in view. Or the person might pivot to something more detestable than bad economic reasoning... would being more *well-read* actually help here? Or is it more about being open minded? Or being committed to reasonable debate and epistemological humility? 

I think people are perfectly reasonable to advocate their complaints, but what sort of response should be justification for ignoring their policy recommendations or their unreasonable complaints is another matter. Very few people respond well to being called irrational or even to having their opinions countered by evidence without a sense of personal connection (and this is excluding bad-faith conversations entirely). To finally circle back to the first thing you said in your response, I don't think that I am putting all ideas at the same level, but, absent evidence that someone is just trying to rant/insult/score points, I take complaints - even ones that I think are unreasonable - seriously. I think that is part of being humble, and I don't have much patience for detestable ideas, and god is it exhausting sometimes, but I really don't see a way forward if those committed to reasonable disagreement and humility don't encumber ourselves with as disquieted a mind as we can handle. You can't model the behavior of a humble tolerant minded empirically grounded political agent without dealing with the unreasonable in some ways. That means telling them they are wrong in an effective and appropriate way and similarly advocating for the things that you believe in!

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720851809.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with what you say. And yes, "well read" might have been the wrong choice of words, given that someone can ignorantly stumble on the truth, or read themselves into non-truth.

I also agree that complaints should be taken seriously, and that humbleness is key. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722233527.0" user="KuntaStillSingle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Obviously the economics of immigration are pretty much in favor of much more immigration if you ask (most) economists

I agree with this but I think that misrepresents the debate. Most 'anti-immigration' are actually 'anti-illegal immigration.'

 It may make a ton of sense to ease up on immigration requirements (how many naturalized citizens could pass a U.S. citizenship test?) It probably doesn't make sense to seriously step up border control (at least as far as it is expensive to do). It makes a lot of sense to bust anyone employing illegal immigrants and either deport or grant citizenship to residing illegals. To call them 'dreamers' and allow them continued residency despite illegal status is ridiculous. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723261669.0" user="YNGBLKWLF" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with you on this. I believe many people say they are ‘anti-illegal immigration’ but are actually ‘anti-immigration.’

I forget the term but it’s essentially covering up a bias/prejudice with a more politically acceptable stance. We see it all the time with videos showing American citizens being berated for speaking a different language or wearing a different sort of dress. Do the people berating their fellow citizen know for sure that they are illegal or not? No, but they will tell them to leave “this country” anyway. 

And I fail to see the issue with allowing those dubbed ‘dreamers’ to stay in the country with ‘illegal’ status. To my knowledge, these are Americans who were brought to the country at a very young age and only know life here. We should be deporting these individuals back to the countries of their birth? And you’ve already mentioned how arduous the immigration/citizenship process is. What alternative is there to them remaining here while they try to finish that process and continue with higher education or military service?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723288065.0" user="KuntaStillSingle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;should be deporting these individuals back to the countries of their birth

Ideally they should be legalized... if they can not reasonably be made citizens or granted visa then yes they should be deported. It's sad, sure, but it's a symptom of a broken system and the system should be fixed instead of letting them live and work illegal jobs.

&amp;gt;military service

Soldiers serving are on visa and have an easier naturalization process, they are also adults and should be held responsible if they somehow manage to become an illegal alien. 

&amp;gt;how arduous the immigration/citizenship process

Then make it less arduous, don't uphold a ridiculous system with the notion 'people can just circumvent it anyway.' Make an effective system and prevent people from circumventing it as far as is economical.

I don't think we should have extensive border patrol, because I'm very doubtful it's a good investment, but I do think we should hold investigate and hold companies accountable who are employing illegal immigrants, force them to pay meaningful punitive damages if they haven't done the due diligence to ensure they are legal, and force the illegals discovered to become citizens or deport them within a reasonable timeframe. If we have any moral obligations as a country it is at least to ensure labor is fair and no one is allowed to work without the same rights and protection laws, if companies want to exploit people they should at least be forced to do so in another country and pay a steep tariff if importing from one that does not have reasonable workers protections and rights compared to ours. Allowing illegals to work in butcheries or canning plants for less than minimum wage is more evil than deporting them, so while it's not an ideal solution it is better than what we have now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723423174.0" user="YNGBLKWLF" delta="False">
    <text>I completely agree the system is incredibly broken and needs to be fixed ASAP. The current travesty IMO is that the Democratic Party seem to be extremely reticent to call immigration a major issue other than DACA. There needs to be a fix to the system not just helping illegal immigrants once they get here. It’s almost like *The Jungle* for them since they don’t have the protections granted full American citizens.

However, the amount of masked xenophobia in this country today is sickening. It sank in for a friend of mine who originally supported Trump because her family spent hours at the border daily getting in legally. I’m not sure of the specifics but I believe she is an American citizen but her parents weren’t. Months after the election, she realized that for all the rhetoric and bluster spewed in 2016, it wasn’t just about illegal immigration. Those calling for a wall don’t want illegals nor any others coming in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720875613.0" user="Thefreeriderproblem" delta="False">
    <text>We can't just shut people out of the discussion. But we also don't need to engage with all ideas. Instead, we need to figure out what each individual can/are reasonably able to contribute to the discussion. 

I agree that not all potential or proposed solutions are good ones. But even the person who has these "detestable wishes" has something to contribute to the discussion. They should still be able to express to the community their hardships. In your example, the solution was based on a false assumption about immigrants. But the problem is still real and important. I think we still need to listen when they say, "I am struggling to find work." We can't just shut people out of the discussion. But we don't need to engage with the idea that it's the immigrants fault because there is research by experts about the impact immigration has on a community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721388271.0" user="Borisv14" delta="False">
    <text>On a side note, consensus isn't science. Just because they all agree on a certain idea it doesn't mean it's correct. You think Einstein had consensus from other scientists that his theory of relativity works? I understand your position and even studying epistemology at the highschool level makes you question all of your political stances, and what you think is best for something. When you read some politician saying he is going to bring in universal basic income, some people just agree, and don't see what the negative consequences could be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721687482.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that consensus is correct. I'm saying that it's *more* reasonable to believe that the consensus is correct in comparison to your own ideas and findings, unless you have some very special reason for believing otherwise. 

They could be wrong, but it's more likely that they're closer to the truth than you are, if you disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30722873684.0" user="aloofball" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, Einstein upended physics. But it's also important to recognize that he wasn't some random outsider. He had a PhD, he was recognized as a brilliant mind in his field.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720802612.0" user="Laurcus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People in such a position might reasonably say "I wish we were more like the Nordic democracies, when it comes to economics."

This is a great example since I know a bit about this. This is a position that seems reasonable but may in fact not be. Allow me to explain. The Nordic democracies "work" economically because of extraneous factors. Very homogeneous populations which results in low crime which reduces overall economic hardship. There's also other factors like population size, (Texas is bigger than these countries.) which make the system difficult to import onto the US. An economic system that works for 5 people won't necessarily work for 325 people.

And despite all those factors working in favor of the Nordic countries, the average income of a Norwegian American is higher than the average income of a Norwegian living in Norway.

Because of all this data, I think it's highly likely that if the US went full steam ahead on trying to implement the Nordic model, we would enter another great depression and millions would die.

I guess what I'm trying to say is, a position that seems reasonable to someone uninformed might actually be catastrophic, regardless of the specifics of how that position gets implemented. The position itself might be rotten from the start.

Even if you disagree with what I said about the Nordic countries, you mus understand that this is a possibility, that seemingly innocuous positions could have dire consequences that are not easily foreseen by the uneducated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30720854046.0" user="tunaonrye" delta="False">
    <text>The point was just about inequality being something that motivates people politically. Policy recommendations have to be evaluated on their merits. What counts as merit is a central issue.

BTW It's weird to judge average income of a Norwegian American compared to a citizen of Norway... and "millions would die" ? Like in a nuclear war? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721838403.0" user="Laurcus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;BTW It's weird to judge average income of a Norwegian American compared to a citizen of Norway...

Why? It's the best comparison you can make. If you take  population A and they make 50k a year in their own country, and the same population makes 70k per year in America, then it's foolish to think putting population B into the system of the home country of population A is going to have a positive effect.

And it's not just Norwegians. This is true of all the Nordic countries. In all these cases, these rich Nordic people end up richer, (By about $20,000 per year.) if they come to the US. That is strong evidence that the economic systems of their own countries hurt more than they help, relative to the US.

&amp;gt;and "millions would die" ? Like in a nuclear war?

No. Like in the Great Depression, where 7 million people died of starvation while food rotted in warehouses. Do they even teach you people history anymore?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721887073.0" user="tunaonrye" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you take population A and they make 50k a year in their own country, and the same population makes 70k per year in America, then it's foolish to think putting population B into the system of the home country of population A is going to have a positive effect.

That would be a test of what is more economically beneficial for individual citizens (on average). But that isn't what looking at average salaries of Norweigan Americans would test, because that isn't the same population. People don't randomly emigrate to the US from Norway. 

&amp;gt;No. Like in the Great Depression, where 7 million people died of starvation while food rotted in warehouses.

Where in the historical record is there evidence that something like Nordic social democracy would lead to a global recession?

&amp;gt;Do they even teach you people history anymore?

Being insulting is unnecessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721127414.0" user="Slapbox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  But advocating for change does not require perfect knowledge, it just requires a reasonable complaint.

This is simply what's required to make a complaint. To choose the correct course of action, you certainly need more knowledge than what you have laid out above. Many terrible ideas sound fantastic when all you consider is the complaint and not the implications of the recommended course of action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30721810151.0" user="Voted_Quimby" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  "I wish people in my country didn't go bankrupt from medical expenses."

Yeah but this is something pretty much everyone agrees on. Many times both candidates claim to care about the thing you care about, but disagree on how to achieve it. Evaluating which is the better candidate requires some actual policy knowledge and not just a vague feeling of wanting change or improvement or something.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
