<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="69" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30721431594.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct

I'll give you a hint: none of them are.  Every "scientific" model (or pseudo-scientific, as most economic models are) is an incomplete model of reality.  The doubts you have, physicists also have about the some of the models they use.  That's just how ideas work.  They are an approximation, and when you delve deep, the little parts you ignored become important.

However when someone says "the system is broken because all of my friends are drowning in student debt and their parents can't afford their hospital bills," that's a lot different from some ideological argument.  

In that case, the system in fact is not working for them.  Unless you're going to say there is no conceivable system where those things wouldn't be true, then you have to agree it is not the best system for them.  In which case it becomes completely logical for them to advocate for a different economic or social system. 

People who "think scientifically" dismiss these things as "anecdotal evidence," but the fact is that making decisions for yourself based on personal experience is much more logical than basing decisions off of models that some rando came up with.  Unless you're seriously critically analyzing all the methodologies and double checking the data analysis, you're really just falling into an appeal to authority fallacy. 

And coming from someone who has studied these things more than most, if for instance you think market economics is a great descriptor of the low-wage labor "market", you're definitely in no position to be saying anyone else's opinions aren't worthwhile.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
