<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="41" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720876685.0" user="sp0rkah0lic" delta="False">
    <text>Most political choices don't require the kind of in depth knowledge and understanding you are discussing here. 

I don't need a degree in philosophy to have a conscience, or to have a sense of right and wrong. I may believe that it's our moral obligation to help the poor by providing them resources, or I may believe it's more effective to provide them with skill training, or I may believe that they must learn to help themselves. All of these are simple enough positions to understand and advocate for. 

I might believe that war is wrong, or that in some circumstances it is justified, or that we should be waging it against anyone who threatens us. 

So you vote for or support those leaders who tend to have the same general approach as you would. Then that leader hires the guy with the PhD in economics to IMPLEMENT those ideas. It's a damn good thing that we have specialists in these areas, who understand much more thouroughly the mechanics involved. But, as you say, there is even vast disagreement among the experts, so it's not as if expertise = certainty. Ideally we end up with educated experts whose expertise more or less aligns with the ideology of a leader that was selected by majority. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
