<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30720829472.0" user="HeroSmasher" delta="False">
    <text>Just because most people can't make the most elegant, reasonable, or global solution to a problem doesn't mean they shouldn't be able to advocate for their point. It is their right in most countries, especially the United States, to say what they believe and be properly heard, for better or worse. We should understand their side of the argument, try and change their views, and if we fail, leave them to the flawed logic that keeps them happy or advocate against it. Whether or not they are properly equipped to advocate for changes in politics or economics, they still have a right to give their two cents on the issue.

The United States(My country)as a whole was actually built with these people in mind: Our founding fathers realized that not everyone allowed to vote is equipped to make the right decision, so they created our democratic republic on that note, making the vote of a citizen in matters of policy go not to the change in policy they consider optimal, but really to the elected individual they consider best equipped for the situation. Are these votes exempt from political bias and misinformation? Of course not, but remember that the elected individual(who is usually much more well-educated on the matter than the average citizen)is allowed to make whatever decision they like when the time comes, despite what   their supporters would have wanted.

You are correct that the reason people affirm these views so easily is because of social pressures from friends, family, and society as a whole. A lot of people are able to maintain relationships only because of their political views. Most people really don't care about politics, especially parts of which that don't directly affect them or those they love. And in cases where they are affected, they often have insight to share, even if it isn't backed up by thousands of hours of economic and philosophical studies.

The reason you are having trouble affirming your own views is likely because you do not have the social pressures that make it so easy; your peers are just as split as you are, and your education allows you to see things in a much less simple light, a blessing, and a curse.

Now, personally, I make my decisions on politics based on what I think makes the most sense. I don't do what my friends tell me, I do the amount of research I need on each issue to construct a hypothesis that goes well alongside my own personal philosophies and worldviews. Others likely do the same. Some, of course, can be misinformed, or guided by different things. Perhaps I am under-equipped for this argument, being a minor who has never voted on legislature and never attended an economics class. Or maybe my outsider status allows me to see the bigger picture. Regardless, people should be able to at least advocate for what they think is right, whether or not it is correct objectively.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
