<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="555460162.0" index="106" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/96pfsy/cmv_most_people_are_not_well_read_enough_to/">
    <title>CMV: Most people are not well read enough to reasonably advocate for political or economic change</title>
    <original_poster>I_am_Norwegian</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Edit: "Well read" was a poor choice of words. I think "have done their due diligence" might be more accurate.**

I'm writing this because I want to be proven wrong, because people saying political things, especially as if obvious has started to annoy and anger me more. Especially if they're making fun of someone for their political views, even if I disagree with those views. I hate feeling angry, so hopefully writing my thoughts out will help.

In trying to figure out my own political views, I've come to realize that I can't reasonably hold the views I held, or any other views. I studied economics, mainly the school of thought that appealed to me. But then more and more I came to realize that I couldn't say if the Keynesian or post-keynesian or the Chicago school or MMT etc. were correct, and that even people who devote their lives to the study of economics struggle with the same thing. The same thing happened in philosophy, especially as I came to realize the importance of epistemology and ontology.

And you can't reasonably expect people to put in the effort and time that it takes to sort through these fields. And that there is still such debate among the experts that even if you become and expert, the truth will not be obvious. I've come to understand what Socrates meant when he said something like "I only know that I know nothing".

I've also come to believe that people hold the beliefs they do more for social reasons. Less for the truth of the beliefs, but more because their reaffirm their identity, and their social bonds.

I can't blame them for that, or for not spending thousands of hours sorting through political thought, philosophy and economics. But a part of me still believes that they haven't done their due diligence, and I get angry that they can affirm themselves and their beliefs, while I sit here uncertain, unable to succinctly articulate why, or how to get this across properly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30723294515.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>Having read a few of the comments below and drawing on my own feelings, which to some extent mirror yours-  could never get furious about the economics of brexit, it’s just too complex for me to be definitive on what the outcome will be therefore strong emotions seem misplaced. 

But I would say you could see a micro and macro view. Take the Luddite revolution in Britain, the people who wanted to smash the machines that were taking their jobs...were they wrong or right? On the one hand history sees them as fools because such machinery has pushed our civilisation forward and made the lives of millions, billions, better. On the other hand they were trying to feed their families. So they were right AND wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723302550.0" user="I_am_Norwegian" delta="False">
    <text>I never get angry at economics or theory, only sometimes those that espouse them. Ever felt annoyed at a brexiter? Or the other side? 

The luddites were wrong about the issue of the machines themselves. They would, and did make us richer. They were right about their own jobs. So yes, they were right and wrong, but about different issues. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30723373757.0" user="physioworld" delta="False">
    <text>well i've been angry about brexit, but usually about discrete facts that are easily checkable, like the idea that brexiters were saying we'd get 350 million a week for the NHS...like wtf, but if someone said like "I think that brexit will allow britain to be more prosperous in the 21st century"...I jyst don't know enough to get angry about that.

That's exactly it, there are different issues at play, i can understand heightened emotions when a policy will directly affect you in a clear way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
