<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="556141362.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9741f6/cmv_fines_should_scale_according_to_the_persons/">
    <title>CMV: Fines should scale according to the person's wealth</title>
    <original_poster>onlyfoolandhorse</original_poster>
    <original_post>...or some other punishment should be included. The punishment should be worse depending on how much money people have.  


Fines are supposed to be a deterrent.  
For a deterrent to work the accused must want to avoid the penalty i.e. the fine.  
A billionaire hardly minds if he gets a £200 fine!

Notes:  
 \- Sometimes this wouldn't be possible, but when it is possible the extra admin would be well worth it.   
 \- Additional punishments could include some sort of public shaming, more driving licence points deducted, etc. I don't know, just anything which puts wealthier people off commiting crimes. It doesn't necessarily have to be money, although money makes sense as it could go towards helping victims of the crime (e.g. helping victims of speeding motorists).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30725871029.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Fines are supposed to be a deterrent.

In theory, yes; however, in practice the issue is complicated because of external variables like enforcement rate. Most drivers will speed knowing that the number of officers on patrol at any given time is several orders of magnitude lower than the number of drivers. It is this fact that leads to a fine's diminished efficacy in deterring traffic offenses. Fines also act as a form of monetary retribution for society. When a driver commits a traffic offense they are harming the safety of others and this forms a legal basis for the government to seek retribution for the people. A wealthy person speeding does not endanger society more than a poorer person speeding. Therefore, the financial status of a driver has no bearing on the severity of his or her offense and so should not be included in the calculation of a fine. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30726458580.0" user="Iraeis" delta="False">
    <text>I like the retribution argument. But I don't think a low enforcement rate nullifies the deterrent effect. A 1 in 100 chance of receiving a less severe reprimand is still less of a deterrent than a 1 in 100 chance of receiving a more severe reprimand. hence, the punitive aspect of the ticket can't just be ignored.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30727336351.0" user="irishman13" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, the wealthy person speeding does not endanger society any more, but the punishment is less of a burden on them than for a poor person. If we considered traffic laws as deterrent rather than merely retribution, wouldn't you say that, inherently, a flat fine system would be less of a deterrent for the rich than the poor?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
