<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="556141362.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9741f6/cmv_fines_should_scale_according_to_the_persons/">
    <title>CMV: Fines should scale according to the person's wealth</title>
    <original_poster>onlyfoolandhorse</original_poster>
    <original_post>...or some other punishment should be included. The punishment should be worse depending on how much money people have.  


Fines are supposed to be a deterrent.  
For a deterrent to work the accused must want to avoid the penalty i.e. the fine.  
A billionaire hardly minds if he gets a £200 fine!

Notes:  
 \- Sometimes this wouldn't be possible, but when it is possible the extra admin would be well worth it.   
 \- Additional punishments could include some sort of public shaming, more driving licence points deducted, etc. I don't know, just anything which puts wealthier people off commiting crimes. It doesn't necessarily have to be money, although money makes sense as it could go towards helping victims of the crime (e.g. helping victims of speeding motorists).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30725955949.0" user="Ellem_Mayo" delta="False">
    <text>This is an incredibly bad idea. Rich people usually do not have their wealth stored in a bank account that has FDIC insurance. Rich people usually have their net worth stored in the form of illiquid assets. But you will say what about Jeff Bezos, Mark Zuckerberg, etc? They do have most of their net worth in stocks which is considered as a liquid asset like cash. They are considered cash since they can be liquidated on the next opening  market day. However, this is not good because they own such a large percentage of Amazon and Facebook respectively. Their net worth currently might be ___ amount but doesnt mean their net worth is that amount when they start selling. They will experience something called Market Impact. Selling so much stock in a certain company will influence the price of the other sellers and buyers. This will ulitmately lower their net worth substantially. What they could do to stop this is to sell over a streched period of time. I also believe that everyone should be treated equally. Why should this person only get a $10 because he doesn't work the 120 hours a week that Elon Musk works? Just because Elon is smarter and works harder, he has to pay more? That is not fair for elon musk. They are all humans subject to the same human mistakes. Life is a game that supports economy of scale. Don't try to change the rules, just play the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30727320282.0" user="hadzir" delta="False">
    <text>Use the Norwegian system then

Minor misdemeanors (public urination, minor traffic offences, trying to smuggle a bottle of booze accross borders) are fined like normal. A flat fine issued directly by the officer, and you avoid being listed on criminal records.

Criminal offences, that actually go to court, are punished with fines. These fines ARE listed on your criminal records, and they scale on your wealth. If the crime is really serious, there will also be jail time.

These fines are issued by the judges and are typically calculated as some percentage of your income. If you have little income, but high wealth (as per tax returns), you can be fined off of that.

If you have no wealth, no income, you can be issued community service or jail time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
