<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="556141362.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9741f6/cmv_fines_should_scale_according_to_the_persons/">
    <title>CMV: Fines should scale according to the person's wealth</title>
    <original_poster>onlyfoolandhorse</original_poster>
    <original_post>...or some other punishment should be included. The punishment should be worse depending on how much money people have.  


Fines are supposed to be a deterrent.  
For a deterrent to work the accused must want to avoid the penalty i.e. the fine.  
A billionaire hardly minds if he gets a £200 fine!

Notes:  
 \- Sometimes this wouldn't be possible, but when it is possible the extra admin would be well worth it.   
 \- Additional punishments could include some sort of public shaming, more driving licence points deducted, etc. I don't know, just anything which puts wealthier people off commiting crimes. It doesn't necessarily have to be money, although money makes sense as it could go towards helping victims of the crime (e.g. helping victims of speeding motorists).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30725776471.0" user="This_Initiative" delta="False">
    <text>How is the government supposed to accurately know how much wealth someone has?

 Lets use a personal example of mine. The government doesnt know how many guns I own, let alone what their worth is. They simply dont keep track of it. How are they going to accurately gauge my wealth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30725809709.0" user="3R3B05" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose using their income as a basis would be the easiest way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30725895965.0" user="This_Initiative" delta="False">
    <text>Income has nothing to do with wealth. You can have an extremely high income and not have jack shit for wealth (look at NFL players), you can have extremely high wealth without having any income (look at retired people)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30725957174.0" user="3R3B05" delta="False">
    <text>Income and wealth are directly connected, people who have a high income will be wealthy in a short time *in general*.

Income has everything to do with wealth, you'll never accumulate wealth without having a high income. I'm not saying it's a perfect 1:1 but it's the best way for the state to check it, as the government knows about your income.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30725992001.0" user="This_Initiative" delta="False">
    <text>Not in general. Most people are not wealthy, because regardless of their income level they spend all of what they earn as they get it.

And you definitely can accumulate high wealth without high income. Join the military and live like a frugal jerk while investing what you can in the stock market. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30726122813.0" user="thechill_fokker" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not true.  You can have a perfectly modest 30-55k a year combined household income and be a millionaire in your 50s as long as you avoid new cars, credit cards and other unnecessary expensive items.   Fines should be equal no matter what you make.  Plus the EXTREME wealthy can some years report a loss to the government during a down year.  Do they get money back during a down year when they get a fine?  If you want to measure “wealth” by annual income then a business owner who looses 3 million in a bad year is doing worse off then the hard working waffle house fry cook that does he or she’s damndest to make the best hash browns known to man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30727092905.0" user="Bizzyguy" delta="False">
    <text>To add onto this, people with business’s can make millions of dollars while only paying themselves low amount. I’m a property manager who works with landlords. After all write off and other tax tricks, they can report an extremely low income compared to what they actually make.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30726571550.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How is the government supposed to accurately know how much wealth someone has?

While we don't currently, we could collect data on this. Many countries outside of the U.S. do track wealth.

And even in the U.S., we do do this to a much smaller extent for things like Medicaid which does look at assets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30726720767.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30726776091.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How is the government supposed to accurately know how much wealth someone has?

Everyone files taxes, do they not? I'd say that provides a good guesstimate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30726778767.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
