<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="556141362.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9741f6/cmv_fines_should_scale_according_to_the_persons/">
    <title>CMV: Fines should scale according to the person's wealth</title>
    <original_poster>onlyfoolandhorse</original_poster>
    <original_post>...or some other punishment should be included. The punishment should be worse depending on how much money people have.  


Fines are supposed to be a deterrent.  
For a deterrent to work the accused must want to avoid the penalty i.e. the fine.  
A billionaire hardly minds if he gets a £200 fine!

Notes:  
 \- Sometimes this wouldn't be possible, but when it is possible the extra admin would be well worth it.   
 \- Additional punishments could include some sort of public shaming, more driving licence points deducted, etc. I don't know, just anything which puts wealthier people off commiting crimes. It doesn't necessarily have to be money, although money makes sense as it could go towards helping victims of the crime (e.g. helping victims of speeding motorists).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30727108215.0" user="natha105" delta="False">
    <text>Our society would be fundamentally different - in all sorts of ways - if people could be relied upon not to be giant fucking assholes.  The problem is, every single time we (society) trusts someone not to be a dick, they completely let us down.  Cops plant evidence and lie on the witness stand.  Charity workers defraud the charities.  Politicians take bribes.  Presidents lie their faces off.  It is so bad that we actually need to take into account how people will behave badly under a system when we propose it.

And this is the problem with scaling fines.  Its a great idea, it really is.  There is no reason not to do it.... except for the unintended consequences.  You give municilalities, and states, and governments a HUGE financial incentive to hit one group of people, and they will do it.  If you make more than X you will basically have a dedicated cop following you around all day giving you huge tickets for every single thing you do wrong.  It would make it impossible for the rich to function in society and it would be nothing more than a cash grab.  The effect of this would be that the wealthy would limit their exposure to the world as much as they could.  They wouldn't drive cars or even have driver's licences  - the cost of a full time driver would be forever less than the fines they would incur.  They wouldn't live in the same areas as everyone else - they would want gated communities to keep the cops out.

All you would accomplish would be to isolate the rich, and turn the government into the enemy of yet another group of people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
