<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="564888063.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cbif3/cmv_the_current_national_us_gun_control_laws_are/">
    <title>CMV: The current national US gun control laws are all that’s needed right now.</title>
    <original_poster>ElderAcorn</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I won’t go into all National US gun laws, I will point out the ones that I think need pointing out because they pretty much sum up the gun control debate.

According to http://lawcenter.giffords.org/gun-laws/policy-areas/who-can-have-a-gun/categories-of-prohibited-people/#federal

“The federal Gun Control Act of 1968, codified at 18 U.S.C. § 922, generally prohibits the sale of firearms to any person who:

Has been convicted of, or is under indictment for, a crime punishable by imprisonment for more than one year;

Is a fugitive from justice;

Is an unlawful user of or addicted to a controlled substance;

Is underage;

Has been adjudicated as a mental defective or committed to a mental institution;

Is unlawfully in the United States or has been admitted to the U.S. under a nonimmigrant visa;

Has been dishonorably discharged from the military;

Has renounced his or her U.S. citizenship;

Is subject to a court order restraining him or her from harassing, stalking or threatening an intimate partner, his or her child or a child of a partner, or engaging in other conduct that would place an intimate partner in reasonable fear of bodily injury to the partner or child; 
or
Has been convicted of a misdemeanor offense of domestic violence.”

I think that these address the people that no one wants getting a gun to the best of anyone’s capabilities to find out about someone. If you want to know what crimes have a mandatory minimum of 1 year or more here’s a list that I think you’ll find reassuring https://famm.org/wp-content/uploads/Chart-All-Fed-MMs.pdf

As for background checks, the only people required by law to do a background check are private sellers ( http://lawcenter.giffords.org/gun-laws/policy-areas/background-checks/universal-background-checks/#federal ) 

“Federal law imposes various duties on federally licensed firearms dealers. Firearms dealers must, among other things:

Perform background checks on prospective firearm purchasers.

Maintain records of all gun sales.

Make those records available to law enforcement for inspection.

Report certain multiple sales.

Report the theft or loss of a firearm from the licensee’s inventory.

Federal law imposes none of these requirements on unlicensed sellers, however.”

As stated in the quote, unlicensed sellers do not have to do any of these things by law, but they actually do have to if they don’t want to go to jail. The people not allowed to be sold gun from the top cannot be sold guns by anyone licensed or not. That means that a licensed dealer would be forced find out about the person while an unlicensed would do it because if they did give a gun to someone who fits one of those conditions, they’d get the same punishment as if the licensed dealer were to do the same. They are both equally punished if they sell to a person fitting the list, licensed dealers are only forced to check by law. 

All in all, this adds up to mean that people that we don’t want to have guns will either not have guns, or we have no laws being proposed that could any further not give guns to those people without restricting regular citizens from getting guns

Edit: This statement sums up my deltas “To clarify my new clause: The current national gun laws along with the requirement to properly store guns and background checks required for all buyers regardless of seller are all we need.”</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30793306095.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/ElderAcorn (OP) has awarded 2 delta(s) in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [here](/r/DeltaLog/comments/9cc1p1/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_the_current_national_us_gun/), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view doesn't necessarily mean a reversal, or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
