<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="51" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30796054133.0" user="konfettiboy" delta="False">
    <text>It's only a jerk move if you go over there and ask them to turn it down or off and they refuse.

They want to listen to music which they clearly showed to you. 
You don't want to listen to it which they could assume but can't know for sure. 

If it was some extreme music which is noise to 99% of people they are probably jerks (that probably just want the attention). But maybe right now they think they do you a favour with their free radio music. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796415870.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Oh lord. Anyone reading this: absolutely no one, ever, thinks you are doing them a favor by offering “free” music near their campsite.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796524730.0" user="Wabbit_Snail" delta="False">
    <text>Agree. I have the same problem on ski hills. I want to hear the sound of the snow under my skis, I want silence. I'm not always in the mood for music. People have their own devices, they can use earplugs. 

As for the campsite, I regularly go to a National park where playing music out loud is actually forbidden. Guitar is permitted. And I love it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796889462.0" user="konfettiboy" delta="False">
    <text>I know that but you can't assume that everyone is as smart as you and me. And they don't have to think that they do you a favor it's enough when they think you don't mind.
The point being that you have to communicate what you want because others often assume the wrong thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
