<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30794988374.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Most of the time you can just hear nature, **people talking**, **kids playing**, lots of birds and squirrels

When you camp in close vicinity to other campers one of the things that you knowingly sacrifice is audio-privacy. In your view what makes playing music different to letting their kids shout/play, or having a normal conversation? Given that the music is being played at a similar volume level to those things of course (playing music obnoxiously loud in public is clearly antisocial), what makes it different and unacceptable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795017424.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Conversation and play are fairly universal.  Musical genres are not. Hip hop, blues noodling, modern country, twee indie are all loved by some and loathed by others.  It’s an unpredictable variable — and unlike conversation , one that is entirely within the power of others in this transient community to skip for a night.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795041719.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Conversation and play are fairly universal

I think that's very disputable. A lot of people hate kids and the sounds of screeching/laughter. Then you have anything remotely related to politics / views on current affairs or contentious issues. Why is listening to someone discuss a view/value you disagree with different to listening to someone listen to a genre of music you don't like?

&amp;gt; and unlike conversation , one that is entirely within the power of others in this transient community to skip for a night.

Again disputable, how have you decided what is "within people's powers to skip for a night". Surely you could say that for one night, it may be considerate to stop your kids playing. Or to not laugh. Or to only talk in whispers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795059103.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I am saying that 75% of people do speak but do not play music ; it is the social norm and has been for a decade at least.

People who speak so loudly that you understand their political views from a couple of campsites away are not using a normal conversational voice.  

It could be there are medical conditions or special circumstances that make music necessary . I don’t know. I do not think it is the case most of the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795084137.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 75% of people do speak but do not play music

&amp;gt; it is the social norm and has been for a decade at least.

It's going to be very hard to come to any logical conclusion to this discussion if you start using unverifiable statistics as basis for your views.

&amp;gt; People who speak so loudly that you understand their political views from a couple of campsites away are not using a normal conversational voice.

I thought we were discussing music vs. conversation at a constant volume level. Are you saying that you CAN hear music but that you CAN'T hear conversation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795106846.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>No, mostly conversation is a murmur at this distance. Music is played loud enough that the campers   can hear it over their conversations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795110750.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>So the issue isn't that they're playing music, it's that they're playing loud music. I imagine that if they were talking at the same volume as the music, then that would be an issue too? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795122508.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>No. It’s not ‘there is a loud noise and I don’t like loud noise’ . Squirrels  are often very loud and IDGAF.  The issue is that an unnatural noise is being played for the pleasure of a few without regard for the  effects on everyone else.  Someone playing tv or watching a movie would be similar, but thankfully that almost never happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795131973.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>Just to clarify, what would it take for someone to change your view on this topic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795141403.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Someone to explain the value,  or  the ‘other side’.   I put this here (instead of as a rant) because it happens often enough that I know there are redditors who have been the music players, and I hoped to hear that POV.   It could be ignorant or label of empathy — but maybe there is something else there . </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795175396.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>Not to sound accusatory but I don't feel that you've refuted any of the points in this thread well enough to claim to have a solid logical grounds for your argument. Most of your posts don't directly respond to or refute anything, but instead just add details and tidbits to your original overall assertion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795184619.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps my original post was not detailed enough .  The real thing I want to get to is the ‘why?’ Not the ‘what noise level is ok?’</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795194538.0" user="jazz_to_the_bee" delta="False">
    <text>The nature of CMV is that you make an initial assertion and have that point of view critically challenged by other redditors. Your initial POV was that "playing music on a speaker at a campsite is NOT okay whereas speaking, playing, etc IS".

We may discuss why people play music if that helps us critically evaluate the original assertion, but otherwise that is secondary to you having to prove why your assertion is sound and valid against the challenges that you receive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795506247.0" user="dexwin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;to you having to prove why your assertion is sound and valid against the challenges that you receive.

Please cite the rule that states that.

The guide states conversation,  not debate. You come across as hunting for deltas, and are frustrated by OP. There is no onus on them to " refute any of the points in this thread well enough to claim to have a solid logical grounds for [their] argument. "

Your job is to change their view. Their job is to be willing to have their view changed, not to accept if your argument has logic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795464695.0" user="saintcrazy" delta="False">
    <text>Because they enjoy it? Because their taste for that music is something that is shared by that family and it helps them to have fun and bond with each other? Maybe they like to sing along when their favorite song pops up in that playlist, maybe they like to dance, maybe it just makes everything more fun and energetic for them. Maybe years from now they'll hear one of those songs again and be reminded of the memories they made while on this camping trip.

Listening to nature is nice too, different people derive enjoyment from different things. Besides, they surely won't play music all day and all night, so you'll still get your quiet time at some point. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795614413.0" user="mmouchi" delta="False">
    <text>But why should they get to listen to it loud enough to disturb people a few campsites away? If it is louder than a normal talking voice for the neighbor's, then they are infringing on those people selfishly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795702044.0" user="saintcrazy" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't asking them to turn the music off be infringing on their enjoyment as well? 

So now we're stuck - either they play the music, and OP enjoys his camping trip less, or they shut off the music, and the other guests enjoy their trip less.

A reasonable compromise would be to ask them to turn their music down a bit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796841964.0" user="mmouchi" delta="False">
    <text>No because they can still hear the music at a quiet volume next to them. Asking then to turn it down to a volume that would not disturb others conversations isn't infringing at all. And if their enjoyment comes solely from it being loud, then they are in the wrong venue and are selfishly imposing on others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797713307.0" user="saintcrazy" delta="False">
    <text>...that's why I said asking them to turn it down is a reasonable compromise. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797765289.0" user="mmouchi" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, and my initial comment already covered that. There was already an answer to your comment before you made it </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795207091.0" user="thebreaksmith" delta="False">
    <text>But it’s hard to know what you’d consider ‘the other side’ when we don’t really know which side you’re on. No one here seems to disagree that playing music at a loud volume is shitty, but if you’re bothered by someone laying down background tunes, I could debate you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795464947.0" user="spongue" delta="False">
    <text>I can imagine feeling OK about playing music at a public campground sometimes, so here's my reasoning... and I may not be the kind of people/group you're thinking of, but it's one example. 

Let's say I'm camping at a public campground by myself. Compared to where I might normally camp, this is practically civilization; there are bathrooms, water, trash cans, and other facilities. There are people all around, virtually no privacy. I can see and hear my neighbors. There are cars driving around, the road is probably paved. This is not a wilderness experience, so I don't treat it as one. 

Of course, I recognize blasting music is not a polite thing to do, but I see no reason why not to play some music at a conversational volume as long as it's not too late at night. Just loud enough for me to hear the details, and maybe people will hear it if they walk close to my camp, but at most it'll be a slight background noise that blends in with the other noise.

Maybe someone gets offended at my "unnatural" sound. I can understand, because there are things that bother me about being there, too, which are not ideal; maybe I'm triggered by some parents yelling at their kids, or someone is running a generator, or some group of people is staying up late around a fire laughing loudly. And I wish they would stop! But I have to just let it go because that's the nature of group camping. If I don't like it I can leave. And since everyone has the same rights at a campground, I'm not going to feel bad about producing a bit of sound of my own. Maybe I'm anxious about being in a crowded space and want to hear something that helps me feel comfortable so I'm not focused on what all the other people are doing.

I think singling out music as an unacceptable noise source, assuming the volume level is the same as conversation, is fairly arbitrary. We all have our things that bother us but it's not helpful to rationalize why the thing that bothers us is *the one thing* that shouldn't be allowed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795526587.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Someone to explain the value, or the ‘other side’.

Okay how about this: You don't get to dictate what sorts of noises others make at their campsites. As long as they maintain a reasonable volume level, they're free to do whatever. If someone camping wanted to have academic conversations about homosexuality, and you were a bigot, do you expect them to stop?   
  
If you want a camp ground without any music, you're free to start your own that disallows music, or petition the owners of the camp grounds to disallow music. Otherwise, you're arbitrarily inserting yourself into someone else's business because it "annoys you."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795533958.0" user="Ikhlas37" delta="False">
    <text>I feel the biggest problem with this is the amount of variables.

1) is the camping area, a cool young hip tip of place for drinking/and laughs or is it more advertised for nature lovers and remoteness?

2) loudness of music

3) How common is it that people play music there?

If it isn’t a place so much for social, drinks and fun but more relax and taking / getting lost in the nature and scenes. Then the music is a problem.

How loud it is and what time its played? Having slightly less then conversation level music after dinner is different to Chad blasting bangers all night/day.

If everyone is playing music, you’ve come to the wrong place.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795676438.0" user="TrontRaznik" delta="False">
    <text>Just a tip: if you want to avoid the music, park near a fast flowing river. That'll drown out the sound after 15 feet or so</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795949267.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>How about someone watching a TV that has a conversation on it?  Conversation is only bad if it comes from an electronic device?

You've contradicted yourself, also.  In one post you said music is worse because it's louder and in another post you said music is worse even at the same volume.

You've repeatedly said that everyone, or at least most people, will agree with you, but you're ignoring the many people disagreeing with you.

Bro, do you maybe just have a problem with other people's music?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795915806.0" user="BerryGoosey" delta="False">
    <text>Talking doesn't typically persist for 8-12 hours at the same level. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796321244.0" user="virak_john" delta="False">
    <text>You’ve clearly never met my brother-in-law . </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797769379.0" user="ausipockets" delta="False">
    <text>He doesn’t want his view changed </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795559831.0" user="WerhmatsWormhat" delta="False">
    <text>Where did you come up with that stat? It seems like you pulled it completely out of thin air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796639477.0" user="KazuyaDarklight" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to be pedantic for a sec just because people tend to so often simultaneously embrace and reject this.  Depending on how much they are invested into the norm in question.

Social norms change, what was accepted a few years ago may or may not be ok today or maybe on it's way out and vice versa. Not long ago segregation was a social norm, it was expected, terrible though it is to us now. Taking a more equitable tract, some time ago men not wearing shirts was socially unacceptable.

Things change, claiming "this is how it has been" alone only really has any power against a one off event, it quickly falls in the face of a trend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796697601.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>True. I’m not talking about tradition so much as the current paradigm. But if you camp 1 night a year you probably don’t know the paradigm. 

However it is usually best to  observe what others are doing and try to ‘when in Rome’ ideally .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796797457.0" user="KazuyaDarklight" delta="False">
    <text>But then you have people here in the comments who purport to be frequent campers saying, for their areas at least, that this IS the currently evolving paradigm.  The wording of many/most of those complaining seem to indicate that they are frustrated with an increasingly common occurrence, which would make it the trend I mention at the end of my reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796814769.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>It certainly is the norm at music festivals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796985306.0" user="KazuyaDarklight" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sure it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795381717.0" user="carbonclasssix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why is listening to someone discuss a view/value you disagree with different to listening to someone listen to a genre of music you don't like?

What? Rarely do people talk so loud camping that you can make out their entire conversation, or even if they do it echoes and it's nearly impossible to make out every word of the conversation. That is a bizarre analogy. 

Additionally, at times when people want quietude (in the evening) people are mostly going to be getting their kids to calm down. I rarely hear kids being loud (especially "screeching") in the evening or at night when camping. 

When people play music they are playing it to be heard above their conversation, as well as music having a tendency to be attention-grabbing (as I detailed in another comment), and that's the problem that OP is taking issue with. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796171523.0" user="MetalIsLaw" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a woods guy and am much more tolerant of the sound of children than your shitty music taste through a bluetooth speaker. I come to the woods to escape the digital monopoly on our lives. Children are at least not digital (though they are absolutely abnoxious... just less so.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796467912.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>So it’s not the actual music that annoys you, it’s just the fact that it’s digital? 

Not everyone goes camping for same reasons as you. Some people just want to spend time with friends and family that they may not see too often. If they want to play some music at a moderate level while they converse or play games, even if that music is the shittiest genre of music, I really fail to see the harm there. I’d be too busy having fun with my own family and friends to give a shit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796951786.0" user="MetalIsLaw" delta="False">
    <text>No it's the music. The word digital was extra. I want to be free of the modern world.

The point is, we can both be happy if you wear headphones dude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796971933.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>If I was camping by myself then yeah that would make sense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796692979.0" user="mossyskull" delta="False">
    <text>Can confirm... least favorite part of car camping is waking up to the horrible screeching of children! 
Any genre of music is better than the noise of kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795404279.0" user="DootDeeDootDeeDoo" delta="False">
    <text>I'd rather listen to music I dislike than someone's children making noise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796468705.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796493710.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/LeaveMyBrainAlone – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+LeaveMyBrainAlone&amp;amp;message=LeaveMyBrainAlone+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5bf7c1/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795410843.0" user="fluteitup" delta="False">
    <text>It's also how many people enjoy themselves. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796850613.0" user="carbonclasssix" delta="False">
    <text>People can enjoy themselves however they want to, but when they are in a society/around other people they agree to certain things to benefit from that society. When camping they are benefitting from the ease of access to a "wild" place that might have toilets, showers, etc. but still be "remote." To benefit from that the expectation for most people is that you will be relatively quiet. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795518831.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Hip hop, blues noodling, modern country, twee indie are all loved by some and loathed by others.

Well, frankly, that sounds like a personal problem. If they're maintaining acceptable volume levels, it doesn't what they're playing as long as it's not potentially offensive.   
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795844774.0" user="goodolarchie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Conversation and play are fairly universal. Musical genres are not.

I'd take it one step further and say talking, and children (including the noises they might make, within reason of a responsible parent... that's a whole 'nother CMV topic) are necessary in pretty much any context.  That the rest of the world needs to hear your music is not.

People might hate the sound of kids playing, it's borderline impossible to stop children from making sound, and they are necessary for the survival of our species.  Comparing that to bluetooth audio broadcasting (as is made below) is a pretty thin link.   

Also, this issue is incredibly pervasive and has gotten worse in previous years.  It's a cultural condition - broadcasting audio in public places including the bus, a restaurant, on a hike... and for a good portion of my life it wasn't acceptable, or considered very rude.  I still feel the latter is true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796050625.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;broadcasting audio in public places including the bus, a restaurant, on a hike

Those are some very different examples, though.  On a bus people are essentially "trapped" with you, in a restaurant they have paid for the ambience.  On a hike or out camping is different though, if you don't like the sounds where you're hiking then hike somewhere else.  If someone is playing music at a campsite loud enough to bother you it's probably too loud, but when you're outdoors that's either \*very\* loud, or the listener is too sensitive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796441941.0" user="RaconteurRob" delta="False">
    <text>How is it any different? If I'm out hiking, I'm on a trail. I may be miles into that trail. I'm not going to turn around because someone wants to ruin the experience for everyone else. Why should everyone on that trail have to stop the activity WE'VE ALL COME TO DO because one guy wants to listen to his favorite song and didn't bring headphones? 

If I'm camping in a public campsite, I've paid to be there. Just as in a restaurant, I've paid for the ambience, i.e. the sounds of nature. And yes, people play their music very loudly. One thing people don't realize is that when you don't have all of the noise of the city around, sounds travels pretty far even at a low volume. So what would be a normal volume at home is unacceptable in a campsite. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796483853.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I think it’s understood that acceptable volume means acceptable volume for that specific environment. How’s that even relevant? I thought we were under the presumption that the music is being played at an appropriate volume level</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796538138.0" user="RaconteurRob" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. I just think people don't really consider that when playing their music at a campsite. You should turn it down more than you would at home because the sound travels more. They assume it is acceptable because it's no louder than they usually play it, but you can hear it much further away in a campsite. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797643797.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; People might hate the sound of kids playing, it's borderline impossible to stop children from making sound, and they are necessary for the survival of our species. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

People might hate the sound of sex, but it's borderline impossible to have sex silently, and it's necessary for the survival of our species.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30799359093.0" user="goodolarchie" delta="False">
    <text>Sex is an event that can be controlled. Children... you can't get a little bit and sometimes pregnant. Also sex can be enjoyed without broadcasting to an entire campground. I'm all for camp sex. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795944145.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>If I'm going camping I'd much rather hear someone's music than their kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795948694.0" user="lQdChEeSe" delta="False">
    <text>Listening to kids is 10x more annoying</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796527021.0" user="MustacheEmperor" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like music bothers you much more than conversation and play. That’s completely valid. But, someone could be at the same campsite making the same complaints about kids running around, but saying “the music’s not bad, that I can tune out.”

In either situation, part of using a group campsite is accepting that you are compromising your sonic privacy. If you want a peaceful environment, you need to go to one. There is no shortage of the great outdoors in most of the US, at least. It is a “jerk move” to show up to a group campsite and demand everyone follow your rules to maximize your enjoyment, no different than if I showed up and told some family to keep their kids in the tent if they’re going to be loud. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796547422.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I get what you’re saying, but, thing is, we can all make conversation. Only one camper at a time can make noise. If we all put our car radios on it becomes cacaphony.  So much worse. That’s why I said conversation is less intrusive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796799546.0" user="duckhunt420" delta="False">
    <text>" Only one camper at a time can make noise. If we all put our car radios on it becomes cacaphony. So much worse. "

So you think only one person can talk at a time? What about a very raucous conversation where people are talking over each other? If everybody talked at once, it is still a cacophony. Have you ever been in any crowd? If you camp next to a drunken party of people, you're saying it's not intrusive at all and they are each respectfully speaking to each other one at a time?

It seems like your problem is with volume of music instead of music itself but you refuse to concede that point. 

If you want "the other side," it's that some people find music very important for setting their mood and ambience. Or just enjoy listening to music in general. For some, they might enjoy sitting in silence listening to music far more enjoyable than conversation. So "everybody likes to talk" could easily be replaced by "everybody likes music" and still be true. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796813551.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Of course the problem is volume. If I couldn’t hear it, I wouldn’t know about it!

If campsite 20 and campsite 21 both have people talking it sounds like people talking. If site 21 plays the Eagles and site 21 cranks up Drake .. it doesn’t sound like music playing, it sounds like 2 incompatible songs playing at the same time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796846508.0" user="duckhunt420" delta="False">
    <text>So if these two campsites played music to a reasonable level so it's not obtrusive to you, it'd be fine? If this is the case, then playing music to a considerate volume is acceptable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796957715.0" user="RedCloud26" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not disagreeing with your point, but if you camp next to others you do sacrifice privacy. There are plenty of free camping spots (especially in the west, if your from US) you can go to instead and then you can be as loud as you want and listen to your own music if you so please!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797809224.0" user="ahshitwhatthefuck" delta="False">
    <text>Welcome to "roughing it".  If you want control of your environment, stay home.  One day you'll learn that the point of camping is to subject yourself to nature.  You may hear birds cawing, humans playing music, wolves howling, trees blowing in the wind, water rushing through a river or even crickets chirping.  You don't have a say in the matter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795358431.0" user="carbonclasssix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In your view what makes playing music different to letting their kids shout/play, or having a normal conversation?

Television, and to a lesser degree music, is made to be attention-getting. Obviously there is music that isn't attention-getting, but that's not the music people are going to complain about. The music people (OP) complain about is music that is made to get your attention. Constantly having your attention being diverted from what is supposed to be a relaxing evening is bothersome and invasive. This would be similar to a baby crying. A baby's cry is evolutionarily honed to get people's attention. It's not often that people bring babies camping, mostly for the baby's safety, but if it were more common people would complain because having their attention constantly distracted every time the baby started crying would be incredibly disruptive to the tranquility that people seek when camping. Kids playing and people talking is not nearly as distractive and disruptive. In fact, personally, I find conversation in the distance or in another room soothing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795677963.0" user="social_contracts" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When you camp in close vicinity to other campers one of the things that you knowingly sacrifice is audio-privacy.

Yeah... if you're among campers who are jerks.   If you camp among decent respectable people, they will value the quiet peaceful atmosphere that exists and take care to not disturb it for the sake of their neighbors.  Selfish jerks, however, will blast their music, shout, yell, cause trouble, and let their kids do the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795797603.0" user="fuckswithboats" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Your CMV is like "CMV: It's a jerk move to hang wind chimes in a residential community within earshot of other neighbors." or "CMV: It's a jerk move to allow your kids to yell and scream in a library."

Windchimes and kids yelling and screaming in the library are equivalent? 

Also, windchimes are offensive?

Holy fuck</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30801379065.0" user="social_contracts" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah they're equally obnoxious things done by selfish people who don't give a rat's ass about anyone's comfort except their own. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30801738088.0" user="fuckswithboats" delta="False">
    <text>I dunno, bro, the little old lady down the street with a windchime on her back porch doesn't seem nearly as obnoxious as kids yelling and screaming in a library. 

This might be a little bit more about *you* than windchimes buddy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796316925.0" user="goldandguns" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In your view what makes playing music different to letting their kids shout/play, or having a normal conversation?

I feel like there's a lot of very clear differentiations between those things</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796885763.0" user="SenatorAstronomer" delta="False">
    <text>I gotta agree here.  If you want to go camping and hear nature and not be bothered, you need to get out of the small public campsites and get out into nature.  I know as a Montanan I am probably spoiled in this regard because of opportunity, but it's the only way I know.  Public campsites in close proximity to each other, this is what you get.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
