<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795531672.0" user="fuckurprivacy" delta="False">
    <text>Camping close enough to have people within earshot is not camping. 

If you really want peace and quiet there are secluded camp sites, but generally they are farther away and not at big parks.

Otherwise, deal with people and their noise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795624262.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Camping close enough to have people within earshot is not camping.    
  
I don't see how it doesn't qualify. Could you please elaborate?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795636106.0" user="fuckurprivacy" delta="False">
    <text>You camp to be with nature. Camping next to other people just turns into a middle class trailer park.

Like I said, if you want quiet, you go real camping, other wise deal with your neighbors.

I'm fine with both kinds, just know the difference though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795759145.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>[🤔](https://i.imgur.com/6qA29Y9.png)  
  
Seems like a needless, gate keeping distinction. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795773257.0" user="fuckurprivacy" delta="False">
    <text>Apparently not, other wise this post wouldn't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795802552.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>How so? Camping is camping no matter where you do it. Whether you're 250 miles into the Canadian wilderness or in a park in the city, or even in your backyard, you're camping.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795820190.0" user="fuckurprivacy" delta="False">
    <text>Anyone who's gone camping where you can't park your car anywhere near your campsite knows the difference. If a radio is bothering you, that's your own fault.

Go camp where you aren't in a parking lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795823817.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Anyone who's gone camping where you can't park your car anywhere near your campsite knows the difference.

There's certainly a difference. But it's two different types of camping, not camping and non-camping.   
Are you really going to gatekeep sleeping in a tent? Because you are, and it's not a good shade on you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795829853.0" user="fuckurprivacy" delta="False">
    <text>Man, this whole post is about this guy complaining about noise. You can't have it both ways. This is why I don't call it real camping. If you have to comlain on the internet about other people, you aren't camping properly.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
