<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="95" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30797280044.0" user="trying629" delta="False">
    <text>I absolutely agree with you that it is intrusive and rude. I live a short drive away from multiple parks, but it's always the ones with lakes or rivers which draw the trash out. It's almost like they went to park because they couldn't act a fool at home.

However, if you are going to a public park with campgrounds, then it is to be expected that others will be there to enjoy it, too. You idea of enjoyment and other people's idea are totally different. When I take my family to a public park, I do it with the knowledge that there will be obnoxious people there. The family with the screaming kids. The teenagers who have nothing better to do but ride bikes and yell at people. The family of chainsmokers blaring crappy music while their dollar store hotdogs cook. The kids who turn their phones up and play games at night.

Consideration for others is becoming a lost trait. Public parks are a great way to see this in action  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
