<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="35" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795684109.0" user="alphazulu8794" delta="False">
    <text>I hate to be that guy, but if you want privacy and your "own campsite", go out and actually camp in the wild. Dont just sit at an RV park.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795779069.0" user="DeviousPigeon" delta="False">
    <text>I go camping every year over new years in wild bushland without power/reception/cabins and we are always within five-ten metres of the next campsite. Hardly an “RV park”. In Australia you have to have a permit and **site** to camp on for majority of park-land. Plus if you have a family, or for pure convenience you would want to camp in a place with basic facilities i.e. toilets and showers. 


You should still be entitled to your own privacy noise wise in these areas and shouldn’t just be brushed aside as to move to somewhere more isolated.

But agreed, if OP is in a commercial campsite which generally has a pool/cabins barely on the edge of a main town then you should expect noise. Although I don’t think this is the case if he is talking about being able to “hear the birds and nature” when the music isn’t around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795793812.0" user="alphazulu8794" delta="False">
    <text>In the states(just assuming from OP) you can rent a campsite near others, typically in a larger park where you can hike or swim and hear nature. But even as a kid, my grandpa would take me into the woods and have us camp in the wilderness. I agree, with small kiddos camp in a community. But any older than 8, just go into the wilderness and enjoy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796821913.0" user="mirror_scotty" delta="False">
    <text>Since Bluetooth speakers are now polluting hiking trails in a big way, that argument loses effectiveness.  Now I can be ten miles out in the backcountry and still have to put up with someones idea of relaxing noise.   Should I?  I'm becoming more and more vocal about not appreciating this attitude towards other trail users.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796833306.0" user="alphazulu8794" delta="False">
    <text>Just politely ask them to turn down their music. I keep my headphones off on the trail in case someone screams or an animal is near, but I keep my music at the lowest setting so I can hear it, but more than 5 ft away you wont. I understand the annoying people are out there, they may just not realize they suck.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796846081.0" user="mirror_scotty" delta="False">
    <text>A group of 5 with a speaker is aware of what they are doing.  As another pointed out, I am not getting into a confrontation with anyone far away from law enforcement and without even cell phone coverage.   

Anyone thoughtless enough to do this on a hiking trail might argue back or worse.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797182689.0" user="alphazulu8794" delta="False">
    <text>If you just ask them to turn it down politely, you'd be surprised. It's what I do if its bothering me, and typically people are chill. Most hikers aren't intentionally douchebags, and overall a chill culture.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
