<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="71" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30796515662.0" user="CreeDorofl" delta="False">
    <text>You must just enjoy arguing or at least complaining, because this obviously is dick behavior and I have no idea why you'd want to stop believing that. 

[waits for post to get deleted... but seriously, is there no standard in this sub about whether posts are made in good faith?]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796520741.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I love you for thinking I’m do obviously right that it shouldn’t be a question.

However. I’ve been humbled many times in life. Particularly after having an autistic kid — everything I though id do about kids are parenting is turned completely upside down. I am someone who has been wrong many times and I am open to having my view changed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30799933521.0" user="CreeDorofl" delta="False">
    <text>fair enough :)  Well I am glad you're openminded, but hope your mind stays closed on this one, I wouldn't want to encourage these other campers. People go camping specifically to get away from other people's noise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
