<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795862395.0" user="Aborticus" delta="False">
    <text>Yo, park ranger here. 10pm quite hours, before that oh well. We will ask to turn it down if it's too loud but idk go for a walk if it makes you angry. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796366557.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>I think OP is talking about day time music. Like he said - he is cooking dinner. Unlikely to be past 10:00.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796958263.0" user="pseudogentry" delta="False">
    <text>I think that's the balance to be struck. OP has every right to enjoy peaceful camping, in the same way that others have the right to play music *within reason*. I do a lot of camping in the U.K., aside from my festival work, and I vary my behaviour depending on the company. If there's kids around, or families trying to get some peace and quiet, then rein it in and shut it down around dinner time. On the other hand, if we're the only people in the entire field, I'll blast Wu-Tang hard as I like until the cows come home.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
