<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="63" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30796420611.0" user="humanmanguy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off. )


So you’re salty about it, and you want people here to somehow make you happy/not salty in your current situation? Maybe this should’ve been a /r/trueoffmychest post?


If you’re bothered by the noise from other campers, then you probably went into it with the wrong mindset and expectations. The fact that you’re redditing right now kinda proves that point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796428215.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I think I really hoping to hear: 

my autistic kid needs music-to be calm

my mom thinks bears will eat her and the music will keep them away

It’s central to my experience for (other reasons I haven’t thought of)

Only redditing while waiting for water the boil! 

By the the music people at the next site  door are packing up. They do seem like nice enough kids. Waaaaay younger than I’d have thought based on their 1990s music picks.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
