<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30794950293.0" user="Helpfulcloning" delta="False">
    <text>Why would it be fine when in a backyard but offensive when camping? 

What really is the difference with a two families hanging out sitting in seperate backyards and if one starts playing music than if it was in a camp ground? The only difference really is a lack of fence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30794987636.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>No walls at all.  I can’t go inside to enjoy my own recreation.  We’re all sitting outside,  a few dozen yards apart,</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795077994.0" user="Helpfulcloning" delta="False">
    <text>Loud enough music can still stop you going inside to get away from it.

Is a fence really that much of a difference? It doesn’t block the music? What if they put out a windbreaker? 

The “we’re all sitting outside a few dozen yards apart” still applies with a backgarden. In fact you could technically be sitting closer in a backyard. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795090222.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>What’s a windbreaker? 
I am not talking about loud obnoxious music that would shake the walls. Just ‘now everyone in this section of the campground is hearing Kenny Chesney whether they like it or not ‘ level. (I’m actually missing U2).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795908143.0" user="Zagged" delta="False">
    <text>windbreaker: https://i1.adis.ws/i/jpl/bl_026763_a?w=478&amp;amp;h=478&amp;amp;qlt=80</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796491184.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>If you can’t get over the fact that some people enjoy different genres of music than you, then maybe you should just go home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796499899.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t care why they listen to , I care that they are forcing me to listen to it. See the difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796502202.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>No ones forcing you to do anything</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796508910.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Not true.  Picture a dozen families sitting around campfires quietly , and then one group starts blaring music. 
The dozen families could all pack up and leave, but with tents and fires going that would take a while.  At least for a short time — they are forced to content with that noise.  Or bitch to the noisy group , but , that can lead to the volume going up. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796514038.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Well, then the issue is really that the music too loud then, correct? Or am I missing something here </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796529092.0" user="tweetypi" delta="False">
    <text>That's just something that sucks about being around people. You don't know that the other dozen families are upset by it. Personally I kind of enjoy it. That's also why I don't go to campsites that ban music.




My opinion is that there are generally posted rules about campgrounds, and if you choose to go to one that has not banned music then you are accepting that someone might play music. I've been to ones that have quiet hours, or don't allow speakers, or ones where it's known to be a party place and music is encouraged. If your enjoyment of camping is based on how other people around you act, then either find a campsite with rules you agree with, or pay a premium to get a campsite far away from others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797053144.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>You are missing the point of the question. The question is whether it "should" not whether it "is". In other words, your case is "because the camp ground does not ban music, therefore music played is not a problem". This is a circular logic.

I should not kill people because it is banned. I should rape because rape is not banned. Both of those statements are both fallacies.

With the logic of "don't like it? Leave!", it's very hard to argue against. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797119531.0" user="tweetypi" delta="False">
    <text>But you think they should ban it. I disagree and enjoy going to places that allow you to play music. The answer isn't to take a poll and say, "51% of people would prefer no music so everyone should not play music", it's to go to a campground that suites your needs. Want quiet, go to a park that advertises and creates rules around being a quiet place. I don't think it should be banned so I don't go to parks where they ban music. Why go to a park that has rules you don't agree with and then complain that others are following the rules of the park?





The answer is, don't like it? Find a place that suites your needs. I like to play music so I look at the rules and find a park that will allow me to do that as it is part of my enjoyment. If someone's enjoyment is based on me not playing music, then they shouldn't be at the park that allows it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800241512.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are still missing the point. The question isn't "how to find peace at campground". A practical answer for that question is "go to a park that ban music". You are then correct. 

However, why should "banning music" or "allowing music" a thing at all? If a park has no rules regarding this matter, what is the rationale this park would process before it decided "ban or not to ban" or take any action at all. We can expect that fellow campers have enough manners not to intrude others while sharing the space without any rules. 

As for my personal view, I do find it puzzling that people bring their whole house with them, RV and beds and all the tech, to a campground and call it "enjoying nature". But everyone is entitled to the space if they reserved it. I just don't think they get to abuse it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800827358.0" user="tweetypi" delta="False">
    <text>








&amp;gt;We can expect that fellow campers have enough manners not to intrude others while sharing the space without any rules.




Again, you find it intrusive. It is not guaranteed that everyone who goes to a campground wants peace and quiet. That is proven because there are campgrounds that offer peace and quiet, and ones that offer the ability to play music, and both types get customers. Why should it be assumed that it's a quiet park if there's nothing advertising/enforcing that?




Your view seems to be that people should assume that campgrounds with no posted rules should be assumed to be quiet zones, but I disagree. In my opinion you should take the rules and campground culture into consideration, but I don't agree that quiet campgrounds are objectively better as you seem to. Both quiet campgrounds and noisy campgrounds have their purpose, I don't think it's fair to go to one that isn't specifically either and then get mad that it isn't the way you prefer it.




And the rationale is generally the opinions of the customers. If it's something that affected your enjoyment, talk to the park staff. If you think having quiet hours or a no speaker rule or just that certain people should have been talked to, bring it up to them. They might change the rules around next year based on feedback.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800896830.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that park should be quiet. I do expect that people who play music understand their impact to people around them and be considerate. I don't need to ban anyone. I also don't think one is better than the other objectively. 

I suppose I do presume that park without rules means "quiet" as not to intrude on others. Seems like you disagree... Is everyone entitled to disturb others?

On the notes of the park, I belive their missions should guide their actions and not treating the people using the park as "customers". 

This is a national park and their missions isn't making money or customers satisfaction. Perhaps their goals are to allow maximum access and enjoyment of the park with minimal impact to it's natural habitats. If so, it can use that to guide the answer to questions such as "does music increase enjoyment for everyone of the park with minimum impact to habitat?" If answer is yes, then sure. If no, then no. 

Private Parks can do what they want. Perhaps they can focus on revenues. And the answers should really thinking about how to get the most money into the park </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797818156.0" user="ahshitwhatthefuck" delta="False">
    <text>Why can't you go camp in the actual wilderness instead of this Walmarty fake-camping version you currently partake in?  You don't seem to enjoy it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796797246.0" user="Marvelous_Margarine" delta="False">
    <text>People like you make me pull my hair out.  

OP you just have to out 'adult' them.  Go up to than and say hi, I would appreciate not having to listen to Kenny fucking Chesney or any one else all day.  And if they don't listen play your own music at the same level until they get annoyed and turn it off.  Then turn yours slightly down and play it for another hour and then turn it off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796852195.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty sure no ones stopping you from just playing your own music to begin with. You would probably block out each other’s music with your own. The other people would probably have no idea that you’re trying to ‘adult’ them... they’ll just think oh that guys playing music over there. What a perfectly normal fucking thing to do. There not gunna think ah man that guy totally out ‘adulted’ us by playing his own music. Damn!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800410383.0" user="cat_of_danzig" delta="False">
    <text>Who gets to decide which genre is played. If I am not OK with Kenny Chesney, do I get to put NWA on my speaker to drown it out? Does the next site then get to throw Green Day on? Then another some Celine Dion? Who makes the decision?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800428768.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Lol what do you mean? You can play whatever music you want. That’s my point. As long as it’s not too loud or too late in the night. And I can play whatever music I want. And we can all live happily ever after</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800445817.0" user="cat_of_danzig" delta="False">
    <text>I mean that if your music is loud enough for other campers to hear, what is their recourse if it is not their taste? I like some [Einstürzende Neubauten](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kn14Rq8sUAg) now and then, but I bet you don't want to hear it across a burbling creek when camping. 

Is it not better to avoid music altogether, rather than to offend? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800453495.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>I thought we were under the assumption that the music was being played at an acceptable level? If it's not, then you go over to them and politely ask them to turn it down. If it's a campground, you could probably call security or the front desk or even the cops. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800459439.0" user="cat_of_danzig" delta="False">
    <text>OP's complaint is that they are being forced to listen to someone else's music. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797261421.0" user="exotics" delta="False">
    <text>You could always go over and request a song..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795763752.0" user="Feroshnikop" delta="False">
    <text>.. and that's when it becomes a legitimate legal issue in most places.

Noise complaints don't just refer to people whining about noise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796351035.0" user="Helpfulcloning" delta="False">
    <text>Some people have relatively thin walls that they’re able to hear reasonable music outside through their walls. 

Also most noise complaints will be ignored unless it is within certian hours (say, 11pm to 6am). You can have a jackhammer going on outside and the noise complaint will be ignored. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795488439.0" user="ghostlonefight" delta="False">
    <text>Right, and most folks have like a chain link fence or maybe a privacy fence. Neither of those things block sound noticeably. I'd wager that you're actually closer to your fenced off neighbors and their sounds. I think the main thing is that you understand that people like playing music while they enjoy a good time. That good time could be at a campsite, or in a backyard, but the reason for the music is the same. It's something that the DJ likes, or maybe it's just inoffensive background noise, or maybe it was mom's favorite playlist and boy do we miss her or whatever. Any of those things could be reasons for the music and none of them change when you're at the campsite vs backyard. In both cases you can let your neighbor know that it's a little louder than you like, just put up with it, appeal to an authority if it's really obnoxious (campground supervisor or cops), or just accept it as common background noise at a campsite (like loud talkers, screaming kids, and so on). 


On another note, if you're camping on a campground, then you have to kind of expect people noises lol </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797702872.0" user="everythingsexpensive" delta="False">
    <text>Also I don't know about you but I usually camp on a body of water, water carrys  sound WAY more than just sitting in your backyard</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
