<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795015486.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>Singing songs around the campfire while someone plays on their guitar is a camping pastime that was very special to me and I really can't imagine trying to prevent people from the tradition of singing campfire songs.

I understand that "playing music" on a bluetooth device might be a bit different to you than "playing music" on a guitar, but I wanted to make sure that that differentiation is there as I see no issues with people playing music on instruments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795033293.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I agree.  I’m talking about ‘music as background noise’ not actively making music with friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795369551.0" user="MOGicantbewitty" delta="False">
    <text>Today, that is how you make music with friends. Live music isn’t as big of a part of everyday culture anymore. We don’t even know the lyrics to campsongs. So you put recorded music on, and maybe you sing a little to that. Or it triggers a memory or conversation. Or it sets a mood for the scene around the fire. People use recorded music very similarly to how live music used to be used.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795425649.0" user="MAKE_ME_REDDIT" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree heavily with this. Live music is still very much a thing for the majority of people. I don’t even know where you’re getting this idea. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795480638.0" user="velogeek" delta="False">
    <text>There's a huge difference between live music at a venue  (no matter how small, casual, or otherwise) and casual acoustic guitar at a campsite with friends.  The latter is significantly less common than it was 10-20 years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795585671.0" user="MAKE_ME_REDDIT" delta="False">
    <text>The latter was what I was referring to. It’s really not less common. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795613884.0" user="velogeek" delta="False">
    <text>Must be where you live then because I don't think I've heard it once since iPods and mobile speakers became a thing.  Recorded music has been king every time I've gone camping in the past 10-15 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795632624.0" user="MAKE_ME_REDDIT" delta="False">
    <text>Find better camping spots</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795662730.0" user="TrontRaznik" delta="False">
    <text>I've been camping all around the Colorado Rockies almost every other week for the entire summer and haven't heard a single campfire song. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796594926.0" user="KazuyaDarklight" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think I a single friend who plays(Double digits so lets not play that game). With easy playback of a huge selection comes a reduced need to be able to do it yourself unless that's really your thing. And don't be the "get better friends" guy. It's an extra rude way to be dismissive of a reality you don't like and they are good people, they just don't play camp instruments.

Edited to acknowledge I am aware of a guy at work who plays but no one from my medium size friend group does. (Dost protest too much? With the way people like to do "snappy comebacks", sometimes you have to.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796921494.0" user="MAKE_ME_REDDIT" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously? You don’t know a single person that plays guitar? I find that really hard to believe </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796979213.0" user="KazuyaDarklight" delta="False">
    <text>KNOW yes, and I apologize I did word that poorly as I meant "know" in the sense of friendship, there is this one guy at work I know does guitar(out of nearly 300 employees, not saying others there don't know how to play, but he is the one guy who's been public about it), but am friends with no, and no I don't simply have friend group in the single digits. =p</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797003128.0" user="MAKE_ME_REDDIT" delta="False">
    <text>I think that says more about the circle you run in than it does about modern times. Most people that play casually aren’t going to be super public about it unless it comes up. By contrast, I just graduated from college and I’d say at *least* 1/4 or the student population could play guitar at some level. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797008143.0" user="KazuyaDarklight" delta="False">
    <text> I don't know, I think that says more about the school you went to than it does about modern times.

Seriously, anecdotes vs anecdotes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795430074.0" user="jimbobzz9" delta="False">
    <text>    Today, that is how you make music with friends.

Speak for yourself. Sounds like you need more musical friends.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796012818.0" user="trojan25nz" delta="False">
    <text>Or be happy with the friends you have and Use the technology available to you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795477821.0" user="joeverdrive" delta="False">
    <text>Never have I ever heard anyone sing along to modern music from a bluetooth speaker at a campsite. For some reason, acoustic music and singing is publicly tolerated and even enjoyed outdoors while recorded music simply isn't. 

One reason people used to learn to play music because there wasn't any other way to hear it. Now, like so much else, music is something for people to buy and consume, not create. It's silly to say "that is how you make music with friends" and almost insulting to people who put in the time and effort to learn an instrument or sing well. 

Many of us including myself see camping as a sort of escape from that material/consumer culture, and to bring elements of it with you like that doesn't make sense to us. Of course, you have every right to go out to the woods and watch Netflix on your iPad all night. But once your neighbor, who presumably is trying to enjoy a natural atmosphere free of digital distractions, has to hear it, he or she is ripped from that feeling of escape, and it becomes inconsiderate behavior.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795547424.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>Get better friends, I sing along all the time and my friends do too </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795662668.0" user="slaqz" delta="False">
    <text>So your at a campsite and one of your friends brings a Bluetooth speaker and plays music but no one ever sings along to any of the songs? That’s what I’m understanding from your first statement and it seems absurd. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795668318.0" user="AlgaeToday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; One reason people used to learn to play music because there wasn't any other way to hear it. 

That isn't true at all. People have been playing music from their cars for as long as pop music has been on the radio. Portable transistor radios have been around since the 1950s.

Society didn't put down musical instruments because recent technology enabled them to hear music wherever they choose, if that were true I'd argue it has more to do with spending leisure time online as opposed to learning to play and perform with instruments. All that said, I don't think guitars at campsites have really gone anywhere, it's definitely still a thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795682227.0" user="VengefulCaptain" delta="False">
    <text>If that bothers you then you should book campsites that are more secluded from other sites. 

My family bought a cottage but when we used to car camp we would get the camp sites that are about a minute walk between sites.

If you book an RV site and are expecting only background forest sounds you are gonna have a bad time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797615903.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Never have I ever heard anyone sing along to modern music from a bluetooth speaker at a campsite

That's great, some of us do it all the time. Like, last month.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795751751.0" user="vtesterlwg" delta="False">
    <text>and this is terrible. live music should be a big part of culture, it's much more fun</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796018543.0" user="Nitrome1000" delta="False">
    <text>Not all of us got to bring big fuck off cellos to or spent hours in band practise and unless you want me tooting my recorder I'm going to be playing some lo-fi hip-hop to study and relax to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796053819.0" user="vtesterlwg" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; lo-fi hip-hop to study and relax to.

LOL

listen to this shit instead

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=isxvXITTLLY

if you don't you're not a true chivalrous nobleman tbh</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796130276.0" user="Nitrome1000" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;if you don't you're not a true chivalrous nobleman tbh

I mean if I ever feel the need to fuck up eastern Mediterranean than sure I'll play some German deus vult. But until than im tooting  on my recorder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795865142.0" user="justsaying0999" delta="False">
    <text>This is so plainly wrong. You don't make music by playing back songs from your ipod. And way, way more often than not, music played back is just background noise, not something people actively engage with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795556525.0" user="WerhmatsWormhat" delta="False">
    <text>In terms of disruption, what’s the difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795583685.0" user="Cainpole" delta="False">
    <text>It's entertaining when playing live. Annoying when playing on a radio. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795589006.0" user="MAKE_ME_REDDIT" delta="False">
    <text>How so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795910564.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>not the person you asked but I came here to say the same sk I'll answer. Music traveling from a speaker while camping has a harsh, grating sound because it's a shitty 3" speaker. The sound that travels from human voices and an acoustic guitar (for example) is actually very pleasant to the ears. I realize that's an opinion but it's true just the same. There is nothing more aggravating to hear carrying from another camp than the high range only noise of a small speaker. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795938390.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>So by that logic it's fine if the speaker is better and makes good quality sound?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795995928.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>Well it's way beyond that but for the sake of argument if you recorded people singing and playing guitar using really nice gear and then had some audiophile set up a speaker system that would emulate the exact output as real people than yes I suppose a bigger speaker would change my opinion? Good grief </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796017818.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>Why good grief?

You just admitted that your view is not based on the music itself.  You're upset because your view was changed on CMV?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796029119.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>You're being obstinate by suggesting that. The initial discussion was why it's acceptable to play a guitar and sing while camping as opposed to playing music through the sound systems that everyone brings camping. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796043811.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796341381.0" user="whitef530" delta="False">
    <text>u/thief90k – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+thief90k&amp;amp;message=thief90k+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5b63hf/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/thief90k – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+thief90k&amp;amp;message=thief90k+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5b63hf/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796937025.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Lol why do you have to do the recording and producing? He’s just saying what if you weren’t using a shitty 3” speaker. Can you only listen to your own recordings on speakers that are bigger than 3”? You’re all over the place man</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797159273.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797160751.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Gotta love blatant racism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797164185.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>So edgy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797166733.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>So edgy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797170066.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Then please explain for me why I need to record my own music if I were to get speakers bigger than 3”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797210354.0" user="IIIBlackhartIII" delta="False">
    <text>u/choke_on_my_downvote – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+choke_on_my_downvote&amp;amp;message=choke_on_my_downvote+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5bu06h/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796084083.0" user="codymariesmith" delta="False">
    <text>what if they're a bad singer? what if they're not very good at guitar?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796646702.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>what if? Wasn't the point at all. Like not even a little bit.... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30798658292.0" user="codymariesmith" delta="False">
    <text>then I don't want to hear that shit and it doesn't make it any better than a couple speakers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800820456.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>Are you familiar with the concept of things being relative to one another? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795835522.0" user="afhverju" delta="False">
    <text>I like eggplants, therefore everyone must like eggplant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795919407.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>more like, "overcooked three hour old eggplant is gross but fresh perfectly cooked eggplant is better". There is a difference there no? Even if somebody thinks that the former is better they're still wrong</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795940546.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not like that at all.  Personally I can't stand live music 90% of the time, I like to hear well-mastered pre-recorded studio music.

Also we're talking about opinions, so if someone likes overcooked eggplant they are not wrong, they just have a different opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796002520.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't trying to die on eggplant Hill I was just pointing out that it was a shitty analogy for you to use in the first place. My point was that there is nuance (which you still fail to grasp clearly) and that your well mastered studio music is going to sound horrible to other people simply because of the nature of the speakers that you would be playing then with in a goddamned campsite. Jesus christ this sub.... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796016572.0" user="thief90k" delta="False">
    <text>"Jesus Christ this sub" because it's disagreeing with you?

Some speakers are fantastic and give fantastic quality sound.  If you were complaining about shitty speakers then you'd find more people agreeing with you, but you're not, you're complaining about the music in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796033079.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>You don't know anything about acoustics and you don't actually even understand what I'm saying. 👋 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796440887.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Dude ... I don’t necessarily disagree with you on the whole live vs. recorded but holy shit man let people enjoy what they want to enjoy lol. Some people like the color green, some people like the color blue. These things are called opinions. And not everyone is going to have the same ones.

Also, live music being better than recorded music is extremely circumstantial. It won’t always be black and white. Some bands/musicians sound better live, some don’t. Some people have really nice speakers, some don’t. And some people get weirdly offended when other people have different tastes, some don’t. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796659364.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>We're talking acoustics here not musical prefence... has nothing to do with taste at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796682298.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>So you’re saying that preferring live music over recorded music has nothing to do with your taste in music? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796921414.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>The comment was specifically in reference to music coming from a nearby campsite and I was arguing that, all things equal in terms of musical skill etc, there is a big difference between a song rattling through a shitty Bluetooth speaker and coming from human voices and acoustic instruments. Never did I say anything about live music being better than recorded music. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796966606.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>    Never did I say anything about live music being better than recorded music.

That’s what the original commenter was saying though. So that’s what the discussion is about. You’ve derailed now. I’m not really sure what you’re fucking point is. Yeah shitty speakers sound like shit. Very profound insight there. The quality of the speakers is not even relevant to the main discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797156648.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't responding to who you think I was? Either way don't get pissy with me because you misunderstood please. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797159313.0" user="LeaveMyBrainAlone" delta="False">
    <text>Who were you responding to who you think you was once were?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797607564.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;We're talking acoustics here not musical prefence

I take it you've never seriously shopped for headphones.  Acoustics are almost entirely musical preference.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800827635.0" user="choke_on_my_downvote" delta="False">
    <text>That's simply not true at all. People can prefer bad sound to good sound but I'm not sure that you know what the word acoustic means. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795600754.0" user="erichermit" delta="False">
    <text>the disruption is the same but "singing songs 'round a campfire" is acceptable all the same. This is because there are additional considerations to apply.

1. this action requires effort on the part of the noise creators, meaning its unlikely to go on and on and on. Someone can leave the radio playing for hours and hours but generally will transition from song singing to other activities periodically.
2. its such a beloved camping tradition that most everyone would agree its worth the compromise to allow it. this is not true for playing a radio, which aside from disturbance also has the unwelcome affect of bringing nonhuman elements to the camping area, which for many is about distancing oneself from such elements to various degrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795874585.0" user="AnimusCorpus" delta="False">
    <text>Also, no one is bringing a drum kit/bass guitar/amp combination to go camping. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796031365.0" user="matholio" delta="False">
    <text>It's not universally beloved.  I personally can't stand it when someone gets their guitar out and takes on the role as bard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796308546.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796348216.0" user="whitef530" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Danielhibbs – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+Danielhibbs&amp;amp;message=Danielhibbs+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5bbrr6/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796450682.0" user="the_fat_whisperer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a guitarist and I completely agree.  Guitar music in general is not everyone's cup of tea.  To add to that, its usually someone who has only practiced enough to be the "brings his guitar" guy that does it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796705112.0" user="SJNLACNL" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah if you like Wonderwall and Wagon Wheel those guys are great.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796930055.0" user="the_fat_whisperer" delta="False">
    <text>Its shame too because I am a huge Oasis fan.  Wonderwall is amazing when Noel or Liam Gallagher are performing it.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796984141.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797036167.0" user="etquod" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/scamper_pants – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+scamper_pants&amp;amp;message=scamper_pants+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5bq91p/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797231271.0" user="JessieTS138" delta="False">
    <text>agreed. they never know how to play, and nobody can carry a tune (even with a forklift).

i don't even like it on TV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796273539.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>1. How do you determine the arbitrary period of time for which it is acceptable for campers to engage in a noisy activity?

2. There is no expectation of avoiding nonhuman elements in a public campground; people who go camping in densely populated areas are the ones to blame for having unrealistic expectations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796926043.0" user="HawkSpotter" delta="False">
    <text>Well put, erichermit—totally agree. To answer OP’s question— no you are not wrong.  

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795928983.0" user="Liberty_Call" delta="False">
    <text>One is generating noise for the sake for generating noise while people do other things that have nothing to do with the noise.

The other is a bonding activity based on generating the noise. The noise is the activity, and it is an activity that is a deeply ingrained camping tradition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796028128.0" user="matholio" delta="False">
    <text>Don't underestimate the bonding power of a shared music genre.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796144862.0" user="madjarov42" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, that exists, but it's far outweighed by the much more likely scenario of not everyone within earshot sharing the taste. And even if they are, they may not want to be listening to music at all - even if it's the genre they like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796275927.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>The same is true of the bonding experience of singing songs around the campfire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796347016.0" user="madjarov42" delta="False">
    <text>But to a lesser extent. I never listen to country music, but if someone was singing it at a campfire (well) I'd be totally absorbed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796486233.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>Good for you, but i dont see how your hypothetical personal experiences carry any weight here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796571959.0" user="madjarov42" delta="False">
    <text>By extrapolation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797328802.0" user="mgraunk" delta="False">
    <text>We cant extrapolate from your own opinions and experiences, they're too subjective and specific.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797385979.0" user="madjarov42" delta="False">
    <text>OK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795938823.0" user="PurpleIcy" delta="False">
    <text>One isn't earrape dubstep, I guess?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795944519.0" user="crystaloftruth" delta="False">
    <text>One is wholesome like camping</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797458821.0" user="YungEnron" delta="False">
    <text>One is an activity that ends the other is a set and forgotten state of constant noise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795943390.0" user="EYNLLIB" delta="False">
    <text>Your whole question is invalidated simply on the basis you can't expect quietness when you pack in a small campground with hundreds of other people. If you're after peace and quiet, that's not how you get it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795996541.0" user="BeardOfEarth" delta="False">
    <text>There's a huge difference between "expecting quietness" and "expecting other people not to play loud music through speakers in a shared campground."

One is an absurd statement by you. The other is a normal expectation of basic campground etiquette. 

More importantly, by your own logic your entire comment is invalidated. Have you ever been in the woods at night? It's not quiet. Unless you're in a desolate area with very little animal or insect life, things are constantly making noise at night. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796577005.0" user="calviso" delta="False">
    <text>"Nature sounds" are animals making music (mostly 'cause they tryna fuck).

Making music around the campfire is making music.

Playing music already made is not.

Ergo, guitar around the campfire is acceptable. Bluetooth speakers are not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796587789.0" user="smoogstag" delta="False">
    <text>Mate, how is that any different than the people who play their music from their phones out loud with no headphones on the subway? Sure, you don’t expect a subway car to be QUIET, but it’s still a dick move that nobody else enjoys. 
You go camping to get away from city noise and bustle (and to get drunk and eat hot dogs). Top 40 radio, or any pop music from shitty speakers, is decidedly urban, and thus not fitting for a campground.
Cooking over a fire is quite common while camping but if you lit one up in Ikea because you wanted lunch you’d get arrested. There’s a time and a place for things. That’s what the OP is saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796380162.0" user="the_real_klaas" delta="False">
    <text>Even then.. most players of acoustic guitars should either practise a lot more before, or learn how to dampen their strings a little.. that sounds carries a whole lot farther than most people are aware of</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796551978.0" user="PursuedByASloth" delta="False">
    <text>To me, this is an issue of volume rather than whether the music is live or recorded.

Often when I go camping, I see a couple of people playing acoustic guitar and singing in the campground. The noise level produced by that activity is pretty quiet, especially with a max of 6 people per campsite. 

Imagine a different, much louder instrument.... trumpet, electric guitar, bagpipes? You bet I’d have a problem with that, even if I generally like those instruments. Doesn’t matter that they’re making live music with friends. 

So if a fellow camper wants to play music on their speaker or radio, that’s fine with me as long as the volume is kept at a reasonable, respectful level. This is subjective, but IMO, reasonable is ‘conversation’ level (i.e. no louder than regular voice volume). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796688554.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I agree! If it can hear all the lyrics clearly from a couple sites away, it’s not earth shatteringly loud , but it’s too loud got a campground. But quiet as talking normally? No problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797384312.0" user="zensnapple" delta="False">
    <text>Makes sense. Like if it were people screaming at each other loudly I'd have just as much of an issue as if they were playing Dave Matthews Band at the same volume.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797394810.0" user="PursuedByASloth" delta="False">
    <text>Hahaha I’ve had this experience and I was pissed! It was a bunch of drunks late at night, of course. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797431799.0" user="mdmeaux" delta="False">
    <text>Just to be clear, do you actually like those three instruments? Do you like them played together? Because that would be an interesting trio.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797474048.0" user="PursuedByASloth" delta="False">
    <text>Lol! I’m so glad you asked. 

As a kid, I had a neighbor who would stand in his backyard and serenade our entire block on the bagpipes. I honestly loved it. I loved the way the sound waves reverberated in my chest. I’m sure some of my neighbors complained. 

I love the bright, brassy sound of a trumpet, too. 

I’m lukewarm on electric guitar. 

All three together? That would be quite a cacophony! 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797498622.0" user="gaslightlinux" delta="False">
    <text>You're talking about what we called "canned music." It was always considered a strict no-no for multi-group gathering places, with the exception of pre-planned, announced, and permitted events.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795566475.0" user="TheReformedBadger" delta="False">
    <text>Can I borrow your guitar quick?  I play a mean wonderwall</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795592724.0" user="knowledgelover94" delta="False">
    <text>Maybeeeeeeee you’re gonna be the one that saves meeeeeee</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795934346.0" user="eddiemoya" delta="False">
    <text>That's entirely different. I agree, that kind of activity is welcome, and when I've been near others doing that I was only annoyed in the sense that I was jealous.

The thing about that though is that it takes effort, it's personal, and it doesn't go on all night long most often, because there's effort involved.

I've been around a campsite that turned on speakers blasting shitty hiphop and pop music form early morning and all night long - *and they fell asleep with the music still playing!!!*. It's lazy, impersonal, everyone around you hates it, and it's far too easy to just leave it on as "background noise".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796072180.0" user="Spastic_hawk" delta="False">
    <text>I went "Eurocamping" with my folks when I was 15. I took my small acoustic and was happily strumming Nirvana songs (quite badly), when a disembodied  English voice from a nearby tent bellowed "stop playing that fackin' guitar or I'll facking smash it!"  


I was super-embarrassed, and didn't dare play again until we'd left the campsite. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796964885.0" user="paradigmx" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing will make me cringe and nope the fuck out of a camping trip more than an acoustic guitar. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796997272.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>Some of my favorite campfire memories is the camping trips we took when I was younger with a bluegrass band.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797027680.0" user="paradigmx" delta="False">
    <text>Some of my favourite memories are of listening to the wildlife, rivers, and the breeze through the trees. Someone breaking out a guitar means that rather than anyone being able to have a conversation around the fire, now you have to participate in some impromptu concert. It's usually also the douchebag that has the guitar and his actual goal is to get laid. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
