<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795680627.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795791123.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/social_contracts – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+social_contracts&amp;amp;message=social_contracts+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5ayb8z/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
