<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="92" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30797222887.0" user="TheChampis1" delta="False">
    <text>Myself and my family always go camping every year to the same campground, and once we’ve spent the first day setting up everything the first thing we do in the morning is get out the radio and put on rock music. We’ve never gotten complaints, even from people walking past the front of the campsite.

To me, it’s just an issue of volume, and potentially how much space there is in between camp sites and whether or not they are vacant. I always put on the radio at fifteen the first time, and walk to the nearest open site. If I can hear it, I turn it down to twelve. That is normally unable to be heard at the next site. 

So I’d say play your music if you want, but keep it at a respectable volume. If you walk in front of a neighbor’s site, ask if they can hear it or if they are bothered by it. You don’t always have to have it, of course. I always enjoy turning it off and just reading a book and listening to the sounds of nature.

I’d say that as long as the volume is low enough that it won’t disturb the next site, and that they aren’t bothered by it, then playing music is fine.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
