<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795209661.0" user="NorthwesterlyHog" delta="False">
    <text>Background music is pretty common. They play it in stores, on the phone, in the elevator. I don’t really think most people mind inoffensive, low volume, background music, so i doubt most people think it’s a jerk thing to do.

Also, when you stay in a public place you have to make allowances for others behavior. Maybe they like to wake up and talk to their kids at 7 am while you’re still sleeping in your tent. But you have to expect that to happen, because most people do wake up around that time for work and school so they’re on a schedule.

None of these things are out if the norm - background music, people waking up early, kids playing, etc. it might be out of the norm for YOU, but because you are in a public space you need to be accepting of typical behaviors... and background music is pretty typical for a lot of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795212877.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not typical for camping. In my experience, as someone who does it regularly. But perhaps I just get lucky a lot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795230687.0" user="NorthwesterlyHog" delta="False">
    <text>If you hear it every five days I’d argue it’s pretty typical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795262331.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>LOL that is fair! It’s not like it’s everyone though, 25 families here and just one makes the problem .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795407011.0" user="NorthwesterlyHog" delta="False">
    <text>I will say, I think some people are just more chill about people in their personal space. At one end of the spectrum you have people who road rage if your car gets too close to theirs, and at the other end of the spectrum you have people who will literally rub their arm against you at Walmart and not be bothered by it.

There’s nothing wrong with wanting your personal space to be respected. But if you learn to go with the flow a little, and enjoy the WHOLE experience of things, like the neighbor listening to crappy music while you camp, you might not have a heart attack as soon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795717743.0" user="MothaFuknEngrishNerd" delta="False">
    <text>I was totally with you until the snarky ending.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796594997.0" user="NorthwesterlyHog" delta="False">
    <text>If you get a sense of humor you might not have a heart attack as soon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797807208.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797875346.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ausipockets – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+ausipockets&amp;amp;message=ausipockets+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5c7w4o/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795579206.0" user="WerhmatsWormhat" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve replied to a couple separate comments of yours, and I apologize - I just think it’s easiest to address each point individually. Anyway, for this one, it seems like there’s a specific situation about which you have an issue. It’s possible that in your scenario, based on norms of the area, it was inappropriate; however, that doesn’t make it generalizable to the point that your post suggests. There are many camping areas where playing music like this is the norm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795807911.0" user="devlinontheweb" delta="False">
    <text>If other people camping around you bothers you, go somewhere more remote?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796683756.0" user="jamshak" delta="False">
    <text>I also do a lot of camping, and in my experience, most people see it as kind of a dick thing. If sites are relatively large and music can be played without it being loud to others, go for it, but if I’m right beside you, like I can hear your conversations, I don’t want to hear your music and I’ll assume you don’t want to hear mine. Audio is pretty hard to block out and can really ruin a trip if it’s bad enough. Now, different camp grounds are going to have different expectations and reputations, but if I’m somewhere relatively isolated and quiet and 1 person is causing the problem, I’d be a little upset. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30799408266.0" user="HorseIsLikeMan_" delta="False">
    <text>It's completely a dick thing that assholes do. I can't believe anyone here is either naive enough, or enough of an asshole, to argue against you and tell you to "go with the flow" or "enjoy it as part of the experience". Honestly, the fuck is wrong with motherfuckers like this? When all I want is some peace and quiet out in nature, and to just get away from the stress of living and working in a loud city, there always have to be assholes that come along and fuck the whole fucking thing up. Fucking assholes ruin everything; that's what I'm learning more and more now days. Fucking. assholes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
