<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795241659.0" user="PGRBryant" delta="False">
    <text>This is why I go backpacking and generally dislike public campgrounds. :) 

That said, I think it’s pretty dependent on the setting. Some campgrounds (like dunes) allow 4wheelers and other chaos. I’ve definitely been annoyed by a 5am wake up of a blasting engine after staying up until 2 around a campfire. But, that’s kinda the gig in the public woods. You’re choosing to step a little farther away from society, and part of “society” are the formalities that keep us comfortable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795939246.0" user="eddiemoya" delta="False">
    <text>I'm deing to start backpacking. I feel like there's more I need to know/gear I need to fet though before making the jump from fully packed car-camping to backpacking.

We only started camping a bunch this year, in my 30s. I'm a city boy. I never camped as a kid, my family wasn't into the outdoors at all, but I am now.  We've been avid hikers for years, but this year started camping, in part to facilitate our hiking. Our campsites are really just staking grounds for multiple days of hiking.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796020900.0" user="Deathwatch72" delta="False">
    <text>Im pretty sure blasting an engine near people at 5 am is a dick move no matter where you are. Turning it on and it idling is one thing, and but sitting there and revving it up is asinine. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
