<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="62" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30796407724.0" user="visualize_and_attack" delta="False">
    <text>If you want privacy, pay for privacy. There are plenty of places you can go and dictate your experience.  But when you’re in a public space, you have to expect other people to enjoy themselves just like you want to enjoy yourself. 

If I go to the public lake and want to go fishing but there are people water skiing and ruing my experience, do I have the right to be upset? No, I don’t because the lake is public and water skiing is a normal thing to do on a lake. 

Listening to music is a normal thing for friends and families to do when they are on holiday. 

Just because you like camping a certain way, doesn’t mean every one does. Stop being an entitled ass and let people enjoy themselves.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
