<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="60" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30796392161.0" user="stemid85" delta="False">
    <text>If you're in a camping area then you have to learn to live with other people.

I'm from Sweden so I rarely camp around other campers. We have allemansrätten and plenty of wild areas to camp.

So the last time I was bothered by other campers was 2013 I think, when I camped near a well used beach and some kids were partying near by. And that only bothered me because they partied to well after midnight and I had biked there so I needed sleep. I could have moved my tent further down the beach, but I didn't know the terrain and didn't expect them to party so long after it got dark.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796400445.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>I agree you have to learn to live with other people, which is why I didn’t impose on them by asking them to shut it down. My view is that they are the failures here in that they did not care about the impact of others.

My intent in posting was to hear another view . I did read one guy say people may do it to alleviate  anxiety if they’re not used to being outside, which makes sense. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
