<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795559974.0" user="JoeZMar" delta="False">
    <text>I live full time in an RV and travel the US. I mostly stay at state parks because they’re usually the most nature oriented. 

Mon-thurs is usually peaceful and serene and Fri-sun its usually packed with people like that. To them they’re getting a weekend free to unwind and a lot of people use this as an excuse to play loud music and grill because it isn’t just a day in their yard.

The music never bothers us it’s usually the kids that run through our yard and play with our kids toys that are outside SUPER early. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795585533.0" user="adudeguyman" delta="False">
    <text>How old are your kids?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795591506.0" user="JoeZMar" delta="False">
    <text>Two year old boy and five year old girl. It’s mostly startling when you can hear people going through your shit while you’re sleeping then you realize it’s just kids and not a big deal. I don’t ever say anything, but damn man I have kids of my own to wake me up. And this isn’t my “neighbors” kids it’s literally my “new neighbors” kids every weekend when we get a new group of people in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795634665.0" user="adudeguyman" delta="False">
    <text>Are you rv schooling them? What's your long-term plan? I find it interesting doing this full time with kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795644691.0" user="JoeZMar" delta="False">
    <text>Yup. We originally thought we would do the RV thing for a year and then prep for school. Since then my wife and I have learned a lot and we’ve committed to home schooling our kids for at least the next several years. We build our lesson plans around places we are going to see and be around. It’s awesome and we’re saving to buy a catamaran to sail the world next. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795653452.0" user="adudeguyman" delta="False">
    <text>I'd love to give my kid that experience. How awesome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30798130135.0" user="TeflonFury" delta="False">
    <text>Look at Captain Fantastic over here.

But really, sounds like a cool, unique way to learn about the world.  Keep at it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30798229578.0" user="JoeZMar" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks! It’s definitely had its ups and downs but we feel very special we figured out this is the way we want to live our lives. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
