<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="42" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795837120.0" user="XxKeen103xX" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you on the most part. As a camper I understand where you're coming from. I enjoy being able to hear the sounds of nature without the influence or human noise. On the other hand I also have enjoyed bringing a bluetooth speaker while I go camping, mostly so I can listen to the music without the interruption of everyday life. It can enhance my experience of camping. That being said, I don't want my camping experience to intrude on someone else's. I try to be very mindful of how loud the music is being played and take in account how close the nearest campsite is as well as the time of day. During the night I feel music should be barely audible to the nearby listeners. Sound carries a lot more at night and could easily ruin another campers sleep or enjoyment. People who are not mindful of this are just dicks in my opinion. During the daytime I have a little more leeway just because it's the fucking daytime and who gives a shit. As long as it isn't blaring, I'm ok with it. If I have a problem I can just get up and go hike somewhere because that's probably what I should he doing anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797090771.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>Headphones?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30798432455.0" user="XxKeen103xX" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I've done that. It's not super helpful though when the friends you are camping with want to listen too.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
