<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795069361.0" user="coltzord" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I wish they’d shut that crap off

Instead of wishing, why don't you go talk to them, ask them to turn down the volume or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795082322.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>They’re on vacation, just like me . I wouldn’t ask anyone to change their vacation for me over  a mild annoyance .  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795504729.0" user="DaSaw" delta="False">
    <text>No, just quietly judge them behind their backs.

If I may ask, is it the volume that bothers you? Or the fact that you can hear it at all? The former is reasonable. The later is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797070972.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>For me, if I can hear the music for 3 hours straight, even at reasonable volume, that's pretty annoying. I mean, want to take a nap, or read something, or just breath a little, Drake in the background isn't going to help. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797795708.0" user="ausipockets" delta="False">
    <text>Im just picturing a bunch of families camping and enjoying themselves while OP furiously responds to comments on this thread trying to convince everyone to be as outraged as he is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795528399.0" user="Xzillerationer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I wouldn’t ask anyone to change their vacation for me over a mild annoyance .

But you are. By wanting to disallow music, you're making them change their vacation from the start.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795600195.0" user="EldeederSFW" delta="False">
    <text>No, he doesn't want to disallow it, that would be changing their vacation, like you said. He just wants a bunch of people on the internet to tell him how right he is about these people being jerks. That's all. If he cared so much about nature, he wouldn't be asking this on reddit from his campsite in the middle of labor day weekend. It also might explain why in over 4 hours there has not been 1 delta awarded. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796051707.0" user="BeardOfEarth" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it makes much sense to accuse someone of looking for validation if they specifically picked the one subreddit dedicated to the exact opposite of that. Makes as much sense as someone going to /r/trees looking for people who support marijuana prohibition. 

But that's just me. Maybe I'm wrong. Maybe your comment somehow makes sense. Change my view. 

And don't whine about deltas. That's as petty as complaining about a lack of upvotes.

No one owes you anything. The OP appears to have been responding to comments on here for the last seven hours. He's debating with people who disagree with him, which is the intention of this entire subreddit (and is also the exact opposite of seeking validation). Apparently no one has changed his mind. 

Deltas are earned. They're not guaranteed with every post. If they were then they would mean less. It's impressive when someone has earned a lot of them. You sound like you're mad that you have none. Don't be mad. Be more convincing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795718195.0" user="shusshbug" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who is the type of person you're complaining about, I wish you would ask. I always play music when camping but I will always turn it down or off if asked.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796562541.0" user="ThePandagator" delta="False">
    <text>I am in the same boat. I have run weekends with friends camping at a local state park. We tend to play music when we are cooking, boating, etc.

If people ask us to turn it down we have no problem doing that. People are generally respectful and sometimes just aren't paying attention to how loud their music actually is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795772033.0" user="cecilpl" delta="False">
    <text>I would much rather have you come over and ask me to change my volume. That way I don't have to worry that I'm offending anyone and can relax, and let people approach me if they'd like me to change anything.

Otherwise, I have to worry that I might be offending someone, even if everyone would actually be fine with my music.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795865998.0" user="Aborticus" delta="False">
    <text>Campers shouldn't talk to campers, talk to the security and they will handle it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796480416.0" user="montarion" delta="False">
    <text>what? why</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797452380.0" user="rotide" delta="False">
    <text>I'm so confused.  If you were worried about bothering others with your music, why would you not just use headphones?

In my experience, those who _intend_ to bother others (or simply couldn't care less about it) play music via speakers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797509137.0" user="cecilpl" delta="False">
    <text>Because I want to enjoy the music together with my friends? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795580500.0" user="AngryParsley" delta="False">
    <text>If you're camping, you're often in a remote place far from law enforcement and out of cell phone range, so it's best to avoid anything that could spark conflict. One time I was camping near people who were blasting loud music. I started walking towards them to ask them to turn it down, then somebody in their camp pulled out a gun and started firing into the air. I turned around before they noticed me. Had I decided to confront them a minute earlier, things might have gone very differently for me.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796410072.0" user="1234567777777" delta="False">
    <text>What is wrong with America? If I had such a neighbor with music playing too loud I would definitely confront them. Then suddenly they pull out a gun? A what now? Oh, a gun. Yeah ok. I guess they will shoot me now because I raised a concern? They really do have to shoot me over such arguments so that I can find refuge from such humans in heaven and he gets to spend time in prison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797660748.0" user="Phyltre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Then suddenly they pull out a gun? A what now? Oh, a gun. Yeah ok. I guess they will shoot me now because I raised a concern?

Random confrontations and beat-downs is definitely a thing that inebriated camping people are capable of, especially in rural areas.  Your incredulity doesn't change reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797800968.0" user="ausipockets" delta="False">
    <text>99% of the time you’d have no such issue. I’m not sure why people wouldn’t ask in a friendly way to lower the music.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30798047317.0" user="AngryParsley" delta="False">
    <text>To be fair, carrying guns while camping in the western US is not uncommon, as there are animals that can kill you. It wasn't the presence of the firearm that made me turn around, it was the irresponsible discharge of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796018898.0" user="BeardOfEarth" delta="False">
    <text>In a perfect world, that conversation always ends well. 

In the imperfect world in which we live, the reality is that the group of people already doing something rude  often aren't going to respond politely. 

I agree with you that it's best to address it directly with the hope that maybe they didn't realize they were bothering others. In my experience, most people at campgrounds are pretty nice and just trying to enjoy their vacation like everyone else. And even if they don't react positively and don't stop blasting music, at the very least you said what you felt needed to be said. 

But I don't begrudge someone for not wanting to potentially start a conflict with people who are already displaying poor manners, especially since in that campground setting you'd be taking the risk of pissing off a group of jerks whom you'll be sleeping near.

I do agree with your way of thinking, but that's at least one reason why someone wouldn't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30799403060.0" user="HorseIsLikeMan_" delta="False">
    <text>Because most people who are big enough assholes to annoy other people with their music could give two shits about who it's annoying. I've tried approaching neighbors about the noise they create at 2-3am, and all it got me was cussed at and threatened. You're dealing with dickish assholes in almost every single one of these cases.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
