<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="96" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30797341214.0" user="galacticsuperkelp" delta="False">
    <text>While it's definitely discourteous to others, it's pretty fair game in daylight hours car camping. People who would play their music loudly mostly do it in good conscience and with and without the goal of disturbing others. If approached politely, most would turn it down and apologize. Such a test would be good proof of most people's better conscience and unawareness that playing music that loudly was frowned upon. Campgrounds are a common good and have to be shared reasonably between people who like to hear music outdoors and people who just like to hear the outdoors. (After dark I'd definitely agree with your CMV but for obvious and different reasons.) 

Camping still offers many opportunities to get out into nature without having contact from other humans. There are hiking trails and quiet nooks. There's also always the backcountry. In most parks I've been to in Canada, radios/speakers are allowed car camping but not in the backcountry which accessible only by hike or canoe, to protect both people and (I assume) wildlife.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
