<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795556362.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>As some one who’s a avid outdoorsman and music major, I’m the asshole every time except I have loud good sounding music on high quality speakers. Sorry it’s loud, but I don’t really care, that’s my one I don’t give a fuck about. I accommodate for everything except I will never turn off my music. I might turn it down if you ask nicely but be a dick about it and I’ll make sure you leave. I’ve got as much right as you do, and especially since I’m at a campground packed in it’s a party man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795622954.0" user="TheResPublica" delta="False">
    <text>Are you one of those people that plays music in other public settings as well? Like on a train or in a bus? Maybe walking down the street? 

The weirdest one I’ve ever seen was at the gate of an airport.... for an hour. 

I only ask because I have always been curious as to the motivations of these people. Do you see it as sharing your taste in music with the world? Do you think other people just going to spontaneously start vibing with you? 

It’s always been a curiosity of mine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796717954.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t really do it in public places people wouldn’t enjoy it. But I will gladly bump it loud in social settings. And yeah I think it’s sharing my tunes. I love music and it is my favorite thing in the world so I think maybe I can cheer someone else up a little bit when they hear a good song too. I’m also the guy with 2000 in my car stereo and you hear me before you see me. I just really love loud music and think people are way too uptight about music. Like oh my god it’s someone enjoying something and relaxing, let’s crush the fun because I hate music and think it’s annoying </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30802836874.0" user="little_snailor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Like oh my god it’s someone enjoying something and relaxing, let’s crush the fun because I hate music and think it’s annoying

I love the idea that someone is enjoying music and relaxing! I play music, and I love jamming out to music in general.

&amp;gt;I love music and it is my favorite thing in the world so I think maybe I can cheer someone else up a little bit when they hear a good song too.

However... I don't love the idea that I need to listen to other people's loud music because *they* like it. Loud music is really disturbing and distracting for me - sort of like if a stranger was repeatedly poking me in the head or screaming in my face. I understand that's not what it's like for you. And that's totally fine! But please, if you want to be a more considerate and pleasant human being to other members of society, consider using headphones or at least turning your music down for the rest of us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795965219.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796719782.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796775058.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>u/itchy136 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+itchy136&amp;amp;message=itchy136+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5bkl2e/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796773505.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>u/estheredna – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+estheredna&amp;amp;message=estheredna+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5b4eub/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796595290.0" user="PursuedByASloth" delta="False">
    <text>So what is “good sounding music” to you? That’s pretty subjective, isn’t it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796723259.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. In all genres there is regarded in general good music. Almost everyone would agree the Beatles are good rock music. Almost everyone would agree Snoop Dogg is good rap music. I’m a DJ and do weddings all the time, so I’m pretty good at nailing general tastes with the crowd I’m around. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30796932651.0" user="PursuedByASloth" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, you seem to believe you have superior taste in music. You cite being a music major, preferring music that is critically acclaimed within its genre, and working as a wedding DJ as evidence for this unstated conclusion. 

As someone with an education background in both classical music and English literature, I admit to feeling that my tastes are better than others’ at times. But I realize projecting that attitude would be extremely off-putting, so I keep that shit to myself. 

You don’t really have much to gain by being “right” about something as subjective as artistic taste. People are going to like whatever they like, regardless of whether or not it’s “good.” Being respectful, open to different perspectives, and humble, though.... those qualities will get you far in life. 

Just my two cents— take it or leave it. 







</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797106670.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797173572.0" user="PursuedByASloth" delta="False">
    <text>You’re right that I don’t know you— which is why I’ve drawn upon my own past experiences of making an ass out of myself to make my point. 

Nobody likes likes a know-it-all. I’ve personally been at the receiving end of that lesson on more than one occasion. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797309733.0" user="PepperoniFire" delta="False">
    <text>u/itchy136 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+itchy136&amp;amp;message=itchy136+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/-/e5bsvla/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797085135.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>Why not get a set of headphones? If you truly enjoy musics, headphones offers superior sounds quality. Unless you enjoy the style of enjoying music than the actual music, like a truck with a massive subwoofer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30797111873.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>Headphones don’t offer superior quality at all. The drivers can’t recreate bass correctly unless you drop tons of money and even then it’s subpar. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800247612.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>You mean a portable bluetooth speaker can yeild better quality than a good set of headphones? Are people bringing surround sound system to the campground now? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800338717.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah man the JBL line of Bluetooth the more you connect they can go stereo. You can pair up to 8 so if you have 3 of the blimps it's pretty dank. Also I've seen it all camping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800714183.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>Oh man. Crazy. Don't you think it's a bit excessive to bring a surround sounds system to nature to "enjoy music?". Perhaps do so at the comfort of your home? What's the benefit? 

Anyway. Cool beans. I'll never get it and I'll keep judging people for "loving nature" but bring their modernized world with them everywhere they go. :3</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800785103.0" user="itchy136" delta="False">
    <text>Bruh if you are at a big campsite it ain't nature</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30800905895.0" user="olidin" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you presume I stay at big campsite? I typically tent camping and that share with car camping. Even with car camping you can bring quite a bit of convenience. 

You can say "go to the woods" but not every park allows that. Also not every primitive campsites are immediately accessible. Often the only options for even the most ambitious Backcountry campers is to hit the campground. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
