<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="567468370.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9dutea/cmv_album_art_that_solely_consists_of_a_portrait/">
    <title>CMV: Album art that solely consists of a portrait photograph of the artist's or artists' face(s) without any interesting makeup is boring, lazy, and uninteresting.</title>
    <original_poster>Zalmoxis_1</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples: Phil Collins's [*Face Value*](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/c/c9/Phil_Collins_-_Face_Value.png/220px-Phil_Collins_-_Face_Value.png), [*No Jacket Required*](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/2f/Phil_Collins_-_No_Jacket_Required.png), [*...But Seriously*](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/f/f5/Phil_Collins-But_Seriously.jpg)


Taylor Swift's entire discography




Album art serves important functions- to draw a newcomer in and to be aesthetically pleasing. A good album cover ought to tantalize a listener and make them listen to the record.  It can  convey the tone and content of the album "loudly" with blunt and bold symbolism, or it can be mysterious and subtly hint at the content with a minimalist design.


 Additionally, it should be aesthetically appealing to some degree. This is important if you own a physical copy of the album, whether it be vinyl or cd, as it encourages you to preserve the quality of the casing. Additionally, it can be appreciated as you would appreciate any other piece of art. It also makes the band look more serious and professional about their work.



In my opinion, the portrait album covers I provided as examples have none of these qualities. First of all, they don't necessarily stick out. If it wasn't for Collins's and Swift's fame, these records could easily be passed over in a record store. They don't have any unique or noteworthy qualities to them- they're quite vanilla and inoffensive. It's just someone's face without any particular unique makeup or costume. Additionally, they're quite boring to look at. 


Secondly, it's hard to discern the tone and content of the album. Phil Collins seems to be donning a neutral expression in many of the album covers. This obviously makes it hard to determine what kind of music is going to be in the album.



I added the "makeup" caveat as it actually can make portrait covers interesting. Just look at Bowie's *Hunky Dory* and *Aladdin Sane*


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30811145897.0" user="MrGraeme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Album art serves important functions- to draw a newcomer in and to be aesthetically pleasing. A good album cover ought to tantalize a listener and make them listen to the record. It can convey the tone and content of the album "loudly" with blunt and bold symbolism, or it can be mysterious and subtly hint at the content with a minimalist design.

Is it not possible to do this with a portrait? [This](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/f/f5/Phil_Collins-But_Seriously.jpg) album art conveys a very different message than [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fearless_(Taylor_Swift_album)#/media/File:Taylor_Swift_-_Fearless.png), for example. 

What constitutes "interesting makeup"? Would [Made in Germany](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Made_in_Germany_1995%E2%80%932011#/media/File:Made_in_Germany_1995%E2%80%932011_(album)_cover.jpg) get a pass while [Heaven Upside Down](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heaven_Upside_Down#/media/File:Marilyn_Manson_-_Heaven_Upside_Down.png) not make the cut? What about musicians who do not wear copious amounts of makeup, such as male country singers? Surely they could convey the content of their album with a head shot?

&amp;gt;Secondly, it's hard to discern the tone and content of the album. Phil Collins seems to be donning a neutral expression in many of the album covers. This obviously makes it hard to determine what kind of music is going to be in the album.

I got a bit of the opposite impression, actually. I found that, after giving the Phil Collins albums a listen, their respective album art seemed perfectly reasonable at conveying the tone of the music. Both No Jacket Required and But Seriously seem to be emotional/serious albums based on their album art, which lines up relatively well with the content of those albums. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30811347292.0" user="Artist552001" delta="False">
    <text>I personally love photographs as album covers, as I quite enjoy what can be captured and conveyed by a photograph.

Also, side note: Even if u/zalmoxis_1 doesn't enjoy photographs as album covers, Taylor Swift's album 'Speak Now' is not actually a photograph. It is a painting </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
