<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="572887756.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9h2z0s/cmv_free_markets_vs_planned_economies_and/">
    <title>CMV: Free markets vs. planned economies and democracy vs. authoritarianism both teach us the lesson that centralization of power/control is inefficient and a bad idea. Therefore, the means of production should be democratically controlled and resource management should be done via market principles.</title>
    <original_poster>Horror_Policy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm leaning towards market socialism lately.

On the one hand, we know that planned economies don't work. Markets seem superior in every way for resource management, because they are decentralizing. 

On the other hand, democracies teach us the same lesson. All the various types seem to have been more successful than monarchies or dictatorships.

So democracy seems to be the most effective and successful way of governance and control over particular things that require control and definite decisions, also because they are decentralizing.

The two ideas are perfectly compatible, and they both teach us we are better off distributing the responsibility and power over everything.

The most basic idea behind socialism is that the "means of production", the things people need to live, should be democratically controlled. This seems very reasonable. 

Private property for profit is exactly the same process as an authoritarian planned economy trying to consolidate more power towards itself. It's self-serving and inefficient. 

Why would it be any better than democratic control by representatives elected by the community, just because "its private property"? This is dogmatic. 

To me, this is a basic contradiction and a violation of the same pro-market principles used to justify it. 

All the motivations for innovation and efficiency are there in democratic control. 

Nothing changed except the notion of "profit", which in this broader scope plays the same role as "political power" in authoritarian regimes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30852957110.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>there is a difference between government and business, and here it is.

With dictatorships, you don't have a good mechanism for selecting the best dictator.  The dictator is the person most able to metaphorical or literally kill competitors and dissenters.  Occasionally its the son of the previous dictator, but that typically doesn't last terribly long.  Democracy, though imperfect, is much much better at selecting leaders.

But in business we do have a good way of selecting the best leaders.    People who build successful businesses become the leader of those businesses.  If you can build a business, you can lead a business.

We have something else in a free market, that I wouldn't be quick to give up.  We can buy and sell the means of production freely.  I can buy the means of production today.  And i do buy the means of production twice a month, when part of my paycheck goes into my 401k.   In our system we have the freedom to buy the means of production or to buy consumer goods or to hang on to cash.  I personally, like that freedom very much.

and in our current system we *already have democratic control* over the leaders of businesses.  But you only get a vote if you decide to buy into the company.

You haven't exactly said how your system would work.  Does everyone in the country vote or do only employees get a vote?  how are profits distributed?  Who "owns" the means of production?  All citizens own all companies?  All employees own their their company of employment?  Proportional to years work?  How would we transition from the current distribution to the future distribution?  Are current owners bought out?  Who pays them?  Are their assets taken from them?  I have a decent amount of saving invested in the means of production in my 401k.  For a decade I've forgone nice things in order to invest my money.  I hope that isn't just stolen from me.  what about boomers who planned intelligently for their retirement, are they compensated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30854731080.0" user="CJGibson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; With dictatorships, you don't have a good mechanism for selecting the best dictator. The dictator is the person most able to metaphorical or literally kill competitors and dissenters. 

So like when Amazon crushes their competition?

&amp;gt;But in business we do have a good way of selecting the best leaders. People who build successful businesses become the leader of those businesses. If you can build a business, you can lead a business.

I'm not sure why this applies to business but not to nations?  Why isn't the best leader of a nation the person who builds the most "successful" nation?  It also seems to ignore a lot of the realities of how successful business get started, what determines whether a business will be a success, and the entire question of capital.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30854822008.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>There are lots of businesses within a nation. If some or several of them fail, the region can tolerate that. But if there is typically only one nation in a given region. We cannot tolerate the failure of a Nation. So survival of the fittest isn't a good selection mechanism for governments.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
