<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="572887756.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9h2z0s/cmv_free_markets_vs_planned_economies_and/">
    <title>CMV: Free markets vs. planned economies and democracy vs. authoritarianism both teach us the lesson that centralization of power/control is inefficient and a bad idea. Therefore, the means of production should be democratically controlled and resource management should be done via market principles.</title>
    <original_poster>Horror_Policy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm leaning towards market socialism lately.

On the one hand, we know that planned economies don't work. Markets seem superior in every way for resource management, because they are decentralizing. 

On the other hand, democracies teach us the same lesson. All the various types seem to have been more successful than monarchies or dictatorships.

So democracy seems to be the most effective and successful way of governance and control over particular things that require control and definite decisions, also because they are decentralizing.

The two ideas are perfectly compatible, and they both teach us we are better off distributing the responsibility and power over everything.

The most basic idea behind socialism is that the "means of production", the things people need to live, should be democratically controlled. This seems very reasonable. 

Private property for profit is exactly the same process as an authoritarian planned economy trying to consolidate more power towards itself. It's self-serving and inefficient. 

Why would it be any better than democratic control by representatives elected by the community, just because "its private property"? This is dogmatic. 

To me, this is a basic contradiction and a violation of the same pro-market principles used to justify it. 

All the motivations for innovation and efficiency are there in democratic control. 

Nothing changed except the notion of "profit", which in this broader scope plays the same role as "political power" in authoritarian regimes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30852797130.0" user="massive_schlong" delta="False">
    <text>Democracy depends on a well informed, well educated voter base that also needs to be a large majority of the total population.  This means that the only successful democracies must be small, which makes it very hard to have a manufacturing or industry based economy.  You may be right, but a free market democracy will quickly become inefficient through corruption or self-induced centralization.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
