<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="572887756.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9h2z0s/cmv_free_markets_vs_planned_economies_and/">
    <title>CMV: Free markets vs. planned economies and democracy vs. authoritarianism both teach us the lesson that centralization of power/control is inefficient and a bad idea. Therefore, the means of production should be democratically controlled and resource management should be done via market principles.</title>
    <original_poster>Horror_Policy</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm leaning towards market socialism lately.

On the one hand, we know that planned economies don't work. Markets seem superior in every way for resource management, because they are decentralizing. 

On the other hand, democracies teach us the same lesson. All the various types seem to have been more successful than monarchies or dictatorships.

So democracy seems to be the most effective and successful way of governance and control over particular things that require control and definite decisions, also because they are decentralizing.

The two ideas are perfectly compatible, and they both teach us we are better off distributing the responsibility and power over everything.

The most basic idea behind socialism is that the "means of production", the things people need to live, should be democratically controlled. This seems very reasonable. 

Private property for profit is exactly the same process as an authoritarian planned economy trying to consolidate more power towards itself. It's self-serving and inefficient. 

Why would it be any better than democratic control by representatives elected by the community, just because "its private property"? This is dogmatic. 

To me, this is a basic contradiction and a violation of the same pro-market principles used to justify it. 

All the motivations for innovation and efficiency are there in democratic control. 

Nothing changed except the notion of "profit", which in this broader scope plays the same role as "political power" in authoritarian regimes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30852822568.0" user="Nicolasv2" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; On the one hand, we know that planned economies don't work

Detail, but we know that nation-wide planned economies never worked till now. Nothing can be told about nation-wide planned economy managed by IA for example, and small scale planned economy work pretty well.

&amp;gt; Markets seem superior in every way for resource management, because they are decentralizing.

You seem to imply a correlation between decentralization and superiority where there could be none. Markets could be superior because historically, centralizers did not have enough data input to take correct decisions, and not because of the inherent superiority of decentralization. 

&amp;gt; On the other hand, democracies teach us the same lesson. All the various types seem to have been more successful than monarchies or dictatorships.

Not that much in fact. Athenes felt, after french revolution there was multiple wars that put back emerors and kings to the throne, etc. 

Only recent western countries seems to be managing to work well, and they can't be described as democracies either. After all, they are representative systems, and as such they are elective aristocracies, with sometimes some democratic elements (such as public votations , referendums). Eventually, you can say that meritocratic systems with limited power position duration are more resilient that lifelong power owning.

Again, what we could deduce that distribution of power is the key, but we could also say that the key is just to have the right data to take the appropriate decision, and that historically, you could not get that in a autocratic system as a lone person (or a small group of people) are unable to ingest that much data to manage a country. But it could work quite well on smaller scales (look at a partiarch in the old times managing his family well for example), and with newest information technologies, the quantity of information that can be treated simultaneously from the same spot is rising, so the drawback of centralization (lack of computation power) is decreasing. 

&amp;gt; Therefore, the means of production should be democratically controlled and resource management should be done via market principles.

Therefore, as we saw, centralization work well in small environments, and is limited by a lack of capacity to treat too much information when the group is growing. 

For small companies, centralisation is then perfectly efficient. And for bigger ones, as long as their top management have access to enough data, and to algorithms that can compute all these efficiently, there is no reason why democratic control would be more efficient than autocratic one. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
