<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="577631717.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9jwnhh/cmv_in_the_show_the_good_place_the_presence_of/">
    <title>CMV: In the show "The Good Place", the presence of both Tahani and Chidi contradict the rules presented of who ends up there</title>
    <original_poster>SirApatosaurus</original_poster>
    <original_post>#Spoilers for The Good Place season 1. 

----

In The Good Place, Chidi is shown to have deserved to end up in the "Good" place because whilst he tried to live a good life and do what he thought was right, he was indecisive to the point where it caused harm to his friends and family.  

Tahani lived a life of charity and tried all that she could to help others, however it is revealed that this was overruled by the fact that she did so for selfish reasons. 

Chidi's judgement was based on the notion that how he affected those around him mattered more than his intentions. He never meant to hurt anyone and tried to do what he thought was right, but simply failed to do so in practice. 

Tahani's judgement was based in the notion that her intentions mattered more than what she did. 

The two of them are in direct contrast to each other. One did immense good but for the wrong reasons, and one did harm but unintentionally whilst trying to do what he thought was right.   
If Chidi belongs in the "Good" place then the impact of one's actions matter more than a person's intentions. If Tahani belongs in the "Good" place then the intentions of a person matter more than what they do. 

So CMV, Tahani and Chidi do not both belong in the "Good" place, only one of them does by the rules proposed in the show. 

Edit - people have already made points on the following topics and I will not award deltas for them: 

* The high bar proposed in the brief presentation on how the system works, requiring people to be close to perfect
* We don't know if we can trust anything in the presentation as it could have been a lie by Michael


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30889830125.0" user="catladyxoxo" delta="False">
    <text>Is Chidi acting out of an impulse to help others or out of an impulse to do what is right, according to moral philosophy? I think that Chidi’s motives are to follow the correct set of principles as rigidly as possible, and his indecisiveness comes from the ways that certain moral philosophies contradict one another. In this sense, I don’t think his intentions are entirely pure in the same way that Tahani’s are totally corrupt. He asks “What do we owe to one another?” but he practices a kind of telescopic morality (as with Mrs Jellyby of Bleak House). Mrs Jellyby is a character who constantly makes pamphlets for helping people in Africa but ignores the poverty that surrounds her. Chidi is similar in that he cares more about the way his actions affect blueberry farmers than those closest to him and consistently ends up hurting those people.

This is all to say 1) I don’t see his intentions as wholly pure because he is more invested in not doing the wrong thing than in helping others and 2) he can’t get points for ethically pure actions he doesn’t take. Do we ever see him doing anything that would get him positive points while alive? The show seems to suggest that you can’t learn how ACT with moral virtue from books alone, and it’s worth noting that only Eleanor actually passed the Judge’s test at the end of season 2.

I was always bothered more by Jason being in the Bad Place, as unlike Eleanor and the others, he doesn’t seem to be as capable of virtuous actions. Like, all stupid people are automatically damned for eternity?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
