<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="577631717.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9jwnhh/cmv_in_the_show_the_good_place_the_presence_of/">
    <title>CMV: In the show "The Good Place", the presence of both Tahani and Chidi contradict the rules presented of who ends up there</title>
    <original_poster>SirApatosaurus</original_poster>
    <original_post>#Spoilers for The Good Place season 1. 

----

In The Good Place, Chidi is shown to have deserved to end up in the "Good" place because whilst he tried to live a good life and do what he thought was right, he was indecisive to the point where it caused harm to his friends and family.  

Tahani lived a life of charity and tried all that she could to help others, however it is revealed that this was overruled by the fact that she did so for selfish reasons. 

Chidi's judgement was based on the notion that how he affected those around him mattered more than his intentions. He never meant to hurt anyone and tried to do what he thought was right, but simply failed to do so in practice. 

Tahani's judgement was based in the notion that her intentions mattered more than what she did. 

The two of them are in direct contrast to each other. One did immense good but for the wrong reasons, and one did harm but unintentionally whilst trying to do what he thought was right.   
If Chidi belongs in the "Good" place then the impact of one's actions matter more than a person's intentions. If Tahani belongs in the "Good" place then the intentions of a person matter more than what they do. 

So CMV, Tahani and Chidi do not both belong in the "Good" place, only one of them does by the rules proposed in the show. 

Edit - people have already made points on the following topics and I will not award deltas for them: 

* The high bar proposed in the brief presentation on how the system works, requiring people to be close to perfect
* We don't know if we can trust anything in the presentation as it could have been a lie by Michael


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30889329069.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>You would have a point except Chidi knows his being good tortures people.  He is selfishly obsessed with doing the right thing.  He's like the pharasies (sp?) Described in the bible, going around doing moral things all the time but ultimately immoral because they do it for show.  He isn't honest with his boots friend to be honest with him or have a friendship with him, he's honest with him to make a show of being honest.  He ultimately doesn't care about others and that negates all his study of ethics. He's knowable, he goes through the motions, but he missed the purpose. And that's what got him sent to the bad place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889375249.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>It's been a while since I watched season one, but that's not how I remember him?  
Yes he had an unhealthy obsession with trying to do the right thing, but I don't remember him ever doing so so he could feel or seem superior to others.  

He was just trying his best to do what was right. Do you remember any clips/scenes that support your argument?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889416982.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>You don't have to do it to feel superior to others. The point was that he didn't care about them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889494915.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>But if he didn't do it to feel superior (or a similar insincere reason), he still intended to do good, but just failed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889559960.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>See he didn't intend to to good, Not really.  He knew what he did was torture to every one else. And he continued to do it.  So all the 'moral' things he did weren't moral.   

His entire character is to point out that when you do the 'right' thing without considering how it actually affects people it can have the exact opposite effect. Hence the phrase "the road to hell is paved with good intentions."  To get to heaven you need to both do good and have good intentions.

Chidi, even if you give him the good intentions, still knowingly tortured people. He rationalized it through morality and ended up doing the exact opposite of what he should have done. He didn't do good. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889688890.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>I believe he did intend to do good, and he did try to be a good person. Being aware of the fact that he sometimes does harm does not mean that he's a bad person, he just is crippled by indecisiveness.  

I won't say what specifically in case you haven't yet started season 3, but there's a moment where him and only him is the victim of his inaction and he is directly faced with it, but he doesn't initially resolve to be more decisive even though it was only him who would have suffered.  
And then later in the episode he tries to be more decisive but faces consequences and hurts people and he struggles with that. 

He tried to do good and had good intentions, but just failed to properly execute. In a system that measures based on intentions, he wouldn't necessarily be a bad person. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889745422.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>When you know you have a failing and don't correct it Your doing bad.  He had a glaringly obvious weakness he knew about. When he didn't fix it and continued to torture others he did bad.  No amount of good intentions can override that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30890056026.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>In a system that is based heavily on intentions it could. His intentions were good, so even if he messed it up it could have been ok depending on how judgement was determined. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30890637594.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>Bad intentions can negate good deeds as it did for tahani.  But good intentions don't negate bad deeds.  And he has  a plethora of those.   Most from trying to be ethical. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
