<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="577631717.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9jwnhh/cmv_in_the_show_the_good_place_the_presence_of/">
    <title>CMV: In the show "The Good Place", the presence of both Tahani and Chidi contradict the rules presented of who ends up there</title>
    <original_poster>SirApatosaurus</original_poster>
    <original_post>#Spoilers for The Good Place season 1. 

----

In The Good Place, Chidi is shown to have deserved to end up in the "Good" place because whilst he tried to live a good life and do what he thought was right, he was indecisive to the point where it caused harm to his friends and family.  

Tahani lived a life of charity and tried all that she could to help others, however it is revealed that this was overruled by the fact that she did so for selfish reasons. 

Chidi's judgement was based on the notion that how he affected those around him mattered more than his intentions. He never meant to hurt anyone and tried to do what he thought was right, but simply failed to do so in practice. 

Tahani's judgement was based in the notion that her intentions mattered more than what she did. 

The two of them are in direct contrast to each other. One did immense good but for the wrong reasons, and one did harm but unintentionally whilst trying to do what he thought was right.   
If Chidi belongs in the "Good" place then the impact of one's actions matter more than a person's intentions. If Tahani belongs in the "Good" place then the intentions of a person matter more than what they do. 

So CMV, Tahani and Chidi do not both belong in the "Good" place, only one of them does by the rules proposed in the show. 

Edit - people have already made points on the following topics and I will not award deltas for them: 

* The high bar proposed in the brief presentation on how the system works, requiring people to be close to perfect
* We don't know if we can trust anything in the presentation as it could have been a lie by Michael


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30889277401.0" user="LondonDude123" delta="False">
    <text>Thats... Actually a really good point...

However as we later learn, the 4 were put there to torture each other. Tahani was ultimately there to be *better* than Eleanor, and Chidi to pretty much bore Eleanor to death (pun intended).

Other than "Thats what Michael planned", I dunno what to tell you bud...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889289865.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>Even though they were chosen to torture each other, they'd have to first be eligible for the bad place so that they could be selected.  
They should not both have been eligible in the first place, based on the rules presented in the show. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889494877.0" user="SJHillman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; based on the rules presented in the show

Given where they are, and the people who work there who tell the characters (and by extension the viewers) what the rules are, why should be believe that they're being honest about the rules in the first place? Especially considering that the entire premise until you get to the twist is based on lies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889510525.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>True, but unfortunately someone else has made this point and I awarded them a delta, but before you made this post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889644033.0" user="That_Deus_Ex_Girl" delta="False">
    <text>In the second season, we see evidence (through his discussions with other Bad Placers as well as what he says after he gives up lying to them) that Michael was honest about a surprising amount, including things that didn't help his plan or that the gang couldn't have figured out in any normal way, for instance:  


* Although he is not a good place architect, he expects failure to be punished with "retirement," which is exactly what he describes it as
* They do, in fact, seem to use an act-based point system to judge people
* Janet is in fact a totally functional, normal and helpful Good Place Janet, as presented (although he didn't mention she was stolen for obvious reasons)

When they ask him why he told the truth about any of this stuff, he suggests that he thought it was a stronger lie to base most of what he says on the truth (i.e. that he should only lie about where they are, not about the system in general).  


People in the Bad Place HQ, as well as the neutral Judge, who have no reason to lie, paint a very similar picture of the afterlife to the one Michael presents early on. If the museum exhibits are to be trusted, which also seems reasonable given that they're by and for Bad Placers, people can end up in the Bad Place for all kinds of petty reasons.  
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
