<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="577631717.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9jwnhh/cmv_in_the_show_the_good_place_the_presence_of/">
    <title>CMV: In the show "The Good Place", the presence of both Tahani and Chidi contradict the rules presented of who ends up there</title>
    <original_poster>SirApatosaurus</original_poster>
    <original_post>#Spoilers for The Good Place season 1. 

----

In The Good Place, Chidi is shown to have deserved to end up in the "Good" place because whilst he tried to live a good life and do what he thought was right, he was indecisive to the point where it caused harm to his friends and family.  

Tahani lived a life of charity and tried all that she could to help others, however it is revealed that this was overruled by the fact that she did so for selfish reasons. 

Chidi's judgement was based on the notion that how he affected those around him mattered more than his intentions. He never meant to hurt anyone and tried to do what he thought was right, but simply failed to do so in practice. 

Tahani's judgement was based in the notion that her intentions mattered more than what she did. 

The two of them are in direct contrast to each other. One did immense good but for the wrong reasons, and one did harm but unintentionally whilst trying to do what he thought was right.   
If Chidi belongs in the "Good" place then the impact of one's actions matter more than a person's intentions. If Tahani belongs in the "Good" place then the intentions of a person matter more than what they do. 

So CMV, Tahani and Chidi do not both belong in the "Good" place, only one of them does by the rules proposed in the show. 

Edit - people have already made points on the following topics and I will not award deltas for them: 

* The high bar proposed in the brief presentation on how the system works, requiring people to be close to perfect
* We don't know if we can trust anything in the presentation as it could have been a lie by Michael


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30889362705.0" user="ZeusSaidNo" delta="False">
    <text>Chidi's there for the same reason Eleanor is.  Being indifferently selfish.

Eleanor clearly didn't care how her actions hurt others.   She didn't intentionally damage the dress, and while she sold shirts it was for money, not to inflict pain upon her friend.  She littered because she didn't care, etc, etc. None of it was primarily to damage others, it was just the easiest path for her.

Same with Chidi.  Making a decision was extremely painful for him.  His was more comfortable in his indecisiveness even though he was certainly intelligent enough to see from an objective viewpoint it was damaging to everyone around him.  And damaging to his friendships as well (I don't recall if his friend was going to remove him from the wedding after the trial failure).  He has the capacity to do good if he could just decide on a path. 

Either one knew they could change their actions to make their lives and the lives of others better, each failed to take action.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889457252.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>But Chidi still tried to act morally and do what he thought was right, it's just that his personal limitations interfered with his ability to do so.  
He wasn't an inherently bad person, unless the standard by which the good/bad place judges is based on the effect one has, regardless of the intent behind it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30890613167.0" user="gyroda" delta="False">
    <text>Was he trying to do what was right, or was he insisting on justifying every action within various sets of principles in order to cover up/justify his own indecisiveness? Was he really interested in doing the most good, or was he scared of having to take responsibility for making a decision? It seems to me that more than anything he tried to find a sure way to evaluate his choices because he didn't want to actually make decisions himself, even if he knew what the correct choice was all along.

I've done this to an extent in my life; I can be indecisive at times and it has screwed me over in the past. I don't want to commit either way and then I'm left with neither choice because I left it too long. Chidi does this to the extent that it has a huge negative impact on everyone else around him.

Tl;Dr: Chidi isn't interested in doing the most good so much as he's scared of making decisions and the possibility of mistakes. He wants the decision making process taken out of his hands by a philosophical framework. He'd rather not take action in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
