<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="585198385.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9oetyp/cmv_all_drugs_should_be_legalized_xpost_from/">
    <title>CMV: ALL drugs should be legalized. (x-post from r/unpopularopinion)</title>
    <original_poster>conjo434</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm opened to changing my mind about drugs that can make people hurt other people (i.e. Amphetamines, PCP). But apart of these, ALL drugs (including heroin, cocaine, LSD, etc.) should be 100% legal to buy and use, and with strong regulation on production and sell (i.e. the government can choose to not give out licences to produce and/or sell specific drugs, but is refrained from prosecuting users in anyway, unless they harmed someone else).

Two main reasons for my opinion on the matter:

1. Humans should have complete freedom in regards to THEIR OWN body. If someone wants to use any substance, it's their right, and their responsibility if they fuck their lives in the process. It's a basic principal for me. "But hey, we as a society will have to bear the costs of those dangerous choices!" - well, yeah, same as we have to do it for people who chose to do extreme sports, and nobody suggests to prohibit those. We should put emphasis on education (and open up to using drugs as a way to improve mental health/self-understanding/self-exploration/etc.)
2. It doesn't matter how much drugs are illegal, one constant in human psychology is that a lot of us WILL TRY TO MESS WITH OUR STATE OF CONSCIOUSNESS. It's so deeply rotted in us, that there are strong evidences (to my understanding) that agriculture started together with the production of alcoholic beverages. PEOPLE LIKE GETTING HIGH, and they will keep on doing that - if it's ain't legal, they will do it illegally. And without (at least somewhat) taxed and regulated products - these things are prone to be low quality with all sort of shit in them, and enrich criminals while endangering the safety of many more people. It is just unavoidable - there are simply two options and two options alone: either people take drugs legally, or people take drugs illegally. Never will the "problem" disappear just because you can get punished for that. Never will people stop getting in different states of consciousness.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30947835531.0" user="GreenKnightGawain" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument against the social defense of drug prohibition isn't very convincing. All you've really said is that there are multiple kinds of behavior damaging to society. That some are legal and some are not shouldn't have any bearing on what we ought to do - at the very least, this is far from evident.


Ultimately, if the legalization of all drugs would harm society (which you seem to tacitly admit), why in the world would it make sense to do so? What is your justification for this morality of individual freedom you express?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30947921333.0" user="conjo434" delta="False">
    <text>Simply because I believe one has the right to their own body. You should be able to pump as many harmful chemicals into yourself so long as you give consent to it. I'm not saying it wouldn't be harmful, I'm saying that you should be fully responsible for any harm that you cause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948071979.0" user="GreenKnightGawain" delta="False">
    <text>This potentially sounds good, but it's not how it works in reality. If a person without car insurance causes a major accident, there're not going to be able to 'take reasonability' without being independently wealthy. If a drug addict kills himself with drugs, he's not going to be able to 'take reasonability' for anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948008808.0" user="EwokPiss" delta="False">
    <text>Fast food seems to be quite detrimental to our current society. As that is a societal harm, should we not make that illegal?

If we start in a state of nature (i.e. free from all rules), but, by choosing to create a society, accept to be bound by some rules, then shouldn't the onus be on those who take a freedom away to show that it ought to be taken away rather than the opposite (i.e. the government has complete control but chooses to give us some freedoms for particular reason)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948114672.0" user="GreenKnightGawain" delta="False">
    <text>I would have little issue with, at the very least, heavily regulating fast food to the point that it doesn't look anything like it does now. It's pretty insane in my country.

And I think that only works if you make the presupposition that freedom is somehow a more desirable state than the opposite in a general sense. That man supposedly begins in a state of freedom isn't a great concern of mine. It's also not at all clear we start in a state without rules - that's another presupposition. There could very well be metaphysical ethical/moral rules imposed upon us without society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948167928.0" user="EwokPiss" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the the thoughtful response.
It is interesting that you would regulate fast food, but I think you run the risk of heading down a slippery slope (a fallacy on my part, but I think, ultimately, a legitimate argument). Do you regulate salt intake, then, as well? That is also detrimental in the quantities that many people consume it. With all of these rules, aren't we getting closer and closer to oppression and totalitarianism? 
As for my argument regarding freedom, you might be right to point out that it isn't an inherent good. I would argue that it is inherently good, but to take up the argument anyway, I would argue from the opposite. A government deciding everything on everyone's behalf is bad because it stifles innovation and subjective satisfaction. The opposite of a totalitarian regime would be anarchy (state of nature, perfect freedom) which isn't necessarily desirable on it's own either, but I think better as innovation still progresses (satisfaction perhaps not). Thus, we should err toward perfect freedom unless given a specific argument against a specific action. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948478991.0" user="GreenKnightGawain" delta="False">
    <text>I think there is a distinction between something like fast food / drugs (specifically in the context of drug abuse) and something like salt. The former are not necessary at all, and are often very negative. Sure, there are some relatively healthy fast food choices, and certainly some drugs are far more dangerous and detrimental to physical/mental health than others, but generally speaking these things probably hurt society a lot more than they help it. Salt is actually needed to survive, and the issue of taking in too much salt is really subject to broader health concerns. If a person has a healthy lifestyle, they aren't going have health issues related to consuming too much salt, and thus it is really way too specific of a concern. The government should do its best to promote general healthiness, and I do think that would include things like regulating the fast food industry far more than it already does, at least in my country.

I agree that totalitarianism is a concern. However, I think that there are many areas the government could do more in. The government shouldn't exist as a barrier between a citizen and freedom, but rather it should exist as a vehicle to facilitate the maximum amount of flourishing (meaning the maximum amount of greatness a citizen can achieve, essentially) for each individual citizen, and thus society as a whole. On the other hand, I do think freedom is also important, but allowing citizens to effectively poison themselves is not very high on the list of freedoms I think people should have. And thanks for your thoughtful response as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
