<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="585198385.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9oetyp/cmv_all_drugs_should_be_legalized_xpost_from/">
    <title>CMV: ALL drugs should be legalized. (x-post from r/unpopularopinion)</title>
    <original_poster>conjo434</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm opened to changing my mind about drugs that can make people hurt other people (i.e. Amphetamines, PCP). But apart of these, ALL drugs (including heroin, cocaine, LSD, etc.) should be 100% legal to buy and use, and with strong regulation on production and sell (i.e. the government can choose to not give out licences to produce and/or sell specific drugs, but is refrained from prosecuting users in anyway, unless they harmed someone else).

Two main reasons for my opinion on the matter:

1. Humans should have complete freedom in regards to THEIR OWN body. If someone wants to use any substance, it's their right, and their responsibility if they fuck their lives in the process. It's a basic principal for me. "But hey, we as a society will have to bear the costs of those dangerous choices!" - well, yeah, same as we have to do it for people who chose to do extreme sports, and nobody suggests to prohibit those. We should put emphasis on education (and open up to using drugs as a way to improve mental health/self-understanding/self-exploration/etc.)
2. It doesn't matter how much drugs are illegal, one constant in human psychology is that a lot of us WILL TRY TO MESS WITH OUR STATE OF CONSCIOUSNESS. It's so deeply rotted in us, that there are strong evidences (to my understanding) that agriculture started together with the production of alcoholic beverages. PEOPLE LIKE GETTING HIGH, and they will keep on doing that - if it's ain't legal, they will do it illegally. And without (at least somewhat) taxed and regulated products - these things are prone to be low quality with all sort of shit in them, and enrich criminals while endangering the safety of many more people. It is just unavoidable - there are simply two options and two options alone: either people take drugs legally, or people take drugs illegally. Never will the "problem" disappear just because you can get punished for that. Never will people stop getting in different states of consciousness.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30948162266.0" user="GuyLJr" delta="False">
    <text>First let's make a distinction.  It is not a crime to ingest any of these substances, sometimes it may be a condition of parole, but you cannot be charged with a crime simply for failing a drug test and therefore your OWN body argument is not legitimate to me.  It is the production, distribution, sale, and possession of these drugs that is illegal.

Second, let's suppose drugs are legalized (for the sake of argument only those drugs commonly used for recreation).  How do you suppose any industry markets and sells heroin without extreme liability concerns?  The largest contributing factor between over the counter medications and prescription are the likelihood of abuse and the risks of overdose.   

 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30950559282.0" user="tuseroni" delta="False">
    <text>i don't think that's a distinction that matters. "you can use it, you just can't possess it" 

this is splitting hairs to such an extent you risk causing a nuclear reaction.

if the possession is explicitly illegal, the use is de facto illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30951723533.0" user="GuyLJr" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it is a clear distinction when using the "control over my body" argument.  What if I wanted to put enriched, weapon grade uranium in my body (this would be legal as far as I know)?  Does that mean I should automatically have the right to possess it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30953457673.0" user="tuseroni" delta="False">
    <text>it's still NOT a distinction, it is all the same illegal for you to put weapons grade uranium in your body because it is illegal for you to possess or acquire weapons grade uranium in order to do so.

in other words, if you can't have it, you can't use it. so yes, if you have the right to put something in your body you must also have the right to acquire and possess that thing. one implies the other.

also i don't think you should have the right to put weapons grade uranium in your body...that would make you a health hazard to anyone in the area who will be getting lethal doses of radiation, also to the coroner, will also be a lot harder to dispose of your body...

i suppose if you can show that you can safely put the uranium in your body, that it's inside of some kind of containment unit that doesn't leak radiation and there are protocols in place for handling the uranium containing unit upon your demise. (maybe you have a really extreme pacemaker or something. could be a very small amount of the stuff, an RTG powered by weapons grade uranium would probably produce a good amount of power, and people HAVE used radioactive elements and an RTG in pacemakers before...fun fact: those pacemakers were made in the 50's i think and are still running)

but if possessions of something is illegal, its use is de facto illegal. you can't use something without possessing it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30953754444.0" user="GuyLJr" delta="False">
    <text>But the distinction is in the WHY you cannot use it.  The own body argument states that no one can tell me what I can and cannot put into my body, not that I have the right to possess everything that may be ingest-able.  The laws against possession are rooted in other factors.  Look at the history of supplements at GNC with diuretics like Meridia and Ephedra.  It became illegal to sell these substances because they kill people at unacceptable rates (what is unacceptable is subjective).  Opiates, amphetamines, cocaine and derivatives, and other drugs all have serious side effects.  So I guess if you are willing to make the argument that the entire FDA should be abolished then we can have a conversation about that.  But you can't pick and choose what drugs the FDA gets oversight over because those are the ones you think should be legal for your own biased reasons.  What about steroids, methotrexate, Warfarin, Prozac, Lithium, Insulin.  What if the regulations for selling these things go away?  The market will be flooded with dangerous magic pills.  The precedent has far reaching consequences.

Another example of the distinction between possessing and ingesting is the long stood prohibition against cuban cigars.  These were banned, not for health reasons (although that argument is a good one), but for economic and foreign policy reasons.  There are many reasons to prohibit the sales of certain items.  And the only way to effectively prevent selling them is to also prohibit possession of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30953838485.0" user="tuseroni" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Look at the history of supplements at GNC with diuretics like Meridia and Ephedra. It became illegal to sell these substances because they kill people at unacceptable rates 

kinda making my point here, the SALE and POSSESSION were illegal to prevent the USE or CONSUMPTION of the thing. 

that is, that banning the possession is de facto banning the use.

that's actually my only point from the start...you were arguing with someone else before that..my point is and has always been "banning the possession is banning the use, and it's not a useful distinction to say it's banning the possession only"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30953877417.0" user="GuyLJr" delta="False">
    <text>But it is still not illegal to consume any of these things, that is an indisputable fact, and so when you say " If someone wants to use any substance, it's their right, and their responsibility if they fuck their lives in the process.", as the original post said then your argument is flawed from the start because that right already exists.  The argument is really, "they should be able to purchase it legally somehow".  That distinction needs to be made because the arguments about why we can't just allow anyone to sell any drug they want are self-evident (to me at least) when you look at the big picture of pharmaceuticals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30954048430.0" user="tuseroni" delta="False">
    <text>not even purchase, you can't legally grow or create your own. you are not allowed to POSSESS it, which means you are not allowed to consume it.

as i said, just because it isn't EXPLICITLY illegal, doesn't mean it isn't DE FACTO illegal. the consumption of, say, marijuana, is illegal because the possession of marijuana is illegal. one implies the other.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
