<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="585198385.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9oetyp/cmv_all_drugs_should_be_legalized_xpost_from/">
    <title>CMV: ALL drugs should be legalized. (x-post from r/unpopularopinion)</title>
    <original_poster>conjo434</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm opened to changing my mind about drugs that can make people hurt other people (i.e. Amphetamines, PCP). But apart of these, ALL drugs (including heroin, cocaine, LSD, etc.) should be 100% legal to buy and use, and with strong regulation on production and sell (i.e. the government can choose to not give out licences to produce and/or sell specific drugs, but is refrained from prosecuting users in anyway, unless they harmed someone else).

Two main reasons for my opinion on the matter:

1. Humans should have complete freedom in regards to THEIR OWN body. If someone wants to use any substance, it's their right, and their responsibility if they fuck their lives in the process. It's a basic principal for me. "But hey, we as a society will have to bear the costs of those dangerous choices!" - well, yeah, same as we have to do it for people who chose to do extreme sports, and nobody suggests to prohibit those. We should put emphasis on education (and open up to using drugs as a way to improve mental health/self-understanding/self-exploration/etc.)
2. It doesn't matter how much drugs are illegal, one constant in human psychology is that a lot of us WILL TRY TO MESS WITH OUR STATE OF CONSCIOUSNESS. It's so deeply rotted in us, that there are strong evidences (to my understanding) that agriculture started together with the production of alcoholic beverages. PEOPLE LIKE GETTING HIGH, and they will keep on doing that - if it's ain't legal, they will do it illegally. And without (at least somewhat) taxed and regulated products - these things are prone to be low quality with all sort of shit in them, and enrich criminals while endangering the safety of many more people. It is just unavoidable - there are simply two options and two options alone: either people take drugs legally, or people take drugs illegally. Never will the "problem" disappear just because you can get punished for that. Never will people stop getting in different states of consciousness.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30947758580.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>Medical forms of Amphetamines, cocaine, heroine, and several other street drugs are already available by prescription (Vyvanse/Adderall, lidocaine, and other opioids respectively).  They are technically already "legal" they just require a prescription because insurance doesn't want to pay for them if you are just going to get high off them, and doctors generally don't want to prescribe them to somebody for that reason.  

&amp;gt;PEOPLE LIKE GETTING HIGH, and they will keep on doing that - if it's ain't legal, they will do it illegally

People also commit murder despite it being both illegal and quite taboo.  Should we just not bother making murder illegal?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30947784580.0" user="conjo434" delta="False">
    <text>I'm moreso talking about drugs being legalized recreationally, and murdering *another person* is very different to using drugs that can only impact *yourself*, as long as you keep it in moderation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30947892691.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;murdering another person is very different to using drugs that can only impact yourself, as long as you keep it in moderation

I agree with this in principle, but in practice it's a different story.  While I definitely think we need massive reforms on how we treat people who use drugs regardless of legality, I don't think all drugs should be freely recreationally available.  This is because in practice certain kinds of illicit drugs are so addictive as to seriously incapacitate the free will of those who use them.  

I know that this kind of thinking is a bit of a slippery slope, but I am hard pressed to find any redeeming value in legalizing crystal meth (for example) given the extreme measures people will go through to obtain it, the damage it can do to people's bodies as well as their psyche, the often incredibly dangerous brewing process, and the obvious alteration in mental states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948032437.0" user="gigafood" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree that there is no benefit to more people doing meth, I don't agree that that translates to there being no benefit to legalizing meth. Looking at Portugal's decriminalization of all drugs in 2001, it can be seen that drug related deaths and drug related crime have both gone down, and many of the adverse health effects of long term drug use have gone down as well. Admittedly, this is only looking at decriminalization, not at legalization. The key difference there is that it is not legal to sell drugs, only to buy(effectively), have, or use them. The primary reason that legalization is promoted over decriminalization, therefor, has nothing to do with the user and everything to do with the supplier. Making it legal eradicates a MASSIVE source of revenue for gang activity, which is a source of many crimes. Additionally, allowing the state to tax the sale of these drugs provides a massive reduction in untaxed revenue, and allows high taxes on drugs to be put towards rehabilitation. 

The bottom line is that no one wants more meth users, but that's not what legalization has been shown to result in. There's a reason that plenty of people break the law to smoke weed, and much fewer do so to smoke meth. For the vast majority of people, they don't avoid meth because it's illegal, but because it's, well, meth. What legalization does do, however, is make the people that do meth more safe, provide them more and less-stigmatized methods of rehabilitation, provide income to the state, and reduce gang activity in the area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948098886.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>Again, I agree we need to do a much better job with how we treat addiction and addicts.  I definitely think decriminalization is an option for drug use, though maybe not drug dealing for certain drugs.  

I'm all for safer and less stigmatized methods of rehabilitation.  I'm all for harm reduction.  But I don't think certain substances should be fully and freely legal because their potential for harm is too great.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948147726.0" user="gigafood" delta="False">
    <text>Keep in mind that when I say legalisation in terms of selling, I don't mean that selling drugs on the streets would be legal. Much like alcohol currently, these drugs would be distributed in ways allowed by a state, and selling outside of those bounds would still be illegal.

You say that you are okay with decriminalization, but that is effectively the same as what I am proposing, except that the source would be from regulated(read: as safe as they can be), state-sponsored sources, rather than drug dealers. Within decriminalization, it is effectively legal to buy, because while the trade itself is still illegal, you as a consumer cannot get in trouble for buying. The only differences is how regulated the production is, and who the profits are going to.

ninja-edit: note that I recognize that this policy is not a realistic one to apply directly in our current political climate, and would need to be rolled out as a series of progressive policies over time. This is a purely hypothetical discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948149918.0" user="gigafood" delta="False">
    <text>Keep in mind that when I say legalisation in terms of selling, I don't mean that selling drugs on the streets would be legal. Much like alcohol currently, these drugs would be distributed in ways allowed by a state, and selling outside of those bounds would still be illegal.

You say that you are okay with decriminalization, but that is effectively the same as what I am proposing, except that the source would be from regulated(read: as safe as they can be), state-sponsored sources, rather than drug dealers. Within decriminalization, it is effectively legal to buy, because while the trade itself is still illegal, you as a consumer cannot get in trouble for buying. The only differences is how regulated the production is, and who the profits are going to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948063276.0" user="EwokPiss" delta="False">
    <text>This seems to be setting up a spectrum in which some activities of the same kind are treated different due to degree. Thus, caffeine is legal because the effects are less harmful to the individual. Alcohol is regulated because the effect can be more harmful, but meth is right out because of the amount of harm. I think this is a good argument, regardless of my personal opinion that the OP is correct. However, like with all things on a spectrum, you have to come up with a rationality so that we can take each drug or activity in turn to determine where to draw the line of legality. Is it just the damage to the body (in which case sky diving might be illegal because death is very probable if it goes wrong) or is it also the probability along with the damage (thus if there is 100% probability to damage and that damage is severe enough, then it would be illegal). What probability would we need to get to that threshold of illegality? 

Again, I think this is a good argument to a certain extent, I think it opens up quite a large amount of questions, inconsistencies, and issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948082328.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;Again, I think this is a good argument to a certain extent, I think it opens up quite a large amount of questions, inconsistencies, and issues.

I agree.  It's definitely not the kind of thing that should be finalized by people on the internet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948169901.0" user="EwokPiss" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30947998217.0" user="EwokPiss" delta="False">
    <text>Murder is different because it infringes on other's rights. That is why murder is illegal and drinking alcohol (at least one of the arguments) is legal. 

Further, cocaine is still illegal even if you offer to pay for it out of pocket. I don't believe that the OP intended for the individual to be given the drugs, but would pay for them, just like they would with caffeine or alcohol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948102845.0" user="I_am_the_night" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Murder is different because it infringes on other's rights. That is why murder is illegal and drinking alcohol (at least one of the arguments) is legal. 

See my other response as to why I agree with this distinction in principle but not necessarily in practice.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
