<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="585198385.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9oetyp/cmv_all_drugs_should_be_legalized_xpost_from/">
    <title>CMV: ALL drugs should be legalized. (x-post from r/unpopularopinion)</title>
    <original_poster>conjo434</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm opened to changing my mind about drugs that can make people hurt other people (i.e. Amphetamines, PCP). But apart of these, ALL drugs (including heroin, cocaine, LSD, etc.) should be 100% legal to buy and use, and with strong regulation on production and sell (i.e. the government can choose to not give out licences to produce and/or sell specific drugs, but is refrained from prosecuting users in anyway, unless they harmed someone else).

Two main reasons for my opinion on the matter:

1. Humans should have complete freedom in regards to THEIR OWN body. If someone wants to use any substance, it's their right, and their responsibility if they fuck their lives in the process. It's a basic principal for me. "But hey, we as a society will have to bear the costs of those dangerous choices!" - well, yeah, same as we have to do it for people who chose to do extreme sports, and nobody suggests to prohibit those. We should put emphasis on education (and open up to using drugs as a way to improve mental health/self-understanding/self-exploration/etc.)
2. It doesn't matter how much drugs are illegal, one constant in human psychology is that a lot of us WILL TRY TO MESS WITH OUR STATE OF CONSCIOUSNESS. It's so deeply rotted in us, that there are strong evidences (to my understanding) that agriculture started together with the production of alcoholic beverages. PEOPLE LIKE GETTING HIGH, and they will keep on doing that - if it's ain't legal, they will do it illegally. And without (at least somewhat) taxed and regulated products - these things are prone to be low quality with all sort of shit in them, and enrich criminals while endangering the safety of many more people. It is just unavoidable - there are simply two options and two options alone: either people take drugs legally, or people take drugs illegally. Never will the "problem" disappear just because you can get punished for that. Never will people stop getting in different states of consciousness.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30947995884.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>No matter what drugs that are smoked will not just effect your body.  Meth fumes alone can be found in walls and air ducts years after smoking or production stops, we have found those same chemicals in children of users and producers.  The same thing applies for any drug that is aerosolized, it's inherent in act.  Given that now we have to legalize all drugs but not smoking them, which seems very hard to enforce and for some drugs leaves very little options outside injection, which can be very much worse than inhalation for thier bodies, and lead to more overdoses.  That or criminalize smoking around children, which again seems hard to enforce and goes against already existing precedent, in that smoking cigarettes around children is legal.  Also it opens up a whole moral quandry around highly addicitve drugs are a biological imperative and lower cognitive skills, so we would be punishing people who for all intents and purposes are following the laws, for side effects of those legal actions that they can't control due to thier mental impairment and need to take the drugs.  Now a simpler and more legally sound method would be to make all obviously dangerous drugs to people's bodies illegal, because even if they make the decision others can be effected.  It's similar to stuff like super deadly chemicals or radioactive stuff, people aren't allowed to just own those, they are regulated and not allowed to the general public so as to protect people from thier effects.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
