<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="585198385.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9oetyp/cmv_all_drugs_should_be_legalized_xpost_from/">
    <title>CMV: ALL drugs should be legalized. (x-post from r/unpopularopinion)</title>
    <original_poster>conjo434</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm opened to changing my mind about drugs that can make people hurt other people (i.e. Amphetamines, PCP). But apart of these, ALL drugs (including heroin, cocaine, LSD, etc.) should be 100% legal to buy and use, and with strong regulation on production and sell (i.e. the government can choose to not give out licences to produce and/or sell specific drugs, but is refrained from prosecuting users in anyway, unless they harmed someone else).

Two main reasons for my opinion on the matter:

1. Humans should have complete freedom in regards to THEIR OWN body. If someone wants to use any substance, it's their right, and their responsibility if they fuck their lives in the process. It's a basic principal for me. "But hey, we as a society will have to bear the costs of those dangerous choices!" - well, yeah, same as we have to do it for people who chose to do extreme sports, and nobody suggests to prohibit those. We should put emphasis on education (and open up to using drugs as a way to improve mental health/self-understanding/self-exploration/etc.)
2. It doesn't matter how much drugs are illegal, one constant in human psychology is that a lot of us WILL TRY TO MESS WITH OUR STATE OF CONSCIOUSNESS. It's so deeply rotted in us, that there are strong evidences (to my understanding) that agriculture started together with the production of alcoholic beverages. PEOPLE LIKE GETTING HIGH, and they will keep on doing that - if it's ain't legal, they will do it illegally. And without (at least somewhat) taxed and regulated products - these things are prone to be low quality with all sort of shit in them, and enrich criminals while endangering the safety of many more people. It is just unavoidable - there are simply two options and two options alone: either people take drugs legally, or people take drugs illegally. Never will the "problem" disappear just because you can get punished for that. Never will people stop getting in different states of consciousness.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30948421298.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30948489606.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/user_some – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+user_some&amp;amp;message=user_some+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9oetyp/-/e7tw2pe/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
