<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="590599984.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9rmlv4/cmv_if_i_found_out_that_i_was_on_the_truman_show/">
    <title>CMV: If I found out that I was on the Truman Show, my best course of action would be to ignore it.</title>
    <original_poster>CatchHere8</original_poster>
    <original_post>Obviously there are some downsides to living in the Truman Show. For this argument I will assume I am an adult, if I was still a young child I think leaving the Truman Show would be a better option.

My whole life is on display and I have absolutely no privacy. If I am already an adult, there's pretty much nothing for me to protect, people already know everything about me. At least in my illusion of a world, no one can really use anything I've done against me because it would quickly become obvious that I am being monitored. 

Another potential problem with this is that I am living in a fake world. I don't really think that matters. If I have grown up in this fake world, to me it is my real world and there is no advantage to leaving. Doing so and joining the "real world" would likely be traumatizing and I would never really integrate into society properly. I would probably have to go into hiding and significantly alter my appearance to stop people from stalking or harassing me.

I still have free will, it's not like I'm a robot that the director is controlling. Sure, he tells the actors what to do, but this doesn't affect my free will any more than normal people in the normal world interacting with me does. 

I'm also treated with extreme care on the show. I'll never be homeless or starve (sure the director could probably make that happen to spice things up, but I don't think they would risk my health like this for very long). I would be given the best healthcare, and honestly, if immortality was invented I expect I would be towards the top of the list to get it. If I do eventually die, it will probably be peacefully at an old age with my entire family by my side. 
 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30989088699.0" user="joemiller02" delta="False">
    <text>You would totally ruin the ending to that movie though</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
