<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001745941.0" user="Arahad2" delta="False">
    <text>We do treat is as a mental disorder, and the preacribed solution is transitioning into the gender they identify with. It has a huge success rate and leads to the long lasting happiness of both the individual in question and the people around them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001761630.0" user="0991906006091990" delta="False">
    <text>But studies I've read state this is joy true and results in many cases where the transitioning individual regrets it. Especially in M-T-F.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001772374.0" user="Arahad2" delta="False">
    <text>I'd be interested in seeing those studies. My information comes from being roommates with a mental health care provider for four years, so while it's a knowledgeable statement, it comes from someone in the weeds, not the metadata.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
