<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001762594.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. 

Because it works.

&amp;gt;  Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help

We don't do this because it doesn't work.

&amp;gt; Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way.

Schizophrenia doesn't have any good medical *or* psychological strategy that works well, however the medical strategy works better than the psychological approach, so medications are used. Unfortunately they have rather unpleasant side-effects, but they at least keep people on the near side of being able to manage their own lives.

Depression has both medical and psychological strategies that work and help, and in terms of evidence base there's not a lot going between the two. Antidepressant medications in general have an effect, but this effect is only marginally better than placebo. Psychological strategies work too and have a good evidence base.

Neither medication nor psychological strategies work in gender dysphoria and fail to provide a relief of symptoms. Refusing treatment in transgender people also results in high rates of psychological distress and suicide. This is even higher than in depression or psychosis.

Allowing someone to express their gender identity, including in providing cross-gender hormones, overall reduces distress. This is why it's done, because it works while other strategies don't.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
