<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001742551.0" user="DeleteriousEuphuism" delta="False">
    <text>One current treatment for gender dysphoria (which is a mental ailment afflicting some transgender people, not a synonym) is hormone therapy. I assume this is what you mean by chemical imbalance treatment? Otherwise I have no idea what you're proposing.

Edit: bad wording.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001757865.0" user="0991906006091990" delta="False">
    <text>Hormone therapy is usually there to assist in transition though, not to "correct" their gender.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001766253.0" user="DeleteriousEuphuism" delta="False">
    <text>Transitioning is how you treat gender dysphoria. The correct gender is whichever helps them function well internally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011773423.0" user="Cham-Clowder" delta="False">
    <text>There’s a lot of evidence HRT is the most important thing to alleviating trans people’s issues. Like trans brains are able to finally “wake up” so to speak once they go on the correct hormone.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
