<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31003012912.0" user="fatarella" delta="False">
    <text>Why do people care if another person is gender expansive? It does not affect your life at all. No one is forcing you to alter your gender - there are no roving gangs of transgender folk forcing you to change your behavior at all.

At the most, we ask that you call us by our preferred pronouns, but there is no penalty should you not wish to do that. Well, we would also be pleased if you didn't vilify us, or fail to hire us for a job we are qualified for.  Or beat us up, that would be nice too.

What I am saying is there is no cost to you for my transgender status. So, why do you care so much about it? I'm not being disengenuous; I truly do not understand why people get so obsessed with my genital status.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31004364659.0" user="0991906006091990" delta="False">
    <text>Well I mean, to start, I'm not sure if you feel attacked or something but I was simply asking why it's not treated like similar mental illnesses. I mean I can believe I'm a chair, we're not going to go about turning me into a chair now are we.

Since we're going to go off topic and instead talk about why this matter, I see a genuine issue when it comes to things such as sports and other gender specific issues.

I personally do not feel it is fair that a transgender M-T-F competes in a Fenale oriented sport. Whether it's a female swim team or cycling or what, they have an innate advantage from their male physiology. 

Additionally, I work with two "non-binary" individuals. I am respectful, I refer to them as they or them, but they have different mentalities. One is okay if I slip up here and there but the other has taken me to HR previously for referring to them as her. I'm sorry, but you want me to go against hundreds of years of a social structure and never call you she, when you look like a female? That I find is unreasonable. If someone does it out of disrespect that's one thing but if it's not due to disrespectful then what's the issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31004587572.0" user="fatarella" delta="False">
    <text>I understand (but disagree) with your point. My experience has been that my brain is female, but my body was male. To me, it is a mistake that needs correction. I don't know what caused the error, but am glad that correction is available.

I agree that sports competition between mtf females and cisfemales would, on the whole, not be fair. Are you seeing a lot of this? I haven't, but I'm not very sporty.

And I'm sorry that you have been reported to HR for pronoun error. I've never been hostile about pronoun error unless I suspect that the intent is malicious. And I'm lucky because I truly haven't experienced much hostility. I live in a blue state, and most people have been very polite. Which is nice, as I am not hugely attractive. 

Have you talked to the lady in question, and told her that you are trying your best? It would be lovely if that conversation could happen. We are all humans, just trying to get along after all. I would hope she is receptive to an honest conversation. TBH, I still mess up some pronouns. I love the idea of gender free speech, but old dog, new tricks, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31732264310.0" user="Ronaldo007tm" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose he made the point. You stated, genuinely, why do people care so much if it doesn’t affect them, and the poster gave an example if how it HAS affected them. And that’s the issue, in society, other people CAN be affected. The prefferred pronouns for me is an issue. 

I don’t get to dictate to you what you do with your body, just as you don’t get to dictate what words I do and don’t say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31005109542.0" user="LedZeppelin1602" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It does not affect your life at all.  
&amp;gt;there is no cost to you for my transgender status. So, why do you care so much about it?


1. There have been attempt in Canada to criminalise not calling trans people by their preferred pronouns, which would impinge on our rights to call a spade a spade, this will likely come up again
2. Trans literature is being introduced to early years and primary schools, this as well as other promotion of transgenderism as a lifestyle has caused a [930% rise in six years](https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-nottinghamshire-35532491/) of kids confused with gender, this promotion affects our children's wellbeing
3. There are advocacy groups seeking to make sex-reassignment surgery tax payer funded and some countries already have this in place, so it affects our income
4. Media talks about trans all the time. A British news site I use had two stories in one day and one of the local TV channels has a show about trans with ads about it between every other show on the channel, so people are exposed to it without seeking it out and it's on it's way to being unavoidable.

So it does affect our lives</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31005275791.0" user="fatarella" delta="False">
    <text>1. Vote against it. If more people want the legislation than don't, then you'll have to use non-gendered pronouns. I have to be honest with you, I don't ever see this becoming law. 

Calling someone by their preferred pronouns is simple politeness. Do we have to start legislating good manners? 

2. The article you cite points to increased acceptance of transgenderism as the cause of increased transgenderism as noted by the NHS, not children's literature. Personally, I think we should have a good hard look at endocrine disrupting chemicals in the environment as the cause.

3. Gender dysphoria is real, and has a cure, gender confirmation treatment. Why would we choose this organic disease as being less deserving of treatment than other illnesses?

4. I'm tired of all the trans talk too. Let those of us who seek treatment live our lives without the constant interest in our genitalia. There's a lot of stuff the media bangs on about that I have no interest in, so I turn it off, or turn the page. No one is forcing you to watch or read anything you don't want to.

I just want to live my life free of vilification, with no one denying me employment, housing, medical treatment, etc., because of my gender status.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
