<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001916553.0" user="DuploJamaal" delta="False">
    <text>We are treating them by letting them live as their preferred gender.

You've got to consider that different problems require different solutions.

Schizophrenic and delusional people need to be healed, but gay and trans people only suffer because our society forces them to hide their true identity.

LGBT people are only seen as unnatural because our western culture is based on Christian religious beliefs. The only reason they are seen as unnatural is because they do not fit into the story of the Garden of Eden, but reality is simply more complex than "but that's God's plan".

Transgender people wouldn't be suffering from gender dysphoria if we wouldn't force them to live as the wrong gender. If they can transition socially their suicide rates drop dramatically and their mental health improves drastically.

It's also no surprise that transitioning helps them considering that they evidently have a brain structure like the opposite sex. They simply want to live according to their brain structure, but not according to their genitals. It's just that your brain decides what kind of person you are, but not your genitals.

Additionally transgender people aren't the only ones that suffer from gender dysphoria. People who have gotten a sex change at birth and were raised as the other gender also develop strong gender dysphoria. And - unsurprisingly - transitioning to the gender that's in line with their brain heals their gender dysphoria.

Tl;dr: gay people do not need a prey-the-gay-away camp just because the Bible sees them as unnatural and the same is true for transgender people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
