<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001796682.0" user="AChosenAdjective" delta="False">
    <text>Skimming over your replies, I get the impression that you think that any issue a person has should be corrected, whether it be schizophrenia or being transgender. Is this accurate? If so, why? Assuming that we have a perfect 'cure' for any mental illness, or for being transgender (which in both cases we definitely do not), why is it so important to change them, as opposed to accept them as they are and support them? And given the complications of being intersex (where due to anomalies in chromosomes or hormones, someone's sex isn't perfectly male or female), how can we reliably determine what someone's gender should be?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
