<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31650125589.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31650195560.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/xNinja36 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), before [messaging the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+xNinja36&amp;amp;message=xNinja36+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/-/ejfo179/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
