<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31005544231.0" user="JoJackPro" delta="False">
    <text>You are seriously misinformed. I pray you find people with brains to stear you in the right direction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31006355390.0" user="0991906006091990" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, for one, if you read anything posted here, it's clear that I have. 

Additionally, I'm not sure if you're implying that I don't have brains? If that's the case, you may want to spell steer correctly before you attack another person regarding intelligence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31016460076.0" user="thegreencomic" delta="False">
    <text>If only there was a subreddit he could go to which allows open-minded people to invite a critique of their views which explains why they are flawed.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
