<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31016612851.0" user="BrunetMale" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine if you were in history class and learned about the following:

Hundreds of years ago, there was a kingdom tucked away that regularly engaged in mass kidnapping and rape of women and girls. One day, a young boy’s sister was kidnapped and he vowed to one day save her! Years later, after he grew and trained in swordsmanship, he came back to town and killed all the men he could possibly find that didn’t surrender and swear to change their ways, and he single handed lay saved the entire kingdom and the citizens therein from a lifetime of horrors.

You would probably be told about what a hero that person was.

today however, any modern discussion of going over and dealing directly with situations like this are typically met with lots of resistance...

“Somebody, Just do it.” -Nike</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
