<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31006655366.0" user="circlhat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;. I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, 

It doesn't deserve respect, but the issue is far more complicated since you properly come from a culture that allows male genital mutilation , and justifies it by saying it's not as bad or harmful as female.  even though 20,000 nerve endings are removed from men and 9000 are removed from women. But most western culture have decided that is ok because they profit off of this.

In most western cultures men can not be raped nor can women be pedophiles so when a women rapes a baby another woman judge declares her innocent of the crime because she is a woman.

&amp;gt;https://www.thestar.com/opinion/star-columnists/2018/10/25/court-says-pedophilia-does-not-apply-because-perpetrator-is-a-woman.html

She openly raped a baby boy, rape his anus, recorded it, smile while doing it and walks away freely.


All I'm saying is every culture has their darkness , until one culture has achieve perfection you aren't helping anything you are missing with a delicate social balance , clean your own shit up first before you even attempt to look at others</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
