<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31006128603.0" user="Chocomon" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I didn't have to click the video to know what's coming.

I'm not going to argue about your thesis, just about your choice of example of a "cultural tradition", since it isn't one.

The thing is that bride kidnapping in Kyrgyzstan is not exactly a cultural tradition, but a new phenomena. [Research](https://web.archive.org/web/20080820221004/http://faculty.philau.edu/kleinbachr/2007_study.htm) suggests that wasn't part of Kyrgyz culture until the sovjet era. Before bride kidnapping was unheard of, except for rare cases during war times or lovers running away together to avoid paying a dowry. Not only that, but it started to appear during a time when it was banished by the sovjets. 

Since the end of the sovjet union, it was "revived" as a tradition even though it actually never was one.

Now, consentual played bride-kidnapping is a popular wedding "game" in this region. The best men will "kidnap" the bride before the ceremony in her wedding attire and there is also a [popular sovjet movie](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kidnapping,_Caucasian_Style) that involves bride kidnapping. My best guess is that some people might have misunderstood those as signs of an old tradition that they tried to revive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
