<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31003639594.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>The very understanding of *fundamental human rights* is itself cultural; it's been derived over hundreds if not thousands of years from European culture that itself was influenced by Christianity.  The irony is that this belief is itself not universal at all, and many people in the West don't even necessarily buy into it.  The only rights we have are the ones that we establish for ourselves and maintain for ourselves.  We're free to change our condition but sometimes by force, though that's a more antiquated expectation.

The idea that Kyrgyzstani are doomed to be this way forever ignores the fact that they weren't this way since time was tracked and that they may decide for themselves to do something different.  The exact same way the West largely decided for itself.

Not to mention that the best changes come from within.  Outside forces that, as you put it, used "social advocacy, education, and funding of women's empowerment groups" is rather vague.  What would those look like?  Physical buildings?  People not from the area walking around and up to people's houses?  An invading force?  Invading forces from the West have rarely left a place any better.

Also, it's clear in that video that the women being kidnapped aren't happy about it either.  Not every Kyrgyzstani practices the tradition - particularly outside the actual ethnicity.

The idea that someone has a bad way of life that is immoral and needs to change is exactly what you find with many religions.  Many people, hundreds of millions if not billions, might say that you need your way of life changed and they'd advocate for the same thing.  I don't think you'd be willing to adopt any traditions forced on you in weirdly the same manner as forcing anyone to do anything is bad, by your own post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
