<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31005604315.0" user="rottenlittleshit" delta="False">
    <text>Every person with every mix of culture has the right to voice their opinion and anyone has the right to deny that opinion. If you share a dumb or unpopular opinion you should expect it to be rejected. No matter how reasonable your opinion is you can't expect people to actually change theirs. If it is their culture to kidnap women for marriage I think that is terrible. I think the culture of an average American is healthier but they are not perfect and neither is anyone else. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
