<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31008343870.0" user="theUnmutual6" delta="False">
    <text>Assume for a moment that you have a shitty hobby. Maybe you're in a cult or on hard drugs or something. An intervention is arranged. Would it be more effective from:

1) a group of your closest friends or family the people who are on your wavelength and really get where you are coming from.

2) a bunch of strangers who embody everything you dislike about the world. New age travellers, investment bankers, teenage mums, whatever group of humans instinctively makes you think "these people need to sort their life out".

The same principle applies here. You're most likely to make a change in response to advocacy from people who share your values, life view, and experiences. 

So in terms of effectiveness, change usually sticks when it comes from within rather than from outside.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
