<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31011672542.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service.

This is a bad analogy because children don't pay taxes, plus public schools are funded by the tax dollars of everyone and not just those who use the service.

What you fail to realize is that customers are the source of income used to pay servers *regardless* of whether or not the servers work for a flat wage or a tip. If an employer pays their servers a flat wage, then the price of food will be raised to compensate. If servers work for tips, the food will be cheaper and customers will tip. Either way, the customer ends up paying about the same more or less.

One of the MAJOR misconceptions about tipping is that tipped workers who don't make enough money in tips go home with less than minimum wage. Although it's true that tipped workers make less than minimum wage hourly, it's assumed that they're going to make at least minimum wage after they're tipped. If a server does *not* make minimum wage after they're tipped, then their employer has to make up the difference so that the server makes min. wage.

Tipping is a great system for min. wage jobs because it means workers have a chance of making more than min. wage, instead of making *just* minimum wage. And although most people would argue that servers should simply be payed more than minimum wage, many of these same people would also prefer servers make min. wage instead of tips for reasons I won't delve into.

If you care about the well being of workers, you should be in favor of tipping. Why? Think of it this way.

If a server works for a flat wage, then you're paying the employer 100% of your cash and hoping they pay their workers fairly. You're paying for the server *indirectly*. If the server isn't getting paid what you think they should be, then there's not much you can do about it.

However, if a person works for tips, then you pay the server *directly*. If you think the server deserves min. wage, you can tip low. If you think the server deserves more than min. wage, you can give them a generous tip. That money goes to them and perhaps other staff such as cooks, bussers, etc.

I must emphasize. The customer will pay about the same regardless of whether servers are tipped or if they're working for a flat wage. Tipping just allows for flexibility and generosity. If a person doesn't want to be generous, then the server will make min. wage (which is likely what they'd make if they were paid a flat wage).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
