<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31011646592.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>Waiting tables and relying on tips would definitely change your perspective on this.  I was never one of those smiley-cheery-bouncey-bubbly-etc servers but I was efficient and I could hustle, and sometimes that's enough.  I worked for those tips and I paid the price when I didn't.  

You take tips away and you take away the drive to provide top service from 99% of the people who bring you your food and drinks.  Believe me, if I have a 7-top of little old ladies and a 4-top of executives, the executives are at the top of my list every choice I make and every service I provide; little old ladies just don't tip.  

Nowadays I go through a drive-through for breakfast every day, and every day they get a dollar tip (and my bill is always less than $5 - usually it's $3.23).  Drive through guy sees me, waves, *brings my order before I get to the window*, sometimes even gives me a free breakfast just because (..just because I'm a good tipper).  

Sir or ma'am, tipping is the greatest when you want to motivate good service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011652006.0" user="adashofasshole" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for your perspective, makes more sense :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011701244.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>I'm laughing because you've brought back that feeling of  "Hey, I did a good job but I still got stiffed!"  

Edit: Thanks for the gold!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012166791.0" user="ariwolfe" delta="False">
    <text>There’s multiple studies showing that tips don’t change very much regardless of service. Most people just tip the same amount or not at all because of their personal preference. 

&amp;gt;You take tips away and you take away the drive to provide top service from 99% of the people who bring you your food and drinks

This is because without tips the person is likely making 3 or 4 bucks an hour. You’re essentially saying take away the money and people won’t want to work. Of course that’s true and a living wage would go much further as an incentive to be good at your job.

&amp;gt;Believe me, if I have a 7-top of little old ladies and a 4-top of executives, the executives are at the top of my list every choice I make and every service I provide; little old ladies just don't tip.

I work for tips too so I totally understand and agree with this. I go a little more out of my way for customers that tip well. But with that being said, it’s just inherently unfair. Those 7 ladies are paying customers that are now getting a lower quality service because someone believed to be richer than them walked in. The server isn’t getting the tip until the end of the meal so they don’t actually *know* who will tip more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012235351.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>I'm curious,  but without that snippity "source?" vibe.  I don't know what those studies mean by "most".   

But yeah, I agree most tables just tip whatever.  And for me that means maybe in the range of 80% of them - and that's for decent to really good service (and my observations were that the happy-funny-bouncy-etc waiters almost always got good tips, almost always regardless of service quality).  But the other 20%, for me, tipped well because their glasses were full, they didn't run out of hot sauce, all the things to do with *good service* were done without their asking.  

I just don't think " a living wage" is really going to motivate better service, and I'm not saying that to be ornery.  Isn't there research that shows there's a relationship between the nearness in time to a reward (or punishment) and the action that caused it?    People getting a good tip right then are going to try harder to get another good tip - by performing their duties better - than people just earning their quotidian living wage day in and day out.  

And that's all my 2 cents I got on this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012710956.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>Tips do not encourage good service, they create discomfort and an adversarial relationship between customers and servers.

Tipping does not improve service. It's just been stuck there because of tradition and because of owners not wanting to pay fair wages and because of those waiters who make way more than a fair wage in total. 

Right now, most people's tips vary by very little. The difference between what most people tip for bad service and good service is very small, so many times waiters and managers don't even know how customers felt, due to societal pressure to tip.

However, if tipping was not a factor, then service would likely improve overall, because if tipping wasn't an issue, then customers would start telling managers what they thought of service.

Most professions are not tipped and people try to do a good job, because they want to get positive reviews and to keep their jobs.

Most people think about tips emotionally and not rationally, so unfortunately it is quite difficult to get rid of tipping, because to do so, people would have to look at it logically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013004682.0" user="wellillbegodamned" delta="False">
    <text>Every four days, you've already tipped enough to pay for an additional breakfast that you're not getting.  By the end of a year you've tipped enough to have been able to buy yourself *three months' worth of breakfasts* had you not tipped.  

Getting the occasional free breakfast in reward for your tips is an abysmal return on your investment.  And the other perks have even *less* value:  you could certainly make do without being waved at, and having your order brought *before you get to the window* does you little good since you still can't access until you get to the window.  

All in all you've made a colossal error in judgment that costs you nearly $300 a year for no real benefit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013180395.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>This part always floors me. When I see comments like the one you addressed or when I see people talk about tipping a bartender an extra $20 at the beginning of the night, because then they get a free drink (that costs a few dollars) every once in a while when they visit that bar. Or they get a bit heavier pours of $4 drinks.

I roll my eyes and figure not math wizards. Not like they haven't paid for that free drink or heavy pour many, many times over.

And plenty of times, they don't even get these extras, the bartender just smiles at them more or is extra happy to see them. Who cares?

I would be extra happy to see someone who is nice to me and gives me a bunch of free extra money, too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013363722.0" user="piano679" delta="False">
    <text>Umm, better service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015065822.0" user="wellillbegodamned" delta="False">
    <text>Is she sticking her head out the McDonalds window and giving him a blowjob before he drives away?  How much better service can you get than "I pull up to the window, they hand me my food, I drive off"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013170403.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>But the restaurant (your employer), as well as the customers (your employer's paying clients) would want you to give good service to all the paying customers, so I see your example above as a case against tipping, rather than a case for tipping.

Those low tippers could be big spenders when it comes to ordering, thereby increasing profits for the business. They could write reviews that get read. They could say positive and negative things about the restaurant to everyone they know and to everyone they encounter. They could be regulars if they are happy, also increasing profits. 

So, our flawed tipping culture and how it negatively effects server behavior could be costing businesses lost business, unhappy clients, negative reviews, etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015750891.0" user="corgiporgipie" delta="False">
    <text>That’s definitely not true. In restaurants in the US and countries where tipping is not a thing, service is pretty much the same. The idea that if waiters don’t get tipped they will give terrible service is just dumb. If waiters give bad service they will get fired and replaced with ones that do. From what you said tipping just creates bad service. You already created a biased opinion on people you don’t know determining the quality of their service. 
Without tipping everyone could have the same equal service.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015777942.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The idea that if waiters don’t get tipped they will give terrible service is just dumb.

Are you even aware you created a strawman out of something I didn't say?  Answer that and I will continue the conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015812024.0" user="corgiporgipie" delta="False">
    <text>“You take tips away and you take away the drive to provide top service from 99% of the people who bring you your food and drinks.”

And like everyone else supporting tipping in this post is saying pretty much the same thing. And immediately after you say you make people who you think tip your top priority over people who you think don’t tip. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015977210.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; “You take tips away and you take away the drive to provide top service from 99% of the people who bring you your food and drinks.”

Yes, I did say that, and I stand by it no matter how many people disagree; correctness of a personal opinion is not based on votes.  

I have to guess about the strawman answer since you didn't make a direct response.  But let's be fair, it looks pretty obvious you knew what I meant and your answer implies that.  Wasn't it obvious that I was talking about "top service" though?  I think OP got that since he as much as admitted I'd given him a new perspective.   

So why did you change my statement about top service to being about terrible service in your response: "The idea that if waiters don’t get tipped they will give terrible service is just dumb."?   

&amp;gt;  You already created a biased opinion on people you don’t know determining the quality of their service. Without tipping everyone could have the same equal service.  

Yeah, well, after years waiting tables I learned little old ladies tip for shit.  True that's bias and true that's opinion.  But it's *educated opinion* based on years of experience.  And I never said I gave them bad service (which I appreciate you didn't actually accuse me of).  They got the normal average service you seem to be content with.  And yes, the suited businessmen got the top tier hustle; because there I had a chance at a 30% plus tip if just one of them noticed what was going on.  Which actually happened from time to time.  

&amp;gt;  In restaurants in the US and countries where tipping is not a thing, service is pretty much the same  

And at tables where I didn't hustle my experience bears this out to be true.  But at the ones where I did hustle there was a marked increase in the chances of a good tip.  Is this so improbable?  Man I was a college student who also worked kitchen duty to make ends meet.  The potential for good tips spurred me to provide the best service I could muster, and it paid off enough to prove to me I was doing the right thing.  My Heartfelt Thanks to every last customer who knew I was working hard for them and rewarded me for it.  They paid my rent, my meals, my gas, and my college.

Hopefully some day you'll be in a place you see some kid going the extra mile for you, and you'll reward them with a better than average tip.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017107813.0" user="corgiporgipie" delta="False">
    <text>All that is my whole point. None of that should be happening. No one should get “better service” based on tips. Everyone should get the same service. Waiters shouldn’t have to worry about customers paying their rent. Their employers should be doing that.  The customer shouldn’t have to worry about that at the end of their meal anyway. Guilt tripped into tipping the expected amount. Just the fact that there is an expected amount proves tipping is not a tip anymore, it’s their paycheck. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017125729.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>Great.  Go be an employer running a restaurant and make sure everyone who works for you doesn't need tips, and makes that living you say they should.   Or find some other venue where you live up to that.

Go on.  No excuses now.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017145996.0" user="corgiporgipie" delta="False">
    <text>Well the fact that it’s not a problem anywhere else. Even in the US plenty of restaurants don’t require tipping. And if a restaurant can’t stay afloat with out skimping on their employees pay it probably means that place is pretty shitty. It will probably close down but new ones with better business practices and food will open up.  Trust me restaurants will not die out anytime soon. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017967923.0" user="HomunculusEmeritus" delta="False">
    <text>I just don't understand how people who know so much aren't happy, dynamic, wealthy, and out there enjoying the fruits of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017987755.0" user="corgiporgipie" delta="False">
    <text>What are you talking about? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
