<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31011600734.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>So we have two options: (1) have restaurants build in the tips and raise prices by +20% across the board, or (2) have food that costs 20% less with the option of paying +15% or +25% depending on what you're feeling like that day and the quality of service you received.

Why wouldn't you automatically want the latter scenario? More options, and even ability to choose to just straight up pay 20% less if you wanted to (it's not illegal to forego tipping). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011637645.0" user="adashofasshole" delta="False">
    <text>3. Expect to not pay tip as employees are being paid a live able wage (which I know is not to be expected)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011781248.0" user="4trezz" delta="False">
    <text>Employers are legally required to pay the difference between (wage + tips) and regular minimum wage. So basically, tipped employees are guaranteed at least minimum wage.

In practice, tipped employees tend to make way more than others in the restaurant... many of whom only make minimum wage themselves. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013910819.0" user="eye_patch_willy" delta="False">
    <text>Then prices are going up a lot more than 20%. Nobody had the right to a livable wage, you earn a proportion of the value you generate in the market. I'm paid more than a waiter because I have skills that allow me to charge willing customers $160 an hour. No restaurant is going to raise prices, maintain customers, and share the entire increase in revenue with staff. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31018847081.0" user="Kelaerrr" delta="False">
    <text>I think that this is all about statistics. I’ve heard that they always earn more money than other employees from the restaurant and that it’s usually above minimum wage. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011665161.0" user="jkseller" delta="False">
    <text>please stop acting as if the business's revenue is in direct correlation with what they pay servers. It is not and does not have to be. Most (very small businesses are the exception) businesses would have a very small percentage in net loss by raising tipped employees wage to minimum. At least at minimum wage there is little to no economic pressure on the customer to "put food in the server's mouth". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011780393.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>Raise the server's wage to minimum? They already make, at least, min. wage. Plus any pressure for a customer to tip will be mitigated to making them pay more for the cost of the food. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011801102.0" user="jkseller" delta="False">
    <text>I just said it would not be required to raise the cost of food in the vast majority of places. The vast majority of places have enough money to have the servers make minimum wage without tip assistance. They just don't because they don't have to. The answer here is greed, like it is for almost everything else. You really think it's something else? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011993210.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;just said it would not be required to raise the cost of food in the vast majority of places. The vast majority of places have enough money to have the servers make minimum wage without tip assistance. 

This is blatantly false. Most sit down restaurants go out of business because profit margins are incredibly thin in most cases.

Furthermore, lets imagine what you said is true. Let's imagine that business owners can pay their workers without raising the cost of food. If we do away with the tipping system, would the do it? If they're as greedy as you say, they wouldn't. These greedy business owners would simply raise the cost of food to make up for the money they're losing paying their workers. Of course, this is under the assumption that business owners are as successful and as greedy as you say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012064177.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>But servers generally don't make minimum wage when you factor in tips; they generally will make a lot more. I think removal of the tipping process will inevitably lead to servers making less, so I'm not in a huge rush to get there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012075170.0" user="jkseller" delta="False">
    <text>That's the real thing, servers always try and confound this discussion by cause they benefit from people tipping. Doesn't mean it should be that way</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012088481.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>Right. But when it comes to me personally and an *entertainment industry* like going out to a restaurant/bar, I really like the fact that people are paid well. What are we going to do? Follow the model of other low/mid skill industries like car manufacturers and drive wages down to the lowest possible denomination? Not even keeping up with inflation?

Not sure why you and everyone here is so keen to take money out of these people's pockets so you can have your burger or whatever for like $1 less. That's not me. 

I've never had a problem with tipping. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012096842.0" user="jkseller" delta="False">
    <text>I think people would still tip, but I think the scale wouldn't be on this 20% of a 100 dinner for 2 shit. That has never made sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012103892.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>But why not? If you're paying $100 for a dinner, it's a pretty nice place. Wouldn't you want someone with experience taking care of you? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012146194.0" user="jkseller" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly the level of service at a Chili's or Friday's is more than great for me. After that, I am paying more for the sake of food quality and clout honestly factors in a little. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012188938.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>Well for instance, if I'm buying $40 plates or whatever, it's nice to have someone who is knowledgable about the wines, about the entrees, and someone who will be attentive, etc. It's an expensive night, and I think a good server adds to the experience. I get some people aren't as into that, but for me good service is part of the experience. 


 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012202668.0" user="jkseller" delta="False">
    <text>And you would reward that yourself. There should be no expectation, extraordinary service would get rewarded when it happens, not as an expectation for an expensive meal on its face. It's the expectation that people are pissed at, because no one wants to be considered a dick for not personally paying a server 20 an hour for walking my food that she didn't suggest back and forth, and filling my cup a couple times. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013356437.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>" It's the expectation that people are pissed at, because no one wants to be considered a dick for not personally paying a server 20 an hour for walking my food that she didn't suggest back and forth, and filling my cup a couple times."

Precisely! The voice of reason!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013349201.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>It is the sommelier's job to help you with your wine choices and to tell you details about wines, as well as to explain various wines in a pairing and why they were chosen, etc.

Regarding explaining menu items, the executive chef or chef de cuisine could write a detailed description for each item just once and then customers could just get that. I have never encountered any employee who could describe a dish in more detail or more passionately than the chef.

All I need from the waiter is to be polite, to bring me my food and beverages (and refills), with my glass never being empty, to take plates away, to bring me the check in a timely manner and to cash me out quickly. That's it.

I am no there for counseling, to chat, to joke, etc., and such things are not worth extra money to me.  I just want polite, professional service, that's it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011693147.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>I like option 1.

That way a waiter has a reliable wage, and the consumer has a reliable consistent price. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011755202.0" user="Savanty" delta="False">
    <text>But that scenario lacks the incentive for a waiter to provide anything other than ‘adequete’ service. 

You’ve been to restaurants where you order a drink, the waiter never comes back to provide refills, they drop off your food, and later on the check. They avoid eye contact when you’re trying to get their attention. That’s the bare minimum of service that should be provided. 

You’ve also been to restaurants where waiters pay attention, come back for refills before you’ve finished your first drink, write down and read back your food order to ensure it’s correct, check on you again a few minutes after they’ve dropped off the food to see if there’s anything else you need. In general, they’re available. 

And good waiters are tipped more than those that provide the bare minimum, which is fair. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011810848.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But that scenario lacks the incentive for a waiter to provide anything other than ‘adequete’ service.

Of course it does.  Like every other job: if you do a bad job you are fired.

How come, attorneys, accountants, garbage men, airline pilots, etc etc don't need to have a tip system to provide an outstanding service?

&amp;gt;You’ve been to restaurants where you order a drink, the waiter never comes back to provide refills, they drop off your food, and later on the check.

Yeah, and that happens in both tipped and non-tipped cultures.  Such experience is pretty rare though (IMHO), in both tipped and non-tipped cultures.

&amp;gt;You’ve also been to restaurants where waiters pay attention, come back for refills before you’ve finished your first drink, write down and read back your food order to ensure it’s correct, check on you again a few minutes after they’ve dropped off the food to see if there’s anything else you need. 

That's what happened in vast majority of places I have been to in both tipped and non-tipped cultures.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011875710.0" user="QuantumDischarge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Of course it does. Like every other job: if you do a bad job you are fired

I've had plenty of bad experiences with low to moderately paid service employees and not one has ever been fired.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011882231.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>I had bad experiences with tipped employees too.  They were not deterred by bad tips.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011905612.0" user="QuantumDischarge" delta="False">
    <text>At least in those outcomes, you have the ability to pay less for sub-par service. If the guy at best buy is too busy to talk to a co-worker than help me find something, I can't take $10 off the cost of whatever I was buying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011912679.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>I really don't want to bother with this "pay less" game.  

Does not excite me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013254410.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>Not giving you refills is not providing adequate service. Unless there is an option  for the customer to get up and get refills themselves, providing service that is adequate in any way, shape, or form, is consistently providing refills.

By paying menu price + tax, the customer is paying for food and drinks (including refills) and for those things to get to them consistently and to get sauces and whatever they need.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011784465.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>1. Min wage plus tips is more reliable than just min. wage.

2. The consumer can pay 15-20% every time they go out, which would make the prices consistent. Your second point really isn't even an argument as much as it's an unrelated, false, statement. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011800169.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Min wage plus tips is more reliable than just min. wage.

Yeah but guaranteed "Min wage + 20%" is more reliable than Min wage + tips.

&amp;gt;The consumer can pay 15-20%

That's not consistent.    I have to do math at the end my meal.  Is it 15?  Is it 20?  It's different every time.  Count me out of this experience.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012044921.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yeah but guaranteed "Min wage + 20%" is more reliable than Min wage + tips.

Most restaurants aren't going to pay min. wage + 20%, they're going to pay min. wage. That's the nature of serving at restaurants. They're low wage jobs.

You're probably thinking, "Then let's raise min wage!" Sure, we could raise the min wage by 20%, but then my argument would still be true. It's better to work the new min. wage + tips than to merely work the new min. wage.

But if you think most restaurants would pay more than min wage if tipping was abolished, then please let me know! If you think they would still try to get away with paying min. wage and you think we need to raise min. wage to stop them from paying low wages, then my point remains true and you will have to admit tipping is still better even if min. wage has to be raised. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012058098.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;they're going to pay min. wage.

Then they will have a harder time finding waiters and will have to raise the wage.

The market will work itself out.

&amp;gt;But if you think most restaurants would pay more than min wage if tipping was abolished, then please let me know!

I just did.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013527614.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then they will have a harder time finding waiters and will have to raise the wage.

You believe that if restaurants paid a flat minimum wage, hardly anyone would agree to work for such low wages, which would force restaurants to pay their workers more.

However, you believe people who work for tips are paid too little. Question, why is it that people wouldn't work for a flat min. wage, yet they're willing to work for a low tipped wage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013575208.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Ha?

That'a not what I am saying.

If you are a making an average of X = W+ T (wage plus tips) you can be expected to demand around X = W (wage) if there was no tips.

My gripe with tipped wage is that it's INCONSISTENT, not that's it's too low.


Imagine Waiter 1 who makes:

January - 1500$

February - 1500$

March - 1500$

April - 1500$

Now imagine Waiter 2:

January - 500$

February - 1500$

March - 1500$

April - 2500$


They *averaged* the same income. However Waiter 2 got evicted in the winter because he could not pay January rent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013698734.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>You don't need an education to become as server. You also don't need an advanced skill set. And because there are tons of people who are willing to work minimum wage, the supply of potential servers is far too high to allow anyone to bargain for a higher starting wage as a server. Practically nobody is going to get a flat wage equal to what they'd expect in tips. If servers worked for a flat wage, I am certain they would almost all work for min. wage or close to min. wage.

So if we looked at your example, I would argue that Server 1 would only make min. wage. So we could call that 1200 per month. Server 2 would then make 1200 per month or more. If server 2 is used to making 1600 a month but they make 1200 on a slow month, they can get themselves in a sticky situation. However, they'll still be making more money than waiter 1. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013733966.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Look up BLS stats. Servers (on average) already make barely more than minimum wage, even with tips.

https://www.bls.gov/ooh/food-preparation-and-serving/mobile/waiters-and-waitresses.htm

The market will bear what it will bear, regardless of having a tip culture or not.

If a young, attractive, outgoing, college age energetic sever is making 20$ an hour  in a hip bar she is not going to hang around for $7.25. she will go and get a different job of *some kind*. And trust me, that hip bar does not want servers they can realistically hire at $7.25.

On the other hand some late night suburban diner lady who is making $7.25 right now (counting tips) - she will continue making that in wage.

The fundamental supply/demand of labor market is not going to swing dramatically based on tip culture changes </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011797384.0" user="Leolor66" delta="False">
    <text>One small issue with that. Service.  Travel to a country where tipping isn't expected.  You will be subject to mediocre service and still be paying a higher price with the tip included. Tipping encourages better service, or at least it should. 

My daughter waited during college and tips gave her between $8-$10 an hour on top of her $7 wage.  It was a semi fast food place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011810098.0" user="Tinie_Snipah" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Travel to a country where tipping isn't expected. You will be subject to mediocre service and still be paying a higher price with the tip included. 

This is an opinion, not a fact.

It shows a difference in American culture vs other cultures. It doesn't show that tipping creates better service, not by any means. The difference in culture is how most Europeans are perfectly happy to just order their food and only speak the waiters when their food arrives, and when they want to pay. American diners much prefer constant service, with refills and chatty staff.

It's just a cultural difference, nothing to do with tipping</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011814883.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You will be subject to mediocre service 

Not my experience at all.

I have been to France  and Japan and got service that was as good or even better than in US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012809066.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>Because tips do not improve service. That's not reality of the situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012053229.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>Unfortunately, we take away tipping and servers are going to make less and are going to be worse off. 

Worse off because now the person working the dead morning shift and the hellish 100 MPH Saturday shift will be making exactly the same. In a high turnover industry, managers need these incentives to get their scheduling correct and the removal of tips will be fucking over everyone involved in this process. No incentives to work the busy shifts, even if you're a spry college student who wants to make bank working all the shifts that the older "lifer" waiters don't feel like dealing with. Just kinda sucks.

Second, I believe removing tips will mean less money for waiters. I don't believe restaurants would pay their staff the same amount of $$$ waiters would make on a busy saturday, and we'll just water down the industry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012063408.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Worse off because now the person working the dead morning shift and the hellish 100 MPH Saturday shift will be making exactly the same. 

Why?

The owners can pay different wages for different shifts.

&amp;gt;Second, I believe removing tips will mean less money for waiters. I don't believe restaurants would pay their staff the same amount of $$$ waiters would make on a busy saturday, and we'll just water down the industry.

The owners will pay as much as the market will bear.  Just like in every other industry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012078512.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why? The owners can pay different wages for different shifts. 

Is this possible? I'm not an accountant, but I feel like it'd be somewhat difficult to do this and a lot of extra book keeping for the owner. The current process seems more efficient. 

&amp;gt;The owners will pay as much as the market will bear. Just like in every other industry.

Right, but want to point out that low/med skilled wages have remained rather stagnant across the market in non-tipping industries, and have hardly kept up with inflation over the last 40 years. I kind of like the fact that waiters/bartenders can actually make a pretty good living. Again, not sure why every one here is in such a rush to change that. Seems kind of mean-spirited. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012112722.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Is this possible?

Sure.  As long as you pay min wage or more your can structure your pay scale any way you want.

&amp;gt; it'd be somewhat difficult

It's really easy.  Modern payroll software solves "problems" like these for breakfast.

&amp;gt;I kind of like the fact that waiters/bartenders can actually make a pretty good living

They rally don't make a pretty good living though.

They make barely more than min wage: the average is 10$ an hour or 20K per year.

https://www.bls.gov/ooh/food-preparation-and-serving/waiters-and-waitresses.htm

Sure, waiters in a few HIGH CLASS establishments make good money,  but those will probably get paid more anyway in a non-wage economy, because quality restaurants complete for quality wait staff.

For every college-age attractive waitress in a swanky bar who makes bank (which she still will in a non-tipping world), there are 10 people working for a local diner who are barely scraping it together and are really hurt by a night where they get bad tips.  These people could use a CONSISTENT wage, they can plan their life around.

I actually think it's mean-spirited to insist that we should place livelihood of real people trying to get by on a mood of tip-givers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012121135.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose the core question is, do you think the tip to wages only change would result in *more money* made by servers or less at any given establishment? I would argue the latter, but I realize I could be incorrect. What do you think? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012133557.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>I think the take-home money would stay more or less the same, on average.

It will just be more consistent.

Salaries/Wages are governed by labor supply and demand more than anything else.  These fundamentals will not change based on the tip-culture.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012181012.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think the take-home money would stay more or less the same, on average.

If you think it will stay the same, then that's a valid argument. I however do not think it will stay the same, *especially* for the go getters who work the hard shift and are extra attentive, etc. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012208986.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>The go getters will get raises, because restaurants want to retain such workers.

Just like in every other industry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013195500.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>"The owners will pay as much as the market will bear. Just like in every other industry."

Exactly this!!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011862823.0" user="Cybyss" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why wouldn't you automatically want the latter scenario? More options, and even ability to choose to just straight up pay 20% less if you wanted to (it's not illegal to forego tipping).

Having more options isn't necessarily a good thing, especially when you don't really know what you want.

If I'm "out of the loop" with regard to local tipping culture, I would feel very awkward having to decide whether I'm expected to offer a tip, and how much of a tip it should be. If I was to go to a Japanese restaurant to have some sushi, for example, I honestly wouldn't know whether I'm supposed to leave a tip just for the waiter, or whether I'd be expected to offer two separate tips (one for the waiter, one for the sushi chef), since I've read in a few places that tipping the sushi chef is sometimes considered the polite thing to do. This is one of the reasons I've never had sushi before.

In general, I suspect that most of the time people tip, it has more to do with avoiding the awkward feeling of being "that guy who didn't tip", and less to do with wanting to reward exceptional service.

If all restaurants had tips built into their prices automatically so that I didn't have to worry about it, I probably might have tried sushi by now. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012038521.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If I'm "out of the loop" with regard to local tipping culture, I would feel very awkward having to decide whether I'm expected to offer a tip, and how much of a tip it should be. 

Tipping is very straightforward, in my opinion. 15% standard and anything above that is being nice. I'm 32 and these % have never shifted around to my knowledge. 

&amp;gt;This is one of the reasons I've never had sushi before.

I've eaten sushi out maybe 75+ times in my life and have never had a problem or have heard of a problem with someone following standard tipping procedures above. I think you're over thinking this haha. 

&amp;gt;In general, I suspect that most of the time people tip, it has more to do with avoiding the awkward feeling of being "that guy who didn't tip", and less to do with wanting to reward exceptional service.

You just give 15% and that's it. It's a straightforward process. 

&amp;gt;If all restaurants had tips built into their prices automatically so that I didn't have to worry about it, I probably might have tried sushi by now.

No disrespect, but you not trying sushi because you're worried about the tip is a very unique problem, specific to you. Just follow standard tipping procedures. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012370492.0" user="Cybyss" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;No disrespect, but you not trying sushi because you're worried about the tip is a very unique problem, specific to you. 

Haha, maybe you're right :)

&amp;gt;Just follow standard tipping procedures.

Well, knowing who to tip vs. who not to tip in our society is actually pretty complicated. There's a reason we have to have [articles like these](http://www.traveller.com.au/a-guide-to-tipping-in-the-us-when-do-i-tip-and-how-much-39x1t) (I don't get out much, so they're probably as useful to me as to foreigners).

So, I guess I'm to just leave a tip for the waiter on the table like in normal restaurants and not worry about tipping the sushi chef? Is there a difference between a sit-down restaurant vs. a sushi bar where you sit in front of the chef?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012404473.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So, I guess I'm to just leave a tip for the waiter on the table like in normal restaurants and not worry about tipping the sushi chef? 

I'm going to go out on a limb and say that 15% tip on the bill at a sushi restaurant is perfectly acceptable. I would imagine 95%+ of people don't tip sushi chefs, and that likely tips are shared. I'm sure they all work it out. 

And hey, if you want to throw the sushi chef a $5 I'm sure he/she will be perfectly happy with it. Don't put so much pressure on yourself!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
