<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31013300372.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>Restaurants have experimented with doing away with tipping. They pay their servers appropriately, and the cost is reflected in the price of the food. First, this results in less business because the food is perceived as more expensive. Yes, you can rationalize that it's the same thing, but it doesn't *feel* the same, and a customer's feelings are very important for keeping their business. It's the same reason prices always end in .99 or whatever instead of making it a whole number. $19.99 *feels* like less than $20. So, lower prices are better for business.

Secondly, the waiters paradoxically made less money. Yeah. They generally pocket more after tips than they did if paid a fair hourly wage. This is both a product of good business, and customer wanting to treat good waiters with proper compensation. Tipping just works. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
