<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31011609851.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Are you advocating for getting getting rid of tipping in general or are you saying that people shouldn't judge others who don't tip?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011630699.0" user="adashofasshole" delta="False">
    <text>I think that the responsibility of tipping should not fall onto the consumer. It should first and solely be blamed on their employers for not paying enough. It should fall onto the consumer last as they are already paying for a service. 

I also acknowledge the moral aspect of tipping, but that is the only argument I can understand much less respect.

That being said I also think people should not judge for not tipping, unless the service was above and beyond. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011681148.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think that the responsibility of tipping should not fall onto the consumer. It should first and solely be blamed on their employers for not paying enough. It should fall onto the consumer last as they are already paying for a service.

I mean if the employer ups their pay to minimum wage, the cost is getting pushed on to the consumer anyway. Unless you think that a waiter/waitress job isn't worthy of minimum wage, then you are somewhat expected to make up the difference as a consumer. It's kind of just shifting at what point are you paying for the service.

&amp;gt; That being said I also think people should not judge for not tipping

So to me personally, everyone's actions in public are open to be analyzed by others. We are always evaluating people based on what we see, I mean its how we choose who we form relationships from the beginning. Someone not tipping when it is widely known that waiters/waitresses are paid quite a bit below minimum wage is of interest and it is considered considerate to do so is an interesting signal of their character or situation to me, and I'm curious to know why they broke with this standard practice of our shared community. For example, if they justify it by saying there is nothing saying they have to, I would probably be less likely to rely on them in the future as they've just signaled that social expectations aren't enough to push them towards what our community considers proper behavior. 

Your view gives a signal as well. You state that you still tip even though you don't necessarily wish to do so. That signals to me that you are someone who, despite not wanting to, will still conduct yourself in a way that is acceptable and in line with your community. If I were your neighbor, we may not always see eye to eye on certain issues, but you've given me a signal that you can put the community's interests before those of your own, so I would have less fear of you taking advantage of me. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011708975.0" user="adashofasshole" delta="False">
    <text>I guess I had some bad wording. I don’t hate tipping, I had the idea that the responsibility of making their wage live able falls onto the consumer. I’m more than happy to tip someone so that they can maintain a house over their head after doing me a service. 

But I see your point, balance is needed, and if restaurants increased their wages, they’d have to find the money somewhere </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
