<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31011586831.0" user="jitz860" delta="False">
    <text>In jobs that are service oriented, like a waiter or bartender, tips encourage them to do their job better thus giving the customer a better experience  while also giving the employee opportunity to better earn money.  For poor service, you don’t tip.  If we did away with the tip system, restaurants would just raise the prices on the menu and the end result would be the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011643588.0" user="-fireeye-" delta="False">
    <text>Businesses absorbing their costs and treating wages as fixed cost like everyone else is positive, if they're employing someone that person's income shouldn't be variable based on business. That's business's risk to deal with and manage - hence they get to keep profits as reward for risks. If they're being expected to take on risks of bad business cycle, they ought to be fairly compensated with share of profits. On employee side, tips unfairly transfers risks from employers to employees.

On customer side, it's not my job to evaluate businesses employees. My interaction is with the business, and I expect the business has training and disciplinary procedure to deal with its employees. If I have a problem with service, I don't have problem with a particular employee, I've problem with the business. On customer side, business is unfairly offloading its managerial duties onto customers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
