<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593540940.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tdn4c/cmv_tipping_makes_no_sense/">
    <title>CMV: Tipping makes no sense</title>
    <original_poster>adashofasshole</original_poster>
    <original_post>The general logic I hear behind tipping is because the driver or waiter does not make enough money. 

Well how is it the consumers fault that they are not making enough money? I can see the fault being placed on the employer for not paying enough, or even the company, but to place the responsibility on the consumer is completely lost to me. It would make more sense to me to even blame the employee for not working harder to find a better paying job (not the main point). 

The equivalent would be expecting kids to bring in money to give to underpaid teachers, which makes a lot more sense to me as students in public schools are not paying teachers for their service. 

Please, change my view. 

Edit: I still give my fair share of tips, also I understand it is not mandatory but it is highly frowned upon when someone doesn’t tip. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31011573857.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>The reality is that the law allows waiters to be paid $2.13/hr with the expectation that they make up the difference in tips.  Sure, the restaurant has to ensure that their wage + tips equals minimum, but if that happens too often the waiter will just get fired.

I don't agree with tipping as a practice, but so long as there is a minimum wage exception for waiters, you have to tip them.  Not doing so is asking them to basically work for free.  If we want to change the custom, we need to close the exemption _then_ stop tipping.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011666856.0" user="core2idiot" delta="False">
    <text>But that also varies per state. So if I'm out of state I usually I have to look this up to know how much I should tip. My state doesn't have a different minimum wage for tipped employees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011669575.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>True, but all the more reason to change the law at a national level.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013154477.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>How much do you tip in your state?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013724470.0" user="core2idiot" delta="False">
    <text>For counter service, zero.
For table service it varies, between zero and a few bucks.
Although I also really don't like being asked to tip before I eat, so it will trend towards zero in that situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013836360.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>Have you experienced any weird occurrences at restaurants due to these practices? May I ask in what state you live?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013931086.0" user="core2idiot" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, not really, occasionally I get flak from the people I'm at the restaurant with but never from the server. I live in Oregon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013957237.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>That is awesome! Do you go to the same restaurants sometimes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013964691.0" user="core2idiot" delta="False">
    <text>Quite frequently.  I live in a small town. Although as an asterisk I break those rules occasionally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011688170.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The reality is that the law allows waiters to be paid $2.13/hr with the expectation that they make up the difference in tips. Sure, the restaurant has to ensure that their wage + tips equals minimum, but if that happens too often the waiter will just get fired.

If a server isn't making enough in tips to make above min. wage, then either the server is a jackass who deserves to be fired, the restaurant is overstaffed, or the restaurant isn't doing well and on a path of failure to begin with.

&amp;gt;I don't agree with tipping as a practice, but so long as there is a minimum wage exception for waiters, you have to tip them. Not doing so is asking them to basically work for free.

You just stated that employers make up the difference if a server doesn't make min. wage after tips. How can you say that not tipping them is the equivalent of making them work for free? If you don't tip, you're making them work for min. wage (about $7.25-$8.00 if I remember correctly).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011693856.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If a server isn't making enough in tips to make above min. wage, then either the server is a jackass who deserves to be fired, the restaurant is overstaffed, or the restaurant isn't doing well and on a path of failure to begin with.

Maybe so, but that doesn't really address this situation.  Even if, on average, the server makes enough to get past minimum, that doesn't excuse any individual from not tipping.  Not tipping is asking other people to make up for the wages the server should have earned when they waited on you.

&amp;gt;How can you say that not tipping them is the equivalent of making them work for free?

They did work for you, and you did not pay them for that work.  The fact that someone else may have paid them enough for it to average out doesn't change the fact that you did not pay them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011715582.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Maybe so, but that doesn't really address this situation.

I was merely addressing your specific claim in regards to servers being fired for making less than minimum wage. It was not a statement about tipping as a whole.

&amp;gt;They did work for you, and you did not pay them for that work. The fact that someone else may have paid them enough for it to average out doesn't change the fact that you did not pay them.

I think I understand what you're saying. If you don't tip a server, although they aren't technically working for free per se, they're still making the same amount of money than what they'd make if you hadn't showed up at the restaurant at all. If this is what you're trying to get at, then I can give you that one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011720134.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I was merely addressing your specific claim in regards to servers being fired for making less than minimum wage. It was not a statement about tipping as a whole.

Fair enough.

&amp;gt;they're still making the same amount of money than what they'd make if you hadn't showed up at the restaurant at all.

Yes, **and** they are having to do the additional work of waiting on your table, which they would not have to do had you not come to the restaurant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31011756403.0" user="NemoC68" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, and they are having to do the additional work of waiting on your table, which they would not have to do had you not come to the restaurant.

Yeah, I'll give you that. But do consider the reverse.

If a server is paid a flat wage, they'll be paid the same regardless  of whether it's slow or busy. So if they're serving twice as many tables as usual, they won't receive additional compensation. Tipping is good for offsetting this issue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31013405375.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>So customers should avoid coming into stores or restaurants, and avoid calling companies' phone numbers, because then employees have to actually do work??? It's a job. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31012863916.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>Some states don't have a separate minimum wage for waiters. California's minimum wage is something like $10.50-11 in the lowest paying cities and it goes up from there. So tips are given on top of that. But unfortunately, waiters here expect the same tips as they do in states that pay $2.50+. Tipping culture is out of control in our country and customers are the ones getting screwed and some waiters, while businesses and highly tipped waiters are raking it in, and making way more than the fair market wage would be for those positions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
