<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593993382.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tnc86/cmv_schools_should_place_as_much_emphasis_on/">
    <title>CMV: Schools should place as much emphasis on developing children's mental health as they do on academic learning.</title>
    <original_poster>Starrcade87</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the goal of the education system should be to help children grow into healthy adults. 

Academic learning is good, but I would argue that it's actually less important than learning how to take care of yourself and your mental health.  For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends, but being mentally healthy is something that will serve us all our lives.

How should this be achieved?  I don't know exactly, but a few ideas:

\- Keep licensed therapists on staff at every school, and give every child at least 1 hour per week of dedicated therapy time, and more for students who are troubled.

\- Allow students to take at least 1 hour of outdoor sports and recreation per day.  Getting exercise and sunshine is vital for us to feel happy as humans.

\- Teach students valuable life skills that they will need as adults.  Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed.  This may seem a bit off topic at first glance, but financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult.

In other words, school shouldn't just about math, reading, and science.  Spend time and effort developing kids as people and not only will they be healthier, they'll learn better too.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31015956339.0" user="IaniteThePirate" delta="False">
    <text>Since you said in a comment that your idea applies to secondary schooling, I'm mostly focusing on that.

While I agree with the idea that mental health should be a bigger focus in schools (though I strongly disagree that it's more important than academic learning), I disagree with many of the solutions you have offered. I don't believe they are realistic or even beneficial. 

&amp;gt; - Keep licensed therapists on staff at every school, and give every child at least 1 hour per week of dedicated therapy time, and more for students who are troubled.

For one, this would require schools to hire a huge amount of therapists. If you had a high school with 1,600 kids (ignoring the fact that many have more than that) and you wanted each kid to meet with a therapist once a week, you'd need to hire 46 therapists. That's if each one spends their entire day doing nothing but meeting kids. 

Assuming you could even find enough therapists, and that they were all good therapists, how would the school pay for them? Many schools are already way underfunded. But forget that, where would they meet the kids? I'd be willing to bet very few schools have an extra 50 offices sitting around unused.

Ignoring that point, would this even help the kids? Sure, some kids could get a benefit from this. But most kids don't need this. And most will just be annoyed with it, and not want to talk about anything. Forcing people to go will just make them hate it.

Additionally, when would this happen? Do students get pulled out of class? I know for myself and for many other people that would cause more stress than anything else. Imagine if you're falling behind in a class like Physics, and you're forced to miss the class so that you can go talk to someone you don't need to talk to. 

&amp;gt; - Allow students to take at least 1 hour of outdoor sports and recreation per day. Getting exercise and sunshine is vital for us to feel happy as humans.

This works in elementary and maybe middle school. But how would you make this work in high school? When would this happen? Do all the students leave at once? Are they supervised or just expected to return? 

If they don't all leave at once, how do you stagger it? For example, my school staggers lunch into three separate blocks. They make this work by assigning it to your third period. Then they have a 2 hour window for lunch/third period. You either spend thirty minutes at lunch followed by 90 minutes in class, 45 minutes in class, 30 minute lunch, then back to class for 45 minutes, or you go to a 90 minute class and then a 30 minute lunch. This works well. But if you stretch the time to an hour? Or an hour and a half including lunch? If that was staggered, that takes up 4.5 hours, or more than half the school day. That fucks the entire schedule up.

So you'd have to release them all at once, realistically. To do what? Structured exercise? Just free time outside? Then you gotta supervise them or they'll do dumb shit. And what happens if the weather sucks and you can't go outside? Does everyone hang around the halls? Or just spend an extra hour in the classroom.
What about when it rains or is cold outside? Then what?

And where does this extra time come from?
Are you cutting time out of other classes? That would cause a number of problems on it's own. Or are you adding an hour to the day? Which would essentially be forcing students to lose an hour of their own time to stay at school for mandated outdoors time. That doesn't sound very helpful.


&amp;gt;  Teach students valuable life skills that they will need as adults. Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed. This may seem a bit off topic at first glance, but financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult.

I don't disagree that these things are important, but they're not exactly related to your main point.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
