<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593993382.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tnc86/cmv_schools_should_place_as_much_emphasis_on/">
    <title>CMV: Schools should place as much emphasis on developing children's mental health as they do on academic learning.</title>
    <original_poster>Starrcade87</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the goal of the education system should be to help children grow into healthy adults. 

Academic learning is good, but I would argue that it's actually less important than learning how to take care of yourself and your mental health.  For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends, but being mentally healthy is something that will serve us all our lives.

How should this be achieved?  I don't know exactly, but a few ideas:

\- Keep licensed therapists on staff at every school, and give every child at least 1 hour per week of dedicated therapy time, and more for students who are troubled.

\- Allow students to take at least 1 hour of outdoor sports and recreation per day.  Getting exercise and sunshine is vital for us to feel happy as humans.

\- Teach students valuable life skills that they will need as adults.  Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed.  This may seem a bit off topic at first glance, but financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult.

In other words, school shouldn't just about math, reading, and science.  Spend time and effort developing kids as people and not only will they be healthier, they'll learn better too.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31015694885.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends 

Learning algebra isn't about memorizing formulas for life and being able to apply it at the snap of a finger.  Learning algebra is good because it causes your brain to think in ways it wouldn't otherwise, and it gets the brain used to critical thinking in a structured way.  The benefits of algebra extend beyond just doing math.  Every class in school is mainly geared toward doing that, but we also consider practical, real world goals and things people experience.  That's why most best practices exercise critical and executive thinking while imparting useful information for living in the modern world.

Mental health is important but you can't *teach* it.  Mental health is very personal.  You don't need an entire class dedicated to telling you to go for a walk.  Especially if it's school that makes it difficult to find time.  You don't need school to tell you to get more exercise - those lessons should be embedded in physical exercise.  There's nothing in a mental health class (and this is because you likened it to algebra) that shouldn't exist in a healthy school anyway.

* Keeping licensed therapists on staff is nice but costly, and most kids probably don't need therapy.  Rather, making therapy accessible outside school is a better option for everyone.  Education can't solve every issue, and I say that as an educator.
* Asking schools to give kids an hour of exercise per day can just be made into: school gets out 1 hour early.  Otherwise you're paying every staff member for kids not to be in class.  I agree that kids should have off periods but dictating what they do with it won't necessarily help.  If a kid is struggling in math, telling them to take a walk isn't what they need.
* It's a great idea to teach things like "managing finances", but that's covered in math anyway.  That's what finances are.  All my math classes had financial situations involve.  But then again, things change.  Finances change.  We can't really prepare everyone for everything.  Managing a check book, which we don't have anymore, is easy: you just write down what you spend.  It's basic addition.  Algebra is exactly what prepares you for things like functions and percentages.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
