<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593993382.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tnc86/cmv_schools_should_place_as_much_emphasis_on/">
    <title>CMV: Schools should place as much emphasis on developing children's mental health as they do on academic learning.</title>
    <original_poster>Starrcade87</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the goal of the education system should be to help children grow into healthy adults. 

Academic learning is good, but I would argue that it's actually less important than learning how to take care of yourself and your mental health.  For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends, but being mentally healthy is something that will serve us all our lives.

How should this be achieved?  I don't know exactly, but a few ideas:

\- Keep licensed therapists on staff at every school, and give every child at least 1 hour per week of dedicated therapy time, and more for students who are troubled.

\- Allow students to take at least 1 hour of outdoor sports and recreation per day.  Getting exercise and sunshine is vital for us to feel happy as humans.

\- Teach students valuable life skills that they will need as adults.  Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed.  This may seem a bit off topic at first glance, but financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult.

In other words, school shouldn't just about math, reading, and science.  Spend time and effort developing kids as people and not only will they be healthier, they'll learn better too.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31015279418.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>- the education system is to educate - not mental health.
I think the problem with todays students is they are too sensitive.  


- something strange is happening on America’s colleges and universities. A movement is arising, undirected and driven largely by students, to scrub campuses clean of words, ideas, and subjects that might cause discomfort or give offense. Greg Lukianoff  “The Coddling of the American Mind,” Lukianoff, a First Amendment lawyer and the president of the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education (fire), and Haidt, a social psychologist at New York University, observed that “in the name of emotional well-being, college students are increasingly demanding protection from words and ideas they don’t like,” and argued that capitulating to requests to banish certain ideas from classrooms and campus events would likely increase student anxiety and depression, rather than ameliorate it.

- In June, a professor protecting himself with a pseudonym wrote an essay for Vox describing how gingerly he now has to teach. “I’m a Liberal Professor, and My Liberal Students Terrify Me,” the headline said. A number of popular comedians, including Chris Rock, have stopped performing on college campuses Jerry Seinfeld and Bill Maher have publicly condemned the oversensitivity of college students, saying too many of them can’t take a joke.

- During the 2014–15 school year, for instance, the deans and department chairs at the 10 University of California system schools were presented by administrators at faculty leader-training sessions with examples of microaggressions. The list of offensive statements included: “America is the land of opportunity” and “I believe the most qualified person should get the job.”

- The current movement is largely about emotional well-being. More than the last, it presumes an extraordinary fragility of the collegiate psyche, and therefore elevates the goal of protecting students from psychological harm. The ultimate aim, it seems, is to turn campuses into “safe spaces” where young adults are shielded from words and ideas that make some uncomfortable. It is creating a culture in which everyone must think twice before speaking up, lest they face charges of insensitivity, aggression, or worse.

- There’s a saying common in education circles: Don’t teach students what to think; teach them how to think. The idea goes back at least as far as Socrates....But vindictive protectiveness teaches students to think in a very different way. It prepares them poorly for professional life, which often demands intellectual engagement with people and ideas one might find uncongenial or wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015305810.0" user="Starrcade87" delta="False">
    <text>I am arguing specifically about primary and secondary schooling, not universities.  Apologies for not clarifying that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015369157.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>- I believe this includes those in primary and secondary schooling as well - I believe it a generational thing and according to the authors I mentioned - this started with those born after 1995.

- from an article, 
Thanks to Helicopter Parents and The Self-Esteem Movement, Schools Have Banned Musical Chairs...Psychologists have been studying play behavior in children for a hundred years. The importance of play -- including rough-and-tumble play -- is undeniable. "But but but... What about their self-esteem?" well-meaning but misguided educators stammer.

Here's the thing:

​Aggression, competition and losing don't actually hurt a child's self-esteem. But they do teach children valuable coping and resilience skills.

- What do you expect them to do when they get to college if they've never even had the experience of controlling their emotions and navigating social situations during harmless games like Red Rover or Musical Chairs?

- This is what happens when parents and teachers make decisions in the name of “self-esteem” or “mental health” or “equity”... without actually doing any research about whether their feelings align with the facts.

- For example, lots of schools -- from elementary to secondary -- commit time, energy, and resources into "self-esteem" development in students. But the research shows that There is No Benefit to "Teaching" Self-Esteem, though it could cause long-term damage. 

- If that weren't bad enough, schools have taken several well-intentioned (but ultimately harmful) measures to "protect" students' self-esteem. For example, many schools have become anti-competition zones -- games with winners and losers are no longer acceptable, in spite of the fact that decades of psychology research show that competition is an important and healthy part of every child's development. 

- According to Roy F. Baumeister et al.'s 2003 meta-analysis, Does High Self-Esteem Cause Better Performance, Interpersonal Success, Happiness or Healthier Lifestyles,

No. There is no relationship between high self-worth and achievement. 

In fact, high self-regard is commonly found in narcissists, bullies and sociopaths. People with high, unwarranted self-esteem often have an inflated sense of popularity and likability. They get hostile when criticized or rejected. They alienate others.

- Stanford Professor Mark Lepper stated, "The people who understand motivation better than anyone else in the world... are people who make video games. We should listen to them."
Instead, parents and teachers listen to "feelings."

- Here's the thing about children: you can't insulate them from bad things forever. Eventually, they're going to run into problems you can't fix for them.

They're going to have to face a problem on their own. It's not if; it's when. And when the time comes, you want your child to have the emotional and cognitive maturity to turn a disappointment into a learning opportunity. 

- the best mental health is self
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015870685.0" user="IaniteThePirate" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be focusing on political correctness and people getting offended. But there's way more to mental health than that.

&amp;gt; the education system is to educate - not mental health. I think the problem with todays students is they are too sensitive. 

Just, for example, at my school. Even if you ignore all other mental health issues and anxieties, people are killing their mental health because we suck at dealing with stress. People have killed themselves over it.

We're put under a ton of pressure, told to take a lot of difficult classes, and overloaded with work. Then there's so much pressure to do well that people don't know how to deal with it. Learning new material for 8 different classes, managing several hours of homework each night, and all with the feeling that if you don't get it you're just worthless and stupid. And I'm guessing you're reading this and thinking that it's not *that* bad, because I don't have the words to accurately describe the feeling. But it's a lot.

And we don't really know how to deal with it and it's crushing us.

And that's ignoring the million other issues.

But let me state it again: multiple people at my school, and all across the country, have killed themselves because they didn't get help they needed.

I don't think OP's ideas are realistic, but I feel you're completely misinterpreting the point. Focusing on mental health doesn't mean everyone's a winner or whatever other crap you've brought up. For example, from the one semester of health class that we had to take, here are some topics that were briefly touched on:

- Maintaining healthy relationships

- Maintaining balance in your life

- Healthy vs Unhealthy stress, and what to do about it

- Signs of mental disorders and resources to seek help

- Ways to help a friend that is struggling

- Ways to resolve conflicts 

- Methods of communication (ex. passive, passive aggressive, assertive, and aggressive)

- How to calm yourself down if you're very upset

- Healthy decision making and goal setting

These were touched on very briefly in a class we had to take for one semester only.  I do believe having a required class that goes more in-depth would help a lot of students here. 

Like you said: 

&amp;gt; They're going to have to face a problem on their own. It's not if; it's when. And when the time comes, you want your child to have the emotional and cognitive maturity to turn a disappointment into a learning opportunity.

So why not give them the tools?


I don't know why you're under the impression that mental health = never facing disappointment. That's just plain wrong and an argument nobody is making.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31016061318.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>1. I understand the difficulties of school.  I worked full time and went to grad school.  my own personal experience is not evidence for anything but just to point out I understand the load.

2.  The whole purpose of school is for academics.  

3.  Your going to add another component which will distract from the schools primary mission - academics.

4.  there will be a cost component to this which raises tuition and students suffer.  Students are already under a mountain of debt and now some will not even have the opportunity to even get an education.

5.  The "crap" I brought up is why I am not understanding your connection between an academic institution and mental health facility.

- Maintaining balance in your life is not the mission of an academic institution.  How would one even begin to teach this to students from various economic situations?  All of this comes from just living life, making mistakes.  There are various outlets one could take to improve oneself such as courses on line - seminars - etc.  https://www.studyinternational.com/news/how-to-maintain-your-life-study-balance-at-university/

- Healthy vs Unhealthy stress, and what to do about it.  Not the job of an academic institution. They have these things called doctors and with Obama Care - you could get this information.

- Signs of mental disorders and resources to seek help. Not the job of an academic institution. 
 maybe try this advice: http://www.mentalhealthamerica.net/conditions/finding-help-when-get-it-and-where-go

- Ways to help a friend that is struggling, again, is not the core mission of academics.  maybe try this: http://www.mentalhealthamerica.net/conditions/finding-help-when-get-it-and-where-go or you may need to try this: https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/  it is highly individualistic but not the responsibility of academics

- Ways to resolve conflicts.    try this: https://www.helpguide.org/articles/relationships-communication/conflict-resolution-skills.htm

-Methods of communication (ex. passive, passive aggressive, assertive, and aggressive).  You can take psychology courses, sociology courses and yes, there is communication classes.  If you want to talk to a counselor - that is not the purpose of academics

- How to calm yourself down if you're very upset - again, highly individual.  have you tried smoking pot?

- Healthy decision making and goal setting - highly individual but try this: https://www.msuextension.org/health/documents/MT199011HR.pdf

You could also take health classes, seminars, go to a library and get a self help book.  All of these actions are what school is trying to teach you in the first place.  Learn to get answers yourself and know where to go to get those answers.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31016131651.0" user="IaniteThePirate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The whole purpose of school is for academics

The purpose of school is to learn important skills and knowledge. This includes skills such as managing stress and balancing your work. 

Additionally, kids learn more effectively when they have a good mental-state. It is much harder to focus on a class when you're overwhelmed with other issues. 

&amp;gt; there will be a cost component 

Not necessarily.  Hell, you could literally just extend health class to last a full year and spend more time focusing on mental health. That's not going to cost any school a significant amount of money. 

&amp;gt; to this which raises tuition and students suffer. 

So maybe you missed the part where OP said (in a direct reply to you), " am arguing specifically about primary and secondary schooling, not universities." 

This is not about college or universities. My comment was focusing on high schools. There is no tuition required for high school.

 &amp;gt;Students are already under a mountain of debt and now some will not even have the opportunity to even get an education.

Again, that doesn't apply at all to high school, does it? And even with a university, I would be highly skeptical of a claim that adding one new class raises the cost of tuition. Or do you mean to tell me they never add new classes anywhere? Or that every time they do it raises the cost significantly enough that students can't afford it? Due to one class?

&amp;gt; The "crap" I brought up is why I am not understanding your connection between an academic institution and mental health facility.

I'm not understanding what you're saying at all. In your first comment (that I saw) you were talking about how students were too sensitive and safe spaces are dumb and shit. Which is not something I feel like getting into an argument about. Then OP said they weren't talking about universities, and you changed your argument to schools never letting kids compete or fail. 

Neither of which are what focusing on mental health means. 

&amp;gt; Maintaining balance in your life is not the mission of an academic institution. 

I'm sensing that you think school should be 100% work and that students should never be taught other important skills? Even skills that allow them to do better in school?

&amp;gt;How would one even begin to teach this to students from various economic situations? 

Same principle for everyone. Plan ahead,manage your time, set aside time to relax, when possible. Prioritize tasks, recognize when the most productive thing to do is to take a break. Things like that.

&amp;gt;You could also take health classes, seminars, go to a library and get a self help book. 

 I feel you're missing the point, then. Sure, you can find all this information in books or online, but is that not true of everything you learn in school? You're also forgetting the benefits of having kids sit down in class, and discuss it. It forces kids who would normally think this stuff is dumb or uncool to sit down and at least think about it. It opens up discussion and leads to deeper thoughts. 

And mental health is very, very important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31016283310.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>- Regardless of problems in even basic areas like reading and mathematics, which study after study continue to show schools are not doing well, our educational institutions have moved on to other concerns. Not only do schools continue to add free meal programs to their institutional menus, but employment services, physical and mental health services, environmental initiatives, and now diversity programs  have been added to a growing list of non-academic initiatives. These kinds of programs certainly have value, but their role in an institution whose purpose is inherently academic has a cost....With schools so over-committed on things that have traditionally not been a part of their academic mission, a new poll of American attitudes toward public schools commissioned by Phi Delta Kappa is instructive. It shows that, while schools are increasingly confused about their purpose, most Americans know what schools are for....What do you think should be the main goal of a public school education: to prepare students academically, to prepare them for work, or to prepare them to be good citizens?”....The net result is that most parents of school children think academic instruction is the purpose of schools. That’s an important finding in an educational world where the purpose of schools has become a playground for non-academic interests. 
https://classicallatin.org/most-parents-of-school-children-think-academics-is-the-purpose-of-schools-survey-finds/

in summary - the real world does not give a shit about your mental state.  School is for academics - if you cant handle the load in school because of other issues, then stop and deal with your shit until your ready to go back to school and focus on the academics.  too stress - take fewer classes.

- you want to learn about life, then live it , make mistakes, learn. school will only give you knowledge - using that knowledge, applying it you gain wisdom.

- in high school, I took home economics, learned to balance a check book and other basic life skills.  If I had issues, I went to a school counselor but if I needed serious mental health help,, then that was up to my parents to see after.  

- School will not teach you the things you are describing - life does</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31016347264.0" user="IaniteThePirate" delta="False">
    <text>If you're going to copy/paste instead of forming your own argument, at least choose a reliable source. The page you linked had no source attached to it. Who was surveyed for this poll? How many people, and how were they selected? Adding to that, the website it's on is trying to get people and schools to pay money for a specific curriculum they sell. 



&amp;gt; the real world does not give a shit about your mental state. 

No shit? Which is why it's important to have the skills to manage your mental and emotional health. 

&amp;gt; School is for academics 

What do you define as academics then? Does gym class count? Health class? Home economics? 

If they count, then  why shouldn't a class such as this count as well?

If they don't count, should they be removed?

&amp;gt;  school will only give you knowledge

School gives you understanding of how and why things work. It helps you build the skills to solve problems you encounter. It teaches you how to think logically about things. If all you're getting out of school is knowledge, you're doing something wrong.


&amp;gt; if you cant handle the load in school because of other issues, then stop and deal with your shit until your ready to go back to school and focus...take fewer classes.


As I've said, multiple times, we are discussing high school. You can not just stop going to high school. You do not have the option in high school to take fewer classes either. That is not how high school works. 

&amp;gt;in high school, I took home economics, learned to balance a check book and other basic life skills

Does maintaining your mental health not count as a basic life skill?

&amp;gt; I went to a school counselor but if I needed serious mental health help,, then that was up to my parents to see after.

Not everyone has parents who are willing or able to take their kid for help. Additionally, why not give students the tools to manage their own mental health as much as they can? Some things you can't do on your own, but plenty of stuff can be. Such as everything I listed in my previous comment.

&amp;gt; School will not teach you the things you are describing - life does

Nobody is arguing that school does. The argument is that school should. And you have not provided me with one reason it shouldn't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017578111.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>- if you went to school and learned something then you know your argument about my source is a logical fallacy - Ad hominem

- a school is not here to teach you basic life skills - it is for academics.  basic life skills are individual learning by living life.  you can teach things like economics or cooking skills or how to balance a check book in school which will prepare you for those things in life that can make you successful


- you are not going to teach a high school student about mental health and somehow thats going to make everything better for them.  mental health is long process and requires dedicated professionals who have time to focus on the individual issues.

- because mental health requires professionals to address a highly individual and specific mental health issue.  schools are not the right outlet for that or are they equipped or trained for that.  I have friends who are high school teachers and though they are great teachers they are not mental health professionals

- the only alternative is to hire mental health professionals which do add a cost to tax payers and it would be limited so the student thinks they are getting the attention they need but the school wont be able to provide it. 

- it is not the responsibility or the mission of a school to provide mental health.  Im not saying mental health is not important or there are not solutions to getting treatment but mental health and academics are apples and oranges, they dont belong together and they actually distract from each other and both become ineffective if you try to put them all in one basket. There just is not enough band width for a school to be all the things an individual requires....mental health, a parent figure, a nanny, a place to get hugs. 

-  Im sure schools in a rich area could provide this but if the parents are rich, they will already have the resources to provide their own personal health care to their child.  Poorer schools are fighting for resources and many teachers who dont get paid shit have to buy their own pens and papers.  some teachers buy meals for their students.  Teachers cant even afford their own basics in life because the schools dont pay them enough.  You cannot maintain quality teachers if they cant afford to make a living...you then get the low cost teacher who is ineffective but that is all the school district can afford.  

- you want to add mental health service to a school district when they cant even afford their own teachers which distracts from the mission of academics.  students are failing in academics so hey, lets shift resources to mental health and say fuck it, students dont need academics they need a psychologist.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31017825441.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>Im going to try to explain this in another way:

-	Mental health is a clear need for every individual on this planet.  Academics is not a need of every individual on the planet in terms of survival.  The question is if an academic institution is responsible for this need and my argument is no.  Academic pursuits are a higher need of individuals but it is not in the same category as a mental need.
-	I agree that in order to achieve academic success you will need to have mental stability but it goes back to the question, is this the responsibility of an academic institution?  My response is clearly not
-	If I compared my academic success to another individual, lets say a girl in Afghanistan who would be killed if she did get an education, then I clearly have an advantage.  I could achieve my higher need of academic success because my lower needs were met.  The question for the girl in Afghanstin girl would still be the same – is the school responsible for her academic opportunities by providing her with needs such as physiological needs, safety needs, social needs?
-	I look at all this through Maslow’s hierarchy of needs when I come to the conclusion that a school cannot possibly be responsible for all the needs of an individual in order for that individual to become successful.  They play a narrow mission in the success of an individual’s academic pursuits but they are no substitute for other institutions to satisfy the other needs of an individual
-	I included an explanation of Maslows hierarchy below:
-	Maslow's hierarchy of needs is a theory in psychology proposed by Abraham Maslow.  His theories parallel many other theories of human developmental psychology, some of which focus on describing the stages of growth in humans.a classification system which reflected the universal needs of society as its base and then proceeding to more acquired emotions[3]. Maslow’s hierarchy of needs is used to study how humans partake in behavioral motivation intrinsically. Maslow used the terms "physiological," "safety," "belonging and love," "esteem," and "self-actualization" to describe the pattern through which human motivations generally move. This means that in order for motivation to occur at the next level, each level must be satisfied within the individual themselves.
-	Furthermore, this theory is a key foundation in understanding how drive and motivation are correlated when discussing human behavior. Each of these individual levels contains a certain amount of internal sensation that must be met in order for an individual to complete their hierarchy[3].The goal of Maslow's Theory is to attain the fifth level or stage: self-actualization.[4]
-	Physiological needs:  (Homeostasis, Food, Water, Sleep, Shelter) Physiological needs are considered the main physical requirements for human survival. This means that Physiological needs are universal human needs. Physiological needs are considered the first step in internal motivation 
-	Safety needs: ( Personal security, Financial security, Health and well-being, Safety needs against accidents/illness and their adverse impacts)  In the absence of physical safety – due to war, natural disaster, family violence, childhood abuse, etc. – people may (re-)experience post-traumatic stress disorder or transgenerational trauma. In the absence of economic safety – due to economic crisis and lack of work opportunities – these safety needs manifest themselves in ways such as a preference for job security, grievance procedures for protecting the individual from unilateral authority, savings accounts, insurance policies, disability accommodations, etc. This level is more likely to predominate in children as they generally have a greater need to feel safe. Safety and security needs are about keeping us safe from harm. These include shelter, job security, health, and safe environments. If a person does not feel safe in an environment, they will seek to find safety before they attempt to meet any higher level of survival,
-	Social belonging:( Friendships, Intimacy, Family) the third level of human needs are seen to be interpersonal and involves feelings of belongingness. This need is especially strong in childhood and it can override the need for safety as witnessed in children who cling to abusive parents. Deficiencies within this level of Maslow's hierarchy – due to hospitalism, neglect, shunning, ostracism, etc. – can adversely affect the individual's ability to form and maintain emotionally significant relationships in general.
-	Esteem Esteem needs are ego needs or status needs. People develop a concern with getting recognition, status, importance, and respect from others. Most humans have a need to feel respected; this includes the need to have self-esteem and self-respect. Esteem presents the typical human desire to be accepted and valued by others. People often engage in a profession or hobby to gain recognition. These activities give the person a sense of contribution or value. Low self-esteem or an inferiority complex may result from imbalances during this level in the hierarchy. People with low self-esteem often need respect from others; they may feel the need to seek fame or glory. However, fame or glory will not help the person to build their self-esteem until they accept who they are internally. Psychological imbalances such as depression can distract the person from obtaining a higher level of self-esteem.
-	Self-actualization  (Mate Acquisition, Parenting, Utilizing Abilities, Utilizing Talents, Pursuing a goal, Seeking Happiness) "What a man can be, he must be."[5]:91 This quotation forms the basis of the perceived need for self-actualization. This level of need refers to what a person's full potential is and the realization of that potential. Maslow describes this level as the desire to accomplish everything that one can, to become the most that one can be.[5]:92 Individuals may perceive or focus on this need very specifically. For example, one individual may have the strong desire to become an ideal parent. In another, the desire may be expressed athletically. For others, it may be expressed in paintings, pictures, or inventions
-	Self-transcendence- In his later years, Abraham Maslow explored a further dimension of motivation, while criticizing his original vision of self-actualization.[9][10][11][12] By this later theory, one finds fullest realization in giving oneself to something beyond oneself — for example, in altruism or spirituality. He equated this with the desire to reach the infinite.[13] "Transcendence refers to the very highest and most inclusive or holistic levels of human consciousness, behaving and relating, as ends rather than means, to oneself, to significant others, to human beings in general, to other species, to nature, and to the cosmos"
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31019927904.0" user="IaniteThePirate" delta="False">
    <text>So I wasn't going to bother replying at all because you keep repeating the same things over and over without acknowledging anything I've said, and it's clear that continuing would be a waste of time.

But this:



&amp;gt; if you went to school and learned something then you know your argument about my source is a logical fallacy - Ad hominem

has been bothering me all day. You're the one who doesn't seem to know what fallacies are. Ad hominem would be something like if I pointed out all your grammar mistakes and called you uneducated and refused to engage with you. 

You copy/pasted a source instead of thinking for yourself. When I went to investigate that source it was pretty clearly bullshit. Pointing out an unreliable source is not ad hominem. If you want to get into fallacies, look up what an appeal to false authority is. 

I'm sure this reply accomplishes nothing, but I just thought I'd let you know. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31020978844.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>all you have done is comment on my source without commenting on what it said.  The source is valid.  Ad hominem (Latin for "to the person"), short for argumentum ad hominem, is a fallacious argumentative strategy whereby genuine discussion of the topic at hand is avoided by instead attacking the character, motive, or other attribute of the person making the argument, or persons associated with the argument
-  I completely agree with you that mental health will sabotage an education - 
- your original question has nothing to do with mental health but who is responsible for providing it.
- There are many institutions available to handle mental health which have the expertise.  Academia does not have the expertise to handle this and if they tried it would never be able to meet the actual needs of each individual but would also add a huge cost.
beyond that, it is not their mission to provide mental health.
- if you want to have a discussion with only those that agree with you then I am not that person</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31021040393.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>I dont want you to feel Im dismissing you so maybe we need to start with a definition of academics
1. adjective [ADJ n]
Academic is used to describe things that relate to the work done in schools, colleges, and universities, especially work that involves studying and reasoning rather than practical or technical skills.
- Academics is about knowledge - studying a certain topic to develop the knowledge base on a topic and build on that knowledge.  When you go through high school and college - you are learning what came before - the current knowledge.  When you go to graduate school you are studying the latest research and building on that knowledge.

so to answer your question, is gym class academic - yes it is.  it is teaching knowledge of that topic. you can go to college and do research and build on that.  you could study sports medicine for example.
- According to Nietzsche, history could inspire us to emulate certain deeds. we could study the lives of great individuals for guidance on how to shape our character or else read history as a compendium of mistakes we should avoid, or as a way of bolstering our sense of identity through an understanding of our origins.
- </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
