<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="597970490.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9w0kze/cmv_bernie_is_almost_as_militarily_hawkish_as/">
    <title>Cmv: Bernie is almost as militarily hawkish as Hillary Clinton.</title>
    <original_poster>eminemski</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to start this off by saying that I was a huge Bernie supporter till about a week ago when I saw his voting history. I believe that, though he voted against the Iraq war, he voted to invade Afghanistan, and he voted for a bill that funds war in the middle East. He also admits to funding four different annual war spending bills over the past 15-20 years. He gave lots of rhetoric which I appreciate about ending the wars in 2016, and aiding war torn countries. Please change my view because I was so hyped for Bernie in 2020, but now I don't see how I can vote for someone who voted for bills that might kill more people than they save. 

Thanks!!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31051926493.0" user="FNNeocon" delta="False">
    <text>Afghanistan was the morally justifiable war that we had no chance in hell of winning and iraq was the victorious war that we are damned to hell for starting.

The rip on Afghanistan War is not that it wasn't morally justified. It was. Obama called it "The Good war" although Obama may be too far right from for you with what you've written. The Taliban was an Islamo-Fascist regime that ruled by strict traditional laws like jailing people for owning a television, not having a long enough beard, teaching women how to read and taking them to school. If a regime like that rose in the USA by a hardcore religious Fascists you would want another country to topple that government. 

The Taliban was not the legitimate government of Afghanistan. Afghanistan hasn't had a legitimate government since the Soviets invaded. It has been in a constant state of civil war. in 2001, we immediately sided with one side of the civil war, the Northern Alliance and we swept them to victory. However, instead of letting the Northern Alliance run the country we forced them to disband and we appointed Hamid Karzai, a tribal leader, as their leader and moved the country towards democracy. Woman can now read, go to school and even serve in parliament. The Taliban was an islamo-Fascist regime. The US did not start a war in Afghanistan, we intervened in a civil war.

We had every right to intervene. To protect the human rights of minorities and women. To respond to a declaration of war by Al Qaeda.

The vast majority of civilian deaths aren't even from US soldiers, it is from the Taliban who brutally repress those in the territory they hold.

The problem with Afghanistan is that the war CANNOT be won and we couldn't have known that in 2001.

For completeness sake, i will explain how we won the Iraq war. The iraqi constitution that was voted on in 2005 which was drafted by a parliament elected in 2004 is still in place. It took 2 years for South Vietnam to fall after US troops left but Iraq is still holding on after 7 years of no US troops on the ground.   


Why did South Vietnam fall but Iraq still holds on? For 1 reason, the terrorists in Iraq were hardcore fighters trained by the Taliban and everywhere they held territory in Iraq they enforced harsh religious codes. The largest organization in iraq was literally called "Al Qaeda in Iraq" which later turned into ISIS. 

Iraq is just not Afghanistan. Afghanistan is an incredibly rural, religiously backwards, highly conservative country. Iraq is far more urban and had a history of secularism under Saddam Hussien and that didn't disappear the day Saddam died. Iraq was a secular country and it rejected the increasingly dogmatic foreign elements of the insurgency.

It is inaccurate to compare South Vietnam to Afghanistan as US troops have not left Afghanistan yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053199142.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Well no. Afghanistan residents were innocent and still killed by the invasion probably. Why is there a difference between invading Afghanistan and Iraq if innocent people die in both? Both were run by evil people</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
