<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="597970490.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9w0kze/cmv_bernie_is_almost_as_militarily_hawkish_as/">
    <title>Cmv: Bernie is almost as militarily hawkish as Hillary Clinton.</title>
    <original_poster>eminemski</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to start this off by saying that I was a huge Bernie supporter till about a week ago when I saw his voting history. I believe that, though he voted against the Iraq war, he voted to invade Afghanistan, and he voted for a bill that funds war in the middle East. He also admits to funding four different annual war spending bills over the past 15-20 years. He gave lots of rhetoric which I appreciate about ending the wars in 2016, and aiding war torn countries. Please change my view because I was so hyped for Bernie in 2020, but now I don't see how I can vote for someone who voted for bills that might kill more people than they save. 

Thanks!!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31047084370.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047123349.0" user="hamsterbeef" delta="False">
    <text>The USSR experienced an enormous rise in standards of living under a planned economy, and perestroika resulted in an enormous loss in life expectancy comparable to an active invasion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047130642.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think of the Solzhenitsyn foundation's estimate that they killed 63 million people and the KGB admitting to it being at least 45 million?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047145271.0" user="hamsterbeef" delta="False">
    <text>I think that the The Gulag Archipelago is largely a discredited book, and I wonder how the KGB managed to kill 45 million people given that most of the hardcore mass murder was done prior to its foundation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047153507.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>And the deaths under Mao's great leap forward?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047159345.0" user="hamsterbeef" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that it conclusively proved that Mao didn't know shit about agriculture, and that we should really respect birds more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047172180.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>So do you think central planning could work if we only had the right plan?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047189521.0" user="hamsterbeef" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that an honest assessment and comparison of planned economies versus free markets, should at least take into account the devastation caused by liberalisation of markets, and number the famines and disasters of non-planned economies too before a judgement is made.

It seems unfair to count every single death by famine as being an inherent problem of planned economies, while ignoring the deaths caused by famines in capitalist systems, or by capitalist exploitation of client states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047194790.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>You already explained Mao's role in the famine. Are you changing that now to say his policies weren't directly responsible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047209469.0" user="hamsterbeef" delta="False">
    <text>Mao killing sparrows combined with making peasants make pig iron undoubtedly exacerbated the death toll by quite a large margin, I have never said otherwise.
But what I *am* saying is that if we do count that as a problem of planned economies, we should equally count famines that occur under non-planned economies and capitalist systems as failures of those particular systems. 

And by that metric, the Great Chinese famine under Mao stands out significantly less, and is also the *last* Chinese famine. Where previously it was not uncommon for there to be *several* every century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047218824.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>I'm happy to look at whatever data you are alluding to. What famines under capitalism are you referring to that caused tens of millions of deaths?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047276431.0" user="hamsterbeef" delta="False">
    <text>The persian famine during WW1 caused somewhere from 2 to 10 million deaths, which is a larger percentage o the Iranian population than died during the great Chinese famine. This famine was partly caused by profiteering and occupation by capitalist powers.

The famines of China in the 19th century had a death toll exceeding that of even the highest estimates of Mao's great leap forward^^1 (And while China at the time could not be said to have a truly capitalist economy, it establishes a pattern of famines unconnected to planned economies), the famines in China in the 1920-30s happened under the KMT who were attempting market liberalisation and killed about a dozen million Chinese in total.

The famines in the British Raj in around 1900 were the direct result of British economic policies and killed millions of indians, the bengal famine in the 1940s were once again the fault of British policies, Great Bengal famine of 1770 killed a third of Bengalis according to some sources and was *once again* the fault of British economic policies.

I could point you to more cases of mass starvation, but frankly the subject is depressing and the point is already made. People have starved both before and after planned economies.

1:I think it's about equal with Frank Dikötter. But frankly he can fuck right off as he claimed that the unequal treaties and the opium wars were actually good for China, and as such can be safely ignored for cogent analysis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047336971.0" user="torrasque666" delta="False">
    <text>Are you familiar with the history of socialism in places like Norway and Iceland? Because that was what Bernie was leaning towards. Societal support, not planned economies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047357929.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>I am familiar. Sweden specifically was on the brink in their central planning and had to re-privatize many of their industries including their health care and education systems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047715448.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ItsPandatory – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+ItsPandatory&amp;amp;message=ItsPandatory+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9w0kze/-/e9gmrma/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
