<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="606775187.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a19aqb/cmv_if_a_guy_has_trouble_dating_until_his_30s_he/">
    <title>CMV: If a guy has trouble dating until his 30s, he should avoid romantic relationships altogether in his later life</title>
    <original_poster>uniklas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry if this is post is guy centric, but if you feel this applies to women in some way, please include them too. 

I've seen it a few times, a guy for whatever reason is completely non existant to women in his 20s (mostly a combination of shyness and about average looks), he is the kind of guy that *wants* a relationship (like most of the people out there) and grows more desperate by the year. Then his 30s come and suddenly women start noticing him, he gets into a relationship, and then settles for the first woman he has ever been with in a long long time. The woman turns out to be trash of a human being, but the guy thinks he is so lucky to have found someone and she is the best he will ever get so he stays together for 10 or more years. Basically he settles for the first gal that has showed him some interest maybe ever.

I believe a guy like this would be happier if he would never date anyone ever, since he hasn't developed the skills necessary to screen people properly and will most likely fall prey to a woman that is a terrible human being.

Why do I think he will necessarily fall for this kind of a woman as there are plenty of nice 30 something or whatever somethings women out there? There are plenty of formerly young and pretty and shallow women who have got together with rich and shallow men in their 20s, men who have stayed rich and shallow, but women have stayed young and pretty, so they have parted their ways. These women, understandablly, go desperate pretty fast and figure they won't find anyone rich to care for them anymore, so they reduce and reduce their expecations until we get to the level of maybe well of single guys, and who is easier than the guy who won't even try to court anyone anymore? Give him some attention and he is yours to keep.

All is well and good, if she is a decent enough person, but chances are that someone who has been pampered with expensive material things from a young age up until then will not find joy in anything less than she had before and often times the guy will not be able/struggle to hold her to her standarts of living.

So to repeat myself a bit. It is great if a guy like this finds a girl he matches with later in life, but the odds are he won't, as he just doesn't have the skills necessary to do so. He is overwhelmingly more likely to be snatched by someone who has nothing to them except past beauty and he being as unexperienced as he is will think this is all there is to it and will settle for it.

I believe a guy like this would be way happier and even happy overall if he just got to terms that he ought to stay single forever and just work on his platonic relationships or whatever that truly gives him joy and meaning in life.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31122464437.0" user="thelawlessatlas" delta="False">
    <text>While there isn't much worth arguing in your chain of logic, there is something wrong with your initial assertion that the type of man you describe *should* avoid romantic relations - that he would be "way happier" by doing so. Your argument either simply ignores, or implicitly rejects, the idea that finding a life-long companion adds an inestimable value to one's life. There's also a reasonable amount of scientific evidence that humans are wired to seek such a relationship and not finding one lowers the viable threshold of overall happiness. Given this, how is can anyone be "way happier" by giving up on their search? Even if the outcomes you describe are highly likely, why do they make not trying something those men "should" do? I feel like you can't substantiate your position without addressing these ideas....</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
