<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="606775187.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a19aqb/cmv_if_a_guy_has_trouble_dating_until_his_30s_he/">
    <title>CMV: If a guy has trouble dating until his 30s, he should avoid romantic relationships altogether in his later life</title>
    <original_poster>uniklas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry if this is post is guy centric, but if you feel this applies to women in some way, please include them too. 

I've seen it a few times, a guy for whatever reason is completely non existant to women in his 20s (mostly a combination of shyness and about average looks), he is the kind of guy that *wants* a relationship (like most of the people out there) and grows more desperate by the year. Then his 30s come and suddenly women start noticing him, he gets into a relationship, and then settles for the first woman he has ever been with in a long long time. The woman turns out to be trash of a human being, but the guy thinks he is so lucky to have found someone and she is the best he will ever get so he stays together for 10 or more years. Basically he settles for the first gal that has showed him some interest maybe ever.

I believe a guy like this would be happier if he would never date anyone ever, since he hasn't developed the skills necessary to screen people properly and will most likely fall prey to a woman that is a terrible human being.

Why do I think he will necessarily fall for this kind of a woman as there are plenty of nice 30 something or whatever somethings women out there? There are plenty of formerly young and pretty and shallow women who have got together with rich and shallow men in their 20s, men who have stayed rich and shallow, but women have stayed young and pretty, so they have parted their ways. These women, understandablly, go desperate pretty fast and figure they won't find anyone rich to care for them anymore, so they reduce and reduce their expecations until we get to the level of maybe well of single guys, and who is easier than the guy who won't even try to court anyone anymore? Give him some attention and he is yours to keep.

All is well and good, if she is a decent enough person, but chances are that someone who has been pampered with expensive material things from a young age up until then will not find joy in anything less than she had before and often times the guy will not be able/struggle to hold her to her standarts of living.

So to repeat myself a bit. It is great if a guy like this finds a girl he matches with later in life, but the odds are he won't, as he just doesn't have the skills necessary to do so. He is overwhelmingly more likely to be snatched by someone who has nothing to them except past beauty and he being as unexperienced as he is will think this is all there is to it and will settle for it.

I believe a guy like this would be way happier and even happy overall if he just got to terms that he ought to stay single forever and just work on his platonic relationships or whatever that truly gives him joy and meaning in life.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31119599124.0" user="HeWhoShitsWithPhone" delta="False">
    <text>Even if we accept all your clames, the advice we should give is to be comfortable being single and to learn to tell the difference between someone you would want to have a relationship and not. What is to gain by not still looking for a potential partner, as long as you do it in a reserved mannor?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119739101.0" user="uniklas" delta="False">
    <text>This is what I am saying, how likely is someone who has never had any sort (or very little) of romantic attachment in his life be willing to close contact with someone who is in his view probably his only chance.

How do you get from a state of mind of:

1. I'll be single forever, would have been nice to have someone, still I think if I concentrate on myself I'll live a decent life.

2. Holy shit, she actually want's to be with me?? I haven't had anyone interested in my in X number for years, and it probably wont ever happen again.

To this: I think it is possible for me to find someone who is actually good for me, even if I haven't got any luck in the past I think something has changed.

How do you get from a state of mind that shit, she is my only hope, to she actually isn't, I'm better of without her. Maybe it is hard for people to see, but it is no trivial task to prove this to yourself, as often times that particular relationship might not be unberable (no overwhelming violence of any kind, just unmatched expectations, low key manipulations and unending guild trips), it might just be toxic, but it still feels good about being with *someone*, who would leave that thinking they will never find anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
