<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="606775187.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a19aqb/cmv_if_a_guy_has_trouble_dating_until_his_30s_he/">
    <title>CMV: If a guy has trouble dating until his 30s, he should avoid romantic relationships altogether in his later life</title>
    <original_poster>uniklas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry if this is post is guy centric, but if you feel this applies to women in some way, please include them too. 

I've seen it a few times, a guy for whatever reason is completely non existant to women in his 20s (mostly a combination of shyness and about average looks), he is the kind of guy that *wants* a relationship (like most of the people out there) and grows more desperate by the year. Then his 30s come and suddenly women start noticing him, he gets into a relationship, and then settles for the first woman he has ever been with in a long long time. The woman turns out to be trash of a human being, but the guy thinks he is so lucky to have found someone and she is the best he will ever get so he stays together for 10 or more years. Basically he settles for the first gal that has showed him some interest maybe ever.

I believe a guy like this would be happier if he would never date anyone ever, since he hasn't developed the skills necessary to screen people properly and will most likely fall prey to a woman that is a terrible human being.

Why do I think he will necessarily fall for this kind of a woman as there are plenty of nice 30 something or whatever somethings women out there? There are plenty of formerly young and pretty and shallow women who have got together with rich and shallow men in their 20s, men who have stayed rich and shallow, but women have stayed young and pretty, so they have parted their ways. These women, understandablly, go desperate pretty fast and figure they won't find anyone rich to care for them anymore, so they reduce and reduce their expecations until we get to the level of maybe well of single guys, and who is easier than the guy who won't even try to court anyone anymore? Give him some attention and he is yours to keep.

All is well and good, if she is a decent enough person, but chances are that someone who has been pampered with expensive material things from a young age up until then will not find joy in anything less than she had before and often times the guy will not be able/struggle to hold her to her standarts of living.

So to repeat myself a bit. It is great if a guy like this finds a girl he matches with later in life, but the odds are he won't, as he just doesn't have the skills necessary to do so. He is overwhelmingly more likely to be snatched by someone who has nothing to them except past beauty and he being as unexperienced as he is will think this is all there is to it and will settle for it.

I believe a guy like this would be way happier and even happy overall if he just got to terms that he ought to stay single forever and just work on his platonic relationships or whatever that truly gives him joy and meaning in life.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31119650375.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and will most likely fall prey to a horrible human being

How are you calculating this?

For this to be true, wouldn't it need to be true that *most* people are horrible human beings?

If only 10% are horrible, it'd seem has chances are better than average to *not* get a horrible person, wouldn't they?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119660757.0" user="alaricus" delta="False">
    <text>I would imagine that a majority of human beings are horrible, but I'm not sure that it would make OPs theory impossible even if it weren't the case, as the population of single men over 30 are a minority, they would only require an or lesser number (because their awful partners could affect more than one "victim") than the population of single over 30 men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119666539.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I would imagine that a majority of human beings are horrible

Why would you?

That seems demonstrably false, so I'm curious where you are getting this?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119679002.0" user="alaricus" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have studies or anything. Just anecdotal observation. By and large, humanity seems pretty intent on hurting everything it can except for their close friends (if they even have that much compassion.) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119707992.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't every country have near 100% crime rates and half the population killing the other half, etc. if almost every single person was a horrible human.

Would horrible people have children, and would they care for them if they did?

Shouldn't we see nearly all children being beaten and malnourished?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119701013.0" user="uniklas" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that even 10% are horrible. I'm saying that horrible women are overwhelmingly more likely to go after / get luck with guys that have got discouraged from even trying over the years.

Guy is doing whatever, the chick somehow starts up a chat. If it's an average guy, he will soon see her for who she is and not entertain her further, our unexperienced guy will see this as a chance and if it goes far enough get burned.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119742299.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>But you are saying that's the most likely scenario, right?

If horrible people are outnumbered more than 10 to 1 by non-horribles, then how can that be *more* likely?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119828282.0" user="uniklas" delta="False">
    <text>I can't provide any real numbers, so I hope that *in principal* explanation will seem logical to you.

Imagine having 50 guys and 50 girls. Let's say that if a guy goes after a girl he has a fixed 4% (can be any number you like) chance to get on with that particular girl, and he goes after lets say 5 girls in that particular time frame. All the girls stay passive, and only get aproached. So he has (1-(1-0.04)^5)% chance to find a mate, which works out at around 18.5% in this case.

Now let's say there are a few women who also go the guy way and start aproaching, so basically they can get twice the interactions in the same timeframe, doubling their chances.

(I'm not sure why I decided to include numbers, seemed fun for me to do, sorry if you find it untasteful)

Now of course this model isn't any good, real social interactions aren't as simple, but I hope you can see my point. Desperate people (horrible women in this case) will use a shotgun aproach, they will go after as many people as possible to increase their chances. Average guys will see them for who they are and turn them down, but the guys who don't do any of the approaching themselves will view this as a once in a lifetime opportunity, as in reality, how often do women actually aproach? Never happened to me personally in my 23 years of life, but you know, I'm sure it happens *sometimes*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119859506.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>So, to be clear- your entire view is predicated on the idea that ending up with a horrible woman is the only realistic possibility if they forego being alone forever, but you now admit you don't actually know that to be true, and can't actually defend that statement at all?

If your theory is based on a premise you can't support, should you still hold to that theory?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119918611.0" user="uniklas" delta="False">
    <text>I believe it is rational to believe something you have learned from your experience.

I believe it is rational to think that if you have tried enough without any luck to think there is an abysmal chance being there.

I think it is rational to start to live a life in an assumption of being single forever, and just for the sake of your own peace of mind start to be contempt with it.

I think it is rational that by winning something (a chance with a woman in this case) that you thought had a near 0 chance before, and it being something you want in general, you won't throw this fluke of an opportunity (in this particular view) away.

What my view stands on is I think it is actually *better* to throw these kinds of chances away as there is a big chance that the person that you have "won" is actually bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119951683.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What my view stands on is I think it is actually better to throw these kinds of chances away as there is a big chance that the person that you have "won" is actually bad.

You just said the same thing - you *think* there is a big chance that the 'prize' is rotten- but you can't explain how you think that or why anyone else *should* think that.

Again, your entire theory rests on this point- a point you have admitted to having no good reason to believe is *actually true.*

*Should* people hold to beliefs that are based on things that they can't support ?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31120045491.0" user="uniklas" delta="False">
    <text>You are trying to point out that my belief is wrong because it is a belief. And of course I wouldn't be here if I had some kind of data that had concrete evidence one way or the other.

What I have is my reasoning which I have done to the best of my abilities and I am openly asking people to poke holes in it.

I think it impossible to have a solid support for every view one has, but what is neccesarry is to have an oppinion based on reason and the information you have, also it is important to have an open mind to change your view if the evidence or support sways in other direction.

So to say it again, it is a view, I have explained my reasoning, am asking where did I fault it as in all honesty I don't want to believe this as it eats at me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31120098693.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;am asking where did I fault it as in all honesty I don't want to believe this as it eats at me.

I've told you twice- you have an error in logic right where you are suggesting the 'evil harpy' ending is more likely, or even likely, because you have no good reason to believe that to be true.


If that isn't true, and ending up with a evil hag is only one of several possible endings, the entirety of your argument falls to shambles .

You absolutely shouldn't believe this to be true based on the arguments you've made.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119705488.0" user="PerfectlyHappyAlone" delta="False">
    <text>It only requires most people who are "in the market" to be horrible. It's much like the job market (at least in my field). Most the applicants suck, but astoundingly most the people employed don't. The bad apples keep going around applying for jobs they can't do, so most places filter them out. Sometimes they get through, but it's usually figured out and they end up getting fired.

In the same way, good partners get paired up and are no longer available. The bad ones are still floating around in the available pool. Most people can filter them out (see the red flags), but the kind of person OP is describing doesn't know how. The good people still exist, but for the most part they are just not available.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31119853091.0" user="uniklas" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly, there are many analogies to this. Used car marked for example is similar. The good cars get snatched instantly often by people who resell them for a markup, as it is their job/bussiness, so they have the experience to filter junk out. And then there is the regular folk, who know fuck all about cars, and just want something that works, but all they see is cars that are there for months on end and eventually start to think that this is all there is to it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
