<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="606775187.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a19aqb/cmv_if_a_guy_has_trouble_dating_until_his_30s_he/">
    <title>CMV: If a guy has trouble dating until his 30s, he should avoid romantic relationships altogether in his later life</title>
    <original_poster>uniklas</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sorry if this is post is guy centric, but if you feel this applies to women in some way, please include them too. 

I've seen it a few times, a guy for whatever reason is completely non existant to women in his 20s (mostly a combination of shyness and about average looks), he is the kind of guy that *wants* a relationship (like most of the people out there) and grows more desperate by the year. Then his 30s come and suddenly women start noticing him, he gets into a relationship, and then settles for the first woman he has ever been with in a long long time. The woman turns out to be trash of a human being, but the guy thinks he is so lucky to have found someone and she is the best he will ever get so he stays together for 10 or more years. Basically he settles for the first gal that has showed him some interest maybe ever.

I believe a guy like this would be happier if he would never date anyone ever, since he hasn't developed the skills necessary to screen people properly and will most likely fall prey to a woman that is a terrible human being.

Why do I think he will necessarily fall for this kind of a woman as there are plenty of nice 30 something or whatever somethings women out there? There are plenty of formerly young and pretty and shallow women who have got together with rich and shallow men in their 20s, men who have stayed rich and shallow, but women have stayed young and pretty, so they have parted their ways. These women, understandablly, go desperate pretty fast and figure they won't find anyone rich to care for them anymore, so they reduce and reduce their expecations until we get to the level of maybe well of single guys, and who is easier than the guy who won't even try to court anyone anymore? Give him some attention and he is yours to keep.

All is well and good, if she is a decent enough person, but chances are that someone who has been pampered with expensive material things from a young age up until then will not find joy in anything less than she had before and often times the guy will not be able/struggle to hold her to her standarts of living.

So to repeat myself a bit. It is great if a guy like this finds a girl he matches with later in life, but the odds are he won't, as he just doesn't have the skills necessary to do so. He is overwhelmingly more likely to be snatched by someone who has nothing to them except past beauty and he being as unexperienced as he is will think this is all there is to it and will settle for it.

I believe a guy like this would be way happier and even happy overall if he just got to terms that he ought to stay single forever and just work on his platonic relationships or whatever that truly gives him joy and meaning in life.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31119617988.0" user="ChewyRib" delta="False">
    <text>- Im older and met a psychopath when young, felt all my friends are getting married so why not.  this cost me a lot in money and time to get divorced.

- never had trouble dating but found it difficult compared to some of my peers.

- my point with sharing this is I dont feel its a problem for only those who never dated in their 30s.  you can always find a bad relationship to get into.

- another point is that even though that particular relationship I had was the worse in my entire life it was also a catalyst that help me improve myself.  I understood myself more, what I wanted out of life, what I wanted in a partner.  I couldnt date for a few years after that but during that time, I grew as a person.  So I would say I wouldnt trade that experience for a different outcome.

- If you are starting late on the dating scene - you are still working with probabilities of failure and success as everyone else.  even if you have 99 failures, each one should be taken as a learning experience even if you dont end up with the person of your dreams.  You may also find someone of your dreams.  work the numbers and eventually something will happen.

- I will close with this advice from an article

- For a lot of men, the anxiety surrounding their dating inexperience can be overwhelming. They become intimidated by women whom they fear have more experience than they do. They become too afraid to approach anyone, never mind people they’re attracted to. They set themselves up for failure by looking for reasons why others couldn’t possibly like them or why they couldn’t improve, and wait for the Universe to deliver instead.

But your inexperience doesn’t have to be the handicap you think it is. Here’s how to overcome your dating inexperience and find the success you want.

- Whether they recognize it or not, a lot of people treat dating like a game. To them, dating is less of an organic experience and more of a collection of statistics, perfect builds and arbitrary rules that bear absolutely no relationship to reality......Of course, this window of opportunity bears about as much resemblance to reality as Pokemon does to animal husbandry. The numbers are arbitrary and invented and almost always tend to be pulled from thin air; I’ve had 15 year olds email me in desperation, deathly afraid that they missed their window and are now doomed to lead sexless lives forevermore.

- We tend to make assumptions based around expectations built up by pop-culture and expectations about what makes a “real” man, assuming that everybody (but us) has been riding the sex train since the 5th Grade ....The numbers are actually fairly small; the average man has around 6 sexual partners in his lifetime and usually loses his virginity between the ages of 17 to 24. In fact, the younger you are, the odds higher are that you’re actually going to have fewer partners than previous generations.

- But here’s the fun thing about numbers: they don’t tell you as much as we think. Someone who’s had many sex partners may be the last of the red hot lovers… or they may be unable to keep a relationship going. Someone who’s had very few may well be shy and awkward… or he may have had a long, happy relationship with one person.

Numbers mean sweet fuck all.The thing is, no matter what some STEMBros believe, relationships aren’t math problems and statistics. Dating and relationships are sloppy affairs, a collision of sexual chemistry, lifestyle compatibility and no small amount of luck. Numbers are data, dating is about people.

- So even if you do happen to be on the far end of the dating curve, how do you keep your inexperience from working against you?

Own Your Inexperience, Don’t Let It Own You
First things first: you need to own your lack of dating experience.

However, there’s a significant difference between owning your inexperience and letting it own you. If you venture into any ForeverAlone or incel community like /r9k/, you’ll see hundreds of people lamenting how much sex they’ve never had and how the world is conspiring against them. That’s not taking ownership of being socially inexperienced; that’s making it the core of your identity and letting it overtake your life.

- Don’t Make Excuses
There’s two ways that making excuses doesn’t help you. First and foremost is trying to rationalize away your inexperience. You don’t need to explain or justify it; trying to find reasons why it’s less “shameful” than others’ just reinforces the idea that there’s something shameful about it in the first place. You don’t need to explain or excuse your lack of dating experience; “I had other priorities” or “Just hadn’t met the right person” are all you need to say if pressed. It is what it is and that’s fine. 

- Similarly, letting your inexperience dictate your behavior is a loser’s game. Yes, you’re worried that you won’t know what to do. Everybody feels that way, especially in the early days of a new relationship when everything is wonderful and you’re afraid of putting your foot wrong and screwing up a great thing. But inexperience doesn’t excuse or justify needy behavior or make it acceptable.

Nor does experience directly correlate into confidence. I’ve known many, many people who’re masters in their fields yet are insecure wrecks. I’ve known people who believe themselves unto gods who I wouldn’t turn to for an opinion about cheese.

- Inexperience can be frustrating, but it’s not the handicap people think it is. Don’t let self-limiting beliefs hold you back. Worry less about what you haven’t done and focus on learning how to be more awesome and the dates will come.
https://www.doctornerdlove.com/overcoming-your-dating-inexperience/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
