<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125386461.0" user="Slenderpman" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the problem lies in the fact that too many representatives don't understand the issues or have money influencing their decisions. However, the solution isn't to make them spend more time writing. It's to increase the length of congressional terms.

Congressional terms are too short. Why do US house reps serve only 2 years? They have to spend half of their time campaigning and securing campaign funds. No wonder so many reps take money from companies! They really have like a years worth of time to do policy and another year to meet with donors and do favors. That's not right. Their terms should be 6 years, an the senate should be 10 years. 

This way, when each term is over, the electorate has sufficient time to determine whether or not they like the performance of the incumbent AND the representatives can afford to spend less relative time fundraising and campaigning and more time reading about the issues. If the incumbent doesn't perform well or the district changes demographics or ideology, newer, younger politicians will be preferably to old, out of date politicians.

The logic can't really apply to the president. The president's 4 years is perfect because the president is allowed to be political. Congress, on the other hand, needs to be less political and more productive. Deadlock, hyper partisanship, and flip flopping majorities isn't a good recipe for a productive congress.

What's also not a good recipe is overburdening reps under the current system. There are hundreds of votes a year. How do you decide which ones are worth explaining? So many votes are bipartisan if not nearly unanimous. Do those all need explanations? They only have two years right now and I don't want them spending less time legislating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126101751.0" user="Sirz_Benjie" delta="False">
    <text>If this were really the problem, then the senators would not fall victim to it either. The real way to fix this is to have term limits for congressmen. That way, it's more difficult for the lobbying organizations to keep buying votes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
