<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125799657.0" user="kingoflint282" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it would make any difference. The politicians that vote a particular way would just regurgitate whatever argument was floating around. You used the NRA as an example, they would just write out a short explanation for legislators who voted in favor to use, and they would just change up the wording a little so they didn't all have the exact same answer. 

"I believe this is best for the American people because guns don't kill people, people kill people. We're standing up for the first amendment rights of citizens everywhere!" This would be followed by citations to whatever data they feel would help their argument, and data can almost always be manipulated to seem to favor whatever viewpoint.

Articulating a reason for why they voted a certain way is easy. It won't always be a good reason, but there will be one. Unless you have someone who decides what reasons are good enough to justify voting for or against a particular legislation, nothing changes. And that would involve completely overhauling our system of government. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
