<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125375467.0" user="dawn990" delta="False">
    <text>Legislative bodies are still people that will reason in a way that may differ from yours. Someone who is for something can have great reason to be pro, and someone who is against can have great reason con - at the same time, depending who you ask.

Judges, for example, are bound to act by law even if that seems morally unfair. Said law doesn't need to be either moral or fair. It just needs to be passed in a legal way. But law is never sterile conclusion based on facts. It always have a bit of what legislative organ finds moral.

And that's a loop. Because we're again at the beginning. They are people. They don't even have to be smart people. And they were elected. Logic is that voters elected candidates who they find are most suitable to represent their interest. Even if 99% of the people agree that some law is great, there will always be that 1% who will debate how that law is flawed and passed with wrong reasoning.

Even if someone would be obliged to write why he chose to vote the way he did, it still wouldn't make any difference because very small percent of people is so dumb that they can't even bullshit their way out of their lies - and that's probably first thing you need to be capable of doing when entering politics.

It's very illegal to pass a law that will have great impact on company you're associated with. It's called conflict of interest in mild cases or simply bribe in bigger ones - and most politicians aren't dumb enough to be obvious about it. Bribe and conflict of interest is still something that's so well hidden that even if you see it with your own two eyes you still need evidence and all you have is your word.

Do politicians vote for their own interest? Sure they do. Either it's simply something that will bring them certain benefit amidiatlly or it's "if I scratch your back, will you scratch mine". 

27th Amandman that was ratified in 1992 (that's really interesting story to me) is great example of how people in 1789 were aware that abuse of power is not just possible, but so well spread it needs to be put in constitution.

EDIT: spelling</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
