<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125095648.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest.

Who decides what counts as reasonable? 

&amp;gt;If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation?

I suspect you'd see a lot of answers like, "While there are good arguments on both sides of this issue, I think this law would result in more harm than good."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125212912.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>Reasonable would be something based on facts and research. Climate change denial is not reasonable. Getting rid Net Neutrality is not reasonable. Cutting funding to planned parenthood just because they provide abortion services is not reasonable (they don't use federal funding to cover for abortions).   
There are plenty of small reasonable things that can and should be passed but aren't because some big company doesn't want to lose some money. Unless there is an assessment that proves that passing reasonable legislation does more harm than good, there is no reason not to pass it. It also works the other way around with trying to pass harmful legislation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125258537.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Reasonable would be something based on facts and research.

That's not what I asked.  Who _decides_?

Say I'm a Senator, and I vote no on a bill.  I say, "Based on what I've read from X,Y, and Z, I think the long-term effects of this bill will be terrible for the American people."  You, a citizen disagree with my assessment.  What do you do about it?  Who would be responsible for judging whether my assessment was reasonable?

Is there one person who's job it is to examine all the justifications and decide who's right?  What would stop _them_ from allowing things they liked and vetoing things they didn't?  Is it a committee?  Are the people elected, appointed, drawn by lottery from the voting public?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125644118.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>The people/voters will decide. I just want them to be more informed by having undeniable evidence of the reasoning behind their legislator's vote. 

Supporters of a legislator can just hear Yes or No and blindly support them, but if confronted by others or even by facts, they will either have to come to the conclusion that they were wrong or just dig their heads further into the ground. 

This is a legislation about transparency and recording of opinion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125682854.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>So if I vote on a bill and I say "I think this bill will be bad." and that's all the reason I give, what do you want to happen?  In your OP it says I shouldn't be allowed to vote on the bill.  Now you're saying the people/voters decide.  If it's the voters deciding, do you mean that you're going to record my reason and they'll vote against me for being too vague?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125721079.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not what I meant. Lol. I meant the voters will decide as they already do whether or not to re-elect that representative given now their actual reasoning.

So for your example what I would want to happen is for the representative to explain WHY they think it would be bad and to have something substantive to base it on like some research, data, or opinion from someone with experience and expertise in the field. If they’re unable to provide that, there vote shouldn’t count. Their constituents will in turn, hopefully, learn to question this representative and really dig deep about why they didn’t bother giving a good reason and hopefully they vote the correct way next time they’re up for election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125758108.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>I get what sort of statement you want from the representative. You're not being clear on what consequences you want from someone who doesn't give a good enough answer. You start by saying the voters will decide by voting them out.  Later you say that the vote on the bill shouldn't count.  Which is it?

If the vote shouldn't count, _who decides which votes will count_?  It can't be the voters voting in elections, that happens way later.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125770052.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>The vote shouldn’t count if they refuse to provide sources for there reasoning. If they just say it’s bad without saying why and without providing supporting evidence for it, it shouldn’t count. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125804797.0" user="cortesoft" delta="False">
    <text>What would count as a valid source? Some blog on the internet? I am not exactly sure what would be gained by that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125881742.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously. I feel like this question is not in good faith. How do you think scholarly journals or articles get published? How do you think professors grade papers with citations? If a legislator can’t tell what a good/reputable source is they shouldn’t legislate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125899732.0" user="cortesoft" delta="False">
    <text>It was in good faith, and I am sorry if it didn't come across that way.

Yes, a professor can set certain standards for sources, and they are able to enforce them. In your proposed system, though, who would decide when a source isn't good enough? Who takes the role of the professor? Who would have the authority to say, "sorry, your source isn't good enough, your vote doesn't count"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125908577.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>This is why providing multiple sources is important. And providing only skewed or untrustworthy ones should receive criticism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125991115.0" user="cortesoft" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And providing only skewed or untrustworthy ones should receive criticism.

Sure, but you don't need a law for that. You can't pass a law that says "Voters shouldn't vote for candidates that don't provide good sources"... that is up to each individual voter. You can't legislate that voters should care about facts. No law can make that happen.

Almost all legislators will put out a press release, or a post on their personal web site, explaining why they vote for a law. Of course, 99% of those explanations are vapid and generic, but they are there. I am not sure what your law would change.

I am 100% in agreement that I wish voters cared more about facts and the truth. But we can't change that with the passing of a law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127971909.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How do you think scholarly journals or articles get published? How do you think professors grade papers with citations?

Both of these examples have **someone** deciding whether a source is trustworthy or worth citing.  What is the equivalent in your proposed system?

Author writes a paper, submits it to a journal, editor decides whether it's worth publishing.

Student writes a paper, submits it to a professor, professor decides whether the cites are to good sources.

Senator lays down her argument, submits it to ___________, __________ decides whether it's good enough for the vote to count.

What goes in those blanks?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125821569.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. I say my source is 4chan.  Good enough?

What about if I cite a Brietbart article? Daily Caller? My hairdresser?

Who will decide which sources are good enough evidence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125881518.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>Seriously. I feel like this question is not in good faith. How do you think scholarly journals or articles get published? How do you think professors grade papers with citations? If a legislator can’t tell what a good/reputable source is they shouldn’t legislate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125902029.0" user="cheertina" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that they shouldn't.  But in that case your CMV boils dow to "people should be better", which, sure, I agree with, but how do you make it happen?

In your analogy to grading papers, who is doing the grading for a representative? If we could trust representatives to self-enforce these transparency statements because they're all honest and forthright, we wouldn't _need_ the transparency statements.

You're not thinking hard enough about how people would try to get around what you're trying to do. If I know "the right thing" and I'm getting paid to do the opposite I would be as vague as possible.  How would you stop me?

Edit: you mention publishing papers and getting grades.  Both of those have someone judging the quality of an argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128031161.0" user="zeperf" delta="False">
    <text>The point is that you are asking for a LAW. You have to have very clear standards and punishments. It's not a bad faith question, of course your responders know what you want, but that has nothing to do with how to craft a law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128695580.0" user="superfudge" delta="False">
    <text>Legislators vote on many things that don’t have clear, objective answers. What papers or evidence would you provide for deciding something like mandatory sentencing minimums? Or the right to terminate a pregnancy? These issues can’t be easily resolved by consulting evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128865541.0" user="CreativeGPX" delta="False">
    <text>It's in good faith; it just tries to pry past the massive assumptions you're relying on to keep this from being what turns us into a one party state.

Scholarly journals are peer reviewed. Who is the peer of the congressperson? It's the rest of congress. So, if you apply the same standard for evaluating compliance with this rule, then whoever the dominant party is at the time gets to decide what the valid sources are... which would only make it more likely to force people to stick to the party line. ... Also, peer review has its downsides. For example, it was a long and rocky road for Behavior Economics to gain any credibility in the field of economics, even if though they had data supporting their theories and refuting the other ones because it undermined a lot of core areas traditional economists relied on. So, perhaps what you are suggesting would make us a much more conservative nation.

Professors can and do have whatever bias they want. Most people aren't particularly worried about that bias because each case where a judge (i.e. professor) had a bias impacts a voluntary action (continuing that degree at that school) of anywhere from a single student to a single school, which is a drop in the bucket given how many schools and professors there are. People who know that professor is wrong only need to put up with it for a semester or a few years, unlike congress where the bias can have permanent effects on what everybody is mandated to do.

But it's also worth noting that all of the most contentious issues do not boil down to objective matters. You can be on either side of abortion with the same facts, but a different subjective choice of when the right to life is granted to a biological thing. You can be on either side of gun rights with the same facts, but a different subjective choice of what level of which risks you're willing to accept or how important it is to have guns. You can be on either side of consumer laws or healthcare laws with the same facts, but a different subjective choice of what people are entitled to have government do for them. You can be on either side of climate laws with the same facts, but a different subjective choice of what economic burdens we should tolerate or which (if any) level of government should have which regulatory authorities. A congressperson could find a few sources that say government power in general should be limited and then cite them any time they vote against anything ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129630758.0" user="desert_igloo" delta="False">
    <text>They are making the point that it is still subjective and that is really no way to make this objective. Which is what is need for a law like this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125395296.0" user="workingtrot" delta="False">
    <text>Get a room of 10 educated, reasonable people together, and 10/10 will agree that man-made climate change is a huge problem that needs to be solved. However,  you'll probably get 10 contradictory opinions about how to accomplish that. It's not like there's just one big climate change law that needs to be passed and then all our problems will be solved </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125653631.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>That's not the issue. The issue is about the legislators knowing about those 10 educated people's well informed and researched opinion and disagreeing it for no good reason and using that disagreement to pass legislation to the contrary.   


If a bill came up to eliminate the EPA despite it helping the environment and the reasoning behind eliminating it was because the majority of the legislature didn't believe in climate change and that we can harm the environment, that is irrational and unreasonable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125831122.0" user="cortesoft" delta="False">
    <text>What if their stated reason is, "I don't think the government should regulate anything"

That wouldn't require a source, because it is more of a principle than a logical reason. Would that be an ok response?

If it is, then why couldn't they respond that way for every request for a reason: "I don't think the government should be involved in that"

I think the main problem is that many decisions aren't made based on differing notions of facts, but on differing notions about the role of the government. There is no "source" you can site for that.

In addition, a lot of reasons could be "I don't think the government is going to be able to do the thing they want to do effectively" or "I think the resources to enforce that would be better spent elsewhere"

Those aren't things you can fact check.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125591485.0" user="Daotar" delta="False">
    <text>Whose facts and research? Why do you get to decide what is fine and what isn't?

Those things aren't reasonable to you, but to plenty of reasonable people they are, and it's very dangerous to start saying that whoever disagrees with you about such things is by definition unreasonable, especially since those 'unreasonable' people will eventually be in power and be charged themselves with determining what is 'reasonable'. It's just not anywhere near as easy to require 'objective facts' be used in political processes when politically no one agrees on what the 'objective facts' are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125632090.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;getting rid of net neutrality is not reasonable

To you, it isn't. To me, it's letting people do what they want with their own property, which is perfectly reasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125670448.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>Net neutrality is the principle that Internet service providers treat all data on the Internet equally, and not discriminate or charge differently by user, content, website, platform, application, type of attached equipment, or method of communication.

What's reasonable about major ISPs being able to limit speeds of certain websites and services? It's not saving them money. 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126089711.0" user="Sirz_Benjie" delta="False">
    <text>Your original argument has many merits, but here you're simply discrediting your opponent's as unreasonable simply because they disagree with you. I am a huge proponent of net neutrality, and I would be hard pressed to vote for any congressmen that voted to support it. In this case especially, you are ignoring what the person you are replying to is saying. They believe that people (or corporations, presumably) should be allowed to do what they want with their property. It's bad form to outright dismiss your opponent's argument as unreasonable. Instead, just reply with the consequence that you stated. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127071001.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>It's reasonable because the websites are using the ISP's bandwidth to function. The ISPs should have a right to use their property how they deem fit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129013651.0" user="CreativeGPX" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Net neutrality is the principle that Internet service providers treat all data on the Internet equally

Treating everything equally means treating nothing in a way that's particular to its needs. Some traffic needs to arrive immediately and on the first try (e.g. 911 VOIP call). Some traffic needs better bandwidth (e.g. buffered video). Some traffic needs better latency (e.g. video games). Meanwhile, some traffic is not at all hurt by low bandwidth (e.g. text message), low latency (e.g. loading a web page) or low reliability (e.g. a mail server can try to send again in a minute). Net neutrality is a regulation that interferes with network optimization like the above. Therefore, in order to provide all of the above, a network needs to be substantially larger and more expensive. That will be difficult for any newcomer to the industry and will be more expensive for any existing networks and therefore its customers.

&amp;gt; charge differently by user, content, website, platform, application, type of attached equipment, or method of communication.

What if I want them to charge differently? Airlines make the vast majority of their income from business and first class tickets which enables them to sell coach tickets at substantially cheaper than what they could if they charged the same price for every seat. This makes flight viable for many people that it wouldn't otherwise be viable for. Letting companies segment markets can have positive effects for consumers, especially the poor.

Meanwhile, since people already pay for different internet speeds/caps and since large companies already have a substantial advantage because of things like edge caching, even with net neutrality, this doesn't solve the idea that small companies either need the blessing of large companies or massive amounts of money to compete with the performance and reliability of large companies.

&amp;gt; What's reasonable about major ISPs being able to limit speeds of certain websites and services? 

What reasonable about the government telling people what to do with their private property and restricting the capacity of to private citizens from deciding what exchange they'll accept from each other?

&amp;gt; It's not saving them money.

That's an extremely difficult thing to prove, but it doesn't have to save anybody money, so we don't really have to do that research.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138062163.0" user="SoresuMakashi" delta="False">
    <text>Because they own the service? Is it really any different from a lounge charging extra for access to their VIP area?

You keep saying throughout this thread that a short paragraph of reasoning is sufficient, then battle on virtually every controversial issue as if only one side (which, might I add, runs conveniently along party lines) can be reasonably supported. Why do you think these issues are controversial in the first place? It's precisely because different people find different things reasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126612903.0" user="IdiotII" delta="False">
    <text>Well, we started with 2A on this thread.  Facts and research have pretty much unanimously indicated that semi-automatic AR's do not put the population in danger.

But facts and research aren't the only things that matter.  We have a constitution, and it is the end-all-be-all of law.  If there's a clause in the constitution that establishes something as law, and facts and research determine that it's bad for the people, you don't get to just ignore it with a simple majority vote.  This is because the constitution covers what are considered "universal truths," as in, things that are the way they are regardless of majority opinion at any given point in time.  50 years ago, it wasn't an absolute certainty to most people that cigarettes will give you lung cancer.

Yes, you can change the constitution, but it was designed in such a way that the core of it can't be *easily* changed.  There has to be a VERY good reason, and if there is, the idea is that the obstacles that must be overcome to amend the constitution should be able to be overcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126802044.0" user="nimbledaemon" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of legislation isn't really supported one way or the other by hard facts.

Take the planned parenthood and abortion issue for example.  The real determining factor in whether you're pro life or pro choice comes down to your opinion on when life begins, or what constitutes consent to become pregnant and raise a child, and the best you can do with logic is some philosophical reasoning which is hardly a hard fact.

If you go with the pro life side, then you're justified in defunding planned parenthood because they offer abortion services, or in pro life terms they actively participate in the killing of innocent human beings, and whether or not the federal funds go to the abortion services they help the organization as a whole, and they don't want federal money being used to support an evil organization.

If you go with the pro choice side, then defunding planned parenthood is ridiculous because the money doesn't touch the abortion services anyway, and only hurts the rest of planned parenthood.  This would put innocent people in danger of not being able to choose if they have kids or not, just because they want to have the sexual experience common to all of humanity, and the odds didn't roll in their favor.  Which leads to unwanted children, which leads to more crime and suffering in the future, which perpetuates poverty because poor people don't have the resources to plan, etc. etc.  

The point is, the difference is in the interpretation of the facts rather than the facts themselves.

And then you get into omnibus bills, where legislators could be voting for or against based on a single part of the bill.  All that you could fit into a paragraph would be I voted for the bill because article A section iii is necessary because X paper says Y.

So you get all this extra stuff made into law, and the justification lawmakers give might not actually have anything to do with why they really wanted a bill to pass, they just choose the thing they could best justify and explain that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127335576.0" user="resolvetochange" delta="False">
    <text>Climate Change Bill:

"I have chosen to vote against Carbon Taxes as while science shows that the climate is changing there is insufficient evidence to prove that the change is man-made. We should not restrict economic growth without sufficient proof." -- links to studies about how the climate changes with or without humans, and a few studies that had the least observed impacts due to human activity

Net Neutrality:

"I have voted for the Internet Freedom Act to ensure that ISP's have the freedom to manage their own service and provide improvements in speeds to certain highly demanded webpages". ---links to cases about freedom of speech, businesses having rights to their own services/ terms and conditions, etc

What would statements like this coming out solve?

You *want* people to be more informed, you *want* transparency and honesty, you *want* objectivity. But none of that will come of this. 

It would be more redirection by wording bad things to sound like they are good, reasoning made up when the real reason is they were paid off by the corporations, etc. Politicians already put out statements like that, look at articles or advertising whenever a bill is coming up and you will find a few sentences like that with some "proof" linked.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
