<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="80" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31128792334.0" user="NuncErgoFacite" delta="False">
    <text>There is the argument to be correct and there is the argument to be effective.  

If you are looking for righteousness... politics is the wrong place to be looking.

On the effective side of the discussion - a politician is successful in their career by convincing the people they should be voted for AND convincing people and companies to donate to them to fund those election efforts.

If a voting record serves those goals then the politicians will vote in such a way.  Asking politicians to account for thier voting actions is like asking a lawyer to find enough loophole laws to allow you to do a thing.  You will get a legal reason that has everything to do with good government and nothing to do with elections and money.

So the effective answer is they do in the congressional record already... and it is legally legitimate reasons that speak nothing to the type of answers you are looking for.

TLDR: My children get one treat at the grocery store if they behave while we go shopping. Last week they wanted a bulk box of cookies.  I asked them why they needed such a big box.  They replied the extra cookies were for dad.  I don't believe them.  If only I could force them to answer in such a way that they would tell me the truth...

TLDR2:  Politicians are like diapers. They should be changed often and for the same reason.  - Mark Twain </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
