<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125408395.0" user="ItsAConspiracy" delta="False">
    <text>This wouldn't make any difference at all.

I once visited my state legislature and it was an assembly line for laws. I watched for an hour and they passed one after another, boom boom boom. Probably passed ten different things while I was there.

I was there with my girlfriend. We were sitting in a balcony surrounding the legislature, along with about two hundred other people. The lady next to us said "you guys are tourists, right?" "How'd you know?" "Because I know everybody else here, we're all lobbyists." She pointed out who everybody was, they were sitting in groups by industry.

If the legislators had to write essays justifying their votes, they wouldn't possibly have time for it all. But that's an easy problem to solve. They'd just have the lobbyists write the essays for them. They'd be sure to make it sound good.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
