<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31124968947.0" user="Bookwrrm" delta="False">
    <text>They already are dodgy and lie, why would getting them to write it up change anything.  In the us the Democrats would have thier aides go-to whatever left leaning think tanks and have them source stuff and write it up, and the Republicans would go-to thier right leaning think tanks and get sources as well.  Then we just devolve into arguing about what they wrote rather than what they are saying, until the legislature actually changes all this would do is kick the can down the road and make public responses slower.


Also let's be frank, the answer on both sides is they voted because of money or ideology and it's really not difficult to see that and requiring thier aides to come up with sources won't change that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125230379.0" user="xiaodre" delta="False">
    <text>This is it.  A perfect illustrative example is when Cory Booker spiked the drug import overhaul.  People were up in arms, because there was no good reason why he did it, they were talking about importing drugs from canada, which are the same drugs we in the us have at half the price.  He just fell back on the old standby, the fda needs to be able to regulate the quality of drugs.  He didn't care, and he's still in office so despite what the progressive populists said, they didn't care enough to get him out.  Its just one example of so many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125863928.0" user="misersoze" delta="False">
    <text>Allowing US to import drugs from Canada won’t make US drugs cheaper in the long run, it will make Canadian drug cost as much as US drugs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126743489.0" user="xiaodre" delta="False">
    <text>ok, that's an argument, right?  an economic argument.  You could take that and make a reasoned argument about it.


For Cory Booker, it really just came down to his donors, big pharma in NJ.  His donors wanted him to spike the bill (Bernie's bill by the way).  Well, he needed an excuse that wouldn't put him up against Bernie and possibly split the left.  Especially since Bernie's arguments are mostly economic.  So he went with an old standby excuse.


They just lie.  Politicians will just lie like rugs.  And you can try and pin them down with a written statement, but it doesn't matter, it will still just be lies.  This was Bookworm's point I think, and its a good one.


If this goes on, I'll pick an illustrative example from the right for balance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127007961.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>At least their lies would be on paper and the most up to date at the time of voting. Many people don’t believe in Global warming but the people who are stupid enough to explain why they believe it (snowballs in Congress anyone) are instantly ridiculed. This goes back tot he saying “it is better to be silent and thought a fool than to open your mouth and remove all doubt.” Right now they have the benefit of plausible deniability. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
