<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125265747.0" user="Judicator01" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think being required to give an explanation would mean that explanation were honest or provided any value to any voters. Let's say people vote along the party line. **They would subsequently all write the exact same paragraph.** Maybe some people would add some flourishes to be different, but how would this change anything?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125409792.0" user="dawn990" delta="False">
    <text>I agree. 

Even if law is "reasonable" there still can be a lot of similar or same answers. No one would write full on dissertation about their vote, and in TL:DR party members would write same things because their vote was based on same reasoning. It's not illegal for two or more politicians to base opinion on the same research (*that* law would be unreasonable).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127164697.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>Especially in today's climate where even lying under oath seems to be shockingly common, what would make anyone be truthful in their explanation?

Even if the truth was "I voted on this because XYZ Corp paid me a bunch of money and I want a new boat", no one would say that. You can always come up with a reasonable-sounding explanation for both sides of an issue. 

Like in OP's gun control example, someone could say that they voted against enhanced measures because they would unfairly affect the lower classes, and that giving constitutional rights unequally is wrong. Sounds plausible enough, satisfies OP's proposal, and changes absolutely nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127464544.0" user="thorface" delta="False">
    <text>This is especially the case with a republican senator complaining about reforming mandatory sentencing. When he's presented with arguments on how he's actually wrong, he simply repeats his "reasoning" of how this is a "poorly thought out" policy that won't change anything. When he's pushed on why it's poorly thought out, he provides some BS line of how it's not tough enough on crime or some other nonsense platitude that does't mean anything and is entirely symbolic.

Requiring someone to explain their view often time accomplishes nothing, as you stated here.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
