<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31124968608.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>Though it's a fascinating idea, I think it's going to be an ultimately fruitless exercise that's just going to waste everyone's time. Why? Because it won't get politicians to admit to anything (which I think is your goal). 

For instance, with the NRA example someone would simply say "there are already a large amount of restrictions and regulations around purchasing a firearm" (which is true), and "and this law X would make it even more difficult to obtain a firearm than it already is today, therefore infringing on our second amendment". That's it. 

So in other words, despite the fact you're trying to get someone to admit to voting party lines or that they're in cahoots with the NRA, you're still not going to get that with this proposal.

People will always work around it with their explanation.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
