<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125048748.0" user="hannasf" delta="False">
    <text>There is the Congressional Record.  It is chockablock full of why people vote why they do. You can also write them and ask.  Gun ownership is protected under the Second Amendment and when someone presumes to create caveats to the Right, then they need to justify it legally. The other thing to remember is that one size does not fit all.  All the gun control in the world has not helped some big cities. You can't apply the same rules to rural America. Farmers need to be able to deal with predators. They may need to put down a sick or wounded animal when the large animal vet can't get there quickly. I've had to put down sick goats and hogs. I've had to kill foxes and fisher cats destroying my flocks. I've had bears on my back deck on a fairly regular basis. I've had scary situations with humans and the police did not get here for 45 minutes or more. Never shot anyone, but certainly needed to show I was capable of that. My town is too small for a municipal police force. 

Vermont and Maine -- very blue states -- have some of the highest gun ownership per capita in the country. Also extremely low crime rates. Even the liberals are gun owners.  Gun control is a non starter in northern New England. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125177972.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>I just used gun control as an example. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125199824.0" user="PoliticalStaffer22" delta="False">
    <text>The gun control stuff aside, the main point of this person's response stands. 95%+ of the time and 100% of the time on any piece of controversial legislation a written response can be found. (In the US at least).

Legislator's reasoning for voting in favor or against legislation is almost always in the Congressional Record. If you have a question for a specific member on why they voted a specific way, write to them and they will almost always respond with their reasoning, in writing.

Therefore, your statement already exists because legislators are held accountable to their voters. If they don't explain themselves sufficiently, they will be voted out of office.

There is no need to put a legal requirement on this when it already happens in practice.

Furthermore, your requirement would actually hurt our governing and legislating process. How? Congressional staff in offices are already overworked and underpaid (congressional offices only have a finite amount of resources they can spend on staff). For example, a staffer for a member of the US House of Representatives usually makes 40-50K (to live in DC which is expensive) and must be responsible for briefing the member of congress on 10 different issues. IE. Agriculture, Energy, Environment, Trade, Judiciary issues, Second Amendment, Small Business, Technology, Communications, and Rural issues. Your requirement would only increase the bureaucracy of the government and further slow down legislation from getting passed. Furthermore, adding work to these staffers would only reduce the amount of time that they can spend on understand their legislative portfolio, which only increases the ignorance the member has regarding a piece of legislation. One way to fix this would be to hire a new staffer and pay existing ones less, but that would exacerbate an already MASSIVE brain drain on Capitol Hill.  Any needless/duplicative work required by an office just takes away from actually governing.

Brain Drain: [https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/03/when-congress-cant-think-for-itself-it-turns-to-lobbyists/387295/](https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/03/when-congress-cant-think-for-itself-it-turns-to-lobbyists/387295/)

EDIT: To make clear I was not commenting on gun control in any way </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126796188.0" user="ECONOMIC_DEMOCRAGUY" delta="False">
    <text>Spot on about the Congressional Record but I do have one nitpick about Hill Staffers:

Yes they are poor and overworked (many of them going to law school at night to try and get ahead), but they are in no way responsible for being well-versed on 10+ legislative topics. In every office I saw when I interned, there were at least 5 full time staffers and a military fellow to divide these topics up. This way, the Congressman could consult with one or two individuals at a time to get a full report on any given bill without having to involve the entire team.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127041143.0" user="PoliticalStaffer22" delta="False">
    <text>I am just talking from personal experience having those issues that I listed as my responsibility. I also have friends who had 10+ issues as well.

Senate offices are different, as they have about 5 issues to worry about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127082826.0" user="ygnomecookies" delta="False">
    <text>Let me also add that committee reports are often even more helpful than congressional reports. They include research, information from interest groups and hearings with outside experts that help them form the bill that’s voted on in the chambers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128176713.0" user="Logisticks" delta="False">
    <text>To add another point about why saddling congressional staffers with more redundant work is a bad idea:

There's been a serious problem of brain drain over the past few years during periods, as many of the most ambitious and brightest staffers have begun quitting their federal jobs to work as lobbyists.  One of the main reasons for this has been congressional gridlock, as staffers who feel that they are spinning their wheels without any real potential for career advancement realize that they have many more opportunities for career advancement if they decide to take a lobbying gig instead of remaining a federal employee (and get paid way more to boot).  Saddling these staffers with more redundant busywork is only going to increase the number of ambitious people who decide that it's just not worth it to work as a congressional staffer when they could be making more (and probably accomplishing more for their personal career) as a lobbyist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129891155.0" user="PoliticalStaffer22" delta="False">
    <text>You should check out my post on this. Its about paying staff more. 

[https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a1nsul/cmv\_congressional\_staffers\_should\_receive/](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a1nsul/cmv_congressional_staffers_should_receive/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129286437.0" user="See-9" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a link to this for Net neutrality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129353228.0" user="PoliticalStaffer22" delta="False">
    <text>Admittedly, Net Neutrality isn't something that I have been following. 

That being said, Net Neutrality was originally an FCC rule during the Obama Administration. [https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/net-neutrality](https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/net-neutrality)

The Trump Administration FCC decided to repeal this rule. 

[https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/11/the-fccs-net-neutrality-rules-are-officially-repealed-today-heres-what-that-really-means/?utm\_term=.8d16ac0c5136](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-switch/wp/2018/06/11/the-fccs-net-neutrality-rules-are-officially-repealed-today-heres-what-that-really-means/?utm_term=.8d16ac0c5136)

Therefore, there was no original vote in favor of or repealing Net Neutrality in congress. 

The Senate voted to advance a resolution to advance a motion vote on restoring Net Neutrality through the Congressional Review Act, this vote passed. The House has yet to vote on this legislation. There will almost certainly be a House vote on this issue in the coming months.

OK, back to the senate vote. Because the Senate was using the CRA to advance a motion that repeals the Trump FCC repeal of net neutrality, the vote is not only on Net Neutrality and therefore is not black and white. What do I mean by this? Some Senators voted against this resolution that would have voted to restore Net Neutrality because of the process that this action is taking place, and not because they are against Net Neutrality itself. So therefore, until there is a direct vote on legislation that codifies Net Neutrality, rather than a vote using the CRA, some members can explain their vote against this resolution through opposition to procedure. Obviously, this is esoteric Senate procedure, and I am not an expert on Senate procedure. If you have any other questions, I will try and answer them for you. 

Regardless, here is the Congressional Record on that vote for your review. 

 [https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CREC-2018-05-16/html/CREC-2018-05-16-pt1-PgS2698-2.htm](https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CREC-2018-05-16/html/CREC-2018-05-16-pt1-PgS2698-2.htm)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133739965.0" user="See-9" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;OK, back to the senate vote. Because the Senate was using the CRA to advance a motion that repeals the Trump FCC repeal of net neutrality, the vote is not only on Net Neutrality and therefore is not black and white. What do I mean by this? Some Senators voted against this resolution that would have voted to restore Net Neutrality because of the process that this action is taking place, and not because they are against Net Neutrality itself. So therefore, until there is a direct vote on legislation that codifies Net Neutrality, rather than a vote using the CRA, some members can explain their vote against this resolution through opposition to procedure. Obviously, this is esoteric Senate procedure, and I am not an expert on Senate procedure. If you have any other questions, I will try and answer them for you.

That shows no opionions from the Nays.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31140051921.0" user="joe_average1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Therefore, your statement already exists because legislators are held accountable to their voters. If they don't explain themselves sufficiently, they will be voted out of office.

The myth that politicians are held accountable by the electorate is one of the biggest whoppers told in our country. First off, most people vote along party lines. That means that because of gerrymandering most people are in a safe district that will go to the party and historically (yes there are counter examples) parties run the same guy. Second they aren't required to say why they voted a certain way nor do most. I remember Richard Burr being asked directly in a debate why he voted over 90% along party lines and he completely dodged the question.  

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I don't think this kind of requirement is something that should fall on staffers. If you can't articulate why you voted a certain way and how it's good for the country, your state as well as your constituents then that's a major problem. I don't think anyone would expect a full on dissertation so much as 3-5 page report summarizing what their decision was based on and the impact of their vote. As pessimistic as it sounds I'm betting that if you put a mind reader on the hill after a vote you'd find out a lot of folks voted yes or no because they were told to and not because it was the best choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125406411.0" user="jungleWorn" delta="False">
    <text>You did not address the first half of their reply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125416679.0" user="PolkaDotAscot" delta="False">
    <text>But you said they voted against “a reasonable measure” in regards to gun control. What is reasonable? Reasonable to you and I could be very different concepts. 

And perhaps the reason the NRA contributes, backs, and endorses that particular legislator is because they’re already very anti-gun control, which in turn, the NRA likes. 

Edit: just because you/OP doesn’t understand why anyone would vote against (or for) something, doesn’t mean there’s anything shady going on. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125711704.0" user="ChestBras" delta="False">
    <text>Also, legislatively "shall not be infringed" is kind of a big one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126026959.0" user="VicarOfAstaldo" delta="False">
    <text>“But I don’t like it so I’ll ignore that because it’s old.”

Seems to generally be the jist of that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127837187.0" user="That1one1dude1" delta="False">
    <text>Like the whole “well regulated militia” part</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129964787.0" user="ChestBras" delta="False">
    <text>Can't have it if you don't have gun.  
If everyone have guns, you can then, indeed, have a militia.  
It doesn't mean it YOUR militia, or it's the government's militia, it just means that, if people are armed, and shit goes down, which includes shit from the government, a well regulated militia can step up.  
You do know that regulated is a synonym for "well oiled", right? It has nothing to do with rules.  
The only way to have a regulated militia is to make sure people have arms, AND know how to use them. So, firing range should be state sponsored and paid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126935815.0" user="Drunk3ngineer" delta="False">
    <text>"Senator, why did you vote against this law that would violate the Constitution?"

"it was unconstitutional"

"I'm sorry sir we need a minimum one page reasoning with sources"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126993604.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>Something could be said about the need to prove something is violating the constitution. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127987095.0" user="WillCookForSex" delta="False">
    <text>Sometimes things are just so obvious a proof isn't needed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129530233.0" user="Ndvorsky" delta="False">
    <text>Considering half the country disagrees on the subject, I would say this is not one of those things. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127835676.0" user="That1one1dude1" delta="False">
    <text>This sounds like something someone who has no understanding of how Constitutional interpretation works would say</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31129969098.0" user="ChestBras" delta="False">
    <text>Interpretation? Lawl, it's written, and pretty simple to follow.  
There's just some assholes who want to redefine words.  
The constitution should have just referred to a dictionary of the time to shut these fucks up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127228442.0" user="velogeek" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And perhaps the reason the NRA contributes, backs, and endorses that particular legislator is because they’re already very anti-gun control, which in turn, the NRA likes. 

I wish more people understood this.  Activist groups and corporate donors are treated as one and the same far too often.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127317300.0" user="ComteDeSaintGermain" delta="False">
    <text>Canadian law LOVES to use the word 'reasonable'.
Even their Charter of Rights (Similar to bill of rights) allows for the rights to be suspended 'if reasonable'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127518531.0" user="graceburger" delta="False">
    <text>Recently read an article about a 70 year old man who is heading toward dementia. He gave his POA to a new friend to help the old guy pay his bills. The new friend had a criminal past and began to sell off a substantial gun collection without permission. 50 some weapons, many AR styles of varied calibers were stolen. Now, just maybe, there might be a reason to limit, not ban, certain aspects of bearing arms. I would love a tank. It would make parking simple, yet I can’t get one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128000001.0" user="PolkaDotAscot" delta="False">
    <text>

So, someone’s friend sold his guns? Or stole his guns? Your comment is confusing and none of it even makes sense as a reason for 

&amp;gt;Now, just maybe, there might be a reason to limit, not ban, certain aspects of bearing arms. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126000821.0" user="DragoonXNucleon" delta="False">
    <text>I agree in theory. In practice, "this law would be harmful to America and sets a bad precedent. That is why I voted no."

Have I really contributed, no. But I have satisfied the requirements. The issue isn't the explanation, its the conflict of interests, the permanent campaigns, the voter disenfranchisement. If we had a better system we would get better outcomes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126323872.0" user="Hatewrecked" delta="False">
    <text>I see those issues as stemming from the main issue: voter non-involvement.

What % of Americans can name their federal senators and representative, let alone their state reps/sens (who are arguably more important than their federal counterparts), let alone know what issues they voted for/against, let alone why they did so? People don't care about politics. They have political opinions, sure, but they're all-in-all disconnected from what goes on in Congress. Washington DC looks like a black box where tax money goes into and bad policies come out of. 

When the midterm elections only excite less than half of the eligible votes, it doesn't really matter what system you implement. The apathetic or uninformed nature of the average voter is what will bring about bad results.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126947941.0" user="RedHatOfFerrickPat" delta="False">
    <text>I think that if we made politicians into, well, basically monks (a comfortable but materialistically meagre life with no prospect of wealth)... there'd be much more dedicated people in government. For one thing, it'd take a real devotion to public service to decide to live in the sort of way I'd suggest having them live, and for another, everybody in government would know that everybody *else* was very devoted too. I think people would do near their actual best, and we'd have people who are largely altruistic... well, that or religious nutters. But I think it's worth thinking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127205253.0" user="reneno" delta="False">
    <text>Assuming that you mean paying them less - not compensating politicians would lead to only independently wealthy people being able to perform the job. It’s a lot easier for someone who’s already a millionaire to spend half their time sitting in legislature than someone who’s barely scraping by working full time.  Just the idea of living in the district they represent and working in DC implies that a legislator needs to be able to afford 2 apartments minimum.

Assuming you mean giving up their existing wealth like a monk - Becoming a monk works because it is assumed to be a lifetime commitment to give up wealth.  If someone with considerable assets was forced to give up their independent wealth for a position they could be voted out of within a few years, would they become homeless or have enough of a pension to be set for life after only one term?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126250852.0" user="MaggotMinded" delta="False">
    <text>Hahaha this guy going off about gun control as if that's the view we're supposed to be changing just made my day. Dude just focused in on the thing he wanted to debate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126251121.0" user="OGDoraslayer" delta="False">
    <text>And got served for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126486743.0" user="KuntaStillSingle" delta="False">
    <text>But you tried to sneak the premise "there is such thing as reasonable gun control." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126785550.0" user="unclefisty" delta="False">
    <text>Also if you think the NRA spends a lot boy are you in for some surprises. They're not even in the top20 of lobbying spenders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127367223.0" user="Damdatswhack" delta="False">
    <text>but they are the top spending gun lobby group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127408266.0" user="unclefisty" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah out of like maybe a total of five groups.

The gun lobby is still nothing compared to most others.

Politicians don't fear NRA lobbyists they fear the votes of NRA members</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127493072.0" user="Damdatswhack" delta="False">
    <text>True. I guess they don't need to spend that much on lobbying because of their active member ship like you mentioned and their outside spending which is easily top 10. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128066865.0" user="allugalansan" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I don’t know why people think the gun lobby is so big. Look up big pharma, energy, and telecom then tell me who is spending the most money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128137870.0" user="unclefisty" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's the drum beat of every anti gun organization.

The news media is usually happy to repeat it as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125199904.0" user="asimpleanachronism" delta="False">
    <text>Also, not one of those examples would call for the need of an automatic assault weapon. Most of what you described as "rural needs" for firearms can  be dealt with using a shotgun, any pistol of a decent caliber, and/or any rifle of a decent caliber. 

Most of the current gun debate deals with access to military-level assault weapons, concealed carry, modifications such as bump stocks, and universal background checks. While bringing up the dichotomy between gun culture/needs in rural vs the rest of America is interesting, it's a red herring with regards to contested gun law in the current US political climate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125282116.0" user="vdgmrpro" delta="False">
    <text>How readily available are automatic “assault weapons”?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126210888.0" user="randuser" delta="False">
    <text>Semi-automatic rifles with high capacity magazines are fairly readily available.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125284278.0" user="hannasf" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't a red herring. The Second Amendment does not differentiate. How much real crime is committed by these assault rifles?  But for a few notable exceptions very few. Most are committed by the very handguns, rifles and shotguns you've agreed we should be permitted to have.  If someone wants to commit mass murder all they need is a pressure cooker and some shrapnel. Or, a vehicle with a working accelerator and full gas tank. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125955811.0" user="Chabranigdo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Also, not one of those examples would call for the need of an automatic assault weapon

Ah. Yes. The fabled automatic assault weapon. Except "Assault weapon" translates to "It looks scary", and they're not automatic weapons in the first place, because those are already strictly controlled to the point of hilarity. The last time I've heard of an automatic weapon used in a crime was in the fucking 90's. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126021624.0" user="junkhacker" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The last time I've heard of an automatic weapon used in a crime was in the fucking 90's. 

and it wasn't a legally manufactured one either!

legally owned automatic weapons haven't been used in a single crime since, like, the 30's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126023760.0" user="Memories_of_You" delta="False">
    <text>Automatic firearms are already banned across the board in the US.  You have to go through immense hoops to get one.  Only very rich people and firearms dealers can get one.  Or you can get them illegally, but that’s already illegal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126610598.0" user="plzhlpwthtrk" delta="False">
    <text>You do not have to go through immense hoops.  You pay a $200 fee for the license and you can have one.  The thing is they cost like $40,000 because you can only buy one from a very limited pool of them that existed before 1986 or so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126628379.0" user="Memories_of_You" delta="False">
    <text>As well as fill out a 12 page application, submit your finger prints and photo to the bureau of tobacco, alcohol, and firearms, have them do a background check and then wait forever.  You don’t just pay a fee and pick one up.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126641648.0" user="plzhlpwthtrk" delta="False">
    <text>It's like slightly more onerous than getting a passport...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126637968.0" user="plzhlpwthtrk" delta="False">
    <text>"Military level assault weapons" is just silly.  

What quality of a consumer rifle makes it qualify for that label that wouldn't be just as useful for hunting or self defense?

Semi-automatic fire makes follow up shots when you miss WAY more likely to hit, especially when using an optic.    Pistol grips and folding stocks make the gun easier to carry and easier to aim for some folks.  It can't be the caliber because .223 really isn't very large when compared to large game calibers like .308.

What makes a military rifle different is the ability to throw more than one bullet downrange when you pull the trigger.   That's useful in a firefight but not really so much for hunting or home defense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126782058.0" user="hannasf" delta="False">
    <text>Exactamundo.  My Ruger 22 is semi automatic.  I've used it to kill fox, porcupines, raccoons, and also sick farm animals. It looks like an air gun. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125383337.0" user="samirillion" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but a better summary would be good. Just like min three- max five sentences to explain a vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125945866.0" user="Chabranigdo" delta="False">
    <text>"What part of 'Shall not be infringed' was too hard to understand?" only takes a single sentence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126775707.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31127484920.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>u/hannasf – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+hannasf&amp;amp;message=hannasf+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/-/eas2tuj/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126119501.0" user="scandii" delta="False">
    <text>here in Sweden guns are also legal for your use case.
however that also requires a written exam on pretty much everything hunting as well as proof of ownership of a gun cabinet.

this is seriously enough to disuade most people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126828937.0" user="hannasf" delta="False">
    <text>In most states you need to pass a class to get a hunting license.  Now the difference here is that we have a Constitutional right. The same people who rail against voter ID often want to set limits on the Second Amendment. You either have a right or you don't.  Most people with multiple weapons have a gun cabinet, however, owning one does not mean you will use it. 

More people are killed by means other than guns.  But guns grab the headlines. Who cares about a junkie overdosing or a drunk driver hitting a tree?  Or some old fool who kept smoking after he was diagnosed with heart disease?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126629507.0" user="doubleplushomophobic" delta="False">
    <text>But tons of guns from Vermont end up in ny and mass, where they are not used to fend off coyotes. This isn’t a fun control argument, but you can’t portray Vermont’s gun policy as un an-allayed positive. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126773210.0" user="hannasf" delta="False">
    <text>So I should lose my chickens and rabbits because you have low lives in NY and MA?  Don't think so.  Have you ever had to pick up chicken carcasses from the back forty? ( I'm guessing you don't have a back 40)  You ever have to wrangle with a rabid raccoon or skunk?  Or if you did, you probably called "people " to deal with it. We don't have "people". Game warden may or may not show up with a trap in several days. 

Detroit and Chicago  tried to blame Indiana for its crime because people got guns there. What sophistry. Detroit, MA and NY can set up stop and search  at the border if they are so determined to enforce their laws. It's not VT's or ME's job to make life easier for MA.  Come to the Kittery Trading Post and Cabela's any Saturday. Parking lots right full of MA cars. Go shopping in NH.  Parking lots right full of people from MA avoiding sales tax.  Police your own people. It's not our job to do it for you. State Police take a good look at cars from NY and MA coming into Maine and VT for drugs. The epidemic in northern New England is from drugs coming from the Bronx and Lawrence, MA. How about you guys doing your job to police them?  Then they won't be driving north to trade guns for drugs because they addicted the dairyman's daughter.  Oh, MA is not responsible for the drug addiction in rural New England?  Then VT and ME are not responsible for the gun crimes in MA. 

It's a splendidly positive policy. And just think. The Supreme Court will back it up. Even Bernie knows that blue Vermont would lose its crap if he turned gun control happy. Angus King knows that in Maine. 

Oh, and Maine has Constitutional Carry. They don't even need a permit for concealed carry. Has the crime rate skyrocketed?  Nope. But a few crimes have been stopped because armed citizens have intervened. Google "Augusta Walmart parking lot.  Citizens arrest" for starters. 

Solve your own problems. Fix your own people. We don't owe you a lifestyle change because you have thugs in your states. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31128860418.0" user="doubleplushomophobic" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, I’m from rural Oregon and live in northern vt, Fuck the chickens, I’ve lost cats and dogs to predators. I don’t know why you’re accusing me of being some city slicker. 

None of these laws would stop you from being able to protect your animals.

Why does a convicted felon from out of state not being able to buy a weapon bother you? It doesn’t influence you in any way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
