<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="72" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31127995794.0" user="Babybaluga1" delta="False">
    <text>I truly do sympathize with OP’s frustration and do understand that politicians often make boneheaded decisions or vote along party lines. The problem lies in the proposed solution: placing such a requirement on legislators may become too coercive.

Representatives should be given significant freedom to vote as they see fit because they have been elected to speak for their constituents. Who would enforce such a requirement? It obviously couldn’t be an outside body because that would violate the separation of powers. So it would have to be the body itself. So what happens if a democrat writes an “unsatisfactory” justification in the eyes of a republican controlled house? You might say that the justification need only be short and sweet. But then this would encourage legislators to simply provide their party’s talking point, something they already do.

The good news is, there are two ways we can achieve a similar result without hitting these hurdles:

1. Committees: They do the heavy lifting in terms of analysis and policy justification. Committee findings and transcripts are accessible online. Essentially committee transcripts will help indicate how the party feels about legislation. I know this doesn’t solve the problem of legislators thinking independently. However, it at least helps show the party block’s justifications.

2. Statute policy statements: Some statutes provide brief policy statements before law. This doesn’t help explain the no votes. But it does help explain the yes votes. The legislator could pass a law which says every bill must contain a 1 page statement. 

3. Campaign finance and lobbying reform: the status quo currently incentivizes legislatures to not think for themselves. Say I’m a gun loving second amendment republican. Say I have a 500 page bill in front of me and I have an NRA-1 page fact sheet about the bill. Which one do you think I’ll read? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
