<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="66" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31127384835.0" user="KnightHawk37" delta="False">
    <text>What you're asking for is that legislators be qualified for their positions, and that they publicly explain what they are doing and why to the populous. That is completely unreasonable, and here is why. Currently the only qualification any legislator has is the ability to be elected and re-elected. Everything else they do is in service to that single aspect because if they cannot maintain their positions then they cannot continue to do anything in said position. This is true for good and bad legislators alike. Time and time again you see that the growth of a visible conscience in a legislator is a thing that precipitates the end of their career.

There is no incentive for them to do anything other than what is needed to be elected and re-elected. Many people think term limits will correct this, but what will really happen is they will all be rookies. The opposite must be true then, but there needs to be some way to remove a person who no longer serves in the interest of the people.

If, somehow, legislators where required to do as you say without first changing the incentives they already have you would no doubt find that they will pay written lip service to this. All of the ones with the same voting pattern would likely submit a copy/pasted version as each other after having agreed internally that they all have the same reasoning. This is basically what they already do. Each party agrees on their reasoning and they tell each other what the party is doing and they all follow suit.

These people have already proven time and time again that they are very clever wordsmiths (if they were not then they would not have their positions). Forcing them to prove that yet again would not actually make any progress toward anything other than giving them yet another way to present their same arguments.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
