<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125354036.0" user="notshinx" delta="False">
    <text>I very much like your idea, but I see one flaw. Congress is already slow; if you have to force 635 people to submit and keep track of written records analyzing an entire bill (many of which are as thick as books), they will take even longer and further lower their productivity.

This could be better addressed if various parts of the McCain-Feingold act were reinstated or made even more strict. If only individuals could donate a maximum amount to politicians campaigns, the campaign finance part of one's interest would be eliminated. If assets were forced into blind trusts for the session (which they may already be), then they have no personal monetary incentive. This approach solves a lot of other problems and doesn't reduce congress' efficiency at the same time. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
