<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="56" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31126468420.0" user="seattlechunny" delta="False">
    <text>I believe this had been said before, but I do want to clarify something. Are you saying that each legislator should always publicly post their reasoning for every single bill, or that when called upon, should be able to explain their vote?

I believe that the latter is already being done. Every time that I've been concerned about my legislators, on the local, state, and federal level, doing something that I felt was questionable, I've felt comfortable writing an email to them expressing my views and asking for their opinions. They've almost always gotten back to me within 2 days - probably their staff responding to me with a message that the representative had already prepared, but it did give me good insight into what they were thinking. Afterwards, I would typically respond, expressing my understanding or continued dissatisfaction of their position. 

Perhaps the reason why they shouldn't need to be explaining how they voted in every single vote is purely in the numbers of how many obscure things they have to vote on. From looking at the (2017 Congressional Report Card)[https://www.govtrack.us/congress/members/report-cards/2017], most representatives submit multiple bills, with some sponsoring hundreds. Does every representative need to justify how they voted in every one of them? And that doesn't count all of the votes in committee, or by roll call, or by a bunch of other ways!

While it is the legislator's responsibility to represent the people, I think what you are expecting is almost over the top. Perhaps that would make sense for *major* legislation, but then you run into the question of what counts as major or not. I think a better way would be to expect legislators to respond promptly to your request for their explanation, and vote against them if they do not. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
