<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="51" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31126305246.0" user="canopus12" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I voted to pass this CMV into law, because I think it will introduce a much needed transparency to the government

&amp;gt; I voted not to pass this CMV into law because it is a pointless waste of taxpayer dollars.

Both arguments are reasonable, and a hypothetical lawmaker can choose which ever argument he wants to formally write up, based on who paid him. Simply forcing a lawmaker to reveal *one* reason for their vote doesn't make it the real reason, nor does it preclude lobbiers from being the real reason.

Additionally, what counts as a good source? Flat earth politicians will vote for those policies based on dubious sources, but how could it be legally shown to be dubious? Same for anti vaxx - plenty of 'sources' for that. Or climate change - I'm sure a politician can dig out a 'study' which supports voting against any laws to deal with it. So all such a summary would really do is tell you that the politician is good at spin, twisting the facts, and not that he has a rational reason for voting for or against a law.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
