<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31125518361.0" user="grumblingduke" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing.

The European Parliament has 750 members.

At the last Plenary session, (12-15 November) they had something like 162 separate votes. And those are just the ones that went to a formal roll call. Sure, not every MEP will vote on every issue, but we're still looking at something like 100,000 paragraphs or page summaries with sources. And that's just for one month.

Instead we have a system whereby if you want to question an individual representative's vote on a matter, you do it directly with them. And if they don't give you sufficient answer you vote against them in the next election (or even campaign against them).

It's not perfect. But I'm not sure how must better your system would be. Perhaps it will work better for smaller legislatures that don't vote as much.

Of course, even if that did happen, what makes you think that the representative would be entirely open in their response? Say they were influenced by the NRA to vote some way - the NRA will have provided talking points somewhere, and all the representative needs to do is repeat them (ideally rephrased), without disclosing where they came from. There's no way to prove that what's in their response is actually why they voted the way they did, or if they believe it. It's just the excuse they gave - and politicians tend to be very good at coming up with excuses.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
