<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="607392345.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a1mixl/cmv_legislative_bodies_should_be_required_to/">
    <title>CMV: Legislative bodies should be required to explain, in formal writing, why they voted a certain way when it comes to legislation.</title>
    <original_poster>01123581321AhFuckIt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think publicly elected officials responsible for driving policy and legislation should be required to explain why they vote certain ways in writing. Voting along party lines is reprehensible regardless of the side. Politics shouldn't be a game about which side wins, but rather which fact-based opinions win regardless of sides. If the legislative bodies have no reasonable explanation for why they voted a certain way besides voting along party lines, they should not be allowed to vote because we have no reason to believe that they're not voting out of self-interest. If, for example, someone in Congress voted against what seems to be reasonable gun law without explanation, but you can see in their financial disclosure that the NRA contributes a lot of money and support for them, how are we to know that their vote was not influenced by the NRA without them explicitly citing so and explaining what other reason compelled them not to vote for said reasonable legislation? I'm not even asking for a long written response from them. A short paragraph or page summary with sources they're using to base their vote on is good enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31124975288.0" user="MasterLJ" delta="False">
    <text>What determines "reasonableness" or a "good reason"?  These subjective systems are just never going to work.  Who watches the watchers?  You seem to be focusing on the NRA, which gives me an objective point to pick on.  The NRA is an interest groups of citizens, with very little industry money injected, who are pretty low on the overall [Congressional donor list](https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/summary.php?id=d000000082), compare that to whichever other industry you like. I also guarantee there are reasonable arguments against "reasonable gun laws" that you are probably envisioning, starting with SCOTUS precedence, including something as simple as Registration, or Universal Background checks that store data.  

I've often fantasized about a Datatocracy, where you have to pick the metrics, and how they are defined, that you are trying to improve (increase/reduce, whatever), and the timeframe.  If your law doesn't have the correct impact in the timeframe provided, it's automatically repealed.  There are tons of issues with my suggestion too, but it's a step towards the objective.

EDIT:  Also, your system focuses on votes not cast towards "reasonable" things, what about votes cast for unreasonable things?  Again, citing your example of guns, it would highly unreasonable to pass anything like an Assault Weapons ban, given that rifles account for ~300 gun homicides per year (compared to about 9k+ for hand guns - source : FBI Table 8), and with Heller v DC SCOTUS precedence that accepts reasonable limits to the 2nd Amendment, but states that what is in "common use" is reasonable, of which, the AR-15 is one of the most common semi-automatic rifles out there.  Even so, if you pit reasonableness vs unreasonableness, you are right back where you started.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125197382.0" user="01123581321AhFuckIt" delta="False">
    <text>There is no such thing as "assault weapons". Assault rifles are pretty much impossible to get unless they're old. I am actually okay with most of the gun laws in existence today. I just think certain things like gun shows and ownership of an excessive amount of firearms should not be a thing. Anyway, I digress. I just used that as an example, not as the crux of my argument. You can literally put almost anything in its place that can be reasonable like legalizing and tax marijuana, net neutrality, not taxing energy independent homes for not being connected to a grid, etc. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31125235681.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126105149.0" user="UKFan643" delta="False">
    <text>But see, you’re using this word reasonable as if there is some sort of universally acceptable definition of policy positions that are reasonable. I think it’s completely reasonable to stop regulating the internet under Title II as if it’s the same thing as cooper telephone wiring but you obviously disagree. So in your world, any vote I make reducing that regulation would be unreasonable and my vote shouldn’t count. 

This is so patently absurd and against our civic values I can’t believe the large pile of comments you’ve read saying the same thing hasn’t convinced you that it’s a terrible idea. And, since I get to decide what’s reasonable, I am going to decide that your vote doesn’t count. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31126097075.0" user="geel9" delta="False">
    <text>What do you think about the idea that once a metric becomes a target it loses all value as a metric?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
