<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31133053551.0" user="FreshNothingBurger" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up.

That one I disagree with. The entire point of a home defense firearm is that it's ready to go *the moment you hear the proverbial bump in the night*.

That logically means it's quickly/easily accessible and *at least* in condition 3 (loaded magazine inserted, no round in the chamber), preferrably in condition 1 (loaded magazine inserted, a round in the chamber, safety on). 

Now whether that's a wise decision to make when for example children are in your house is a different question entirely (I'd argue it isn't). 

&amp;gt;especially those who hoard guns

What difference does the size of my armory make? If I'm determined to start killing until somebody ends my life, I will pick one and go - it really doesn't make a difference whether the cops find 2 more guns in my house or 20. 

Hell even professional warfighters rarely carry more than a rifle plus a sidearm just in case their rifle goes down, and that definitely doesn't qualify as "gun hoarding".  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133093962.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Not because of the likelihood of them using all those guns for something nefarious, but because I would venture there are some underlying mental health problems with some of those people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133133803.0" user="FreshNothingBurger" delta="False">
    <text>What's the difference between a "hoarder" and a collector? Where does one end and the other begin? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133139034.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>That should be for a mental health professional to differentiate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133191052.0" user="FreshNothingBurger" delta="False">
    <text>The *unalienable right of the people* should depend on the verdict of a single individual? How can you guarantee that this individual is not politically or racially motivated towards either side?

Should we do the same with voting rights, bring back the southern "literacy" tests to determine whether somebody is fit to exercise his or her unalienable right to vote? Or should we institute a thought coherency committee to determine whether somebody should be granted the right to speak freely? 

How about the right to a speedy trial before a jury of their peers or protection from police searchings?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133249640.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>That is exactly how the judicial system works. Most decisions are made by one person- the judge. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133281409.0" user="FreshNothingBurger" delta="False">
    <text>You don't appear before a judge unless there's evidence leading to a credible assumption that you are involved in the breaking of laws while in your example you are to appear before a judge in order to receive permission to exercise your rights to begin with. No, it's not the same at all. 

Apart from that, there are jury trials and the ability to escalate your case to the next-higher court. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133329084.0" user="notmy2ndacct" delta="False">
    <text>That's some wild speculation you've got going on there. People collect all kinds of things for all kinds of reasons. You wouldn't assume a car collector was off his rocker after he buys his tenth car, would you? After all, cars kill many times more people annually than guns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133350906.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Most car collectors aren’t paranoid that the government is coming for them. Plenty of gun nuts are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133375669.0" user="notmy2ndacct" delta="False">
    <text>And plenty aren't, so it's illogical to assume every guy collector is an unstable person. I'm sure it would be easier to attack their position if every gun collector was mentally unstable, but that's not a factual representation of every gun collector. What you have here is a strawman fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134029314.0" user="SkaterMan" delta="False">
    <text>burn that strawman op</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134082722.0" user="cyclonewolf" delta="False">
    <text>Source (That is not anecdotal) please? This isn't a very good argument. It just kinda comes off like you don't like guns- which is perfectly fine, but it won't convince anyone who doesn't already agree with you which is counterproductive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134744178.0" user="FreshNothingBurger" delta="False">
    <text>Most governments aren't going around banning certain cars by feature or name either. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134729478.0" user="HolMat16" delta="False">
    <text>Umm no I disagree me having several rifles pistols and shotguns does not mean I have mental health problems </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135833399.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Did I say everyone? No. But the whole “don’t tread on me” attitude is damn prevalent, and that is literally people who think the government is coming for them and their guns are the only thing stopping it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133807145.0" user="WelfareBear" delta="False">
    <text>If you don’t lock your guns up, you’re more likely to be killed by them than some big bad home invader. The economics of leaving loaded guns around the house in the name of self defense don’t square up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134273057.0" user="JmamAnamamamal" delta="False">
    <text>Only if you count suicide</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135299313.0" user="dogboy49" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you don’t lock your guns up, you’re more likely to be killed by them than some big bad home invader.

Maybe.  So what?  Are you saying that my options for self defense should be limited because ***you*** (or someone else) thinks that the economic payback is not high enough?  While we're at it, maybe I should not be allowed to build a bomb shelter in my basement, since the economic price doesn't balance with **your** idea of what the economic payback will be.  In the end, the economic value of an activity ***to an individual*** is the only value that matters.  Not yours.  Not the government's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135935057.0" user="WelfareBear" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, that’s not how society works. Everyday we balance the economic impact on a personal vs social level. It’s why we make you wait until 16ish to drive, or do crack. The personal benefit you get by those actions is outweighed by the social cost. You should check out Social Contract Theory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135971268.0" user="dogboy49" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Everyday ~~we~~ adherants of the Social Contract Theory  balance the economic impact on a personal vs social level.

FTFY.  

Personally, I am not a big fan of any contracts (Social or legal) into which I, as an ***individual***, did not enter *voluntarily*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136013998.0" user="WelfareBear" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, so you’re what, like a sovereign citizen or something? Anyway, it doesn’t matter terribly much what you believe, because society is strong enough to impose it’s will on you. Which is lucky for us, because O wouldn’t want to live in a world where nobody considers the consequences of their actions on others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136267772.0" user="dogboy49" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Anyway, it doesn’t matter terribly much what you believe, because society is strong enough to impose it’s will on you.

Yeah, sure, might makes right.  Well, as long as ***you*** are part of the current group that is in power.  /S

&amp;gt;...nobody ~~considers~~ is forced to consider the consequences of their actions on others.

FTFY.  Just because I believe I should be free, that does not mean that I don't consider the actions of others.  I don't believe in agressing against others. My experience has been that I get the same treatment in return.

So, let's move away from all this theory, and get down to reality.  I have never agressed against any other human, neither intentionally nor accidentally, with my guns outside of military service.  Furthermore, I do not intend to agress against others.  How does **my** personal possession/management  of **my** guns adversely affect society?  Statistically (which seems to be the justification you have cited), I am unlikely to be a threat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136292907.0" user="WelfareBear" delta="False">
    <text>So seriously are you one of those guys that thinks the country is actually a corporation and like is a dick when you get pulled over? Like yell about misremembered maritime law?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137294802.0" user="dogboy49" delta="False">
    <text>So, no answer.  Got it.  Enjoy the rest of your day!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138856578.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Anyway, it doesn't matter terribly much what you believe, because society is strong enough to impose its will on you.

Glad we've clarified that society is using immoral force to coerce people into acting the way the majority wants.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
