<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31132651995.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132660273.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I’m more curious to see if anyone can defend that </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133484391.0" user="UnibrowStylist" delta="False">
    <text>Well are the guns loaded they are waving around?  I would say a lot of people do dumb stuff with unloaded guns and in my opinion thats alright but thats where I draw the line.  Some people are very careful to check the barrel, make sure its safe then act a fool with the gun to project a bad boy nature.  Thats stupid, but a lot of things are stupid and you can't cure stupid.

I saw this one guy brag on facebook about how he accidentally shot himself and wouldnt go to the hospital, so I get where you are coming from.

As far as the background checks and mental health checks, I disagree with that bc who determines whose mentally sound?  The govt could decide someone who votes a certain way cant own guns, dont think it hasnt happened before?  It has.

I like the israeli approach, everyone must own a rifle and go through gun safety classes (military service).  There are so many guns in this country and so many ways to get one illegally and easily, we might as well embrace the age old adage "if you dig yourself into too deep of a hole, keep digging".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134147538.0" user="FuZhongwen" delta="False">
    <text>First weapon safety rule: Treat every weapon as if it were loaded.

There is a reason it's number 1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135863988.0" user="UnibrowStylist" delta="False">
    <text>Ya I get it tough guy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132666914.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134070739.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/shieldtwin – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+shieldtwin&amp;amp;message=shieldtwin+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/-/eavl3j6/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133001267.0" user="nullagravida" delta="False">
    <text>Holy shit, THANK YOU. I've never found the ~~tight~~ right place to say this (bot keeps deleting me for not being a proper cmv) but why why why do people put perfectly reasonable, common sense, everyone-should-think-this views on CMV?! 

If we must, we could make r/HMASAPMUATV (Help Me Anticipate Stupid Arguments People Might Use Against This View)....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134069176.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Chaoticsinner2294 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), before [messaging the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+Chaoticsinner2294&amp;amp;message=Chaoticsinner2294+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/-/eavks0r/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
