<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31133366286.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>Would you extend this same reasoning to cars?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133373785.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it already is. That’s why you can get reckless driving tickets and get your driving privileges taken away</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133389599.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>But you could still buy a car with a suspended license. If you commit a gun crime you can lose the right to buy them.

I'm not sure I understand your position, what sort of change are you advocating for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133400285.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>You can’t title a car (at least in my state) without a license and insurance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133430291.0" user="ItsPandatory" delta="False">
    <text>But you could  wave your car around on social media or dress it up or make fun of someone else's overly safe driving and not lose your car.

Is there some change you are advocating for? I'm not sure what your objective is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133500024.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>Please cite this specific law.

A title is a document proving ownership of property. 

You may be confusing this with a *"registration"* with allows its use on public roads. There are many cars that are 'titled' but not registered. They are just illegal to operate on public roads.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134281370.0" user="DrHideNSeek" delta="False">
    <text>Not just a gun crime, any felony at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138862649.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Only on public roads. You can do whatever you feel like with a car on your own property.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
