<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31132863968.0" user="dustdealer" delta="False">
    <text>Can guns be fun? Yes.

Are toys fun? Yes.

Are guns toys? No.


There's a BIG difference between enjoying firearms and being unsafe with them.

You can have plenty of fun with a firearm in a safe manner. People that endanger themselves or other people by not following safety rules should lose their privilege to own them. I don't think you'll find anyone that will argue with my last statement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132896349.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I would like to agree that no one would argue, but there are so many stupid gun owners who believe it’s their god given right to own guns and do whatever they like with them that I’m hesitant to do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132917068.0" user="dustdealer" delta="False">
    <text>If I had to put on my "idiot hat" and think of things from their viewpoint. I guess I could complain and say that the 2nd Amendment allows me to own guns. Full. Stop. With no if's, ands, or buts. What I do with them is my choice and no police/government can tell me what I can own. And if they want to take my guns that I'm unsafe with, come and take them, etc.

/idiot hat removed


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132927233.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Something something cold dead hands something something Murcia...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133685389.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>So did they change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133736953.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>No</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133759971.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134031073.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/-7ofSpades- – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+-7ofSpades-&amp;amp;message=-7ofSpades-+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/-/eaw8ixv/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133760213.0" user="-7ofSpades-" delta="False">
    <text>Replied</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133761358.0" user="-7ofSpades-" delta="False">
    <text>Thrice


Wait maybe I should of done these in reverse order. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133761691.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>Why not? The view you came here asking people to change, "people who treat guns like toys aren't responsible enough to own guns" ~~is beside the point~~ is indefensible (at least in the United States), responsibility doesn't enter into it. By the law, they would argue it is their right. Simply being *alive and old enough* makes them responsible in the eyes of the law, by definition.

(I edited the above because I realized i could have been more clear)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133768552.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not arguing the law. Laws can be changed. I’m arguing what is responsible. And if you cannot be responsible with guns you should not own them. It’s not hard to understand. I have yet to see an argument that would change my mind on that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133808606.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, you weren't that clear in your OP. You said

&amp;gt; I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like.

Guns are their right? And they can use them how they like? They don't need to defend it. 

"Irresponsibility" is also difficult to qualify. But let's say we're going by-

&amp;gt; The Four Rules

&amp;gt;-All guns are always loaded.

&amp;gt;-Never point the gun at anything you are not willing to destroy.

&amp;gt;-Keep your finger off the trigger until your sights are on target (and you have made the decision to shoot).

&amp;gt;-Be sure of your target and what is beyond it.

So in the scenario you mentioned in the OP: someone does something dumb on social media with a gun, waves it around. Or is critical of the idea of locking up their guns in a vlog. Does that cross the threshold of 'irresponsibility'? Then what happens? When a cop sees someone not exercise perfect trigger discipline... that's when you take their guns away? Forever? For a year? They get a ticket?

(I just edited a sentence out because it came across as adversarial, I just don't think you're being as clear as you think you're being)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134499385.0" user="rpmisms" delta="False">
    <text>It’s only the second item in the constitution. No big deal or anything. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134500985.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>And what about the whole “well regulated militia” part? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134681314.0" user="rpmisms" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not a clause on the main statement of the sentence, which is that the right to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed.
So, yes. Cold dead hands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135118624.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135119832.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>u/bartnet – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+bartnet&amp;amp;message=bartnet+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/-/eax1na8/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/bartnet – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+bartnet&amp;amp;message=bartnet+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/-/eax1na8/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135128923.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>Super fair. Was this automated? Or are you that fast?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134782164.0" user="Bumpkin_at_home" delta="False">
    <text>See DC vs Heller Case, as this affirmed the 2nd to be individual.

Edit: downvote me all you want; but it's fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135242467.0" user="Morthra" delta="False">
    <text>The Supreme Court has interpreted that to not be a qualifier. That is to say, the right to bear arms is not contingent upon being part of a well regulated militia, instead, having a well-regulated militia requires that citizens have the right to bear arms.

So the Second Amendment essentially says "The government may not pass a law that restricts weapon ownership for any reason"

We ignore that for some regulation (such as regulation that essentially banned full-auto weapons) but the point still stands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135868265.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I think we need to remember that while the founding fathers were writing about these inalienable rights and how all men are created equal, they didn’t allow women to vote,  AND THEY FUCKING OWNED OTHER PEOPLE. It took another hundred years to change that shit (*by amending the constitution*), so maybe they aren’t the best people to look up to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136570709.0" user="jark831" delta="False">
    <text>But he's saying that the Supreme Court made the decision. The decision happened in D.C. v. Heller in 2008.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136579287.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that. However, I think we can all agree the Supreme Court is extremely politicized, and the gun lobby plays a huge part in this. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136594904.0" user="jark831" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that SCOTUS is extremely politicized...but I was just pointing out that someone isn't looking to the founding fathers to point out that SCOTUS has held a certain way in the 21st century

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136607625.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136984904.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>They also won a guerrilla war against a tyrannical government against all odds, so they probably know what you need to overthrow a government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137002007.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a false analogy. The government they were fighting had poor tactics for guerrilla warfare, something which has since changed, plus they weren’t fighting a military with tanks, drones, and F18s with small arms. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137025131.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>People own more than small arms.  Also the US has lost many guerrilla wars in modern times.  Seems like you just don't know any history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137109759.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>You are neglecting the fact that in those wars we lost the enemy was being funded/supplied by another government.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137175600.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>Whose to say that a government wouldn't fund a US revolution?  There are plenty global superpowers who would greatly benefit for the current US to be overthrown.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135954213.0" user="cstar1996" delta="False">
    <text>The court has also ruled, in Heller that "The government may not pass a law that restricts weapon ownership for any reason" is not true. As Scalia wrote, "the Second Amendment is not a suicide pact." There is not an unlimited right to bear arms in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138058309.0" user="FreshNothingBurger" delta="False">
    <text>http://constitution.org/cons/wellregu.htm

and

https://www.quora.com/What-do-the-terms-%E2%80%98arms%E2%80%99-%E2%80%98well-regulated%E2%80%99-and-%E2%80%98militia%E2%80%99-mean-in-the-Second-Amendment

The phrase "well-regulated" has little to do with "regulated" as it's being used in modern days. 

The same goes for the term "militia" - its not an organisation bur rather the sum-total of the armed citizenry. 

http://www.sightm1911.com/lib/rkba/ff_militia.htm</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138801870.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>The part that is clearly a separate provision, not a requisite? The part that courts have consistently ruled on as such?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134735433.0" user="skooterblade" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, you're one of those folks that thinks a bunch of slaveowners who didn't want to pay taxes or have women or non property owners vote were the ultimate wisdom on how a society should function, huh? Cool. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136434944.0" user="UltraChicken_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;slaveowners 

Slavery has been part of human history for a very long time. The pure fact that someone did something immoral in the past shouldn't invalidate everything they've ever done.

&amp;gt; didn't want to pay taxes 

They didn't want to pay taxes to a country hundreds of miles away when they had no influence in the politics of the said country, which is pretty clearly a shitty situation. 

&amp;gt; women or non property owners vote 

As with slavery, this was common with the times, and for most of human history. Stop it with the moral relativism, this was 250 years ago, and modern liberal values didn't enter the mainstream until after their death.

&amp;gt;the ultimate wisdom on how a society should function 

The US constitution was a revolutionary concept for its time. Prior to this point, most countries didn't have one single document containing the supreme law of the land. It was certainly flawed by modern standards, but you're deluded if you think it's fundamentally flawed because you're all in for that moral relativism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135110832.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>It's not the second item in the constitution, it's the second *amendment* to the constitution. An amendment is a 'change after the fact'. The "second item in the constitution" enumerates the powers of the office of the president, who they can pardon and when.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133364412.0" user="i_guess_i_am_a_scout" delta="False">
    <text>Does the text of the 2nd Amendment really say that, though? I find that I disagree with the current interpretation of it, which is, as you said, "allows me to own guns, full stop".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133684938.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>I posted lower in the thread before I saw that this was already brought up, but you should really just look up the 2A. It's really short. Here it is in its entirety. Emphasis mine

&amp;gt; A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, **shall not be infringed.**

So they would argue exactly that; it doesn't matter if they're using them irresponsibly, it's their right. Full stop. A similar example could be like, just because someone uses the air they are breathing irresponsibly (for instance tirelessly advocating for the second amendment) doesn't mean they don't have a right to that air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133979537.0" user="i_guess_i_am_a_scout" delta="False">
    <text>Right, and I struggle to see the relationship between maintaining a well-regulated militia and the idea of "guns for everyone, full stop". It's like the 2nd Amendment advocates gloss over that first part.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134050981.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, that is the angle I learned to take when arguing with the 2A crowd while toiling in the facebook mines. "Guns for everyone, without limits" is *one* interpretation of the amendment. Another interpretation, that I would argue is more valid, would be that "the right of the people to form a well regulated militia and bear arms shall not be infringed". If they want to shoot a gun so badly they can join their state's national guard. Because you know what will protect you against the 'tyranny' of the federal government? The sovereignty of your state. You know what will protect you against someone breaking into your house? The well regulated local police force. People aren't exactly dying from an epidemic of home invasions overseas.

I'm arguing with OP elsewhere in this thread not because I disagree with them, but because I think their arguments are nonsensical and shitty. If we want to engage successfully with with the 2A crowd's ideas we need to be (forgive me) armed to the teeth, intellectually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134438539.0" user="colemannugent" delta="False">
    <text>You should read [what the founders said and wrote about the subject](https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Second_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution) if you want to know how they interpreted it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135093991.0" user="bartnet" delta="False">
    <text>Are you super concerned with how they literally intended it verbatim in the 18th century? I personally am more concerned with how we as a society interpret and adopt it today. Looking this over though, the phraseology of earlier drafts of the amendment lean a lot more heavily on the 'militia' emphasis, so there you go.

&amp;gt; *The right of the people to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed; a well armed and well regulated militia being the best security of a free country; but no person religiously scrupulous of bearing arms shall be compelled to render military service in person.*

&amp;gt;Original text of what was to become the Second Amendment, as brought to the floor to the first session of the first congress of the U.S. House of Representatives. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134712677.0" user="kool1joe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I guess I could complain and say that the 2nd Amendment allows me to own guns.

I'd argue that this isn't entirely true. Just like freedom of speech doesn't allow 100% unmittigated luxury of saying whatever you want - the 2nd amendment is the same way with guns. This is apparent with laws that regulate who can own guns (background checks/felons being denied) what type of guns you can own (full auto guns being illegal) and where they can be utilized (banned from any federal land). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134254494.0" user="DrHideNSeek" delta="False">
    <text>I'm pretty sure it technically is their God given Right, at least in America. Isn't there language in the Constitution that says the Rights are bestowed unto us by God and that government is only to insure those Rights?


EDIT: I was mistaken, it's in the Declaration of Independence.

&amp;gt;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness. — That to secure these rights, Governments are instituted among Men, deriving their just powers from the consent of the governed...


http://www.ushistory.org/declaration/document/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31303244610.0" user="Hyperschooldropout" delta="False">
    <text>The way it was explained to me in school was that our rights are given to us from “nature,” not by the government or any sort of god. We exist, so we have these rights. That way, it can’t be said that someone who doesn’t believe in the same diety as us still holds the same rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132898034.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>But yes, shooting guns is fun when done responsibly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133254377.0" user="phoenixrawr" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think you'll find anyone that will argue with my last statement.

At least in the US, owning them's not a privilege so you can't lose the privilege to own them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134174817.0" user="SlickStretch" delta="False">
    <text>What about toy guns?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134431701.0" user="banable_blamable" delta="False">
    <text>Hahaha is that a joke? There's a sub called 'progun' that literally advocates for everyone on earth being able to own a gun</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
