<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31134841326.0" user="bcdhlbrg" delta="False">
    <text>It’s hard to know where to begin, so I’ll start with your final statement. I think this is a faulty reading of the gun laws in the United States, and therefore isn’t something that anyone should be asked to defend (despite the fact a number of gun owners have taken to social media in various capacities to affirm this parts of this particular view). 

“Guns are [one’s] right and [one] can use them how [one] likes.” We need to break this down. Gun ownership is a legal right in the United States—this is true. But that doesn’t mean that anyone can use them as they like. Obviously, you can’t murder at will with your firearms in any of the states…this is a limit on the way you can use your guns. All fifty states have a series of restrictions on gun ownership and use. It varies from state to state, but no single state has any law that permits completely unrestricted ownership or use of firearms (see all the various laws making murder, armed assault, under-age ownership, who can carry and where, and so on against the law (again, all of this varies from state to state, but no state is 100% unrestricted in these matters)). What state and federal law doesn’t do especially well is measure responsibility with regards to ownership. It’s a difficult thing to qualify.  

It’s important to note, since so many gun ownership advocates immediately point to the Second Amendment, that the function of that particular decree is simply to ensure that the federal government will always permit citizens of the United States to possess firearms—individual states, and even individual cities, maintain their right to define that ownership as they do (some are more restrictive, others are less restrictive, and so on and so on (and yes, legally, the definition of “well regulated militia” has evolved over a couple hundred years to get us to a point where the right to own a firearm is extended to the majority of citizens). 

What the second amendment doesn’t do is establish a measure of responsibility (at least, outside of the well regulated militia, which has been legally addressed in various capacities for a couple hundred years so that we are where we are today). This is left up to the individual states, and each state has laws that address this. One comment pointed out that, in the eyes of the law, if you are alive and old enough, then you this makes you responsible in the eyes of the law by definition. I would reject this, and modify it by saying that if you meet the requirements of you municipality to own a firearm, then your right to do so won’t be restricted by the powers that be, so long as you store it, transport it, an so on, within the restrictions of your local municipality’s laws. But, the law doesn’t measure responsibility in the way you are understanding it (the way I also believe responsibility should be understood, for the record). 

Without some sort of legal barometer for firearm responsibility beyond what individual states already emply, I think we enter a much more philosophical discussion when addressing your points. What does it mean to be “responsible enough” to own a firearm? And, as a society, how do we measure this? 
 
Let’s look at your assertions that guns aren’t “toys” and should be treated with respect. As others have pointed out, this is a fairly common sentiment amongst many gun owners. Speaking from personal experience, my father and other adults exposed me to firearm use at a young age while also instilling an awareness of the serious mentality one must adapt when dealing with a firearm. I learned very quickly that guns are dangerous, and as such, must always be treated with caution. They could only be used under circumstances in which it was clear that said use would not result in any harm to the user, or anyone within range of any bullet fired from that gun. They are powerful tools that must be treated as such, like any powerful tool. I don’t have any sort of data on this, but I suspect this is a common experience amongst gun owners—at least, those who grew up in families where gun use was a matter of familial and cultural heritage. As such, these sentiments definitely exist in the larger culture of gun ownership in the United States.

To me, anyone that picks up a firearm and treats it as anything less than a machine with the power to kill is reprehensible—on this, I think we agree (as do many gun owners). But again, we lack a legal barometer to assess the level to which one must demonstrate this mentality with regards to gun ownership. OP said in a comment that they are not arguing laws because they can be changed. They’re arguing for a definition of responsibility. But in order for a definition of responsibility to have any sort of weight in our society, it must be codified into law. And there are plenty of laws that govern and restrict the use of firearms in the United States (again addressing your final point: nobody can legally use a firearm in a completely unrestricted manner in this country). 

How, exactly, would you like to see responsibility addressed in law? I think your argument would be more effective if it were reframed. Establish a list of what you see as irresponsible behaviors regarding firearms that aren’t currently addressed by the law. Then, propose a series of legal changes that address them. For example: CMV, citizens shouldn’t be permitted to own a firearm until they’ve demonstrated an understanding of the laws regarding the use and storage of said firearm, as they exist in their state, as well as prove to the state that they aren’t otherwise prohibited from owning a firearm for previous criminal or mental health reason. 

When addressing the argument framed in that way, we can better unpack the limits of the Second Amendment, and what the various SCOTUS cases over the years have decided to allow with regards to federal regulation and the ways individual states can legally address the necessary qualifications for gun ownership. Maybe it becomes an issue of individual licensure, or maybe it becomes an issue of extended background and mental health evaluation. Maybe it’s a conversation about the federal government placing a hard limit on the number of firearms owned, the way there’s a federal limit on the amount of destructive capacity that’s easily available to the every day citizen (you can easily own a semi-automatic rifle, but there are additional legal checks for owning fully automatic weapons and destructive devices, and anything outside of those laws are illegal to own). 

Hopefully it’s a conversation about all of these issues, but we can’t get there until the initial premise is framed in such a way as to quickly get us past all the boilerplate nonsense we so often see in gun ownership discussions. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
