<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31133554181.0" user="Bara-ara-ara-ara" delta="False">
    <text>Why should anyone live to your standards? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133570955.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Why are people so against better background checks for gun buyers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133600809.0" user="Bara-ara-ara-ara" delta="False">
    <text>Again, why should anyone live to your standards?  

What moral mandate do you have to police the behaviour of others that are acting within the laws of the land.

What reason does there have to be to defend against such an unreasonable argument as yours?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133721058.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>If you think that it’s unreasonable for people to act responsibly and get background checks and mental health screenings before purchasing something that is explicitly intended for killing other things then there is no reasoning with you. Literally the only reason I can think of that you would be against those things is if you don’t think you would then qualify yourself to buy guns. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134777974.0" user="Bara-ara-ara-ara" delta="False">
    <text>Suddenly I'm the unreasonable one for not agreeing with you? 

I can't be reasoned with for not nodding along to your law change proposals?

And it's because I'm afraid I won't measure up to your standards?

Yeah. Sure.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135828161.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>No. You are unreasonable because you seem to think that gun ownership doesn’t come with responsibilities, with is fucking ludicrous. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136233308.0" user="Bara-ara-ara-ara" delta="False">
    <text>Paint whatever picture you want, call me all the names you want. I'm not the one saying the laws should be changed on my whim to suit my personal tastes.

You want your mind changed? Look at what your saying to me - not once have I mentioned guns. Your unreasonableness is ludicrous.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
