<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31135071530.0" user="alekbalazs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like.

I think it is absurd to think of owning guns as a right. When the 2nd amendment was written, they hardly had semi-automatic guns. They had no idea that almost any American should be able to walk into a store and buy a rifle that can fire as fast as you can pull the trigger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137016914.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>I think it is absurd to think of free speech as a right. When the 1st amendment was written, they hardly had hand-held mass communication devices. They had no idea that almost any American should be able to walk into a store and buy a phone that can send as fast as you can type..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137324456.0" user="alekbalazs" delta="False">
    <text>Terrible false equivalence. Nobody (or very few people) dies as a result of free speech. How common is gun violence in America? How many people were shot to death vs countries like Germany, Japan, or really any other country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137346893.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>Irrelevant.  If you can completely remove one amendment do to the fact that it is "outdated" then we must remove them all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137490653.0" user="alekbalazs" delta="False">
    <text>The 21st amendment was repealed. Does that mean we need to repeal all of them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137714471.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn't repealed due to being outdated.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137946958.0" user="alekbalazs" delta="False">
    <text>It depends on how you define "outdated"


Id say that after the prohibition era, We realized that amendment was "outdated"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137968212.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>It wasn't outdated, it was ineffective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138880096.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>It was repealed because it went against a basic principle of property rights. There was no legal precedence for the amendment to have ever been written.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139174129.0" user="alekbalazs" delta="False">
    <text>So the government overstepped its boundaries, which was later overturned? That sounds like a shitty law that was later turned over because it didn't match the tone of the times.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
