<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31133039998.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>Guns are not these unpredictable pieces of metal that you seem to think that they are. 

The only "real" rule of gun safety is to not point a loaded gun at something you're not willing to shoot. Without any supporting evidence, I'm not sure there's anything that you have to show that they're using guns in an irresponsible manner. 

&amp;gt; and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up

Locking up guns increases real gun safety if you have young children. 

If you do not have young children, there's no real reason to lock up guns because they're not unpredictable. A gun will not just magically go off. In every other scenario, there's simply no reason to lock up guns. 

&amp;gt; I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like.

A gun will only go off in the following circumstances: 

* The gun is loaded and has a round in the chamber 

* The gun has its safety disabled 

* The trigger is pulled 

When a gun is fired: 

* A bullet will be fired at high speed out of the barrel 

As long as the gun isn't defective and there aren't any blockages in the barrel, guns are incredibly predictable. 

There are far less variables when it comes to shooting a gun then when it comes to other activities. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133100837.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>The “guns don’t kill people people kill people” argument is old hat. Irresponsible people with guns kill people or themselves regularly, and wouldn’t if they didn’t have a gun. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134066273.0" user="cyclonewolf" delta="False">
    <text>The “~~guns~~ *cars* don’t kill people people kill people” argument is old hat. Irresponsible people with ~~guns~~ *cars* kill people or themselves regularly, and wouldn’t if they didn’t have a ~~gun~~ *car*. 

You should also be advocating for public transit, automated cars only, and walkable cities then as well. Drunk drivers and stupid idiots with cars kill people everyday.  People with multiple DUIs still have their licenses. If you fuck up with a gun, get a felony AT ALL, you can no longer own guns (in the US).  This is not the case with cars, which are way less regulated considering you can buy a ~~car~~ *possible killing machine* anywhere and anytime.  

Your other comments lead me to believe that you don't agree with this.
Those same people you are talling about being crazy and paranoid are driving on the road with everyone else.  If you want to claim that a higher number of gun collectors/owners should be seeing a mental health professionals than there are drivers, then i would love to see a source confirming this. It seems like you dont know many gun owners which may be leading to biased opinions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134518447.0" user="Flayre" delta="False">
    <text>We have car permits and you're right that people take this PRIVILEGE as a right instead. Plenty of people on the road that have no business driving, yet they still are. Laws and enforcement should be more strict, I don't think anybody is saying the opposite...

At the very least, gun ownership should be at the bare minimum considered like driving permits. Guns should not be considered an unrestrictable right, but like cars, they should not be available to anyone.

All kinds of dangerous equipment/tools are subject to restrictions, why should guns be an exception ?

Hell, even in Canada it's not even that hard to be able to own a handgun (I have that permit) and yet look at our gun crime statistics.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134744618.0" user="InertiaOfGravity" delta="False">
    <text>Are gun permits not a thing in the us?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134761425.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>That would be an infringement like a poll tax.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134985378.0" user="Flayre" delta="False">
    <text>As far as I know and depending on state of course, there are no permits for owning guns. Conceal carry and stuff like that, yes. There are checks when you buy them usually, too.

But nothing like a driver's permit... Where you had to take classes or else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136326787.0" user="Bumpkin_at_home" delta="False">
    <text>Most states require a form of test, then when you purchase, there is a federally mandated background check. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136936203.0" user="Flayre" delta="False">
    <text>Can you give me an exemple of tests ? I haven't heard of any yet, I'll try to see what I can find on google

Edit : So far, there's a background check like you said and for some states you apply for "permits", but there are no test or exam requirement from what I gather ? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136947979.0" user="Bumpkin_at_home" delta="False">
    <text>States like California, New York, Illinios and many others require a Firearms Safety Certificate in order to buy and requires a test in order to acquire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137007847.0" user="Flayre" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I found what you were talking about for California !

Kind of sounds like what I did here in Canada, though I had more comprehensive tests and more demonstrations.

Looks like for the majority of the U.S, guns are still pretty easily accessible ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137123047.0" user="Bumpkin_at_home" delta="False">
    <text>Not exactly. Big misconception about America that guns are easily acquired. At least where I live the basic process assuming you have nothing to begin with, is;

1. Take a 30 question on the firearms laws of your state and some federal.

2. Once passed, it is 18 years of age for shotgun or rifle, 21 for pistol (21 for pistol just federal in US). Then choose what you want to buy.

3. You purchase, then the waiting period of 10 days is now in effect. This is when the background check will take place.  Includes medical and criminal history.

4. Once you return after the 10 days, if it is a pistol, you will have to do a safe handling demonstration. Long guns, sometimes happens from my understanding.

5. Once you've completed safe handling; you now must prove that you own a safe or locking device. If you have neither this is where they will add the price of a gun lock to the total and you will walk out with one.

This is a commonality throughout most of the states. Regardless of where you go, you WILL have to have a background check done. The waiting periods may be the same or different, but some states may not have safe storage laws or maybe not safe handling. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31137786847.0" user="Flayre" delta="False">
    <text>From what I can see on wikipedia notably, states with such "strict" (by u.s standards) gun laws are definitely in the minority.

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gun_laws_in_the_United_States_by_state</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134673297.0" user="Pulsatile" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure how anyone makes this argument with a straight face considering how, unlike guns, cars are vital to daily life.

Even more ridiculous when you consider the CDC has been researching car safety for decades and the result is far, far less deaths per mile driven. Meanwhile Congress has prevented the CDC from researching gun safety.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134746137.0" user="InertiaOfGravity" delta="False">
    <text>The center for disease.control?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134893145.0" user="ThisBeCat" delta="False">
    <text>There is no “cars don’t kill people” argument because it’s not common sense to ban cars due to traffic accidents. There’s only a “guns don’t kill people” mantra because people needed a catchy way to push back at common sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136470323.0" user="UltraChicken_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The “~~guns~~ *cars* don’t kill people people kill people” argument is old hat. Irresponsible people with ~~guns~~ *cars* kill people or themselves regularly, and wouldn’t if they didn’t have a ~~gun~~ *car*. 

In the state of Pennslyvania, we require 6 months of supervised practice, insurance, registration, and a practical exam before we let people drive a car unsupervised. Even after you're licensed, you need to obey strict rules for driving to ensure as much safety as possible. Accidents still happen, but not necessarily because of operator fault. Poor weather and road conditions can be factors. Cars also have the primary purpose of transportation.

We require a background check for a gun. No license for it, nor insurance in case you harm another person. For something designed for the purpose of killing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133459815.0" user="down42roads" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The only "real" rule of gun safety is to not point a loaded gun at something you're not willing to shoot.

Just to clarify, there are 4 real rules of gun safety.

* Always treat them like they are loaded
* Keep your booger hook of the bang switch until ready to fire
* Never point it at anything you aren't willing to destroy
* Be sure of your target and what is beyond it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134386968.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>This guy is an irresponsible gun owner </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134757563.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing he said would lead me to believe that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134769835.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The only "real" rule of gun safety is to not point a loaded gun at something you're not willing to shoot.

There are a great many other safety rules to follow than just that one.

Theres things like knowing your backstop, ensuring you're using the appropriate ammunition, knowing your target, finger indexed until ready to fire, proper weapon maintenance, securing weapons, treating any weapon as loaded, etc.

This guy is irresponsible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134777619.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>That rule is the conglomeration of the four rules. It was weird of him to say it was "the only real rule" but it is still correct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134782659.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>No no it isn't.
That's exactly the attitude that gets people killed.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134788344.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>Are all these rules equally important? Or is it possible that there is an order of importance? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134797597.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, all safety rules are equally important and should be followed.

Thats called being a responsible gun owner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134803232.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>I wonder if it's possible to condense all the safety rules into a single sentence...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134812750.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>Doubt it. 

How would pointing the weapon in a safe direction going to prevent someone hurting themselves using improper ammunition?

Or stopping a child from getting a loaded weapon?

How about knowing whats behind your target? Or understanding the penetration properties of the weapon?

Say you point the gun in any direction, but you pull the trigger because you put your finger in the trigger housing? Is that not unsafe? 

What about during a draw? People have shot themselves on draws.

What about ricochets?

You should stop.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134833146.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>So, how many safety rules do you have? Why weren't these issues to me when I took RSO training?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134878888.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>1. A lot. Those rules are written in blood. In other words, someone died and as a result a rule was learned

2. Because you have insufficient training.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134883925.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>It was the Marines after all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134885832.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>The Marines I know take weapon safety very seriously. 
The Marine run ranges I shot one were also very stringent. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134888323.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>Treat every weapon as if it were loaded.

Keep your finger straight and off the trigger until you intend to fire.

Never point your weapon at anything you don't intend to shoot.

Keep your weapon on safe until you intend to fire.

These are the USMC weapon safety rules, btw, and every Marine, last I knew, was required to memorize them. 

A range safety officer would absolutely be required to memorize them as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134897807.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>It's not like I don't have them memorized. I'm only saying that restating these rules as one sentence would make the most important gun safety rule. I dont know why you're fighting me on this.

Gun safety is paramount. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134898448.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>Not to you obviously</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134906723.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>You don't know anything about me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134907698.0" user="TheAnomaly85" delta="False">
    <text>I know you don't take gun safety seriously.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134923628.0" user="doogles" delta="False">
    <text>Ok.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134581510.0" user="Spike_N_Hammer" delta="False">
    <text>I think you might need to look up information on gun accidents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31303255001.0" user="Hyperschooldropout" delta="False">
    <text>That part about guns only going off if the trigger is pulled isn’t true, always. Have you ever heard of a “slamfire”? It’s where a sufficient impact on a firearm, in certain circumstances, could set off a bullet in the chamber. I own an antique rifle, a Russian SKS, that is known for having this issue. There are spring loaded firing pins that fix the problem, but obviously not everyone has them. For this reason, it is never safe to store an SKS chambered.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
