<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31133901104.0" user="destroy233" delta="False">
    <text>What exactly does “dressed up” mean? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133961411.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>The one that comes to mind are the “guns don’t kill people” people who post pictures of their guns allaying around the house or doing household chores/the like. I’m sure if you google it you’ll find some examples </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133985643.0" user="destroy233" delta="False">
    <text>Assuming I understand what you mean, that’s just trashy behavior akin to “flexing” your money or drugs. I fail to the see the issue with posting “dressed up “ photos. Now if there is a young child in the house then yes, not properly securing your firearms or flaunting that they aren’t is extremely irresponsible. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134989739.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;people who post pictures of their guns allaying around the house 

If you take a picture of your gun sitting there, you are in control, so where is the problem? You don't know if he took it out of the safe to take the photol.

&amp;gt;or doing household chores/the like 

Again, what's the problem? Secured in a holster is how police carry their guns for their jobs all day long. 

It seems more that you object to people showing guns as daily objects instead of vilifying them like you would want to see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136482848.0" user="UltraChicken_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;police carry their guns for their jobs all day long.

Police have to take months-long courses to become certified police officers, who carry these weapons in order to carry out their **job** of protecting the public and keeping order. If they use the weapon, they're held publicly accountable. An average joe isn't the same as a policeman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136994161.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>Most of the academy isn't dedicated to firearm handling.  Most of it is academic learning of what actions break what laws.  I know children who could easily pass the POST test.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138819154.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>My entire job is to handle weapons and use them to kill people. I spend maybe four or five days at the range total a year.

Cops don't spend the entirety of their police academy at the range learning gun safety.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31140991091.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Police have to take months-long courses to become certified police officers

Most of that is rules, regulations, laws, stuff like that. Very little of it is firearms training. Your average gun enthusiast is much better trained in firearms than the average police officer, who only got the little bit of required training and shoots his gun maybe once a year for mandatory qualification. 

I recently read a story of suicide by cop. The officer first shot four times from 30 feet, hitting the grass, a tree, a car, and a house. No, they certainly are not all highly trained in firearms. 

&amp;gt;who carry these weapons in order to carry out their job of protecting the public and keeping order

Right. Their job. It makes the use of their guns a much more complex issue since they can be on the offensive, using their gun to enforce laws. But someone carrying at home has one simple use: self-defense. It's much less of a risk than an officer. 

&amp;gt;If they use the weapon, they're held publicly accountable.

Anybody who uses a weapon improperly can be held accountable. That's not special. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138815817.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think they are just leaving them around the house with no supervision on them? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
