<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="27" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31219531310.0" user="thumbsofkolo" delta="False">
    <text>Well OP (u/snbrd512) I hope you are still replying to this I will take a non 2nd amendment standpoint to this. You talk about people showing off with guns immaturely and recklessly on social media

 In canada we require licenses for firearm purchases and use nation wide. You have to be approved by the government you meet the government standards to use a dangerous piece of machinery that when used is capable of harming/killing the user and others around it.

The same goes for our cars as in the US. You need to prove to government standards that you can operate a vehicle safely and legally to be allowed to drive one. Yet every day I would be willing to bet 95 percent of people speed. Change lanes without signalling, don't check their mirrors when reversing all dangerous or at the very least not taking full precautions.

The same goes with guns. Just because they act recklessly does not mean they are not aware of how dangerous their weapon is nor does it mean they are not responsible enough to own it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
