<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31132841700.0" user="HeyYallWatchThiss" delta="False">
    <text>I would ask why you feel that those who "hoard" guns require special treatment?

More to your point, I would be interested to see an example of mocking gun safety. Many gun owners do not lock their guns, this is true. However, I would argue that this need to lock them all up is situational. If I had toddlers in the house, you'd best believe I'd have one. If all I had was me, then I would feel less of a need to lock them up. In particular, a self defense weapon needs to be readily available. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132850658.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Because I would venture to say that many people who Hoard  guns do so out of either paranoia or a hoarding disorder. The whole “I’m gonna fight off the might of the US military with my stockpile of guns” type. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132949710.0" user="HeyYallWatchThiss" delta="False">
    <text>I would disagree. Take a hop over to r/guns. You'll find that most people simply enjoy collecting them. I can attest to this as well. Do I like the idea of fighting for freedom? Sure. But then I also enjoy collecting. The nature of the collection is no more cause for concern than any other hobby. While it does, of course, have more potential for destruction, I don't believe that most of our gun related problems stem from die hard collectors, or even full blown survivalists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31132961121.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I got no problem with collecting. But I don’t think any can disagree that there are some people who do it out of paranoia, and I think a mental health professional should take a hard look at people like that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133032692.0" user="HeyYallWatchThiss" delta="False">
    <text>Strictly speaking this brings  a slew of practical implications though. What is the number of guns that qualifies one for advanced screening? Is it going to make future permits harder to get? This would be, it seems to me, very difficult to legislate in such a way as to not have the effect of having large negative results on freedom for a modest/insignificant gain in violence prevention.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
