<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31134121346.0" user="cfuse" delta="False">
    <text>It's pretty simple: if you give people a choice of any kind then you must be prepared for them to choose differently than you. You choose to exercise your rights responsibility (as most do) but some do not. That's the price of a right. Gun ownership is in no way unique as a right under that principle.

For me this boils down to a political question: Do others have the right to make choices you wouldn't? That's not a Left-Right political axis question, it's a Authoritarian-Libertarian one. Authoritarians want to force you live your life according to their choices, libertarians want you to be responsible for your own choices. As with all political ideology it's a spectrum with caveats when people attempt to apply it in the real world.

No choice is free from consequence. There will always be accidents and abuses, rights or no. Unless those misadventures are intolerable then the utility of the right is likely to be more important than precluding it. A good example of that is the right to drive a car despite it being a deadlier weapon than a gun. More people are injured and killed by cars than guns. Hell, more people are killed by food than either. Unless someone can tell me why guns are special then as far as I'm concerned they're the same as any other utility with risks.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
