<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31132964623.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>Gun ownership in the US is considered a constitutional civil right. There are no limits to civil rights. It's freedom of religion in any circumstance, not freedom of religion as long as you don't join (what I consider to be) a cult. It's freedom of speech in any circumstance, not freedom of speech as long as you don't say (what I consider to be) something offensive or hateful.

You can treat guns however you want. You can't shoot others or even endanger them, but you can treat guns like toys or mock gun safety if you like. Waving guns around? As long as you aren't waving a loaded gun around another person, that's your right. Dressing up guns? That's fine too as long as it doesn't endanger anyone else. Mocking gun safety? Sure. All three of these are not just protected under the Second Amendment, but the First Amendment as well.

We live in a society where you can wave your hands around as long as you don't wave them too close to another person and punch them in the face. You can't even endanger them by waving too close that you risk hurting them. Anything else is your business. The Second Amendment is written such that there is no requirement to be responsible. You can wave guns around as much as you like in private. So everyone is responsible enough to own guns under current law because the level of responsibility required is zero. The only limits are not to hurt or endanger others, and none of the things you listed qualify.

If you are talking about the concept of what *should* the law be instead of what the law is, at that point any number of positions can apply. It's just as fair to argue that guns should be limited to people who are responsible as it is to argue that guns should be banned entirely. If you won't have sex for a dollar, but will have sex for $1 billion, we know what you are. We're just negotiating a price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134629440.0" user="Spike_N_Hammer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There are no limits to civil rights 

This is not true. For instance, there are limits and exceptions to free speech: incitement, false statements of fact, obscenity, child pornography (yes, it is different from obscenity), fighting words, speech owned by others, and diminished protection for commercial speech. A constitutional right is not free from limitations.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; The Second Amendment is written such that there is no requirement to be responsible.

The Second Amendment is 

&amp;gt;A well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.

 A well regulated Militia. It is quite possible that it was written with an intent to require responsibility. It is also possible that it was written with States in mind (security of a free State) not citizens. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134766905.0" user="Bumpkin_at_home" delta="False">
    <text>I am going to have to correct you on the last part; that DC vs Heller and I believe the Miller case from 195? has reaffirmed that the 2nd Amendment itself is a guaranteed individual right and does not require a state militia in order for the right to exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134806632.0" user="Spike_N_Hammer" delta="False">
    <text>From United States v. Miller

&amp;gt; In the absence of any evidence tending to show that possession or use of a "shotgun having a barrel of less than eighteen inches in length" at this time has some reasonable relationship to the preservation or efficiency of a well regulated militia, we cannot say that the Second Amendment guarantees the right to keep and bear such an instrument. Certainly it is not within judicial notice that this weapon is any part of the ordinary military equipment, or that its use could contribute to the common defense. 

This seems to strongly disagree with your position. 

While you are correct that in 2008 DC v. Heller held that 

&amp;gt; The Second Amendment protects an individual right to possess a firearm unconnected with service in a militia, and to use that arm for traditionally lawful purposes, such as self-defense within the home

To argue that there is not that ambiguity in the wording is ridiculous. Just consider that the law that DC v. Heller challenged was over 30 years old.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135834543.0" user="GoldenMarauder" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are no limits to civil rights. It's freedom of religion in any circumstance, not freedom of religion as long as you don't join (what I consider to be) a cult. It's freedom of speech in any circumstance, not freedom of speech as long as you don't say (what I consider to be) something offensive or hateful.

As others have pointed out, this is unequivocally not the case.  Voting is a civil right, yet in most states we variously restrict the right to vote of those who are incarcerated, on probation, have ever committed a felony, and even in some cases those in jail awaiting trial.  The right to free speech does not protect you when your speech is defamatory, or when it contains "a call to imminent lawless actjon".  And your freedom of religious exercise is incidentally bounded by many laws because their primary effect is not directed towards religious practice.

Obviously there's never going to be a law that says "being silly with a gun forfeits your right to own one", that would be absurd.  But civil liberties are not and have never been without exception. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
