<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608332769.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a26okh/cmv_if_you_treat_guns_like_toys_or_mock_gun/">
    <title>CMV: if you treat guns like toys, or mock gun safety, you aren’t responsible enough to own guns.</title>
    <original_poster>snbrd512</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, if you want to own guns, that’s your business. However, I see WAY too many people on social media doing irresponsible things with them. Waving them around in stupid videos, posting pictures of them “dressed up”, and posts mocking basic gun safety like locking your shit up. This level of reckless irresponsibility not only makes you look like an idiot, but is fodder for liberals who are scared of guns (that said, I am 100% in support of better background checks and mental health screenings for gun owners, especially those who hoard guns). Anyone who has ever been in the military, or even taken a gun safety class, should know that guns aren’t toys, and you treat your weapons with respect, yet many people don’t seem to understand this. 

I guess what I’m asking is for someone to defend the viewpoint that their guns are their right and they can use them how they like. 


Edit: so far I haven’t seen an argument that isn’t “SECOND AMENDMENT!!!!!”  which doesn’t at all address the responsibility aspect of my post. I get the law says one thing. I’m not arguing the law. I’m talking about whether or not someone is responsible enough to own guns. Maybe I didn’t articulate that well enough. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31133070864.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>Depends entirely on what you consider "gun safety".  For example, some one here on CMV explained it was law in their country to have their gun disassembled, in a safe, and no ammo in the house.  This is clearly ridiculous level of gun "safety".  

I will mock the shit out of that.  That is a law passed by someone who has never held a gun before.  That is a law that makes their population victims.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133083047.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>I’m guessing you are talking about Switzerland, which does this because everyone of age is technically military, and ammo is kept as supply depots. They have some of the least gun violence </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31133198112.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>I can't remember the country.  The point is that the level of gun safety is useless.  You may as well not own a gun at that point.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134263628.0" user="thesnowguard" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it depends what the point of ownership is. If your ownership of guns is to deter a tyrannical government disassembled guns owned by people who know how to assemble and use them still work. If the point is home protection then obviously a disassembled gun is very useless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134298789.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If your ownership of guns is to deter a tyrannical government disassembled guns owned by people who know how to assemble and use them still work.

Not until the government shows up at your door at 3 AM to take them away from you.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134312963.0" user="thesnowguard" delta="False">
    <text>True, if they managed to do that to the entire country at the same moment with no one getting any warning then yeah it would be quite useless</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134346864.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah lets just sacrifice the unlucky first people who get their shit stolen and probably murdered after.  Instead of just not being stupid in the first place...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135848612.0" user="snbrd512" delta="False">
    <text>Aaand here’s the paranoid “the governments coming for me” type i was talking about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31136356167.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>And here is a history denying person that acts like the government is perfect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31140494784.0" user="thesnowguard" delta="False">
    <text>I thought the point of a deterrent was it stops them trying in the first place. There is absolutely no doubt that if a government tried to take over that there would some death, no matter the circumstance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31140554727.0" user="Timewaster12" delta="False">
    <text>It serves both, as the deterrent stops the actual person kicking in doors for guns (aka state police) and the actual revolt is the threat to the politician or head of the tyranny (as the people would surely execute them.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31134994005.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>It's not Switzerland. You keep your fully-functional gun at home, and you can keep all the ammo you want too. Ammo is supplied by the government only for shooting festivals and in case of actual war. 

They do have some gun violence, but their rate of violence is far lower than other European countries with much higher restrictions on guns. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31135937640.0" user="Saxit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;because everyone of age

Every male of age (though women may volunteer). There is yet no separate rules for owning guns if you're male or female.

&amp;gt;is technically military

No. Just because you've done your mandatory conscription doesn't mean you've done military training; you can do civilian service instead of armed service.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conscription_in_Switzerland

&amp;gt;ammo is kept as supply depots

This is only for the state provided ammunition.

It isn't hard for a private citizen to buy ammunition really. You order a background check online (takes a week, and last for half a year), and show that and an ID at the store. You can buy any ammo and store at home. Instead of the background check you can also show a weapon owner's card (similar to the FOID in Illinois).

It's a similar procedure to what we have in Sweden, the difference is that here I can only buy ammunition that I can use; that rule does not exist in Switzerland.

They have the loosest firearm laws in Western Europe and it's easier to aquire a gun in Switzerland than in several US states.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
