<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31140031015.0" user="Hanginon" delta="False">
    <text>Do you even know or agree with the US Constitution, which enumerates the rights of the citizens and the responsibilities of the government?

The 14th amendment of the US constitution guarantees everyone *[the equal protection of the laws](https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/A1IwAHU9gLL._SY500_.jpg)*. The unintended consequences of your proposal would be that of making all but this group actually less beholden to the laws of the land, 

The real issue you are addressing is the lack of application of the edict of equal protection under the law, which is the same thing you are proposing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31141038517.0" user="Stormthorn67" delta="False">
    <text>Equal protection doesnt mean treating every crime as the same. Couldn't the use of the authority of law being abused to commit a crime (such as arresting someone as an officer, and then raping her now that I have her restrained) be considered an aggravating factor, similar to how things like premeditation are considered worse in cases of killings?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31141045968.0" user="Hanginon" delta="False">
    <text>Your example constitutes a secondary crime, which should be punished accordingly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31142674035.0" user="SecondChanceUsername" delta="False">
    <text>Does the 14th legal wording also imply not only "equal protection" but also equal consequences I.e. Punishments etc.

Then we cross into 8th amendment territory. And if one charge or punishment is considered too harsh for one citizen, then by definition it's too harsh for any/all citizens. 

I think most people in this thread agree that ideally, LEO, even the most corrupt should not be held 'more accountable' but the way recent cases against LEOs have been adjudicated it seems to a majority of the public that average citizens would be punished more severely and thus are in a sense punished for not being a government employee. Which I strongly disagree with. But in order to make up for an obvious bias that judges &amp;amp; prosecutors and juries have in favor of LEOs/ex-LE facing trial/imprisonment, i think a statute mandating equal or greater than punishment for corrupt criminal LEOs would do society well.

Truthfully, prison has not been proven to deter crime anyway. And once a crime is committed usually assuming it's serious enough, the individual will go to greater lengths not to get caught for the original one including committing more crimes. 
The war on drugs illustrates my point well. But that doesn't stop the enforcing of these harsh laws and penalties.

So therefore I agree with OP that those in positions of power should be held to the same standard but face higher stakes if they violate public trust. It will discourage abuses of power in the first place and give citizens true justice when corruption does come from authority. Many average citizens are already too scared to testify against LEO and that is simply not okay.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
