<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31139145225.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>I earnestly do not believe that on duty LEO's (Law Enforcement Officials/Officers) should not be charged more harsh than civilians that commit the same crime. I believe everyone should be treated fairly in the eyes of the law and any judge or investigation that is providing questionably favorable punishments for LEO's should be investigated themselves. There is a reason that lady justice wears a blindfold. Judges/Prosecutors have a duty to uphold the law and at this point in time they tend to actually have a harsher punishment in the long run. If a judge or prosecutor or lawyer is punished under the law, they run the risk of losing their license to practice law and in-turn have a possibility of losing their livelihood. Alternatively, issues regarding police officers should looked at with a open and caring eye. No matter what you did, the crime is still there and no matter what way you think about it, police officers are people too.
Police officers hold a job that could possibly be considered one of the most stressful jobs out there. They wake up in the morning, or night because they have to patrol even when you are asleep in your bed. They get dressed in their uniform and they put their duty belt on. They kiss their loved ones goodbye and hope, and I say hope because there is no guarantee that they will come back home safe after their shift. They hold a very high stress job that, in the heat of the moment, can yield very destructive results. No one is born a police officer, and no one is born a criminal. Officers of the law decide they wish to serve their community, protect their community, and keep peace in their community, all while they have to worry about themselves, their livelihood, their families, and other aspects. Police officers are righteous people who face fear and defy death to protect those who may not even know their name, and the side effects of that stance can be to much to handle at times. That does not mean they should be treated harshly due to their experience with the law, they should looked equally but with their stresses and experience within mind. 


Resources: 
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9WGLkQDy3Jk (Officer breaks down after shooting of a suspect.) 
https://youtu.be/5mEuHrm-GXU?t=35 (Demonstrates how fast things can go south in a law enforcement perspective)(skipped to 35 seconds because it is just driving)
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LuqVPPEgG08 (Police officers dont just shoot whenever they see a gun, they educate and they care)
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=is6mEWTdiD0 / https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OJ9slGZsRew&amp;amp;t=2s (officers are not always right in their judgement or their actions, and I do not intend to saw they are perfect)(Both officers have since been terminated)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139367903.0" user="jungleWorn" delta="False">
    <text>Police being receiving harsher punishment for committing crimes *would* be judging police officers the same before the law like every other person. 

In other disciplines: engineering, doctoring, lawyering, etc., these individuals are given extra privileges other people do not have as a result of their training. At the same time, because these people have been trained so thoroughly, a misuse of these privileges easily results in civil or criminal charges. Engineers, doctors, and lawyers who use their position to commit a crime are also often charged more harshly than a a regular person who commits a crime. Where I live, failure for a doctor to intervene when a person has a heart attack can result in criminal charges. Similarly, engineers can be held criminally liable if they approve flawed designs which kill people. Lawyers who act unethically can be sued. 

The reason these people are judged more harshly is twofold. Firstly, consideration has to be given to this person's character. While a regular person might not see the signs of a heart attack, a doctor has been trained such that if they *can't* then there is something seriously wrong that this person can study medicine. Likewise, when somebody becomes a doctor they have sworn an oath to fulfill their duties as a doctor. Don't like it? Don't become a doctor. This same line of reasoning ought to apply to a cop; you have sworn a duty to uphold the law. If you fail to do so, then you are judged more harshly because you have not just broken then law, you have failed to uphold the duty. Don't want that duty? Don't become a cop.

Secondly, when a professional breaks a rule, they are not just damaging their own reputations *but also* the reputation and good standing of the institutions which they serve. When Andrew Wakefield published fraudulent data linking vaccines to autism, he shook the public's trust in vaccines for no other reason than to make money. Likewise, when a cop commits a crime, their crime is even worse than when a regular person commits a crime because not only have they committed the same crime, but they have shaken the public's trust in police services. It's even worse if this cop has used their position, either explicitly or implicitly, to commit the crime, as this does even worse damage to trust in police as a whole.

Good cops don't get charged with planting evidence, or assault, or murder. On the other hand, bad ones should be charged, and if they *are* convicted it isn't unfair to take into consideration that they should have known better when we choose their punishment. Don't want to be held to a higher standard? Don't choose a job requiring a higher standard, plain and simple.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139390348.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>While I do agree with you about damaging the reputation of institutions and oath of service, but in the end we are not machines. We cannot flawlessly spot a heart attack and we cant know if someone has a gun or not until it is nearly to late. We are all people that have flaws and sometimes those flaws can stem from stressful environments that might be surrounding the individual during this time. Discussions of morality and requirements can be saved for later but I do not believe harsher treatment under the law (i.e longer jail terms or fines) is right for those serving under a official capacity. If they are convicted like a normal citizen, their harsher treatment will come in the form of a ruined career and being put out of work that requires special training and licensing that can be taken away if they fail to uphold their duty or are convicted of a crime. Their harsher punishment is that of humiliation and the reality that they will have to give up on that line of work and find one that requires a different skill set or no skill set at all. They cannot go back to the occupation they trained for or payed thousands of dollars in education for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139414159.0" user="jungleWorn" delta="False">
    <text>You're not quite getting my point. Giving a police officer a harsher punishment *isn't* treating them any different under the law. By virtue of a cop's position, when a cop commits a crime they *are* committing a more worse crime than a regular person because of the points I have already stated (i.e. 1. they are showing a character flaw because they ought to know better, and 2. they are eroding public trust in policing as a whole). *Just* charging a cop without regard for their background as a police officer *is* to treat them as above the law. 

Quite frankly, and I mean this respectfully, I don't care how much a cop's tuition costed or how hard they might have to look to find a new line of work after their commit a crime. We don't do this for any other professional who abuses their position, even in a high demand position. Cops have very hard jobs. I don't dispute that. However, we have to hold them to the same high standard we hold every other professional in a demanding job. You know what other jobs are really hard? Being a paramedic, an emerge doctor, a nurse, a soldier, an engineer working critical systems, but when these people fail at their jobs or abuse their positions they get charged nonetheless with no concern for how much debt that are in. There is no reason not to hold cops to the same standard. Again, don't like being held to a high standard like this? Don't choose a job where you are held to that high standard.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139430046.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not debating that they shouldn’t be held to the same standard, I’m saying that they shouldn’t have harsher laws like longer jail terms for a single charge just because they are a police officer. Why I’m trying to say is a police officer should not charged and sentenced 5 years in jail for murder when a normal person would be charged 3 for the same murder. Additionally in most states there are abuse of official capacity laws that tack on more punishment for public officials. Thus the need for harsher punishment of those, say in public service positions, should not have to have harsher punishment for crimes that can be committed by anyone. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139444915.0" user="jungleWorn" delta="False">
    <text>Charging a police officer 5 years instead of 3 years often would be holding them to the same standard as everybody else. As a cop, you should know better than an average person not to commit a crime, meaning your character is seriously tarnished if you do commit a crime. At the same time, your crime causes more damage than when a regular person commits a crime because of how you have damaged trust in policing. 

What all of this means is that a crime committed by a cop always does cause more damage than that of an average person committing a comparable crime, *because* of their position. Resultingly, a cop should be punished more harshly for the "same crime" because they cause more tertiary damages just by being a cop committing a crime.

Again, nobody is forcing anybody to be a cop. If a cop doesn't want to be held to a high standard, they can choose another career path with a lower standard. Just like a doctor doesn't have to keep doctoring if they don't like how they can be sued for malpractice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139455667.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>Again I’m not saying they should not be held to a high standard, they absolutely should. But they should not receive longer jail terms because they are officers. They already have additional charges placed on them because they are officers. EVERYONE has equal access to the laws of the state they live in, the city they live in, the county they live in, and the country they live in. EVERYONE should know better than to go out and murder someone. Just because someone holds an occupation that deals with laws, they should not receive harsher punishments for the same crime. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139467002.0" user="jungleWorn" delta="False">
    <text>You yourself admit that a cop committing a crime causes more damage (i.e. in the form of de-legitimizing policing to the public) than a person who commits the same crime who is not a cop. This alone means that a harsher punishment for the same crime is justified if we're taking severity of the outcome of the crime into account (which we do everywhere. There's a reason attempted murder nets you fewer years in prison than a successful murder).

Obviously everybody should have equal access to the law. However, holding people to a high professional standard in a career they *choose* to pursue is not denying anybody access to the law. As a police officer, one gains a great deal of privileges nobody else gets. Along with these privileges comes responsibilities. Nobody is forcing anybody to become a cop. Being held to a higher standard comes with the territory just like doctors who get charged more harshly because they are doctors. Don't like it? Don't become a cop. Don't become a doctor. Don't choose a high demand career. There are plenty of fields out there where people's lives aren't dependent on you not screwing up, and where you aren't acting as a representative for *everybody* in your line of work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139482380.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>You cannot logically believe it is right to punish someone harsher because it has a backlash on people’s opinion? You can’t logically believe that any court of law will take in the personal opinion or viewpoint of a person and consider it fact? That is not how the law works, just because a doctor fails to save a life because they couldn’t spot a heart attack but tried to help anyway despite the fact they were dead, it would not be fair or just to charge them for 5 years of jail time if someone who was not a doctor did the same thing. The reputation of people is based on public opinion, and public opinion shakes around constantly. Public relations with the institutions that employ those professionals that did wrong, the burden of dealing with that public opinion should remain with the institution and not with the law and the courts. The courts are here to deal with criminal matters and civil matters. They are not hear to deal with the PR backlash from a shooting or a failed operation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31140367721.0" user="ray07110" delta="False">
    <text>Everything you said applies to a human being that is free. But a police officer enforces the policy of the state against the citizens of that state. When they put that uniform on and do their job they are no longer a protector of humans but an enforcer for a ruling entity. This is were police lose their humanity and can not be thought as equal with its citizens, how can they be? They walk around with a gun in order to enforce the government's policies. The protector of everyday citizens are the citizens themselves. I alone protect my family against any bad force that is out there. Police come after the fact. Police enforce rules and collect money to stuff the state's coffers. I know a lot of good people who are police officers, but that does not mean they do not do the bidding of bad people. Good intentions do not equal good results. It is immoral to be a police officer and unconstitutional. Police officers holds people lives in their hands. Police is judge, jury and executioner and they hand out judgements all the time. A person who has respect for others never become police officers. There is a huge difference between an ordinary citizen and a police officer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31140994173.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that you believe that police officers and normal citizens are different is completely absurd. Police officers should and will always be people too, they are not machines that are manufactured to strictly enforce laws and make money for the government. Police officers are normal everyday people who have chosen to make a change in their community and to serve their community. Police officers have chosen to take up the duty to uphold the law and abide by it. Police officers have taken the charge to care for those who may not care for them, they have taken the charge to protect those who will try to harm them or harass them or who have no care for their safety at all. Police officers have taken the charge to protect not only their family, but yours, your neighbors and everyone else in that community. Police officers have the most humanity there can be. They care for others even when their life is on the line . “Blessed are the peacemakers, for they will be called children of god” Matthew 5:9</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31141507298.0" user="ray07110" delta="False">
    <text>Reference to Matthew is not about the police. Police officers are children of the state(satan). As I told you previously the police is an immoral career. The duty of the police is to enforce policy not "protect and serve". The only thing they serve is judgment and the only thing they protect are politicians and criminals. What gives you the right as a human being to be the only person to be protected by the state and shoot people? How is this on the same level as a regular citizen? You have the power of life and death in your hands and to take people's freedom away. How is this on par with normal citizens? How is it that cops can claim self-defense when they were the ones doing the assaulting and threatening? 
 You seem to have an affinity to man-made laws that borders on the realm of excessive admiration. You need to look into your own heart and have love for human kind.
 
Here is a Bible passage for you from Mark 7: 7 Howbeit in vain do they worship me, teaching for doctrines the commandments of men.

8 For laying aside the commandment of God, ye hold the tradition of men, as the washing of pots and cups: and many other such like things ye do.

9 And he said unto them, Full well ye reject the commandment of God, that ye may keep your own tradition.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31141998162.0" user="OlympusxGaming" delta="False">
    <text>You are correct in saying that the only sworn duty they have is to enforce laws and maintain order in their jurisdiction. However, most departments do not solely practice this. Most departments have prided themselves on protecting and serving the people of their community. They pride themselves on being there for those who cannot protect themselves. Under no circumstances are protected unfairly by the state. They have to follow the same laws as everyone else. It is their job to go out there and find the guns on the streets, find and seize illegal drugs, and protect and serve those in their community. I have an affinity for man made laws because those laws are what keep us as a civilized and rational society that allows us to have discussions like this. I have looked into my own heart and found love for human kind. I myself strive to be a blessing to someones life everyday, no matter how big or small it may be. I wish to become a police officer because I genuinely care for those in my community. I would be willing to lay my life on the line if it means that I am able to make my community safe for those who live there now and those who have yet to come. "Blessed are the peacemakers, for they will be called children of god" While it does not refer strictly to police, it refers to those who bring peace by any means. That can be said for police. They bring peace by ending conflict. They end conflict by enforcing the laws that are in place to keep peace. They bring peace by taking those guns that are used to shoot innocent people, and confiscating them and keeping them off the streets. They bring peace by taking that hardened criminal off the streets. They bring peace by risking their lives to hunt down and catch that serial murderer who just killed innocent children while they were learning at school. 

I end this post with one more verse

Romans 13:1 "Let every person be subject to the governing authorities. For there is no authority except from God, and those that exist have been instituted by God.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31163936381.0" user="ray07110" delta="False">
    <text>I apologize for the late response, I was pretty busy this week.

You agree that the police's mandate is to enforce policy with the idea of maintaining order. but maintaining order means maintaining the status quo that the state and its' politicians are your rulers and you either do as you are told by your rulers or face confinement or death. That is the order they maintain. Priding yourself in protecting and serving does not mean you are actually "protecting and serving" it just means that you are either making your self feel that you are or others are making you feel like that. The reality is that the police do not protect and serve in any community that they are established more than a regular resident of that community. Stats prove this. The state protects its police officers from prosecution routinely. they go under a different review process from regular citizens. When they are considered for prosecution their employment with the state as a policy enforcer weighs heavily on these decisions. The scale of justice is balanced heavily on their favor because of the uniform. Yes it is their job to get the guns and drugs off the streets as part of the process of ensuring that the citizens comply with the laws and regulations that do not produce any quality or safety to their lives, but puts them under threat of bodily harm by the strong arm of the politicians. laws do not keep us civilized but our love of humanity does. We are civilized because most of us understand the benefits of humane interactions not because a politician said we have to be good with each other. If you wish to become a police officer, then that means you don't mind hurting others to enforce someone else's ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
