<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31139026579.0" user="AussieMazza" delta="False">
    <text>Let's say that your idea was set into law and those who work in law enforcement are now punished more severely than those who do not work in this field (let's call it the **harsh law**). To me it just opens up more questions than answers (below are some I thought of just quickly. I'm sure others could think of more):

* At what point does the harsh law commence? i.e. is it immediately when a new police cadet is sworn in, or after they have been employed for a certain period of time? Surely those who have worked in law enforcement for many years have built up a much broader knowledge (and hence ways to circumvent the rules) than a fresh cadet straight out of school or college?

* At what level of law enforcement work does this law no longer apply? i.e. are people who work in an office capacity in law enforcement still subject to this rule?

* Does the harsh law apply only to people who are actively employed in the law enforcement industry or does it cease when they cease their employment? In the case of the latter, these people generally wouldn't have forgotten all that they have learned (short of a brain injury or similar), but in this case would no longer be tried under the harsh law.

* What crimes or offences will be judged under the harsh law? Will it be every transgression, no matter how minor, or just the more severe criminal charges such as assault, murder etc? Who decides this? (I ask this last question because if high-level judiciary decide this, there is a conflict of interst, yet they are arguably the best placed to make such decisions)

* How would this law actually be administered, realistically?

The biggest issue I see here is unfairness. The law is supposed to be just (I agree that it often isn't, but that's a separate discussion). This rule creates an 'us vs them' and opens up a pandora's box of questions. 

Realistically this kind of law would be very difficult to implement and adminster and would constantly be at risk of conflicts of interest, thereby negating any positive deterrent effects it is supposed to have. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
