<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31207203701.0" user="ZackaryCW" delta="False">
    <text>You list two examples of corruption, which is a very small sample size. I feel like your argument is more oriented towards corruption. I'm going to guess that you would agree that a corrupt citizen should receive a harsher punishment than a moral law enforcer. The aspects to which you warrant these people (the two examples you gave) receiving harsher punishments aligns more with corruption than an ability to enforce law; citizens are also capable of being corrupt. If a person has the ability to be corrupt, one could make an argument that increasing punishment for that is not a good idea. If one has the power to influence a punishment system, and if it is known that they will be punished more harshly due to the fact that they have influence, this will give them more motive to try and corrupt their way out of punishment.

I will assume that there is something intrinsic about law enforcers that warrants harsher punishments. With that in mind, I see some issues:

Claim: people in law enforcement should be punished more harshly

Reason: These two examples illustrate how some "who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it"

Warrant / Axiom: Being in a law enforcement position exempts them from the "full weight" of the law

I'm having issue with the warrant you seem to be implicitly assuming when trying to argue this claim. (If these aspects of your argument \[the claim, reason, and warrant\] aren't accurate, ignore what I'm about to say). Let there be a group P. P has the ability to carry a function over another group C. C does not have the ability to carry the same function as P. In this case, let this function be the arrest of people, let P be law enforcers, and C be citizens. There is nothing inherently stopping P from performing said action on P; that would be a corrupt function over C. Therefore, your argument must be more focused on corruption. From the two examples listed, it seems that your disgust actually comes from people being able to "get away with it." Law enforcers are punished for crimes accordingly since citizens can't do it. I think that arguing for harsher punishment on corruption is more potent that arguing for harsher punishment on law enforcement. Anyways, that's my take on it. It sounds like you're having a debate with your friend? Best of luck! :D</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
