<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31139177599.0" user="Glock-N-Roll" delta="False">
    <text>Should cops be held LESS responsible for crimes? - No. Nobody should get more rights than someone else, especially not to a point where they (cops) can easily abuse their power without consequence. 

Should cops be held EQUALLY responsible for crimes? - Yes. Everybody should always be held equally responsible for the same crime. 

Should cops be held MORE responsible for crimes? - No. Not only would that make cops more likely to abuse power to cover up their crimes, but it would also make cops less likely to *protect and serve* when needed because every action they make could possibly result in going to superjail, so they’ll be too paranoid and worried to make any actions. But most importantly, you wouldn’t be holding them equally responsible for their actions just as you should with anybody else. 

In short, everybody should always be held equally responsible for the same actions, regardless of their status, job, title, position, etc... with that said, there is (and has been) a very serious issue in this country with cops never being held fully responsible for committing a crime that any civilian would have been sentenced to decades in prison for. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31139391136.0" user="jungleWorn" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think many reasonable, good cops are going to fail to act for fear of being charged with a crime by acting. Doctors who make mistakes can also receive massive civil or criminal charges, but you don't see doctors failing to act because we might just hold them responsible if they fail. Quite the opposite, actually: because doctors know they can be held liable for their professional actions they make sure they're on their A-game. We should require the same of our cops instead of catering to the lowest-common-denominator cops who's already on the force.

Also, cops receiving harsher punishments for a crime they are convicted of *is* holding these cops to the same standard as everyone else. If I'm a doctor who uses my position to rape women, I'll be charged more harshly than a regular person who date-rapes an equal number of women at bars. The reason for this is two-fold: firstly, I should know even better than the average person not to rape women, and secondly my use of my position as a doctor to rape women has eroded the trust the public has in doctors. 

These same principles apply to cops. When a cop beats his or her SO, or beats somebody to death, or they do something else heinous, it is clear that as per their position as a cop where they deal with crime every day they *ought* to have known better. Likewise, their crime erodes the trust the public has in police as a whole, meaning that the damage of their crime is more than that of a normal person who commits the same crime and who has only caused the damage which directly comes from their crime.

There's nothing unreasonable about holding cops to a higher standard when this "higher standard" is one we apply to virtually every other professional across the board.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
