<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="608962307.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a2k6bn/cmv_police_and_people_who_work_in_law_enforcement/">
    <title>CMV: Police and people who work in law enforcement (judges, prosecutors, etc.,) should be punished more harshly for crimes than the average citizen.</title>
    <original_poster>TheZek42</original_poster>
    <original_post>Edit 2: on further deliberation with my friend (who holds another view on the subject, but previously couldn't explain it... He says that police officers are people too, "capable of the same mistakes and deserving of the same treatment[/punishment]..."

I disagree with this.

Original post:

With the recent murder of Botham Jean in Dallas, by a police officer who received "[favourable treatment](https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/dallas-police-officer-arrested-for-shooting-black-man-at-his-home-20180910-p502t1.html)" afterward (she was allowed to go free while the shooting was being investigated, despite having already shot an innocent man prior to this,) and the rape of a handcuffed woman *on the hood of the arresting officers car* \- a crime punished by [90 days in prison](https://www.newsweek.com/colorado-police-officer-who-raped-handcuffed-woman-he-was-taking-home-1238485) \- it's apparent that some of those who are trusted to uphold the law are also exempt from the full weight of it.

In my opinion, it's **disgraceful**.I believe that those who are trusted to "protect and serve" should receive the *opposite* treatment of what it appears they currently do - not a slap on the wrist, but the full weight of the law on their shoulders when the law they claim to uphold is broken by them in the line of duty.  


Edit: Italics

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31138711385.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>What are you saying exactly? If a police officer uses their authority in furtherance of a crime, that is in itself a separate crime, and they technically should receive a harsher sentence than if a civilian did it. 

Or do you mean police should be punished for manslaughter the way civilians are? Like if they are in a car chase and hit someone accidentally they should go to jail? I don’t think that’s a good idea.

The problem isn’t sentencing, but the close relationship law enforcement has with prosecutors and courts. Prosecutors need to work with police in the vast majority of cases, so they need the police to like them. Any prosecutor who is seen as being too harsh on police officers is going to have a short career.

One remedy some states have been looking at is creating [special prosecutors offices at the state level](https://www.brennancenter.org/blog/new-york-attorney-general-special-prosecutor) — either prosecutors whose only job is to work with internal affairs and go after corrupt and criminal police officers and other officials, or at least prosecutors who are not operating at the city level, where they would need to build relationships with law enforcement. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31138812873.0" user="jerrydisco" delta="False">
    <text>We give police officers a level of trust which we give to nobody else. If anyone flashes their lights at you on a dark road in the woods at night, the only time you’ll ever stop is if that person is an officer of the law.  We allow these strangers we’ve never met to walk up to our cars, knowing they are armed with deadly weapons, while we’re helplessly waiting to be interrogated. 

This trust should not freely be given, and if that trust is violated by an officer, than in my view they have lost their privilege to “protect and serve” me.

However, history shows that the police knowingly violate the trust and commit crimes against citizens. If these crimes can go unpunished or leniency will be given because the perpetrator is a cop, then what can I base my trust off of?  Why would I ever stop for blue and red lights, when there’s a small but significant chance It won’t turn out well for me, through no fault of my own? 

The relationship between citizens and law enforcement depends on trust, which is difficult to provide if we know that they can get away with certain crimes. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
