<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31159394084.0" user="beingsubmitted" delta="False">
    <text>I've done quite a bit of recruiting for my company. Obviously the company doesn't want to pay people more than they have to, but you would be amazed how much money we lose recruiting, and then training new employees. If we lose someone good who was here relatively long term, we have to hire on average 4 new people to replace them, 3 of which will be gone within a year... we'll get some productivity out of the new people, but they'll be training, so it won't be much. Most new employees barely pay their own salary here in their first year, and again, 3 of the 4 won't make it that long. No one is paying their own salary in their first six months. Altogether, it can cost 2 or 3 times what we're paying someone to replace them, sometimes more, especially if that person is experienced and highly productive. On top of that, if a seasoned vet leaves, there's a good chance they'll bring others with them. From a purely "business owners trying to get as much as possible from employees for as little as possible" you definitely have to give people enough to keep them around. Now, if you're unskilled or entry level, that's completely different, but generally speaking, we'll err on the side of good reviews. Bad reviews, for our company, mean one thing... we want you to not work here any more, but would prefer if you quit so we don't have to fire you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
