<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31161814398.0" user="NameLily" delta="False">
    <text>Plenty of businesses don't pay some of their employees as much as they should, that much is true.

But unless an employee sucks, businesses have every reason to give them deserved positive reviews. One of the reasons people stay at a place where they are not compensated as much as they could be elsewhere is because they feel praised and valuable to the company.

If a business were to not pay enough and to also give negative reviews to good employees, it would just be hurting itself. Such behavior would guarantee that their employees would always be applying to other companies and always looking for better jobs.

Employee turnover rate at such a business would be off the charts. They would only manage to keep the worst, most unskilled, most desperate employees. All the good employees would run to other companies.

Such a business would not do very well. They would be losing productivity, constantly be training new employees, etc.

This would be a terrible and very illogical plan of action for a business any way you look at it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
