<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="611555437.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a43r71/cmv_businesses_have_no_logical_reason_to_give_an/">
    <title>CMV: Businesses have no logical reason to give an employee a good review.</title>
    <original_poster>scroopynoopersdid911</original_poster>
    <original_post>Why would they? so that they have to give you more money? it serves no logical reason to give an employee a good review. If the point of the business is to squeeze any potential value out of eery employee why would they allow an employee to have something to point to when asking for a raise. In my case, my review has been deferred for another year because they won't give me a bad one and they know i'll ask for more money. Anyway, cmv businesses have no logical reason to give a good review. 


EDIT: Thanks for all the career advice. I actually like where i work and i do not think ill be leaving. this is not a veiled attempt to make me feel better or whatever. i'm just wondering from a logical standpoint. so..... you guys can stop making this a "lets give op career advice" thread.

EDIT 1: I will reduce my view to simply "is it not easier to replace an employee, and/or keep them unhappy as oppose to giving good reviews and higher wages". i will point to Amazon and Walmart as examples. I agree that predominant management theory says "keep them happy, they will work harder" but i haven't really seen much evidence to support that yet other then theory.

Resolution: MY view has changed, i award a delta to every reply i got.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31159137880.0" user="acvdk" delta="False">
    <text>There are 3 logical reasons I can think of:

1. Many people thrive on positive feedback and praise. If you are getting no feedback when you are doing a good job, it can make you feel undervalued and cause you to lose motivation or even leave. Both are not ideal for the employer.

2. It provides documentation as to why someone deserves a promotion or raise. That way, if someone says they were passed over for a promotion (or fired) for an illegal reason, the company can say, "well actually, the promoted/not fired employee was getting consistently better reviews."

3. Employers actually want to be paying people as much as possible, provided that they add value commensurately. I would much rather pay someone $200K and have add $500K to my bottom line than pay someone $40K and have them bring in $100K.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31159339687.0" user="scroopynoopersdid911" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Δ

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31159371327.0" user="Jaysank" delta="False">
    <text>If your view has been changed, even a little, you should award the user who changed your view a delta. Simply reply to their comment with the delta symbol below, being sure to include a brief descriptin of how your view has changed. Be sure to leave the delta **OUTSIDE** of quotes.

&amp;gt;Δ
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
