<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="614370847.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a5s3kv/cmv_a_rationing_system_not_unlike_what_britain/">
    <title>CMV: A rationing system not unlike what Britain had during WW2 would be beneficial for the US.</title>
    <original_poster>RedShocktrooper</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the aftermath of WW1 Britain looked at their rationing system during the war, and concluded that there was... lots of work that could be done. During WW2, they had a whole section of their government basically devoted to making sure that, damn the U-Boats and the Blitz, they were going to keep everyone fed. This also caused a bit of a dietary shift, but as a result of the rationing it should be noted that *food quality increased* and life expectancy (when it wasn't truncated by bombings and long-range rocket strikes) actually went up on average. Admittedly, this came a the price of making food not too terribly exciting (thus mock duck and mock chicken) which to be fair probably discouraged overeating.  


Given the current tendency for cheap food to also be incredibly fattening food, a shift to a rationing system that ensured everyone had access to fresh veggies and also limited the intake of any one person's would result in an upward trend in general US health. Though, since we're not in a "enemy nation flying bomber runs over our cities and sinking our transport ships" situation at the moment there is no need for it to be so stringent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31181816366.0" user="ReasonableStatement" delta="False">
    <text>There are many problems to address here, but an easy place to start is this: what do you think people's response to your suggestion that they eat mock chicken?

Given American history, I mean:

Prohibition.

The War on Drugs.

Arms dealing.

Do you really think the result would be "beneficial?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31181854577.0" user="RedShocktrooper" delta="False">
    <text>Doing more research into it myself, it even seems Britain, even under the threat of bombing, ran a pretty high "black market" of trading unwanted coupons and forging them for profit. Creating mandatory scarcity is a good way to put what people want out of the public eye, and as proven with the War on Drugs and Prohibition (at the least) it also means what the can get their hands on is going to be absurdly potent or addictive. I'm not immediately sure how this would relate to, say, limiting how much dry weight of chocolate one could buy, but if there's a legal limit to what can be purchased (especially given *rationing*) there will be people who want to fill in the gap, and people willing to fill in that gap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31181857716.0" user="ReasonableStatement" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I'm not immediately sure how this would relate to, say, limiting how much dry weight of chocolate one could buy, but if there's a legal limit to what can be purchased (especially given rationing) there will be people who want to fill in the gap, and people willing to fill in that gap.

Exactly, and when people who find jail time regrettable fill that gap, out come the guns.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31182223285.0" user="Mdcastle" delta="False">
    <text>There's also the trend for potency of such goods to go up and there are no quality controls. During prohibition people switched from beer to hard liquor because it was less risky transporting more concentrated alcohol and people died because there were no quality controls. Under your proposed scheme to ban food that tastes good there would be a switch from hamburgers and steaks to deep fried Twinkies,  that have probably been sitting around collecting bacteria for a couple of days. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
