<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="614370847.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/a5s3kv/cmv_a_rationing_system_not_unlike_what_britain/">
    <title>CMV: A rationing system not unlike what Britain had during WW2 would be beneficial for the US.</title>
    <original_poster>RedShocktrooper</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the aftermath of WW1 Britain looked at their rationing system during the war, and concluded that there was... lots of work that could be done. During WW2, they had a whole section of their government basically devoted to making sure that, damn the U-Boats and the Blitz, they were going to keep everyone fed. This also caused a bit of a dietary shift, but as a result of the rationing it should be noted that *food quality increased* and life expectancy (when it wasn't truncated by bombings and long-range rocket strikes) actually went up on average. Admittedly, this came a the price of making food not too terribly exciting (thus mock duck and mock chicken) which to be fair probably discouraged overeating.  


Given the current tendency for cheap food to also be incredibly fattening food, a shift to a rationing system that ensured everyone had access to fresh veggies and also limited the intake of any one person's would result in an upward trend in general US health. Though, since we're not in a "enemy nation flying bomber runs over our cities and sinking our transport ships" situation at the moment there is no need for it to be so stringent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31181819143.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This also caused a bit of a dietary shift, but as a result of the rationing it should be noted that food quality increased and life expectancy (when it wasn't truncated by bombings and long-range rocket strikes) actually went up on average.

Source?

I can't find anything to support this argument.

&amp;gt;Given the current tendency for cheap food to also be incredibly fattening food, a shift to a rationing system that ensured everyone had access to fresh veggies and also limited the intake of any one person's would result in an upward trend in general US health. 

The bureaucratic challenges to manage this would either be enormous, or it would require cutting down food choice enormously.

In addition, messing with the market is risky if you mess up. For example, Venezuela succeeding in creating a food crisis by messing with food prices.

A better and easier solution would be to change subsidy structures. Disadvantage unhealthy food, give advantages to healthy food, and watch as systems settle into place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31181839420.0" user="RedShocktrooper" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;Source?  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;I can't find anything to support this argument.

Unfortunately I don't remember it offhand. The core of this idea is that a while back I watchedone of the hosts of InRangeTV (typically a firearms youtube channel) go a full week on foods that someone in Britain would've eaten during the WW2 rationing that lasted until the 50s. They didn't go into gas or clothing rationing, though, and I don't remember the title of the book Ian McCollum referenced. I'll need to re-watch the video(es) and come back to this specific point.

&amp;gt;The bureaucratic challenges to manage this would either be enormous, or it would require cutting down food choice enormously.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;In addition, messing with the market is risky if you mess up. For example, Venezuela succeeding in creating a food crisis by messing with food prices.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;A better and easier solution would be to change subsidy structures. Disadvantage unhealthy food, give advantages to healthy food, and watch as systems settle into place.

Compared to Venezuela (who already imported most of their food before messing around with food prices, let alone after it), the reason I think the US would be able to benefit from it is because at least I believe it has the capacity to ensure every last one of its citizens is fed. Another reason for this is because in this day and age, even the homeless can have a phone, which would eliminate the need to print ration cards or coupons.  


That being said, a subsidy would probably the better (and less extreme) option. I'd say "the ration card is how much of X you are *guaranteed* " but that sounds quite a bit like food stamps but applied to everyone with a social security number. I.E. any past that and there's no 100% assurance you're going to get it.   


This is also probably a good argument for me not trying to start a conversation at 2:18 AM my time. I should have waited to midday after some sleep and I probably wouldn't have made this post (either due to forgetting it, or because I would've realized what a horrible idea it could be).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
