<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632005030.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aga27a/cmv_the_republican_party_could_guarantee_a/">
    <title>CMV: The Republican party could guarantee a victory in the next election if they would reach out to labor unions.</title>
    <original_poster>humbleprotector</original_poster>
    <original_post>While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-union president, the Democratic party championed for labor. But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters. The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, and the effects of the democratic economy. Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support. Change my view.....</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31329412790.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree that Democrats have not been as friendly to labor over the past 30 years as they had prior to that, the Republicans have been even worse. A large part of the entire GOP platform over that same 30 years has been to systematically demolish institutional support for labor unions. Take things like right-to-work laws, blocking public sector unions from striking, opposing every single pro-labor movement (raising minimum wage, increasing funding for classrooms, family/maternal/paternal leave, etc).

Simply reaching out to labor unions would totally fly in the face of the entire GOP ideology. To say the Republicans would have to reach out to unions isn't that simple. They would have to completely change their platform in many crucial ways. This would lose them a ton of support among their donor class, massively hurting the GOP in other ways. On top of that, making a few concessions in the lead up to the next election (which would obviously be seen as the political ploy it would be) wouldn't erase 40 years of virulent anti-labor policies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329441160.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>Good point. But considering the Democratic has a new platform that pushes policies that aren't "friendly" they are policies that hurt tremendously.  Maybey the Republican party isn't the answer, but it seems like the democratic padty isnt either. There is a massive voting group that is on the fence at this point. They could use a LABOR PARTY as the UK has. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329583610.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>You may have had a point 15-20 years ago. Now, though, the Democrats are moving more and more towards labor. They've been pushing raising the minimum wage, increasing negotiating power for unions, providing mandatory maternal leave, etc. 

It seems to me that your view of the Democratic Party platform is stuck in the 90s. The modern party, especially since the 2016 election, has moved to the left.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329750579.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>I completely disagree.  Hillary just recently was pushing for TPP</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329775891.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe 4 years ago, or so, when she wasn't in office and wasn't running for anything. As soon as she started running for office, though, she started opposing TPP. She recognized that the Democratic base opposed it, and changed her positions to match that.

Also, I'm not convinced that the TPP is wholly bad for labor unions. There were *some* provisions which labor didn't particularly like, but there were some other which they really really liked. It was a massive trade deal between many countries. It was necessarily incredibly complex, and trying to portray it a single way is a bit disingenuous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329791756.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>She supported TPP up untim 5 weeks before trump won the election. She changed her stance when it started to look like she may not win. But why, Making American workers compete with Phillipine wages is a great idea!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329869146.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>That's demonstrably false. She announced her opposition to the TPP on October 7, 2015, more than a year before the election, and about the time she started seriously campaigning.

[Source 1](https://www.cnn.com/2016/07/27/politics/tpp-what-you-need-to-know/index.html)

[Source 2](https://www.politico.com/story/2016/10/hillary-clinton-trade-deal-229381)

[Source 3](https://www.businessinsider.com/what-is-tpp-2016-9)

By all accounts, she supported the TPP when she was serving as the Secretary of State for the Obama Administration, when she was actively negotiating the deal. She left office in 2013. Then, in October 2015 the finalized deal was announced, and she immediately announced opposition to it, a position which did not change for the rest of the election.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329901083.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>I was paying close attention.  I am a dem. And it was a huge issue for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329934700.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>If you were paying attention, why do you falsely believe she only started opposing TPP 5 weeks before the election when she actually started opposing it over a year before the election?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31330055548.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>Because it was still on the news even that close to election day. I have no reason to lie about it. Your best argument  is that the leading Contender for a presidential candidate of the Democratic Party was willing to pass devastating legislation just a few months prior to the election instead of just a few weeks? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31330099585.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that at all. I'm saying she supported the trade deal while it was still being negotiated, 5 years before the 2016 election, then, as soon as the deal was finalized and the details announced, 3 years after she stopped being involved in the negotiations and over a year before the election, she announced opposition to it.

The reason you kept hearing about it right up to the election is because you succumbed to GOP propaganda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31330108209.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>If it was GOP propaganda than Bernie was in on it too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31331016398.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>Will you acknowledge that she changed her position and opposed it more than a year before the election? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31331157370.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>No. I knew I was not mistaken but went ahead and looked into it again just now. I found several YouTube campaign videos with my very first search. You should look into it. Google "bernie tpp" and "Hillary tpp" 
These videos are during the campaign. Does everyone here just disagree and call it fact just because it would help their discussion if it was?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31331214047.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a little confused. Those sources verify she announced her opposition to the TPP during a debate in October 2015. Can you link anything stating she supported it more recently than that? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31332879971.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>I’m still curious as to your answer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31333005214.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>Of course you are. Nevermind the fact that the democratic presidential candidate(the best they have to offer) even supported such an anti American, anti worker Bill isn't relevant. You want to get technical over which news outlets ate reporting her flip flop dates correctly. Well, the first time she flip flopped is separate from the 2nd. I already informed you how to look into it. I am not a news outlet but I didn't write any of their campaign speeches either. Hope that helps. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31333836593.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>I want you to provide evidence that she supported the TPP later than October 2015. If you can’t, you should edit your other comments saying that she did to reflect that you were wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
