<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632005030.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aga27a/cmv_the_republican_party_could_guarantee_a/">
    <title>CMV: The Republican party could guarantee a victory in the next election if they would reach out to labor unions.</title>
    <original_poster>humbleprotector</original_poster>
    <original_post>While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-union president, the Democratic party championed for labor. But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters. The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, and the effects of the democratic economy. Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support. Change my view.....</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31329864580.0" user="BolshevikMuppet" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with any "if X candidate or party gained the support of Y group they'd win" is in assuming that the members of that group are single-issue voters.

The AFL-CIO is a massive group, with a huge membership, and no way to compel any of their members to support a party or candidate, or even a way to force their members to care more about "labor issues" than about other issues.

You can't compromise on a couple of labor issues (particularly since labor unions are split on issues like "godawfully stupid tariffs" and "protectionist bullshit") and expect to draw in labor voters en masse.

And the bigger compromises (strengthening NLRB regulations, ending right to work legislation, restoring public service unions in Republican states) would require such backpedaling that the GOP would lose a bunch of their "small government, free market" libertarian base.

&amp;gt; the effects of the democratic economy

You mean recovery after a recession?  Or the previous democratic economy which included a balanced budged and substantial wage growth before Bush threw it off a cliff in the name of tax cuts for the wealthy?

&amp;gt;Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving

Clinton still won a majority of union household's votes, and union support for Trump has been on a steady decline for his entire presidency.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
