<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632005030.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aga27a/cmv_the_republican_party_could_guarantee_a/">
    <title>CMV: The Republican party could guarantee a victory in the next election if they would reach out to labor unions.</title>
    <original_poster>humbleprotector</original_poster>
    <original_post>While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-union president, the Democratic party championed for labor. But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters. The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, and the effects of the democratic economy. Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support. Change my view.....</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31330374576.0" user="Ddp2008" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't Trump doing this?

He has protectionist policies, (tariffs and higher standards for Mexico) and the Democrats are against him.

Trump wants to curb both legal and illegal immigration.  (Although the Democratic party isn't for open borders by any stretch).

So for what you have written, republicans are doing this.  What they haven't done is push up labour rights and wages.  Increasing min wage to 15 means people above that will be able to push for more money, and more rights mean they will have more protection and bargaining power.  

But it really comes down to does pandering matter or general belief in markers matter.  Republicans think that markets will make us richer long term, so they are doing things for future generations vs pandering with bad policies to today's people.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
