<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632005030.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aga27a/cmv_the_republican_party_could_guarantee_a/">
    <title>CMV: The Republican party could guarantee a victory in the next election if they would reach out to labor unions.</title>
    <original_poster>humbleprotector</original_poster>
    <original_post>While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-union president, the Democratic party championed for labor. But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters. The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, and the effects of the democratic economy. Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support. Change my view.....</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31329573971.0" user="JustARegularIdiot" delta="False">
    <text>The Republican party already has almost all of the union members that it could possibly get, and reaching out to union members would not bring in a significant number of new voters. This is for three reasons. 

First, union membership has been on a steady decline for decades, so the total effect that unions have on elections is small and getting smaller. 

Second, those members are not evenly distributed across the country. Union membership is highly concentrated in the darkest of blue states/districts. Making gains among union members might help the Republicans flip an occasional swing state/district in a very close election, but even though most union members are in states like New York, there are not enough there to flip New York to Republicans.

Third, if you look into the demographic make-up of unions, you find that race and education almost entirely explain the current split in favor of Democrats. This means that Republicans would not be trying to make gains with non-college-educated white voters in unions because the party already has them. Instead, Republicans would have to make gains among black union members, and I'm not convinced that appeals to union membership is the missing piece in relations between black voters and the Republican party.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

So, in the end, Republicans appealing to the unions would probably only bring in a very small number of voters who mostly live in areas that won't make much of a difference.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
