<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632005030.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aga27a/cmv_the_republican_party_could_guarantee_a/">
    <title>CMV: The Republican party could guarantee a victory in the next election if they would reach out to labor unions.</title>
    <original_poster>humbleprotector</original_poster>
    <original_post>While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-union president, the Democratic party championed for labor. But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters. The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, and the effects of the democratic economy. Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support. Change my view.....</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31329726443.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>[neoliberalism](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neoliberalism) almost demands they not do this, though, at least honestly.

The party that claims the free market is the ultimate decider of what is good and that considers the individual the most important unit of society just cant promote unions.

They would have to (at least pretend to) fundamentally change who they are.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329769041.0" user="humbleprotector" delta="False">
    <text>Free market doesn't put the individual first. Look at Detroit.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329811275.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say 'puts the individual first' - neoliberalism does just the opposite- it *blames* the individual for all mistakes, saying that if bad things happen to you, it's your own fault.

That partly why our government hasn't spent serious money to help the people of detroit (or flynt) - because neoliberalism says that's their own fault, and they should fix their own mistakes.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
