<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632005030.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aga27a/cmv_the_republican_party_could_guarantee_a/">
    <title>CMV: The Republican party could guarantee a victory in the next election if they would reach out to labor unions.</title>
    <original_poster>humbleprotector</original_poster>
    <original_post>While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-union president, the Democratic party championed for labor. But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters. The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, and the effects of the democratic economy. Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support. Change my view.....</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31329672295.0" user="HippocratesDontCare" delta="False">
    <text>\&amp;gt;While Ronald Reagan was a very anti-Union President

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Arguable. Ronald Reagan was actually a leader of a Union (the only President who has held such a position in organized labour) and publicly advocated for Labor Unions in the Eastern bloc countries and Soviet Union. The most contentious notable thing he did with organized labor was enforcing Federal Law with the Air Traffic Controller Union during their strike, which led to a dramatic decrease of Labor strikes in the following years. I don't think he did much else besides for maybe having some appointees in the Labor department that were anti-Union.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\&amp;gt;But in recent history Bill Clinton drafted NAFTA. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

This is false. NAFTA passed under Clinton's Presidency, but it was mostly negotiated in the George H.W. Bush's admin, with a vast majority of the GOP Congressional delegation voting for it, and the Democratic one being split. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\&amp;gt; With the Democratic support of Outsourcing USA Jobs and now open borders they lost a tremendous amount of loyal supporters.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[It's been argued that the last Tax Bill includes incentives for businesses who off-shore](https://aflcio.org/2017/11/29/what-experts-are-saying-about-outsourcing-and-gop-tax-bill), and [Congressional Republicans voted against the 'Bring Jobs Home Act', which would end tax credits for companies that outsource](https://votesmart.org/bill/votes/49616#.XD4aPXbYrnE). There is no legislative support of Open borders in Congress. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;\&amp;gt;The AFL-CIO is a massive lobby group with one of the largest voter support of any but they saw their support fractured in the last election because of policies pushed by the Democratic Party, 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

The AFL-CIO publicly comments, endorses, and criticizes legislation and Executive moves all the time, which the vast majority of the labor regulation and general issue disagreements they have is primarily with legislation that is primarily pushed by Republicans.  

[https://aflcio.org/scorecard/legislators](https://aflcio.org/scorecard/legislators)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;Forcing an American worker to compete with illegal wages, and with third world wages is not Labour friendly and loyal Democratic voters are leaving because they haven't seen a return for all their loyal support

I agree, but those are largely Republican policies or phenomenons that Congressional and State Republicans largely protect and incentive:

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[https://www.foxnews.com/food-drink/trump-winery-in-virginia-seeks-more-foreign-workers](https://www.foxnews.com/food-drink/trump-winery-in-virginia-seeks-more-foreign-workers)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-immigration-farmers-trump/trump-reassures-farmers-immigration-crackdown-not-aimed-at-their-workers-idUSKCN18B1BB](https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-immigration-farmers-trump/trump-reassures-farmers-immigration-crackdown-not-aimed-at-their-workers-idUSKCN18B1BB)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/03/us/trump-golf-club-illegal-immigrant-employee.html](https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/03/us/trump-golf-club-illegal-immigrant-employee.html)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-immigration-visas-idUSKBN1A21PA](https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-immigration-visas-idUSKBN1A21PA)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

For Republicans to successfully reach out to most Labor Unions, they would have to stop introducing and passing legislation that undermines Union participation, to stop opposing and subverting proposed and existing State and Federal labor entitlements, to stop directly publicly advocating against Union drives (which numerous GOP Governors--primarily in the South--do), stop trying to weaken and reduce the rights of Public Unions, and stop subscribing to an ideology that is fundamentally at odds with labor unionism and utilitarianism, which is no small task, and would entail a massive ideological shift within the party and likely meet very fierce resistance among some donors and factions among the base. All of this is unlikely, both given the past and current actions of Republican Governors and State legislatures they control.    

 

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31329789791.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The most contentious notable thing he did with organized labor was enforcing Federal Law with the Air Traffic Controller Union during their strike

He didn't have to ban the striking controllers from federal service for life, but he did it. He said it would take 2 years to return to normal staffing, but it was 10. That was pretty darn contentious.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
