<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632832865.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/agrsyp/cmv_now_that_we_have_evolved_past_the_need_to_eat/">
    <title>CMV: Now that we have evolved past the need to eat meat, it is completely immoral to do so.</title>
    <original_poster>Inquisitive2k</original_poster>
    <original_post>Not a vegan or even a vegetarian, but I still hold this belief. I understand that we have evolved as carnivores, and that eating meat has always been essential to human survival. It holds nutrients you cant find anywhere else like B12, its heavily saturated which makes it an efficient food, and ot tastes damn good (which i would guess has something to do with evolution aswel).

These arguments are still valid in underdeveloped or poor countries, and under extreme conditions. However, in modern day western society's I can't seem to find one ethical argument for eating meat (not to mention the toll it takes on the environment). 

Is everyone just lazy like me, or is there more to it?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31740267749.0" user="bourne0814" delta="False">
    <text>We have not evolved beyond the Paleolithic era. The humans we are today are the same species that existed during the time of hunter-gatherers. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

In fact, pernicious anemia occurs as a result of an inadequate intake of vitamin B12. The demographics most prone to contracting pernicious anemia and the subsequent gastric carcinoma caused by pernicious anemia are vegans and vegetarians. This is because B12 is only found in animal products. The only way to consume vegan B12 is to get the synthetic version. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

[This blog post](https://donnypodrasky.blogspot.com/2019/03/why-it-is-important-to-eat-meat.html) contains many great sources that explain why humans are not only required to eat meat to remain healthy but are best off eating significantly more meat that MyPlate and The Food Pyramid suggest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31740288134.0" user="lnfinity" delta="False">
    <text>No animals or plants are capable of producing vitamin B12. It has always been exclusively produced by bacteria and archaea. The "vegan synthetic" kind is the exact same kind that is in every animal.

&amp;gt;No eukaryotic organisms (including plants, animals, and fungi) are independently capable of constructing vitamin B12. Only bacteria and archaea have the enzymes required for its biosynthesis.

[Source](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitamin_B12#Laboratory_synthesis)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31741925175.0" user="bourne0814" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, regardless of what the direct mechanism of production of B12 is, the fact remains only animal products contain B12. You will only find synthetic B12 outside of animal sources.

Here's a book about the sources of B12:
https://books.google.com/books?id=alAsDwAAQBAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=sources+of+B12&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwi76bHdydLhAhXKVt8KHeH0C-gQ6AEwA3oECAUQAg#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=sources%20of%20B12&amp;amp;f=false

To reference bacteria and claim that B12 is not of animal origin is akin to referencing mitochondria and claiming that animal bodies don't produce heat.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
