<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632832865.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/agrsyp/cmv_now_that_we_have_evolved_past_the_need_to_eat/">
    <title>CMV: Now that we have evolved past the need to eat meat, it is completely immoral to do so.</title>
    <original_poster>Inquisitive2k</original_poster>
    <original_post>Not a vegan or even a vegetarian, but I still hold this belief. I understand that we have evolved as carnivores, and that eating meat has always been essential to human survival. It holds nutrients you cant find anywhere else like B12, its heavily saturated which makes it an efficient food, and ot tastes damn good (which i would guess has something to do with evolution aswel).

These arguments are still valid in underdeveloped or poor countries, and under extreme conditions. However, in modern day western society's I can't seem to find one ethical argument for eating meat (not to mention the toll it takes on the environment). 

Is everyone just lazy like me, or is there more to it?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31336056605.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Your premise is based on the assumption that there is something morally wrong in killing animals for food, there is not. 

It should also be noted that we cannot get B12 from plants. Even the B12 obtained for supplements is obtained from Zooplankton which are microscopic animal life. 

We are omnivores and it is no more immoral for us to eat meat than it is for a bear to eat meat. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336107489.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>We have cognitive abilities that gives us the choice. The bear does not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336190239.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>That in no way assigns moral value though. You have to prove that it is immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336193276.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>How does one go about proving mortality? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31340351590.0" user="kicktowards" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think it would be immoral for a bear to kill and eat a human for food? If not (I'm assuming you would say no, it's not immoral), wouldn't your above logic imply it would also be fine for me to kill and eat a human? 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

(Not trying to set you up for a 'gotcha!' or anything, just genuinely curious about how you are thinking about this.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
