<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632832865.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/agrsyp/cmv_now_that_we_have_evolved_past_the_need_to_eat/">
    <title>CMV: Now that we have evolved past the need to eat meat, it is completely immoral to do so.</title>
    <original_poster>Inquisitive2k</original_poster>
    <original_post>Not a vegan or even a vegetarian, but I still hold this belief. I understand that we have evolved as carnivores, and that eating meat has always been essential to human survival. It holds nutrients you cant find anywhere else like B12, its heavily saturated which makes it an efficient food, and ot tastes damn good (which i would guess has something to do with evolution aswel).

These arguments are still valid in underdeveloped or poor countries, and under extreme conditions. However, in modern day western society's I can't seem to find one ethical argument for eating meat (not to mention the toll it takes on the environment). 

Is everyone just lazy like me, or is there more to it?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31335833920.0" user="TehNACHO" delta="False">
    <text>Well if nothing else, I want to point out that evolution was not the driving factor for our lack of dependency on meat, it's mostly medicine, agriculture, and a whole lot of artificial breeding, not natural evolution.

Also there's a fun topic in hunting that I don't feel a lot of people fully realize with the "moral" argument, and that is invasive species and imbalanced ecosystems do a shit ton of harm to the environment and in many ways it's much more "moral" to hunt and balance the ecosystem then to ignore it. This isn't just poor and underdeveloped societies mind you, this is the American South, the British Coastline, and much anywhere in the world where predator-prey dynamics can (and will) go unbalanced. Is it immoral for a hunter to kill a wild hog or giant alligator when their presence and overabundance in an environment actively harms the environment? Is it immoral for that same hunter to not eat the meat provided by that kill, potentially wasting a lot of nutrition (and other resources for the pure vegan argument). 

Your title hinges on two points, that we've evolved past the need to eat meat, and eating meat is absolutely immoral. The first point is, frankly, wrong. The second point however fails thanks to the word "completely", meaning that exception cases where animal murder and/or not wasting the resources from said hunting are suddenly incriminated in your declaration despite them being some of the best exercises for the situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335906560.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>I would agree with a lot of the points you are making. I use evolution (probably falsely) about human progress, which would include medicine and agricultural development.
Hunting is of course in a whole other ballpark compared to agriculture. I would say killing animals are sometimes moral. These are however special cases, and not the cases i have a problem with. Another way of phrasing my standpoint would be: "In society's where humans no longer get any specific benefits from eating meat other than pleasure, it is immoral to still do so". Discounting hunting for species control, which of course makes it more ethical to eat the animals than to discard them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336353165.0" user="TehNACHO" delta="False">
    <text>Just to nitpick, I think you really need to consider that ecological imbalances are not "special" cases, they're the norm. Nature is inherently chaotic, hunting even for purely ecological reasons is no exception, it's the rule.

But okay, it sounds like what you mean is in regards to the general populace, so let's take this from a place of nutrition. There is one weakness that every restricted diet has - paleo, keto, vegetarian, carnivore, doesn't matter - the general populace is not fully equipped to tackle those diets on a nutritional level. [The general populace couldn't even maintain adequate nutrition with a totally unrestricted diet.](https://thebiostation.com/bioblog/nutrient-iv-therapy/do-you-have-vitamin-deficiency/) Absolutely restricting meat as a dietary option will only exasperate this and related problems. For all the damage to human life trying to implement this sort of change would cause, it would seem far more immoral to force this sort of standard on the general populace of any country, even modern western ones.

This is all of course without talking about how, especially in western countries, people could just make do with eating less meat (not no meat, *less*) and focusing on slow and ethical means of agriculture, which still provides meat as an option for the general populace, minimizes harm to animals (or even provides a net benefit if you consider how pampered some farm animals are on farms that already execute on high standards), and minimizes harm to the environment if there's a net loss in demand for meat.

In other words, I think your frame of reference is wrong. The question shouldn't be "is eating meat unethical/immoral", the question should be "how can we eat meat (as a society) in an ethical and moral way". The latter way of thinking also incorporates hunting smoothly without having it sticking out as an exception to the rule.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
