<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632832865.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/agrsyp/cmv_now_that_we_have_evolved_past_the_need_to_eat/">
    <title>CMV: Now that we have evolved past the need to eat meat, it is completely immoral to do so.</title>
    <original_poster>Inquisitive2k</original_poster>
    <original_post>Not a vegan or even a vegetarian, but I still hold this belief. I understand that we have evolved as carnivores, and that eating meat has always been essential to human survival. It holds nutrients you cant find anywhere else like B12, its heavily saturated which makes it an efficient food, and ot tastes damn good (which i would guess has something to do with evolution aswel).

These arguments are still valid in underdeveloped or poor countries, and under extreme conditions. However, in modern day western society's I can't seem to find one ethical argument for eating meat (not to mention the toll it takes on the environment). 

Is everyone just lazy like me, or is there more to it?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31335826102.0" user="Fenald" delta="False">
    <text>Immoral as a word has no value.  It's completely open to interpretation what's immoral to one person isn't immoral to another.  What is it about animals specifically that makes it immoral to you?  Are pesticides immoral?  Is hand sanitizer immoral?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335846658.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>I would agree. The situation i keep coming back to is that of a "judgement day" of sorts. Imagine an advanced alien civilization, or an ASI (artificial super intelligence), or even God if you will - coming to judge us. I don't want to go all philosophical but it seems to me that killing without purpose is somewhat objectively immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335860342.0" user="Fenald" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose is sustenance just as it has always been.  Imagine if someone decided it was immoral to eat corn.  Corn is alive we don't NEED to eat corn to survive we can just eat other things so why are we killing so much corn?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335900343.0" user="nu173" delta="False">
    <text>animals feel harm and experience emotions that plants do not. it is better to harm and kill plants than animals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336039831.0" user="Robodix" delta="False">
    <text>That is why you hold your current morals. Perhaps these hypothetical aliens are plant-like beings and they see eating plants the same way you see eating animals? As u/Fenald was pointing out, morality is completely subjective. In a case of a 'judgement day' like scenario the only hope is that the judge will have moral values similar to your own as it would be impossible to know those morals beforehand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336041787.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;what's immoral to one person isn't immoral to another.

yes thats called a disagreement. now its your turn to explain your position and provide arguments. thats the whole point this subreddit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336055725.0" user="Fenald" delta="False">
    <text>I asked him follow up questions cutting them out of the quote doesn't mean they weren't there.  I'm sorry I didn't present my full and complete argument in 1 post I wanted additional information about his views.....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336099719.0" user="Bengom" delta="False">
    <text>your questions are nonsensical to the point of absurdity. is handsanitzer immoral? no, but what the fack has that to do with eating meat?

what youre implying is that all moral stances are equal, disregarding any arguments or logic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336123306.0" user="Fenald" delta="False">
    <text>I'm trying to figure out why he values life.  If he values life for the sake of life then hand sanitizer is immoral as is eating plants.  If he values life because of pain and fear then these animals bred and raises under the control and protection of humans experience far less pain and fear than they would in nature.  Animals don't die of old age in nature.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
