<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632832865.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/agrsyp/cmv_now_that_we_have_evolved_past_the_need_to_eat/">
    <title>CMV: Now that we have evolved past the need to eat meat, it is completely immoral to do so.</title>
    <original_poster>Inquisitive2k</original_poster>
    <original_post>Not a vegan or even a vegetarian, but I still hold this belief. I understand that we have evolved as carnivores, and that eating meat has always been essential to human survival. It holds nutrients you cant find anywhere else like B12, its heavily saturated which makes it an efficient food, and ot tastes damn good (which i would guess has something to do with evolution aswel).

These arguments are still valid in underdeveloped or poor countries, and under extreme conditions. However, in modern day western society's I can't seem to find one ethical argument for eating meat (not to mention the toll it takes on the environment). 

Is everyone just lazy like me, or is there more to it?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31335926940.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Please state your moral system.

There are plenty of moral systems that allow for meat eating morally. You can't just issue a blanket statement of "X is immoral" without stating which moral system you adhere to because without doing so you are framing the argument so that the person responding to you has to guess your moral system and that allows you to soapbox.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335978170.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not aware of any specific moral system i adhere to. It seems most people would agree that kicking a dog is immoral. Why are we exempt from this "rule" when it comes to killing other (less likable?) Animals just because we used to need to eat them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336049100.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It seems most people would agree 

Forgive the hyperbole but most people being in agreement about anything has no bearing on morality. Most of Nazi Germany agreed it was a good idea to kill jews, does that make the acts of the Nazi's moral? Consensus is a terribly unscientific way to arrive at any conclusion. Even moral ones. Just because *a lot of people agree* doesn't change the fact of the matter.

Do you have a better reason than this for actually not wanting to eat meat?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336079183.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>It's a valid argument because i see a fallacy in it, and because i would see the opinions of most people changed. You are of course correct about consensus but that's sadly the best option we have (read: democracy).

No, my argument (i know realize) relies solely on my moral compass. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31336108735.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are of course correct about consensus but that's sadly the best option we have (read: democracy).

Democracy isn't a moral element we are discussing, its a pragmatic one. In fact, democracy is derived from the moral system of utilitarianism, and if you are arguing in favor of utilitarianism then its very easy to continue to justify eating meat. 

If a person gains more utility from consuming meat, than the animal provides while being alive throughout its entire life then it is moral to eat meat.

This makes a very simple justification for something like Lobster, which are basically sea cockroaches and posses no capacity to feel pain. The alternative is a human being, who may very well suffer mentally from the inability to continue consuming meat. At which point you must reconcile that an animal that can't feel pain and is essentially inert because its got no mental faculties other than to continue living then *you are justified in eating meat* if you are a utilitarian. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
