<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634030621.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ahhh5p/cmv_my_unconventional_dietary_habits_of_only/">
    <title>CMV: My unconventional dietary habits of only eating snacks are completely healthy</title>
    <original_poster>chubby_leenock_hugs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not actually ever make proper structured meals; rather I eat a lot of raw vegetables in the form of ball peppers, tomatos, oranges, cucumbers, pineapples and grapes throughout the day as well as a lot of instant noodles whenever I feel like it and as far as meat is concerned I might eat some frankfurthers, dry sausage, raw salted herring or make a hamburger and put it in a bun of bread. Essentially I eat "snacks" throughout the entire day.

I should also note that I do this whilst working; I do not take the time to sit down and properly dine and do not own a dining table. You often hear people say you should take the time to eat and sit down but I don't know how true that is.

I believe that in doing so I consume a balanced, varied, diet without the effort of cooking or creating meals; I do not see why concentrating food into three meals per day with breakfast and lunch being bread-based and dinner being warm would make it healthier since the inside of the stomach mashes it up together anyway before nutrients are extracted.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31345975722.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31355662567.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/curlybamboo129 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), before [messaging the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+curlybamboo129&amp;amp;message=curlybamboo129+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ahhh5p/-/eeel1nu/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Sorry, u/curlybamboo129 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+curlybamboo129&amp;amp;message=curlybamboo129+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ahhh5p/-/eeel1nu/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
