<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634030621.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ahhh5p/cmv_my_unconventional_dietary_habits_of_only/">
    <title>CMV: My unconventional dietary habits of only eating snacks are completely healthy</title>
    <original_poster>chubby_leenock_hugs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not actually ever make proper structured meals; rather I eat a lot of raw vegetables in the form of ball peppers, tomatos, oranges, cucumbers, pineapples and grapes throughout the day as well as a lot of instant noodles whenever I feel like it and as far as meat is concerned I might eat some frankfurthers, dry sausage, raw salted herring or make a hamburger and put it in a bun of bread. Essentially I eat "snacks" throughout the entire day.

I should also note that I do this whilst working; I do not take the time to sit down and properly dine and do not own a dining table. You often hear people say you should take the time to eat and sit down but I don't know how true that is.

I believe that in doing so I consume a balanced, varied, diet without the effort of cooking or creating meals; I do not see why concentrating food into three meals per day with breakfast and lunch being bread-based and dinner being warm would make it healthier since the inside of the stomach mashes it up together anyway before nutrients are extracted.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31345992751.0" user="grizwald87" delta="False">
    <text>There's no health issue associated with snacking. But that's a lot of salt, sugar, and simple carbs in your list.

A nutritionist would tell you to mix more veggies in with the fruits, to replace as much cured meat as possible with fresh meat, and to swap out the instant noodles for more complex carbs like whole wheat pasta.

An athlete would go one step further and urge you to keep an eye on the ratios between those food groups, as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31345998491.0" user="chubby_leenock_hugs" delta="False">
    <text>Well I didn't say anything about the ratio so I'm not sure how you conclude anything about the ratio.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31346015594.0" user="grizwald87" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know you conclude criticism from "keep an eye on."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
