<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634030621.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ahhh5p/cmv_my_unconventional_dietary_habits_of_only/">
    <title>CMV: My unconventional dietary habits of only eating snacks are completely healthy</title>
    <original_poster>chubby_leenock_hugs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not actually ever make proper structured meals; rather I eat a lot of raw vegetables in the form of ball peppers, tomatos, oranges, cucumbers, pineapples and grapes throughout the day as well as a lot of instant noodles whenever I feel like it and as far as meat is concerned I might eat some frankfurthers, dry sausage, raw salted herring or make a hamburger and put it in a bun of bread. Essentially I eat "snacks" throughout the entire day.

I should also note that I do this whilst working; I do not take the time to sit down and properly dine and do not own a dining table. You often hear people say you should take the time to eat and sit down but I don't know how true that is.

I believe that in doing so I consume a balanced, varied, diet without the effort of cooking or creating meals; I do not see why concentrating food into three meals per day with breakfast and lunch being bread-based and dinner being warm would make it healthier since the inside of the stomach mashes it up together anyway before nutrients are extracted.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31346017288.0" user="DeltaBot" delta="False">
    <text>/u/chubby_leenock_hugs (OP) has awarded 2 delta(s) in this post.

All comments that earned deltas (from OP or other users) are listed [here](/r/DeltaLog/comments/ahhq3k/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_my_unconventional_dietary/), in /r/DeltaLog.

Please note that a change of view doesn't necessarily mean a reversal, or that the conversation has ended.

^[Delta System Explained](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltasystem) ^| ^[Deltaboards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/deltaboards)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
