<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634999159.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ai28hj/cmv_there_is_no_position_on_either_side_of_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: There is no position on either side of the US immigration policy debate that makes any damn sense.</title>
    <original_poster>Roboculon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sure, the extremists in most debates don’t make sense, that’s normal. In this case, extreme conservatives want mass deportations of all illegal aliens, and extreme liberals want wide open borders where all are welcomed without limit. Either extreme seems clear it would be a disaster.

But what would a reasonable moderate (or slightly liberal) position be? I can’t think of one! Here’s how I currently interpret our balance:

* yes, we need at least some border security, we can’t just let people slip past the border checkpoints whenever they want.

* however, if you do successfully sneak past our border security, congratulations, you made it! We don’t like to deport people once they start setting down roots, so welcome aboard!

* therefore, we should have moderate border security that stops some people, but we will sort of look the other way sometimes too.

Letting people stay based on how successfully and for how long they evade the law seems like nonsense to me, but I can’t think of a better way. Is there one?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31355748114.0" user="NukedPengwing" delta="False">
    <text>This is already sort of the liberal position? Democratic leadership (Pelosi and Schumer) have both already said that border control is important, but believe a wall is ineffective and expensive. The issue is mostly for democrats is mostly the children of immigrants who have built a life here but had no choice in crossing the border (DACA recipients) and Asylum seekers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31357388903.0" user="Roboculon" delta="False">
    <text>Sure the wall would be ineffective, but that is not my question. It’s totally besides the point that Trump is a moron.

I’m trying to understand what is the liberal/moderate endgame? If border control is important, do they ultimately plan to stop people from entering illegally? The talk of amnesty for children sounds like a way to forgive entire families, since we aren’t going to just deport parents, right? So how do we word that new law to explain that people with kids will be allowed to stay and people without will not? Should the border have signs posted that say “no entry, you will be deported, unless you’re bringing children”?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
