<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634999159.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ai28hj/cmv_there_is_no_position_on_either_side_of_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: There is no position on either side of the US immigration policy debate that makes any damn sense.</title>
    <original_poster>Roboculon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sure, the extremists in most debates don’t make sense, that’s normal. In this case, extreme conservatives want mass deportations of all illegal aliens, and extreme liberals want wide open borders where all are welcomed without limit. Either extreme seems clear it would be a disaster.

But what would a reasonable moderate (or slightly liberal) position be? I can’t think of one! Here’s how I currently interpret our balance:

* yes, we need at least some border security, we can’t just let people slip past the border checkpoints whenever they want.

* however, if you do successfully sneak past our border security, congratulations, you made it! We don’t like to deport people once they start setting down roots, so welcome aboard!

* therefore, we should have moderate border security that stops some people, but we will sort of look the other way sometimes too.

Letting people stay based on how successfully and for how long they evade the law seems like nonsense to me, but I can’t think of a better way. Is there one?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31355754411.0" user="MadeInHB" delta="False">
    <text>Well we can't really just let people break the law. If someone crosses the boarder illegally, doesn't matter how long they have been here, I'd say 2 options
1) they get documented and follow everything that would happen if coming here illegally. 
2) if they didn't do that - that's when they get deported. 

There has to be a way to document everyone here. We do it for citizens. So immigrants shouldn't be different. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356705580.0" user="Trorbes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well we can't really just let people break the law.

Sure we can. Happens all the time. Marijuana is illegal at the federal level, after all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356831340.0" user="MadeInHB" delta="False">
    <text>Apples and oranges. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356874677.0" user="Trorbes" delta="False">
    <text>How so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356890042.0" user="MadeInHB" delta="False">
    <text>States have mad laws to legalize it. If another state, where it's still illegal, catches someone, then there are penalties. Hell how many people does US have incarcerated for Marijuana? And these are citizens. 

But immigration - they aren't citizens. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356984266.0" user="Trorbes" delta="False">
    <text>What does it matter if states have legalized marijuana possession? It's still illegal at the federal level, and the federal government can still prosecute people for marijuana-related charges in states where it is legal. The fact they choose not to is my point.

What is the relevance of citizenship?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31357016556.0" user="MadeInHB" delta="False">
    <text>Feds won't prosecute in states because Feds do not arrest people like that. That would be the state police. So the state police just follow state laws. 

And citizenship means everything. Because if you're not a citizen, tax money should not be used for that person in jail. They should be deported. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
