<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634999159.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ai28hj/cmv_there_is_no_position_on_either_side_of_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: There is no position on either side of the US immigration policy debate that makes any damn sense.</title>
    <original_poster>Roboculon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sure, the extremists in most debates don’t make sense, that’s normal. In this case, extreme conservatives want mass deportations of all illegal aliens, and extreme liberals want wide open borders where all are welcomed without limit. Either extreme seems clear it would be a disaster.

But what would a reasonable moderate (or slightly liberal) position be? I can’t think of one! Here’s how I currently interpret our balance:

* yes, we need at least some border security, we can’t just let people slip past the border checkpoints whenever they want.

* however, if you do successfully sneak past our border security, congratulations, you made it! We don’t like to deport people once they start setting down roots, so welcome aboard!

* therefore, we should have moderate border security that stops some people, but we will sort of look the other way sometimes too.

Letting people stay based on how successfully and for how long they evade the law seems like nonsense to me, but I can’t think of a better way. Is there one?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31356191564.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>You said "immigration", but your post is focused solely on prevention of unlawful entry and the treatment of those who are unlawfully present, so I will stay on that topic.

Right now, there is strong demand for migrant farm labor that is simply not met by those who are lawfully present.  Farmers in these industries who have tried to hire young US citizens for these types of jobs found incredibly low retention. Locals just don't want to do it.

Because of this, both the democratic and republican party don't want the government to go after and prosecute these employers who knowingly hire individuals who are unlawfully present in order to work their orchards.

We can't have our oranges and eat them too. If we want this cheap produce grown in the US, then we need a legal temporary work program that fills this need. Enabling people who are already present filling this need to come forward and register for a renewable temporary work visa, so that we know who they are, is a reasonable policy. Asking law enforcement to hunt down the employees, while fully knowing that our agriculture industry depends on them and giving a free pass to the employers, is hypocritical. 

It puts those unlawfully present who are working the fields in a very exploitable position because employers can use law enforcement as leverage against their unlawfully present employees.

If you want to go after the people who have been in our country for a long time, you need a transition plan for the industries that depend on those individuals. You need to level the field between employees and employers by punishing employers who hire those who are unlawfully present, not just deport their employees.

Lastly, and less somewhat unrelatedly, those who crossed the border as children didn't have agency in that decision. You want someone, when they turn 18, to move to a country that they don't even remember, and might know absolutely no one in? After our government spent money educating them for a decade? To what end? How is that remotely reasonable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356290274.0" user="Roboculon" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, those are the reasons I was referring to when I said mass deportation would be a disaster. So what is the answer? Surely not simply granting legal status to whoever shows up illegally. Is sort of intermittently enforcing our laws the best balance we can come up with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31358427186.0" user="Ze65a" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, ICE did an overblown performance or “raid” last year. They opted to raid a greenhouse in Ohio because they could. They made sure to pull out all the stops including guns, dogs, and at least one helicopter to harasss unarmed greenhouse workers. I believe that raid helped spark the debate about separating children from parents. 


I mean, why raid somewhere where the people may have gun, drugs, and human sex slaves and the illegal immigrants may shoot back? Just raid a greenhouse where they immigrants are working hard labor.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
