<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634999159.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ai28hj/cmv_there_is_no_position_on_either_side_of_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: There is no position on either side of the US immigration policy debate that makes any damn sense.</title>
    <original_poster>Roboculon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sure, the extremists in most debates don’t make sense, that’s normal. In this case, extreme conservatives want mass deportations of all illegal aliens, and extreme liberals want wide open borders where all are welcomed without limit. Either extreme seems clear it would be a disaster.

But what would a reasonable moderate (or slightly liberal) position be? I can’t think of one! Here’s how I currently interpret our balance:

* yes, we need at least some border security, we can’t just let people slip past the border checkpoints whenever they want.

* however, if you do successfully sneak past our border security, congratulations, you made it! We don’t like to deport people once they start setting down roots, so welcome aboard!

* therefore, we should have moderate border security that stops some people, but we will sort of look the other way sometimes too.

Letting people stay based on how successfully and for how long they evade the law seems like nonsense to me, but I can’t think of a better way. Is there one?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31355808390.0" user="SaintBio" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But what would a reasonable moderate (or slightly liberal) position be? I can’t think of one!

You apparently didn't think very hard. The Democratic Party website outlines their position on immigration as follows:

&amp;gt; The Democratic Party **supports legal immigration, within reasonable limits**, that meets the needs of families, communities, and the economy as well as maintains the United States’ role as a beacon of hope for people seeking safety, freedom, and security. People should come to the United States with visas and not through smugglers. Yet, **we recognize that the current immigration system is broken**.

&amp;gt; More than 11 million people are living in the shadows, without proper documentation. The immigration bureaucracy is full of backlogs that result in U.S. citizens waiting for decades to be reunited with family members, and green card holders waiting for years to be reunited with their spouses and minor children. The current quota system discriminates against certain immigrants, including immigrants of color, and needs to be reformed to the realities of the 21st century. And there are real questions about our detention and deportation policies that must be addressed.

&amp;gt; Democrats believe **we need to urgently fix our broken immigration system**—which tears families apart and keeps workers in the shadows—and **create a path to citizenship for law-abiding families** who are here, making a better life for their families and contributing to their communities and our country. We should repeal the 3-year, 10-year and permanent bars, which often force persons in mixed status families into the heartbreaking dilemma of either pursuing a green card by leaving the country and their loved ones behind, or remaining in the shadows. We will work with Congress to end the forced and prolonged expulsion from the country that these immigrants endure when trying to adjust their status.

&amp;gt; We believe immigration enforcement must be humane and consistent with our values. **We should prioritize those who pose a threat to the safety of our communities, not hardworking families who are contributing to their communities.** We will end raids and roundups of children and families, which unnecessarily sow fear in immigrant communities. We disfavor deportations of immigrants who served in our armed forces, and we want to create a faster path for such veterans to citizenship.

Do you consider that to be an extreme position? It seems to be perfectly reasonable and moderate to me.

&amp;gt; We don’t like to deport people once they start setting down roots, so welcome aboard!

Under President Obama, 3.2 million people were deported. You are simply wrong.

&amp;gt; extreme liberals want wide open borders where all are welcomed without limit

Find me a single source from a liberal that confirms this, I'll wait.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31355971100.0" user="Roboculon" delta="False">
    <text>You cited the democratic position, which I never said was extremely liberal. It looks Similar to the moderate position I outlined. That is, we should have borders and rules, but we shouldn’t focus too hard on enforcement. Like you quoted, enforcement should be deprioritized unless they are some kind of threat. If a nice friendly family gets here illegally, we should look the other way and let them stay. 

It all just seems like nonsense to me. It should not be possible for nice friendly families to be here illegally. If we want them to stay, then they should be deemed not illegal. But how would that work? Should the law just say that if you have a family and a job you are automatically legal, regardless of how you got here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356321943.0" user="SaintBio" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If a nice friendly family gets here illegally, we should look the other way and let them stay.

It doesn't say we should look the other way. That's putting words in their mouths. It clearly says that we should give them a path to citizenship. That's not looking the other way.

&amp;gt; Should the law just say that if you have a family and a job you are automatically legal, regardless of how you got here?

I see no reason why anyone would advocate for that. Though, we already do automatically make children citizens merely by virtue of their being born, so it's honestly not that far fetched. Rather, we should continue what already happens, whereby people apply for citizenship and go through the standard procedures. The only problem is that the procedures are currently too restrictive, and suffers from an enormous backlog. Which is why the Democratic position refers to reforming the process of acquiring citizenship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356414771.0" user="Roboculon" delta="False">
    <text>Saying we look the other way is putting words in their mouths? This is your own citation.

&amp;gt; We believe immigration enforcement must be humane and consistent with our values. We should prioritize those who pose a threat to the safety of our communities, not hardworking families who are contributing to their communities

This is semantics. If you are prioritizing deporting only criminals, and purposefully not deporting those who are “hard working families”, it sure sounds like a plan to look the other way.

Again, don’t misunderstand, I’m not saying we should deport more people. I’m saying our policy shouldn’t be based on having rules we only follow half the time. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356457125.0" user="SaintBio" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, it's absolutely putting words in their mouths. The section you quoted does not say, anywhere, that we should look the other way. What it says is that we shouldn't prioritize deporting harmless illegal immigrants. Moreover, if you had critical reading skills, you'd have noticed that earlier in the post they explained what they believed should be done with these families. Namely:

&amp;gt; create a path to citizenship for law-abiding families

This is not semantics. This is you missing the forest for the trees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356623815.0" user="jay520" delta="False">
    <text>Ultimately this is semantics. Creating a path for citizenship for "law-abiding illegal immigrants" (an oxymoron if I've ever heard one) instead of punishing them for breaking the law is what I would consider "looking the other way".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31356957663.0" user="chitterychimcharu" delta="False">
    <text>I really feel like this conservative urge to punish is the root of so much disagreement. Your view seems to boil down to, it's not a moderate solution if the 11 million here illegally are allowed to stay. A moderate solution is to deport 3% of the total population? That's pretty extreme from where I'm sitting. Would a path to legal permanent status but not citizenship be moderate in your view. I'm appreciative of arguments that it is bad to allow mass law breaking but there are no sacred values in the real world. There are no benefits to deporting 3% of the population and so many costs to doing so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31357365283.0" user="Roboculon" delta="False">
    <text>That’s the thing, I’m not conservative, and I’ve stated now several times that I don’t think we should be deporting these people. I’m just saying the policy of selective non-enforcement of our laws seems crazy. If we want these people to stay, they shouldn’t be illegal. 

And yet, how do we achieve that “path to citizenship”? It would be very hard to write a law that says: sneaking past the border is illegal, and you will be deported if you do it —unless you have a family and get a job, then we’ll let you stay. Feel free to ignore the border if you plan to start a nice family here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31357613475.0" user="chitterychimcharu" delta="False">
    <text>What would be hard is getting support for that law, writing the law is easy. People with proof of residency prior to a date who come forward. Nobody's proposing an ongoing system where any future illegal migrants get the same treatment. I mean we'll obviously still have a huge problem with illegal immigration because we're the world is poor af and immense concentrations of wealth create incentive for people to do crazy things
Edit: saw the comment pointing you to the 2013 bill, how would you describe your view now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31357792638.0" user="Roboculon" delta="False">
    <text>One key point in the 2013 bill, which you mentioned briefly, was that any sort of amnesty should be for existing people, not for future people. So we’d effectively say “ya our system was unfair before so anyone who’s not causing trouble and is already here gets a free pass. But from now on we are going to be strict. Yes, letting in lots of people, but they all have to follow the rules. Our laws are better, and we are going to start actually enforcing them.” I suppose that could achieve the goal of not being too harsh, while simultaneously having laws be enforced.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
