<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634999159.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ai28hj/cmv_there_is_no_position_on_either_side_of_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: There is no position on either side of the US immigration policy debate that makes any damn sense.</title>
    <original_poster>Roboculon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sure, the extremists in most debates don’t make sense, that’s normal. In this case, extreme conservatives want mass deportations of all illegal aliens, and extreme liberals want wide open borders where all are welcomed without limit. Either extreme seems clear it would be a disaster.

But what would a reasonable moderate (or slightly liberal) position be? I can’t think of one! Here’s how I currently interpret our balance:

* yes, we need at least some border security, we can’t just let people slip past the border checkpoints whenever they want.

* however, if you do successfully sneak past our border security, congratulations, you made it! We don’t like to deport people once they start setting down roots, so welcome aboard!

* therefore, we should have moderate border security that stops some people, but we will sort of look the other way sometimes too.

Letting people stay based on how successfully and for how long they evade the law seems like nonsense to me, but I can’t think of a better way. Is there one?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31358317991.0" user="uselessrightfoot" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're failing because you're not taking a systematic approach, you're not considering the causes.

We would be okay with an open border with Canada (we pretty much have that anyway). Why can't we do it with Mexico.

The reasons are complicated. We can talk about the economic inequality, the failure of NAFTA and other free trade policies in central and South America, the drug war, the CIA and state department meddling in politics and allowing right wing juntas to mass murder and enabling corporate exploitation, extreme historic racism against mexicans and indigenous populations (look up "operation wetback" for example) and I'm sure much more.

So we need to look at why the southern border is a problem to begin with. What can we do to solve the underlying issues so that (1) we aren't worried about border security, and (2) millions of people aren't forced to abandon their homes and move here to be undocumented aliens. 

Unless we look at the systematic issues, and at the very least fix the massive problems our foreign policy is causing around the world, nothing we do is going to make sense.

And when we understand that then we can finally be able to say, everyone deserves equal rights regardless of where they are from. We must welcome everyone and so should the governments of every other state.

But that requires a change in the global order. It requires a global order based on cooperation and protection of people rather than exploitation and war.

This is the only morally and logically consistent position. And yet it remains a pipe dream because no one is willing to consider the systematic and historic problems and focuses and starts with the assumption that we simply, for some reason, need border security. And I would say the assumption that unlimited illegal aliens would be a disaster is also faulty. A more open border allowed more freedom of movement so people didn't get stuck on this side. They worked for a while or seasonally and moved back. 

This is what needs to be done:

1. End all foreign wars and political interventions. That means pull out of Syria, Iraq, Afghanistan, Libya, Yemen, Qatar, Korea, Cuba, etc. etc. We are bombing countries and controlling countries for the benefit of American corporations. The victims are the people.

2. Make the UN, WTO, IMF, actual democratic organizations where all countries have an equal say, and don't exist to solidify the hegemony of world superpowers.

3. Re-negotiate all "free trade" deals to protect workers around the world rather than corporate profits. NAFTA, for example, fucked Mexico's economy. Create a worldwide minimum wage (maybe $10/hr).

4. End the drug war and abolish the DEA. Declare a national emergency to deal with the opioid crisis. In fact, this is linked to our broken healthcare system and economy as well so invest in that as well. 

5. End covert operations and interference in foreign governments (particularly in Latin America). Abolish the CIA.

6. End economic sanctions on countries like Iran, Russia, and North Korea. End the embargo on Cuba (and close Guantanamo bay while we're at it).

7. Forgive debts by foreign nations to corporate banks in the west (at least we can control american ones). Third world countries are so much in debt that money actually flows out of Africa and Asia and into Europe and North America, despite all of the foreign aid.

8. Related to 3, allow countries to build up their economies and nationalize natural resources like oil. So many places are controlled by foreign corporations and all the wealth is sucked out of them. While their own industries fail to develop. 

9. Stop wasting billions on border security. Abolish ICE and DHS. Use those funds (and more) to help refugees and help re-build Mexico's and Central America's economy.

10. Finally, allow open immigration and movement of all people with minimal restrictions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
