<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="642532844.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/cmv_pink_floyd_is_massively_overrated/">
    <title>CMV: Pink Floyd is massively overrated</title>
    <original_poster>DextersLittleHelper</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pink Floyd is often held up as the gold standard of bands. They’re cited as being deep and conveying a message, as well as being masters of their instruments.

To me, they are incredible self-indulgent. They write music that is likely more enjoyable for them to play than for their audience to listen to.
Their messages may differ from the typical “I love you” type songs that most artists stick to, but are they really that deep? There are plenty of artists with songs that have much stronger messages than songs like Another Brick in the Wall (just one example song), and with much more complex musicality. 

I think that a chunk of the adoration for Pink Floyd comes from the nostalgia, another chunk comes from their music being so hand-in-hand with drug use (really, this music is not aimed at sober people), and a lot of it is people who got into it as a kind of music snobbery (“music used to be soooo much better back then!”)

Of course, music is subjective. Many people genuinely enjoy Pink Floyd, which is completely fair. But I get so sick of people insulting other bands and glorifying Pink Floyd (looking at you, WatchMojo). 

Pink Floyd are terribly overrated.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31419722486.0" user="LivingInTheVoid" delta="False">
    <text>How many listens have you really given them? I’ve listened to Dark Side more times than I can count, and I still find new things I’ve missed.  You don’t appreciate them because you don’t understand it.  

But to better inform my view because I may be assuming things about you. Please tell me how much Pink Floyd you’ve listened to in your life.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420401692.0" user="DextersLittleHelper" delta="False">
    <text>I never sat down and listened to the whole album cover to cover, but they’re popular enough that I hear them reasonably often. While I appreciate that they are good within their genre, they don’t really appeal to me. I don’t tend to go back and try and try again to get into something that I dislike. However, it’s not my personal like or dislike that makes me feel they’re overrated.

I like Beyoncé’s music- I think she is good in her genre. However, I also think she is incredibly overrated as well. I think people sometimes get very fixated on certain artists to the point where it is almost taken overboard, and goes beyond their skills and into an almost cult-like status.

I mentioned Pink Floyd specifically, because they have been coming up a lot lately in conversation or on videos I have watched, but there are plenty of similar examples. I’m sure you could think of some yourself.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420450511.0" user="LivingInTheVoid" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I never sat down and listened to the whole album cover to cover,

That’s why.  You can’t judge a book by its cover.  Look, get really really really high.  Listen to Dark Side in a dark room for all 43 minutes.  Now do it again another day.  Or listen to Animals or Wosh You Were Here.  Get back at me when you do.   Because your generation is built upon singles, where Floyd made Albums.  It’s meant to be experienced as a whole.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420630758.0" user="DextersLittleHelper" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the suggestion, but I’m not into getting high, so it’s probably not for me.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31421635625.0" user="LivingInTheVoid" delta="False">
    <text>Then still do what I said but without getting stoned.  You can’t call a band over rated if you’ve never listened to them.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420545509.0" user="ZwiebelKatze" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you should reserve your opinion until you really have a sense of a thing. Otherwise, it’s just a Dunning-Kreuger exercise. 

I don’t like Van Halen very much. It’s not a sound that works for my ear-brain. But I know enough to know it’s not something I have too much knowledge of as a result.  So I don’t really have a strong opinion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31426622422.0" user="metamatic" delta="False">
    <text>I say this as someone who wasn't particularly interested in them enough to collect all the albums until about 10 years ago:

Don't get high, just sit and really listen to an entire Pink Floyd album. Any of them up to and including "The Wall". I'd pick "Wish You Were Here" over "Dark Side of the Moon", because if you aren't moved by "Shine on You Crazy Diamond" then you might just be dead...  but go with whatever you have to hand. Make sure you have a good sound system and listen to the entire album in one sitting.

Like many prog rock bands, Pink Floyd can't really be appreciated in the space of a single, because they typically produced their best work either as sprawling 20+ minute pieces, or as entire albums focused on a single concept.

If you lack the patience for that, maybe get a good copy of the 1972 concert movie "Live at Pompeii".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
