<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="642532844.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/cmv_pink_floyd_is_massively_overrated/">
    <title>CMV: Pink Floyd is massively overrated</title>
    <original_poster>DextersLittleHelper</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pink Floyd is often held up as the gold standard of bands. They’re cited as being deep and conveying a message, as well as being masters of their instruments.

To me, they are incredible self-indulgent. They write music that is likely more enjoyable for them to play than for their audience to listen to.
Their messages may differ from the typical “I love you” type songs that most artists stick to, but are they really that deep? There are plenty of artists with songs that have much stronger messages than songs like Another Brick in the Wall (just one example song), and with much more complex musicality. 

I think that a chunk of the adoration for Pink Floyd comes from the nostalgia, another chunk comes from their music being so hand-in-hand with drug use (really, this music is not aimed at sober people), and a lot of it is people who got into it as a kind of music snobbery (“music used to be soooo much better back then!”)

Of course, music is subjective. Many people genuinely enjoy Pink Floyd, which is completely fair. But I get so sick of people insulting other bands and glorifying Pink Floyd (looking at you, WatchMojo). 

Pink Floyd are terribly overrated.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31422179303.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31422213351.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/PasmaklininSulo – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+PasmaklininSulo&amp;amp;message=PasmaklininSulo+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/-/efnycpz/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
