<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="642532844.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/cmv_pink_floyd_is_massively_overrated/">
    <title>CMV: Pink Floyd is massively overrated</title>
    <original_poster>DextersLittleHelper</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pink Floyd is often held up as the gold standard of bands. They’re cited as being deep and conveying a message, as well as being masters of their instruments.

To me, they are incredible self-indulgent. They write music that is likely more enjoyable for them to play than for their audience to listen to.
Their messages may differ from the typical “I love you” type songs that most artists stick to, but are they really that deep? There are plenty of artists with songs that have much stronger messages than songs like Another Brick in the Wall (just one example song), and with much more complex musicality. 

I think that a chunk of the adoration for Pink Floyd comes from the nostalgia, another chunk comes from their music being so hand-in-hand with drug use (really, this music is not aimed at sober people), and a lot of it is people who got into it as a kind of music snobbery (“music used to be soooo much better back then!”)

Of course, music is subjective. Many people genuinely enjoy Pink Floyd, which is completely fair. But I get so sick of people insulting other bands and glorifying Pink Floyd (looking at you, WatchMojo). 

Pink Floyd are terribly overrated.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31420123995.0" user="Senecarl" delta="False">
    <text>For me, it was their commitment to the album as the unit of composition as opposed to the song, plus the fact that they had something to say. It took them a while to find their place because Syd Barrett was the leader early on and he certainly wasn’t as articulate or serious as Waters could be.

If they seem indulgent, it’s possibly because they came from jazz/blues and since improvising is a big part of that, they kept that vibe alive throughout their work. There are definitely songs of theirs that are indulgent but I still fucking love the likes of Echoes, Astronomy Domine, Shine On, Sheep. The most indulgent stuff was early on (Syd Barrett) and later with Dave Gilmour as leader. Their last album was unbearable and you can ignore most (all?) of what happened after The Final Cut because Roger Waters was the soul of the Pink Floyd that fans love. Though the others contributed some great music and lyrics, the drive to say something was his.

Waters was in charge when they had their sound down with the likes of Dark Side, The Wall, Animals, Wish You Were Here and The Final Cut. Albums like Meddle are also great but they were a waypoint, something the band had to pass through to get where they got. That one is a mix of standard rock ballads and a long experimental song that I really like.  I could have it on repeat for hours.

Bear in mind that nostalgia is important not for its own sake but because the impact of say Dark Side was so much more in 1973 than it would have been today. This was years after The Beatles and others had changed music forever and it was so hard to find something new. Pink Floyd did what The Beatles tried to do with Sgt. Pepper and The White Album, and what The Beach Boys tried to do with Pet Sounds and Smile, let the album be the focus.

Pink Floyd’s 5 major albums are closer to a novel or movie (The Wall literally is a movie) in my mind because they have coherent themes (mostly) that run through them and the music is varied yet consistent. I only listen to these Pink Floyd albums all the way through and never on shuffle. To pull out Another Brick in the Wall pt. 2 or Wish You Were Here is like yanking a chapter from a book and expecting it to be representative. Which it kind of is but you lose so much context.

Of course you might just dislike what they do. All I can say is I love the sound, the lyrics, the composition, the linking of ideas and themes, the experimentation, and of course the bands and albums that undoubtedly exist thanks to them. They were unique.

Edit: adding Pink Floyd gateway playlist as I guess this was made with PF sceptics in mind: https://open.spotify.com/user/eoineo/playlist/7dpmDkVTOFJYqICI31WRUD?si=T5gxrFrSR_a66L_G2Y4Hyg</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
