<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="642532844.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/cmv_pink_floyd_is_massively_overrated/">
    <title>CMV: Pink Floyd is massively overrated</title>
    <original_poster>DextersLittleHelper</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pink Floyd is often held up as the gold standard of bands. They’re cited as being deep and conveying a message, as well as being masters of their instruments.

To me, they are incredible self-indulgent. They write music that is likely more enjoyable for them to play than for their audience to listen to.
Their messages may differ from the typical “I love you” type songs that most artists stick to, but are they really that deep? There are plenty of artists with songs that have much stronger messages than songs like Another Brick in the Wall (just one example song), and with much more complex musicality. 

I think that a chunk of the adoration for Pink Floyd comes from the nostalgia, another chunk comes from their music being so hand-in-hand with drug use (really, this music is not aimed at sober people), and a lot of it is people who got into it as a kind of music snobbery (“music used to be soooo much better back then!”)

Of course, music is subjective. Many people genuinely enjoy Pink Floyd, which is completely fair. But I get so sick of people insulting other bands and glorifying Pink Floyd (looking at you, WatchMojo). 

Pink Floyd are terribly overrated.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31419839697.0" user="CheeseCandidate" delta="False">
    <text>About self indulgence, I'm not really sure what you mean. They are usually pretty calm, with pretty thoughtful arrangements. For example, David Gilmour's solos aren't at all showboaty, it's what I would use to show someone an expressive and collected way of playing. Richard Wright is really good at making key arrangements that don't get all up in your face(which he definitely could if he wanted), but still become an organic part of the songs.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I kinda don't like when people attribute things to drugs, some people do the same thing with 2001 A Space Odyssey, it's a cheap way to dismiss someone elses enjoyment. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think it's absolutely fair that they are where they are in the discourse, they have some milestone albums, which had an impact on both pop culture and art</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420424644.0" user="DextersLittleHelper" delta="False">
    <text>In regards to the self indulgence comment, I think you kind of helped highlight what I mean to an extent. Their music isn’t showboaty - someone go plays showboaty music is doing it specifically for an audience, as a kind of “look at me” statement. Self indulgent music is almost the opposite - it’s enjoyable for the musician to play and may have impressive technicalities that they and their band appreciate, but it is often harder for an audience to get into it.


I’m not the first person to attribute their music to drugs - it really does have that stereotypical sound to it, like someone floating off on an acid trip. Similar to how trance music sounds perfect for someone on ecstasy. Even though sober people probably enjoy both genres, there is a specific sound to their music that makes people link it to drug use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31421216747.0" user="CheeseCandidate" delta="False">
    <text>But their music isn't particularly awesome to play, for example Another Bring In The Wall you are glued to D minor, then a schweet lick happens, but not at all self indulgent. Money is in 7/4, and a bit tighter to play, but I'm not sure if it would be self indulgence, more like a schweet arrangement "gimmick".  

&amp;amp;#x200B;

With how many albums they sold, I would find it hard to believe drugs played a major part in it. Not saying it had no affect at all, but it is a major stretch</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
