<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="642532844.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/cmv_pink_floyd_is_massively_overrated/">
    <title>CMV: Pink Floyd is massively overrated</title>
    <original_poster>DextersLittleHelper</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pink Floyd is often held up as the gold standard of bands. They’re cited as being deep and conveying a message, as well as being masters of their instruments.

To me, they are incredible self-indulgent. They write music that is likely more enjoyable for them to play than for their audience to listen to.
Their messages may differ from the typical “I love you” type songs that most artists stick to, but are they really that deep? There are plenty of artists with songs that have much stronger messages than songs like Another Brick in the Wall (just one example song), and with much more complex musicality. 

I think that a chunk of the adoration for Pink Floyd comes from the nostalgia, another chunk comes from their music being so hand-in-hand with drug use (really, this music is not aimed at sober people), and a lot of it is people who got into it as a kind of music snobbery (“music used to be soooo much better back then!”)

Of course, music is subjective. Many people genuinely enjoy Pink Floyd, which is completely fair. But I get so sick of people insulting other bands and glorifying Pink Floyd (looking at you, WatchMojo). 

Pink Floyd are terribly overrated.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31419635724.0" user="Raurin" delta="False">
    <text>This is an opinion, not a view. 

Music is art, and art is subjective. Pink Floyd makes people feel a certain way or think about certain things that they find pleasurable. 

If you disagree, then your feelings are also 100% correct, but your feelings (or even the feelings of you and all of your friends) don't make the band overrated.

When something is overrated, you need to argue that "people don't like it as much as they say they like it" not that "I don't like it as much as people seem to like it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31419711106.0" user="DextersLittleHelper" delta="False">
    <text>“Opinion” and “view” are the same thing - that is why they are changeable.

I don’t think people like it as much as they say they like it - I think a lot of the like stems from drug use and nostalgia. Much like people a few years ago claimed to love I Gotta Feeling by the Black Eyes Peas - it was loved because it was a great song to go out and get drunk to. Now, people still hold a nostalgia from those days so the song is still loved/memorable.

Pink Floyd was/is big in the drug community, and therefore a lot of the love of their music stems from people associating them with times they got high.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31419740686.0" user="Raurin" delta="False">
    <text>Opinion in this sense is subjective, lacking an objective answer. eg: Strawberry ice cream is inferior to chocolate.

A view is a perspective ostensibly based in fact but potentially objectively wrong. eg: The benefits of forced vaccination outweigh the detriments.

If people like it because they associate it with things they like, that doesn't change the fact that they like it. I don't buy this line of argument because it boils down to "they don't like it; they just think they like it."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420063014.0" user="Bistai949" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to disagree with you on this one. Nothing in this sub is objective. Can you use evidence to back up you're ideas? Sure, but that's true with all opinions. The only thing in this world that's "objective" are observational facts. Sky is blue, the earth is round, the speed of light is c. ect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420224654.0" user="Raurin" delta="False">
    <text>Potentially objectively wrong. You missed the important bit. There's ambiguity in a view, so either position is... arguable at least even if one side is obviously the better position.

The point of CMV isn't always to say "your view is wrong." More often than not it's "this other perspective on the problem is better."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420239771.0" user="Bistai949" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;obviously the better position

And what makes that position better? Because you think so? 

There's no objectivity in "better"; it's an opinion. There are things that are generally agreed upon in a society, but that doesn't make them objective. That just makes them consensus.  
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420264907.0" user="Raurin" delta="False">
    <text>Are you willing to accept there are two kinds of opinions? Some are *entirely* subjective while others have *real effect* on people and things.

A view is a subcategory of opinion in this sense. If you refuse to acknowledge the difference, that's on you, and nothing you're writing is objectively wrong, but there is a distinction to be made here. You use these words synonymously, but I believe you're doing yourself a disservice by ignoring the nuance between the words.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31421140384.0" user="Bistai949" delta="False">
    <text>You could say that, certainly. And some opinions have more facts to them than others. Though, I don't really find it valuable to differentiate the two. Opinions are opinions. In a way they all have an effect on each other and other people. I think these kinds of discussions are valuable, but you can never call them "objective". I just find this minute differentiation pointless.

But that's all up to you. My only point was that none of this is kind of thing is objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31419854206.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>The drug association doesn't explain why they were popular in their own day with the public at large outside of a single counterculture. During the time Pink Floyd's most classic albums came out, drugs were still looked down on by most people. There was something about the music that got people outside of prog and psychedelic culture to take notice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31419715246.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
