<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="642532844.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/amjpik/cmv_pink_floyd_is_massively_overrated/">
    <title>CMV: Pink Floyd is massively overrated</title>
    <original_poster>DextersLittleHelper</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pink Floyd is often held up as the gold standard of bands. They’re cited as being deep and conveying a message, as well as being masters of their instruments.

To me, they are incredible self-indulgent. They write music that is likely more enjoyable for them to play than for their audience to listen to.
Their messages may differ from the typical “I love you” type songs that most artists stick to, but are they really that deep? There are plenty of artists with songs that have much stronger messages than songs like Another Brick in the Wall (just one example song), and with much more complex musicality. 

I think that a chunk of the adoration for Pink Floyd comes from the nostalgia, another chunk comes from their music being so hand-in-hand with drug use (really, this music is not aimed at sober people), and a lot of it is people who got into it as a kind of music snobbery (“music used to be soooo much better back then!”)

Of course, music is subjective. Many people genuinely enjoy Pink Floyd, which is completely fair. But I get so sick of people insulting other bands and glorifying Pink Floyd (looking at you, WatchMojo). 

Pink Floyd are terribly overrated.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31419697677.0" user="mortaeron2" delta="False">
    <text>You also have to think of the influence this band has caused.

Being innovative and bold is just as important as being good at an instrument and at writing lyrics and notes.

Try listening to meddle. The album starts heavy but gets so chill, and then you listen to dark side of the moon and it's culminating to a finale so difficult to remake.

It's stuff like this, for me. Managing to pleasantly surprised your audience, while maintaining a certain style and image.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31419731634.0" user="DextersLittleHelper" delta="False">
    <text>I think the problem I find is that, while it’s perfectly reasonable for people to enjoy them or be moved by them, not everybody gets a kick out of their music in that way. And yet, time and again, they are pushed forward as being the band that all other bands are measured by.

Because music is so subjective, other bands shouldn’t be compared to them in the first place, let alone negatively compared. 

While they are good at their genre, not everybody likes that genre, or their particular take on that genre. That’s why I would argue they are overrated. I think many people default to saying Pink Floyd are the best, because that’s what people have been saying for so long now, and other equally subjectively good music gets neglected because of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31419748180.0" user="mortaeron2" delta="False">
    <text>Well, because of the subjectivity of the matter then, you have to compare the apples to apples.

If you say Pink Floyd are better than Iron Maiden, there is a logical fallacy which cannot be explained, except by saying you prefer one to the other.

I believe it's the stuff I wrote above that makes them comparable to other bands of a similar genre.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420027390.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>That's a reasonable position, but it's very different from trying to write off their appeal as drug culture and nostalgia. It's reasonable to object to any one band being the standard that all music is judged against, but that doesn't mean that people don't love their music as much as they claim to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31420392150.0" user="moleware" delta="False">
    <text>So because you don't enjoy Pink Floyd, they are overrated.  Got it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
