<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644178994.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anizoy/cmv_the_government_doesnt_have_any_special_rights/">
    <title>CMV: The government doesn't have any special rights to products that make use of publicly-funded research.</title>
    <original_poster>kuriousgoomba</original_poster>
    <original_post>I typically consider myself fairly fiscally liberal, but I saw two reddit posts in recent days I don't really agree with that garnered a lot of support from other redditors. 

1) [If Software Is Funded from a Public Source, Its Code Should Be Open Source](https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/an43i7/if_software_is_funded_from_a_public_source_its/)

(Note- I don't disagree with the main point of the article, I am all for open standards. I disagree with the idea that a university researcher can't patent software and spin it off as a private company because they are publicly funded).

2) [Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Calls Out Sexism As Her Big Pharma Knowledge Is Labeled 'Inadequate'](https://www.reddit.com/r/AlexandriaOcasio/comments/anebj0/alexandria_ocasiocortez_calls_out_sexism_as_her/)

(Note- I don't disagree with AOC's claim that her treatment by the media and the op-ed in question is sexist, because it is. Rather, I disagree with her claim during the hearing that government funding justifies public ownership of the final product.)

Both these articles seem to be getting at an idea that because the government initially funds certain ventures, they have a right to mandate public access to the product at either reduced cost (pharma) or for free (open-source code).

I think that I fundamentally disagree with some of the redditors commenting on these posts when I think about the purpose of government research funding. In general, I think the government's role is to fund basic research projects and produce novel ideas that private industry can then use to benefit people in a wide variety of ways. This includes pharmaceuticals, advances in alternative energy, novel algorithms, etc. etc.

In other words, if government researchers publish open-access research papers about a promising pharmaceutical candidate that a big pharma company eventually develops into a patentable drug, that doesn't seem like a situation where the government can mandate the pharma company sell the drug at production-cost simply because they published the initial research. To me, this seems like a situation where the system is working well. Taxpayers don't fund research because they expect a direct financial payout. They finance research because they expect a preponderance of high-quality and creative research programs to lead to welfare-improving products in the end (such as new medicines). There may be other reasons to mandate reduced prices, such as the elasticity of demand when it comes to medicine. But to say that companies are obligated to lower prices because it was initially public-domain research doesn't seem correct to me. 

There are other viable economic systems where the government can, for example, produce energy at cost. But because we live in a capitalist system we ought to use the power of the free market to soak up the innovative ideas that public universities and research programs produce and put them to work developing products people will purchase because they see value in them. 

Is this the correct way to view public-private research relationships? Please, change my view! 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31432443300.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>Having an open source project doesn't mean that it can't be profited from.

The examples you have given are cases where private companies have used public funding to develop something, then turned around and asked the government to prohibit anyone else from building their idea.

A software patent is different than copyrighting software. It is a claim that no other company can write their own software that works the same way in the same application space.

If a company releases their code under, say, an Apache license, they can write new code that they keep as a proprietary that uses the open source code. They can use the open source code as a launchpad for private ventures, while still allowing others to build on the same base.

Openness and profitability are not mutually exclusive. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
