<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644178994.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anizoy/cmv_the_government_doesnt_have_any_special_rights/">
    <title>CMV: The government doesn't have any special rights to products that make use of publicly-funded research.</title>
    <original_poster>kuriousgoomba</original_poster>
    <original_post>I typically consider myself fairly fiscally liberal, but I saw two reddit posts in recent days I don't really agree with that garnered a lot of support from other redditors. 

1) [If Software Is Funded from a Public Source, Its Code Should Be Open Source](https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/an43i7/if_software_is_funded_from_a_public_source_its/)

(Note- I don't disagree with the main point of the article, I am all for open standards. I disagree with the idea that a university researcher can't patent software and spin it off as a private company because they are publicly funded).

2) [Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Calls Out Sexism As Her Big Pharma Knowledge Is Labeled 'Inadequate'](https://www.reddit.com/r/AlexandriaOcasio/comments/anebj0/alexandria_ocasiocortez_calls_out_sexism_as_her/)

(Note- I don't disagree with AOC's claim that her treatment by the media and the op-ed in question is sexist, because it is. Rather, I disagree with her claim during the hearing that government funding justifies public ownership of the final product.)

Both these articles seem to be getting at an idea that because the government initially funds certain ventures, they have a right to mandate public access to the product at either reduced cost (pharma) or for free (open-source code).

I think that I fundamentally disagree with some of the redditors commenting on these posts when I think about the purpose of government research funding. In general, I think the government's role is to fund basic research projects and produce novel ideas that private industry can then use to benefit people in a wide variety of ways. This includes pharmaceuticals, advances in alternative energy, novel algorithms, etc. etc.

In other words, if government researchers publish open-access research papers about a promising pharmaceutical candidate that a big pharma company eventually develops into a patentable drug, that doesn't seem like a situation where the government can mandate the pharma company sell the drug at production-cost simply because they published the initial research. To me, this seems like a situation where the system is working well. Taxpayers don't fund research because they expect a direct financial payout. They finance research because they expect a preponderance of high-quality and creative research programs to lead to welfare-improving products in the end (such as new medicines). There may be other reasons to mandate reduced prices, such as the elasticity of demand when it comes to medicine. But to say that companies are obligated to lower prices because it was initially public-domain research doesn't seem correct to me. 

There are other viable economic systems where the government can, for example, produce energy at cost. But because we live in a capitalist system we ought to use the power of the free market to soak up the innovative ideas that public universities and research programs produce and put them to work developing products people will purchase because they see value in them. 

Is this the correct way to view public-private research relationships? Please, change my view! 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31432093081.0" user="fedora-tion" delta="False">
    <text>Why shouldn't the government be allowed to make rules around its investments. That's part of capitalism. If someone offers you money in exchange for something, they're gonna make you sign a contract around that. Sure, the contract is often something like "you will pay back that amount of money + interest" but it's also often things like "you will give us X% of the company/profits/executive control". Why should this be different when the investor in the government. The government has something the researcher wants (money) and something they want in exchange (control over the distribution of the fruits of that money to the people it governs). If a researcher doesn't like it they can go work at a private pharma company. They don't NEED to work for a government funded institution.

Hell, as a taxpayer I'm very annoyed to know my government is letting people take my tax money to develop products and then just letting them sell those products and keep all the profit. That's bad business on the government's part.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432678539.0" user="kuriousgoomba" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm, I see where you are coming from. I think I'd be annoyed if I viewed it through that frame as well. But from where I'm coming from, I'm okay with a business "letting them sell those products and keep all the profit." 

A more appropriate analogy in my mind than investment is a gift from one's parents, or something to that effect. After all, at the end of the day the government shouldn't be operating like a business, wanting to fund ventures that maximize financial return on investment. They want to see their people flourish, and so to that end public research is sort of a 'gift', not favoring any particular company, but allowing for a higher quality of product to be accessible to the public. The government might *measure* their return on investment not in dollars they get back, but rather how much of an impact their research has, in terms of patients helped, diseases cured, etc. 

What do you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432798093.0" user="fedora-tion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The government might measure their return on investment not in dollars they get back, but rather how much of an impact their research has, in terms of patients helped, diseases cured, etc.

Well that's my point though. The government maximizes the number of patients helped and problems solved through price ceilings. Where I live the flu vaccine is free every year because the government subsidized that. This helps reduce the cases of flu outbreaks.  If it was purely in the hands of private corporations then the price would have to be above $0 and less people would get it, which would mean more holes in the herd immunity which would be bad for everyone. 

If the government pays for it to help the general public, the government should get a say in how accessible it is to the general public. Putting a price ceiling on things accomplishes that by putting the kibosh on Martin Shkreli types.  Also I feel that price ceilings make government investment more fair. If I'm a private company paying for my own R&amp;amp;D how is it fair to me that some guy getting government funding can develop a competing product to my own with no personal financial risk and then immediately spin off a private company that's my direct competition. It disincentivizes independent reserach to not have a drawback to government investing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
