<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644178994.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anizoy/cmv_the_government_doesnt_have_any_special_rights/">
    <title>CMV: The government doesn't have any special rights to products that make use of publicly-funded research.</title>
    <original_poster>kuriousgoomba</original_poster>
    <original_post>I typically consider myself fairly fiscally liberal, but I saw two reddit posts in recent days I don't really agree with that garnered a lot of support from other redditors. 

1) [If Software Is Funded from a Public Source, Its Code Should Be Open Source](https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/an43i7/if_software_is_funded_from_a_public_source_its/)

(Note- I don't disagree with the main point of the article, I am all for open standards. I disagree with the idea that a university researcher can't patent software and spin it off as a private company because they are publicly funded).

2) [Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Calls Out Sexism As Her Big Pharma Knowledge Is Labeled 'Inadequate'](https://www.reddit.com/r/AlexandriaOcasio/comments/anebj0/alexandria_ocasiocortez_calls_out_sexism_as_her/)

(Note- I don't disagree with AOC's claim that her treatment by the media and the op-ed in question is sexist, because it is. Rather, I disagree with her claim during the hearing that government funding justifies public ownership of the final product.)

Both these articles seem to be getting at an idea that because the government initially funds certain ventures, they have a right to mandate public access to the product at either reduced cost (pharma) or for free (open-source code).

I think that I fundamentally disagree with some of the redditors commenting on these posts when I think about the purpose of government research funding. In general, I think the government's role is to fund basic research projects and produce novel ideas that private industry can then use to benefit people in a wide variety of ways. This includes pharmaceuticals, advances in alternative energy, novel algorithms, etc. etc.

In other words, if government researchers publish open-access research papers about a promising pharmaceutical candidate that a big pharma company eventually develops into a patentable drug, that doesn't seem like a situation where the government can mandate the pharma company sell the drug at production-cost simply because they published the initial research. To me, this seems like a situation where the system is working well. Taxpayers don't fund research because they expect a direct financial payout. They finance research because they expect a preponderance of high-quality and creative research programs to lead to welfare-improving products in the end (such as new medicines). There may be other reasons to mandate reduced prices, such as the elasticity of demand when it comes to medicine. But to say that companies are obligated to lower prices because it was initially public-domain research doesn't seem correct to me. 

There are other viable economic systems where the government can, for example, produce energy at cost. But because we live in a capitalist system we ought to use the power of the free market to soak up the innovative ideas that public universities and research programs produce and put them to work developing products people will purchase because they see value in them. 

Is this the correct way to view public-private research relationships? Please, change my view! 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31431834629.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I disagree with the idea that a university researcher can't patent software and spin it off as a private company because they are publicly funded).

Why should a university researcher get all the rights to an invention if he has been using public money to make that invention?

Should not the government get at least part ownership in the patent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432270974.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>If the government wants to make a deal that says "You can take this research money as long as you give us part ownership of the patent for whatever you develop." That would be completely reasonable. If they give away funds for research, they can't reasonably try to claim that this was the deal after the fact.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432288975.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Right. That should be the deal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432708224.0" user="kuriousgoomba" delta="False">
    <text>Can you elaborate more on how this structure would look? Are you thinking a sort of system where private companies that access public research papers must sign some sort of agreement that they will give a portion of the profits back to the government as a return on investment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432725398.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Can you elaborate more on how this structure would look? 


Same as now, but if you are taking Government money you have to provide manadatory license to US government (at a discount) for any intellectual property that results from Government funded research.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432817801.0" user="kuriousgoomba" delta="False">
    <text>Ah okay, so if for example a pharma company reads some government open access research and uses it to make a drug, they wouldn’t be obligated to give partial license to the government, since they didn’t take government money? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432849310.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>Sure.  Using knowledge is OK.

It's not OK to take money and then screw the taxpayers who gave you that money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432973102.0" user="kuriousgoomba" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough- thanks for your input.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31433003458.0" user="Hq3473" delta="False">
    <text>So is your view changed?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
