<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644387032.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anng7s/cmv_respect_for_elders_and_authority_figures/">
    <title>CMV: Respect for elders and authority figures shouldn’t be expected, but rather earned like the rest of the population.</title>
    <original_poster>dyxing</original_poster>
    <original_post>First time poster here :)

The idea that one should always maintain respect for those older than them, or more powerful, doesn’t seem to stand currently. And this can be perceived as largely constructive, as there is no longer blind respect for authority figures, and people are better able to speak out against oppression and injustice, even if having to stand against those older/more powerful. Additionally, this generation seems to be more critical of ideas, values and traditions held by this group of people, and this is essential in ensuring that younger or more vulnerable people aren’t taken advantage of simply because the other party is older or holds more influence.

In this case, respect should be earned, but of course, one would always be expected to remain courteous and acknowledge the fact that age is often correlated with wisdom. However, by the same token, it should be acknowledged that this is not always the case, and so it shouldn’t be expected that their perspectives are final, or correct.

However, the issue with this is that, it seems as though this general lack of respect has been emulated by mostly insolent children/teens, who act in defiance without any rational ideological backing, despite their own conviction. And this seems to be perceived as problematic in and of itself, with parenting a much more onerous task, and with the consequent diminished value of rules, laws and the like. 

So where do we find the balance? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31435471851.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>I think all respect should be given on credit, but old people should be given additional credit because they are a product of their times. 

Old-old people are probably racist by our standards. So they would run through their credit faster than your peers. 

If everyone is racist, it’s not the person, it’s the culture. 

Evidence?  We’re murdering life on this planet with our consumption. If respect is conferred upon us individually, you’re a murderer. 

Even if you excuse the behavior, by your standard your great grandkids should have less than zero respect for you. 

You deserve, I deserve no respect. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31437574079.0" user="dyxing" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not referring exclusively to those who are “old-old”, but even then, I would say that I respect  them as an individual, but I don’t think I am obliged to respect their ideas, especially when they try to impose them on me.

I will acknowledge the fact that those ideas are a product of their time, but that doesn’t make me any more inclined to accept them. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
