<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31449822941.0" user="greenmoonlight" delta="False">
    <text>You can pick whichever side and claim they started the war. So Germany started annexing the neighboring countries? Well, there's still no war unless the other country fights back, so who's to say who's at fault, right?

The Treaty of Versailles was definitely designed to humiliate and cripple Germany, but when Germany under Hitler started violating the treaty and making demands, they were given many concessions as the Allies tried to avoid a direct conflict. The Munich agreement was the ultimate example of this, when Allies violated a defense treaty with Czechoslovakia just to avoid going to war with Germany again.

They were essentially giving in because they knew Versailles had been unfair. And Germany still wanted to pick a fight.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
