<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31453180545.0" user="nsci2ece" delta="False">
    <text>So maybe everything you said is true... but have you forgotten about the Asian side of WW2 as well? The Japanese were an Axis power - are they not responsible too? Are you going to say that the British and the Chinese started WW2 in the Pacific?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31453210443.0" user="SC2_BUSINESSMAN" delta="False">
    <text>It was basically two different conflicts at one time period, wasn't it? They only got tied together because of the Tripartite Pact and also Pearl Harbor (and Germany's subsequent declaration of war on the US) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31454836113.0" user="xxFactFinder" delta="False">
    <text>THE AUCKLAND STAR, AUGUST 13, 1937

[https://paperspast.natlib.govt.nz/newspapers/AS19370813.2.60](https://paperspast.natlib.govt.nz/newspapers/AS19370813.2.60)

THE AUCKLAND STAR, AUGUST 14, 1937

[https://paperspast.natlib.govt.nz/newspapers/AS19370814.2.57](https://paperspast.natlib.govt.nz/newspapers/AS19370814.2.57)

The New York Times, Aug 31, 1937

Official foreign observers and officials of various foreign governments who participated in various conferences here in seeking to avoid the outbreak of local hostilities, agree that the Japanese exhibited the utmost restraint under provocation, even for several days keeping all of the Japanese landed force off the streets and strictly within their own barracks, although the move somewhat endangered Japanese lives and properties. "Opinions may differ regarding the responsibility for the opening of hostilities in the vicinity of Peiping early in July," said one foreign official who was a participant in the conferences held here before Aug. 13, "but concerning the Shanghai hostilities the records will justify only one decision. The Japanese did not want a repetition of the fighting here and exhibited forbearance and patience and did everything possible to avoid aggravating the situation. But they were literally pushed into the clash by the Chinese, who seemed intent on involving the foreign area and foreign interests in this clash."

[http://query.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=9507E3D8173DE23ABC4950DFBE66838C629EDE](http://query.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=9507E3D8173DE23ABC4950DFBE66838C629EDE)

The Sydney Morning Herald, October 7, 1937

[https://trove.nla.gov.au/newspaper/article/27982533?browse=ndp%3Abrowse%2Ftitle%2FS%2Ftitle%2F35%2F1937%2F10%2F07%2Fpage%2F1186407%2Farticle%2F27982533](https://trove.nla.gov.au/newspaper/article/27982533?browse=ndp%3Abrowse%2Ftitle%2FS%2Ftitle%2F35%2F1937%2F10%2F07%2Fpage%2F1186407%2Farticle%2F27982533)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

The Roosevelt Myth, by John T. Flynn (pp.173-174)

[https://mises.org/library/roosevelt-myth](https://mises.org/library/roosevelt-myth)

Foreign relations of the United States.1937.V3. (pp.635-637)  
[https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=umn.31951t002485401;view=2up;seq=4](https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=umn.31951t002485401;view=2up;seq=4)

Foreign relations of the United States.1938.V3. (pp.164-165)

[https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=uc1.b5174569;view=2up;seq=4](https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=uc1.b5174569;view=2up;seq=4)

Foreign relations of the United States. 1941.V.4. (pp.90-92)

[https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=uc1.b5174585;view=2up;seq=4](https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=uc1.b5174585;view=2up;seq=4)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
