<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31468582577.0" user="cand86" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you, but to play devil's advocate (actual argument I've heard):

More contraception leads to more sex, which necessarily creates more opportunities for contraceptive failure (because it's definitely not 100% effective!).  As such, contraception being made more acceptable and accessible (rather than stressing abstinence and only having sex when you're ready to have a child) leads to *more* abortions in the end, even though it seems like it's preventing them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468655104.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>I'll have to do some research on how the accessibility to contraception correlates with the number of abortions. I REALLY don't think this claim will be supported but if it is and there aren't any confounding variables I'll give you a delta. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468743635.0" user="Quinneaux" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, typically the burden of proof is on the one making the claim. I'm with you that this feels like a paper thin argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468761967.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>That's how I view it as well, but when I get some free time I'll look into it nonetheless. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469699199.0" user="shandower" delta="False">
    <text>Keep in mind what else the people who make this claim (and who aren’t playing devils advocate) consider to be undeniable truth. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470784984.0" user="Quinneaux" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure I follow what you're getting at. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471836085.0" user="you_got_fragged" delta="False">
    <text>I think he's saying that the people who support that idea strongly believe in it and their minds cannot be changed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469193715.0" user="LilSebs_MrsF" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;More contraception leads to more sex,

Are there any studies that show this to be true? Contraception is used by people who already are going to have sex. Contraception is not an aphrodisiac that makes people want to have sex when they otherwise wouldn't. More bike helmets don't lead to more bikes. More aspirin access doesn't lead to more people having headaches. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469780572.0" user="orangeLILpumpkin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Contraception is not an aphrodisiac that makes people want to have sex

No, but it gives people the freedom to have sex that they want.  And they may not have that sex absent the access to birth control.

I'm assuming that you're aware that many people don't have sex they want for many reasons.  Lack of access to birth control is one of those reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469508570.0" user="PauLtus" delta="False">
    <text>I think people will still end up with a whole lot more unwanted pregnancies in reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469517178.0" user="Birdbraned" delta="False">
    <text>Given there's actual data about the increased teen pregnancy rate in states with abstinence-only education compared to others that educate contraception... eh?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469648759.0" user="Asha42" delta="False">
    <text>That is absolute bullshit, I hope you told them they're a moron </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470009449.0" user="DeviaI" delta="False">
    <text>whoever made that argument obviously has 0 experience with Teens in hormonal overdrive. Teens will bone no mattter the situation that is an unequivocal truth, so society and educational system need to prepare them to do it in a safe and healty way. Assuming you can prevent it is delusional and preposterus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470400817.0" user="infrequentaccismus" delta="False">
    <text>I would add that many people argue against contraception simply for the sake of being against extramarital sex. Their thinking goes like this: if I offer contraceptives, people will think I’m endorsing or supporting their decision to have sex and I don’t support it unless they get married. Others argue against contraceptives simply because it’s against their religious beliefs.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471453296.0" user="smash_the_stack" delta="False">
    <text>It would be tricky to calculate. You need to know the percentage of unprotected sex vs protected sex both before and after the change is made in regards to availability. You also need a percentage for conception for unprotected sex. No idea what the numbers would be, but I feel like it would definitely result in a lower rate of unwanted pregnancies. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
