<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31468588647.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>Universal access to contraception is already there in the western world. I'm not aware of anything that prevents anyone of legal age from obtaining any form of birth control they so wish from their doctor. Certain forms of birth control are even more widely distributed -- anyone with a couple of quarters can buy condoms from the truck-stop bathroom. 

I'm not sure what you're referring to that there's this barrier to universal access to contraception -- its already there. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468695611.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>While condoms are readily available and for a low cost, birth control is not. As I've already mentioned, no one likes using condoms so a lot of people (wrongly) decide to forgo using them. Birth control can cost anywhere from $15-$50 dollars per month, meaning $160-$600 annually. I didn't touch on this subject in my original post but $600 annually is a LOT of money for those living in poverty, which is the demographic that tends to have the most unwanted pregnancies -- although I would argue this isn't the only variable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468707470.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>Your lifestyle is not for someone else to pay for though. It is immoral to make someone else pay for your own lifestyle choices. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468750056.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>This is swinging the discussion into a different topic - that being of whether or not taxes for social programs is moral - so I don't want to fall down the rabbit hole and change themes. I will say that I think the cost of providing cheaper or even free access to birth control will probably have a net cost lower than the cost of unwanted children being born. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468753336.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>If we're going to go by cost then just sterilize -- it will last longer </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468781219.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>People still want the opportunity to have children in the future when they're ready, sterilization would not be a viable solution to this solution. On top of that, I would think that getting your tubes tied or getting a vasectomy is similar to what you're talking about and it's reversible, but they can cost up to $6000 and $1000 (not including follow up visits) respectively. This is again not affordable for many of those living in poverty so it will not solve the issue of unwanted pregnancy.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469881655.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People still want the opportunity to have children in the future when they're ready, sterilization would not be a viable solution to this solution.

True. And birth control is a solution to this problem. However solutions don’t just show up out of nowhere. Developing these pills takes lots of money and man hours in research. They can’t just give it away. And as previously stated by another user, you can’t make someone else pay for you to have a convenience. That being said, I definitely see how is many instances it should be covered by insurance. But you gotta have health insurance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469985620.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>"Developing these pills takes lots of money and man hours in research. They can’t just give it away."

While that may have been true 50 years ago, it isn't any more.  Those companies reaped their investment on their patent and the patent has now expired.  Many oral contraceptives are in the public domain, which means they can be made very cheaply.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470017170.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;which means they can be made very cheaply

Still not free. And that’s the point. Do we make someone else pay for something for you. It’s not a matter of how much something costs it’s the principle behind making someone else pay. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471052222.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>Still cheaper than paying for an unwanted baby.  If you are worried about your tax dollars going to the poor, then birth control is a great way to make sure less money is spent on them.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471072797.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not worried about them going to the poor. That’s not what this is about. 

&amp;gt;then birth control is a great way to make sure less money is spent on them.

Not even sure what you mean by this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471250469.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do we make someone else pay for something for you.

If you are talking about paying for someone else to have birth control, my assumption is you are paying for someone else who can't afford it.  Thus the poor.  If you aren't talking about paying for the poor to have it, who are you talking about?

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471277964.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do we make someone else pay for something for you

Their socioeconomic status is irrelevant to this principle. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471330986.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so you are not lamenting the amount of money that is being spent.  


Instead you are saying, what exactly?  That people shouldn't pay for birth control for other people in general?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471717352.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>Essentially, yes. Why does the fact that you want something mean I have to pay for it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471838995.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>That is how taxes work.  The OP is saying birth control should be free, provided by the government via taxes, in the same way that Medicare is now.

Are you against Medicare?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471954631.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I can’t really remember how this thread started but I thought this comment thread was about how “having access” and paying for it are 2 different things. Everyone has access, no one is preventing anyone from purchasing it. I just don’t think others should pay for it. 

But to go along with your Medicare logic, I am against socialized medicine but that’s not what birth control is. 

You can either buy your own bc or just not have sex and boom, problem solved. No one else’s money needed. Medicare is more like insurance meaning it’s purpose deal with situations that are out of your control... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31473212804.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>I see.

I absolutely think tax money should go to pay for birth control if people want it and can't afford it.

If they can't afford birth control, they can't afford a kid, and we'd end up paying for that kid instead
.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31474071588.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>I understand where you’re coming from but this argument assumes there is only 2 options. Buy BC or have a kid. But there’s a third option, don’t have sex. If you can’t afford BC or a kid then the responsible thing to do may be to not put yourself in a situation where the result is a kid. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31474429273.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>People want to have sex.  Almost all people will do it if given the chance.  


Saying that people just won't is just ignoring the problem.  


You may choose to ignore the problem, but I would rather tax money went to pay for birth control for people who can't afford it to prevent those of those who will have sex (which will be a large proportion of them) from having children they can't afford.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31474794074.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>So because someone else wants to engage in a behavior that may result in a perceived negative consequence then I should pay for it? That’s what I don’t understand. Having sex is a choice, doesn’t matter how many people make it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31475652048.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>Having sex is a choice in the way that eating healthy is a choice, and exercising every day is a choice.

Most people can't choose to do the right thing if biology is pushing them in another direction, or if they can it some of the time, they can't keep it up a life time.

If sex were really choice, then there wouldn't be so many unwanted pregnancies to begin with.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31476631656.0" user="Craigslistiscool" delta="False">
    <text>This whole "sex isnt a choice" line of argument youre going down is a little frightening. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31476868357.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, reality is frightening.

Sex is a biological imperative.

People have trouble saying no to it.

So unless we want to take care of unwanted babies, we should use birth control.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469129368.0" user="cory_schwartz" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure that is singing into a different direction. If we're talking about about providing access by redirecting taxes,  this seems right on topic.  If doctors and drugs were free,  this wouldn't be an issue,  would it? Isn't paying for these things with other people's money exactly the reason it's an issue at all?

This is the only reason I'd personally be against this measure.  Otherwise,  I don't have any objection.  If the government wasn't involved and a personal friend asked me to help them out,  I probably would. If it were myself or my partner,  I definitely would.  But if I'm being compelled by law to pay for someone's sexual habits, I think they should take the cheaper route and just use condoms. 

Aside from the morality of taxes for personal  purposes, we also want taxes to be effective for society overall.  

If the contraceptive solution is surgical, pharmaceutical,  or other more expensive solution, this comes by tunneling taxes away from other programs. 

The proposed solution is not terrible if it causes more benefit than it costs,  but you would have to measure that somehow.  My guess is that condoms are already a cheap solution, and are easy to acquire.  The additional expense might reduce the overall effectiveness of taxes paid. By that I mean that a road repair might have greater public benefit than a single person having contraceptive. 

Furthermore,  I don't know how this will be limited.  If doctors and pharma know treatments will be guaranteed, why would they make them cheap?

 If 20ish% of my working life is going to the government,  I want they are spending my years and labor on something worthwhile. Making an expensive choice when there is a cheap and effective choice already(Condoms) doesn't seem like an effective choice to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470001411.0" user="FITeacher" delta="False">
    <text>It is cheaper to prevent babies people can not afford than to pay to raise them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470221795.0" user="SaveToTheADrive" delta="False">
    <text>Considering the amount of social programs that already exist to help parents that can't afford to support children, it's possible that paying for contraception in this way might actually spend less public money.  Children are far more expensive than contraceptives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472479588.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>Then mandatory sterilization for welfare recipients </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472524626.0" user="SaveToTheADrive" delta="False">
    <text>That doesn't sound unreasonable at all. /s

Even providing optional incentives for voluntary sterilization (or even something like a reversible vasectomy) is treading on incredibly shady moral ground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472551585.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>Why?

I would favor a system of no public welfare, where no tax money is used for social programs at all (naturally accompanied by the dramatic reduction/elimination of most taxation). 

But if there is a system of public welfare, then those who are on it have a moral responsibility to only steal the bare minimum, part of that is not having kids. If self-control is lacking in these people, then the best way to do it would be to make them incapable of having kids. This is especially true given that intelligence and many other factors beneficial to society are linked strongly with genetics, someone who's parents are on welfare likely have less desirable genes and it is in society's best interest to prevent them from passing it on. If you have a moral objection to getting sterilized, then don't take welfare money. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472624993.0" user="SaveToTheADrive" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why?

I didn't think I really needed to explain compulsory sterilization.

&amp;gt; I would favor a system of no public welfare, where no tax money is used for social programs at all (naturally accompanied by the dramatic reduction/elimination of most taxation).

Why? Social programs help people who need them. Yes, people take advantage of them, but there are also people in desperate need of help that cannot get it anywhere but their government.

&amp;gt;If self-control is lacking in these people, then the best way to do it would be to make them incapable of having kids. 

People can be financially irresponsible in many ways. Perhaps permanently castrating someone because they need help at some part in their lives is horrific. Not everyone that needs government assistance stays there forever.  Many people are just one cancer diagnosis or car accident away from requiring it.

&amp;gt; This is especially true given that intelligence and many other factors beneficial to society are linked strongly with genetics, 

"Intelligence" is relatively irrelevant.  There are plenty of responsible, contributing members of society that have lower intelligence. If smarts is that important, why not fund education better? 

Eugenics is also a moral nightmare, as you are going down the path of **punishing a member of society for something that is not their fault**.

&amp;gt;  it is in society's best interest

You haven't sufficiently justified this. I would say that wantonly sterilizing "undesirables" is incredibly poor for society, because it oppresses large amounts of people (of which the society is comprised of). By the same line of reasoning, why not just herd up all the stupid, the poor, the unvaccinated, and the disabled, and kill them? Society would benefit, would it not?

&amp;gt; If you have a moral objection to getting sterilized, then don't take welfare money. 

Choosing between starving and getting sterilized isn't a valid choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472718354.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why? Social programs help people who need them. Yes, people take advantage of them, but there are also people in desperate need of help that cannot get it anywhere but their government.

Because it is immoral to steal from one person to give to another, regardless of who you're stealing from or who you're giving it to. Those who which to donate to others can do so voluntarily in a method outside of taxation. 

&amp;gt; People can be financially irresponsible in many ways. Perhaps permanently castrating someone because they need help at some part in their lives is horrific. Not everyone that needs government assistance stays there forever. Most people are one cancer diagnosis or car accident away from requiring it.

Why would that be horrific? Again, the agreement would be to abstain from having kids -- sterilization would only be used for those who refuse to do that but still wanted to get welfare benefits. Part of taking someone else's money or using someone else's stuff is that there needs to be conditions for it. I don't care if you take a hammer to your own car, but if I'm letting you borrow my car I can and should set expectations such as not taking a hammer to it. If you are in a position of your life where you cannot care for yourself then it should be a requirement that you can't bring others into the world. 

&amp;gt; "Intelligence" is relatively irrelevant. There are plenty of responsible, contributing members of society that have lower intelligence. If smarts is that important, why not fund education better?

Because intelligence is an innate trait that's relatively unchanged by education. Its possible to improve your education, but not your intelligence. 

Its a bit like playing basketball, no matter how much a midget plays basketball, he'll never beat a moderately skilled player who's 6 or 7 foot tall. They can get better at basketball then they were yesterday, but they'll never be a world-class basketball player. 

&amp;gt; Eugenics is also a moral nightmare, as you are going down the path of punishing a member of society for something that is not their fault

You're not punishing them as much as making sure that the best interests of society are met. If someone is a leech on society, they should not be reproducing. Period. 

&amp;gt; You haven't sufficiently justified this. I would say that wantonly sterilizing "undesirables" is incredibly poor for society, because it oppresses large amounts of people (of which the society is comprised of). By the same line of reasoning, why not just herd up all the stupid, and the poor, and the disabled, and kill them? Society would benefit, would it not?

Because all human life has a basal value. All people are not equal, but they still have a base value, similar to how a penny and a $100 bill are both money, but one is worth quite a bit more than another. 

&amp;gt; Choosing between starving and getting sterilized isn't a valid choice.

The choice isn't between starving -- its between getting government assistance. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472807060.0" user="SaveToTheADrive" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Because it is immoral to steal from one person to give to another, regardless of who you're stealing from or who you're giving it to.

Taxes aren't stealing. They are a necessary contribution to the government that provides invaluable services to its citizens.

&amp;gt; Because intelligence is an innate trait that's relatively unchanged by education. Its possible to improve your education, but not your intelligence.

Shorter and taller than average people tend to have lower life expectancies. Should we also incentivize these people to stop reproducing for "the good of society?"

Society is not improved by alienating a part of it.

&amp;gt; the best interests of society are met

A society also includes the people within it.  What you're proposing is not in the benefit of the society.

&amp;gt; The choice isn't between starving -- its between getting government assistance. 

And without assistance, some people would be unable to survive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31476884867.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Taxes aren't stealing. They are a necessary contribution to the government that provides invaluable services to its citizens.

If anyone was to do what the government was doing it would be illegal. Morality does not depend on self-proclaimed labels. 

&amp;gt; Shorter and taller than average people tend to have lower life expectancies. Should we also incentivize these people to stop reproducing for "the good of society?"

If they were much, much lower then perhaps, however, the two do not differ by a huge amount 

&amp;gt; Society is not improved by alienating a part of it.

Of course it is. Part of a garden is not merely the presence of flowers, but also the elimination of weeds. 

Society does not prosper when all are treated equally, rather society is best benefited when those who show the most promise are taken care of. Given that there are finite resources in the world, it makes sense to give them to those who show the most promise. Society and mankind does not progress evenly at a steady pace, but moves by leaps and jumps by the work of great men. 

&amp;gt; A society also includes the people within it. What you're proposing is not in the benefit of the society.

Of course it is. It is best for society (both born and unborn) that those who are incapable of feeding themselves do not bring into the world more mouths to feed. 

&amp;gt; And without assistance, some people would be unable to survive.

Then they will get sterilized, but its still a choice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470470455.0" user="proteins911" delta="False">
    <text>As a scientist who does drug development related research, this point of view really irks me. People don't acknowledge the work that goes into developing every single drug on the market. Developing drugs and doing all the preliminary research needed before development even beings requires SO much money and time. I frequently work 15+ hour days, sometimes have to be in lab in the middle of the night, and sometimes go entire months without a day off. Rather than appreciating the crazy schedules many scientists go through to develop vaccines or find cancer cures, people instead just complain that we actually do want a roof over our heads so can't give it all away for free.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Basically what I hear in these discussions is that working crazy hours to bring these drugs to the public isn't enough... I should also use the money I work really hard to earn to buy people the drugs... any why do you want me to do that?.... oh yeah, because people think sex feels better without condoms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31479418295.0" user="NowTimeDothWasteMe" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have an issue with funding all drugs to help people or just birth control? Because the vast majority of people who use birth control do so for non-birth control reasons - ei: to regulate menstrual cycles, treat cramping, reduce risk for certain cancers, etc. So if we as a society have accepted that we will subsidize medications for diabetes/blood pressure/other significant health issues, we should not arbitrarily decide not to supplement an important medication because we disagree part of its use. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470638847.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;I'm not sure what you're referring to that there's this barrier to universal access to contraception -- its already there. 

In the US, that is currently the case because of a Supreme Court case called Griswold v. Connecticut. Griswold is the first use of the "right to privacy" that the Court inferred from the Constitution. Griswold was then the foundation for Roe v. Wade, which legalized abortion. 

The Republican party has been trying to chip away at the Roe v. Wade precedent, and since they now have a stronger 5 vote majority on th e Court,there is a real belief that they will challenge Griswold, and use that to overrule Roe. 

If Griswold is overruled, there would be nothing preventing states from implementing contraception bans, just as Connecticut did. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
