<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31468818803.0" user="kaczinski_chan" delta="False">
    <text>Contraceptives lower the birth rates of relatively responsible people. Abortion lowers the birth rates of relatively irresponsible people. That's a case for supporting abortion but not contraception.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468863370.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>So would you say that this is a pro-choice argument? That since abortion is better at lowering birth rates than contraception for irresponsible people that we should only have abortion but not contraception? I don't see why the two are mutually exclusive. Why would somebody that's pro-choice only support abortion and not access to contraception? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468997706.0" user="kaczinski_chan" delta="False">
    <text>The two have opposite long term effects. If you want humanity to have the best possible future, it makes plenty of sense to support the one that helps and oppose the one that hurts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468916107.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Free, easily accessed contraceptives - especially long acting, reversible contraceptives - reduce the birth rates of all women. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469015316.0" user="kaczinski_chan" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing reduces birth rates evenly - everything steers the gene pool one way or the other. It still biases toward people who are inclined to take preventative action. It would take active eugenics measures to reverse that (whereas abortion has a positive effect by default), and that is impossible in today's political climate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31471360994.0" user="NeonSeal" delta="False">
    <text>Can you elaborate on why this is a reasonable position to have (not saying you agree with this though)?

Are you saying that one might support abortion but not contraception because, if implemented, more children would be born to responsible people and less would be born to irresponsible people?

Because if that is it, I can think of many reasons why this is a completely ridiculous opinion to have including:

* Responsible parenting is not just a function of whether or not you choose to use contraceptives. Not even close?
* I would argue that not having access to any contraceptives is arguably a human rights violation. Sex is something that will always occur, so you will essentially force women to endure abortions when they could have just used less invasive means such as a condom or BC pill. Also, men will have to deal with the psychological and emotional implications as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31472719489.0" user="kaczinski_chan" delta="False">
    <text>That is what I'm saying. To your 2 points:

1. Abortions are generally a response to irresponsible decisions. Not always, but usually. That is enough for there to be an obvious net effect.

2. That is irrelevant to the effect it has on responsible vs irresponsible birth rates. If you value the long term effects over the immediate, my point still stands. In addition, the increased likelihood of pregnancy from sex means women are more picky in favor of men who can support a child, which further improves the gene pool.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
