<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31468633263.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>If you can’t afford condoms or birth control you probably aren’t responsible enough to have sex. While sex feels good and is fun, the only reason it’s their is to create kids. I mean most women never even experience a vaginal orgasm and dudes are usually trying their hardest not to orgasm. 

I would also challenge the notion that universal access to the pill would lead to fewer unwanted pregnancies. None of my friends who always use a condom have impregnated a girl while i have plenty of friends that have gotten their girlfriends or girls who were on the pill pregnant because they didn’t take it correctly. The girls that took it infrequently or different times of the day were usually the younger ones which is who i assume would use the service you speak of. I truly have no idea how people can get pregnant when using a condom properly and how using one improperly is even happening. They either break or don’t and you know either way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468739490.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>I don't find the evolutionary argument that "sex is only there to procreate" convincing whatsoever. It seems like people often forget that evolution cares only about the long-term survival of species and nothing about the well-being or enjoyment of the individual. By your same logic, we shouldn't seek to help people with disabilities or weak immune systems because from an evolutionary perspective they were meant to die so that they couldn't pass on their weak genes to new generations. I find this to be morally repulsive. 

Secondly, your argument against my notion that access to the pill will lead to fewer pregnancies is completely anecdotal which in the world of statistics means is nearly useless. I provided a link in my original post that shows that the pill is twice as effective at stopping pregnancy than condoms. If you can link me research or data that says otherwise then I'd love to have a discussion on the logistics of birth control and its effectiveness, but an anecdote from your experience growing up won't convince me otherwise.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468807803.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>You are right, evolution does not care about that. Having sex has nothing to do with surviving so having the people around you pay for something other than your emergency survival is unjust on so many levels. 

I don’t know how the logic “the community should only provide for people unable to provide for themselves what is necessary to survive” turned into kill the handicapped or people weak immune systems. Are you really saying not ensuring people the access to free birth control is the same as not caring for the handicapped? 

Your world of statistics is based on the verbal testimony of what is probably teenagers afraid to tell their parents they weren’t using a condom  because after a certain age you usually start having sex with only one person who you trust is old enough to take her birth control regularly. Again just think, how do you use a condom the wrong way? Put it on your actual head? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468845255.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don’t know how the logic “the community should only provide for people unable to provide for themselves what is necessary to survive” turned into kill the handicapped or people weak immune systems

Because the basis of your argument is that something does not have value apart from its evolutionary/biological purpose, which is shown from your first comment when you state "While sex feels good and is fun, the only reason it’s their is to create kids". I rebuttled by saying viewing something solely from the relation to its evolutionary/biological purpose can be very immoral. I used the most hyerbolic example I could to give my point, that one could view disabled people or those with weak immune systems as biologically bad because they would be passing on bad genes so why would we bother helping them when they serve no/a bad evolutionary purpose. The basis behind the two arguments are both based on viewing things from a evolutionary perspective which I think can be an immoral thing to do. 

&amp;gt; Your world of statistics is based on the verbal testimony of what is probably teenagers afraid to tell their parents they weren’t using a condom because after a certain age you usually start having sex with only one person who you trust is old enough to take her birth control regularly. Again just think, how do you use a condom the wrong way? Put it on your actual head?

Again, I am going to trust research and data over the fact that you don't understand how people can use a condom incorrectly/that a condom can break. If you can show me research or data of your own that disproves my point I will gladly give you a delta and we can discuss which data we think is more accurate, but without it your testimony is useless to me.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468960714.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	Because the basis of your argument is that something does not have value apart from its evolutionary/biological purpose

No I’m saying to don’t have enough value to be funded collectively by the community. 

&amp;gt;I used the most hyerbolic example I could to give my point, that one could view disabled people or those with weak immune systems as biologically bad because they would be passing on bad genes so why would we bother helping them when they serve no/a bad evolutionary purpose. 

I never said sex was biologically bad or having
It just for pleasure is bad. Again, it’s not something necessary to living so it shouldnt be funded by society. Its not their obligation to make sure you can still have sex for fun while you can’t even afford a condom.

&amp;gt;	Again, I am going to trust research and data over the fact that you don't understand how people can use a condom incorrectly/that a condom can break.

Ok well since I’ve looked it up. I want you to look it up and tell me what you find those researchers you trust so much constitutes  “Using a condom incorrectly”  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469549687.0" user="Birdbraned" delta="False">
    <text>From the planned parenthood website:  
[Condom effectiveness rate compared to everything else](https://www.plannedparenthood.org/learn/birth-control) of effectively 85%

[Condom instructions](https://www.plannedparenthood.org/learn/birth-control/condom/how-to-put-a-condom-on) \- reading between the lines, there's plenty a young person (which seems to be the demographic you assume the highest usage error rate is in) can do wrong:

\-Buy an ill-fitting condom and use it anyway

\-Roll it on wrong

\-Put it on after penetration (and get the girl pregnant through pre-ejaculate)

\-Use an old/expired condom (and thus have an increased rate of breakage)

\-Condom is stored improperly

\-Use the wrong type of lube (and thus have an increased rate of breakage)

\-Not withdraw until the penis is flaccid (increased sperm spillage)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

This is not including the proven methods of condom failure from the anecdotes of the sexually active:  
\-Pretend to put on a condom but actually just roll on the rim (they won't notice in the dark!)

\-Put the condom on but slip it off mid copulation because it feels better

\-Deliberate sabotage of condom integrity

[And more.](https://www.livescience.com/18661-14-common-condom-errors.html)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Compared to the pill, which has an effective rate of 91% and can fail via:

\-Poor storage

\-Poor dosage timing

\-Took the wrong (inactive) pill

\-Vomited it up within 4 hours

[Skip down to "compliance/continuation rates"](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4212440/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469650623.0" user="therealdieseld" delta="False">
    <text>When you start making bad faith argument and say things like “by your own logic” without actually knowing their specific view on disabilities, you sound like you can’t be convinced and just posted to help reassure your position is confirmed by other people... back to the topic at hand, yes it should be universally accessible, I believe everyone has access to go to  a store already. Unless you mean that other people need to help fund this project, then I 100% disagree with you. The pro-choice position should be the choice to have sex or not. Actions have consequences and one of the consequences of sex is pregnancy. If you’re willing to take that chance, that’s on you. Not someone else or government to fund. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468763627.0" user="Quinneaux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;While sex feels good and is fun, the only reason it’s their is to create kids.

I beg to differ. I know a lot of people who have sex for funsies. Obviously if you're just speaking biologically, sure... but we're not *just* slaves to our biology. Pleasure is as much a feature of sex as pregnancies are. This kind of puritan argument really doesn't match the day and age. 

&amp;gt;i have plenty of friends that have gotten their girlfriends or girls who were on the pill pregnant **because they didn’t take it correctly**

What a shocker! How is that an argument against universal access to the contraceptives, though, and not an argument for more sex ed? To be frank, that goes for any contraceptive: there is no situation where it's better to *not* have universal access to contraceptives than it is to *do* have it insofar as you're looking to prevent abortions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468916709.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	but we're not just slaves to our biology. 

I never said you were. I am defending that society is not a slave to your pleasures. 


&amp;gt;	What a shocker! How is that an argument against universal access to the contraceptives, though, and not an argument for more sex ed? 

No, its not. the girls who took the pill incorrectly weren’t thrown a box of birth control and told figure it out. They are told by a doctor not a gym teacher how to take it.

&amp;gt;	there is no situation where it's better to not have universal access to contraceptives.

I think you had a typo after this but it doesn’t matter I’m going to stop you right here. Freedom is a situation that is much better than universal access
To contraceptives </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468984206.0" user="Quinneaux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I never said you were. I am defending that society is not a slave to your pleasures.

You don't think this is even slightly exaggerated?

&amp;gt;No, its not. the girls who took the pill incorrectly weren’t thrown a box of birth control and told figure it out. They are told by a doctor not a gym teacher how to take it.

Yeah, and I was told by a professional how basic French grammar works, but that didn't exactly stick either. If preventing abortions due to unwanted pregnancies was really something we cared about, you'd think we (parents, educators, medical professionals, politicians) would make a stronger effort. 

&amp;gt;Freedom is a situation that is much better than universal access To contraceptives

The WHO agrees that access to contraceptives reduce abortions. As I said: if you're looking to reduce abortions, providing universal access to contraceptives works. If you're arguing that this access shouldn't be paid for with tax dollars because *muh freedom*, then I'm happy to agree to disagree with that. 

The bottom line is super simple: do you want to prevent abortions? Provide universal access to contraceptives. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469043254.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	You don't think this is even slightly exaggerated?

Honestly, no the government or society should only provide what you need to survive if you refuse to work. If you a physically or mentally disabled that is a different story. 

&amp;gt;	Yeah, and I was told by a professional how basic French grammar works

Was its as simple as, you need to take this pill everyday at the same time or it doesn’t work. When you were taught to wipe your ass after you shit did that not stick? 

&amp;gt;	The WHO agrees that access to contraceptives reduce abortions. As I said: if you're looking to reduce abortions, providing universal access to contraceptives works. If you're arguing that this access shouldn't be paid for with tax dollars because muh freedom, then I'm happy to agree to disagree with that.
The bottom line is super simple: do you want to prevent abortions? Provide universal access to contraceptives.

The OP states regardless of my view on abortions. So idk why you are using that as an argument. Since you brought it up though, my view on abortion is unless the woman’s life is in danger you shouldn’t be able to have one. Yes, sex is fun and doesn’t need to be used primarily for having sex, drinking alcohol is also fun, there is an age limit to alchohol consumption though because you need to be mature enough to handle it.

Quick edit: freedom is more important than anything. Ask anyone who isn’t from your privileged country that immigrated from somewhere they were oppressed  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469098800.0" user="rucksackmac" delta="False">
    <text>Not being responsible enough to have sex will stop zero people from having sex...especially considering how irresponsible they are.
Just sayin!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469131157.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>Seems like a parents job not societies. It doesn’t take a village to raise your kid  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469653980.0" user="Asha42" delta="False">
    <text>You're having sex wrong if you're not orgasming.
It being fun is a reason to have sex.
Condoms are contraception.
The pill has drastically reduced pregnancies.
You don't get to say people aren't 'responsible' enough for sex.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
