<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31468546302.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>**Note:** Your thread has **not** been removed.

Your post's topic seems to be fairly common on this subreddit. Similar posts can be found through our [DeltaLog search](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/search?q=abortion+%7C+abort+%7C+pro-life+%7C+pro-choice&amp;amp;restrict_sr=on&amp;amp;sort=relevance&amp;amp;t=all) or via the [CMV search function](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/search?q=abortion&amp;amp;amp;amp;restrict_sr=on).

Regards, the mods of /r/changemyview.

*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468658081.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>My apologies, I'm new to CMV and Reddit as a whole so I'll make sure to be more careful in the future</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469782390.0" user="orangeLILpumpkin" delta="False">
    <text>Don't worry about it.  AutoMod posts this comment on every post here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469820992.0" user="Sheevy_Boi" delta="False">
    <text>Don't worry, it just detected the word abortion and assumed you're against it. I've never seen this post before</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31474428437.0" user="Bolognanipple" delta="False">
    <text>So someone cannot hold conservative views on abortion in this sub?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31474434526.0" user="Sheevy_Boi" delta="False">
    <text>No, it's just that it gets posted a lot</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31474865291.0" user="Bolognanipple" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a fair statement </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
