<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31468640616.0" user="Bolasraecher" delta="False">
    <text>For some fundamentalist christians Sex is meant solely for procreation, and any other sex is immoral.
As such, birth control is not just unnecessary, it actively encourages sinful behavior.
I have known people who hold this position. And while I don‘t agree with it, I think it is logical from their standpoint.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468700872.0" user="cresloyd" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And while I don‘t agree with it, I think it is logical from their standpoint.

I will go even further and question whether it's "logical" but simply: ["By God, it is a sin!!!"](https://www.catholic.com/tract/birth-control)  There is some mention of a duty to procreate, which implies a duty not to avoid procreating, but hopefully even very devout Christians strongly believe that in our overcrowded world.

But those religious-based beliefs do, of course, still exist.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468747265.0" user="4thestory" delta="False">
    <text>I really want to know where most of you guys live that you think anywhere near a good part of the country follows these rules. 

Like maybe there are a few girls who say they are waiting until marriage because of their religion and that usually ends some where between the end of high school and sophomore year of college. To think those girls then say, “well i know I’m going to commit a pretty well known sin by having sex before marriage but i will not avoid procreating because of the small obscure passage somewhere that know one ever follows.”

Come from a person taking something one step further than logical </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31468705459.0" user="Bagool88" delta="False">
    <text>This might be nitpicking, but if their sole argument against the accessibility to contraception is religious I feel that their priorities don't lie with stopping abortion but rather justifying the word of the Bible. I don't think these two things are equivocal because there is an outside factor that pushing their beliefs separate from abortion.   </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
