<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31469767427.0" user="bestdnd" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not a native English speaker, so i'd assume "contraception" means the birth-control pills that are taken regularly or a few hours after unsafe sex.

I do agree that these pills should be available to anyone who wants them. According to Wikipedia (under "birth control", section "legal positions"), it might even be considered a human right.

On the other hand, these pills cost money, and providing it to women all around the world would cost a lot. Consider that there are health risks with these pills (mainly when there are background issues), and we see the reason there more research (and even more money) going into it.

This money we (as the global society) spend on that subject could be spent on other important subjects (housing, clean water, education and more).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470232667.0" user="SaveToTheADrive" delta="False">
    <text>How much money is spent on supporting children whose parents can not afford to?  Isn't it possible that free access to contraceptives might reduce the number of children needing public money enough to pay for itself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470797565.0" user="bestdnd" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but this would only help financing it in the long term. Until then, investing in education might give you a similar effect.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
