<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="649036062.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aqf3fi/cmv_regardless_of_your_view_on_abortion_everyone/">
    <title>CMV: Regardless of your view on abortion everyone should support universal access to contraception</title>
    <original_poster>Bagool88</original_poster>
    <original_post>Like the title suggests, I think that supporting increased access to contraception (especially birth control) is in everyone's best interest regardless of whether they are pro-choice or pro-life. If you're pro-life, easier access to contraception ensures that lower rates of unwanted pregnancies which should then lead to fewer abortions. If you're pro-choice, nobody *wants* unplanned pregnancies to occur, they just want women to have the option available so that a mistake doesn't ruin their lives. 

That being said, I don't see how anyone could be against increased or even universal access to contraception and birth control in particular. Yes condoms are readily available and cheap, but 1) condoms don't feel good so a lot of people make the stupid mistake of not using one, and 2) [birth control is more effective than condoms](https://kidshealth.org/en/teens/bc-chart.html). It seems that both sides would either benefit from or support fewer unwanted pregnancies, so why would anyone ever not support increased access to contraception? 

Edit: Wow this post blew up overnight. Most of the arguments I'm seeing against my view is that since condoms are both cheap and easily accessible that we do have some form of universal access to contraception, or that universal access to the pill would inevitably mean that it would be provided through tax dollars. My problems with this are I've said, condoms aren't immensely effective and work ~ 82% of the time, and while not wanting your tax dollars to go into funding the pill is absolutely a valid and reasonable view to have, neither of these views actually solve the problem of how to prevent unwanted pregnancies. I'd like to open up the discussion and ask those of you opposed to funding the pill with tax dollars how you would propose we lower the rates of unplanned pregnancy. If anyone can come up with a reasonable solution that doesn't involve the use of tax spending I will gladly give a delta. Thanks for the reasonable dialogue so far everyone!                </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31469092164.0" user="Exis007" delta="False">
    <text>For the sake of this post, I'm going to make the argument that birth control is really just abortion in another form. Perhaps because it allows for sperm to meet egg (thus beginning a process I consider to be "life") but makes implantation unsuccessful. Perhaps because I make the argument that by stopping God's will in allowing for babies to be made, you're acting above your station. If you believe life begins at conception and that god bestows a soul upon that life and god is infallible, then any form of birth control that allows for the possibility of ovulation but not implantation (an IUD for example) is, in fact, abortion. 

**But let's say it was never about abortion; it was always about control**. Let's say I don't really care so much about life and babies and abortion, but that what I really want is more control over women. Then abortion alone can't be the thrust of my argument because while that will work for many, it really isn't the point. This isn't a feminist rant, I'm not talking about what should be or can be, I'm just talking about biology. Biologically, child-bearing makes you weak. It straps you with a life you have to nurture and provide for and that's difficult at a survival level. Biologically, simply contributing sperm and hoping for the best makes paternity uncertain. Without birth control, men easily control women. The biological need to care for a child makes women dependent on men for survival and the control locks down paternity so as to ensure that the genes carry forward. Its an effective system. If you strip away the moralizing, if you don't care about the lives of the people involved, it makes a lot of sense. 

If you empower for women to decide when to have children and if they want children, you take power away from men. You threaten the family unit. The family is no longer a system of survival, but rather an optional arrangement that can be created and dissolved by either party. 

And if you hate that? If you're invested in the traditional form of family, if you're invested in the power and control of the old system, if what you want is things to be the way they were, you'd be against abortion AND birth control. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469321631.0" user="5xum" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Perhaps because it allows for sperm to meet egg (thus beginning a process I consider to be "life") but makes implantation unsuccessful.

That... is not how the pill works. Contraception pills work by preventing the woman's ovary from releasing the egg in the first place, so the sperm never gets to meet the egg.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31469792728.0" user="orangeLILpumpkin" delta="False">
    <text>The OP is referring to "birth control"; which includes much more than only the pill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31470252871.0" user="Exis007" delta="False">
    <text>No kidding. 

Hormonal forms of birth control eliminate ovulation through hormones that mimic low-level pregnancy. There's no use, in body logic, to go through the song and dance of releasing an egg if you're already knocked up. That being said, that would be a deeply imperfect system. In some formulations of the pill (take, for example, those that use just progesterone and not the dual hormone combo) the object is not to simply stop ovulation alone but to thicken the cervical mucus thus creating no bridge for the sperm to climb. Additionally, it thins the lining of the uterus such that even if ovulation occurred and sperm reached the egg, the fertilized egg would not implant within the uterus. The lack of a lining filled with nutrients to feed the egg would cause the egg to die off. That's what I am talking about. 

Additionally, forms of birth control like the IUD are designed to rely more heavily on stopping implantation than ovulation. The hormonal form (aka Mirena) will typically attempt to stop both ovulation and implantation like the pill. The copper IUD, Paraguard, does not have a hormonal component. That form **only** stops implantation by being a disruptive shape within the uterus. The egg will be unable to implant in the uterine lining due to the big, bulky copper shape that will disrupt it existing in that space. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
