<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="650468635.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ar9st7/cmv_there_is_no_law_change_to_citizens_united_v/">
    <title>CMV: There is no law change to Citizens United v FEC that restricts business speech without infringing on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press</title>
    <original_poster>shoesafe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please change my view: any legal or constitutional fix that allows Congress to restrict the political speech of business corporations would also allow restriction on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press.

The Citizens United v. FEC (2010) case is famous in US political debates.  The basic issue is that a non-profit corporation made a movie criticizing a politician right before an election, and that violated US campaign finance law.  The Supreme Court majority opinion said there was a First Amendment right for a corporation (or union) to air political commercials during the period before an election, despite the fact that a small portion of the nonprofit's funding came from for-profit corporations.

Here is how the majority opinion by Kennedy states the problem with the federal law restricting speech:

&amp;gt;The law before us is an outright ban, backed by criminal sanctions. Section 441b makes it a felony for all corporations—including nonprofit advocacy corporations—either to expressly advocate the election or defeat of candidates or to broadcast electioneering communications within 30 days of a primary election and 60 days of a general election. Thus, the following acts would all be felonies under §441b: The Sierra Club runs an ad, within the crucial phase of 60 days before the general election, that exhorts the public to disapprove of a Congressman who favors logging in national forests; the National Rifle Association publishes a book urging the public to vote for the challenger because the incumbent U. S. Senator supports a handgun ban; and the American Civil Liberties Union creates a Web site telling the public to vote for a Presidential candidate in light of that candidate’s defense of free speech. These prohibitions are classic examples of censorship.

My view is that any legal or constitutional fix that allows Congress to enforce 2 USC Section 441b against business corporations would also infringe on individual speech or free press.

I will clarify that I am not talking about infringing the right of people to form a corporation for business purposes and then have that business corporation exercise its speech rights.  Although I think freedom of speech applies to anybody regardless of identity - whether foreign or not, convicted felon or not, facilitated by a business entity or not - I am not making that argument here.   I am making a collateral damage argument: if you try to excise for-profit corporate speech, you will affect a not-insubstantial amount of individual speech or freedom of the press.

I am not asking you to change my philosophical view of free speech, since that is pretty firmly held and I am not terribly open to changing it.  I am asking you to change my view of whether it is legally or conceptually possible to target just the one kind of business corporation speech without attacking individual speech or freedom of the press.  I believe that even terrible policy ideas can be conceptually possible, so I am open to changing my view from "it's not really possible" to "it's possible but still a terrible idea."  But I do not see a clear way to isolate just business corporation speech from individual speech and press.

By "individual speech," I am including the right to form a non-profit corporation or other community group, whether it's a big group like Planned Parenthood or the NRA or a small neighborhood organization.  By "freedom of the press," I am referring both to the right of the people to print expressive materials like books, pamphlets and newsletters generally, and to the right to operate journalistic enterprises specifically, whether meant to be objective or opinionated.

There are many different proposed solutions that are a threat to individual free expression or freedom of the press.

* *Status quo ante*.  We could imagine somehow a change to the Constitution or the Court that allows a do-over and Section 441b is back in force with no other changes.  That directly violates individual free speech because it allows the government, for certain election-related speech, to ban your movie or seize your books or destroy your pamphlets if your nonprofit was funded by even one dollar from a for-profit corporation.  That is incompatible with free speech.  Imagine if a major nonprofit political group, which supports all the things you like, were one day silenced because a single for-profit company, owned by a visionary corporate leader who says all the right things and has all the right political friends and all the right political enemies, made a small contribution of cash or supplies.  I think most of us can see how that would be really restrictive of free speech for all the individuals who contributed to that worthy nonprofit.
* "Money is not speech."  A straight amendment that "money is not speech" would be incredibly broad and would per se threaten individual speech.  In Buckley v. Valeo (1976), the Court said, "*A restriction on the amount of money a person or group can spend on political communication during a campaign necessarily reduces the quantity of expression by restricting the number of issues discussed, the depth of their exploration, and the size of the audience reached*."  If we were to take it outside the realm of speech and say "money is not religion," would anyone dispute that a ban on spending money to publish bibles or build temples is inconsistent with freedom of religion?  If you told people they have the right to protest, but they are not allowed to spend any money on signs or flags or matching t-shirts or even travel expenses to attend the protest, I think most of us can see that would pretty clearly restrict their right to protest.
* "End corporate personhood."  Aside from the chaos this could cause to civil lawsuits and to anybody investing in the stock market, this rule might not stop a non-corporate entity or informal group from publishing an ad.  This really depends on the specifics, but unless you have a "money is not speech" rule, ending corporate personhood really does not do anything directly for speech and so does not itself reverse the outcome of the Citizens United case.  There is no way to enforce Section 441b banning corporate speech if there are no more corporations.  That said, a broad rule here might be so sweeping that it makes it very difficult for groups of citizens to form any kind of community group or issue advocacy group, which would violate the individual's right to create a group to spread their own speech.  Most of these proposals are coupled with a "money is speech" amendment as a shortcut.
* "No speech for any corporations."  This obviously violates individual free speech.  If you start a neighborhood group to protest something like police brutality or pollution or tax policy or zoning policy in your neighborhood, and you want to advertise which candidates agree with you and which ones disagree, then "no speech for any corporations" applies to your little community nonprofit.  It also applies to corporations practicing journalism, so it violates freedom of the press.
* "No speech for for-profit corporations."  This is a common proposal to try to protect political entities and target business entities.  If it lets the government stifle the speech of for-profit corporations, then most news organizations and journalistic outfits could be restricted, imperiling freedom of the press.  It also opens up the possibility of a non-profit created by a for-profit corporation, which allows it to circumvent the rule, meaning that business speech is in practice slightly hampered but not very restricted.
* "No speech for for-profit corporations or non-profits funded by for-profit corporations."  This is fairly similar to the status quo ante (pre 2010) and the same criticism applies. The problem here is that this rule quickly gets broad and endangers lots of individual speech done through nonprofit activist groups.  For example, if your community nonprofit raises money locally to fight an important issue, and it raises some of its money from a few small businesses in the neighborhood, you have now invalidated free speech for the whole group.  The nonprofit is tainted by a little bit of business speech, and all those individuals' speech rights are restricted just so Congress can target the threat of business corporation speech.  This is the twist directly confronted in the Citizens United case and the one that distinguished it from earlier cases.  The twist was that a "small portion" of its funding came from for-profit corporations.  The case FEC v. MCFL (1986) had already found Section 441b invalid as applied to nonprofit corporations, but that holding did not extend to nonprofit corporations that received any money from for-profit corporations.  The Court in 2010 extended protection to Citizens United despite their de minimis for-profit funding.
* "No speech for any corporations except for journalism."  Sometimes people try suggest this modification to the ban on corporate speech but it does not seem to be offered in good faith and includes almost no effort to grapple with the inconsistency of it.  Specifically, the inconsistency of making it illegal for corporations to publish news and opinions about elections, with an exception if that corporation publishes LOTS of news and opinions about elections.  Really, it turns on the definition of journalism or freedom of the press.  But it seems that either this journalism/press exception waters everything down and does not target business speech or it gives Congress the power to ban journalism outfits it disagrees with and abandons freedom of the press.
* "Only natural persons have rights."  This is basically a different way of presenting the "no speech for any corporations" rule but it tries to emphasize that it wants individuals to retain speech rights.  Whatever other problems and consequences of this rule, it never seems like it would work unless your intention is also to stop corporations from funding individual speech.  If corporations lack speech rights but humans have speech rights, then you could circumvent a corporate speech restriction by having the individual filmmaker or author or pamphleteer do the speech activity.  The documentary could be published and disseminated by the documentarian, using funds raised by the corporation and paid over to the filmmaker.  To the extent you block an individual from seeking funding for their own speech, you are restricting their speech rights.  Of course, with crowdfunding mechanisms it is not too difficult to imagine getting around the restriction anyway, by having the corporation promote the cause but all the money skips the corporation and goes from individual to individual.  So either the rule is effective at restricting business speech and it also restricts individual speech, or the rule is ineffective at restricting business speech because other funding mechanisms are able to circumvent your rule.

There are probably other variations but these are the major ones of which I am aware.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31478838345.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>First off great post, I haven't thought about the issue in a while and its incredible important.

&amp;gt; "*A restriction on the amount of money a person or group can spend on political communication during a campaign necessarily reduces the quantity of expression by restricting the number of issues discussed, the depth of their exploration, and the size of the audience reached*."

Thinking about this now, I'm a pretty solid member of the money doesn't equal speech camp. Having limits on the amount of money a corporation can spend on campaign ads seems like a good idea, and really very similar to the existing laws that prevent campaign donations past a certain point.  Restricting donated ads tv value seems like a natural extension of this. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31478943436.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks.  What do you think of the argument in Buckley v. Valeo that a restriction on spending money on expression limits expression?

Spending money is just a way to gather resources and energy and direct them at a goal, so limiting money is partially limiting the amount of resources and energy you can spend on speech or anything else.

Maybe these hypotheticals will change your opinion:

\- A Deep South state in 1956 passes a law that nobody can spend money on a political campaign to malign or harm a company resident in the state.  Since money is not speech, it is not censorship when the state seizes illegal flyers bought to advertise a civil rights bus boycott directed at a local bus company.

\- Congress, tired of journalists reporting on scandals, restricts the amount of money that newspapers and other journalistic agencies can spend on salaries and other costs of investigating scandals.  Restricting the money restricts the freedom of the press.

\- The President, tired of what he sees as constant journalistic criticism, gets Congress to pass a law requiring journalistic outfits to equalize their negative and positive coverage based on the money spent for each - for every dollar spent on negative coverage, they must spend at least a dollar on positive coverage. Restricting money restricts freedom of the press and freedom speech.

\- After years of suffering nationwide protests, including anti-war, anti-bank, anti-deficit, and anti-immigrant protests, Congress passes a law that protests cannot spend any money on supplies used at the site of the protest, including signs and flags, paper or clipboards, noisemakers or bullhorns, tents or weather gear, food or drink, or anything else used by protest organizers or distributed to protesters.  Those bringing their own signs, tents, food, etc. must stand away from the protest.  All of those things were bought with money and contributing them to the protest, even if you are the protester, is an illegal contribution.  Restricting money restricts the protest.

\- A government restricts the amount of money that can be spent building new religious buildings.  Restricting the amount of money spent on religion restricts freedom of religion.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31478980535.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>I was supporting a much narrower constriction on the amount of money that an individual entity could spend towards a given election campaign, much like the restriction on the amount of money an individual (corporate or real) can donate to a campaign, there should be a limit on the amount of money an individual can spend on media supporting a campaign. 

I don't think your hypotheticals are relevant to that restriction on moneyed speech, and I don't see it as a slippery slope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31478996438.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>To be clear, I am not arguing slippery slope.  I am disputing the idea that spending money on an activity is different from participating in the activity.  Spending money on your church's building fund is participating in your church.  Spending money to buy your favorite newspaper is participating in journalism.  Spending money on protest signs or TV commercials is speech.

Simply setting a limit is incomplete.  Even a non-zero limit can be a meaningful restriction on the exercise of a right.

If a law said "you can go to church, but no more than 30 hours a year" that would restrict religion, right?  If a law said "you can report on stories in your newspaper, but no more than 5,000 words a year" that would restrict press and speech, right?

Setting a nonzero limit is tacitly admitting that a limit would be a restriction, and then trying to find a 'reasonable' level for that limit on the exercise of a right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31479013829.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>If you aren't advocating a slippery slope position, I'm not sure why you keep bring up cases that aren't directly related to political campaigns. 

All I'm suggesting is a limit on the amount of money an individual can spend on campaign ads, or such campaign relevant material.

I wouldn't set it at zero. It should hover around a few mil dependent on the market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31479061508.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>You are saying that money is not speech.  I am using analogies to expose the flaw in your argument.  I am applying your proposed reasoning in other situations to show that spending money is part of the activity. 

Your contention as I understand it is "money is not speech."  The implication is that "spending money on an activity is different from participating in an activity."  I provided a number of examples showing that restrictions on spending money are restrictions on the activity itself.

I am using analogies so we can get away from all the emotional and cultural baggage around elections and campaign finance.  So instead of implicitly thinking "we need this rule to protect democracy from corruption" we can focus on just your argument.  We isolate the argument by moving it outside the context and dropping it into an analogy.

I think by calling it "slippery slope" you accept that all those analogies would represent restrictions on the exercise of a freedom, right?  If you do agree, then in what way is restricting expenditures on political speech different?

&amp;gt; All I'm suggesting is a limit on the amount of money an individual can spend on campaign ads, or such campaign relevant material. 

I think maybe we are getting to a position where you implicitly agree with me that restrictions on spending limit speech, but that you think such limitations are tolerable or justifiable given the good outcomes you expect from the limit.  Is that correct?

If so, then I think you are not directly disputing my point.  My view is that one cannot target business speech without landing on individual speech or press.

Arguing that a restriction on speech is good does not dispute my view that restrictions on business speech will have collateral effects restricting other speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31479094133.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>My position is more that money amplifies the way that speech is received and that limiting that serves our democracy. My position is limited to the way ads and other funding impacts elections. 

&amp;gt; I think maybe we are getting to a position where you implicitly agree with me that restrictions on spending limit speech, but that you think such limitations are tolerable or justifiable given the good outcomes you expect from the limit. Is that correct? 

No. I think that in the limited context of election campaigns this restriction would help prevent those with massive financial interests at stake, from unduly influencing public discourse. 

My point is limited to campaigns, if you are extending past that you are making a slippery slope argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31479201057.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>Once again, I am not making any slippery slope arguments.  I am not sure why you keep thinking that.

&amp;gt;My position is more that money amplifies the way that speech is received and that limiting that serves our democracy.

My argument is not about whether speech restrictions are good.

My argument is that restrictions targeting the speech of for-profit corporations and business speech will bleed over and restrict other speech, like non-profits, and the freedom of the press.

Any argument that speech needs to be restricted for reasons XYZ is not responding to my argument.  I am making a practical argument that it is difficult to actually target this one type of speech without affecting the other types.  I am not arguing whether speech restriction is good; I am arguing whether restricting only business speech is really even possible to achieve.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31479216933.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My argument is that restrictions targeting the speech of for-profit corporations and business speech will bleed over and restrict other speech, like non-profits, and the freedom of the press.

That's the definition of a slippery slope argument. My suggestion is that we limit all legal entities expenditures on campaign ads.  That's easily possible without it trickling down to other versions of political expenditure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31481068674.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>The slippery slope argument follows the format "if we do this one new thing, then eventually worse and worse things in the same direction will follow."

My argument is that, from day one, any rule broad enough to meaningfully restrict business speech will extend to individual speech, nonprofits, or journalists.  No slippery slope; the same rule.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
