<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="650468635.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ar9st7/cmv_there_is_no_law_change_to_citizens_united_v/">
    <title>CMV: There is no law change to Citizens United v FEC that restricts business speech without infringing on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press</title>
    <original_poster>shoesafe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please change my view: any legal or constitutional fix that allows Congress to restrict the political speech of business corporations would also allow restriction on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press.

The Citizens United v. FEC (2010) case is famous in US political debates.  The basic issue is that a non-profit corporation made a movie criticizing a politician right before an election, and that violated US campaign finance law.  The Supreme Court majority opinion said there was a First Amendment right for a corporation (or union) to air political commercials during the period before an election, despite the fact that a small portion of the nonprofit's funding came from for-profit corporations.

Here is how the majority opinion by Kennedy states the problem with the federal law restricting speech:

&amp;gt;The law before us is an outright ban, backed by criminal sanctions. Section 441b makes it a felony for all corporations—including nonprofit advocacy corporations—either to expressly advocate the election or defeat of candidates or to broadcast electioneering communications within 30 days of a primary election and 60 days of a general election. Thus, the following acts would all be felonies under §441b: The Sierra Club runs an ad, within the crucial phase of 60 days before the general election, that exhorts the public to disapprove of a Congressman who favors logging in national forests; the National Rifle Association publishes a book urging the public to vote for the challenger because the incumbent U. S. Senator supports a handgun ban; and the American Civil Liberties Union creates a Web site telling the public to vote for a Presidential candidate in light of that candidate’s defense of free speech. These prohibitions are classic examples of censorship.

My view is that any legal or constitutional fix that allows Congress to enforce 2 USC Section 441b against business corporations would also infringe on individual speech or free press.

I will clarify that I am not talking about infringing the right of people to form a corporation for business purposes and then have that business corporation exercise its speech rights.  Although I think freedom of speech applies to anybody regardless of identity - whether foreign or not, convicted felon or not, facilitated by a business entity or not - I am not making that argument here.   I am making a collateral damage argument: if you try to excise for-profit corporate speech, you will affect a not-insubstantial amount of individual speech or freedom of the press.

I am not asking you to change my philosophical view of free speech, since that is pretty firmly held and I am not terribly open to changing it.  I am asking you to change my view of whether it is legally or conceptually possible to target just the one kind of business corporation speech without attacking individual speech or freedom of the press.  I believe that even terrible policy ideas can be conceptually possible, so I am open to changing my view from "it's not really possible" to "it's possible but still a terrible idea."  But I do not see a clear way to isolate just business corporation speech from individual speech and press.

By "individual speech," I am including the right to form a non-profit corporation or other community group, whether it's a big group like Planned Parenthood or the NRA or a small neighborhood organization.  By "freedom of the press," I am referring both to the right of the people to print expressive materials like books, pamphlets and newsletters generally, and to the right to operate journalistic enterprises specifically, whether meant to be objective or opinionated.

There are many different proposed solutions that are a threat to individual free expression or freedom of the press.

* *Status quo ante*.  We could imagine somehow a change to the Constitution or the Court that allows a do-over and Section 441b is back in force with no other changes.  That directly violates individual free speech because it allows the government, for certain election-related speech, to ban your movie or seize your books or destroy your pamphlets if your nonprofit was funded by even one dollar from a for-profit corporation.  That is incompatible with free speech.  Imagine if a major nonprofit political group, which supports all the things you like, were one day silenced because a single for-profit company, owned by a visionary corporate leader who says all the right things and has all the right political friends and all the right political enemies, made a small contribution of cash or supplies.  I think most of us can see how that would be really restrictive of free speech for all the individuals who contributed to that worthy nonprofit.
* "Money is not speech."  A straight amendment that "money is not speech" would be incredibly broad and would per se threaten individual speech.  In Buckley v. Valeo (1976), the Court said, "*A restriction on the amount of money a person or group can spend on political communication during a campaign necessarily reduces the quantity of expression by restricting the number of issues discussed, the depth of their exploration, and the size of the audience reached*."  If we were to take it outside the realm of speech and say "money is not religion," would anyone dispute that a ban on spending money to publish bibles or build temples is inconsistent with freedom of religion?  If you told people they have the right to protest, but they are not allowed to spend any money on signs or flags or matching t-shirts or even travel expenses to attend the protest, I think most of us can see that would pretty clearly restrict their right to protest.
* "End corporate personhood."  Aside from the chaos this could cause to civil lawsuits and to anybody investing in the stock market, this rule might not stop a non-corporate entity or informal group from publishing an ad.  This really depends on the specifics, but unless you have a "money is not speech" rule, ending corporate personhood really does not do anything directly for speech and so does not itself reverse the outcome of the Citizens United case.  There is no way to enforce Section 441b banning corporate speech if there are no more corporations.  That said, a broad rule here might be so sweeping that it makes it very difficult for groups of citizens to form any kind of community group or issue advocacy group, which would violate the individual's right to create a group to spread their own speech.  Most of these proposals are coupled with a "money is speech" amendment as a shortcut.
* "No speech for any corporations."  This obviously violates individual free speech.  If you start a neighborhood group to protest something like police brutality or pollution or tax policy or zoning policy in your neighborhood, and you want to advertise which candidates agree with you and which ones disagree, then "no speech for any corporations" applies to your little community nonprofit.  It also applies to corporations practicing journalism, so it violates freedom of the press.
* "No speech for for-profit corporations."  This is a common proposal to try to protect political entities and target business entities.  If it lets the government stifle the speech of for-profit corporations, then most news organizations and journalistic outfits could be restricted, imperiling freedom of the press.  It also opens up the possibility of a non-profit created by a for-profit corporation, which allows it to circumvent the rule, meaning that business speech is in practice slightly hampered but not very restricted.
* "No speech for for-profit corporations or non-profits funded by for-profit corporations."  This is fairly similar to the status quo ante (pre 2010) and the same criticism applies. The problem here is that this rule quickly gets broad and endangers lots of individual speech done through nonprofit activist groups.  For example, if your community nonprofit raises money locally to fight an important issue, and it raises some of its money from a few small businesses in the neighborhood, you have now invalidated free speech for the whole group.  The nonprofit is tainted by a little bit of business speech, and all those individuals' speech rights are restricted just so Congress can target the threat of business corporation speech.  This is the twist directly confronted in the Citizens United case and the one that distinguished it from earlier cases.  The twist was that a "small portion" of its funding came from for-profit corporations.  The case FEC v. MCFL (1986) had already found Section 441b invalid as applied to nonprofit corporations, but that holding did not extend to nonprofit corporations that received any money from for-profit corporations.  The Court in 2010 extended protection to Citizens United despite their de minimis for-profit funding.
* "No speech for any corporations except for journalism."  Sometimes people try suggest this modification to the ban on corporate speech but it does not seem to be offered in good faith and includes almost no effort to grapple with the inconsistency of it.  Specifically, the inconsistency of making it illegal for corporations to publish news and opinions about elections, with an exception if that corporation publishes LOTS of news and opinions about elections.  Really, it turns on the definition of journalism or freedom of the press.  But it seems that either this journalism/press exception waters everything down and does not target business speech or it gives Congress the power to ban journalism outfits it disagrees with and abandons freedom of the press.
* "Only natural persons have rights."  This is basically a different way of presenting the "no speech for any corporations" rule but it tries to emphasize that it wants individuals to retain speech rights.  Whatever other problems and consequences of this rule, it never seems like it would work unless your intention is also to stop corporations from funding individual speech.  If corporations lack speech rights but humans have speech rights, then you could circumvent a corporate speech restriction by having the individual filmmaker or author or pamphleteer do the speech activity.  The documentary could be published and disseminated by the documentarian, using funds raised by the corporation and paid over to the filmmaker.  To the extent you block an individual from seeking funding for their own speech, you are restricting their speech rights.  Of course, with crowdfunding mechanisms it is not too difficult to imagine getting around the restriction anyway, by having the corporation promote the cause but all the money skips the corporation and goes from individual to individual.  So either the rule is effective at restricting business speech and it also restricts individual speech, or the rule is ineffective at restricting business speech because other funding mechanisms are able to circumvent your rule.

There are probably other variations but these are the major ones of which I am aware.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31478863958.0" user="TheYOUngeRGOD" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with other commentators that is a high quality post and my response has no ability to match the sheer scope and depth of yours.  

Anyway what would the issue be with a modified status quo anti, where I would agree it’s rough to stop companies that receive an insignificant amount money, but what about those that receive a significant amount.  Would the best compromise be that their is a cutoff on the percentage of money that these non for profits can receive.  I don’t know what the exact cut off is but it would need to be high enough so as to not over prosecute but low enough that the supermajority of funds aren’t coming from these sources. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31478974063.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks.

I thought about including this as an option, but it's really conceptually messy.  The CU majority opinion briefly considers it just to say they do not see any principled argument for setting a low threshold.  Any threshold would be arbitrary.

What is the cutoff? How is it measured? How old does the contribution have to be before the nonprofit gets free speech rights again? What is the impact of a nonprofit's affiliates getting for-profit funding but the nonprofit itself is not receiving any?

The line gets so messy that it is hard to draw in a way that targets business speech but excludes nonprofit/individual speech.  Either your rule is really tough and lots of non-business speech is restrict or the rule is really limited and lots of business speech is basically unrestricted.

You could protect free speech while targeting \*some\* business speech.  But in order to do that, you would have to create rules so gentle that a business corporation could probably find ways to pretty easily step around them and exercise speech if it wanted.

I also think it lands squarely on individual speech:

&amp;gt;For example, if your community nonprofit raises money locally to fight an important issue, and it raises some of its money from a few small businesses in the neighborhood, you have now invalidated free speech for the whole group. The nonprofit is tainted by a little bit of business speech, and all those individuals' speech rights are restricted just so Congress can target the threat of business corporation speech.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
