<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="650468635.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ar9st7/cmv_there_is_no_law_change_to_citizens_united_v/">
    <title>CMV: There is no law change to Citizens United v FEC that restricts business speech without infringing on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press</title>
    <original_poster>shoesafe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please change my view: any legal or constitutional fix that allows Congress to restrict the political speech of business corporations would also allow restriction on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press.

The Citizens United v. FEC (2010) case is famous in US political debates.  The basic issue is that a non-profit corporation made a movie criticizing a politician right before an election, and that violated US campaign finance law.  The Supreme Court majority opinion said there was a First Amendment right for a corporation (or union) to air political commercials during the period before an election, despite the fact that a small portion of the nonprofit's funding came from for-profit corporations.

Here is how the majority opinion by Kennedy states the problem with the federal law restricting speech:

&amp;gt;The law before us is an outright ban, backed by criminal sanctions. Section 441b makes it a felony for all corporations—including nonprofit advocacy corporations—either to expressly advocate the election or defeat of candidates or to broadcast electioneering communications within 30 days of a primary election and 60 days of a general election. Thus, the following acts would all be felonies under §441b: The Sierra Club runs an ad, within the crucial phase of 60 days before the general election, that exhorts the public to disapprove of a Congressman who favors logging in national forests; the National Rifle Association publishes a book urging the public to vote for the challenger because the incumbent U. S. Senator supports a handgun ban; and the American Civil Liberties Union creates a Web site telling the public to vote for a Presidential candidate in light of that candidate’s defense of free speech. These prohibitions are classic examples of censorship.

My view is that any legal or constitutional fix that allows Congress to enforce 2 USC Section 441b against business corporations would also infringe on individual speech or free press.

I will clarify that I am not talking about infringing the right of people to form a corporation for business purposes and then have that business corporation exercise its speech rights.  Although I think freedom of speech applies to anybody regardless of identity - whether foreign or not, convicted felon or not, facilitated by a business entity or not - I am not making that argument here.   I am making a collateral damage argument: if you try to excise for-profit corporate speech, you will affect a not-insubstantial amount of individual speech or freedom of the press.

I am not asking you to change my philosophical view of free speech, since that is pretty firmly held and I am not terribly open to changing it.  I am asking you to change my view of whether it is legally or conceptually possible to target just the one kind of business corporation speech without attacking individual speech or freedom of the press.  I believe that even terrible policy ideas can be conceptually possible, so I am open to changing my view from "it's not really possible" to "it's possible but still a terrible idea."  But I do not see a clear way to isolate just business corporation speech from individual speech and press.

By "individual speech," I am including the right to form a non-profit corporation or other community group, whether it's a big group like Planned Parenthood or the NRA or a small neighborhood organization.  By "freedom of the press," I am referring both to the right of the people to print expressive materials like books, pamphlets and newsletters generally, and to the right to operate journalistic enterprises specifically, whether meant to be objective or opinionated.

There are many different proposed solutions that are a threat to individual free expression or freedom of the press.

* *Status quo ante*.  We could imagine somehow a change to the Constitution or the Court that allows a do-over and Section 441b is back in force with no other changes.  That directly violates individual free speech because it allows the government, for certain election-related speech, to ban your movie or seize your books or destroy your pamphlets if your nonprofit was funded by even one dollar from a for-profit corporation.  That is incompatible with free speech.  Imagine if a major nonprofit political group, which supports all the things you like, were one day silenced because a single for-profit company, owned by a visionary corporate leader who says all the right things and has all the right political friends and all the right political enemies, made a small contribution of cash or supplies.  I think most of us can see how that would be really restrictive of free speech for all the individuals who contributed to that worthy nonprofit.
* "Money is not speech."  A straight amendment that "money is not speech" would be incredibly broad and would per se threaten individual speech.  In Buckley v. Valeo (1976), the Court said, "*A restriction on the amount of money a person or group can spend on political communication during a campaign necessarily reduces the quantity of expression by restricting the number of issues discussed, the depth of their exploration, and the size of the audience reached*."  If we were to take it outside the realm of speech and say "money is not religion," would anyone dispute that a ban on spending money to publish bibles or build temples is inconsistent with freedom of religion?  If you told people they have the right to protest, but they are not allowed to spend any money on signs or flags or matching t-shirts or even travel expenses to attend the protest, I think most of us can see that would pretty clearly restrict their right to protest.
* "End corporate personhood."  Aside from the chaos this could cause to civil lawsuits and to anybody investing in the stock market, this rule might not stop a non-corporate entity or informal group from publishing an ad.  This really depends on the specifics, but unless you have a "money is not speech" rule, ending corporate personhood really does not do anything directly for speech and so does not itself reverse the outcome of the Citizens United case.  There is no way to enforce Section 441b banning corporate speech if there are no more corporations.  That said, a broad rule here might be so sweeping that it makes it very difficult for groups of citizens to form any kind of community group or issue advocacy group, which would violate the individual's right to create a group to spread their own speech.  Most of these proposals are coupled with a "money is speech" amendment as a shortcut.
* "No speech for any corporations."  This obviously violates individual free speech.  If you start a neighborhood group to protest something like police brutality or pollution or tax policy or zoning policy in your neighborhood, and you want to advertise which candidates agree with you and which ones disagree, then "no speech for any corporations" applies to your little community nonprofit.  It also applies to corporations practicing journalism, so it violates freedom of the press.
* "No speech for for-profit corporations."  This is a common proposal to try to protect political entities and target business entities.  If it lets the government stifle the speech of for-profit corporations, then most news organizations and journalistic outfits could be restricted, imperiling freedom of the press.  It also opens up the possibility of a non-profit created by a for-profit corporation, which allows it to circumvent the rule, meaning that business speech is in practice slightly hampered but not very restricted.
* "No speech for for-profit corporations or non-profits funded by for-profit corporations."  This is fairly similar to the status quo ante (pre 2010) and the same criticism applies. The problem here is that this rule quickly gets broad and endangers lots of individual speech done through nonprofit activist groups.  For example, if your community nonprofit raises money locally to fight an important issue, and it raises some of its money from a few small businesses in the neighborhood, you have now invalidated free speech for the whole group.  The nonprofit is tainted by a little bit of business speech, and all those individuals' speech rights are restricted just so Congress can target the threat of business corporation speech.  This is the twist directly confronted in the Citizens United case and the one that distinguished it from earlier cases.  The twist was that a "small portion" of its funding came from for-profit corporations.  The case FEC v. MCFL (1986) had already found Section 441b invalid as applied to nonprofit corporations, but that holding did not extend to nonprofit corporations that received any money from for-profit corporations.  The Court in 2010 extended protection to Citizens United despite their de minimis for-profit funding.
* "No speech for any corporations except for journalism."  Sometimes people try suggest this modification to the ban on corporate speech but it does not seem to be offered in good faith and includes almost no effort to grapple with the inconsistency of it.  Specifically, the inconsistency of making it illegal for corporations to publish news and opinions about elections, with an exception if that corporation publishes LOTS of news and opinions about elections.  Really, it turns on the definition of journalism or freedom of the press.  But it seems that either this journalism/press exception waters everything down and does not target business speech or it gives Congress the power to ban journalism outfits it disagrees with and abandons freedom of the press.
* "Only natural persons have rights."  This is basically a different way of presenting the "no speech for any corporations" rule but it tries to emphasize that it wants individuals to retain speech rights.  Whatever other problems and consequences of this rule, it never seems like it would work unless your intention is also to stop corporations from funding individual speech.  If corporations lack speech rights but humans have speech rights, then you could circumvent a corporate speech restriction by having the individual filmmaker or author or pamphleteer do the speech activity.  The documentary could be published and disseminated by the documentarian, using funds raised by the corporation and paid over to the filmmaker.  To the extent you block an individual from seeking funding for their own speech, you are restricting their speech rights.  Of course, with crowdfunding mechanisms it is not too difficult to imagine getting around the restriction anyway, by having the corporation promote the cause but all the money skips the corporation and goes from individual to individual.  So either the rule is effective at restricting business speech and it also restricts individual speech, or the rule is ineffective at restricting business speech because other funding mechanisms are able to circumvent your rule.

There are probably other variations but these are the major ones of which I am aware.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31480641921.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>I am coming a bit late to this but I want to come at it from a somewhat different angle: there is an anti-bribery case to be made for restricting large sums of money being spent in a manner which directly benefits particular public officials.

For example, let's say you have a businessman who wants a particular regulation changed.  If he offers a member of Congress a million dollars in cash if they vote to change the regulation, that's clearly criminal bribery.  If he offers that a SuperPAC under his control will run a million dollars of ads to support the member of Congress if they vote to change the regulation, that should also be criminal bribery.

The limiting principle is that the spending has to accrue to the particular benefit of a particular public official.  Ads which support or oppose the election of a particular official or candidate should be treated the same as giving cash money to that public official or candidate.  It accrues to their benefit in either case.  "Issue" ads or the like would not fall in this framework because they don't directly benefit an identifiable public official or candidate to become a public official.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31481262130.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, I have a few responses.

First, to the extent you are talking about explicit quid pro quo, that is already illegal without any change to Citizens United and related caselaw.  So that would militate against the folks who think overturning CU is critical to defending democracy.

Second, this is not really about business speech.  A nonprofit can also engage in explicit quid pro quo for ideological reasons rather than business reasons, right?  This would not touch on most political speech by businesses.  You are really just talking about political speech generally.

Third, you are getting overbroad when you say this part:

&amp;gt;Ads which support or oppose the election of a particular official or candidate should be treated the same as giving cash money to that public official or candidate. It accrues to their benefit in either case.

If helping to get a politician elected or reelected is bribery, is voting for a candidate also bribery?  Or canvassing, volunteering, advocating?  What about when a newspaper editorial endorses a candidate?

The nature of electoral democracy is lots of people trying to get somebody elected.  Many of them believe things and some people organize around those beliefs.  They try to elect people with similar beliefs.  I think it really ruins democracy if it becomes bribery to do things to elect people.

Fourth, regarding restrictions like this:

&amp;gt;"Issue" ads or the like would not fall in this framework because they don't directly benefit an identifiable public official or candidate to become a public official.

This would limit the ability of individuals to say true things about a candidate, namely a candidate's position on an issue, which is definitely a restriction on individual speech.  You might think it's a good or useful restriction, but my view in this thread is not whether speech restrictions are good.  I am challenging anyone to change my view that restrictions on business speech cannot be achieved without restrictions on individual speech or journalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31481538005.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>First, yes obviously a nonprofit can engage in bribery, like any other person or entity could.  Though we regulate the conduct of 501(c)(3) nonprofits pretty heavily as a condition of donations to them being tax deductible and disallow them engaging in political activities because they're not charitable activities.

I was just using a businessperson wanting a regulation changed as an example of someone who might pay a bribe.

Second, as to the idea that explicit quid-pro-quo for PAC spending is currently treated as bribery, it is not.

For example, [there is a PAC who raised $1.1 million dollars](https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/12/17850180/susan-collins-crowdpac-kavanaugh-bribe-newsmax) to donate to a challenger to Sen. Susan Collins and who made the donation explicitly connected to and conditional on whether or not she voted to confirm Brett Kavanaugh to the Supreme Court.  That was given a FEC opinion that it is not bribery.

People can and routinely do tie PAC spending explicitly to official acts in ways that we should, but do not, treat as a bribe.

Third, bribery requires a transfer of a thing of value.  On the list of things you provide, several of them (including voting) are obviously not things of monetary value.  It seems straightforward enough to say in a statute that things that don't have monetary value can't be bribes.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;"Issue" ads or the like would not fall in this framework because they don't directly benefit an identifiable public official or candidate to become a public official.

&amp;gt;This would limit the ability of individuals to say true things about a candidate, namely a candidate's position on an issue, which is definitely a restriction on individual speech. You might think it's a good or useful restriction, but my view in this thread is not whether speech restrictions are good. I am challenging anyone to change my view that restrictions on business speech cannot be achieved without restrictions on individual speech or journalism.

Again, the bribery case only comes up when someone is paying money or giving a thing of monetary value.  Paid advertising spaces are a thing of monetary value.  We know that because you can only get them by paying for them.  Canvassing, volunteering, advocating, and newspaper editorials are not paid for, and therefore not things of value for bribery law purposes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31487075268.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>So this does not seem like you are tackling my prompt, which was about targeting business speech while protecting other speech.  This seems like you are talking about your other opinions on campaign finance.

I think you are making some interesting points, which because of my own philosophical priors I do not exactly agree or disagree.  Some of the things you say I factually disagree with, others I agree with.  But none of it is really challenging my question, which was more a pragmatic concern about whether it is possibly to cleanly separate business speech.

So would you agree with me and my original post that it is not practicable to censor business speech while protecting other speech?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31487359942.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Your original prompt was about _Citizens United v. FEC._  The regulation at issue in _Citizens United_ was one which specified that paid electioneering communications (those which advocated for the election or defeat of particular candidates) are distinct from other communications and subject to FEC regulation and limitations on spending.  I am arguing that the electioneering communications vs other communications framework is a sensible one from an antibribery standpoint, and that there is a compelling government interest in preventing bribery of government officials.

The distinction never made a difference if it was a natural person or a corporation that undertook the speech.  _Citizens United v. FEC_ had to deal with that as a threshold question because the corporation Citizens United is a corporation, but even holding that Citizens United the corporation to have valid first amendment interests, you could then think that on the merits they should have lost (or won on very narrow grounds that their communications weren't electioneering communications as a question of fact).  

For an example of what such a ruling would look like, I'd point you to the [District Court decision in _Citizens United v. FEC_](https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=2887803236861980893&amp;amp;q=citizens+united+v+federal+election+com%27n&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=3,33) which held against Citizens United could not object to e.g. the disclosure provisions that applied to spending on electioneering communications even assuming it had a valid first amendment claim.

It's worth noting that **the law never banned private electioneering communications.**  The speech in question in _Citizens United v. FEC_ wasn't banned.  It was subject to regulation requiring disclosure of donors and other things.  Given the relatively limited regulations, and the strong government interest in preventing bribery (which is mitigated by disclosure requirements that prevent large shadowy payments) and the government interest in preventing foreign spending in US elections (which is not lawful), I think the court was wrong that, even given that Citizens United had a valid first amendment interest in their speech, that the regulations it was subject to were not lawful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31489707444.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>I still do not see how this addresses my point in the prompt, which is also the title.  This seems more like your own take on CU.

There is a common argument that there is some variant akin to "business speech" which can be suppressed without any harm to other speech or press.  The bribery argument does not seem to address that point, does it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31489764985.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>It's also the district court ruling's take on CU, so it seems like an important take.  My point is that given the strong antibribery interests of the government, CU could be overturned without infringing on the free speech rights of individuals or corporate entities, because the pre-CU state of the law was a justified limitation on payments which benefit elected officials and candidates.

You could make a drastic change to CU by totally overturning it, and requiring disclosure of both individuals and corporate entities engaging in electioneering activities without infringing on the individual right to free speech or the freedom of the press.  That's I think a pretty important counterpoint to your thesis statement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31489806135.0" user="shoesafe" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but you are fighting the prompt and not trying to change my view about whether it is possible to divide the types of speech.

I tried to come up with a specific argument which is relevant to the larger debate, but on which I am willing to have my mind changed.

I am an anarchist.  I am very unlikely to ever accept the argument that the government needs to hire police to censor people for saying true things about politics.  So I did not ask people to change my view about Citizens United overall, or about censorship or political speech or campaign finance.  I did not ask people to convince me that government is good or police are trustworthy or politicians can be trusted to implement such a censorship regime honorably.  It would be disingenuous to pretend I would be likely to change my mind on those things.

But I do have a pragmatic criticism of the folks who think that they can "fix" the issue by giving Congress the power to silence businesses while still prohibiting Congress from silencing the other forms of speech.  It's an important question because it animates so many left-leaning Americans who imagine there is a way to cleanly attack business speech while leaving non-profit speech and journalism unscathed.

I am willing to have my view changed on that.  I am very unlikely to think it would be a good idea to restrict such speech, but I am willing to believe it's possible.  Lots of terrible ideas and dumb ideas and bad ideas and silly ideas are possible.  I just happen to think that this bad idea is not really even possible, at least not in the way so many people talk about it.

The people endorsing this silly idea include lots of prominent Senators and other politicians.  So the question of whether it is even realistic is a live issue.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
