<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="653955908.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atcjlw/cmv_equastrian_sports_should_not_be_part_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Equastrian sports should not be part of the Olympics.</title>
    <original_poster>LarryAndBarry</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Olympics in my opinion, is to challenge the boundaries of a humans physical abilities and see who is the best of the best. Its amazing what the human body is capable of when pushed to it limits.

I understand the same level of commitment goes into being a horse rider, but I feel as though equastrian sports is more a test for the horses. In theory, a javelin thrower can use any type of javelin but still throw a winning shot, but a rider can't really do the same with which horse he/she will use, therefore relying heavily on the horses ability to perform as well as their own. In the same vein, why not include the traditional horse racing with jockeys into the Olympics. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31503325126.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Why does relying on an animal teammate diminish an athlete’s performance, but relying on a human teammate doesn’t? A relay race relies on the performance of multiple participants to determine overall ranking, but we don’t say that it shouldn’t be in the Olympics. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503432041.0" user="LarryAndBarry" delta="False">
    <text>Relying on a bicycle doesn't doesnt diminish a cyclists performance. But as I said before - if an equestrians horse passes away a week before their event - are the horse riders odds of winning unaffected? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503447986.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>I compared living creatures for a reason. If a relay team-member dies the week before their race, are the team’s odds of winning unaffected? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503501607.0" user="LarryAndBarry" delta="False">
    <text>Yes,a teams odds of winning a race are of course affected its core members dies, but a back up runner can step in and they can still win. A horse rider with a 2nd rate horse - yes they can still win but the odds are lower which makes me reason if an equestrian relies on the health and fitness of the horse, do they fit the perception of the  Olympics being a test for human abilities</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503523083.0" user="devils_ivy1" delta="False">
    <text>The Olympics are an international sports competition. The definition of a sport is an activity involving physical exertion and skill in which an individual or team competes against another or others for entertainment. By this definition horse competitions are perfectly acceptable in the Olympics</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503547442.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	Yes,a teams odds of winning a race are of course affected its core members dies, but a back up runner can step in and they can still win. A horse rider with a 2nd rate horse - yes they can still win but the odds are lower

Are you arguing that a team’s odds of winning aren’t lower if they’re using a backup runner than if they’re using one of their A-list runners? 

&amp;gt;	do they fit the perception of the Olympics being a test for human abilities

Nowhere in the [Olympic Charter](https://stillmed.olympic.org/media/Document%20Library/OlympicOrg/General/EN-Olympic-Charter.pdf#_ga=2.100809537.1555419405.1550811867-144412069.1550811867) does the IOC describe the Olympic Games as a “test for human abilities.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503461164.0" user="devils_ivy1" delta="False">
    <text>Of course they're affected. They are affected in the same way that a pair of figure skaters is when one of them dies. Riding horses is a partnership that you work tirelessly to perfect same as with any human partnership. I'm sure it's not easy to find a human partner that you are compatible enough with to complete at an Olympic level. While someone of a high calibre could certainly get on many horses and ride well it still takes time to make a team and a horse fit and talented enough for the Olympics is just as rare as any human</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
