<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="653955908.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atcjlw/cmv_equastrian_sports_should_not_be_part_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Equastrian sports should not be part of the Olympics.</title>
    <original_poster>LarryAndBarry</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Olympics in my opinion, is to challenge the boundaries of a humans physical abilities and see who is the best of the best. Its amazing what the human body is capable of when pushed to it limits.

I understand the same level of commitment goes into being a horse rider, but I feel as though equastrian sports is more a test for the horses. In theory, a javelin thrower can use any type of javelin but still throw a winning shot, but a rider can't really do the same with which horse he/she will use, therefore relying heavily on the horses ability to perform as well as their own. In the same vein, why not include the traditional horse racing with jockeys into the Olympics. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31503331949.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>If you go on the Olympic Website you will see that swimming isn't one category. It's two. There's Swimming that measures the fastest, strongest, and most precise swimmers. Then there's *Artistic* Swimming which is a judged event based on presentation. There's a similar split between Gymnastics and Artistic Gymnastics.

This really challenges the view that the Olympics are about challenging physical abilities alone given that there are multiple categories of events judged on presentation and artistry alone, does it not?

And, I don't see how horse racing would differ materially from cycling, sailing, canoeing, bobsleigh, short track skating, or any number of other races. It was in the ancient games, and "driving" a variation of horse racing involving a little cart was an Olympic sport for some time but was dropped when it was clear that too few nations were participating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503376966.0" user="LarryAndBarry" delta="False">
    <text>In both swimming and competitive swimming, team and individual, its still the athletes abilities being tested to whatever standards set out by that sport.

Cycling, canoeing and all other sports that use equipment cannot really be compared to a horse though. If a cyclist breaks his bike he goes and gets a new one and his chance at gold is not affected. An equestrians horse passes away the week before his event, does he still fly a new horse in and have the same chances of gold? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503437258.0" user="radialomens" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; An equestrians horse passes away the week before his event, does he still fly a new horse in and have the same chances of gold?

I would say rather than just being a piece of equipment, the horse is more like the competitor's body which they have conditioned and honed.

Not every human has the same capabilities. In swimming, for instance, there are body shapes that have a big advantage over others. But even if your body isn't *perfect*, you work with what you have. You spend years conditioning so that your muscles can perform at their best. You can work past or with whatever natural disadvantage you can't control.

The horse has natural limitations just like the person's body. But they train that horse just like athletes train themselves.

And some people have bodies where they will just *never* win gold in this sport or that. Thankfully with a horse you can buy a new horse. You cannot force your body to be more hydrodynamic or have longer legs or whatever.

So if the horse dies, it's like breaking your leg. It sucks and you do lose your chance. But it's not unfair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503439088.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>And in various horse events the person is still being tested on their teamwork with their horse. I think that you're drawing a distinction without a difference here.

If a cyclist breaks his bike then learning the foibles of a new bike absolutely changes the odds, granted not to the same extent but bikes are not all identical and each one is often custom designed for the rider.

Additionally, [artistic swimming looks nothing like competitive swimming](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WWb-8itI2AA).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31504299449.0" user="jennysequa" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; An equestrians horse passes away the week before his event, does he still fly a new horse in and have the same chances of gold?

What about the opposite? Are you arguing that you could just jump on a horse trained for Olympic equestrian events and win gold?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503399660.0" user="TheArmchairSkeptic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't see how horse racing would differ materially from cycling, sailing, canoeing, bobsleigh, short track skating, or any number of other races.

I'm not sure quite where I fall on the OP, but with regards to this particular point I would say that there is a very material difference there in that, in all the other examples you gave, the force generating the forward motion is coming from a human body and not a horse.

With regards to the artistic vs technical distinction, I think a case can still be be made for excluding equestrian on the grounds that even in the artistic events, it's still down to purely human strength and form. But then, equestrian certainly has an important physical element for the riders as well, and that's why the line is unclear to me. I think I'm leading towards it being excluded on the basis that Olympics should be restricted to human competitors only, but I'd be curious to hear arguments against that idea.

EDIT: Also I don't think they do races in the Olympics; I think it's mainly just like, the prancing events.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503426945.0" user="devils_ivy1" delta="False">
    <text>Olympic equestrian competitions include dressage, cross country and show jumping </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503446722.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>The once did do "driving", but they haven't since 1968.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31504160941.0" user="jawrsh21" delta="False">
    <text>i think about the horse as a teammate rather than a piece of equipment. Should beach volleyball or doubles tennis be in the olympics?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
