<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="653955908.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atcjlw/cmv_equastrian_sports_should_not_be_part_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Equastrian sports should not be part of the Olympics.</title>
    <original_poster>LarryAndBarry</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Olympics in my opinion, is to challenge the boundaries of a humans physical abilities and see who is the best of the best. Its amazing what the human body is capable of when pushed to it limits.

I understand the same level of commitment goes into being a horse rider, but I feel as though equastrian sports is more a test for the horses. In theory, a javelin thrower can use any type of javelin but still throw a winning shot, but a rider can't really do the same with which horse he/she will use, therefore relying heavily on the horses ability to perform as well as their own. In the same vein, why not include the traditional horse racing with jockeys into the Olympics. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31503321394.0" user="AseRayAes" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the removal of equestrian sports in the Olympics will make the Olympics better, or just that the removal is more accurate to your perception of what the Olympics should be?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503437938.0" user="LarryAndBarry" delta="False">
    <text>This is probably it - the perception of what the Olympics should be. Equastrian sports just doesn't fit the bill for me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503453744.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>What is your opinion of the target shooting then? There are several events that involve rifle shooting or archery. Why should using these devices be in but training and using a horse should not? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503592113.0" user="scgtrp" delta="False">
    <text>Do competitors in those bring their own bow/rifle, or is there a standard kind of bow/rifle everyone uses? If the latter, I'd say that's different, since what you're competing on is still entirely your own skill, and not whether you have a better bow/rifle/horse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503606239.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>They bring their own stuff. They have to meet certain standards, but there can be a significant amount of variation. 

You just seem to lack an understanding of how physical riding a horse actually is. And the riding competition is also judging their training skills. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
