<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="653955908.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atcjlw/cmv_equastrian_sports_should_not_be_part_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Equastrian sports should not be part of the Olympics.</title>
    <original_poster>LarryAndBarry</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Olympics in my opinion, is to challenge the boundaries of a humans physical abilities and see who is the best of the best. Its amazing what the human body is capable of when pushed to it limits.

I understand the same level of commitment goes into being a horse rider, but I feel as though equastrian sports is more a test for the horses. In theory, a javelin thrower can use any type of javelin but still throw a winning shot, but a rider can't really do the same with which horse he/she will use, therefore relying heavily on the horses ability to perform as well as their own. In the same vein, why not include the traditional horse racing with jockeys into the Olympics. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31503305267.0" user="Armadeo" delta="False">
    <text>I would think that finding and training a horse is far better achievement than throwing a pre-made javelin as far as you can. 

I think your classification of the Olympics being a challenge to the boundaries of the physical only is missing key strategic and mental feats as well. 

The Olympics is really just about sport and the sport's eligibility is governed by the IOC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503413049.0" user="LarryAndBarry" delta="False">
    <text>I say physical abilities because ofcourse in sports, a level of strategy and mental focus/ability come into play. Otherwise, Chess could be an Olympic sport (id watch that!). 

Throwing a pre-made javelin is still SOMEONE training their body and investing the time and energy to throw the javelin the furthest than anyone else in the world so to speak. By your logic, I can go out and find a dog to train to do a ropes course, so can that be an Olympic sport?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31503626413.0" user="masterzora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Otherwise, Chess could be an Olympic sport (id watch that!).

It would have been included starting with the 1924 games if they were sufficiently able to distinguish amateur and professional players.  There's a push to add chess to the 2024 games though, in fairness, a similar push to add them to the 2020 games failed. Chess *is* recognised as a sport by the IOC, however, and there's nothing categorically preventing its inclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
