<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="654650438.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atrfie/cmv_the_no_one_is_illegal_response_is_unjustified/">
    <title>CMV: The "no one is illegal" response is unjustified virtue signaling and the term "undocumented immigrant" is misleading.</title>
    <original_poster>snogo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand that there are sensitivities that need to be taken when referring to people who built their entire lives around an illegal act, but nobody cares when we characterize other people as "illegal" due to other illegal acts.

If I illegally dump toxic waste in the local river, I may very well be referred to as an illegal dumper. If I illegally sell cigarettes in the park, I may very well be referred to as an illegal seller. If I illegally grow marijuana in a legal state where a distinction is necessary, I may very well be referred to as an illegal grower.

The only time referring to someone as an "illegal X" gets people riled up is when you are referring to people who immigrated illegally.

This leads to whitewashed terms like "undocumented immigrant" which sounds like there was no illegal act performed. The term "undocumented immigrant" sounds to the uninformed observer like someone who is just like any other legal immigrant but whose immigration was undocumented due to a mishap in paperwork.

It wasn't simply an "undocumented immigration", it was an unauthorized, or illegal immigration.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31508048944.0" user="mrgoodnighthairdo" delta="False">
    <text>Simply being in the country without the proper authorization is not a criminal offense. It is a civil offense. As a significant portion of these people did not cross the border without permission, it is more accurate to refer to as undocumented. Calling them illegal immigrants presumes they have entered the country illegally, which many to most have not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508093357.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Violating civil law is still doing something that is illegal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508111223.0" user="mrgoodnighthairdo" delta="False">
    <text>No, it is not illegal. It is a civil infraction. Overstaying a visa is not a crime. If it is not a crime, then it is not illegal. Unlawful entry is a crime. Unlawful presence is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508733161.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Being illegal means violating a law. Any law. It does not matter if it is in the criminal or civil category. 

For example speeding is a civil offense, yet is still referred to as being illegal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508127223.0" user="snogo" delta="False">
    <text>Please see my response to /u/ColdNotion</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508139680.0" user="mrgoodnighthairdo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are an illegal immigrant because you immigrated illegally, not just because you are staying here illegally.

As it has already been stated in this post and in the link provided by another commenter, a significant number of undocumented immigrants did *not* enter the country illegally. Therefore, they did not commit a crime. To refer to them as illegal immigrants presumes that they have committed a crime. It likely also *presumes* that they entered the country illegally.

Beyond that... what you are saying is that you believe it's fine to use the colloquial "illegal" to refer to these people, a word which presumes their criminality, rather than the more accurate "undocumented" which describes their current status as being in country without authorization without presuming any criminal acts on their part... correct? Is that what you are saying?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508155242.0" user="snogo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a significant number of undocumented immigrants did not enter the country illegally

Even then, just because an act does not carry a criminal penalty does not mean that it is not, in fact, illegal. If I stay in a hotel room for an extra week without paying, I am staying there illegally even if the only penalty may be getting kicked out of the hotel. 

&amp;gt; Beyond that you are saying is that you believe it's fine to use the colloquial "illegal" to refer to these people, which presumes they are criminals, rather than the more accurate "undocumented" 

As stated above, something being illegal does not mean that it has to carry a criminal penalty. If I smoke marijuana in a state where it is decriminalized but still illegal, I am still committing an illegal act and I am an illegal marijuana smoker. 

Personally, I think that the term unauthorized immigrant would be a more accurate/proper term and be less likely to be misused by bigots but that is independent from my argument and I still think that the term undocumented immigrant is misleading at best and a form of whitewashing or deliberate softening/ambiguating of language for a political agenda at worst. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
