<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="654650438.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atrfie/cmv_the_no_one_is_illegal_response_is_unjustified/">
    <title>CMV: The "no one is illegal" response is unjustified virtue signaling and the term "undocumented immigrant" is misleading.</title>
    <original_poster>snogo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand that there are sensitivities that need to be taken when referring to people who built their entire lives around an illegal act, but nobody cares when we characterize other people as "illegal" due to other illegal acts.

If I illegally dump toxic waste in the local river, I may very well be referred to as an illegal dumper. If I illegally sell cigarettes in the park, I may very well be referred to as an illegal seller. If I illegally grow marijuana in a legal state where a distinction is necessary, I may very well be referred to as an illegal grower.

The only time referring to someone as an "illegal X" gets people riled up is when you are referring to people who immigrated illegally.

This leads to whitewashed terms like "undocumented immigrant" which sounds like there was no illegal act performed. The term "undocumented immigrant" sounds to the uninformed observer like someone who is just like any other legal immigrant but whose immigration was undocumented due to a mishap in paperwork.

It wasn't simply an "undocumented immigration", it was an unauthorized, or illegal immigration.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31508050710.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>I would love to take a shot at changing your view here, as someone who does use the term "undocumented immigrant". Now on the one hand, I can understand where you're coming from in worrying that using this language is an attempt to whitewash a potential problem. However, I feel that isn't the case for two significant reasons. I feel that using "undocumented" is more appropriate both on a legal basis and on a moral one, so I would like to help you understand how I see the matter.

Firstly, looking to current immigration law, there's actually a very strong legal reason to use the term "undocumented". As it turns out, the mere act of being in the US without a legal visa or permanent residency [is not a crime, but merely a civil violation](https://www.politifact.com/florida/statements/2017/mar/15/florida-conference-catholic-bishops/being-united-states-unlawfully-crime/). This is hugely important, as [a significant majority of undocumented people enter the US by overstaying legitimate visas](https://www.npr.org/2019/01/10/683662691/where-does-illegal-immigration-mostly-occur-heres-what-the-data-tell-us), not by committing the crime of crossing the border illicitly. As such, calling most undocumented immigrants "illegal" is simply factually incorrect in the eyes of the law. The term "undocumented" is preferable for these folks because it better describes the civil, but not criminal, code that their continued presence is violating.

Secondly, I think there's also a pretty good moral argument to be made for using the term undocumented, although I admit this is a bit more subjective. As a society, we tend to be a lot more forgiving of folks who commit criminal acts because issues with society leave them with few other choices. This is why many of us might not call a father who stole to feed his children a thief, even though he did commit a crime by stealing. Similarly, the majority of undocumented migrants who do commit the crime of crossing the border illegally do so because societal pressures, not selfishness, are driving them to do so. For migrants fleeing from violence or desperately trying to escape poverty, their actions may constitute a crime, but it's excessively harsh to view them first and foremost as criminals. That isn't to say they should be given a pass, or that current immigration law should be ignored, but the use of "undocumented" over "illegal" helps to better recognize the forces driving non-legal migration, thus leaving us with more sympathy and potentially a better understanding of how to solve this situation.

Anyhow, I hope this has helped to shift your perspective a bit! Feel free to reach out with questions, as I'm always happy to chat more. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508090698.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>It is also illegal to overstay a visa. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508121230.0" user="snogo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Firstly, looking to current immigration law, there's actually a very strong legal reason to use the term "undocumented". As it turns out, the mere act of being in the US without a legal visa or permanent residency is not a crime, but merely a civil violation

I think that it is unlikely that either of us are qualified to argue such intricate legal matters but even your source seems to contradict that assertion in many (or most) cases:
&amp;gt; &amp;gt;For instance, an undocumented immigrant who entered the United States improperly would have committed a crime. However, once that person is here, the simple act of being in the United States unlawfully is not by itself a crime.  

I would say that this is analogous to saying that growing marijuana is a crime but smoking it once you already grew it is a civil infraction. You are still an illegal marijuana grower even if you already completed the illegal act. 

You are an illegal immigrant because you immigrated illegally, not just because you are staying here illegally. 

Something being illegal does not even mean that it has to carry a criminal penalty. If I smoke marijuana in a state where it is decriminalized but still illegal, I am still committing an illegal act and I am an illegal marijuana smoker.

I also think that this is a very weak argument because it relies entirely on loose semantics. Generally, people distinguish between a criminal and civil crime because a criminal offence is generally against the government or society and a civil offense is against a private party and can be remedied through the repayment of damages. 

Even then, if a wall street banker was sued by the SEC in civil court due to violations of the law, I think that most people would consider him/her to be a criminal or at least to have committed a criminal act. Moreso, even for purely civil infractions (like internet piracy), a person who downloads illegal content can be referred to as an illegal downloader. 

 
&amp;gt; Similarly, the majority of undocumented migrants who do commit the crime of crossing the border illegally do so because societal pressures, not selfishness, are driving them to do so. For migrants fleeing from violence or desperately trying to escape poverty, their actions may constitute a crime    

So in that case, you would support referring to all rich Canadian/Mexicans with comfortable lives back home who crossed the border illegally as an illegal immigrant while calling all impoverished or desperate immigrants undocumented immigrants? If not, what if the split between those demographics for all illegal immigrants was 50/50? 80/20?   

I agree that in individual cases you may want to use a term other than "illegal immigrant" just like in special cases you may not call someone a thief for stealing but when you are referring to people in aggregate, this doesn't hold water IMO. Also, I don't think that even in those special cases, "unauthorized immigrant" would be a term that is too harsh or insensitive. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31515214600.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>First off, my apologies for being slow in getting back to you. It's been an unexpectedly busy weekend, but I'm glad to finally have the chance to reply. To make this easy, I'm going to try to respond to each part of your comment. 

&amp;gt; I think that it is unlikely that either of us are qualified to argue such intricate legal matters but even your source seems to contradict that assertion in many (or most) cases:

To be frank, I disagree with this line of thinking. Using sources to try to reinforce a position is pretty good practice in my view, and while we're not legal experts, that doesn't mean we can't try to learn. Moreover, I think this source pretty clearly backed up what I was saying, insofar as that merely being in the US without documentation is not a crime. As far as I can tell, the source I linked substantiated that fairly clearly, showing the distinction between entering the country illicitly, which is a crime, and merely being here without permission, which is not illegal.

&amp;gt; I would say that this is analogous to saying that growing marijuana is a crime but smoking it once you already grew it is a civil infraction. You are still an illegal marijuana grower even if you already completed the illegal act.

To use your analogy, I would say that the majority of undocumented migrants are smokers, but only a minority grow their own marijuana. For the majority of these migrants, they've entered the country through legal means (i.e. they're not the ones growing weed), and their subsequent decision to stay after they're supposed to return home is not a crime in itself. 

&amp;gt; You are an illegal immigrant because you immigrated illegally, not just because you are staying here illegally.

This is in large part the point I was trying to make. The vast majority of people who are branded "illegal immigrants" actually did not immigrate into the US illegally. Simply put, this descriptor is improper because their method of entry was not illegal. Instead, when trying to describe people living in the US without permission, including both people who entered legally and illegally, the term "undocumented immigrant" is a much more accurate general phrase. 

&amp;gt; I also think that this is a very weak argument because it relies entirely on loose semantics. Generally, people distinguish between a criminal and civil crime because a criminal offence is generally against the government or society and a civil offense is against a private party and can be remedied through the repayment of damages.

&amp;gt; Something being illegal does not even mean that it has to carry a criminal penalty. If I smoke marijuana in a state where it is decriminalized but still illegal, I am still committing an illegal act and I am an illegal marijuana smoker.

While not all illegal acts carry a criminal penalty, this isn't really relevant here. Staying in the country without documentation isn't an unpunished criminal act, it's purely a civil violation. I know this distinction might seem a little insignificant, and more on that in a second, but it's actually pretty important when it comes to considering how we deal with immigration. For example, were it a criminal violation, every single migrant being deported would be entitled to a formal court case and public defender, which would be a huge expense. 

&amp;gt; I also think that this is a very weak argument because it relies entirely on loose semantics. Generally, people distinguish between a criminal and civil crime because a criminal offence is generally against the government or society and a civil offense is against a private party and can be remedied through the repayment of damages.

This is more than just a semantic issue. The way we treat people in the criminal and civil court systems are very different, as are the ramifications of violating either form of the law. Civil law is intentionally distinguished in order to create rules which help to govern society, but can't be used to deprive people of their rights as punishment if violated. Given that folks probably don't want jail time for parking violations, this separation is massively important where the law is concerned, even if it's a distinction we don't acknowledge as much in popular discourse. 

&amp;gt; Even then, if a wall street banker was sued by the SEC in civil court due to violations of the law, I think that most people would consider him/her to be a criminal or at least to have committed a criminal act.


I respectfully disagree on this front. With violations like this, bankers often violate civil codes at the same time as they violate criminal ones, as part of a larger pattern of bad faith activity. We justifiably call these individuals criminals, as the ones who make the news typically have broken criminal laws. However, financial institutions also regularly break civil codes without doing anything illegal, often unintentionally, and we generally don't brand those who have made such mistakes criminals. 

&amp;gt; Moreso, even for purely civil infractions (like internet piracy), a person who downloads illegal content can be referred to as an illegal downloader.

To be quite blunt, this just isn't factually correct. Internet piracy is an issue that can be either a civil violation or criminal one depending on the circumstances under which it occurred. If someone violated a copyright without meaning to or understanding that what they were doing was not allowed, this is considered merely a civil infraction. However, if a person can be shown to have knowingly violated copyright, especially for personal gain, it's considered to be a criminal act, not a civil one. We call people who knowingly illicitly download copyrighted content "illegal downloaders" because they are in fact committing an act that's considered illegal under criminal law. 

&amp;gt; So in that case, you would support referring to all rich Canadian/Mexicans with comfortable lives back home who crossed the border illegally as an illegal immigrant while calling all impoverished or desperate immigrants undocumented immigrants? If not, what if the split between those demographics for all illegal immigrants was 50/50? 80/20?

I suppose I have two responses for this question. Firstly, just jumping into the technical details of the question, I do think we can fairly treat people who have comfortable lives back home, but chose to ignore immigration law anyways, a bit more harshly. However, I would also contend that these folks make up a dismally small proportion of undocumented migrants. After all, if you can afford the time and money needed to deal with the immigration system, it would be much more to your benefit to enter/establish residency in the country legally. To the contrary, I strongly suspect that the overwhelming majority of undocumented migrants live in the US without authorization because they are forced to by circumstances beyond their immediate control. We know the two biggest drivers of undocumented migration are economic need and escaping from violence, so it would make sense the the majority of these folks are driven by one or both of these reasons. After all, why would you uproot your life and risk massive consequences if you had the option of staying in place?

Secondly, I have an objection to the use of "illegal immigrant" which has more to do with the connotations which have been attached to this phrase. While I understand that it was origionally intended to be merely descriptive, this title has been co-opted by those who seek to demonize and dehumanize migrants in order to push a political agenda. The mere fact that some have taken to shortening this phrase down to "illegals" is firm evidence in my eyes that this phrase can contribute to us looking at these folks as mere criminals, as opposed to people who deserve out sympathy, if not a home in the US. As such, I feel that using "undocumented" helps us to keep a more neutral perspective when it comes to discussing immigration, and allows us to stay more open minded when searching for solutions to this issue. 

&amp;gt; I agree that in individual cases you may want to use a term other than "illegal immigrant" just like in special cases you may not call someone a thief for stealing but when you are referring to people in aggregate, this doesn't hold water IMO.

I think I can see where you're coming from, although I think my opinion here is the mirror of your's. I would say that we can perhaps use the phrase "illegal immigrant", but we should try to limit that use to circumstances in which it is justified by an actual violation of US criminal law. When talking about undocumented folks on the whole, I think "undocumented immigrant" is simply more legally accurate and less likely to inspire overly negative reactions. 

&amp;gt; Also, I don't think that even in those special cases, "unauthorized immigrant" would be a term that is too harsh or insensitive.

I actually think I agree with you that "unauthorized immigrant" could be a great term to use in these discussions. It's descriptive of the situation these folks on the whole face, without running into issues of not distinguishing between civil and criminal immigration codes. Moreover, I concur that this is less harsh, and I would further suggest that it wouldn't evoke the same negative response as using the word "illegal". Finally, given that "undocumented" has also picked up some political associations, maybe just restarting with a fresh term would be best for promoting better political discourse around immigration reform. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31515430124.0" user="snogo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  For the majority of these migrants, they've entered the country through legal means (i.e. they're not the ones growing weed), and their subsequent decision to stay after they're supposed to return home is not a crime in itself.

&amp;gt; This is in large part the point I was trying to make. The vast majority of people who are branded "illegal immigrants" actually did not immigrate into the US illegally

Except that overstaying your visa is an illegal act in that it is against the law. If the law specifies that you can stay here for 90 days with a certain kind of visa and you stay here for 100, you are in violation of the law. Something being against the law and carrying criminal or civil penalties are independent characteristics. 

Are you really arguing that by overstaying your visa, your acts are congruent with the laws of the United States? Would you say that it is a legal act? Is there a real middle ground when it comes to something like this?

From my perspective, overstaying your visa and crossing the border should both be considered as moral equals (not legal equals) once you immigrated illegally because it was the actual immigration that is the issue at hand. You being here on a 90 day visa is visiting, not immigrating. Once you are here long term, you are immigrating without authorization just as you would be if you crossed the border. 



&amp;gt; il·le·galDictionary result for illegal
/i(l)ˈlēɡəl/Submit
adjective
adjective: illegal
1.
contrary to or forbidden by law, especially criminal law.       

&amp;amp;nbsp;


&amp;gt; Staying in the country without documentation isn't an unpunished criminal act, it's purely a civil violation .     

i.e. illegal. If i drive over the speed limit, I am illegally crossing the speed limit even if it is only a civil infraction. Would you agree that it is against the law to drive over the speed limit?   

&amp;gt; Firstly, just jumping into the technical details of the question, I do think we can fairly treat people who have comfortable lives back home, but chose to ignore immigration law anyways, a bit more harshly . 

Don't you think that is a little patronizing to the people who did come here out of desperation? That one person's rich neighbor is referred to as an illegal immigrant if they immigrate illegally but they are "graciously" called a euphemism when they do it because they obviously had no autonomy in their decisions?

&amp;gt; For example, were it a criminal violation, every single migrant being deported would be entitled to a formal court case and public defender, which would be a huge expense .   

This may surprise you, but I actually think that this should be the case and I am not actually pro deportation. I think that the penalty of deportation is way worse than the criminal penalty of short prison-sentences regardless if it is a civil penalty as opposed to a criminal penalty and you should have a right to a formal trial because many of your human rights *are being taken away* . I don't care if this basically paralyzes the deportation system. However, that is just my opinion and I don't have a right to shame someone for calling a spade a spade.     

What I do think we need to do is recognize that unauthorized immigrants immigrated without authorization which is against the law and that should be on the forefront of the conversation for how we deal with unauthorized immigration right next to how we deal with unauthorized immigrants with compassion. 

&amp;gt; After all, if you can afford the time and money needed to deal with the immigration system, it would be much more to your benefit to enter/establish residency in the country legally . 

I know that this is anecdotal but my dad was an illegal immigrant from a first world country who received amnesty during the Regan administration. It may still be a small percentage but I suspect that there may be more people who fit under this demographic than you expect given our exceptionally slow and inefficient immigration system.

Despite the actual demographic breakdown, I don't think that you drop calling something illegal because a lot of people are committing illegal acts for justifiable reasons.    

&amp;gt; While I understand that it was origionally intended to be merely descriptive, this title has been co-opted by those who seek to demonize and dehumanize migrants in order to push a political agenda.  

I agree and due to that I would support the use of a different term, just not "undocumented" which I believe results in the softening and ambiguation of what we are trying to describe when we use that term.   

However, I don't think that it is acceptable to shame people into using a different term and assuming malace when they use the term "illegal immigrant" when it is a perfectly fine descriptor with only small outgrowths of dehumanization attached to the term in our society. 

&amp;gt; I feel that using "undocumented" helps us to keep a more neutral perspective when it comes to discussing immigration, and allows us to stay more open minded when searching for solutions to this issue.    

I think that the term "undocumented" does not help us keep a neutral perspective but puts a thumb on the scale towards the opinion that there should be little to no distinction between authorized an unauthorized immigration. The term undocumented sounds (at least to me) like you are just like any other immigrant but your immigration into this country was undocumented, or unrecorded. That adds an extra degree of separation from the fact that your immigration was undocumented because it was never authorized in the first place.  






</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31509335456.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As it turns out, the mere act of being in the US without a legal visa or permanent residency [is not a crime, but merely a civil violation](https://www.politifact.com/florida/statements/2017/mar/15/florida-conference-catholic-bishops/being-united-states-unlawfully-crime/). This is hugely important, as [a significant majority of undocumented people enter the US by overstaying legitimate visas](https://www.npr.org/2019/01/10/683662691/where-does-illegal-immigration-mostly-occur-heres-what-the-data-tell-us), not by committing the crime of crossing the border illicitly.

It's a crime if you re-enter or don't use an official port.  That most people overstay visas doesn't change that; it's one concept that should be summed up in one word.

And if someone overstayed a visa then they absolutely are documented.  That's the only way you can get a visa.  Framing it like they don't have documents is on par with what you're saying but stands contrary to it.  They're documented and we have proof.  They don't have the right documents.

The word "illegal", especially considering lay usage, doesn't mean "criminal".  It's illegal to jaywalk but you aren't going to be put in a federal facility for it.  It's illegal to liter but I don't know of anyone who's gone to jail - and I've seen cops do it.  Illegal simply means, by its etymology, "not legal".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31515732880.0" user="thegoldengrekhanate" delta="False">
    <text>[actually its less than half of illegal immigrants are overstayed visas](https://www.politifact.com/california/statements/2018/aug/24/kevin-mccarthy/mostly-true-visa-overstays-account-half-all-people/)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

 That report estimated visa overstays in 2014 accounted for 42 percent of the total undocumented population, 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

 "we tend to be a lot more forgiving of folks who commit criminal acts because issues with society leave them with few other choices. "

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Forgiving how? The crime is still punished, even if we sympathize with them. For instance a young gangbanger who entered the gang at ten, and then commits murder at 16 is still a murderer, and should be addressed as such. It doesn't matter that he grew up in poverty, or that he was recruited early by the gangs, he is still called a murderer, not "an unfortunate result of poverty and gang culuter that made the poor decision to take a life" of whatever term you would like to use. He is called a murderer. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

The same with your bread thief, he is not called an unasked borrower, he is called a thief.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

How is trying to escape poverty not a selfish reason? More so how is a central american fleeing to american and not mexico not a selfish act?  They could find work in mexico but pass it by for the higher wages in the US. How is that not selfish?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

A crime is a crime and the societal pressure should not matter. Would "societal pressure" excuse an SS deathcamp guard? He was raised in the Hitler Youth, and he was trained in a dogmatic military like the SS, and he was "just following orders".  Should we call him a camp guard? To " leaving us with more sympathy and potentially a better understanding "?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31519143661.0" user="attempt_number_55" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As it turns out, the mere act of being in the US without a legal visa or permanent residency is not a crime, but merely a civil violation.

That is incorrect. From what you linked "For instance, an undocumented immigrant who entered the United States improperly would have committed a crime. However, once that person is here, the simple act of being in the United States unlawfully is not by itself a crime." ILLEGAL ENTRY, aka crossing the border with NO visa is DEFINITELY a crime. You IMMIGRATED to the US with no visa, aka ILLEGALLY, therefore you are an ILLEGAL IMMIGRANT. 

&amp;gt;thus leaving us with more sympathy and potentially a better understanding of how to solve this situation.

AKA let more of them in, you mean. No thanks. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31519159145.0" user="ColdNotion" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not questioning that it’s illegal to cross the border without a visa or other form of legal permission to enter the US. What I and the source was saying is that simply overstaying a visa doesn’t represent a criminal act. Given that most undocumented immigrants enter the US this way, and not by illicitly crossing the border, I’m arguing that the term “undocumented” is generally more accurate when describing this migrant population, as the majority of these folks have to committed an illegal act in violation of criminal law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31519211180.0" user="attempt_number_55" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What I and the source was saying is that simply overstaying a visa doesn’t represent a criminal act.

Which is a minority of illegal immigrants to the US. Even the MOST generous estimates put it at only 40%. 

&amp;gt;Given that most undocumented immigrants enter the US this way, and not by illicitly crossing the border,

That's just factually inaccurate. You should check your sources. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
