<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="654650438.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/atrfie/cmv_the_no_one_is_illegal_response_is_unjustified/">
    <title>CMV: The "no one is illegal" response is unjustified virtue signaling and the term "undocumented immigrant" is misleading.</title>
    <original_poster>snogo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand that there are sensitivities that need to be taken when referring to people who built their entire lives around an illegal act, but nobody cares when we characterize other people as "illegal" due to other illegal acts.

If I illegally dump toxic waste in the local river, I may very well be referred to as an illegal dumper. If I illegally sell cigarettes in the park, I may very well be referred to as an illegal seller. If I illegally grow marijuana in a legal state where a distinction is necessary, I may very well be referred to as an illegal grower.

The only time referring to someone as an "illegal X" gets people riled up is when you are referring to people who immigrated illegally.

This leads to whitewashed terms like "undocumented immigrant" which sounds like there was no illegal act performed. The term "undocumented immigrant" sounds to the uninformed observer like someone who is just like any other legal immigrant but whose immigration was undocumented due to a mishap in paperwork.

It wasn't simply an "undocumented immigration", it was an unauthorized, or illegal immigration.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31508182729.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>Use the term "unlawfully present". 

It is more direct and not a euphemism like "undocumented". It side steps the concerns others have raised about the distinction between civil and criminal violations of law.

The term "illegal" is inferior in several ways. 

1. actions are illegal, not individuals. Using "illegal" to describe an individual is a misuse of the term. 

2. Negative nouns or adjectives are more dehumanizing than negative participles. A negative noun or adjective sounds more like a defining characteristic than a descriptor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508186764.0" user="snogo" delta="False">
    <text>That sounds like a good idea, unfortunately I am not sure if I am allowed to award you a delta if you haven't actually changed my view in terms of any of the points that I laid out. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31508197025.0" user="TripRichert" delta="False">
    <text>oh no, I won't get imaginary points next to my name on the posts that I make!

If I made you think about the language you use, we're in agreement on the point that I care about. I'm glad we found common ground, even if you feel it isn't a direct enough response to your original post.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
