<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="657527967.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/avh3tr/cmv_modern_marriage_in_the_us_brings_more_harm/">
    <title>CMV: Modern marriage in the US brings more harm than benefit for men.</title>
    <original_poster>cannibalstreudel</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe based on marriage laws and divorce practices that marriage no longer has more benefits than harm for men.

For women it's the opposite. I believe this because whether laws state this or not, practices in divorce court often grant kids' custody to the mother from the father when they aren't more dangerous to their kids than their wife. And often men have to give up half their income/assets in divorce when they often make most of the income of the household.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Sure there are emotional benefits to a long term relationship. But there aren't extra benefits for men on top of an emotionally committed relationship that exclusively comes with marriate.

The security marriage itself brings is only for the woman. She gets to enjoy financial guarantee of sharing income when men often make more than women, and she can be assured of his fidelity - it's backed up by government enforcement... women rarely are punished for fucking another guy and being impregnated at the level men are, and often the man in the marriage gets cucked and is made responsible for raising another man's child.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

tl;dr Men are bringing unnecessary vulnerabilities on themselves when they marry a woman in modern US courts.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If someone can reliably demonstrate that marriage gives more potential benefit to men than potential harm, I would believe marriage brings more benefit than harm to men. And to be clear, I'm not talking about long term relationships, I'm talking about specifically signing a marriage document and putting the law behind the union.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31528175715.0" user="ace52387" delta="False">
    <text>In a family with kids, marriage benefits the primary caregiver more than the breadwinner...however I dont find this unfair, and the primary care giver may be the man. Men as primary caregivers are common enough that it doesnt makes sense to characterize marriage as benefiting the woman.

Marriage also benefits the breadwinner however, since that financial security that marriage promises will allow the primary caregiver to do more caregiving. Without that guarantee, if you are a man and you make more than your wife, shes heavily incentivized to continue to focus on her career as much as she can. Because she makes less than you, her spending less time caregiving means youre spending more time caregiving, which results in a lower income for the whole family.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528258217.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going back to work so I'll be able to respond once I get off in 5 hours</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31529902496.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I hear your point, and having a breadwinner and a caregiver denotes a benefit. I don't see how this is limited to marriage however. If I choose to provide for my girl, and I prove to her that I am ready and able to do it and we gain trust on that setup, I don't see the point of putting the law behind my word. That doesn't help me, it only helps her. That's my point here, not the validity of having a primary caregiver (most of the time a woman) and a primary breadwinner (most of the time a man.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31544643870.0" user="ace52387" delta="False">
    <text>It helps you in that she won't have to be looking over her shoulder at all times. The caregiver gets the short end of the stick without that kind of legal/financial commitment, and the relationship will not be balanced, giving the breadwinner all the power.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Making this commitment lets the caregiver make financial sacrifices much easier, knowing you can't just leave her and completely destroy her financial future. That usually benefits the breadwinner also.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528308416.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In a family with kids, marriage benefits the primary caregiver more than the breadwinner


How can she be a care giver without the essentials paid by trhe father?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528317891.0" user="UncleMeat11" delta="False">
    <text>Fathers can be caregivers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528540306.0" user="Chairman_of_the_Pool" delta="False">
    <text>Are you assuming a family where mom is 100% stay at home for the entire time the children ar minors?  Realistically, in modern times, a lot of families are double income for most or a good portion of the kids childhoods.  Even so, caregiving isn’t sitting around on your butt eating bob bons, waiting for the school bus to drop kids off.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528970784.0" user="ace52387" delta="False">
    <text>No, whoever is the primary caregiver. Generally, 1 parent takes on more caregiving duties than another. Even if both parents have FT jobs, one can make significantly more of a sacrifice than another. For instance, 1 parent works a high powered job, 50-60 hr weeks, the other works a much more relaxed job with work from home options.

Who said caregiving was sitting on your butt?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528990294.0" user="ace52387" delta="False">
    <text>The phrasing of this view isnt quite accurate. It would only make sense if the amount of men acting as primary caregivers was negligible. It is not. So its already wrong in that sense since marriage could sometimes benefit the man more than the woman, by virtue of the man being the primary caregiver.

But overall my point is that even though it benefits one party more than the other, it still can benefit both parties.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
