<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="657527967.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/avh3tr/cmv_modern_marriage_in_the_us_brings_more_harm/">
    <title>CMV: Modern marriage in the US brings more harm than benefit for men.</title>
    <original_poster>cannibalstreudel</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe based on marriage laws and divorce practices that marriage no longer has more benefits than harm for men.

For women it's the opposite. I believe this because whether laws state this or not, practices in divorce court often grant kids' custody to the mother from the father when they aren't more dangerous to their kids than their wife. And often men have to give up half their income/assets in divorce when they often make most of the income of the household.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Sure there are emotional benefits to a long term relationship. But there aren't extra benefits for men on top of an emotionally committed relationship that exclusively comes with marriate.

The security marriage itself brings is only for the woman. She gets to enjoy financial guarantee of sharing income when men often make more than women, and she can be assured of his fidelity - it's backed up by government enforcement... women rarely are punished for fucking another guy and being impregnated at the level men are, and often the man in the marriage gets cucked and is made responsible for raising another man's child.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

tl;dr Men are bringing unnecessary vulnerabilities on themselves when they marry a woman in modern US courts.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If someone can reliably demonstrate that marriage gives more potential benefit to men than potential harm, I would believe marriage brings more benefit than harm to men. And to be clear, I'm not talking about long term relationships, I'm talking about specifically signing a marriage document and putting the law behind the union.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31528163721.0" user="FIThrowAway125" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;She gets to enjoy financial guarantee of sharing income when men often make more than women, and she can be assured of his fidelity  
  
So wouldn't your view be more accurately stated as "marriage in the US brings more harm than benefit to the higher income earner"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528171860.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>More potential financial harm but that's not the only potential harm. And men are still mostly the higher income earners on average.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528212569.0" user="FIThrowAway125" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And men are still mostly the higher income earners on average.  
  
That doesn't matter, though. What matters is the characteristic that truly leads to unfair treatment, not the other attributes those people hold.  
  
I'd still disagree anyway, as I think in the vast majority of households the higher income earner benefited from their partner. It's not "the husband's money" if the reason he got promoted was because he worked long hours and transferred offices every two years and his wife took a step back in her career to support that. So a husband isn't losing "half of his assets," but rather two people are splitting *their joint* assets in half. Do you disagree with that?
  
I'll give you family court, at least anecdotally. That at least from popular stories it seems hard for men to get 50% or full custody of their kids though of course every story is going to have two sides.  
  
But I disagree with the financial take and don't think the *potential* of only getting partial custody in the event of a divorce is enough to discount the benefits of marriage, so can you please list the other potential harms you see? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528261710.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going back to work so I'll be able to respond once I get off in 5 hours</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528413062.0" user="Chairman_of_the_Pool" delta="False">
    <text>Convenient.  Do you make enough money to support a future wife and kids?  Do you have women coworkers who earn as much as you do?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31530056832.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>If finances are joint because the woman took care of the kids while the man focused on his career, then custody is joint because the man provided for the woman so she could focus on her kid. It goes two ways, not just one. Marriage is an unnecessary pressure on a relationship, which is my view I'm putting forth, and while you bring up an interesting point of her helping by taking care of the household, that's if women still hold themselves to that standard. And third-wave feminism abolished that expectation of women. If my girl doesn't clean the house and take care of the kids even after we have a mature adult discussion about it, society today sees me as wrong for expecting her to do that, even if I bring home the bread.

If we stick to traditional roles, cool. It's equal. If we don't, also cool, but that means the man doesn't have any responsibility to provide for the woman if she doesn't have responsibility to take care of the household. She can't take the money and then not provide anything to the relationship... That's why I say it's imbalanced and a net harm to men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31531492362.0" user="FIThrowAway125" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If finances are joint because the woman took care of the kids while the man focused on his career, then custody is joint because the man provided for the woman so she could focus on her kid. It goes two ways, not just one
  
Custody almost always is two ways, as has been pointed out in this thread.  It might not be a straight 50/50 but it isn't nearly as bad as you're making it out to be. Btw - you run into the same custody stuff (and possibly more) even if you aren't married. Alimony could be an argument for you but plenty of people have kids outside of marriage and a wedding ring isn't going to change what happens in a custody battle.   
  
&amp;gt; And third-wave feminism abolished that expectation of women. If my girl doesn't clean the house and take care of the kids even after we have a mature adult discussion about it, society today sees me as wrong for expecting her to do that, even if I bring home the bread.
  
You're missing the point. It isn't about the woman taking care of 100% of household chores and kids, because if you both worked you'd still have some responsibilities at night. It's about a team working together in whatever unique ways their relationship calls for.
  
What if the husband is a lawyer and makes $150k/year, but the wife supported him through law school? Even if she stays home or makes less now she's a big part of their success. What about any time someone is transferred for a job and their spouse has to give there's up?  What about decisions made on the outset where they husband and wife decide *together* that the wife will take a less prestigious (or no) career to be available for the childreN?
  
&amp;gt;She can't take the money and then not provide anything to the relationship...
  
Basically, and this is why it'll be my last post in this thread, this tells me you have a toxic view of relationships and what women are "good for." It screams someone that sees a relationship as a scorecard with points awarded for sex, money and chores. Marriage is a partnership, with give and take and lots of teamwork. It's not as simple as comparing W2s and deciding who's the super star and who is the role player. Yes, of course there are cases where an athlete or actor/actress is hugely successful and they get raked over the coals in a divorce, but those situations are rare and we don't make divorce laws based on them.  For the average man you're way overstating the disadvantages, and even imagining them to a large degree. 
  

  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31534301287.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. Women aren't a huge part of that man's success just by being there. They're a huge part of their success if they're supportive of him and help him succeed. You don't earn anything by being in a relationship. There are many relationships which are toxic... If she just nags him and puts pressure on him to do things but never helps around the house and just uses him as a bank is she "part of his success?" Granted most women are not like this, but it's a spectrum... A woman isn't entitled to a man's money just because she's there. She's not "a part of his success" just because she's there. You said it's your last post in the thread which is your choice. If you decide to continue this discussion I won't hold it against you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
