<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="657527967.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/avh3tr/cmv_modern_marriage_in_the_us_brings_more_harm/">
    <title>CMV: Modern marriage in the US brings more harm than benefit for men.</title>
    <original_poster>cannibalstreudel</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe based on marriage laws and divorce practices that marriage no longer has more benefits than harm for men.

For women it's the opposite. I believe this because whether laws state this or not, practices in divorce court often grant kids' custody to the mother from the father when they aren't more dangerous to their kids than their wife. And often men have to give up half their income/assets in divorce when they often make most of the income of the household.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Sure there are emotional benefits to a long term relationship. But there aren't extra benefits for men on top of an emotionally committed relationship that exclusively comes with marriate.

The security marriage itself brings is only for the woman. She gets to enjoy financial guarantee of sharing income when men often make more than women, and she can be assured of his fidelity - it's backed up by government enforcement... women rarely are punished for fucking another guy and being impregnated at the level men are, and often the man in the marriage gets cucked and is made responsible for raising another man's child.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

tl;dr Men are bringing unnecessary vulnerabilities on themselves when they marry a woman in modern US courts.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If someone can reliably demonstrate that marriage gives more potential benefit to men than potential harm, I would believe marriage brings more benefit than harm to men. And to be clear, I'm not talking about long term relationships, I'm talking about specifically signing a marriage document and putting the law behind the union.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31528222570.0" user="HeWhoShitsWithPhone" delta="False">
    <text>All of the child related issues you bring have nothing to do with marriage. Custody of Children with unmarried parents goes through the same courts as those getting divorced. So Any issues  here would be with having kids not being married.

If your wife cheats on you and has a kid, you can split up and not pay child support. There are some stories of this happening, but they are rare and I suspect they all have extenuating circumstances. In this specific situation marriage could be a huge advantage. If I had a 6 year old that I loved, I would want to know that my custody can be enforced even if I was not the biological father. Once you have a relationship with your child it should not matter if your their biological father or not, their your kid and you should want to be part of their life. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528266731.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going back to work so I'll be able to respond once I get off in 5 hours</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31545101978.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I "shouldn't" want anything. That's my issue with this matter... The obligation put on men rather than a choice given. If the kid isn't mine I can choose what to do, I should never be forced to raise another man's child.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
