<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="657527967.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/avh3tr/cmv_modern_marriage_in_the_us_brings_more_harm/">
    <title>CMV: Modern marriage in the US brings more harm than benefit for men.</title>
    <original_poster>cannibalstreudel</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe based on marriage laws and divorce practices that marriage no longer has more benefits than harm for men.

For women it's the opposite. I believe this because whether laws state this or not, practices in divorce court often grant kids' custody to the mother from the father when they aren't more dangerous to their kids than their wife. And often men have to give up half their income/assets in divorce when they often make most of the income of the household.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Sure there are emotional benefits to a long term relationship. But there aren't extra benefits for men on top of an emotionally committed relationship that exclusively comes with marriate.

The security marriage itself brings is only for the woman. She gets to enjoy financial guarantee of sharing income when men often make more than women, and she can be assured of his fidelity - it's backed up by government enforcement... women rarely are punished for fucking another guy and being impregnated at the level men are, and often the man in the marriage gets cucked and is made responsible for raising another man's child.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

tl;dr Men are bringing unnecessary vulnerabilities on themselves when they marry a woman in modern US courts.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If someone can reliably demonstrate that marriage gives more potential benefit to men than potential harm, I would believe marriage brings more benefit than harm to men. And to be clear, I'm not talking about long term relationships, I'm talking about specifically signing a marriage document and putting the law behind the union.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31528135904.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>What if your wife earns more money than you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528147736.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>If my wife earns more money than me then I'd have a financial benefit but I'd still be more vulnerable in matters of fidelity - if I cheat I'm gone, if she cheats I'll be responsible for raising the kid if she gets pregnant. And if she decides she wants to leave me for someone else I might not get to keep my kids even half the time, and if we don't get joint custody she'll probably get custody.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528174698.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>So, your point here is that being "vulnerable in matters of fidelity" is worse than the financial benefit is good?  Could you justify this?

Second, what if you have a marriage where there's good, open communication between the partners, and so things don't just boil down to who wins if someone cheats?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528187678.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying vulnerability in fidelity is more or less important. I'm saying it's important, if I marry a women who earns drastically more than me, depending on how much it's possibly a net plus. But because of my goals and ambitions and personality (and that of men compared to women in general) myself and the majority of men will make more than their wives so it doesn't apply to myself or to men on average.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528276840.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not saying vulnerability in fidelity is more or less important

This directly contradicts your view that marriage "brings more harm than benefit," right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31545142360.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>For men who are more like women, maybe but that's not who I'm talking about in my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528192871.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>As for your second point there are numerous accounts of "she was amazing until she filed divorce and screwed me over." Meaning everything looks good until it doesn't so you can't guarantee good marriage even if you do have a good relationship - hence the vulnerability for men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528284674.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>Which do you seriously think is more common: a situation where someone believes, with justification, that their marriage is characterized by good communication and things go fine?  Or a situation where someone has been tricked into believing that their marriage is characterized by good communication and suddenly their spouse betrays them?

Seriously think about this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31545145367.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>So you've never heard of people thinking they've got it all covered but then their wife takes a 180 and leaves? It's somewhat common.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31546352956.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't answer the question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31547854889.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>It's such an abstract question that distracts from the point... It's common enough that good marriages go bad to make it a legitimate risk. It doesn't have to be more common than the alternative to make it a significant consideration.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528210355.0" user="techiemikey" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I'll be responsible for raising the kid if she gets pregnant

That's only true if you want it to be true.  If she cheats, she can be gone, and you can take a paternity test to prove the child is not yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528259536.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going back to work so I'll be able to respond once I get off in 5 hours</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31545111064.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>I'd have to see statistics on how this is applied. From what I understand it's not that easy in practice with the law.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
