<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="657527967.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/avh3tr/cmv_modern_marriage_in_the_us_brings_more_harm/">
    <title>CMV: Modern marriage in the US brings more harm than benefit for men.</title>
    <original_poster>cannibalstreudel</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe based on marriage laws and divorce practices that marriage no longer has more benefits than harm for men.

For women it's the opposite. I believe this because whether laws state this or not, practices in divorce court often grant kids' custody to the mother from the father when they aren't more dangerous to their kids than their wife. And often men have to give up half their income/assets in divorce when they often make most of the income of the household.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Sure there are emotional benefits to a long term relationship. But there aren't extra benefits for men on top of an emotionally committed relationship that exclusively comes with marriate.

The security marriage itself brings is only for the woman. She gets to enjoy financial guarantee of sharing income when men often make more than women, and she can be assured of his fidelity - it's backed up by government enforcement... women rarely are punished for fucking another guy and being impregnated at the level men are, and often the man in the marriage gets cucked and is made responsible for raising another man's child.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

tl;dr Men are bringing unnecessary vulnerabilities on themselves when they marry a woman in modern US courts.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If someone can reliably demonstrate that marriage gives more potential benefit to men than potential harm, I would believe marriage brings more benefit than harm to men. And to be clear, I'm not talking about long term relationships, I'm talking about specifically signing a marriage document and putting the law behind the union.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31528141130.0" user="Talleyrand1234" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, you skim over the emotional aspect of marriage like it’s nothing. You can have gripes with the financial aspects of marriage or whatnot, and we can parse that out, but “current laws surrounding marriage tend to disadvantage men in certain marital situations in ways that are unjust and should be revised” is a far cry from “marriage isn’t worth it.” Many men derive immense emotional security and fulfillment from being in a codified, monogamous relationship with someone they love and care about. You can’t just shrug that off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528153904.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>Emotional security comes from long term relationships, not marriage. You don't need marriage for the emotional security. Marriage is just putting the law behind a LTR.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31528197993.0" user="Talleyrand1234" delta="False">
    <text>With all due respect, this just isn’t true. Marriage, whether we like it or not or whether it’s desirable as a society or not, has a VAST cultural import to relationships that just being in a long term relationship can not capture for most people. There’s a big difference between being in a mutually trusting monogamous relationship and literally forming a new entity in the eyes of society to describe the level of dedication you feel towards your partner and vice versa, and inviting all the people who are important to your life to an elaborate ceremony to codify this union. Getting married is considered a big part of achieving success in society; it’s an integral part of the American dream. Maybe for some people this isn’t the case, and to be fair not attaching so much importance to arbitrary legal doctrine and fancy, stupid expensive events is probably a good direction to move in as a society long term, but I’d wager it’s still the case for most American men, especially those with more conservative social values.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31530066348.0" user="cannibalstreudel" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps in your social circles this is true, but the claims you're saying are entirely subjective and just aren't subjectively true to me. I respect that for you marriage is subjectively important, even a core ambition perhaps, and that's cool. For me and many I know, marriage isn't an aspiration.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
