<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="658027977.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/avrtmx/cmv_a_person_can_express_that_they_think_another/">
    <title>CMV: A person can express that they think another person is wrong without the discussion being "an argument"</title>
    <original_poster>IMArguin</original_poster>
    <original_post>My view is that two people can talk about differing opinions with the goal of coming to a closer alignment of their opinions without that discussion being an argument.

I further believe that saying that someone is not explaining themselves clearly, or is phrasing things in a way that isn't precise isnt a personal attack. People should be able to hear minor criticism of their ideas and their expression without feeling like the other person thinks they are dumb. Even the smartest people sometimes say things the wrong way or fail to look at something from every angle.

If a person is willing to change their opinion, then wanting to have a conversation where the other person might change their opinion as well or instead is not invalidating the other person's opinion or not letting them have their opinion.

Wanting to have a conversation stop at "here is my opinion", "here is my differing opinion" is not actually a conversation, and in some ways is more invalidating than wanting to talk about why each person holds their divergent opinion.

Outright saying "you are wrong" is rude, but implying that you think the other person is wrong by asking questions or giving counter examples is not rude.

Everyone has some soft spots and topics that are not open to conversation of any kind, but most topics should be open to some discussion. Especially if it is something that is not a core value, just something a person is interested in or learning.

Please explain to me how any/all of these views are wrong. Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31540437355.0" user="Mrssomethingstarwars" delta="False">
    <text>I believe you may be confusing "connotation" with "denotation". Essentially, your "view" is a matter of semantics. For anyone unaware, a connotation refers to the feelings and thoughts associated with a word, whereas a denotation is the textbook definition. Denotation does not take into consideration society's implications (positive or negative) of using a word opposed to it's synonym. Each person's connotative associations with the word "argument" are slightly different. Sometimes people use it for a lack of a better term. Personally, I use "heated conversation" when two people are passionate about their viewpoints but are trying to find common ground (the same situation I think you are referring to). But ultimately I think the only thing that really matters is how each participant perceives the purpose of the conversation and their perspective on the implications of "argument". As long as they are on the same page, then (pardon my language) fuck what observers think, or classify the exchange as. It really has no bearing on the situation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
