<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668369613.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b1xhal/cmv_the_question_of_do_we_live_in_a_simulation/">
    <title>CMV: The question of "do we live in a simulation" doesn't matter</title>
    <original_poster>mix_420</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this for two reasons:

1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.
2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

Basically what I'm saying here is there's no point in asking this question if you will never have the answer to it, considering the only reason to ask the question is for the knowledge of it, as you'll never achieve it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607158555.0" user="ShIxtan" delta="False">
    <text>The main reason I think it's a relevant question (to answer your #2):

Simulations are usually run for a reason. And they don't usually run forever. If we can guess at the most likely end conditions for the simulation we are in, it could significantly change my day-to-day actions.

For example, one of the most likely simulations I can imagine post-interstellar civilizations running, is slight variations on pre-interstellar worlds. In those cases you would end the simulation around the time of the first interstellar trip, because the complexity shoots up drastically then. If we are in that type of simulation, we should do everything possible to prevent interstellar travel, or at least not make decisions based on the far future.

The other main reason it could matter has to do with acausal trade and decision theory, but I'm too tired to make a good case for that atm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607178177.0" user="ShIxtan" delta="False">
    <text>As far as #1, you should never expect to have absolute certainty about anything. It's all probability. If at some point in the future we discover it's easy to run simulations of entire solar systems, we'd significantly increase the weight of the belief that we're currently in such a simulation. It's not "proof", but "proof" isn't really a thing. It would certainly be evidence that supports the theory.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
