<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668369613.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b1xhal/cmv_the_question_of_do_we_live_in_a_simulation/">
    <title>CMV: The question of "do we live in a simulation" doesn't matter</title>
    <original_poster>mix_420</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this for two reasons:

1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.
2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

Basically what I'm saying here is there's no point in asking this question if you will never have the answer to it, considering the only reason to ask the question is for the knowledge of it, as you'll never achieve it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31605024617.0" user="Stiblex" delta="False">
    <text>It matters a little, because if it were somehow proven to be true, it meant we could do the same with the right technology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31605048938.0" user="mix_420" delta="False">
    <text>Although, that would assume a world outside of ours has the same physics and resources that we do. I wouldn't be surprised if something like this could be achieved, but your point runs under the assumption that everything in our universe would be the same as something in a universe that simulates our own.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31605071369.0" user="Stiblex" delta="False">
    <text>The world outside of ours doesn't have to. If we were to make a simulation with computers, we could choose our own laws of physics and resources.

The Sims is actually a great example of a smaller simulation we have managed to make. Tiny people in a tiny world with very limited laws and resources. Yet it's played out finely and the subjects never question whether their world lines up with ours, and it doesn't have to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31605096181.0" user="mix_420" delta="False">
    <text>I don't deny your assumption is likely, I just would state that it's an assumption.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
