<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668369613.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b1xhal/cmv_the_question_of_do_we_live_in_a_simulation/">
    <title>CMV: The question of "do we live in a simulation" doesn't matter</title>
    <original_poster>mix_420</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this for two reasons:

1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.
2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

Basically what I'm saying here is there's no point in asking this question if you will never have the answer to it, considering the only reason to ask the question is for the knowledge of it, as you'll never achieve it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607301107.0" user="AshleyOriginal" delta="False">
    <text>If the world was a simulation how would you understand what the real world was? 

My best guess is your level of control.

As someone who can very easily lucid dream, I often think in my dreams, "because I'm dreaming and will wake up I can push my boundaries and at least make this dream memorable." - I thought that yesterday in a dream I didn't like very much.

All you need to do is become self aware that you can simply think things different and it will happen, and also notice errors. Noticing errors gives you a lot of control.

I've done many things in my lucid dreams, from dying (and just wandering around after death not sure what I was supposed to do) to flying, to stopping, or reversing time, to understanding snakes (and stopping them from speaking), to living as other people (I feel sorry for a lot of 'em, I hope they are okay), to being other things and giving life to things with no life, to telling myself to just wake up now, sometimes I'll ask for advice, etc etc.

"I don't want to follow this path I'll just stop this from happening etc." Poof. I just think it to be.

Dreams are a strange way we simulate reality. We know they are wrong and it's very easy to have more control in dreams than you do in reality.

You can do a lot in reality, and I feel sorry for those who slowly lose their grip, when their dreams blend in with the real world. As someone who learned how to control their dreams from having so many nightmares I can understand how people feel powerless but you always have some level of control. 

If the world were simulated, I'd try very hard to break it so I could control it.

The real question is why would it be simulated?

I understand we use dreams to understand reality better, I generally understand my dreams right away if I spend a little time breaking down the symbols (if needed, some dreams are pretty straightforward thou) and can generally reapply it to my life or use it to predict the future often the next day or within the week. 

My favorite dream is about someone rushing to hug me, and indeed they came within the week rushing to hug me though I didn't hear the words in my dream, I knew what they would say if they could. I can understand them. Granted you never really know what will happen. I was happy with just a dream, a dream I never told them about, so I was even more surprised to see it come through. They would never believe me if I told them it would happen. They don't believe in that sort of thing but oh well. Dreams are a small part of life anyway.

So how would that apply to a simulation? 

If this was a simulation, we could break it to understand another reality, but unlike dreams we are forced to have, we have nothing that forces us to go beyond. 

So for the most part, I think the simulation question is somewhat useless. Why have a simulation?

We know how to control our life with epienetics to some degree, we already know how much your mind influences your body and senses, we understand ways to earn money and befriend people, we have power to influence others. At some point though, we fail, we fail to have the knowledge we need to control everything. 

Unlike dreams you can hack, real life makes you feel as if you can't control it. It makes you feel small sometimes, and it makes you feel like you aren't the only one to exist. It's annoying because you can't get your way, not all the time at least. I suppose you really have to work and embrace real life to get the most out of it. It's really the opposite of most dreams really.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
