<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668369613.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b1xhal/cmv_the_question_of_do_we_live_in_a_simulation/">
    <title>CMV: The question of "do we live in a simulation" doesn't matter</title>
    <original_poster>mix_420</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this for two reasons:

1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.
2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

Basically what I'm saying here is there's no point in asking this question if you will never have the answer to it, considering the only reason to ask the question is for the knowledge of it, as you'll never achieve it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31612287739.0" user="Zerlske" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.

This is not necessarily true (depends upon the quality of the simulation as some another commenter stated) but framed differently you can say that there is no way of knowing whether or not we live in a simulation, that is something you cannot prove or disprove without omnipotence. 

&amp;gt; There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

I'd say the inquiry has great value from an epistemic point of view, specifically as an example of how little we may know. Descartes *cogito ergo sum* logic ("I think therefore I am") takes us to a place where we can be fairly confident about the existence of a thinking agent of some sort (despite there being issue with his assertion of "I"). But besides that we cannot *confidently* state much more, the best instruments we have for all else is our fallible sensory organs and our fallible biochemical thought processes, which may give us empirical truth but not objective truth (a prerequisite for that is omnipotence, the eyes of god so to speak). In other words, this kind of question can be very useful and matter a lot as it supports epistemological agnosticism, something which I find to be lacking amongst many people. I'll end with stating the Socratic paradox: "I know that I know nothing".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
