<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668369613.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b1xhal/cmv_the_question_of_do_we_live_in_a_simulation/">
    <title>CMV: The question of "do we live in a simulation" doesn't matter</title>
    <original_poster>mix_420</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this for two reasons:

1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.
2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

Basically what I'm saying here is there's no point in asking this question if you will never have the answer to it, considering the only reason to ask the question is for the knowledge of it, as you'll never achieve it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31608464473.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>Well it matters significantly as it would change how we see the world and how we would interact with it and each others because of it. I mean the knowledge that we can die has massive influence on our life despite us having no prove that we would actually die or what that even means. I mean we will never have empirical prove that we are mortal because the one instance that is able to give us that prove is the one instance that will remove our ability to tell.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Also as others have already said it pretty much depends on what kind of simulation you are running.  

* Are you some consciousness occupying a vessel within a different universe?
* Are you a real thing somewhere that is connected to a simulation?
* Are you just bytes of code within a simulation?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I mean you could try code injection, learn about the universe and it's rules and use that in your favor to make exploits. Ok bad example as we already do that. 

But for example it would make a difference whether or not your are in a simulated reality or whether the reality is simulated around you, because one has boundaries which would make it difficult to be rendered and the other could just render your local environment. However it would need to calculate the whole world in order to keep consistency, so you might spot some errors because of the limited computation power needed to fuel the system. 

Also is it a physical or an electronic simulation and what would that be a difference?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
