<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607173679.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>It’s football, we don’t want it to be Americanised.

Stopping the clock in American football takes away all of the momentum, slows the game into a series of moves split up by lengthy breaks. It’s terrible for atmosphere, for the team’s rhythm, and for fans and spectators. Bringing this to football would be a disaster 

It would be a terrible thing for football to take away the momentum and pressure which is maintained or added by the clock, and take away the excitement of injury time on top of that. 

I can’t think of a single reason why it would be introduced. None of your bullet points are particularly good reasons for having a stopped clock - why introduce one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607230057.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>How would it stop momentum? The game already gets stopped. When a player gets injured, the game literally stops as he's helped out or helped off the pitch. With the addition if VAR, you now have stoppages as it gets checked. 

So your argument about momentum, rhythm, atmosphere etc makes little sense as those things already get impacted on the way it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607235823.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I thought this was r/soccer, wouldn’t have replied if I’d realised

Regarding momentum, compare the two sports. 

If you stop the clock then the game is paused indefinitely and unambiguously. You can go for a drink, you can discuss tactics, you can chat to your manager - it doesn’t matter as the time is stopped. It becomes fragmented and each break can be prolonged. This all impacts momentum, atmosphere, fan engagement etc. Without a formalised break in time, none of this occurs unless forced by lengthy injuries etc. 

I mean they show adverts during the game in American football for fucks sake!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607245996.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>Do you understand what the CMV is actually saying? They're talking about those moments when the players are on the floor for instance and getting Medical attention. For those few seconds or minutes, the clock should stop. It doesn't suddenly mean it becomes NFL like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607253189.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Like I said, I thought this was r/soccer 

But to play devil’s advocate, then no he isn’t, why do you think that? 

He’s not specified what kind of stoppage the clock should or shouldn’t be stopped for, and what kind of stoppage should continue as per current rules. It’s pretty clear that having a stopped clock for just some stoppages and not others adds nil value to the game, so the point is redundant regardless? 

I get the impression you haven’t watched a great deal of football?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607264898.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>It would make the game exactly 90 minutes long, thus creating more consistency. Now if a player sits down in the 80th minute from cramp, the ref pauses the clock, the player receives attention or eventually gets up, then everything carries on from where the clock was stopped.

There'd be no more time wasting in the game. No more arbitrary stoppage time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607272619.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not sure what point you’re trying to make now - your previous statement was about momentum and disruption to the flow of the game. 

Now your point is about ensuring the game lasts exactly ninety minutes, which isn’t something which has ever been considered crucial in football and certainly not something you’d sacrifice quality of match for. 

Which point is it you’re trying to make? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607296788.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>What are you on about? You're the one who mentioned momentum first. You said that stopping the clock would affect momentum.

So how does a GK talking ages over a goal kick not stop momentum? How does a player faking injuries not stop momentum? How does a player receiving medical attention not stop momentum? How does the ref going to check VAR not stop momentum?

During United vs PSG, the ref took ages to check the VAR for the penalty. The clock kept going, but the match wasn't being played at all. How did that not stop momentum? Why would it be worse to stop the clock while the ref checks the VAR</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607302094.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I did, to which you responded in your post. Your subsequent post then wildly deviated towards keeping the clock to exactly 90 minutes.

Yes, current stoppages impact momentum. That’s evident. My point - if you actually read it - is about the increased impact on momentum, flow, and disruption caused by stopping the clock. I’m really not sure what your argument is here </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607309549.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>How would stopping the clock change anything though??

Look... The argument is.. everytime the ball is not in play, the clock should stop. How does that impact momentum when there already is no momentum because the ball is not in play.

Also... The 90 minute part is about addressing the arbitrary amount of stoppage time the ref adds. If the clock stops, then the game will be kept exactly at 90 mins. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607311983.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Because the clock only restarts when the ball is brought back into play doesn’t it...

Regarding your point on stoppage time, I don’t think anybody thinks this is arbitrary. But irrespective, stoppage time is a brilliant, beautiful part of football. Getting rid of it would be a real shame</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607325403.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because the clock only restarts when the ball is brought back into play doesn’t it...

Yes. Your point?

&amp;gt;Regarding your point on stoppage time, I don’t think anybody thinks this is arbitrary. But irrespective, stoppage time is a brilliant, beautiful part of football. Getting rid of it would be a real shame

Lol. People said the same thing about implementing VAR. "It's going to ruin the game".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607365079.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Not sure why this is taking so many posts to explain. 

If the clock only starts when the ball is brought back into play, then the footballers and managers (not the officials) have control over the time. They judge whether to slow things further, whether to take a drinks or tactical break, or whether to restart play. As such, if they strategically benefit from doing so, they’ll take their time. After all, play is stopped - there’s no reason to not take a break 

This cannot happen in the current footballing rules, as the referee and officials are in charge of the timing - they add the time at the end and can weight it accordingly for time wasting. This is a very good system, which works very well, and keeps the game moving relatively smoothly

It would only be a couple of seasons before they started bringing advertisement into these prolonged breaks. It would be horrifically embarrassing for the sport

I think VAR is a completely different debate, (as it has a function) and not one to have here. I’m for VAR, but there’s no doubt the effect of VAR on gameplay, rhythm, atmosphere, etc. has been hugely negative</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607379548.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>The footballers wouldn't waste time because there's a certain thing called a yellow card in the game. Players already do try to do exactly what you're saying, and the ref punishes them with a yellow card. So no.. stopping the clock wouldn't suddenly mean the players can take water breaks

&amp;gt;I think VAR is a completely different debate, (as it has a function) and not one to have here. I’m for VAR, but there’s no doubt the effect of VAR on gameplay, rhythm, atmosphere, etc. has been hugely negative

That doesn't compare to the immense positive it has had for the game</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607391766.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>To my knowledge, a referee has never booked anybody solely for disrupting the flow of the game. If the clock is stopped, they’re not wasting time. 

You’re now suggesting a whole new offence is brought in - disrupting the flow of the game. This opens a whole new realm of ambiguity, confusion and issues around timing which don’t currently exist. Where do you judge that flow has been disrupted? 

What are the benefits of all this faff? It’s clear it’ll disrupt the flow, it’s clear it’ll make the end of a match more boring, it’s clear a ninety minute match will now last upwards of say 120 minutes, but what are the benefits of doing it?

Yes VAR will have a clear positive effect on the game, as I suggested in saying I support it. It’s obvious that changing the clock has either no or negligible positives for the game and plenty of negatives and so I’m saying they’re two separate debates which it would be stupid to conflate</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607429408.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To be knowledge, a referee has never booked anybody solely for disrupting the flow of the game. If the clock is stopped, they’re not wasting time.

Lol. Really? If you're going to be difficult then there's no point in carrying on this discussion. There have been **numerous** incidents of players being booked for wasting time. It's not a new offense, it's time wasting. 

If the clock got stopped and players were trying to take water breaks, etc.. they're still wasting time. Ref could easily book them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607439498.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not talking about wasting time. Of course time wasting is an offence but if you stop the clock then it’s not time wasting is it. If the clock is stopped they’re not “still wasting time”, it’s a whole new offence. 

The ref couldn’t “easily book them” for time wasting because there’s no time being wasted. You can’t book someone for time wasting during half time, or after the match. 

How are you not getting the message

It seems you read about one word of my reply then answer with something which I address in full in the remainder of my previous post. You’re yet to give a reason or benefit for this change in timing policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607462861.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>How is it time wasting if time literally gets added? Why book a player for time wasting if you're going to add it at the end? It's the same principal.

I don't know why you're so against technology making football better. I don't know why you suddenly think they'll be adverts or 5 minute water breaks just because the ref will stop the clock for a couple of seconds</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607471939.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607489634.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607494500.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607499355.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607513821.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607523035.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607537530.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607544027.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607554994.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607555564.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/NMPire – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+NMPire&amp;amp;message=NMPire+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/-/eiqa736/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607554764.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/WRDEFC – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+WRDEFC&amp;amp;message=WRDEFC+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/-/eiq9tfn/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607527202.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>How would it avoid time wasting?

It would encourage it more. Teams that are on the back foot would intentionally cause stoppages or fouls to stop the clock and give them time to get their breath back or regroup.

At the moment teams have to balance that against the fact that they’re losing time to come back. 

All this would do would encourage losing teams to stop the clock constantly. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607537236.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>That's literally what teams do already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607574437.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>No they don’t. Why would the losing team run down the clock? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607597991.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>When a team is under intense pressure, they try to relieve it by breaking up play. And there are teams that literally start the game setting themselves up kill off the game and play for a nil nil</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607742213.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, no they don’t. Teams don’t ‘play for nill nill’, a draw doesn’t benefit you in a title race and it doesn’t benefit you in a cup championship because it results in extra time or penalties.

I’m assuming you’re referring to that tactic of parking the bus which isn’t ‘going for a nill nill’ it means you play ultra defensively forcing the opposing team to play deep into your half at which point you take back possession and then counter heavily on the break.

No team ‘plays for nill nill draws’ lmao what kind of tactic is that? You’d end up losing every cup and end up in the bottom half of the league because you’d have 0 wins.

And like I said it’s fine to break up play when you’re on the backfoot at the moment because you’re trading that off by also losing time you need to get back into the game.

With clock stoppages it would just be ‘Oh we’re on the backfoot, no worries just boot the ball out and waste a bunch of time to stop the opposing teams momentum, there’s 0 penalties for us because the clocks stopped anyway’.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607757940.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>Are you telling me now, as a football fan, that you've never heard of teams "playing for a draw"?? Really?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607577648.0" user="manchestersheedy" delta="False">
    <text>But they’re currently forced by the rules to restart play quickly.......</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607602539.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>Why would that not be the same under clock stoppages?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607721805.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>Because the clock is stopped so it won’t be classed as time wasting anymore. Even though it is because you’re allowing players to stop momentum of the other team, get their breath back and reorganise. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607753952.0" user="NMPire" delta="False">
    <text>But then does the time wasting still work now considering that the ref adds time? Commentators have even mentioned that they don't understand why teams try to "waste time" considering that it just gets addes as stoppage time.

I don't think stopping the clock would alter much. The biggest change is increasing the amount of time that the ball is actually in my play. But my argument is that the clock stopping wouldn't have to be for every moment the ball goes out of play.. just for injuries. Hence "injury time"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607807978.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>They do it because it lets the team regroup and mentally get back into the game.

If you’ve ever played a continuous sport like Football then you will understand the mentality when you’re nonstop being hammered by the others teams attacks pulling your formation out of whack. It’s what’s called momentum in football, you don’t get this in American sports because games like American football and baseball are basically turned based sports and basketball courts are too small for play to continuously play out without a reset or play due to it going out of bounds or someone scores a point.

As a defending team on the backfoot any stoppage in time is an absolute massive advantage simply because you are able to regroup your defensive formation and you take the wind out of the opposing sides attack by killing their momentum and excitement when they realise they are breaking you down and could score a goal. Clock stoppages means you can just keep killing the momentum of the game with no penalties. At the moment there is a limit to how much you can do this because you’re wasting your own chance and scoring and coming back into the game. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607312594.0" user="IAmGodMode" delta="False">
    <text>Clock stoppages in American football are used strategically and makes the game far more interesting in the final minutes IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607535832.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>It makes it more boring. Stopping the clock and using dodgy tactics to ruin the flow of the game isn’t more interesting.

It’s far more interesting in football when players who are losing know they are short on time and they have to push hard for a last ditch attempt o goal.

They can’t just boot the ball out of play and stop the clock to catch their breath and regroup and sort some tactics out while an Advert plays like in American sports. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607577899.0" user="IAmGodMode" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They can’t just boot the ball out of play and stop the clock to catch their breath and regroup and sort some tactics out while an Advert plays like in American sports.

That isn't what happens. The play clock is only 40 seconds long.

Edit, word. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608422313.0" user="vans178" delta="False">
    <text>American football for many people is unwatchable at this point, it's gotten way to commercialized and corpratised for people to be able to enjoy. Allotting 3 to 5 hours to a game that takes 60 minutes play time is just absurd. The flow of the game is too inconsistent and being bombarded with stupid commercials really has gotten away from the true feel of the sport. 

Having specific time rules that forbid soccer to be invaded with micro commercials and other nonsense like that is one of the best rules about the sport. I feel like it's lends to how much different American culture is to other countries and something we've gotten horribly wrong here. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607486969.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Except this wouldn't do any of that.

Rather than adding time for the events (pk, card, goal, sub, injury), you stop the clock and restart on the restart. This will lessen the faked injuries too and keep the flow and momentum better.

I'm really not sure how the issues you describe would even come about from such a solution.

Why? Because teams are supposed to compete for 90 minutes not 75 and then see how much of the last 15 a team can kill without letting the ball in play.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607505971.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Teams aren’t supposed to compete for ninety minutes. I have no idea where you’ve got that from? Since football began, the ball has been in play on average c.70-75 minutes per game. If footballers competed for ninety minutes each game the number of injuries and strains and increase in fatigue would be a huge burden.

As for my point it should be fairly obvious. If the ball goes out for a throw in and time is stopped, then there’s no prerogative other than strategy in timing of throw in. If it suits your team you can take a couple of minutes per throw - no time is being wasted after all 

It’s been a disaster with American football, and the capitalisation of football has been terrible for the sport to date. It’s incredibly naive to think prolonged stoppages won’t facilitate more capitalisation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607568903.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If it suits your team you can take a couple of minutes per throw - no time is being wasted after all

This is incredibly easy to make rules around. In basketball there is a clock stoppage after every basket, and the offense has 5 seconds to inbound the ball. Just implement delay of game penalties like every other sport has and I don't think that would be an issue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607582100.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Don't even worry about it.  Don't stop the clock for plays where the ref doesn't have to restart play.  Currently players waste tons of time at those points already so this point doesn't make sense as nothing there is even being proposed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607603908.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>And if you don’t bring the ball into play in five seconds? What if it’s a free kick and you’re sending the defence forward? What if there is an injury or genuine postponement?

Please explain how you’d actually implement it because I think the current system is adequate. I can’t immediately see a clear solution on it if there is a time stoppage - how long would a player have? It would have to be a different amount of time for each type of incident - which would take time to get to grips with. What’s your solution?

And even if you do find a solution on this I can’t see how the rest makes sense</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607673610.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And if you don’t bring the ball into play in five seconds? 

Then the ref blows his whistle and possession changes to the other team. 

&amp;gt;What if it’s a free kick and you’re sending the defence forward?

I'm sorry, I don't follow soccer closely, I don't know what this question is asking. 

&amp;gt;What if there is an injury or genuine postponement?

Then at the referees discretion there is no compulsion to restart the game until the referee says it's time. 



Essentially I don't think that soccer would be ruined at all by implementing a stopping clock. All of your objections could be figured out if a group sat down and decided it needed to change. I also don't think it needs to change. Sports rules are generally fairly arbitrary, and are kept the same mostly for the sake of tradition. 

It's pretty inconsequential whether or not the clock stops in soccer. There aren't a lot of benefits to changing it, because the goal would be to change it while keeping the pace of the game the same, so what's the point. I'm just saying you could probably figure out how to implement a stopping clock without changing the pace of the game. 

The objections should be around tradition and the difficulty of changing the rules across the worlds hundreds of soccer leagues, and what sort of weird stuff happens if say the premiere league changes but the Bundesliga doesn't and then the face eachother in the champions league. 


Saying that the rule changes would somehow ruin the game by virtue of what they actually do just seems fallacious to me. The other arguments are better. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607702403.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>See that first sentence has answered it. Imagine if you’re about to take your free kick, in your own box, but through a disruption to the game you take it in the sixth second. As a result, the opposition has an indirect free kick in your box. Yeah - that’d go down well with fans and teams! Come on, you can’t pretend that’s an appropriate rule. 

There are literally hundreds of different scenarios in which the game is stopped, each of which would demand a different period of time for the ball to return to play. Even the world’slongest rule book wouldnt adequately recognise each of these.

The only other point I’ll make is that it isn’t inconsequential and it wouldn’t be easy to sit down and work out rules. That’s why it’s not been done. There aren’t many benefits you’re right but adding a stopped clock would be incredibly consequential for football - it would fuck the game up completely in numerous ways discussed in this thread.

It’s not a question of tradition, it’s simply a far, far better sport as it is now. The focus absolutely has to be on what the change would mean for the game, not tradition or other arguments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607754449.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but through a disruption to the game you take it in the sixth second

First off, 5 seconds was just an arbitrary amount because that's how long you have in basketball. Second, I don't know what a disruption to the game would be? If the ref decides that the delay is due to an intention by the kicking team to delay the game then an appropriate penalty is assessed.


&amp;gt;It’s not a question of tradition, it’s simply a far, far better sport as it is now.

You're literally appealing to tradition. You don't know that, because you don't even know what the new rules would be. They might make the game better. Who knows? Not me, not you. The reason they don't change is because the game is good *enough* right now, not because it is perfect. 


And it's fine to appeal to tradition! Half of the fun of sports is tradition! Sports are goofy, arbitrary fun! I have no doubt that the uproar among soccer fans worldwide would be considerable if there were a change, because it would be messing with tradition. 


But claiming that some set of rules are *objectively* better in such a subjective environment? Pish posh. It's all subjective. Rugby has waaaaaaay different rules from soccer, and lots of people love watching that. Hockey has waaaaaaay different rules from soccer, and people love watching that. I would wager literally any amount of money that if we lived in some alternate universe where soccer had always been a precisely timed game with clock stoppages and somebody said "hey, how about we just let the clock run for 45 mins a half, then at the end of the half the ref just tacks on however much time he thinks has been wasted during the half, and then he blows the whistle after that amount of time" you'd be vehemently opposed to that rule change too. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607831806.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>But that’s why I asked for your solution, not just an arbitrary number. The point is that there is no set time which can be applied across the board. Certain situations would demand ten seconds, others one minute, others more. There’s no rule which covers this adequately.

It’s obvious what a disruption to a game would be - anything which interrupts the game whether it’s a player down, a player tying his laces, a second ball on a pitch, a player in an illegal position, a non-player on the pitch. 

I’m not appealing to tradition - I wanted VAR, I wanted a fourth substitution in extra time, I want all change that benefits the game without reducing its flow, momentum, match atmosphere etc. to a horrific extent. I struggle to see how you think I may be appealing to tradition here.

You say “who knows, not me not you” like this is a novel debate no one has discussed. The FA have held multiple meetings around this, premiership clubs have discussed it, I’ve spent hours in pubs discussing this. We do know it doesn’t work, we’ve looked for savvy solutions and there isn’t one - that’s why it’s not been introduced. Football isn’t steeped in conservative practices and maintenance of tradition. It’s a progressive sport. 

I don’t think it is a subjective debate at all. Football itself is subjective and arbitrary. However what makes football good or exciting isn’t exactly subjective - it’s contained within the definition of football. As such, while the object is subjective, what makes the object as is isn’t subjective - it’s objective (unless you go down some blind nineties social constructivist alley). 

I think that because - as you say - you don’t watch football or understand it too well it’s difficult for you to recognise that 1) there is no beneficial rule which can be introduced and 2) what makes football great is objectively agreed upon </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607579545.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Teams are supposed to compete for 90 minutes of player controlled time.  There's disagreement among refs if you're supposed to add time for when you stop a free kick to march off 10 or not but its 100% supposed to be 90 minutes of competition. 

Refs are taught to leave the clock running because its a bigger issue to forget to restart.  You wouldn't stop it for throw ins and no one suggested that.  Only that for items which get added time you instead stop the clock.

If it suits your team you could do that now but now you're being grossly disingenuous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607616677.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Where are you getting this from? Every piece of analysis of game time in football has it at c. 70-75 minutes per match. Making players play for ninety minutes would be fun for fans but utter madness for the players.

There’s no sense in stopping the clock for only some incidents, like goals and penalties, but not for others, like free kicks or throw ins. It would be madness to do it selectively since then you’re not solving any problem whatsoever (not that adding a time stoppage does solve a problem) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607632215.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Teams are supposed to compete for 90 minutes of player controlled time. 

&amp;gt;Every piece of analysis of game time in football has it at c. 70-75 minutes per match. Making players play for ninety minutes would be fun for fans but utter madness for the players.

These two things are not in contradiction.

&amp;gt;There’s no sense in stopping the clock for only some incidents, like goals and penalties, but not for others, like free kicks or throw ins.

You already do that you know.  That's what the added time is supposed to address... Specifically its supposed to address whenever the players are not allowed to play the ball... That's what 90 minutes of player controlled time means.  If the players can play the ball the clock is running.  If the ref is stopping the play of the ball, the clock does not run.  

Again, the ref is supposed to be adding time for the latter events only and always.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607660841.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>I get that, but this adds no benefit and only detriment so assumed you’re addressing the question of stoppages for all incidents. What reason is there for introducing stopped time for only these incidents?

All it does it remove injury time, which would be a bad thing, and add additional delays or prolonged delays in play, which is a bad thing. WhT are the supposed benefits?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607704704.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What reason is there for introducing stopped time for only these incidents?

&amp;gt;All it does it remove injury time, which would be a bad thing, and add additional delays or prolonged delays in play, which is a bad thing. WhT are the supposed benefits?

You're moving the stoppage time from at the end of the match to the point at which the stoppage occurs.  Lets say a guy goes down in the 78th minute and stays down for (2) minutes and (1) minute of stoppage time is added to the end...  Play resumes at the 80th minute and runs through 91

You've now lost (1) minute of potential play.  That's bad.  

Instead you'd stop the clock at the 78th and restart it when play resumes, still at the 78th.  You still have 90 minutes of potential play and no time has been lost.  This means at the end when players are going down to waste time, they cannot waste time in this manner.  That is good for the game and for competition.

You stop time for only these incidents because the laws are about 90 minutes of player controlled time so all that you care about removing are the non-player controlled (aka referee controlled) aspects.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607718886.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t matter where it’s “moved” - it’s stoppage time, it’s just a continuity of normal time. It makes zero difference “where” it occurs.

The point you make about lost play is incorrect - you may lose some time, you may gain some time, you may have exactly the right amount of time but either way it’s not a problem it’s a fundamental part of the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607739561.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>You're right, it doesn't matter where it occurs. The issue is time is almost always lost and it's lost at the end when play is most frantic. That's a bad thing. 

And losing time to enable stalling doesn't have to be a part of the game, ESPECIALLY since the referee is supposed to prevent that from happening. The argument you're making is the ref not doing their job is a part of the game... No the ref is not supposed to affect the game, the players affect the game and the ref ensures the rules, including the play time, are followed.

There's nothing fundamental about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607861764.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Would be good to see the research on time lost -  please do share as it would be good to see how much time is lost. We can discuss in detail once I’ve read through the statistics. 

You keep persisting with the idea that time is lost in places - it’s not lost at the end, time is continuous the logic is surreal. 

Certainly don’t think you’ve said anything which suggests it would be useful to introduce stopped time! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607895278.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You keep persisting with the idea that time is lost in places - it’s not lost at the end, time is continuous the logic is surreal. 

What?  

&amp;gt;  Certainly don’t think you’ve said anything which suggests it would be useful to introduce stopped time! 

Huh???

[Here's some numbers for you](https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/world-cup-stoppage-time-is-wildly-inaccurate/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607927594.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting article but I’m not sure you’ve read it? 

I’m talking about stoppages of the nature you are discussing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607967682.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Interesting article but I’m not sure you’ve read it?

I have, that's why I bring it up, it supports everything I'm saying

&amp;gt; I’m talking about stoppages of the nature you are discussing

huh?

 - Regarding purely whistle stoppages - 

&amp;gt;For our purposes, these were the easiest chunks of dead-ball time to tally. This number gave us a base stoppage. And it’s worth noting that these actions alone averaged almost five minutes more than the average added time allotted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608805435.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>There’s no split of only the stoppages you’re referring to, and no information on the inconsistency of them 

An average of five minutes means nothing - if they’re all c. five then this isn’t an issue, but until we see some data we don’t know</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608865360.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Yes there is, the quoted paragraph is over exactly that.

An average of 5 minutes means nothing? Then call the game at 85... But it's not always 5 and goes up and down.

I provided data and still you say no data... I'm no longer even sure what you're talking about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608881064.0" user="WRDEFC" delta="False">
    <text>I’m aware - hence my post. An average doesn’t mean anything in this discussion no.

If it’s always five minutes off then that’s fine, and five of the c. twenty minutes of natural reduction in game time expected in each match. Making each game five minutes longer would be silly.

I think your initial point was about inconsistency rather than consistency though - so yes if you have statistics that show the inconsistency then that could be interesting but like I said nothing in your article does that - hence why I asked whether you’d read it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608929861.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>An average means that there is inconsistencies and the article highlights the high and low differences.

The purpose is to provide a more consistent result and more accurate result and saying that you can burn more time off the clock by exaggerating an injury creates a less consistent on field product. Some matches have 90 minutes of ball availability some have 80... That's not a good thing.

You're saying that you cannot look at the results or almost exact data therefore there is nothing to discuss.

It's pretty simple.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
