<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607290409.0" user="raiderGM" delta="False">
    <text>The way time is handled in soccer is wildly different than American football and basketball and, once I came to appreciate it, I wish both sports were more like soccer, especially basketball.  

Clock stoppage leads to "clock management," the attention-killing use of timeouts and out-of-bounds maneuvers to make the game longer (or the boring use of "stay in bounds" plays to keep the clock running). These things aren't more exciting in any way.  Players know that the time on the clock is the time they have, +somewhere less than 5 minutes, usually. I'm not a huge soccer watcher either, but I've never seen Stoppage Time added more than 5 minutes, which isn't a lot when the clock doesn't stop.

Wouldn't soccer begin to evolve the Foul Em method of "'clock management" which is prevalent in basketball?  Ugh, it is nothing for soccer to emulate.  

Finally, the number one reason to appreciate the running clock in soccer is NO COMMERCIAL BREAKS.  Without commercials, the fans focus on the game, and can appreciate its pace and nuance, the way one player has advantage over his rival.  The game, at first, seems boring because there is so little scoring, but as you watch, you may pick up that there are "unscored scores:"  successful passes, corners won, well-played balls to the wing, control of 50/50 balls. These things typically lead to scores and wins--though not always, for there is always the chance that a team will break out and make a play.  You can meet your friend for the game and you are in and out of the pub in under 2 hours, guaranteed.  

Imagine if basketball minimized clock stopping.  Teams that were down would NOT call timeout (because the time wouldn't actually stop; you want to talk to your players for 30 seconds?  It costs you 30 seconds off the clock), would NOT want to foul. Coaches would be minimized in-game and players would have to make plays.  You would be watching BASKETBALL, not committee meetings with commentary.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607437087.0" user="SilverPhoxx" delta="False">
    <text>Your first point is the biggest one I think. Time wasting in soccer is irritating, but the last few minutes of a basketball game are nigh unwatchable. Especially given that soccer players could just boot it out of bounds as soon as they get a foot to it. It’d be equally if not more frustrating but in a different way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608071923.0" user="Cuntractor" delta="False">
    <text>I think hockey has the best clock format in pretty much any major sport. For example, if you hit the pick into the crowd intentionally from your own zone you'll get a 2-minute minor penalty giving the other team a 4-on-5 advantage. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607445704.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Every issue you describe would be lessened by this. The biggest clock management right now is "injuries." but if there's a stoppage for the injury, then you can't waste 30-60 s after a foul. You get the same slowing play after the ball leaves play and that's fine.

You'd also know how much time is left and there would still be no timeouts or commercials because you are just pausing the clock while play is stopped and what this would do is add probably 3 minutes per half but would be consistent now.

You absolutely wouldn't be watching basketball</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607801619.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>Faking an injury is not biggest time wasting tactic. The majority of the time the referee adds additional time onto the stated stoppage time if there is a stoppage for injury. 

The biggest time wasting tactics would include making last minute subs, taking an age to take free kicks and goal kicks. There is also the classics...row Z, corner flag etc. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607830557.0" user="meco03211" delta="False">
    <text>Do they add stoppage time for free kicks and goal kicks? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607842995.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>Not usually as this is seen to be active time. However, if a player is deemed to be taking to long the referee can issue a yellow card and the time wasted should be added into the stoppage time. They will also add time on for injuries, goals (which is usually due to excessively long celebrations), substitutions, penalties or any other stop in the game that is not considered active playing time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607838776.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>And subs would also result in no time wasted along with free kicks post injury and injuries.  As for wasting time at the kick, the ref can currently control that and should do a better job oftentimes. 

Killing time in the corner is legal and row z doesn't do much anymore in professional cause there are spare balls around the pitch.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607876960.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>Time for substitutions is already added to the stoppage time so in reality the time "wasted" during substitutions is accounted for. IIRC 30 secs per sub is added on. Likewise time is also added on for injuries.

You say row z etc are legal tactics and that is true, but so is taking the maximum allowable time to take a goal kick or corner etc. There is time allocated within the rules for restarting play, and is still considered active playing time. 

Also, smashing the ball into row z does eat up the clock in most cases. Certain competitions do use the multi-ball system, but certainly not the majority of competitions, especially when you consider smaller leagues and not just world cups and the likes of EPL, la liga etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607910121.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Time for substitutions is already added to the stoppage time so in reality the time "wasted" during substitutions is accounted for. IIRC 30 secs per sub is added on. Likewise time is also added on for injuries.

Gotcha, so you do an activity which takes 60+ seconds and add 30...  That is wasted and lost time.

&amp;gt;You say row z etc are legal tactics and that is true, but so is taking the maximum allowable time to take a goal kick or corner etc. There is time allocated within the rules for restarting play, and is still considered active playing time. 

And no one said that wasn't acceptable or we were changing that.  You can still use the legal amount of time and the ball is still considered available for play....

And many to most leagues have moved to a multi-ball system.  We've been using one as low as U-14 near me.  The ref identifies all game balls at the beginning and puts them at the appropriate spots... When a ball gets lost or launched a new one is thrown into play.  It almost eliminates the problem you describe.

[Here's some numbers](https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/world-cup-stoppage-time-is-wildly-inaccurate/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608014288.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>Its funny that you state the average time of a substitution is 60+ secs, when the source that you provided states the average time taken for subs in a game (in one specific competition, may I add) is 3 minutes. Assuming each team makes 3 subs which is true in most games, that's 30 seconds per sub. So it would seem that the source you provided actually proved my point.....so thanks for that.

I dont know where about you live, but certainly where I live its not the case. Its not even used in the top pro league. On top of that, what you described is not the multi-ball system. The multi-ball system is where a new ball is provided to a player immediately when the ball goes out for a throw, goal kick etc. 

Obviously when a ball is "lost or launched"  a new ball is provided.....what did you think happened? Do you expect the ball boy to run out of the stadium or up to row Z to retrieve the ball every time?

Additionally, regarding the row Z tactic. If the ball is launched into the set of fans of the team trying to waste time, it is pretty common for the following situation to happen: ball goes into crowd, crowd keeps ball, new ball is provided to restart play, play restarts, old ball gets chucked onto pitch, play stopped as there is two balls in play. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608056473.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The multi-ball system is where a new ball is provided to a player immediately when the ball goes out for a throw, goal kick etc. 

There are many ways to implement depending on available staff.  You can have the ball provided or have one behind each goal and a few along each sideline.  

But regardless, you're trying to nit pick an incredibly minor point when it can most easily be summarized with a single quote:  

&amp;gt;For our purposes, these were the easiest chunks of dead-ball time to tally. This number gave us a base stoppage. And it’s worth noting that these actions alone averaged almost five minutes more than the average added time allotted.

If you want to argue about one competition or this or that minor point, go for it, but in the end the refs are doing a piss job of adding appropriate time for the known stoppages and accounting for the stoppages at the time they occur would ensure they do a proper job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608111409.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>1. The article you cited is written for American fans, as clearly indicated by the use of "soccer". The reality is that most fans outside america (so its fair to say the majority of fans around the world) dont really care if the stoppage time isnt bang on or not. Its pretty easy to estimate how much time will be added on, which means that there is a general consensus between fans, players and referees as to what an appropriate amount is. It does not matter that some American journalists decided to add up their own idea of what time should be added on and compared it to what the rest of the world is doing.

As well as this, in the source provided they have included instances where it is still considered active playing time within the rules of the game, so their "results" are effectively useless. 

Now, if the clock had stopped each instance your source deemed as wasted time, the game would take forever and no flow would be allowed to develop. It would make for a terrible game to watch. 

The bottom line is this. Almost all fans of football would agree that there is nothing majorly wrong with the way time is managed in football, so why change it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608146470.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>1)  Doesn't matter who its written for its a problem which directly affects the quality of the game.  Its pretty easy to estimate but its being done wrong and your argument is we've learned to tolerate it being done wrong... GOOD JOB!  

&amp;gt;so their "results" are effectively useless. 

Not in the least, they even clarified multiple different levels of the issue.

&amp;gt;Now, if the clock had stopped each instance your source deemed as wasted time, the game would take forever and no flow would be allowed to develop. It would make for a terrible game to watch. 

No it wouldn't, they told you exactly how much time it would add.  The flow would be the exact same as it currently is, only it would have more run time to address the increased stoppages...

&amp;gt;Almost all fans of football would agree that there is nothing majorly wrong with the way time is managed in football, so why change it? 

I disagree.  Many recognize the issue and that it can be fixed...  There's nothing majorly wrong w/ not having VAR but it makes a better and more accurate product and cleans up an on field issue so the players decide the result not the refs.

Why make things better when we've learned to tolerate something?  Great point!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608183683.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>It doesnt directly affect the quality of the game. Its just how the game is played. Increasing the amount of stoppages in a game would directly effect the game. 

Also, how can you say in the same sentence that the flow would be unaffected but also acknowledged that there would be an increase in stoppages. The more stoppages, the less flow the game will have and the more frustrating it will be to watch the game.  

Its become clear that I will not change your opinion on this matter, and im not going to waste my time trying. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608194332.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Increasing the amount of stoppages in a game would directly effect the game. 

Except you're not doing that at all.  You're ensuring the correct amount of stoppage time from the current stoppages is accounted for.

&amp;gt;that there would be an increase in stoppages. 

WHAT STOPPAGES ARE BEING CREATED?

&amp;gt;Its become clear that I will not change your opinion on this matter, and im not going to waste my time trying. 

That's because your argument makes no sense.  You're misrepresenting what is going on and creating your own strawman throughout as illustrated by stating we are increasing the quantity of stoppages when that is clearly not the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608205660.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>This whole thread is about the idea of stopping the clock instead of adding on time. Thats what the topic is. 

What you are saying is a completely different topic.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608231562.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>No, if you stop the clock you're not increasing stoppages of play!

If the end time correct amount of time was added it would make no difference but because the refs seem incapable of adding the appropriate stoppage time you would instead stop the clock to ensure the correct result is reached.

Your entire point is nonsensical...  Whether I add the correct time at the end or in the middle is irrelevant so your point over increased stoppages affecting the game is absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608265814.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>Ok. 

A team is on the break and they win a throw. Normally the attacking team would like to take a quick throw, but this in all likelihood not be possible in your set up. The ref would not allow it, because he would of stopped his watch, and would pull the play back to retake the throw. Its not required, would add nothing to the game, and disrupt play. It would also give the referee yet another thing to consider throughout the game. 

The reason its never changed, or serious discussions of changing it is because very little people are unsatisfied with how the system currently operates. 

Now im done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608274936.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The ref would not allow it, because he would of stopped his watch, and would pull the play back to retake the throw. Its not required, would add nothing to the game, and disrupt play. It would also give the referee yet another thing to consider throughout the game. 

NOTHING IN ANYTHING SAID INSINUATES THIS.

This is the exact strawman in question.  You're making things up to be right against a point no one is making.  What you say would be bad, which is why no one wants that.

Good job being done and having tilted at your windmills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607546107.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Wouldn't soccer begin to evolve the Foul Em method of "'clock management" which is prevalent in basketball? Ugh, it is nothing for soccer to emulate.

The reason the foul method is used it basketball is because it guarantees a quick change of possession after the free throws. If you're down a handful of points with 2 minutes to go, you can't afford to have the other team using the full shot clock before getting their points. You foul in order to limit their points per possession to 2, and to allow their possessions to only be a few seconds, giving you more opportunities to make 3 pointers, and hope they miss some of their free throws if you're able to foul their worse shooters. 


This wouldn't happen in soccer, because a foul doesn't cause a change possession. The fouled team gets the ball right back, and generally get it back in a more advantageous position than they had prior to the foul because they get a free kick. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607751472.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>They don’t get it in a more advantageous position  at all if it is an attack on the break. That is because when there is a stop of play the defending team has time to bring all their players back behind the ball to defend.

It’s why fouling the last man in a goal scoring chance is an instant red card in football. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608275387.0" user="acosmichippo" delta="False">
    <text>basketball has similar rules for fast breaks.  when a player has a “clear path” to the basket and is fouled they get two free throws and the ball back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607547132.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>I agree about the basketball thing, but there are discussions about that as well. But I don’t think you’re incentivized to foul in soccer because 1) you can get ejected for one bad foul 2) the referee is not required to whistle every foul (continuation) and 3) fouling does not come with a high likelihood of gaining possession of the ball because free kicks are different than free throws.

I’ll address the other stuff shortly- gotta go do wedding planning stuff :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607771375.0" user="TheNesquick" delta="False">
    <text>Lol not incentivized to foul? Do you even watch soccer. Professionel freekicks happens Im every game to stop chances from evolving. Players foul good players all the time when they get the ball. The plan from the start is to foul players like Messi as soon as he gets the ball. 

Players even foul to get carded i.e Sergio Ramos in the first game against Ajax. You argue like you have never watched a game before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607790712.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe but you’re not incentivized to foul to regain possession like you are in basketball.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607813356.0" user="TheNesquick" delta="False">
    <text>Still the reason why soccer is so popular is because you only need some guys/girls and a ball to play. It doesn’t matter if you are playing the Champions league final or on a street in Rio. The game is simple yet so complicated and fun. What you want is to make it more complicated and change how it works om different levels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608490861.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>How is stopping the clock any more complicated than tracking and calculating stoppage time? If we’re talking about the game on the street in Rio or in a city park, they’re probably not keeping stoppage time anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609062855.0" user="Kitititirokiting" delta="False">
    <text>His point was a major cup final won’t be the same as some kids playing in the street, because of the reasons everyone’s outlined. If a game with your mates isn’t the same as what you watch on TV or go to see at a stadium it’s just not as fun. Especially so if the difference is making plays more boring and drawn out</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607890586.0" user="icyDinosaur" delta="False">
    <text>No, but to reassemble. Tactical fouls are a thing in football.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608483460.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>I’m curious to hear more about this, actually- how would this be different without the concept of stoppage time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609443052.0" user="BluEtsitra" delta="False">
    <text>Intentional fouls, as it is, are only a small proportion of the fouls committed in a game. For example, you see it when a player on team A is played through, and a player on team B catches up to foul him (pull him by his shirt or bumps him off the ball), in order to prevent a chance on goal. It's a last ditch effort to prevent a shot; other times, fouls are accidental from a challenge or tackle. This takes time off the clock as it is, and unless you're very ahead in the game, the time running out does not hurt team A more than it hurts team B; when you are 0-0, you obviously want more time to get a goal, and even if you're 1-0 up, you'd generally prefer attacking evenly to widen the lead.

Without stoppage time, these fouls can become more rampant. You'd probably see any slightly challenging defenses, like a 3 on 2 or a player running down the wing involve an intentional foul - with the time stopped, you can potentially discard defending with real-time positioning and ability, and instead go to a prepared defensive formation against the set-piece every time. If the skills allow, you'd probably be more comfortable defending a set-piece than defending against a crafty attacking player. Who is to say the manager cannot bombard the team in training to defend set-pieces and simply make that a major strategy in game? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607808265.0" user="looking_for_fat_cure" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But I don’t think you’re incentivized to foul in soccer because

Google Neymar fouls. Then come here again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608172671.0" user="Sharcbait" delta="False">
    <text>In basketball you can get ejected for 1 bad foul. You can also get ejected for too many fouls in 1 game. It is probably the sport where fouling is the most incentivized, there are whole game plans around fouling. Hack-a-Shaq was TOO GOOD that they needed to change the rules and it still isn't really fixed. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608219027.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not saying it’s a perfect system in basketball, either. But the foul limit discourages fouling to an extent, and I think that it’s a hard issue to address- foul shooting is a legit part of the game, and adding more penalties for end-of-game fouling when behind raises the question, where do you draw the line at the edge of playing more risky, aggressive defense? 

This isn’t really part of the discussion but I saw an interesting proposal for the end of a basketball game- the game ends when either team reaches a score equal to the leading score plus two points after the game time ends. One basket (or two foul shots). If the trailing team goes on a run and gets there first, they win. Maybe not practical but interesting nonetheless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607629049.0" user="pantaloonsofJUSTICE" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, instead of Foul Em, soccer has Kick It Outta Bounds and the lovely Goalie Sits For Half A Minute With The Ball. Gaming the fact that the clock is running is no more pure than gaming the fact it stopped. When you're up in a match you just waste time doing every dead-ball activity slower. 

Basketball, by the way, requires that you have a complete team that can shoot free throws and inbound the ball under pressure. In soccer once stoppage gets announced you can have an Oscar-worthy performance of an injury take the entire extra time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607834773.0" user="Slapbox" delta="False">
    <text>You've thoroughly changed my view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608169169.0" user="Hamsternoir" delta="False">
    <text>There are no commercials in other sports like rugby or Aussie football. The clock is stopped. It all works fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608300051.0" user="acosmichippo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imagine if basketball minimized clock stopping.  Teams that were down would NOT call timeout (because the time wouldn't actually stop; you want to talk to your players for 30 seconds?  It costs you 30 seconds off the clock), would NOT want to foul. Coaches would be minimized in-game and players would have to make plays.  You would be watching BASKETBALL, not committee meetings with commentary.

In basketball, half the team doesn’t get to chill while the ball is on the other side of the field - all 10 players are nearly 100% engaged when the clock is running.

So without stoppages for rest, it would slow the game down severely.  The basketball itself would be much less exciting.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31611162913.0" user="XtremeGoose" delta="False">
    <text>Counter point: Rugby Union

Rugby is played much like soccer but has the clock stopped for significant stoppages. It still doesn't have commercial breaks in the game and it runs fine. The referee runs the game and says when the game restarts. As far as I'm aware there have been no cases of malicious "time management".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
