<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607277355.0" user="xiaodre" delta="False">
    <text>i see timekeeping as an artifact of the history of association football.


we really don't know if changes like what you are asking for will or will never come.  they may (a national professional league would have to demonstrate it, and its usefulness for it to be considered tho).  we just don't know what the future holds, right?


that said, there are several problems with your solution that the timekeeping as it is now make into non-issues.


if there is an attack going on, and the defending team is desperate to get players back, or back into position, they can try to foul, or they can foul or dive away from the play, just to stop play (its why i cannot watch the italian league, its too exasperating).  if the referee sees this as not being relevant to the play on the ball, he will call continuation.


these things happen all the time, and so continuation happens all the time.


its almost like a free play in american football when the defense lines up offsides.  but with continuation, timekeeping becomes really hard and interferes with the game.  it would become a delay in itself, with time being piled back onto the clock after consultations between the referee and the 4th referee (timekeeper).


there's something else, too - the underlying issue with these considerations is that, compared to almost every other sport, scoring in soccer is rare.  much rarer than even hockey, which is also pretty rare.  and even with an attacking team with breakaways and numbers of people.  the defending team, tired at the end of the half, really only has to clear their third for the referee to call an end to the match (this is the its not that big of a deal argument, which is a weak argument, i admit).


point 2: we, the fans, know that unless its overtime in a special circumstance (special matches that cannot be draws), we can allot 2 hours for a match, and its done in 2 hours.  we can go on about the day.  none of this 3.5 hours.  no commercial breaks because some multinational corporation has paid whtever millions of dollars to buy your eyeballs from the league.  no replaying this or making the game slow down to a crawl in the last 2 minutes, or making the last 24 seconds drawn out to 20 minutes of real time, with 3 commercial breaks.  the flow of the game is the flow, without the abuse of the rules to create an artificial way for a team to possibly tie or win (i'm looking at you, basketball, and your stupid 1 and 1 in the penalty foul rules for clock "management")


2 hours.  that's it.  i appreciate that, and i don't think i am alone in that.


EDIT:  Sorry!  forgot to add, time wasting is a violation.  it normally results in a card, which can be a big deal..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607469755.0" user="austhyma" delta="False">
    <text>I record NBA games with my streaming service and I looked and here are the following time lengths of the games in hh:mm. 2:30, 2:21, 2:31, 2:49, 2:30, 2:30. Seems like there's some consistency there. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607653357.0" user="xiaodre" delta="False">
    <text>we can break it down, right?


lowest amount of time 141 minutes.


most amount of time 169 minutes.


a variance of 17%.  that's quite a bit, but its an opinion, and that's nothing to hang my hat on.


here's the kicker for me: all of these games run past 2 hours.  well past.  but the game time itself is 60 minutes.  when you chop it up like that, what you have is an interruption in the flow of the game.


soccer is not that.  it is supposed to flow back and forth, not be interrupted for easily digestible chunks, strategy meetings with the coach and commercials.  its just the kind of game it is.


my thing is, a change has to mean something, or why do it?  there were issues with people scoring goals and the referee and the linesmen not seeing it.  THAT was taking away from the game.  people were getting pissed, and i admit, i was one of those people.  


so now they have goal line technology.  that's an important change.  this change?  its not important.  so why do it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609624262.0" user="austhyma" delta="False">
    <text>Variance is usually calculated as the difference from the mean, not from the two most extreme ends. That brings the variance down to only as much as 13%. 

The games run past 2 hours and the game is actually 48 minutes in the NBA :)

To your other points, I want to restate what you're saying a little: I think change should be solving an identifiable problem with the game. That to me is what "means something". The problem that timed games would attempt to solve is low scoring, low speed games. 

I want to elaborate more on that problem, too. Take for example the Spanish in the world cup this last year. I can't remember the exact game, but I remember watching a game where they completed 700 passes. In spite of this efficiency, they still lost. They managed to make the game incredibly boring and it wasn't even a strategy that paid off. Now imagine if games ended with an average of 5 or more goals scored per match. Would that be more or less exciting in your opinion? 

I think we could both admit that a game where teams are scoring more is more exciting than watching 700 passes completed. 

Eliminating stoppage time I think is an effective way to get to a point where soccer teams score more. 

Teams would have a better chance to orchestrate plays for scoring, and they'd be fresher which would lead to faster pace. Every minute played would be pure soccer action and not a bunch of dicking around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31610962914.0" user="jrob321" delta="False">
    <text>In most instances, a hotly contested 0-0 tie is far more exciting than a 5-0 rout. 

The fact that it's so impossibly difficult to get the ball to pass inside an 8' x 24' goal area when played at the professional level - despite the passing and shooting creativity employed by such incredibly gifted athletes - makes football/soccer the exciting sport that it is. 

Watching Everton lose 1-0 to Liverpool in the 96th minute this year - after playing a far superior team level for the entire match - was more exciting (and heartbreaking) than any other sport I can imagine. 

And watching the clock tick up to 90:00 and wondering just how much longer they would have to play given all the stoppage time that occurred in the second half - only added to the excitement. The minimum of 4 minutes added created such tension to the end of the game, and that tension was subsequently punctuated by the clock ticking past 94:00 as more stoppage time occurred during the minimum.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607475426.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>None of the items you described would be affected by this change. The only change would be fewer rolling on the ground wasting time "injuries" cause you can't waste time like that anymore.

Id say that the clock should stop for any play waiting on the ref to restart play. That is goals, subs, cards, injuries, pks. Some leagues officially stop for VAR and it would be the same. Some refs stop it for a bad injury too. Just expand this behavior and now you get 90 minutes of football rather than 90ish</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607595204.0" user="xiaodre" delta="False">
    <text>well, the change would not affect much of anything, including rolling on the ground.  remember, its continuation.  the only thing it would affect would be after a continuation play, if the play does not result in a goal, then the referee and the 4th referee have to consult and add some time back to the clock.  of course, this consultation takes time too (since they re both in charge of keeping the clock).


then, after every "judgement call" by the referee, he has to consult with the 4th referee to add time back to the clock.  which takes time.


you still have 90ish minutes.  its the same.  its just added back in increments, instead of what we have now - one consultation between the referee and the 4th referee at the end of the half.


so why do it?


well, the op is clear: to gain more fans, especially in america.  does this add to the game?  its not clear to me that it does.  in any way.  the only way a clock stoppage would add is that there is a chance for advertisers to advertise.  is this what is stopping soccer in america from becoming as big as american football, basketball, and baseball, which all have these stopwatch clocks?  commercial success?


i seem to recall that soccer is an incredibly popular sport in america among people, and has been for decades..  if you are looking for commercial success, you can have that change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607619319.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;well, the change would not affect much of anything, including rolling on the ground. remember, its continuation. the only thing it would affect would be after a continuation play

No, if you allow continuation you run the game until the ball goes out of bounds.  In soccer continuation is supposed to be 3s to decide.  No need to consult a clock for anything either.  

No need to do anything for any of your judgement calls...  Does the ref blow the whistle and prevent play from restarting until he gives the whistle to restart?  Yes?  Then the clock stops until he signals it can restart.

So why do it?  Because it would 1) clean up the time wasting in the last 15 minutes of the game.  Now that injury which rolls for 2 minutes and gets 30s added time earning your team 90s killed doesn't earn anything and if you roll and a medic comes out and you are forced to step off the field, your team is down a man without anything.

It removes a lot of subjectivity over the ref and a point of contention about time wasted as well.  Do you think that removing this time wasting creates a better product?  I 100% think it does.

&amp;gt;i seem to recall that soccer is an incredibly popular sport in america among people, and has been for decades.. if you are looking for commercial success, you can have that change.

Huh?  One of the biggest detriments in America is actually the "injuries" and people also regularly complain about the silliness of the clock.  This eliminates both issues while providing a more transparent product to the fans and teams.

This idea that its going to lead to commercials and be complicated is really disingenuous. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607833186.0" user="xiaodre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No, if you allow continuation you run the game until the ball goes out of bounds. In soccer continuation is supposed to be 3s to decide. No need to consult a clock for anything either.

&amp;gt;No need to do anything for any of your judgement calls... Does the ref blow the whistle and prevent play from restarting until he gives the whistle to restart? Yes? Then the clock stops until he signals it can restart.

&amp;gt;So why do it? Because it would 1) clean up the time wasting in the last 15 minutes of the game. Now that injury which rolls for 2 minutes and gets 30s added time earning your team 90s killed doesn't earn anything and if you roll and a medic comes out and you are forced to step off the field, your team is down a man without anything.

&amp;gt;It removes a lot of subjectivity over the ref and a point of contention about time wasted as well. Do you think that removing this time wasting creates a better product? I 100% think it does.


So as far as I understand you, you are thinking that players are already getting away with quite a bit of wasting time, especially in the last 15 minutes of each half, and that this would stop that.  But the 4th referee is already supposed to keep track of those stoppages, and then tell the referee at the end of the half.  The referee then adds on his judgement calls (which, as far as I know, he cannot take away time from what the 4th referee has added up).


The change as I imagine it is to keep track incrementally instead of at the end of the half.  okay.  fine.  But your claim is counterfactual, it'll have to be proven in a league.  I have my doubts that it changes anything.  I mean, you are talking like an additional 10 minutes instead of 4 minutes, right?  And the problem is these are just opinions, so we can argue back and forth like this all day.


The "injuries" are supposed to be accounted for.  This is the first I have heard about or seen posted about the silliness of the clock, but I am used to the european rules since i was a kid.


The idea that companies do not want to find ways to put more advertisements into soccer matches is disingenuous?  That breaks in the flow of the game is one such way?  That stopping the clock is literally the first hurdle to that?  I assure you, it is genuine.


I don't think its complicated though, not sure where you are getting that.  Just slower in real time than it currently is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607890319.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But the 4th referee is already supposed to keep track of those stoppages, and then tell the referee at the end of the half. The referee then adds on his judgement calls (which, as far as I know, he cannot take away time from what the 4th referee has added up).

Correct, he's supposed to but what they typically do is +30 for a goal or card and +60 for a sub and medical injury.  This tends to be far less time than actual stoppage and while we've seen them start doing better with stoppages, the amount in the 2nd half which should be 6+ minutes is most every match.

&amp;gt; I mean, you are talking like an additional 10 minutes instead of 4 minutes, right? 

Yes.  Next match you watch, add up the time the ref keeps the ball from being played.  You'll find its often 10 minutes.  That's not subjective either.

These things are supposed to be accounted for but they aren't.  I reffed for over a decade and did so with a double watch on my wrist... one which ran full time, the other which counted stoppages.    I understand the reason we used to do the clock like this having run matches...  But we don't need to anymore and that's the point.

The commercials piece is disingenuous because its not something which would result from this.  Yes companies would love to monetize in game better but this won't lead to it as we're not introducing stoppages just putting a more consistent check on the clock.

&amp;gt;Just slower in real time than it currently is

What do you mean here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607915019.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>[Here's numbers for the topic](https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/world-cup-stoppage-time-is-wildly-inaccurate/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607771046.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>The timing thing (since I don’t really watch soccer, and I have no reason not to believe you, I’ll take your word for it) is probably the best argument so far. Not enough to change my view (yet) but I can at least appreciate the ability to guarantee that the fans are “done” after 2 hours. The reason why my view isn’t changed is that most of these stoppages aren’t long enough for a commercial. There aren’t 2-minute long timeouts in soccer, and if you want to squeeze a commercial in there during an injury stoppage, I’m OK with that. Even without stoppages, I see ads in the corner of the screen occasionally. I’ll take an actual commercial over an ad that takes up screen real estate while the game is going on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608155217.0" user="Sharcbait" delta="False">
    <text>How many NBA games have you watched? The last 2 minutes of a close game where they foul a lot can take 20-30 minutes to actually happen with the clock stoppages. This includes commercials. They don't NEED to run commercials during all clock stoppages but they do. Because of it if you are watching and need to be done around a certain time you might miss the end of the game.  NFL games have ways that teams abuse the clock at the end of the game as well. Iirc it was the Pats vs Cheifs where both teams scored under 2 minutes because they used clever clock abuse. Does it add a layer to the game? maybe, does Soccer need that layer? Probably not. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608275426.0" user="widget1321" delta="False">
    <text>They don't run commercials in every stoppage in basketball, though. Just during time outs. The clock stops every foul or out of bounds play without commercials (unless, again, a time out is called).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608061261.0" user="lotus_butterfly" delta="False">
    <text>Not even, 90 minutes. 1.5 hours</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608875985.0" user="RedSpikeyThing" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see why the things you mentioned can't be accounted for while still timing the game. If there's continuation then don't stop the clock and the game goes on until the next stoppage.

As for advertising, it's a slippery slope I suppose - NHL hockey comes to mind - but it isn't strictly necessary. See Olympic Hockey, for example.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
