<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31608237438.0" user="rbhxzx" delta="False">
    <text>The thing about soccer is that it’s disconnect from the clock makes it soooo much more interesting. I mean football almost revolves entirely around the clock, and play completely changes during the last two minutes of the game. There’s dedicated strategies to just playing the last 60 seconds of a one hour long game. That would be brutal to watch for soccer fans as the end of their game degenerates into completely new stalling tactics. 

Another point of yours, about football being stopped in the middle of the drive, was used wrong in the analogy. Just like soccer won’t necessarily stop in the middle of an attack, football won’t be stopped during the play itself (hence the passing and lateral strategies used to extend the play pass the clock). And many refs will call the game/half just as the pressure even eases up a little. There is not much unnecessary extension past the clock. 

By adding in a clock the free flowing form of soccer will be disrupted and the meta may begin centering around how well teams can abuse the clock. Stalling will be made much more effective, and teams that can do this will become so much better (hint: teams that are good at stalling winning games is not good for the overall health of the sport). 

Forcing people to play the game instead of adding an extra layer of clock manipulation keeps the players honest, and forces play to be used that’s much more technically interesting, such as formation changes and safe pressure, as compared to just keeping the ball in as much as possible and kicking it out when its going to get stolen. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
