<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="51" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31609079125.0" user="peacefinder" delta="False">
    <text>It’s completely understandable that you should think this. What you’re missing, though, is the culture of the game that makes clock stoppage antithetical. The deepest underpinning of this is, surprisingly, aesthetic.

Fans refer to it as The Beautiful Game, and this is not a joke or an exaggeration. The ideal game has a flow, a rhythm, that is rarely achieved in full but is unusual (and maybe unique) among team sports. The core principle of the rules is to punish anything that intentionally interrupts the flow, and to a large extent the referees are there to set the conditions for the game to flow. The continuous clock is just one of many rules based on this. 

In a more tangible sense, soccer is not just a sport of skill, but of endurance. In an ideal game, both sides would run for 90 minutes straight, with no interruptions but goals scored and a break at halftime.

An example of how strongly this applies is substitution of players. There are no squad changes like in American football, or line changes as in hockey, or unlimited subs as in basketball... every player has to be on the go for the whole game. Each side starts 11 players, who play all match unless substituted. A team is allowed only three substitutes in a game. If you’re out of subs and someone gets injured and can’t continue? Tough, play shorthanded. 

This may seem hardcore, but we’re at the most generous substitution rule in the history of the game. For the first few decades, a substitute referred to a player swapped in because a team member *didn’t show up* at the start of the game. Once the game started, the teams were fixed. In international rules, this was the way it worked for a **hundred years**. 

From Wikipedia:

&amp;gt; The number of substitutes usable in a competitive match has increased from zero—meaning teams were reduced if players' injuries could not allow them to play on—to one (plus another for an injured goalkeeper) in 1958; to two out of a possible five in 1988. With the later increases in substitutions allowed, the number of potential substitute players increased to seven.[14] The number of substitutes increased to two plus one (injured goalkeeper) in 1994,[15] to three in 1995;[16][17] and most recently to a fourth substitute in certain competitions in extra time.[18]

The primary objection to video review of some referee calls - which has been implemented only in the last few years and only at high levels of play - was that it interrupts the game. On the one hand there have been concessions to player safety - one hydration break per half but only in some extreme weather conditions, and slightly better concussion protocols - but on the other hand the new rules for next year limit the ability of teams to use substitutions late in the game to waste time. 

All this is to say that the constant clock is more fundamental to the game than even the size of the field of play (which varies per stadium). It’s baked into the game at such a deep cultural level that it’d be truly shocking if it ever changes. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
