<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607192772.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>I used to be in agreement with you because it would eliminate time wasting, but in several respects it would make things worse:

1. Players would intentionally take ages to get the play going again in order to catch their breath. This would get incredibly boring for those watching in the stadium and at home.

2. It would almost certainly be used for more commercial opportunities, resulting in a cycle where players are actively encouraged to take more time so commercials get more time.

3. The game would finish at unpredictable times making management very difficult. When arranging special conditions with police, traffic, etc. it would turn into pure guesswork and cost much more to run. 

4. They would have a tough call to make on how long the game should be in general. Should it be reduced to 30min halves? 

5. Records and statistics as we know it would be invalidated as the format of the game will have changed. How would you compare old goal scoring achievements with new as they were done under different conditions?

Edit: after consulting some other points, I'd like to add some more reasons to my list:

1. Players would be encouraged to take indefinite time on throw-ins/goal kicks of the manager wanted to chat tactics with his team. What would stop them from basically using it as a time-out?

2. Implementing it across all levels would be very difficult as lower leagues would struggle with the accuracy and logistics of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607329485.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>1. This does not happen in other sports, as far as I can tell. Timeouts are fixed length, and the referee keeps things moving. Players already waste time in soccer to run the clock down.
2. Maybe but I feel that this is irrelevant. I do feel that commercials take up too much time (TV timeouts, anyone?) but how long are most stoppages in soccer? Not long enough for a commercial, I don’t think, save for long injury breaks. Penalty shots contribute to stoppage time but you certainly wouldn’t cut away during one. Stuff like resetting after a foul doesn’t take that long. There are no timeouts in soccer. Where can you actually fit commercials?
3. Is there more variance in game length in other timed sports vs. soccer? I don’t know where you’d find something to back this up.
4. 45 minutes, as before. Why would stopping the clock change that? Theoretically, stoppage time is there to make the length of play 45 minutes, anyway, isn’t it?
5. I think this is irrelevant. Baseball used to have a 154-game season, the NFL used to play a 14-game season, etc. We’ll figure something out if the records start changing dramatically. Not breaking records doesn’t mean the game is worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607384330.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>1. There is a difference between time outs and the ball being out of play. When the ball is kicked into the crowd and the player has difficulty retrieving it, who is going to be penalised for the timeout taking too long? Right now players already push it with throw ins and goal kicks with time wasting. If they could just take an extra 30 seconds, they definitely would.

2. I'm convinced that even on 15 second stops they'll cram in an ad. And I've seen play being missed in basketball because of ads. If this happens in football, I'd be furious

3. Variance would undeniably increase in football. Games are 90 min plus 3-8min stoppages most of the time. Which is absolutely minimal variance. If they stopped the clock every time the ball went out, it would vary far more.

4. You may not be aware of this but the ball is actually in-play for only roughly 55 minutes per game out of the 90. You suddenly make players play 90 in-play minutes and the entire game has changed

5. Maybe it didn't matter to those sports but it absolutely would in football. World Cups, league titles, scoring records are all discussed very often</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607430209.0" user="austhyma" delta="False">
    <text>1. Ball boys/girls exist for this reason. If the ball goes unreasonably far out of bounds a player could simply retrieve a ball from the ball person. If there is no ball person, a referee could issue a delay of game penalty based off an amount of time or maybe make a judgement.  

4. You could shorten the games to accommodate the better clock management. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607438053.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>1. Ball boys and ball girls are hired by the home team and absolutely are encouraged to do what is in favour of the home team. [Example 1](https://www.bavarianfootballworks.com/platform/amp/2018/4/29/17299634/bayern-munich-ball-boys-allianz-arena-real-madrid-eintracht-frankfurt-joshua-kimmich-sven-ulreich#aoh=15528291192855&amp;amp;csi=1&amp;amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com&amp;amp;amp_tf=From%20%251%24s). [Example 2](https://youtu.be/sd38KUjmOho). It can do it two extremes where they waste time or play if very quickly

2. My fourth point in the original post is that it would fundamentally change the game. And how long would you set the game to? No one wants to see the game change at its core so much</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607523029.0" user="dradam168" delta="False">
    <text>/5. Records are discussed all the time in American sports, and when records of a different era are brought up they are simply mentioned in the appropriate context.

Eg, The '74 Dolphins are the only NFL team to ever have an undefeated season (17-0), except the season was only 14 games, and the '07 Patriots (18-1) had more wins and more wins in a row, but didn't win the Superbowl.  Everybody who cares already knows this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607536328.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>Kinda dilutes the achievement of there are always stipulations to the time period that it occurred in. It already happens to an extent in football as number of games changed in the premier League, and golden goal rule was eliminated for example. But the game length changing and time stoppages entering would be such a fundamental change that it would be hard to compare records in scoring at all</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607899494.0" user="dradam168" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think it really dilutes anything.  Being the best at a certain point in time is, I believe, what really matters.

Besides, without context, most records are pretty meaningless.  

Sure, Hank Aaron then Barry Bonds broke Ruth's home run record, but just saying that glosses over Bond's steroid use, or the fact that Babe Ruth spent his first 4-5 seasons as a pitcher.

On the other hand, you have Cy Young with 511 career wins, a number which will NEVER EVER be broken (the 2nd most all time is almost 100 behind, and the #1 active pitcher has 246), but that's because Young played at a time when the game was drastically different than it is today.

All sports evolve, to think that soccer hasn't is ridiculous, and so all records need context to be meaningful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607409498.0" user="SamBrev" delta="False">
    <text>In response to your point 4:

In practice, this is never the case. [This article](https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/world-cup-stoppage-time-is-wildly-inaccurate/) by FiveThirtyEight I read during the World Cup really opened my eyes to how wildly inaccurate stoppage time calculations are. Part of the issue is that stoppage time isn't meant to account for all dead-ball time, but only for "*excessive*" stoppages, which, in principle, is probably a good thing, for reasons others have mentioned, but in particular that games would go on *forever*. In the study, in most World Cup group stage games, the ball was in play for less than 60 of the 90 minutes played. In one, the ball was in play for only 44. Therefore if we *were* to transition to a system like you suggest, you would have to reduce played game time to something like 30 minutes per half to keep games roughly the same length.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607571335.0" user="landoindisguise" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;2. Maybe but I feel that this is irrelevant. I do feel that commercials take up too much time (TV timeouts, anyone?) but how long are most stoppages in soccer? Not long enough for a commercial, I don’t think, save for long injury breaks. 

That doesn't matter if the clock is stopped they would be made into "TV timeouts" (this is already a thing in other sports). if necessary players just wait a few seconds before throwing the ball in after the commercial ends. It's easy to make ads that are 5, 10, or 15 seconds long, so that's how would it start. But once that possibility for making money is there, it would just get worse and worse over time until it ended up looking like American football, where you're watching commercials three times as much as you're watching actual footage of the game.


&amp;gt;Penalty shots contribute to stoppage time but you certainly wouldn’t cut away during one. 

No but you'd cut away before one, during the setup, and after one if it is a goal and the game is being reset for play.


&amp;gt;Stuff like resetting after a foul doesn’t take that long. There are no timeouts in soccer. Where can you actually fit commercials?

Cutting to a commercial doesn't take long either. It doesn't need to be a full 30 or 60 second spot. Moreover many other sports have TV timeouts, where play stoppages are intentionally lengthened to allow for more commercials. If you put clock stoppages in soccer, that will happen there too. Probably not in the first season or the second season, But ultimately the ability to make more money is going to be too tempting for broadcasters to pass this opportunity up. 

And then we all get a much shittier viewing experience and one of the beautiful things about soccer is destroyed.

I get that stoppage time is weird particularly if you're coming from other sports, but I'd say it's worth considering why virtually no regular soccer fans hold this opinion. It comes up all of the time during the world cup win lots of casual folks who don't regularly watch soccer or watching, but among the people I know who watch soccer frequently, literately nobody wants this.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607773764.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;45 minutes, as before. Why would stopping the clock change that? Theoretically, stoppage time is there to make the length of play 45 minutes, anyway, isn’t it?

Did you say you watch American football? Is the length of a football game the time played or a different length of time? I don't watch American football, don't even know how much time the actual play time is, but I know for goddamned sure it's a lot less time than the games actually take.

Edit: I think you may have misunderstood the original point. It's that there's a difference in some sports between length of play and length of game. People accept it where it already exists, but for a sport to suddenly build that in might not go so well. I for one hate it in the most egregious instance (football), and don't see any merit in adding it in where it doesn't now exist. Predictable *game* times has merit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607783114.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>I do watch American football. The length of time “played” is 60 minutes (plus overtime if that happens), and yes, the actual action is a lot less (clock runs for pretty much anything that stays in bounds in the pro game). I think there are flaws there as well, FWIW. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607802139.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>But that initial point isn't about time played, it's about overall length of the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607972240.0" user="lIlIllIlll" delta="False">
    <text>That's not really true though. I'm sure Americans are familiar with *condensed footage*? I believe last years Superbowl, condensed, snap-to-down was only 12 minutes long.


Edit: I looked it up. It's actually 19 minutes. So I was wrong. But I believe the broadcast time was something like 4 hours. That's a lot of dead air time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608222495.0" user="dehehn" delta="False">
    <text>Football isn't just snap to down.  The setting up of the lines on each play are strategic. The planning of each play is a thought out considered thing.  There's suspense in wondering what play they will decide.  Listening to the announcers discuss, discussing with friends.  Watching replay footage to see if someone was in bounds or caught a ball.  I know it's boring to a lot of people but there's a reason that style of game is also interesting to a lot of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608569830.0" user="pointlesswanderer" delta="False">
    <text>He explained that:

&amp;gt;clock runs for pretty much anything that stays in bounds in the pro game

A lot of the clock runs down between a play that ends in a result that doesn't involve a clock stoppage (e.g. a run or a completed pass) and the snap of the next play.  If you watch a game you'll notice there is a "play clock" this is distinct from the "game clock."  The play clock accounts for this "lost" time.

Now bear in mind, although the players are just "standing there" they are certainly not doing anything.  Both the offense and the defense are attempting to read the opponent and change their strategy.  If you watch a masterful QB, like Brady or Manning (when he was still playing) they will change the play a large percentage of the time once they see how the defense is aligned.  This is called an audible.

Football is by far and away the most strategically complex sport; frankly more akin to warfare than other sports.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608940705.0" user="Vivalyrian" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;&amp;lt;Random person's favourite sport&amp;gt; is by far and away the most strategically complex sport; frankly more akin to warfare than other sports.
   
     
Feel like that's what every sportsfan claim about their personal favourite. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608986338.0" user="pointlesswanderer" delta="False">
    <text>Football is not my favorite sport but the strategic complexity is not debatable.  Its so complex that arguably the coaching staff is more important than the players.  There's no other sport where that's even close to the case.

I prefer watching basketball but its like chess v. checkers in terms of strategy.

I compare it to war because a lot of the sport boils down to mind games and espionage.  Its trench warfare with a ball.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609163583.0" user="Cecil900" delta="False">
    <text>Baseball is a lot of very calculated risk taking. Maybe not in a "tactical" or war like way like football but more so than Basketball or Hockey, even though I do love Hockey so much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609249503.0" user="pointlesswanderer" delta="False">
    <text>It is but there isn't really the infinite number of options that are present in football.  If baseball allowed one of the teams to redefine where the bags were play-by-play, then you may start reaching the level of complexity that football has.

Football is the ultimate team sport.  The open secret about baseball is that its an individual sport masquerading as a team sport.  There's very little in the way of "teamwork."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609129865.0" user="doheth" delta="False">
    <text>I think he might have meant tactically complex because I believe that is definitely true while still being strategically interesting. Football has 11 players on both sides lining up for 100+ plays a game in which they each have very specific duties taylored to the specific play.

Any other sport approaching football in tactical complexity is usually an individual sport, like golf or tennis or involves fewer players at any given time, like basketball. Or the sport just involves more "flow" such as hockey or soccer and therefore less pure tactics.

I feel the warfare part is also true compared to most other sports.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31611282623.0" user="Poo-et" delta="False">
    <text>Chess player here. Can confirm every sportsperson compares their sport to chess upon finding out just because it contains a component of strategy.

I know a lot about competitive table tennis and there's a lot that goes into mental strategy, service choice, choosing which ball to attack and so on. This strategic element doesn't make it more strategic than other sports</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608116733.0" user="Danktizzle" delta="False">
    <text>It is well documented that the NFL has an average of 11 mins per 3 hours of game play. So by your logic 49 mins are dedicated to slapping asses in huddle and time wasting. The other two hours are commercials.  

https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052748704281204575002852055561406</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608146361.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;slapping asses

&amp;gt;time wasting

Pick one. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608592309.0" user="pointlesswanderer" delta="False">
    <text>There is so much strategy that goes on between plays it can hardly be considered a waste of time.

Watch [this](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-lz-5SqbVFA) video.  The first 25 seconds of the video is what you call "slapping asses in huddle and time wasting."  The play itself takes about 3 seconds.  

But if actually understand what's happening during those first 25 seconds you'll realize its far from time wasting.  Its a strategic game of cat and mouse.  Manning continues to change the play and the defense reacts and Manning adjusts again until things are lined up in the Broncos' favor.  The play results in a touchdown.

No one with any football knowledge will call what Manning did a waste of time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608779695.0" user="Danktizzle" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, don’t care. I spent my youth being ridiculed for being a soccer player. Then I went to Lincoln when Nebraska won the championship in ‘94. I know a ton about it. (Back then the radio personalities would joke about how much football knowledge husker fans have, not sure if you remember,) 

I saw coach Osborne get Lawrence philips out of 2 assault cases against his girlfriend. He was too important to the team. 

I also know about where football got it’s start at the Carlisle school for Indian boys. A colonel took indigenous kids from their families and forced them into white America through football indoctrination. 

So it is rotten from the start. 

We could talk about how socialism only works when it is billionaires getting cities to pay for their storage stadia. Or how the employee has zero rights and will most likely be retired before 30. I believe the capitalist calls it parity. Or maybe the NCAA. 

You know, the great socialist system of the NCAA. they make a billion and then say their employees don’t get a penny. They can sell their likeness on video games and soda commercials without sharing a penny with the worker. They pack stadia for a premium to see the hit. But they can’t get paid. 

I was in San Diego when junior seau killed himself. I know football. 

Today I refuse to go to the bar during nfl season because their fans are so toxic. The last NFL game I watched was a playoff game about ten years ago. I left before the first quarter was over because I got sick of seeing the same  hailcorporate commercial 30 times. 

for as many times as I have heard an egg toss fan blow off footballers as them not doing anything, I appreciate your attempt at ass-slapping as strategy. 

Hailcorporate to you. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608941810.0" user="hooligan99" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus dude</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608949819.0" user="RYouNotEntertained" delta="False">
    <text>This has absolutely nothing to do with the comment above you. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609108455.0" user="Dakota0524" delta="False">
    <text>Lulwut. What does your comment have to do with the above reply?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609453333.0" user="coleisawesome3" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, so if I’m reading this right(which I’m not sure if I am, it was barely coherent), because shady things happen in football, it automatically makes the game less strategically involved?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31610312307.0" user="DTKing" delta="False">
    <text>Lmao where the hell did this come from it reads like a copy pasta </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31612952161.0" user="evn0" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Nope, don’t care. I spent my youth being ridiculed for being a soccer player. Then I went to Lincoln when Nebraska won the championship in ‘94. I know a ton about it. (Back then the radio personalities would joke about how much football knowledge husker fans have, not sure if you remember,)
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; I saw coach Osborne get Lawrence philips out of 2 assault cases against his girlfriend. He was too important to the team.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; I also know about where football got it’s start at the Carlisle school for Indian boys. A colonel took indigenous kids from their families and forced them into white America through football indoctrination.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; So it is rotten from the start.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; We could talk about how socialism only works when it is billionaires getting cities to pay for their storage stadia. Or how the employee has zero rights and will most likely be retired before 30. I believe the capitalist calls it parity. Or maybe the NCAA.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; You know, the great socialist system of the NCAA. they make a billion and then say their employees don’t get a penny. They can sell their likeness on video games and soda commercials without sharing a penny with the worker. They pack stadia for a premium to see the hit. But they can’t get paid.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; I was in San Diego when junior seau killed himself. I know football.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Today I refuse to go to the bar during nfl season because their fans are so toxic. The last NFL game I watched was a playoff game about ten years ago. I left before the first quarter was over because I got sick of seeing the same hailcorporate commercial 30 times.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; for as many times as I have heard an egg toss fan blow off footballers as them not doing anything, I appreciate your attempt at ass-slapping as strategy.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Hailcorporate to you.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609683911.0" user="sheffieldasslingdoux" delta="False">
    <text>Ok but what about other sports that stop the clock? Like ice hockey, for example. Hockey is fast paced and has limited commercials and breaks. 

Or basketball. 

Or literally every other team sport except soccer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609936823.0" user="Xaielao" delta="False">
    <text>In American football a huge amount of time is spent just waiting for commercial breaks to end, since the game stops when they run.. and they run a LOT. The games generally run 3+ hours, with nearly an hour of that being commercials.

One of the reasons I like soccer more is that they do not stop for commercials. A game is always 90 minutes long + a few minutes of stoppage time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607806269.0" user="practically_not" delta="False">
    <text>All these issues can be solved in pro games by having a visible stoppage clock that adds up during the game as the assistant ref runs it up every time the game stops for more that 15 secs (fouls, goalies, etc). Once the official time is up, the stoppage clock runs down whatever time it added through the game. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608148420.0" user="Danktizzle" delta="False">
    <text>I hope this is the direction it would go if this actually became an issue. I don’t mind the stoppage time they give and think it is another layer of drama added to the end of the game (especially in champions league semi final!).  I don’t know why you would change it. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608460191.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You'd change it because the only thing better than that drama is ending it all with a buzzer beater.  Correct me if I'm wrong, but your can't have a buzzer beater in soccer without it being at least somewhat controversial.  Whoever is on the ass end is going to feel like the shot was early/late pretty much no matter what.  Right?

In closing, buzzer beaters are the tits.  Why wouldn't you want to add them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608491350.0" user="Danktizzle" delta="False">
    <text>So is a 96’ minute goal in a game with 3 mins extra time. 

...After coming back from a 0-2 deficit in the first round and every one wrote you off  

...playing in a foreign country! Absolutely amazing! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608512925.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I dont understand what point you are trying to make.  Is this a reference to something?

If the game is supposed to be 90 minutes with 3 minutes extra time, I'd be might pissed if I lost in minute 96 given I should have won three minutes ago.  And if I won that game, I might think I had a little help.  Doesn't soccer already have a pretty significant corruption problem?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608232296.0" user="LockJ4Ws" delta="False">
    <text>Remember that in soccer the referee can card a player for taking too much time with the ball.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608239251.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>Why does that card matter? Winning the game is probably a bigger reward than a yellow card is a detriment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608262494.0" user="LockJ4Ws" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe, but in big tournaments such as the Champions League and the World Cup if a player  accumulates a certain number of yellows ( usually 2 - 3) over the course of the tournament, the player will miss the next game. So maybe it's stoppage time and a full back is taking his time throwing in a ball because they're winning and he gets carded, but in the previous match he got another yellow card for a rough tackle, Now the player will miss the return leg of the tournament against the same team.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608341622.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>Right, I know that rule. But if the player doesn’t already have a yellow hanging over his head, then is it not a calculated risk to eat the card and waste more time? What if the game were to clinch a championship and future games didn’t matter pending the current game’s result?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608374882.0" user="LockJ4Ws" delta="False">
    <text>that's a valid point. the thing is, no player wants a yellow card hanging over their heads. this is a great example:
https://bleacherreport.com/articles/2822879-sergio-ramos-banned-for-2-matches-by-uefa-for-intentional-yellow-card-vs-ajax 
the player in question picked up a voluntary yellow card because it would have wiped his record clean. that's a strategic move which ended up not paying out, but it is still an example of why no player should play for a yellow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608475071.0" user="mechanical_fan" delta="False">
    <text>Besides accumulating yellow cards during a competition, two red yellow cards during a game become a red. Playing a man down is a very big disadvantage, for obvious reasons.

So, if you already have a yellow card, time wasting can be very risky. And continue to piss off the referee after you already have a yellow card for time wasting can go very wrong too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608965943.0" user="sclsmdsntwrk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This does not happen in other sports, as far as I can tell.


Well because in these other sports there's not 45 minutes of continues plays. For example, in american football, as far as I can tell, having to play for more than 15 secondes without a break is highly unusual. In Hockey players are on the ice for maybe a minute or two before they get to rest.


&amp;gt; Is there more variance in game length in other timed sports vs. soccer?


You're missing the point. A game with hardly any fouls, injuries and throw-ins would be vastly shorter than a game with 15 corners, 3 serious injuries and 30 throw-ins. That would be very impractical, especially for TV-purposes. 


&amp;gt; 45 minutes, as before. Why would stopping the clock change that?


Because playing 45 minutes including small breaks is very different from playing 45 minutes excluding small breaks. The average effective play time in high level soccer games is something like 60 minutes, increasing that by 50% would obviously have a massive impact. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609696839.0" user="sheffieldasslingdoux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	Well because in these other sports there’s not 45 minutes of continues plays. For example, in american football, as far as I can tell, having to play for more than 15 secondes without a break is highly unusual. In Hockey players are on the ice for maybe a minute or two before they get to rest. 

What about basketball? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609734345.0" user="sclsmdsntwrk" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really know anything about basketball. Although a google search tells me they play for 12 minutes before everyone has a break and also they have unlimited substitutions... so it seems my point still stands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31616675212.0" user="savemenico" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think this is irrelevant. Baseball used to have a 154-game season, the NFL used to play a 14-game season, etc. We’ll figure something out if the records start changing dramatically. Not breaking records doesn’t mean the game is worse.

Also you have advanced stats where stats are adjusted with pace/per min etc.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

And it's difficult to compare through different ages since the game has evolved as well, even though the rules didn't change as much</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607336629.0" user="fauxreal21" delta="False">
    <text>These make no sense.  Except maybe #5.  Have you ever watched a timed game, like hockey, or basketball?  None of these issues exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607368651.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>1. Have you ever watched football (soccer)? Players already have bad habits for time wasting. Giving them unlimited opportunity to do it more without consequence will no doubt have bad repercussions.

2. I have watched some Americans sports like the ones you listed and they're absolutely filled to the brim with commercials. I do not want football to go in that direction too.

3. Maybe number 4 isn't an issue because they never operated on a different basis... How can you see setting a new time limit on a game that's 150+ years old won't be a difficult decision?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607461743.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>1. Now there is a consequence. It was done originally to waste time, now it's rendered ineffective and the person is forced to leave the field still so they're down a man for a short tkmr and gain nothing.

2. That's not a concern here. If they were saying that the time stopped should be exactly 30s then you could make that argument but instead it's "don't run the clock for these events" but there is nothing pushing those events to last longer to enable commercials.

3. It's 45 minutes. The ref is currently allowed to stop the clock for these events and is supposed to keep a separate timer for these items. We just don't cause it's tougher.

That's why it's not even wrong. It's a misunderstanding of what is going on and what is proposed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607489395.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>1. I personally believe it still will be an issue. Players regaining energy is a massive part of the game because the games last 90 minutes. Basketball is shorter, NFL rotates squads, baseball is mostly standing around or sitting in the dugout, etc. I think football players are extremely exhausted towards the end of the game and if they slow it down without consequence, they absolutely will.

2. Goal kicks can easily take 30+ seconds. Substitutions can take 30+ seconds, injuries can take 2+ minutes (without the game resuming). If a precedent is set for stoppages taking longer as the clock is stopped, commercials could easily make their way in.

3. Are you aware that the ball is in play for much less than that? Usually less than 60 minutes in a 90 minute game. So if they were to properly stop and start the clock, the game length would need to change </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607592412.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>1.  What would be an issue?  I'm completely confused now...  

2.  Goal kicks don't get restarted by the ref so you don't stop clock.  Substitutions take 30+ seconds AND THAT FULL TIME is supposed to be added on at the end.  Same with injuries.  Everything you describe is how its supposed to work already but doesn't.  What would take longer?  Injuries would take less time and everything else would take the same.

3.  Its not about how long the ball is in play its about how long its available for play.  No need to change the game length.  As I said, you fundamentally don't understand what is being proposed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607612523.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>Look at OP's second bullet point. He is quite clearly stating that it should apply to things like throw-ins too. Besides, the vast majority of the time wasting in a game isn't due to injuries and substitutions. It's how long it takes teams to take their throw in, freekick, goal kick, corner kick, etc. So making this big change you propose will maybe add a couple of minutes per game when in reality you're missing out on 30 minutes of the ball being out of play due to other reasons. Why bother implementing this fix is it doesn't address that issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607623384.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, misunderstood their point there.  I was interpreting that as if they do that to the point of dissent and a card.  

Yeah, don't stop it for OOB play, only the ref's whistle, and it makes good sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609722799.0" user="sheffieldasslingdoux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	I have watched some Americans sports like the ones you listed and they’re absolutely filled to the brim with commercials. I do not want football to go in that direction too. 

Are you just talking about American football? Because  sports like ice hockey and basketball aren’t only played in the US. The excessive use of commercials is an American problem. That’s seperate from whether or not time stoppages would lead to more commercials. I don’t see the evidence for that. Also don’t American networks play more commercials in general?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607369721.0" user="Sydney_Gamer" delta="False">
    <text>I was going to ask if he had ever watched sport at all. None of these make any sense. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607413291.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>Can you provide me with any arguments instead of a blanket statement that doesn't address any points? I feel like people are getting very defensive as if us not wanting to change football is an insult towards American sports. It's not, we just like how football is and think that adding click stoppages will make it worse</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607431627.0" user="Sydney_Gamer" delta="False">
    <text>1. Players slow down play because stoppages are never accounted for correctly. By stopping the clock there is no advantage in slowing play down and this would stop. Any "breathers" would be way less that that.

2. You can't use the clock being stopped to add more commercials any more than you can now. As above, the time for stoppages would reduce.

3. The game finishes at unpredictable times already because stoppage time varies.

4. This one is so nonsensical it's not even wrong. 
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Not_even_wrong

5. Apart from the fact that some "goals per minute" or "minutes played" stats would change by 2 minutes it wouldn't affect anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607460041.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>1. The players would have absolutely no incentive to get play going quickly again with the time stopped. Even the losing team would take ages to get the play going so they can build up some energy again. Teams already do that now by taking injuries. 

2. You cannot guarantee that. I've seen commercials in basketball for the tiniest of stoppages. In Germany they play a commercial between the national anthem and the game starting with is about 20 seconds...

3. As I wrote in another comment, stoppage time very rarely ever varies by more than 5 minutes. It's usually 1-2 minutes after the first half and 2-5 after the second half. 

4. How do you not understand my point? In most football matches the ball is in play for about 55 minutes. If you were to stop the game every time it went out, you'd have to change the length of the game.

5. See point 4 as your math is completely off</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607583047.0" user="Eltotsira" delta="False">
    <text>Bro, the players already have no incentive to get play going quickly. Did you watch this last world cup? I'm a fan, and it was borderline unwatchable because of all the diving. They were barely even playing soccer/football. 

Even your point about changing the game time doesnt make sense. If the ball is in play for an average of 55-60 minutes per game, and there is 3- 5 minutes of stoppage per half, where tf is the other *30* minutes being accounted for? At least the way this person is suggesting the fans, who are spending money and time to watch these matches, get to watch an actual 90 minutes of soccer/football. 

I'd also argue that stoppage incentivizes players to dive, on both sides of the ball. It can completely disrupt game flow and allow one team to get set up at the expense of a few seconds. Or, as in the case of this past world cup and the one before it. You can have guys taking dives and wasting 7+ minutes at the end of the game because they know the ref isnt going to add a full 7 minutes. Arge Tina and Brazil specifically, *both* did this bullshit, and not only is it not fun to watch, it leaves the viewer/fan with an empty feeling like they just wasted 2 hours of their day watching something that ultimately was not a test of skill but rather who could get up a point and run out the clock with fake injuries and shenanigans. 

People *are* providing valid responses to what you're saying, you just dont want to hear them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607600587.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>I think most of these replies are coming from people who only watch the world cup. I watch 3+ games every single week so I like to think I'm quite well placed to understand how time wasting and stoppages play a role in the game now.

To your first point, they'd have even less of an incentive to get play going quickly. I don't want to watch a game where neither team is actually trying to get the game going. 

To answer your question, the other 30 minutes is the ball being out of play for fouls, throw-ins, goal-kicks, corner kicks, etc. The time added to the end is up the the ref. It's meant to be for injuries, excessive goal celebrations and excessive time wasting, although they don't always add it on. People pay knowing full well that they're not going to watch the ball in-play for 90 minutes and if you watched games more often you'd probably know that a bit better. You can't suddenly change the amount of playtime, it wouldn't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607649517.0" user="Eltotsira" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, but then if they're wasting time it gains them nothing, lol. You're completely ignoring the part of the argument that everyone I've seen has pointed out, which is that the incentive to waste time is completely gone. 

No one is suggesting changing the amount of play time. They're suggesting stopping the clock on obvious fouls, unless I'm mistaken.

It feels a little like you're being a bit contrary just for the sake of it, tbh. I may be misunderstanding tho. 

Cheers for real responding, btw. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607796901.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>I've pointed it out a few times actually. The game is exhausting and they have an incentive to slow it down in stoppages to regain some energy. Additionally, coaches often yell tactics at their players. Right now they use injuries as an opportunity to relay information to the team. If they could take longer breaks at other stoppages, they could start using them as tactical breaks.

OP's second point suggests that it's more than just injuries where they'd stop the time. I'd agree it would be a far more reasonable proposition to just stop the time for injuries  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607679714.0" user="Sydney_Gamer" delta="False">
    <text>1. They have an incentive to slow play down now. Stopping the clock takes that away. Teams can currently slow down play if they want, that doesn't change. You're wrong.

2. There will be no more breaks than before, so no more ads that previous. You're wrong.

3. I'm not sure what you find so hard to fathom here. The game currently has varied times, this time would be slightly reduced, so the variation would be lessened. 

4. Because currently the game is supposed to be 90 minutes of ACTUAL play. There is stoppage time. If you just stopped the clock it would be accurate and not fairly random like it is now.

5. I'm not even sure you are aware what math is...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608342647.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>1. I still believe there will be an incentive to slow the game down. Even if it's not to waste time, it can be to regain energy or discuss tactics. There is no point in discussing on this subreddit if you have such a black and white view of things

2. I think the breaks will be longer so more opportunity for ads.

3. Your language is pretty rude to be honest when we're just trying to have a discussion. I don't understand your point that time will be less varied. Surely if the clock is stopped more often, then it'll be more varied. Right now it's almost always a 93-96minute match

4. I don't think that's true. The game has always been played with many stoppages so 90 minutes of actual gameplay is a fundamentally different game than what we play/watch now.

5. It appears in your fourth point that you agreed with me that only about 2/3rds of the game is actually played. So in that case, shouldn't you agree that goal scoring stats would be far more impacted if you suddenly increased in-play time by 50%?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607425397.0" user="axehomeless" delta="False">
    <text>You forgot about amateur football in the lower leagues. The System has to be as permeable as possible, and the refs have to be too. You can't just have a ref in the Kreisliga say "and perfetctly stop the time as well".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607431991.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>Very true. The ease of implementation is a big factor. But that hasn't stopped other innovation from entering such as VAR and goal-line technology. Although I do agree with you because it would be a fundamental change to the rules of the sport.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607463719.0" user="axehomeless" delta="False">
    <text>Very true, but I'd argue that you just simply couldn't go on without it, and that it really doesn't matter if you stop the time or not. I mean, the PL has stoppage times of 8-12 minutes rather often, so why change the system and make it harder for amateurs, but don't accomplish anything for the professionals.

VAR and especially GLT is different. It makes a huge difference for the professionals.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607936946.0" user="1Commentator" delta="False">
    <text>Every other sport manages to have a ref that stops time. Stopwatches are cheap and work well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607973706.0" user="axehomeless" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever refd a football game?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609702863.0" user="sheffieldasslingdoux" delta="False">
    <text>Why is football/soccer so different than any other sport? Somehow stopping the clock works in ice hockey, American football, basketball, etc. Why not football/soccer? What’s so special? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31611117642.0" user="axehomeless" delta="False">
    <text>Most calls are in a grey zone and hugely complicated to make, the refs are overloaded with a lot of different factors to make a good decision already, this will make it even harder without any real benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607430326.0" user="youonlylive2wice" delta="False">
    <text>Take it to much less of an extreme... Clock stops for events which requires the ref to restart play. This means goals, subs, injuries, penalty kicks, cards. Outside of that, still running clock as its 45 minutes of ball available for play. That's what they're supposed to be adding time for already so all you're doing is stopping the clock more accurately than adding time at the end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607453348.0" user="-OptimusPrimate-" delta="False">
    <text>I could see this working better than for every stoppage. But you'd see players manipulating this too with respect to how long they'd take to walk off the field for a substitution, or taking injuries to get more time for their team to recover. I think you'd need to subtract time from the length of the total game too, as the current understanding is that it's 95~ minutes with these delays so adding time stoppages would make the game much longer</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607469156.0" user="brandonjslippingaway" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Players would intentionally take ages to get the play going again

This already happens, it's usually just to game an advantage however. The ref still has the yellow card at their disposal, so time wasting for the sake of it = better than time wasting as a cynical obstruction tactic. I don't know if you've seen much of the most recent Asian Cup, but it absolutely sold me on the time keeping being a liability.

&amp;gt; It would almost certainly be used for more commercial opportunities,

It really doesn't have to be a forgone conclusion in this respect.

&amp;gt; The game would finish at unpredictable times making management very difficult.

If the refs did their jobs properly this would already be the case. Besides, it's not hard to tweak the timekeeping so that both the match runs, and the ball is live for approximately the same amount of time. Two halves of 30 minutes with the clock stopping every time the ball goes dead will get you to roughly 90 minutes, the same as now.

&amp;gt; Should it be reduced to 30min halves?

Yes. I've clocked two or three games with a stopwatch, I'd say the average game sees the ball live somewhere in the ballpark of 55-65 minutes.

&amp;gt; Records and statistics as we know it would be invalidated

There's still going to be pretty much the same amount of play, if anything records are going to be more consistent because the game won't see arbitrary numbers of stoppage time added on at the referee's discretion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607619308.0" user="atred" delta="False">
    <text>All these points about intentionally wasting time are invalid if the same rules about wasting time remain in place, it just counts for the time in a different way. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607736899.0" user="--huel" delta="False">
    <text>None of this happens in rugby, where the clock is stopped during dead balls. So why would it happen in soccer? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608278527.0" user="warlike_smoke" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP but I have some thoughts about your points.

1. This is easily solved with allotting a certain amount of time to resume play. In american football when one play is over the next play has to start within a certain time or a penalty is given. You could give yellow cards to players that purposefully waste time. I feel like this already happens even. Because of stoppage time, it is advantageous to take time to throw the ball in already.
2. I don't know why commercials would be required. You can easily not have commercials due to most clock stops will not be long enough to have a commercial. And ones that are long enough like for an injury you can just require networks not to broadcast commercials. Do you think sports networks are going to turn down broadcasting the world cup because they can't run commercials which they already don't do.
3. I don't see how it makes it any less predictable than it already is. It is never a pure 90 minutes because of stoppage time. All OP is saying is instead of the game clock reading 90+5 at the end of the game it will read 90:00. The 5 extra minutes will just be from a stopped clock rather than added on. It doesn't change match times at all.
4. and 5. I think you are overplaying how much this would change the game. The only change it has is to make the play time an exact 90 minutes instead of an inexact 89-91 minutes or whatever the variance is. Yes maybe you are losing out on a goal when the refs would have extended play to a theoretical 91st minute, but you might be gaining goals that are scored because sometimes the refs don't allot enough stoppage time.

Responses to Edits:

1. As in my first point, refs can still police this and prevent it from getting out of hand, and the current system doesn't really prevent this entirely either.
2. I feel like it increases accuracy of playtime as lower leagues probably have more trouble with giving discretion to stoppage time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608460946.0" user="RettichDesTodes" delta="False">
    <text>To 1. You could punish them for unsportsmanlike behaviour</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31611002334.0" user="sweegotrian" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree with most of your points but there is delay of game penalties in most sports. Meaning you can't just sit around to catch your breath.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31614661830.0" user="tikforest00" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Players would be encouraged to take indefinite time on throw-ins/goal kicks of the manager wanted to chat tactics with his team. What would stop them from basically using it as a time-out?

There is no practical difference from the current rules. If the clock is running but you add the same amount of time on to the end of the game that passed while play was stopped, there is no reason for them not to chat tactics now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31616659490.0" user="savemenico" delta="False">
    <text>1. You can add a time limit for that, like 10 seconds for a throw in since he gets the ball or something like that.
2. If you fix 1, you cannot make commercials longer.
3. Kinda but kinda not, since it's not like it's going to take like 2 hours longer.
4. Yep, since it will be stopped more time i think it should be something like 30-35 mins half.
5. That doesn't really matter in other games (like basketball, game has evolved, and normally that's why advanced stats are for)

I'll add one, how about actually limiting fouls, like 3rd foul yellow card, 5th foul 2nd yellow. Flagrant (yellow) Flagrant 2 (red) (like NBA or something like that). It could be more transparent like that instead of random yellow cards (they would still happen but they can fix it a bit).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; Players would be encouraged to take indefinite time on throw-ins/goal kicks of the manager wanted to chat tactics with his team. What would stop them from basically using it as a time-out? 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Like i said, if you give them 10 seconds to throw in, you have 10 seconds, if you delay the game you get a yellow card.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; Implementing it across all levels would be very difficult as lower leagues would struggle with the accuracy and logistics of it. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Well VAR has been implemented in a lot of leagues so it's not like it can't be done, and it's not like FIBA and NBA have the same rules, but i think it can be done wit a bit of organization</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
