<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607443505.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>There are a few things to consider here and a few have been mentioned already. The flow of play would be considerably impacted. Football is fundamentally different to a lot of spots you have compared it to in that it is a very continuous sport. NFL for example is essentially turn based, which lends itself well to separating the game into small sections (i.e a single play). Football isnt like this and if the clock was stopped every time the ball went out of play, it would seriously effect how the game is played.

For instance, a team is breaking down the pitch and the ball goes out for a throw to them. Normally the attacking team would try and take the throw quickly to continue the attack before the defenders have gotten themselves into a good defensive position. If the clock had to be stopped and started again, its pretty likely that the referee would prevent the throw being taken quickly. This is only one simple example of how the game would be completely changed. 

Looking at it from a different perspective, adding time to the end of the game adds a huge amount of excitement to the end of a tight game! Fans love a stoppage time winner or equaliser and this would be lost if the clock was stopped as you are suggesting. As a fan and being at a game that your team is drawing, but looking the most likely to win, when that board goes up showing 5 mins of stoppage time you get a sense of "my team can win this" and an excitement builds in the stands.  I wouldnt want to lose that. 

Lastly, there is a general idea that kids in a park should be able to play the same game (or almost the same game) as the professionals. This is one of the reasons that VAR has taken so long to come into effect. Changing the way the clock works would just be another thing that takes that away!

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607458909.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>You don’t have to stop the clock for everything. I’m looking at fouls/penalties, bookings, injuries, and such. I could agree that throw-ins should not stop the clock- they’re not generally counted for stoppage time, anyway. 

As far as excitement goes, why can’t the excitement be moved from stoppage time to the last 5 minutes of the game? When a basketball or American football game is tight, the last two minutes are very exciting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607507472.0" user="ThePinkP" delta="False">
    <text>In the original post it was not specified when the clock should be stopped. I thought you ment every time the ball went out of play. Even with stopping time with things that you have mentioned would ruin the flow of the game. Think about the same situation as I explained previously but instead of a throw, its a small foul on the attacking player. Do you stop the clock for that? What about offside? Do you stop the ball for that? Picking and choosing in what situations you do and dont stop time for just adds more for the referee to consider and will add no advantages to the game, while potentially changing the game negatively in a massive way. 

With regards to excitement, its just not the same thing! To start with, if your team is chasing a winner the last five mins are exciting anyway. Then, in the 90th min all the focus switches to how much stoppage time will be added. Then, when the board goes up you get a huge roar from the crowd and the tempo of your team picks up even more. At a live game, after the 90 mins you have no clock telling you how long is left so this adds another level of excitement. 

Every time I see this being put forward as an argument to "improve the game" it is almost always by people who dont watch the sport. Almost all fans that actually go to games (at least in the UK) dont want to change the way the clock works, so why change it? 

We all know and accept that time wasting is a part of the game that is annoying when the opposing team does it, but you have no problem with your team doing exactly the same thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607553970.0" user="FlappyBored" delta="False">
    <text>Because it’s the mental effect it has on the players and the fans.

Scoring in the last minute extra time is always seen as more of an achievement and the intensity picks up considerably compared to a normal 90 min finish. 

Why don’t you get rid of stops in American football and make the whole thing just play out constantly like we do in football?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607588665.0" user="WhimsicalLlamaH" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue the opposite. The intentional fouling to stop the clock is what makes the end of any basketball game unwatchable to me. Intentional fouls in soccer get a red card.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609312818.0" user="bigbrave" delta="False">
    <text>There is a seldom enforced rule in basketball for intentional fouls. At some point they decided not to give a fuck about it so teams can try to mount a comeback with too little time. It has ruined the end of so many games. 

They need to bring it back as a point of emphasis. If a defender isn't trying to steal a ball, just grabbing someone's arm to intentionally commit a foul should qualify as intentional with two shots and the ball awarded to the offense. Problem solved. 

This would also solve the newerish trend of fouling while ahead to keep the other team from shooting a three. Why the fuck should a team be punished for getting fouled?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31616691011.0" user="savemenico" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it's a tactic like Hack a Shaq was, but at the same time anything that stops the clock too much is also bad, it's about having a decent balance</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608085106.0" user="lotus_butterfly" delta="False">
    <text>American football is excruciatingly difficult to watch for football fans.

Too many commercials and the game stops way too often.

Also the ball is held in the hands so why is it called football? At least our football involves kicking a ball *with our foot*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609962636.0" user="thegregslife" delta="False">
    <text>American football is called what it is from it’s history. You are right, it wasn’t named because of how the sport is played. But let me ask you this, what is a rugby? What is a soccer? How do those relate at all to how the sport is played. 

Rugby is named after a British city where the sport was supposedly originated. Long story short, Ruby Football is the actual name (Rugby for short), and American Football is a deviation of the sport Rugby, so the name Football was kept with the sport. Long story short, soccer comes from the name “Association Football” and somebody took the “soc” from “asSOCiation Football” and overtime it became soccer. That’s the basic idea of the names for those sports. If you are more interested, google will give you all the details :) 

Edit: btw, I am a HUGE American football fan, and I agree, the commercials are ridiculous and the sport needs to find a way to shorten the games and have less commercials. BUT, I record all the games and in result, skip all the commercials, so I actually end up watching an entire football game in like an hour or so. Definitely not “excruciatingly difficult” when done in that way! :D </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31610897388.0" user="lotus_butterfly" delta="False">
    <text>Soccer is an American construct. It is football. Not soccer. I'm British.

As for the history of the name I know where it comes from I just hate it.

I also hate rugby football. I say rugby because it makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31611158131.0" user="thegregslife" delta="False">
    <text>When did I say soccer wasn’t an American construct? 

You questioned why American football was named football if the athletes just hold the ball with their hands. So I explained the history to you. But if you were going to question the name of American Football, you can literally question tons of different sport titles that have nothing to do with the sport at all. My point was, sometimes the names of sports are more related to the history rather than the concept of the title. 

To be honest, I’m not surprised you hate all that stuff you named because you seem like a pretty negative person in general. All I was doing was offering an explanation to your question, and instead you returned it with hostility and your sour opinion on the matter, which quite frankly, I really don’t care about. Cheers mate! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31610410574.0" user="RichardRogers" delta="False">
    <text>Because it's played on foot as opposed to horseback a la polo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609342314.0" user="Me180" delta="False">
    <text>He’s not talking about stoppage for things like throw ins. He’s talking about injuries and stuff. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
