<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31608216393.0" user="simonjp" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. 

This is the one I'd like to challenge. I think you're understandably influenced by American sports and this idea seems alien to you. In fact, it's a fundamental part of the game - of many football games in fact, as it's the same in Rugby, too, to counter your first point. *(I think Aussie Rules has stoppages and Gaelic doesn't, but don't quote me)*

I've heard American football being described as playing chess with meatheads. I get it; each 'play' is choreographed, planned. Soccer flows differently. It allows for a different type of game, where yes, you can waste time on the sidelines but you can't waste it on the pitch. Every second counts.

So why is this important? Time management in soccer is different from American football. Players and their managers know how long they have. The ability to add on extra time is effectively a punishment, used only when time was deliberately wasted (or a more serious stop for an injury). In other words, the clock's always counting. This means the players are always hustling, always 'on'. It changes the tactics of the game; it's less about specific 'plays' and more about taking opportunities.

That's not to say there isn't an argument for actually counting the time wasted by injuries so the ref has a good idea what to add.

TL;DR - I believe that as you have been brought up in American sports, you're understandably more comfortable with a game that is time-bound. Time is secondary in soccer; it's more about flow and it's one of the things that makes it a different game. To show you how it's cultural, for me as a Brit there's nothing more frustrating than a sport in which the clock stops every 10 seconds. At most, the "final" 2 minutes of a soccer game will take ~6 minutes, while the final 2 minutes of a basketball game can take 20 real life minutes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608318581.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>Do teams not waste time late in the game by just passing the ball around? I suppose I do have a bias towards American sports. I believe that if the period is X minutes long, it should end when the clock hits X minutes (or zero if you wanna count in that direction).

I can’t argue against flow, as I have no idea what that means. All I know is that I’d be pretty angry if I were a basketball (a game that also involves a good amount of flow, I’d argue) player and the referee allowed a possession to go on after time expired. I guess soccer fans are ok with that and I won’t say you’re wrong for it.

FWIW, I’m not a huge fan of American football timing for various reasons- end of game timing being one of those reasons- a team shouldn’t be able to literally waste over two minutes at the end of a game. I watch it, mostly to socialize with friends, but I would hardly call myself a huge fan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608708601.0" user="pollef" delta="False">
    <text>Well, it's not quite the same as in soccer but the game isn't over when the clock hits 0:00 in American football right? Hook and ladder plays can go on after time has "expired". So maybe soocer is more lenient with it but the concept of "letting the final action play out" exists in American football as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608856251.0" user="simonjp" delta="False">
    <text>One team can try to waste time, but the other team will absolutely be looking for ways to get the ball from them. The game isn't offence/defence like American Football - tackles are regular, possession changes frequently (without stoppage or a reset) and low scores mean late upsets are real possibilities.

I'm not a huge soccer fan, but I know the difference between watching any sport and watching it with someone passionate (even moreso if you watch in person rather than on the telly). My only recommendation if you want to see if your V can be Ced would be to go to a match with a fan. Good luck!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31610456934.0" user="Aug415" delta="False">
    <text>There’s time-wasting in basketball as well. In the final two minutes of the game, you can almost bet the team in the lead will stand at the halfline, ball in their best player’s hands, doing nothing until 5 seconds left on the shot clock. It’s the exact same thing. Just because they’re forced to take a shot at the end of it, doesn’t mean you haven’t just watched 19 seconds of nothing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609753003.0" user="sheffieldasslingdoux" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	I believe that as you have been brought up in American sports, you’re understandably more comfortable with a game that is time-bound. 

Can we get this out of our heads that every major team sport that isn’t soccer is somehow American? There might be the biggest leagues in the USA for basketball or ice hockey. But these sports are played all over the world, and like soccer no country or people “own” the sport. Do no other places in the world exist besides the US and Europe? 

American football is one sport that uses time stoppage. It’s slow. We know that. But what about ice hockey? It’s a fast-paced game and only stops clock when necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31611420233.0" user="UveDebauchedMySloth" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that sports which stop time towards the end promote a strategy teams employ to their advantage and it's super jarring and lame to watch but I think the same thing, in effect, occurs in soccer. I can't argue that one is better than the other though. Soccer players that are allowed to slow clap and walk off the field during a late game substitution, keepers that are allowed to stall their goal kick, players delaying a throw in, etc are all ways soccer players manage the clock and usually that time is not added 1:1 in stoppage. The clock not stopping in soccer does indeed promote a flow but it certainly fails to keep players honest and definitely promotes time wasting.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
