<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="54" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31609491681.0" user="0kely_d0kely" delta="False">
    <text>I think the answer lies somewhere in the middle. I propose that, rather than immediately stopping the clock the moment the ball goes out of play, there is a fixed maximum run-off time per stoppage - let's say, ten seconds for a throw in. The clock will continue to run for ten seconds before stopping, then resume when the ball reenters play.

Stopping the clock the minute the ball goes out of play provides no incentive for even the team who is chasing the game to resume quickly. However, in my scenario the team who is losing will still attempt to resume play quickly to save a few seconds. Additionally, teams who consistently and deliberately go beyond this time to catch their breath or disrupt the game can be reprimanded by the referee.

Instantly stopping the clock and keeping the game at 90min long will significantly increase play time and therefore drastically change the game. Obviously the remedy to this would be reducing the length of a game, but this is a fundamental change. My scenario would allow the game to stay at 90min without drastically changing the amount of play time.

Overall, I believe solution adequately addresses the problem of tactical time-wasting without introducing too many new problems to the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609669820.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>This is sort of what I had in mind. You don’t have to stop for everything.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
