<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="48" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31608736675.0" user="abbaahmad" delta="False">
    <text>My question to you is "why is it important for the players to play the complete 90mins of football?" Whether the ball is in play for 90mins or even 45 mins doesn't mean we get value for our time and/or money. Besides, in most matches, teams are allowed only 3 substitutions. It'll mean if the players, who by the way on average now run about 7 miles a game, to run even more? In American football, while the defense is playing, the offense is resting, in basketball, there's no limit on substitutions, dunno about hockey, though I imagine it's the same. This, in my opinion will only worsen the quality of play. The pitches are big(110 -120 yards by 70-80 yards), and every outfield player runs a great deal at the end of the match. I've watched football for about 20 years, I'd never thought of stoppages until I read the fivethirtyeight article last world cup and I still found it irrelevant. Personally, I think if a person doesn't play football, they don't appreciate the "stoppages"  and the flow of the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609381275.0" user="0kely_d0kely" delta="False">
    <text>Not OP but I subscribe to a similar view. For me the issue isn't that there isn't 90min of play, it's that the amount of play can vary wildly and can be largely controlled by a team looking to waste time.

A successful change to the system would likely end up reducing the clock to an amount of time representative of the time that the ball is usually in play.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
