<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607327201.0" user="iuwerih" delta="False">
    <text>While this system would affect timewasting, it wouldn't completely eliminate it. A lot of timewasting is just teams holding the ball and playing conservatively, which there is no rule against. Also, this doesn't change things like rotational fouling or deliberately breaking up play by committing a foul. 'Flopping' (diving to us Brits) is something that can and should be punished seperately - by a yellow card on the pitch, and retroactive punishment, and VAR will cut down on diving as well. You don't need to change how games are timed

If anything, you have even less of an idea of when the game will end. Now, you know you have 90 minutes + 15 for half time, + maybe 10 minutes max as stoppage time (unless it's a game which goes to extra time, but most don't). So you can accurately predict when a game will end to within 10 minutes. With your system, not only do you have no idea how much stoppage there will be, but you also have no incentive to restart play quickly. There's no difference between a 2 minute stoppage and a 10 second stoppage, so why not drag out every stoppage, get a bit of a rest and disrupt your opponent's momentum? Just as the current system can be gamed, so can this one, except this one would also be bad for the spectators and absolutely terrible for broadcasters, who have less certainty on how long the games they broadcast will take and will struggle to fit programming in as a result. You could also have problems like uneven halves, where one half takes far longer than another.

Discretion is dangerous, but as we can see with VAR, sometimes, leaving things to the referee's discretion makes the game flow better and reduces interruptions. That's why we have referees. We could have every game have 10 officials scrutinising every decision with 10 cameras from 10 differet angles at 10 different speeds. But it would slow the game down to an unbearable degree. Changes, especially changes that take control of officiating out of referee's hands, risk harming the spectator's experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607541122.0" user="ThaChalupaBatman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but you also have no incentive to restart play quickly. There's no difference between a 2 minute stoppage and a 10 second stoppage, so why not drag out every stoppage, get a bit of a rest and disrupt your opponent's momentum?

For this point, they could be booked for excessively delaying the game the same way they can be booked for wasting time. Just because the clock has stopped, doesn't mean the ref will just let them do whatever they want and let them take 5 minutes to set up a free kick. Taking too long while the clock is stopped would be punishable the same way taking too long while the clock is running is. Nothing would change except for the fact that refs wouldn't need to add on time after the 45 and 90 minutes are up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607806073.0" user="iuwerih" delta="False">
    <text>But now you can't take 5 minutes to set up a free kick either, you'll get booked for such blatant timewasting.

And as a system it still relies on the referee's discretion to determine how long is too long, just in a different context. So, really it's still going to have the same weaknesses as the current system, that being that it's only as good as the referee who is officiating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607597649.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There's no difference between a 2 minute stoppage and a 10 second stoppage, so why not drag out every stoppage, get a bit of a rest and disrupt your opponent's momentum?

All of the clock stopping times sports have a delay of game penalty if you take an unreasonable amount of time to return to the game. In basketball if you don't inbound the ball promptly, your team will be given a technical foul. In football you lose 5 yards if you don't reach the line of scrimmage on time. In hockey you'll receive a penalty for putting the puck over the glass in the offensive zone or for intentionally delaying the face off. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607815708.0" user="iuwerih" delta="False">
    <text>And football also currently has a penalty for timewasting. And it's a yellow card, which is more of a punishment than one technical foul, and in a lot of circumstances worse than losing 5 yards.

And it's not like players who timewaste are idiots. They'll slow the game down just enough to be able to deny timewasting, just like they do now - which is why you don't see it punished as much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608820663.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>But you can police how long stoppages last. I ref for a different sport (ultimate) where, due to games being played overwhelming in a tournament format, with multiple games in a day on a schedule, the clock doesn't stop (though we have a single-game format where it does stop and the game moves pretty quickly, including during fouls and out-of-bounds plays). During timeouts, there is a strict time limit for when you have to be ready to play again. During most "live-play" stoppages (turnovers, out-of-bounds), there is a strict time limit to continue play (with exceptions made for discs that go far out-of-bounds). During dead stoppages (fouls, other violations) we keep the players from taking too long to restart.

If we trust the referee to calculate stoppage time, we can trust him/her to manage the pace of the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31609127323.0" user="Alter__Eagle" delta="False">
    <text>There's a certain sense of urgency that would be lost with the clock stopping for free kicks for example. Let's say a favourite has a bad result against an underdog with 5 minutes to go, for a free kick or a corner they might choose to sacrifice some time and bring more bodies up front or they can do the opposite and restart extremely fast. Decisions like this bring variation and tension to the game. With stoppages you would lose that dynamic. In fact you would incentivize the team that is chasing the result to take the maximum time allowed per stoppage.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
