<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="675611334.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b68p1i/cmv_if_the_polishsoviet_annexation_of_the_eastern/">
    <title>CMV: If the Polish-Soviet annexation of the eastern German territories following World War 2 was justified, then so too is the Israeli annexation of the Golan Heights</title>
    <original_poster>SpacemanSkiff</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Golan Heights were occupied by Israel following a defensive war against a coalition of Arab nations including Syria, the nation formerly in control of the aforementioned Heights. Following the Israeli victory, they occupied the Heights as a matter of national security, and have recently been moving to annex them formerly.

Many people say that this annexation is unwarranted, unjust, or illegal. However, precedence shows that this is not the case. Following World War 2, the USSR and Poland annexed about a fourth of Germany, and forcibly expelled some ten million people from their homes (including those expelled from other neighboring nations like Czechia). International law views this annexation as valid.

If international law views the annexation of Eastern Germany by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression as valid, then it follows that the annexation of the Golan Heights by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression is likewise valid.

Either both are valid, or both are invalid.

CMV.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31655171247.0" user="that-one-guy-youknow" delta="False">
    <text>The allies wanted Stalin to give up all his Polish/German territories, allow them to be independent and have free elections. Correct me if I'm wrong, but we didn't get our way not because we accepted what the USSR wanted to do, we were powerless to stop it. We didn't want to start another war with Russia. Thus the Cold War was initiated. So the Polish-Soviet annexation was illegitimate

&amp;gt; International law views this annexation as valid

What's the evidence for this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31655190676.0" user="SpacemanSkiff" delta="False">
    <text>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/German–Polish_Border_Treaty

This treaty finalizes the German Polish border along the Oder Neisse line. This was instated under pressure by the international community who recognized the Polish-Soviet annexation of the eastern German territories as valid. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31655435734.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31656534405.0" user="Nebraska29" delta="False">
    <text>This is a bit of realpolitik as others have pointed out, but that’s true for all international law. Power, not principles, are how the world works. The UN’s and Hague’s rhetoric is often just that, for better or worse.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
