<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="675611334.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b68p1i/cmv_if_the_polishsoviet_annexation_of_the_eastern/">
    <title>CMV: If the Polish-Soviet annexation of the eastern German territories following World War 2 was justified, then so too is the Israeli annexation of the Golan Heights</title>
    <original_poster>SpacemanSkiff</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Golan Heights were occupied by Israel following a defensive war against a coalition of Arab nations including Syria, the nation formerly in control of the aforementioned Heights. Following the Israeli victory, they occupied the Heights as a matter of national security, and have recently been moving to annex them formerly.

Many people say that this annexation is unwarranted, unjust, or illegal. However, precedence shows that this is not the case. Following World War 2, the USSR and Poland annexed about a fourth of Germany, and forcibly expelled some ten million people from their homes (including those expelled from other neighboring nations like Czechia). International law views this annexation as valid.

If international law views the annexation of Eastern Germany by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression as valid, then it follows that the annexation of the Golan Heights by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression is likewise valid.

Either both are valid, or both are invalid.

CMV.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31655592205.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31655644200.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/Slenderpman – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), before [messaging the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+Slenderpman&amp;amp;message=Slenderpman+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/b68p1i/-/ejix79p/\)+because...). Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
