<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="675611334.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b68p1i/cmv_if_the_polishsoviet_annexation_of_the_eastern/">
    <title>CMV: If the Polish-Soviet annexation of the eastern German territories following World War 2 was justified, then so too is the Israeli annexation of the Golan Heights</title>
    <original_poster>SpacemanSkiff</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Golan Heights were occupied by Israel following a defensive war against a coalition of Arab nations including Syria, the nation formerly in control of the aforementioned Heights. Following the Israeli victory, they occupied the Heights as a matter of national security, and have recently been moving to annex them formerly.

Many people say that this annexation is unwarranted, unjust, or illegal. However, precedence shows that this is not the case. Following World War 2, the USSR and Poland annexed about a fourth of Germany, and forcibly expelled some ten million people from their homes (including those expelled from other neighboring nations like Czechia). International law views this annexation as valid.

If international law views the annexation of Eastern Germany by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression as valid, then it follows that the annexation of the Golan Heights by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression is likewise valid.

Either both are valid, or both are invalid.

CMV.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31655189803.0" user="Kirbyoto" delta="False">
    <text>One potential difference is that Israel and Syria did not have an alliance after the war and relationships between the two remained hostile. In comparison, the annexation of Germany that you described took place as a redistribution between three allied governments (the opinions of the populace notwithstanding). That is to say, East Germany, Poland, and the USSR were all "on the same side" when they made the agreement. In contrast, Israel did not take over Syria, rightly or not, and so its action was very clearly taking territory from a still-hostile nation instead of convincing a now-allied nation to cede some territories "willingly".

Another point to note is that the claim of "redress for grievances" was controversial even at the time, which is why Poland and the USSR both invoked historical Polish claims on the region ("*Dmitrow says that "in official justifications for the border shift, the decisive argument that it presented a compensation for the loss of the eastern half of the pre-war Polish territory to the USSR, was viewed as obnoxious and concealed. Instead, a historical argumentation was foregrounded with the dogma, Poland had just returned to 'ancient Piast lands.*'").

Finally, if you want to compare Israel's current tactics to a Stalinist-era policy of ethnic removal...I doubt many opponents of Israel would object to that. Except for the ones who like Stalin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31656015166.0" user="Goldberg31415" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; East Germany, Poland, and the USSR were all "on the same side"

They were on "the same side" as occupied nations of Europe were on the side of the third reich. The eastern bloc nations were occupied by the soviet union with puppet governments in place that were independent in name only or annexed like Baltic states</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
