<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="675611334.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b68p1i/cmv_if_the_polishsoviet_annexation_of_the_eastern/">
    <title>CMV: If the Polish-Soviet annexation of the eastern German territories following World War 2 was justified, then so too is the Israeli annexation of the Golan Heights</title>
    <original_poster>SpacemanSkiff</original_poster>
    <original_post>The Golan Heights were occupied by Israel following a defensive war against a coalition of Arab nations including Syria, the nation formerly in control of the aforementioned Heights. Following the Israeli victory, they occupied the Heights as a matter of national security, and have recently been moving to annex them formerly.

Many people say that this annexation is unwarranted, unjust, or illegal. However, precedence shows that this is not the case. Following World War 2, the USSR and Poland annexed about a fourth of Germany, and forcibly expelled some ten million people from their homes (including those expelled from other neighboring nations like Czechia). International law views this annexation as valid.

If international law views the annexation of Eastern Germany by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression as valid, then it follows that the annexation of the Golan Heights by a nation that had been on the receiving end of aggression is likewise valid.

Either both are valid, or both are invalid.

CMV.
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31655376956.0" user="Barnst" delta="False">
    <text>An unfortunate reality of international politics is that might often makes right.  The new German-Polish border was imposed by the Soviet Union, first during the Potsdam Conference, then by treaty with East Germany after the war, and then as a condition for German reunification in 1990.  At none of these points was the rest of the international community able or interested in resisting this outcome, regardless of whether they felt it was “legitimate.”   Larger geopolitical interests were simply more important.

The same holds true now—whether the original act was legitimate or not, the parties involved find it better to act as if it is legitimate now than to contest the original actions.   That might not have been the case 100 years ago and Germany could very easily have held on to its claims as a *causus belli* against Poland, but Germany a long time ago decided to prioritize the greater project of European political unity over maintaining old territorial disputes and other nationalist grievances.   So whether or not the original act was legitimate, Germany has consciously chosen to legitimize it in the pursuit of other aims.

The same thing is true in the Middle East—the “legitimacy” of Israel’s claim to the Golan Heights doesn’t depend on some precedent of international law.  It depends on whether Syria and other states decide to recognize it, for whatever reason.  To date, they have not.  If they ever do decide to accept the status quo, it will probably be because they’ve decided that some broader regional settlement is more important for their national interests than maintaining a claim to a range of hills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31655707906.0" user="SpacemanSkiff" delta="False">
    <text>!delta

You've pointed out a fact I seem to have overlooked or neglected -- that international actions of this sort are (typically at least) motivated more by geopolitical realities and strategic interests rather than principled stances of any sort.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
