<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677271665.0" user="forrealimadetective" delta="False">
    <text>As other posters have said, I do agree that immigration is good.  Unchecked illegal immigration, however, is not.  If you break down the cost per illegal immigrant for any services they receive, vs the amount of tax paid, you will see it is a net loss to the country.  Yes, I am aware some pay their fair share of taxes, but according to some sources, only around half of illegal (undocumented, etc) immigrants pay taxes:

https://www.vox.com/2018/4/13/17229018/undocumented-immigrants-pay-taxes

This article says that 4.4 million people paid taxes without a social security number for $23.6 billion in taxes.  If you extrapolate those numbers out to an average of around 300 million citizens, the country would only collect around $1.6 trillion, which is around 1/3 of the total amount collected each year.

According to nbcnews (https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/fact-check-how-much-does-illegal-immigration-cost-america-not-n950981) illegal immigrants can account for as much as $54 Billion a year.

Now, is this going to bankrupt the country? No.  If this were a business, though, would you keep this line of your business open indefinitely, operating at a loss? I wouldn't.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
