<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677067167.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>While I tend to agree with you, it is very important to note that immigration _can_ be a good thing (and often is) but it is not _universally_ a good thing.

Immigration - particularly the value of low-skill immigrants - depends on two key economic factors to be successful:

- High opportunity for value-add work for workers of the immigrants skillset

- Low opportunity for social program access for workers of the immigrants skillset without corresponding value addition.

If there are few jobs available to immigrant workers, and no barriers to social program access, then immigrants can become a net drain on the economy.  People will come and get benefits without contributing to the society that is providing those benefits, either by choice or by circumstance.

Now, that all said, we don't live in a society that meets the two criteria I have put forward - we _do_ have jobs for lower-skilled immigrants to take and we _do_ have barriers that prevent people from coming and just leeching off the system unfairly.  In our system (as with most economic systems in the world) immigration - even low skilled immigration - is a net positive.  It just isn't necessarily so in _every_ economic system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677722310.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>Very good points made.  I knew we had a problem with people abusing the system and receiving more benefits than what they're putting in, but I think its unfair to assume that's what immigrants are doing.  I was more under the impression that immigrants are driving change and new ideas but in order to get there we first had to get them into our "system" which is powered by education and individual freedoms.  First generation immigrants might not be able to achieve this, but 2nd and 3rd generations should.  Regardless I think you bring up some valid points</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31678308471.0" user="JovianLizard" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If there are few jobs available to immigrant workers, and no barriers to  social program access, then immigrants can become a net drain on the  economy. 

Why would this a problem caused by immigration? It could just as easily be viewed as a problem caused by a lack of barriers to accessing social programs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31682652814.0" user="iwillcorrectyou" delta="False">
    <text>Because illegals without work and without access to social programs is even worse than being a drain on our welfare. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
