<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31680407577.0" user="FindTheGenes" delta="False">
    <text>I hear this claim a lot about how diversity supposedly "drives innovation." How? By what mechanisms exactly does diversity help us innovate? How is it that relatively homogenous nations in Europe and Asia are thriving in the first world and advancing so quickly? I just don't see the evidence demonstrating that by opening our borders further and allowing larger waves of immigration that the US or any other nation would actually experience any boost to innovation. Hell, before 1965, the US had an immigration policy specifically designed to keep whites as a supermajority, and it worked until it was abandoned. non-Hispanic whites have made up about 80% or higher of the US population for almost its entire history. It developed the first and second ever atom bombs during a time when it was almost 90% non-Hispanic white. I'm not seeing the US suffering in the innovation and advancement department due to a lack of diversity.

And hatred of other groups of people neither necessarily follows from homogeneity nor necessarily hinders development. Don't get me wrong, hating people for their race is a bad thing, but less immigration or even near complete homogeneity does not necessarily create hatred, and this hatred (if it comes about at all) does not necessarily hinder advancement. 

In fact, I would argue that increased immigration pushing more different groups of people together creates more trouble and conflict than it would ever eliminate. The simple fact is that groups of people are different in significant and important ways, and many groups tend not to mix very well. They often clash and/or separate themselves. Chicago, for example, is one of the most diverse cities in the US, and it is one of the most self-segregated. Multicultural society or not, group differences and in-group preferences exist, they are not going away, and they cause problems when different groups interact. 

Then of course there is the destruction of different cultures and genetic diversity as different groups of pepole mix, which is obviously not ideal. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
