<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677241635.0" user="Slenderpman" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with the sentiment, but in practice uncontrolled immigration can legitimately lead to some problems. And again, I do wholeheartedly believe regulated immigration is a good thing, and I'm even more open to it than many. I'm only in the US because my great great grandfather was able to use chain migration to escape Russian pogroms in the early 1900s. 

But back to the main point, which is that too many unskilled and illiterate immigrants is a strain on society. I'm not going to go so far as to say it causes crime, because I don't agree with that, but if we want to expand our social services (which are currently kind of shitty), we need to prioritize those who are already taxpaying citizens (or legal residents). I hate to sound so nationalist, but if the United States were to institute considerably better social policy in regards to things like healthcare, education, and housing assistance, we would undoubtedly have a flood of immigrants trying to use those services. If those immigrants are mostly low skilled, they're not paying high enough taxes to fund the influx. I'm all for the super wealthy paying much higher taxes, but when the most disadvantaged people (in addition to the native poor) severely outnumber those paying the most taxes, it's hard for the system to keep up. 

Now all that being said, if we were able to create social systems that functioned with enough efficiency, I say the more the merrier. Diversity is inherently a good thing so if our systems can handle the extra people and put them in a position where they can assimilate (in a good way), integrate into middle class society, and pay taxes, then I'd be much more in favor of allowing more immigrants. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
