<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677429759.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>We almost all universally support immigration when it comes to high skilled labor especially in markets where we have a shortage.  Nobody gets upset when world class doctors or folks like Elon Musk immigrate to america.

The controversy comes when unskilled laborers immigrate to america.  Basic principles of supply and demand apply to labor markets.  More supply (more workers) means a lower price (lower wages).  immigration of unskilled laborers hurts unskilled laborers already in america.  it drives down the price of unskilled labors.  what good is your diversified communities to someone who cannot find a job?  great so now i cannot afford american food or Mexican food.

personally, I'm not an unskilled laborer.  I'm considered high skilled labor.  So immigration is great for me.  It drives down costs of goods.  I can reap the rewards of diversity: better food, art, rich culture.  Its great for me.

We can debate about whether or not the net effect is positive or negative.  That's hard to say.  but its absolutely not true that its good for everyone.

(the same argument applies to automation btw.  Good for some people, and in long term probably everyone.  But bad for many people especially in the short term)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677861097.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>I think high skilled labor is mostly what i was referring to about driving innovation, in theory, it should lead to better results.  

When it comes to low skilled labor i disagree.  I don't think the flood of immigrants leads to lower wages because the immigrants make up such a small proportion of the working class.  The working class wage is determined by the value of social economic factors like cost of living, GDP and so on.  I don't see the labor market as clear cut as supply and demand.  If I were more educated on this issue im sure i'd be able to make some good counter arguments so you've given me some stuff to look into.  For now since im not that informed I'll just say that I really don't think Immigrants are stealing our jobs and flooding the markets.  

Overall I think immigration has better impacts than it does negative although I think its region based.   Lower income areas are not going to have the same opinions as people who live in cities or more diverse areas.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677990175.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If I were more educated on this issue im sure i'd be able to make some good counter arguments so you've given me some stuff to look into.

You will find what I am saying is true.  these are my ideas, its what I learned in my economics courses.

&amp;gt;Overall I think immigration has better impacts than it does negative

I agree, but you have to think about it this way.  There is a net benefit to society but a small group is suffering because of it.

There are about 10 million undocumented immigrants in the US.  That's enough to have an effect on our economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31678148531.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If I were more educated on this issue im sure i'd be able to make some good counter arguments

I'm really interested in why you said this.

I can't articulate very well why its interesting.  I don't want to come off as condescending.  Its like you are assuming that the education would prove you right.  You're sure you're correct, but you don't yet know the facts that prove you correct. But if you don't know the facts that prove your correct, then doesn't that mean you don't know whether or not you're correct?

Why are you "sure" that an education would prove you correct?  Its worth thinking about.

we all do this.  We form an opinion and then we look for evidence to support our opinion.  We sure look for evidence, then form the opinion.  But we rarely do it in that order.  and even rarer do we catch ourselves doing it in the wrong order.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31678285047.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>Simply cause I don’t believe immigration is to blame for our low skilled labor issues. There’s always two sides to an argument and each one is usually right in its own way.  I can’t debate or discuss something that I don’t know anything about.  If I were better informed maybe I could offer some counter points but I cannot do that if I don’t have the facts. 

Im not trying to prove anyone wrong thats not what I set out to do.  But if someone says “I can’t find a job because all the immigrants take them” then I don’t sit well with that, don’t make an ignorant statement like that before you actually understand the issue. Once you do then you’re free to air your opinions and have discussion. So that’s really all I was trying to say</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31678358030.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>Oh fair enough.

I didn't say it was to blame for our low skilled labor issues and i don't think that it is to blame for our low skilled labor issues.

What I said what that it hurts unskilled laborers already in the country.  (it helps some unskilled laborers, the ones coming into america).

The effect that it has unskilled labor is sometimes exaggerated.  Trump certainly exaggerates it.  A sometimes it is overlooked.  You are overlooking it. 

immigration, automation, and outsourcing are the 3 big things hitting unskilled labor and they are all a net positive.  They are all a net positive for me.  So its tempting for me to ignore or downplay their negative side effects.  

I'm in favor of all of them, and to be honest I don't really care when immigration our outsourcing hurts people.  If an american loses their job to a Mexican or Indian, why should i care more about the American's needs?  Just because i'm american?  I care a little because our collective national security is also my security.  I'm saying they get hurt, i'm not saying i care that they get hurt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31696843032.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think high skilled labor is mostly what i was referring to about driving innovation, in theory, it should lead to better results.

It leads to better results for one particular country, perhaps, but it's part of that brain drain you might hear about.  Advocating for the US to take in so many skilled workers is advocating that the US essentially win and beat other countries.  It's not advocacy for diversity or general help, since the US is already advanced and clearly we aren't just sharing what we have anyway.  We end up with *products,* and we don't always share anyway.  We can invent the computer but then we don't offer it in other people's languages, and it's been hypothesized that if computer tech were made immediately available in places like Africa, most languages there would die off within a decade easily.  That doesn't sound like a pull for diversity either.

In response to the larger body of your post:

&amp;gt;Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities. There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.

We already know from looking at a place like the US that when people mix together a lot, you don't still have a lot of cultures.  The US tends to strip people of their culture.  A 1st generation family's kid will likely understand their parents' language but not really speak it themselves.  It'll be lost by the 3rd generation, if it even holds out.  The kids all end up speaking English instead.  As with computers, it wouldn't make places more diverse.  It would make places less diverse.  People are already, in some areas, abandoning their own ways and their own culture to be Western - or specifically American.  I don't see that as a plus, because no culture is superior.  I therefore favor the very diversity we have and may be losing.  It's not other cultures that'll win out either.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
