<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677060848.0" user="empurrfekt" delta="False">
    <text>This is a straw man position. Virtually no one opposes immigration. The opposition is to open borders and unchecked access to the country. 

So why do you want it changed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677244988.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>Is that really true though?  It seems to me that the people who are opposed to illegal immigration *also* want to restrict or eliminate what would be considered legal pathways for immigration.  For example, eliminating DACA.  Seems to me like it is actually the concern for legality that is the straw man for what boils down to simple xenophobia. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677325359.0" user="empurrfekt" delta="False">
    <text>Saying DACA is legal immigration is like saying it’s a legal transfer of property for the thief to keep your tv. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677457617.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>

Not really.  It's more like saying "this person came here as a child, without any say in the matter, and sending them back to their country of origin would be incredibly cruel since all of their formative experiences have taken place here, so we should let them stay as long as they aren't getting into trouble and are working or pursuing an education".  Actually, that's pretty much exactly what it is saying. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677506784.0" user="empurrfekt" delta="False">
    <text>Fine, it’s like letting the thief’s kid keep your laptop because that’s where all their social media passwords are saved. Where his homework and college essays are stored. Where all his game data are. And it would be cruel to rip all that away from him. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677542982.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>That's a better analogy but it is still just an analogy.  You don't really need an analogy at all to understand the very basic level of human empathy that justifies the policy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679638003.0" user="Mnozilman" delta="False">
    <text>Except the policy is being exploited by illegal immigrants</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679768965.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. DACA is not open to newcomers.  Only those who were around when it was announced and met the requirements at the time. How do you think it's being exploited?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
