<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677164827.0" user="zobotsHS" delta="False">
    <text>It is a situational argument at its core. Immigration _can_ be good. In some circumstances it _can_ be bad. Immigration is only a word because a sovereign nation-state is a thing that exists. Because of that, each state gets to decide who can come in, and should. 

If a country can benefit from immigrants (most cases this is true) then absolutely. If, for example, unemployment is high among the populace, then it should likely be reduced for a bit, as a nation's obligation is to their citizens first. The opposition to immigration isn't always racist or bigoted in nature. Some of it is, certainly. 

It isn't as simple as a thumbs up or thumbs down on the issue as a whole. Saying "Water is a good thing" is true in most cases...but not to one who is drowning.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
