<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31686266902.0" user="starship-unicorn" delta="False">
    <text>I think there are problems with the strength of the claim you are making. It's pretty clear that immigration is often a good thing, but I think it's also clear that it is *not always* a good thing *for everyone*.

The easiest, most America-focused examples I can think of are 1) America itself and 2) Texas.

1. The US was founded by European (primarily English) colonial immigrants, but their immigration was definitely lot a good thing universally. From the perspective of native tribes, it was a huge disaster.

2. American immigrants flooded into Northern Mexico in the early 1800s. At first, most immigrated legally, but the Mexican government grew concerned and began adding restrictions. Eventually a large number of immigrants led a revolt against the Mexican government, eventually gaining Texan independence and then admission into the US. From a Mexican perspective, the immigration of Americans into the area that became Texas, both legal and illegal, was definitely a bad thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
