<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677474219.0" user="kaczinski_chan" delta="False">
    <text>Diversity does not drive innovation. The vast majority of innovations throughout history are the product of a select few demographics. White and Asian men are the only demographics in America that produce more taxes than they consume. Everybody else hampers innovation by consuming more resources than they produce, that could otherwise be spent on it. https://imgur.com/a/KkG9Rsm</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677950725.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think you fully grasp what innovation is, its new creative ideas and insight.  Imagine being in a room full of middle class white males trying to figure out a better way to communicate with foreign business markets.   Then in walks a Japanese man who has international business experience and you hire him to be on your team.  Now you have a leg up on your competition and you have a new perspective, with that comes innovation.  

You can't pin point certain demographics and decide that's the only innovation that takes place, its a universal adaptation thats always happening.  Its also not always about money and resources either.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679783102.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>Innovation has nothing to do with who produces the most or consumes the most.  It's a product of friction in viewpoints, thinking styles, or culture.  It's when something old is seen in a new light by someone new with a different perspective.  There are several studies in psychology that strongly reinforce the notion that more diverse groups are better at creative problem solving.  Everyone thinking the same way is bad for innovation.


Illegal immigrants also pay more in taxes than they receive in benefits because they can't collect government benefits or file for tax refunds even though they often work under borrowed social security numbers.  When it comes to taxes, they can't legally be takers so they're pretty much exclusively givers. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
