<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677249321.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>People are not arguing for ending immigration, so you are trying to fight a strawman. What people are upset about are those that ignore our laws and come into the country outside of the proper channels. They do not respect our culture, nor do they respect actual immigrants. They are criminals by being here illegally and need to be treated as such. The proper legal punishment prescribed for them is deportation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677350391.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>I think wherever there are loopholes people will exploit them case and point taxes.  I don’t agree that people disrespect our culture though unless you could provide some examples.  I think people who immigrate to America experience the most disrespect out of the group. 

I don’t think it’s necessary to deport people either, unless they’re violating the law (outside of them being alien) than I have no problem with them being here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677356514.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>If they do not follow proper protocols they do not immigrate at all. They simply cross the border. They are not immigrants. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679734691.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>Even if that was true (and it's actually not), it would be a pedantic point with no real value to the conversation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31698222538.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>But we don't like loopholes for taxes, so bringing that up is very strange.  We want to close loopholes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31699448961.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn’t call it a loophole even I would just call it cheating the system.  My grandpa puts farm use for all the gas he uses even when its not farm use.  People don’t always declare all the income they make etc.  People are always going to be crooks, just look at our president.  He got elected so he could go in and change the tax brackets for his own businesses.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31699509420.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't address my point.  We don't like that.  Your grandfather is committing tax fraud, by the sound of it.  Why does someone get unfettered access to another country because your grandfather lies on his forms?  I don't see the connection.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677435604.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't true at all.  Lots of people want to cut back on immigration.  We could easily end illegal immigration but allowing everyone in legally.  Remove quotas.  But that's not way people want.  They want to reduce total immigration by stopping illegal immigration.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31677778257.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>Many people are arguing for ending or greatly reducing legal immigration.  It is not a strawman.  The Trump administration in the US for example [has been taking a lot of actions to cut legal immigration.](https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/world/2018/06/12/donald-trump-cutting-legal-immigration/692447002/)  Of particular note Trump frequently attacks the idea of "chain migration," which is his pejorative term for US citizens sponsoring noncitizen relatives to immigrate legally.  He has [blocked other immigration-related legislation on the grounds that it does not stop this form of legal immigration.](https://www.latimes.com/politics/washington/la-na-essential-washington-updates-trump-says-chain-migration-can-t-be-1505483310-htmlstory.html)

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679387094.0" user="cdb03b" delta="False">
    <text>Chain migration for a spouse or children that are still minors is logical. Having it for Elderly parents, adult siblings, cousins, etc is not. Having family should only be a boon to your immigration status if they immediate family so cleaning up the program is a good thing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679515414.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>So then OP was not arguing against a strawman, as people (yourself included) are in fact arguing to reduce legal immigration.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679718982.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>This argument itself is a red herring, as anytime someone suggests making it possible for more people to come here legally so they don't have to do so illegally the people making this "law and order" argument are almost universally opposed to those types of reforms.   The truth is it just sounds nicer than "Other cultures make me feel uncomfortable" and it's a nice bit of cognitive dissonance for those who are unwilling to admit to themselves that's actually how they feel. 


Coming here illegally is tantamount to stealing a loaf of bread to feed your family. It's being willing to do whatever it takes, damn the risk, to do what's best for the people you love or even just to try to be the best possible version of yourself.   Anyone who wouldn't come here illegally, doesn't belong here legally.  

The only thing that separates legal immigrants from illegal ones is luck. Either having had the benefit of better circumstances (better education or family who have already immigrated) or luck of the draw in our racist lottery system.  Either way, do you truly believe that luck makes people better than those without luck?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
