<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677077344.0" user="Ottomatik80" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like some clarification on your stance. 

Are you suggesting that some people are arguing for an end to all immigration, or an end to illegal immigration?

Based on that response, are you arguing for an end to the rules and requirements surrounding immigration into the US?

For what it's worth, the current immigration debate in the US revolves around people entering the country illegally. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679759472.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Are you suggesting that some people are arguing for an end to all immigration, or an end to illegal immigration?

There's no real difference. Our immigration system was designed to minimize non-white immigration. Without serious reform, to "legal" immigration, it's not a real option for 99% of people and the people who rail against illegal immigration never support the sorts of reforms that would create a legitimate alternative.  Opposition to illegal immigration is just trying to put a nicer face on an ugly idea.  It's easy to say you support legal immigration when you know full well that legal immigration might as well be a unicorn for 99% of the world's population and ,99.99% of the people who actually want to immigrate. 

The truth is, there's nobody out there talking about being opposed to illegal immigration who is actually talking about reforming our immigration system to make it possible for people to come here legally instead. That's because for all intents and purposes, being opposed to illegal immigration and being opposed to immigration are the same thing.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31679793524.0" user="Ottomatik80" delta="False">
    <text>You're absolutely incorrect. 

Most of us believe that laws are to be followed, and that they should be changed if we no longer want to enforce them. 

We want immigrants, we simply want them to come here legally. We also want reform to the immigration system, but politicians take stances like yours, where it's either open borders or your a racist. Nothing will happen when you play that game. 

It's not a dogwhistle, or hidden racism. Simply enforce the laws, and fix the system to more easily allow in those that need to come here.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31680967893.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>All I can say in response is that there are currently exactly zero politicians representing that view. if it truly is a common viewpoint, I wonder why it is represented by exactly zero people at the legislative level.

Maybe you truely feel that way, but the evidence suggests you're in a very tiny minority.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31681053084.0" user="Ottomatik80" delta="False">
    <text>Even Trump says we need to fix the laws and the border. 

The majority if Republicans have constantly been saying stop the flood of illegal immigrations, then fix the immigration laws. 

You've really got to stop listening only to Vox and Mother Jones. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31681061641.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>Fixing the laws would stop the flood as you call it.  People are only coming here illegally because there's no alternative, not because they're too lazy to fill out some paperwork.  Do you understand how ridiculously dangerous it is tocross the border?  Do you honestly believe that people are incurring that level of risk because they simply can't be bothered to fill out some forms?  Yes, a very tiny percentage has past convictions for crimes that would probably exclude them from legal entry even if our laws were reformed, but by and large people who come here illegally would choose to come here legally if they could.  They just don't have 20 years to wait trying to win a lottery slot.  

Nobody seriously wants to fix that problem because what they actually want is no more immigration.  Find me one legislative proposal to reform immigration laws by someone supporting a border wall.  It simply doesn't exist and it's farcical to suggest that people are just waiting for more border security to suggest it.  moreover, if they were willing to pass that kind of law, democrats would join them and vote yes on both laws as a package.  They would absolutely support stronger border security if we were actually going to do something about fixing legal immigration.The reason Republicans won't make that compromise is because they don't want more legal immigration.  That's literally the only rational explanation.  Otherwise, Trump would have his useless wall. Most liberals would happily sign on to pointlessly wasting 30 billion dollars on a vanity project if it would come packaged with fixing our immigration system.  Trump will never make that offer because he does not want non-white immigrants.  He's literally said as much.

Show me one single proposal. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31681257793.0" user="Ottomatik80" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2018/06/20/republicans-are-taking-one-more-shot-at-immigration-reform-theyre-going-to-fail/?utm_term=.a3c4fe616d45

Republicans had competing bills to begin the immigration reform process about a year ago.  Both even provided citizenship to the Dreamers, yet Democrats refused to support either one. 

Border security reduces the number of people coming here illegally. 

 People are coming here illegally for a number of reasons; it's quicker than the current legal process, there are essentially no legal repurcussions once you get here, and they are obviously leaving a worse situation at home. 
None of that excuses them from breaking our laws. We have a process in place for asylum where that applies, 

I wish you were correct in thinking that Democrats would support the wall in exchange for better immigration laws. The Democrats proved you wrong just a few months back and forced a shutdown over their resistance to the wall. They could've negotiated whatever reform they wanted, but we both know that's not the Democrat platform. 

I do think that the majority of Americans support both a stronger border and better immigration laws. Our politicians however, are all worthless and will do nothing other than grandstand. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31681384983.0" user="Maxfunky" delta="False">
    <text>The proposal you've linked to has really nothing to say on actual immigration reform.  It just covers DACA and border security.  It does nothing to reform the status quo regarding the system we have for people wanting come here legally (actually it might have had something in there about H-1B visas, I can't recall).  For the record though, some Democrats were very ready to consider that offer but then Donald Trump came out and said it was off the table and that he absolutely would not sign off on it.

The system we have is based on a lottery with an extremely low cap. It was designed to keep people out, not let people in.  Its designed to let only the tiniest trickle of legal immigration happen on a yearly basis. 

And because it's functionallly impossible to come here legally, they come here illegally.  You want to fix illegal immigration over night?  Change this system.  Make it so people can actually come here legally.  It's really as simple as that. 

Again though, zero people on the anti-immigration side are proposing changes to this because they are, in point of fact, They are in fact anti-immigration.  They simultaneously want to keep the system that gaurantees virtually no legal immigration combined with a security apparatus (which doesn't exist and certainly wouldn't be a wall) to prevent illegal immigration.  

Again, nobody ever offered to make these types of reforms in exchange for a wall because nobody who wants a wall wants an increase in legal immigration. Making this offer would be contrary to their actual goals.  But trust me, if they did, they could get their wall. 


Saying that Democrats forced to shut down is a bit like saying that police forced a hostage taker to kill a hostage by not giving him a helicopter.  For what it's worth, there were several points during the shutdown that Donald Trump indicated he was unwilling to negotiate on basically all of his demands and the things even Republicans suggested as compromises were unacceptable.  
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
