<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31680476803.0" user="Kanonizator" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.

That's a strange sentiment considering that closed borders create zero problems. Ask Saudi Arabia or any other nation state that doesn't allow mass migration.

&amp;gt; Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.

Another strange notion considering it was white nation states in Europe that did most innovating for many centuries and they out-innovated everyone else, including more diverse countries. You think that "diversity is a good thing" because *you are told to believe it* and you meekly comply without asking for proof or thinking about it critically. Really, diversity is a good thing? How come then that since it's pursued by western countries social trust has eroded, crime erupted, racial tensions are higher then ever since the american civil war, etc.? If you look at things objectively "diversity+proximity=war" seems a rather more truthful statement than "diversity is good".

&amp;gt; I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures.

I hate to repeat myself but you believe this because you're told to believe this and you comply because the order comes from accepted authority figures. No critical thinking, no checking the facts, no listening to the other side, no nothing, just meekly believing what you're told to believe. What you described here is utopianistic thinking, a *hateful* wet dream that things will magically turn perfect the moment your political opponents are crushed. If you could eradicate those pesky white supremacists or whatever things would instantly become wonderful, right? And who are these "white supremacists"? Well, anyone who doesn't share your vision about the magical future, ie. hundreds of millions of people in the US and billions worldwide. If you could just snap them away like Thanos...

&amp;gt; Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.

Well, what about it? Air travel was invented and perfected by white people with pretty much zero diversity. Also, just because it's easy to travel it doesn't mean that pushing incompatible people to live among each other is a good idea...

&amp;gt; We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.

Yet another strange notion considering it's mostly PoC who voluntarily segregate themselves when arriving at white countries. It's not Billy Bob who forces Somali migrants in the US to live in tight Somali communities, they *choose to do it* because it's a psychological drive for people of all races and religions to seek out others who are like themselves. Actually it's pretty rare for people to enjoy living in places where nobody is like them, but progressives want to force this onto everyone regardless if they like it or not.

But hey, you're perfectly right in that it's good to explore new places, as long as there are distinct cultures everywhere and not the same abhorrent cultural pigwash. If you visit Paris, London and Melbourne and you can't tell the difference between them because every single one of them is "multicultural" in the exact same way then something is seriously effed up, won't you agree? If I visit other countries I want to experience their specific, authentic cultures, not the very same globalist nonsense I have at home already. Mixing cultures together doesn't add to them, it destroys them. When you visit Paris and there's kebab on every corner but no authentic french bistros any more that's not an "improved" french culture, that's french culture *gone*, destroyed forever.

&amp;gt; There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.

We will reach peak diversity when everything will look the same everywhere. It always puzzles me why progressives want to destroy cultures in the name of progress. Doesn't it bother you that you will never be able to see anything authentic anywhere? You exchanged your chance at visiting Cairo to experience what it is *for what it is*, for the chance at having an egyptian themed restaurant in every city in the world, Cairo included.

&amp;gt; Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.

That's the most laughably wrong idea about history ever. It's an americanist view projecting their own recent melting pot ideals unto the entirety of the west. Most of the west is comprised of nation states that have guarded their borders for thousands of years, and migration was always more of a problem than a boon to them. There are some classic migrant populations like the gypsies and the jews, and you can see how many wonders they have brought to the west, all the joy and peace and vibrancy. Oh, wait, they were always, and still are at the center of racial conflicts. They couldn't integrate literally anywhere, there's not a single country on Earth where these people could learn to cooperate with the locals and lead productive lives. Hurray for diversity, I guess...? Well, it must be that every single nation on Earth is gypsyphobic and antisemitic, but no problem, we will force them to take in migrants anyway, and we will imprison everyone who doesn't like it. For progress!

&amp;gt; With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.

Yeah, for the money. Strange thing is if the US was actually racist, sexist, islamophobic or whatever then PoC, women, muslims, etc. would never want to move there.

&amp;gt; My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it.

It's good for those who migrate, but it's a total net negative for the country that lets them in, both culturally, nationally, economically, and every other way imaginable. You might not be able to grasp this, coming from a melting pot and all, but you could at least understand that the US is an exception as it's a melting pot among nation states, so the rules for it are totally different. You could try to argue that migration is not that bad for melting pots (you'd be wrong, but still) but making sweeping statements like "immigration is good for everyone" is insanely ignorant and misguided.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31680732792.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>You sound Nationalistic.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31684842193.0" user="Kanonizator" delta="False">
    <text>Erhm, do you think this is a rebuttal to anything I've said? I presented at least two dozen actual, fact-based arguments and you dismiss all of them saying you think I sound nationalistic? You're here at CMV, you said you wanted your view changed, and when someone posts a detailed answer you ignore all of it based on that his opinion is different than yours and that's somehow makes it illegitimate? Mind blown.

Anyways, nationalism is not only perfectly okay, it's *the* answer to most of the problems faced by the west nowadays. You know, it's obvious that migration causes problems, we just want to solve it differently. You want to keep migration up and silence/incarcerate those citizens who are negatively affected by it, while I say migration is not so good and it should be controlled more tightly. I wonder which of these solutions causes less human rights violations and less long term strife... Your solution's success depends entirely on silencing tens of millions of people, jailing them if they refuse to keep their mouths shut. How enlightened.

(No, migration is not a "right", and if you think otherwise try arguing about it with Mexico, Israel or Saudi Arabia.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31685991291.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>Correct me if im wrong but you typically look out for your own countries interests and you support being independent.  

I on the other hand believe in unity and diplomatic affairs.  So me and you don’t really see eye to eye on this.  Furthermore im not trying to prove my opinion over yours like you’re trying to do to me.  I don’t think you can be right or wrong here.   Thats why its hard to discuss something like this, cause your so passionate about tour beliefs and they differ from mine but really we’re trying to arrive at the same conclusions we just have different ideas about how to get there.  

Most of what you said I don’t believe in so don’t just assume thats my position.  “You want to keep migration up and incarcerate those who are negatively affected by it.” </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31687292095.0" user="Apprehensive_Clock" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Furthermore im not trying to prove my opinion over yours like you’re trying to do to me.

That is the ENTIRE point of this subreddit you realize right? You are here to have your opinion changed. People are trying to prove your opinion wrong.

&amp;gt;I on the other hand believe in unity and diplomatic affairs.

That's wonderful, but that doesn't mean it's the solution that helps people. Think of it this way, if all the talented workers are leaving your country to go to a more prosperous country it makes it incredibly difficult for progress to occur in that country. It's often referred to as "brain drain". We see this in some states in the US  too where tax money is put into educating it's people and as soon as people get that education they up and leave to another state. Those states are taking tax money that could be spent elsewhere to invest in their future citizens to create a more prosperous future. But if those citizens don't stay, that investment for the future is lost and the state loses for it. If the US is taking all of a developing countries most talented citizens, it's harming that country and impeding their development.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31687485472.0" user="dabbin_z" delta="False">
    <text>In principle it makes sense, more people, more competition.  Whose being hit the most in the short term, probably American citizens.  

I think the main difference is you look at it from an economic standpoint and I see it more as a social issue.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31687576954.0" user="Apprehensive_Clock" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In principle it makes sense, more people, more competition.

I'm not certain you understand what my point was. This response doesn't quite make sense to me. It has nothing to do with competition. 

Again, You should look at the impact of "Brain Drain" it very much is a social issue that has social and economic impacts. Think about it this way, the best and brightest could be either helping develop their country become a better place to live for all it's citizens or they could jump ship and move a developed country, taking much of their talents and resources with them. 

I'll lay it out for you as clear as I can. Say a 3rd world country recognizes it needs a larger group of educated people in order for their country to develop, progress, and help solve the nations issues. So they take a big chunk of the tax money and start building schools, paying for the teachers and school resources in order to educate these kids. But as soon as those kids get educated they say I want to get out of here now that I have the opportunity. So they leave with all the resources that were put into them, all the talents and education they could use to improve where they live and make large impacts on their community.  

You are looking at this 1 individual who is seeking to live in a developed country. You recognize this country they are from is living in poverty and think we should be just letting these people in. I'm looking at the impact this has on the nation they are leaving. The brain drain that's occurring. In reality, the best way to help that country improve it's living conditions is for those educated to stay and help build, develop, and progress. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31690035580.0" user="Kanonizator" delta="False">
    <text>I think people have a right to self determination, which means it's you who decides what you do with your life, and nobody else can force you to do anything against your will. I also think countries (or nations if you will) have the same right on a larger scale. What Kenya or Indonesia wants to do is up to Kenyans and Indonesians, and nobody else. You as an american can't force your will on Kenya or Indonesia, even if you think what they do is unenlightened or whatever. You have to respect their sovereignty. Forcing others to bow to your will is what dictators do. Even if you believe in open borders, or creating one global monoculture destroying diversity, you have to respect that other people think in different ways. THAT IS ALSO DIVERSITY: thinking in different ways. You might think that Mongolian culture would be improved by diluting it with other cultures from all around the globe until it's full of McDonalds' and pizzerias and chinese restaurants, but if you're a decent person you respect that most Mongolians love their own culture as it is, and they don't want to replace it with a globalist pigwash. If other people don't share your vision, that's okay. It's not a problem to rectify. The important thing is that they don't force their ideas onto you, and that in turn *you don't force your ideas on them*. This is the key to live in peace with other people. As long as some groups think they should control other groups there will be war.

&amp;gt; I on the other hand believe in unity and diplomatic affairs. So me and you don’t really see eye to eye on this.

Yeah, but I can tell you with certainty that your ideas don't work in reality. You believe in a very nice utopia that can't be created as of yet. If everyone on Earth had the same vision as you it would work, but - weirdly enough - people are diverse, meaning they don't all share your vision, so you either give up on it, or try to force it on people. Or you might want to slowly push humanity towards accepting your vision but that would take hundreds of years at the very least. In the meantime we live in a world that doesn't look like your utopia, in this existing world migration causes tons of very serious problems you refuse to address. In the existing human world people with very different beliefs can't live together peacefully, no matter how hard you wish they could, they simply can't. You try to rectify this problem by ignoring it. You say let's just force incompatible people to live among each other and when conflict inevitably rises we will throw them in jail. Do you not see how insane this is? Christians are killed by the hundreds in muslim countries and you want to bring islam to christian countries? Are you mad? One of two things will inevitably happen in the long run: either muslims will start to kill christians in christian countries as well, or christians will start to murder muslims in retaliation. Or both. And guess what, *this is already happening*, I'm not talking out of my ass, there are hundreds of casualties already on both sides. Do you think this is a form of "acceptable loss" for moving towards your utopia? You don't mind hundreds of people dying in terror attacks and similar events because it's a price worth paying for open borders? That's how psychopaths think. I don't want anyone to die, not a single person on either side, so I support the only possible solution of not mixing these cultures together. This manifests in both not wanting islamists to move to my christian country *and* not wanting christians to move to muslim countries, because I respect muslim countries' rights to self determination and I don't want to create needless conflict there. The key to peace is for incompatible cultures to stay separated *voluntarily*. This doesn't hurt anyone or anyone's human rights. It doesn't take away or destroy anything of value from the world. It only preserves values.

&amp;gt; I don’t think you can be right or wrong here.

In a philosophical sense, no. But in a practical sense there is a huge difference between the results of implementing my ideas and yours. *You think* implementing your ideas will lead to a wonderful world where everyone lives in peace together. In reality implementing your ideas leads to endless violent conflict and the destruction of cultures, and this is undeniable if you take an honest look at the world. Compare the US with Poland: the US is full of violence, gun crime, racial strife, its culture is divided and eroding day by day, parts of it are fighting each other constantly (think cultural appropriation, demolishing statues of white male historical figures, etc.), and if the political climate is any indication it's headed for a civil war in about 15 years. Poland is a freakin' heaven of authentic Polish culture that's stable, peaceful and prosperous. That's globalism vs. nationalism.

&amp;gt; your so passionate about your beliefs 

Absolutely, as the result of mixing incompatible cultures, ie. the hundreds of dead people in Manchester, New Zealand, Paris, Munchen, etc. is a real pain for me, I see them as innocent victims of culture-mixing who would be alive today if globalists wouldn't have opened their borders (without asking them if they agree with it or not...) letting killer and victim meet each other. Regardless, being passionate doesn't have to mean dismissing logic or facts. You can be totally reasonable while being passionate. I see you promoting your ideas passionately, which is okay in itself, the problem is your ideas objectively don't work.

&amp;gt; Most of what you said I don’t believe in so don’t just assume thats my position. “You want to keep migration up and incarcerate those who are negatively affected by it.”

Oh okay, then let me ask what your plans are with the tens of millions of nationalists, christians, atheists, etc. who see mass migration as a problem? If they can vote they might vote for politicians like Trump, is that okay? If not, should we take their right to vote away? What do we do with actual white supremacists? If they're allowed to exist freely New Zealand will inevitably happen again, so should we jail them all? If not, what's your solution? Your vision can only exist in a world where incompatible cultures don't coexist in the same place and you obviously don't want to restrict immigrant cultures, so you *must* restrict native cultures. There's no other option. Well, you may *dream* that the lamb will lay in peace with the lion, but sorry, that will never happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31736598722.0" user="natusbang" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like I haven't read enough about economic effects of immigration from actual research. I found the following in a bibliography from a paper cited elsewhere in this thread:

&amp;amp;#x200B;

\&amp;gt;Smith and Edmonston (1997, Chapters 4 and 5); Ottaviano and Peri (2006a, 2006b). The two poles in the debate about the wage impact of immigration on natives are George Borjas (immigration reduces low-skilled native wages) and David Card (immigration raises all Americans’ wages). Some key cites from this literature are: Borjas and Aydemir (2006); Borjas (1987, 2003, 2005); Card (1990, 2001, 2005); Card and DiNardo (2000); Engerman and Jones (1997); Borjas et al. (1992, 1996); Friedberg and Hunt (1995); Butcher and Card (1991). For a broader review of the economic consequences of ethnic diversity, see Alesina and La Ferrara (2005).  


Would you be interested in doing a sort of reading group where we read these papers and discuss them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31740502109.0" user="Kanonizator" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I don't have the time or patience for that kind of thing, but I can tell you this: the two poles talk about different kinds of migrations. The side arguing that it's good for the economy talks about the "brain drain", a tightly controlled, merit-based migration that benefits the receiving country (but harms the countries that get drained). The side against migration talks about the current state of affairs, ie. mass migration of low-skilled people who move to the west with the specific stated goal of grabbing on to our social safety nets and leech off them. Since 2015 more than 2 million migrants came to the EU and a good 90% of them haven't find legit work yet, we house and feed them at the taxpayers' expense, or more precisely we do this by taking out huge loans from international banks since no government had reserves for this kind of expenditure. Nobody with an intact brain could argue that the latter is beneficial to the receiving countries, you don't have to read anything to know this for sure. If migrants can't find jobs they don't drive down wages, but taxes have to be raised and/or loans have to be taken to cover for the huge increase in social spending, which has the same effect for the citizens as driving down wages would, only worse.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
