<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="678755913.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b843ex/cmv_immigration_is_a_good_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Immigration is a good thing</title>
    <original_poster>dabbin_z</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think we run into more problems trying to keep our borders closed than we do open.  Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation.  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

Think about how fast and easy it is for people to travel in the world.  We should encourage people to move around and explore new places not segregate communities.  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same.  

Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers.  With our civil right and strong economy, it’s no secret to why people want to leave their countries and come to America.  

I guess we already have open borders so thats not really my argument.  My opinion is rather that immigration is good for everyone and we should encourage it. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31677206360.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>I think immigration is overall a good thing, but I disagree with many of your points.

  \&amp;gt; Diversity in population is a good thing and it’s what drives innovation. 

This is limited to artistic innovation. For example Tejano music was borne of the contact between Germans and Mexicans in Texas. What drives technical/scientific innovation is high education levels.

  \&amp;gt;  I think what keeps us from progressing is bigotry and hatred towards other cultures. 

What slows progress is the desire of people to not lose what they value as the good things in their culture.

  \&amp;gt;  There’s nothing worse in my opinion than trying to keep cultures the same. 

Change is not automatically good, and keeping things the same is not bad. If anything, stability has known benefits. The good features and institutions in a culture took generations to work out, and shouldn't be tossed out in the name of change.

  \&amp;gt;  Western civilization has always been about immigration and new settlers. 

Western civilization is broader than just the US, and takes in Europe, where immigration has never been a major factor in building the civilization. But even we are just talking about the US, immigration is only one of many factors, and even it is diminished by the fact that immigrants tend to adopt the regional culture of where they settle and change to conform to it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
