<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31699131902.0" user="SMF67" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by remixes? Do you mean all remixes? Or are you talking about electronic/rap remixes of pop or non-electronic songs?

The remixes that completely change the genre of the song, which other commenters have addressed more, are not necessarily supposed to be better but to appeal to different listening preferences.

Remixes within genres, particularly electronic subgenres, are extremely common (probably around 50-60% of my playlist), and are often far more popular than the original song. They are often welcomed by the original artist as it gives them exposure. Sometimes the remixes tweak the song a little bit to make it smoother, to make it more “exciting” (e.g., progressive trance to uplifting trance), to make it more like modern songs, to make it in the unique style of the remixer, etc. Sometimes a song has like 10 different remixes with different styles. This allows people with slightly different music tastes to find the version of the dong they prefer most, If you want examples of this, just see r/trance where a large number of the songs are remixes of other trance songs.

TL;DR: What is considered a “remix” varies a lot within and across genres. Within some electronic subgenres like trance and house, remixes are extremely common and often more popular than the original song</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31704246300.0" user="TraumaJeans" delta="False">
    <text>Main example of remixes I had in mind were "old" songs re-used in "modern" songs. Whenever it changed the genre of the song, in my mind it tried to put a .quare peg in a round hole

&amp;gt;If you want examples of this, just see r/trance where a large number of the songs are remixes of other trance songs.

I used to listen to trance and house quite a bit and that was one of the reasons I stopped; I had "connection" to the originals and experiencing those, the remixes were breaking that connection and "stealing" from my memories of listening to the original version.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
