<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31706617726.0" user="Legoking" delta="False">
    <text>Since music appreciation is a subjective matter, I can maybe try to change your mind by showing why I like certain remixes over their original counterparts. Keep in mind I know nothing about music theory and terminology so bear with me.

There are several songs in my playlist where I much prefer a remix over the original because in those cases, the remix suits the song better to my musical tastes. Some original songs might not have the things that I like in a song, such as complexity or instrument choice or melody, or they might just be straight up boring. But when a person comes along and does a remix, where they "fix" one of those things that I view as a problem, the remix suddenly becomes a lot more pleasant to listen to.

As a first example:

[Owl City - Saltwater Room (original)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=usR7mMHUhlY)

[Owl City - Saltwater Room (remix)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q5_BjJrteLo)

In my opinion, the original song sounds kind of empty and lacking, in terms of the number of instruments. I much prefer the remix because the song feels fuller due to the extra instruments, and also I really enjoy how the artist added a different melody at the 3:59 mark, which isn't really present in the original. When I hear both versions, I feel like the remix completes the original. This is just my opinion though.

Another reason why a remix could be considered better than an original song, is when that remix changes the genre of the song to a genre of music that a listener enjoys more.

See here:

[Imogen Heap - Hide and Seek (original)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYIAfiVGluk)

[Imogen Heap - Hide and Seek (remix)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W0jEWnWVcgM)

I really love techno, so by turning the original into a techno song, I actually was excited to listen to the remix, and now I love the remix more than the original. It turned a song from a genre of music that I don't like to one that I do like. It also changed the mood of the song into something I enjoy more as well. The original has a sad vibe to it but the remix is exciting and makes me want to dance!

To sum up, a remix of a certain song, if well done, could very well align that song more towards your musical tastes and cause you to enjoy it more, meaning that it would not necessarily be "always inferior" to the original like you say. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
