<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31699487502.0" user="hoere_des_heeren" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of remixes are made by the original artist; if you truly always think the original is better that seems like a cognitive bias to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31704251806.0" user="TraumaJeans" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe a remix by the same artist is qualitatively different from one by a different artist? Perhaps it should even be defined as something else, seeing as the artist has different resources and insight?

&amp;gt;seems like a cognitive bias to me.

It probably is. I guess most of remixes I encountered were by a different artist; remixes by the same artist I could think of when writing the original post are for example David Guetta's, which usually re-jiggle the same song year into a year, which gives me a feeling of beating a dead horse; either play the original or move on to something else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31704267445.0" user="hoere_des_heeren" delta="False">
    <text>There are actually some songs of which for some reason the original mix never got released simply because they liked the remixes more and often artists remix themselves under a different name.

As far as I know no original was ever released of Armin van Buuren's "Burned with Desire" at least I never encountered it; the most popular version is the "Rising Star Remix"... Rising Star is just one of Armin's many pseudonyms... I guess it liked the the second attempt more and released that one instead which sometimes happens.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
