<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31698956726.0" user="DalekForeal" delta="False">
    <text>It is entirely subjective, but I'd have to respectfully disagree. 

There've definitely been songs I've heard and loved, only to find were remixes. On tracking down the originals, it was pretty apparent why the remix gained more traction. 

At the end of the day it's all subjective, but in my experience the possibility does exist. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31704240913.0" user="TraumaJeans" delta="False">
    <text>I did know a few remix examples I liked but still had a feeling that it's "wrong" for some reason but couldn't figure waht exactly. Extreme example would be using samples in rap music; while I don't always like the original as much as the song as used the sample, the latter feels like a not-a-proper-song for some reason. Which probably sounds ridiculous as I won't always be able to tell whether a sample was used (but whenever I found out, it did detract from the song that used the sample). </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
