<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="682071988.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ba3644/cmv_song_remixes_are_always_inferior/">
    <title>CMV: Song remixes are always inferior</title>
    <original_poster>TraumaJeans</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I've ever heard a remix that sounded better than the original song. I know that it's technically subjective to me personally, but have a gut feeling that no remix is all-around "better". I strongly suspect that often artists who produce remixes are piggybacking off the original author. I don't think popularity can be a reliable indication of music quality either. Perhaps here "music quality" is from the technical/effort point of view.

I realize that I can write off any remix song as inferior due to my personal taste, but otherwise don't think I hold any strong views and find it strange that I do regarding this. I know it may sound like an impossible task, but really am open to change my mind. 

(This is not a music request lol)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31699646810.0" user="Darebirth" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying that it's impossible for a musician to take a song and make it better? Or that that TENDS to be the case? Cause if it's the lattet than i agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31704259463.0" user="TraumaJeans" delta="False">
    <text>When you put it this way it does seem ridiculous. My rationale was, when an atrist is working with a complete song, they don't (usually?) have sources and cannot isolate parts of the song; for example cannot isolate individual instrument or voices. They have to operate with blended "chunks" that were designed to work together and introduce something they weren't designed for by the original author. The artist creating the remix did not make the same journey the original artist did and only experienced their final product. This may be different if the original author is the author of the remix.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
