<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31792296833.0" user="masterzora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people.

[Citation needed]

No, really. Even among credible people who sincerely believe overpopulation will be a problem in the not-too-distant future don't think we've hit the point of overpopulation yet.

The planet still has undeveloped and underdeveloped habitable areas, unused or underused farmable land, etc. That's not overpopulated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792342858.0" user="DarthEquus" delta="False">
    <text>The current population is over 7 billion. Estimates on the maximum population the Earth can house before overcrowding and scarcity of basic resources becomes and issue are between 12 and 14 billion. It is also important to realize that larger populations grow faster so it may not be long before we reach that point. 

My follow up question for you is: at what point *should* the government take measures against overpopulation, assuming us humans do not curb it on our own? 

And as for the "unused space" on the planet, you should probably take a look at this video: https://youtu.be/x5OYmRyfXBY 

It won't take long for the finite space of our planet is consumed with no more for a growing population to occupy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792411868.0" user="Puddinglax" delta="False">
    <text>Human population growth isn't just a simple exponential; it tends to plateau as nations become more developed due to increased access to contraceptives, differences in social structures and economic prosperity, etc. [UN median estimates](https://population.un.org/wpp/Graphs/Probabilistic/POP/TOT/) place the population between 11 and 12 billion by the year 2100, with growth beginning to slow. We can already see some countries who's growth rates are declining to the point that they need immigration to sustain their population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792361229.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>While the carrying limit of Earth isnt exceeded yet, the impact of humans on the climate as well as the fact that humans multiply exponentially may very well prove thathumanity will not remain on Earth for, at most, a centiry from now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792459091.0" user="masterzora" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the impact of humans on the climate

Reducing the growth rate is not an effective way to battle climate change within the next century. The problem there isn't that the population is going to grow into a size where climate change is a problem. We already need bigger and faster-acting solutions to either handle or survive climate change, so focusing on the growth rate is misguided there.

&amp;gt; the fact that humans multiply exponentially may very well prove that

It's more complicated than that. Global population growth rate has been on the decline for decades (and, for the record, that starts before China's "one-child" policy and, in fact, there was a small trend back upwards right after that policy started). Global population roughly doubled between 1959 and 1999 but it's not expected to even be close to doubling again come 2039. Even without most of the world having population control measures, growth is reducing itself.

Moreover, carrying capacity is not a static thing. Changes in technology and human behaviour can increase or decrease the carrying capacity. Focusing on increasing the carrying capacity is a much less atrocious way to ensure humanity sticks around beyond the next century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31796503027.0" user="BailysmmmCreamy" delta="False">
    <text>Humans do not multiply exponentially.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
