<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31808006192.0" user="syedumar7" delta="False">
    <text>“The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good”. By saying so, you have placed yourself in a position of authority, whereby ‘good’ is a value given to actions that are self-serving. This is not the case as the shared human experience is riddle with nuanced perspectives that give rise to a multifaceted discourse, wherein there is no one simple law that can be enacted to solve modern day crisis.

You are correct in identifying that humans contribute towards climate change, overpopulation and poor quality of life, however you’ve placed the blame on the existence of a large number of people, rather than individual actions that collectively escalate the identified issues. Also, you have failed to realise that overpopulation occurs in financial and major cities where there is possibility of work, unlike rural or hard-to-access areas. In doing so, you don’t recognise that the consequential poor quality of life is arising from poor resource allocation and waste disposal, intensifying the inequality gap between the rich and the underprivileged. It is possible to create a system for resource distribution waste management that doesn’t compound the current inequality gap; however, this is more complicated than taxing the rich and giving more to the needy. 

Population control won't solve many of what you perceive to be pressing issues, simply because it is not the cause of the issues. Fewer human beings will only result in fewer human beings; there will be no change to individual actions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
