<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31792438211.0" user="Dafkin00" delta="False">
    <text>There’s a really good argument on how population growth creates increasing returns. The view you’re taking on humans is that they are just mouths to feed. More humans means more opportunities for human ingenuity, technological growth, inventions, etc.

Do you honestly think that living standards have dropped since the population growth spike since the industrial revolution? Because living standards have increased and continue to increase. 

And as far as how many people are on earth, the amount of land is much more than enough to hold everyone for a very long time.

What are your specific issues with population growth?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792623591.0" user="DarthEquus" delta="False">
    <text>You do understand there is a limit to how many people the Earth can sustain right? Here is only so much land to farm, so much water to drink, so much space to live. 

Sure, maybe we can keep cramming more and more people in until every square inch of the planet is either over congested city, or overused soil for crops. Too bad for all the other species that went extinct and habitats that were lost just so we could fit more people in. 

Also, complex society is a fragile thing. It only works because enough of the population believes it works. But if all of a sudden fresh food, water, and supplies stop coming in, people become defensive real fast. Just look at any major cort after a natural disaster take out the infrastructure. We do not share well when our survival is at stake. It may be nice to think that everyone is genuinely good on the inside but when it comes down to it, we are capable of very horrible and selfish things. 

https://youtu.be/x5OYmRyfXBY 

This is a good video to explain population growth in a finite space</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792702499.0" user="Dafkin00" delta="False">
    <text>Your statement is government should conduct population control, meaning we currently have an issue, I am saying we don’t currently have an issue. I already said that we have a lot of land to keep us going for a very long time without issues.

You discount the power of human ingenuity. Why does the price of coal, oil, energy not continuously rise because we are using everything up? Because of human ingenuity..

We are consuming less energy, we are more efficient with how we use our land, the price of water is much lower which tells us about the availability of water. Literally the only way we run out of water to the point where innovation is irrelevant is if all the water literally escapes the earths atmosphere. Plenty of innovation which will continue in things like water, the price of water has dropped drastically (it’s less scarce)

Furthermore, as something gets more scarce, there’s more potential for profit and people will invest more in whatever is scarce and find out new and better ways to replace, compensate, or substitute.


It’s not as simple as finite area means the more people we have the worse things are. It’s difficult to see this without an economic argument.

We don’t need to share stuff, there’s money in entrepreneurship and innovation, free markets correct for this. 
This is the benefit of population growth and increasing returns.

Look at William D. Nordhaus, he did work on this and won the Nobel prize in economics for 2018 

The data and ideas to suggest that this argument is plausible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31796637176.0" user="Dafkin00" delta="False">
    <text>You’re gonna downvote and not respond to my statement. 
You’re not looking for a conversation, you’re just looking to sound smart and ignore arguments you can’t contest.
Nice.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
