<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31796182497.0" user="MrMcShrimp" delta="False">
    <text>Hate to break it to you man but you sound like a real life Thanos. Also quick question, what would you do if a person hid their child past the two month limit. Would you still euthanize it after that? What if the child grew to be three or so? Would the child be taken away from the parents and put in foster care or would it just be killed? And also your logic is that since the baby doesn't have enough conscious thought it wouldn't understand dying. Fair enough but then are you saying people with extreme physical and/or mental disabilities should be killed too because they aren't able to understand it? I just am seeing a lot of holes in your logic...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
