<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31792362742.0" user="pluralofjackinthebox" delta="False">
    <text>Every country that has tried to limit population growth with one or two child policies — China, Vietnam, Singapore, Iran — have reversed their decisions due to the economic and social consequences. These countries have no one to take care of their elderly populations and China particularly is experiencing what is known as [Little Emperor Syndrome](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Emperor_Syndrome) — the intense focus of both the grandparents and parents economic, psychological and social resources on single children is leading to the creation of egocentric monsters who are unable to care for themselves. The new generation is not very socially or globally concerned — when they get older I can easily see them not being very concerned with issues like climate change unless it benefits them directly somehow. 

In the developed word, population growth peaked in the fifties and is now below replacement rate. If you want to control population we should try to help develop the undeveloped parts of the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792426585.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>They had problems with sustaining the economy because of fewer jobs. Since AI is quickly advancing, its only a matter of time until they would make sure this wasnt a problem</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792460359.0" user="pluralofjackinthebox" delta="False">
    <text>We’ve been mechanizing people out of jobs for at least two centuries now, it just creates different jobs, and the economic impact of different types of mechanization is unpredictable. Why are you so confident AI will be a good thing, when so many others are worried that the economic impact will be bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792651710.0" user="a_ricketson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Why are you so confident AI will be a good thing, when so many others are worried that the economic impact will be bad?

I think these things are totally consistent. He's saying AI is good in a world with a declining population. Other people are concerned about AI putting people out of work in a world with a stable or increasing population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792463812.0" user="versionxxv" delta="False">
    <text>If AI is seriously what you’re staking the viability your view on, you need to defend that idea.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792626624.0" user="sflage2k19" delta="False">
    <text>I would say a newer generation being a spoiled and selfish is less detrimental than overpopulation and all the social, economic, and environmental effects it can cause.

Besides, Little Emperor Syndrome is a qualitative judgement similar to how people hate on Millenials for using smart phones. In fact, if you had read the very Wikipedia page you cited...

&amp;gt;[Psychological studies](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychology) do not support this view or, at best, offered mixed results. Results from earlier studies are inconsistent with some more recent studies that suggest there are no reliable differences between only children and those with siblings.[\[12\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Emperor_Syndrome#cite_note-wan-12)[\[13\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Emperor_Syndrome#cite_note-shen-13) However, a survey published in 2013[\[14\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Emperor_Syndrome#cite_note-14) on 431 Beijing adults finds that those who had grown up after the introduction of the one-child policy were lacking "entrepreneurial drive and the willingness to take risks.[\[15\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_Emperor_Syndrome#cite_note-15) This even had a significant impact on career choices.

So what is more likely-- that China's One Child policy is to blame, or that old people think young people are selfish and lazy, like they always do?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
