<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31806313926.0" user="tweez" delta="False">
    <text>The idea of population control was first proposed by Thomas Malthus in 17-- I think and has been proven to be incorrect ever since.  Studies have consistently shown that if you want to reduce population then the most effective way is to provide women with education and the ability to have their own career. People in poor nations only reproduce so much because they need children to look after them when they get older. You don't need drastic one child policies or to abort children in late stage pregnancy, you just need to give women educational and financial freedom.

You also make the sweeping statement that AI will take care of jobs, if that's the case then how will people make money in the first place?

Your overall argument that the "ends justifies the means" or basically "for the greater good" is an argument that will allow the rationalisation of any evil. Also, would you be willing to kill yourself for the betterment of society? The people who argue for population control the way you do never seem to think they should be the ones to give up their lives. A bit like how people who argue for communism never seem to think they should be the farmers or work in factories and they should be the ones coming up with policy</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
