<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="694386248.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/cmv_governments_should_conduct_population_control/">
    <title>CMV: Governments should conduct population control</title>
    <original_poster>memestar2016</original_poster>
    <original_post>We’re an extremely overpopulated people and Earth can’t handle this many people. That’s why population control needs to be a thing, favorably on a global scale. The law should be as follows:

No Household should be able to have more than 1 child (keep this up for 2 generations and then change it to 2 in order to keep it static). We wont have to worry about jobs, AI can take care of that. 

Individuals should be rewarded for sterilization. Reproduction should be discouraged. Forced abortions will be enforced on those breaking this law. Allow abortion until birth + allow euthanasia on &amp;lt; 2 month olds (They’d be unaware of what transpires and would not really be aware (not only because of anesthesia but also because age)).

No age purge though: elders have suffered enough already and would diacourage people from working.

I know this is a very controversial opinion and youll think I’m some troll, but fewer people would Also mean that the ones who survive would have better quality of life, climate change would slow down etc. The ends sometimes justify being a bit mean, but ultimately is for our own good.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31792315635.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>Just so you know - China did this.

Also, a lot of nations have a negative replacement rate. They are shrinking inherently. There is a concept called replacement rate. This is basically the needed birth rate for the population to remain stable. 

Without immigration, the US rate is below the level required to maintain populations.

https://www.cnn.com/2019/01/10/health/us-fertility-rate-replacement-cdc-study/index.html

It is the developing nations where population growth is the highest. It is also where governments are the least capable of managing it.

https://www.un.org/en/sections/issues-depth/population/

Given these facts, many governments like the US don't need to do anything about population control. The citizens themselves are a shrinking group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792346324.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>That’s true, but populations grow mainly in crap countries in the third world as well as breeder immigrants in the first world. Over all, the population is growing and we need to keep it at a sustainable level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792351946.0" user="brawnelamia_" delta="False">
    <text>Immigrant birth rates typically drop to that of the local population after the first generation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792374077.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>Tell that to countries like Sweden where MENA immigrants are generally reproducing at a relatively alarming rate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792378063.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792416704.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, Im a racist because I want to apply the laws to all humans indiscriminately. The west is already doing the right thing. We just need to apply the same standards ti the third world, where their rising population is because of poverty and less advanced culture</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792423712.0" user="brawnelamia_" delta="False">
    <text>Never said you were racist. Hey, if I’m mistaken about my claim, I’m open to seeing evidence against it.

Also, you admitted it yourself, the birth rates are due to poverty. The solution is to increase quality of life, not infanticide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792612162.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/brawnelamia_ – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+brawnelamia_&amp;amp;message=brawnelamia_+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/bhf3uw/-/elsczwv/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792363943.0" user="in_cavediver" delta="False">
    <text>Population controls in 'developed' nations relate to immigration controls.  This is a pretty divisive topic right now in the US.

Ineffective governments in developing countries basically means there is no real way to 'control population' there. 

There just is not a way to do what you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792368713.0" user="versionxxv" delta="False">
    <text>“Crap countries” and “breeder immigrants”? Huh. Do you also have a point of view on which countries and people should be forced to stop reproducing first? Maybe your plan should only apply to those crap countries and breeder immigrants?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792400377.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>It should Apply to all but wouldnt practically affect those who are already Living by it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792392267.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>If populations only grow in poor countries, wouldn't the solution be global prosperity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792440671.0" user="memestar2016" delta="False">
    <text>Thats not an option since it would mean everybody would be piss poor. I would rather have fewer people with more resources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792510129.0" user="stubble3417" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I'm not advocating for distributing wealth equally to everyone. I agree there's not a great way for that to work.

But over the next couple generations, poor countries will get richer and richer. Even in just the last 30 years, the world has gotten vastly wealthier. There are 1 billion fewer people living in extreme poverty today as there were in 1990. 

That's one reason that it's likely that world population will keep climbing slowly for a few more generations, then start falling. Probably forever. 

https://futurism.com/world-population-will-fall-never-stop/

https://www.visualcapitalist.com/decline-extreme-poverty-perspective/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31792457100.0" user="irondeepbicycle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; crap countries

&amp;gt; breeder immigrants

Man it never takes long for people holding "overpopulation" viewpoints to show their true colors.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
