<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31926978096.0" user="Zap_Meowsdower" delta="False">
    <text>I take prescription amphetamines almost every day and I definitely don't think they should be legal in the way pot is legal (in my state). You cannot overdose on marijuana; the only way you can die from it is if a dump truck full of it falls on you. This is also true of LSD, which I think should be legalized. But it would be incredibly easy to overdose on amphetamines if you don't know what you're doing or are chasing a high. A medical dose of Adderall causes your heart to beat faster (in a way that's noticeable to the patient), blood pressure to rise, and other uncomfortable physical effects. And a medical dose is far, far below a recreational dose. You'd be selling a heart attack in a bottle. Same with opioids, although possibly worse. Without medical rationing and tracking people will die.

(I don't think people should be locked up for using hard drugs though, it should be treated medically. For instance, many hard drug abusers have ADHD so the "cure" in this case could mean responsibly using the same drug they were abusing.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31930572955.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>-(I don't think people should be locked up for using hard drugs though, it should be treated medically. For instance, many hard drug abusers have ADHD so the "cure" in this case could mean responsibly using the same drug they were abusing.)-

Say that again slowly...what you just said there was that many people who use hard drugs should be given “medical” access to the drug they were previously using through illicit means.

When it comes to amphetamines I have a couple bones to pick with what you said. First off where are the bodies...my understanding is that very few people actually die as a result of chemical OD...though there are many more deaths associated with the drug by way of accident or suicide, often during an extended period without sleep. 

Also I’m pretty sure that the concept of ADHD was developed in the marketing department of a pharmaceutical company that wanted to sell amphetamines (like actually, though I’m not going to look up a citation). Not terribly unlike hallmark making up Valentine’s Day.

Don’t get me wrong I also have that diagnosis and amphetamines are a fantastically useful tool particularly when used sparingly and thoughtfully. As a younger adult I used them as directed and run into a lot of the side effects you mentioned above...after taking a few years off I started taking it in much smaller doses...typically I take 3-4mg between 0 and two times a day depending on what I have going on. I’ve found with that protocol it is much more effective because my body doesn’t develop a tolerance &amp;amp; the side effects are basically non-existent. Just food for thought. My experience has been that if you go to the doctor and tell them that the amount you used to take doesn’t have the same effect anymore they increase the dosage...this is totally illogical and something that needs to be fixed with prescription protocols for both opioids and amphetamines. If you have already established an effective dose which is no longer effective, you are discussing a tolerance problem...which can be much more effectively addressed by reducing the dose / frequency allowing your body to start fresh every day. Sorry if I got off topic...

I’m not quite sure what you mean by a “recreational dose” what I do know is that having had the opportunity to do a bit of trial and error with the drug, the most enjoyable and beneficial use I have found is with about 1/3 of the dose typically recommended by doctors at the start of treatment. 

I think if people who want to add amphetamines to their medicinal toolkit were provided with that sort of info, and safe QC manufactured compounds, the abuse events would be much less common than they are at present.

I might further suggest that if you have those side effects at a noticeable/unpleasant level, you might want to take a week or so off and see what happens if you try a lower dose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31931747388.0" user="Zap_Meowsdower" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also I’m pretty sure that the concept of ADHD was developed in the marketing department of a pharmaceutical company that wanted to sell amphetamines (like actually, though I’m not going to look up a citation). Not terribly unlike hallmark making up Valentine’s Day. 

That's not right at all, but it's pointless to argue about it because your mind is probably made up already.

And yes, it's possible to die from amphetamine abuse alone, not counting accidental death or suicide. It's not as deadly as other drugs, but [this link](https://www.narconon.org/drug-information/amphetamine-health-risks.html) says there were 832 deaths in the UK over a ten-year period, 108 of which did not involve any other drugs. A recreational dose of Adderall would probably be in the range of several hundred milligrams; most people with ADHD (which, again, is real) take between 20-40 mg/day. Part of why the deaths are so low is *because* they aren't available on the open market. If you think that doctors should be more free with handing out low-dose prescriptions to people who might not have ADHD (or opioids for people who don't have pain) then that's a different argument, but it's still not legalization in the way weed is legal. If I wanted to I could buy a trunk full of weed and use it all in one night if I feel like it, but if someone did the same with amphetamines they could have a stroke.

I don't actually have these side effects anymore to the point where it's uncomfortable, but I still feel them "kicking in," as does everyone else I know who takes them. And yeah, tolerance breaks are a good idea and I do take them, but how would a dispensary know to counsel a customer about the proper use of amphetamines? They aren't doctors, and businesses are going to want to maximize their profits by selling as much of their product as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31931953590.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>If you read my original post you would note that process of legally obtaining a drug would include an appointment with a qualified expert in the field / medical professional to provide the critical information (like each pill contains 10mgs...don’t take all 60 at once). Also information about building tolerance, warning signs, precautions &amp;amp; resources if you may be having an acute or long term issue with the drugs. WHICH closely resembles the system which was present in California  during the “medical marijuana” days. Frankly I think it would be better if that system was still in place for recreational cannabis...just with a name change.

Acetomenophin and ibuprofen kill at least 3 times that many people in the UK annually, some years it has actually been way higher. Once again almost all of those were preventable if we put a bit more effort into education &amp;amp; teaching people to make responsible decisions with the things they put in their body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31934743371.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Also I don’t mean to say ADHD isn’t a real thing, just that it is more of a indictment of the modern world at times being incompatible with human nature than it is a malady. If you have a 12 year old boy who has trouble sitting still in school for 7 hours a day...calling that a disease it a bit disingenuous on the part of the medical community IMO. Stimulants can help people like us fit a perfectly acceptable energetic personality into a modern world that isn’t always optimized for us.

With that said I still feel very strongly that most people using amphetamines in the 20-40mg per day range would get much better results from a dosage around 1/4 of that. That has been my experience and after thinking about the chemistry going on in our endocrine system it makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
