<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31916971931.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels. 

Shouldn't that be limited to those drugs that are actually used for recreational use? I mean, it doesn't make much sense to apply this to e.g. prescription drugs used for illnesses, and that may need close medical supervision to be used safely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917455318.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed....once again I think this is a think the market takes care of. You can buy all the rat poison at Home Depot you want and have yourself a party. I don’t think people are going to be lining up at the store for IV’s of chemo. So yes sure, I just don’t know if it would be necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
