<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31916949576.0" user="ContentSwimmer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

What benefit would this give? What's to say that they're "accurate and appropriate"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917068185.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I prefer not to do this, but the best response I have is my own anecdote. I played around with opioids recreationally for a few years around a decade ago. I did a good bit of reading and thoughtful tinkering with my own use along the way &amp;amp; found a few simple bits of knowledge that make it reasonably easy not to die &amp;amp; quitting quite manageable when I felt it was appropriate. All of those concepts are dependent on a measurable dose, which requires legal manufacturing. 

Understanding how the drug works in your body and how it can impact neurological reward pathways &amp;amp; what to expect from a withdrawal experience all make responsible use much more accessible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917187667.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think your experience is the norm, rather than an exception?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917290884.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t...but I think it could be. I try to think out anything I want to do, and trial and error it to find the best ways to do it. A big part of that is that I never get like I was doing anything wrong, just figured it was something with risks I should be aware of and do my best to mitigate. With it on the black market and stigmatized the way it is a lot of users think of use as doing something wrong and this write off the idea of responsible use. That has been devastating to our society and I think it is a fixable problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917368522.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think stigma is the source of dependence and addiction, rather than brain chemistry?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917434856.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Personal experience, lots of conversations with other users...ALSO it isn’t an either or thing. I think the stigma greatly amplified the chemical aspects. We also tell users they are weak &amp;amp; a lot of them believe it, making it harder to act with strength and resolve. Personally I never bought the stigma, I was never ashamed of what I was doing &amp;amp; it made it much easier for me to take breaks, or not use, and expect myself to be responsible when I was using actively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917498014.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you feel your anecdotal evidence is more accurate than systemic evaluations of addiction?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917570312.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think there have been many well conceived systemic evaluations of addictions. And the ones that have happened have been A v B. Rather than the plethora or variables that actually exist in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917590854.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>What qualifications do you have to evaluate the merits of addiction studies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918171886.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I’m just a guy that likes doing a bit of research and challenging assumptions. This is a topic I care a lot about &amp;amp; something I’ve tried to look at from a number of different perspectives &amp;amp; this is where I keep ending up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918178543.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but the people who’s entire jobs and education have been dedicated to studying this topic have ended up at the opposite position regarding addiction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918239560.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve been studying the topic in depth for about 15 years...I think the above statement seems to exclude the possibility of institutional bias...plenty of scientist, nutritionists, and doctors spent entire careers furthering the conclusion that fats were the root of all of our health problems and that refined sugar was just fine. It’s only been the past few years people decided this was worth looking at critically &amp;amp; people are finally starting to see that refined sugar has more in common with hard drugs (in terms of capacity for addiction, health risks, impact on psychology of user)...than it does with food.

I might also point out that the experts are failing...they have failed to stem the tide of addiction through the traditional position on addiction and drugs. The harder they have dug in the worse the problem has gotten. Personally I think it would be great if we started entertaining some alternative ideas in this space.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918247838.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Those same scientists are the ones who have studied and shown the efficacy of things like medication assisted treatment to reduce addiction rates. 

Why are you attributing stigma against drug use to scientists, rather than politicians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918290509.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>The root is political, but the policies, and the ability for politics to impact the curriculum in our educational system has had an irrefutable impact on the way this has been studied by the academic and scientific community. 

And multiply that by 10 within the medical community. And we haven’t even discussed the influence the primary media outlets &amp;amp; their ability to filter what science we hear and don’t hear...particularly in the pre-iPhone world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918300487.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>None of that changes the fact that zero studies suggest that stigma is what causes addiction rather than brain chemistry. In fact, we know it *isn’t* stigma because even when people are using licit, prescription opioids, they become addicted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918307147.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>At a much much lower rate than those who got it through illicit means. Which would coincide with my theory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918322632.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>No, the illicit opioids are much stronger. A higher dose means a greater level of dependence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918348343.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>That’s incorrect. There are pharmaceutical opioids every bit as strong as anything manufactured on the black market. Also plenty of pharmaceutical opioid can be obtained through the black market &amp;amp; while I don’t have any studies to site I would gaurantee addiction rates are higher for those who obtained the identical drug illicitly vs legally.

Also here is an article with dozens of citations to studies and acedemic papers about the links between stigma, addiction, and increased negative impact stigmatizing drug use causes.

https://drugabuse.com/addiction/stigma/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918368838.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but the root cause is the literal brain chemistry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918497853.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Debatable in a chicken or egg sort of way. There is a rather famous study in rodents...where they found that rats with access to both water and water laced with addictive drugs (I think it has been done with cocaine and opioids but not sure about that detail). They found that the rats in the cage became chemically addicted to the drugged water...to their detriment and or death. This has been a major component of the chemical dependence argument.

At some later point the experiment was replicate except that the decked out the cage making it everything a rat could hope for...tubes and toys and ramps, and wheels. All sorts of fun things if you are a rats...turns out the rats in rat castle didn’t have addiction issues, they overwhelmingly opted for the pure water.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31924121249.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Does your proposal to legalize drugs also include a comprehensive anti-poverty agenda? If not, why do you think that society better represents the tubes and wheels, rather than cage?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31930681729.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>IMO my proposal to legalize drugs IS a key component to the anti-poverty agenda. The laws are enforced so unevenly across the economic spectrum it would be comical if it wasn’t so upsetting. This uneven enforcement cripples social mobility in many low income families...it’s in fact so prevalent that there is an entire genre of music dedicated to this phenomenon called “trap music”. We are just scratching the surface here, but that is another essay for another day...and you can find plenty of writing on the topic. 

That said, the modern world definitely has all the tubes and wheels and toys...but it is sort of a pick your own adventure sort of deal. I used opioids recreationally for a few years in my mid twenties &amp;amp; when I decided I didn’t really want to do that anymore I started playing rugby again BEFORE I made any effort to alter my usage patterns. A month or so down that road my brain had mapped a whole host of new pathways to dopamine it could use INSTEAD of the Chemical pathway I had decided I was relying on too heavily. In other words, the chemical your brain gets addicted to is dopamine and it is something your body produces naturally...the opioids are just one pathway...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31930730804.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>What was your income, education, and employment status when you were recreationally using opioids?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31931711642.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Thats a tough question to answer...I have a tough time deciding where you would draw the line between recreational use and medical use. I’ve used it as a pain killer after some traumatic sports injuries...but there are other things you can use for pain...the benefit of opioids is that it’s pathway to efficacy for pain killing is via mood boosting. So you can still laugh and hang out with friends even if you are in pain. So from my perspective you could say any use is medicinal and recreational. 

I guess what I’m saying is to actually have this conversation in a useful way we would first have to make a whole laundry list of distinctions for each part of that question AND following that, the answers would be more like a book rather than a paragraph or two. I can tell you from my effort at keen observation, you will find users of all walks of life...plenty of which will prove to be highly functioning useful members of society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31931747448.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	Thats a tough question to answer...I have a tough time deciding where you would draw the line between recreational use and medical use. I’ve used it as a pain killer after some traumatic sports injuries...but there are other things you can use for pain...the benefit of opioids is that it’s pathway to efficacy for pain killing is via mood boosting. So you can still laugh and hang out with friends even if you are in pain. So from my perspective you could say any use is medicinal and recreational.

This is a massive dodge of the question. You’ve characterized your own use of opioids as recreational multiple times. During those uses, what was your income, employment status, and education level?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31931958440.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>It’s a wide range I don’t know what you are looking for here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31931985025.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Any indication of what your general lot in life was. The fact that you continue to refuse to answer suggests that you know it’s a lot that makes you less likely to become dependent on those drugs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31934631796.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>My general lot in life was pretty good. I’m a reasonably competent hard working guy...with family and friends that show me plenty of love. Money has never been a massive priority for me...sometimes I make more, sometimes I make less, but I like to make sure I’m adding new stuff to my skill set frequently &amp;amp; i often use work as a means to that end. Not ideal if you put a high priority on steady growing income...but pretty great if you are wired the way I am.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31934645670.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so why do you feel that your experience would be a common one? Do you feel your lot was indicative of a common one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31934693696.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely. The primary difference between me and my friends who had a bit more difficulty with this category of substances was that i always approached my drug use with the specific intent to do it a responsibly as I could. I think a big part of that is that I never for a moment thought that I was doing anything inherently wrong (no shame). In other words, I think a lot of people discard the thought of responsible use because they apply some sort of negative morality to their actions from the start. For me, I just figured I was borrowing a bit of dopamine from later to use it now...

I don’t expect everyone to be as diligent as I was with educating myself or paying attention to the subtleties of use...but I do think if people got that information from the start &amp;amp; we made a more inviting cultural environment for candid discussion of experience by the millions upon millions of users...we would end up with a much less destructive scenario.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918315813.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>also I’m not sure I would agree that it is a fact that 0 studies have come to that conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
