<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31916766820.0" user="pluralofjackinthebox" delta="False">
    <text>I mostly agree, just not for *all* drugs. I think purchasing heroin at a safe injection site is a great way to stop overdose deaths and put drug dealers out of business. But some drugs just should not exist.

For instance, synthetic cannabis. Many forms of synthetic cannabis have been sold, often disguised as incense or “plant food.” Whereas normally cannabis often works as a partial cannabinoid agonist, synthetic cannabis often works as a full agonist. This means that, unlike with natural cannabis, with synthetic cannabis you can overdose and go through withdrawals. 

There is just no need for synthetic cannabis to exist. This is true for many synthetic drugs, which are finding increasingly popularity on crypto markets.

Or, carfentanyl. This is a drug thousands of times stronger than heroin. People can overdose just from touching or smelling this drug. Single hits of Naloxone often are not enough to prevent carfentanyl overdose deaths.

Then you’ve got your synthetic cathonones, like “bath salts”, and now we’re increasingly seeing synthetic lsd like “Smile” which you can also overdose on. Hundreds of new synthetic drugs come out each year, too fast for anyone to understand what their long or short term effects might be.

Luckily, most people don’t want to try synthetic versions of drugs if natural versions are available. The main reason why fentanyl is so popular now is because it’s compact and easier to smuggle. Legalization would be a great way to ensure that people stop taking synthetics. But I think we should just legalize naturally occurring drugs, maybe a few synthetics that have been well tested.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31916819666.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I can get down with that for the most part...though I do think the open market would take care of that for the most part. You are going to have a tough time finding synthetic pot in use in a state with legal cannabis. Likewise carfentenyl wouldn’t be found in street heroin if people have legal avenues to safer opioids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917173942.0" user="timwtuck" delta="False">
    <text>Just in regard to your first paragraph, what if the user can't afford to purchase? What if the drug dealer lowers his price? Or should heroin be free at these sites? Then how do you deter use? Do you want to deter use? Is a society hooked on heroin a good thing? 

Sorry for the onslaught of questions!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31953777433.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry took a few days...free has worked well in other countries. It also has not coincided with increased usage rate. Our current process for deterring use has only served to increase usage rates...

I think “deterrence theory” is a particularly sound area of philosophy, particularly when employed in public policy. It’s logical in an aesthetic sense...but doesn’t tend to pan out in the real world. 

Let’s look at the age old example - the best way to learn not to touch a hot pan/stove/pot is to touch one &amp;amp; the ensuing pain/burn will deter child in the future. IN FACT, while that Chile may be scared out of the kitchen for some bit of their life...the will almost assuredly grab a hot pan/pot/touch stove again hundreds of thousands of times. They may use a cloth or a glove, or be quick. Maybe all of the above...at some point they will likely learn the pitfalls of the damp glove on hot metal as well. Humans are capable of understanding nuance...particularly if we are encouraged to explore our world and provided some guidance to facilitate responsible use.

Another example is animals trainers. We know as well as we know anything that the best way to train well behaved well socialized animals (dogs come to mind) is positive reinforcement. It’s simply a better protocol, with better results as compared against a punitive training protocol (this may differ in someway if the goal is to create animals as weapons for war or animal fighting - not that I am condoning that).

My understanding is that this is fairly consistent through mammals, yet we fail to employ it with ourselves as humans. 

In other words...if you are going to use, I want you to have the information &amp;amp; cultural encouragement to do so responsibly. And since the punitive system has been such an utter failure and waste over the past 100 years...maybe we should consider other avenues...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
