<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31916797165.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>my only reservation is that since opioids are so addictive, it would be simple for Amazon to open up Amazon Opium Dens, with discount for Prime members, to just empty out the bank accounts of recreational users. how would we ensure that the opiates given to us by corporate entities aren't somehow engineered to be MORE addictive? etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31916851893.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Like bars set up to clean out peoples pockets with alcohol? 

I would find it unlikely that manufacturers would feel the need to make it more addictive &amp;amp; I think legal standing would open up public conversations getting real and accurate information to users actually making it less addictive. 

We often forget that the vast vast vast majority of people who use opioids in their life NEVER have a major life altering addiction event.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31916990309.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Like bars set up to clean out peoples pockets with alcohol?

this seems like an argument against bars, not for legal opium dens?

&amp;gt; I think legal standing would open up public conversations getting real and accurate information

if the FDA had any actual power, and if doctors on pharma payrolls were not permitted to lie about their studies, and if studies were somehow permitted to do large randomized control trials on addictive potential -- then I would agree that accurate information would be available to the public. but none of that is true. purdue, through their doctors, did lie about the addictive potential of oxycodone and the FDA could do nothing to prevent its rollout.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917406970.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Well that is only if we are working on the assumption that substance use is inherently bad. That is an assumption that I do not agree with. So personally I would see opium dens and bars in a very similar light and both of which have risks and benefits.

The FDA and big pharmaceutical companies have not even had the capacity to actually collect mass scale data, in a multi-variable scenario and make heads or tails of it until the last few years. In other words it’s easy to demonize them BUT this is the first time in history we have had the tools to actually tap into user feedback, stuck mass outcomes and actually start developing best practices for medical use and reasonable guidelines for off label use. 

They tested the drugs for efficacy and safety according to the rules and tools of the day. The tools have changed and the rule need to as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917459804.0" user="mfDandP" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The FDA and big pharmaceutical companies have not even had the capacity to actually collect mass scale data,

exactly. 

&amp;gt; In 1995, when the Food and Drug Administration approved OxyContin, it allowed Purdue Pharma to claim that the opioid’s long-acting formulation was “believed to reduce” its appeal to drug abusers compared with traditional painkillers such as Percocet and Vicodin.

&amp;gt; At a gathering shortly afterward to celebrate the drug’s launch, Mr. Sackler boasted that “the launch of OxyContin tablets will be followed by a blizzard of prescriptions that will bury the competition. The prescription blizzard will be so deep, dense, and white,” according to a document cited in the legal complaint.

&amp;gt; Company sales representatives told doctors that OxyContin couldn’t be abused and were trained to say that the drug had an addiction risk for patients of “less than one percent,” a claim that had no scientific backing. Within a few years, Purdue Pharma was selling more than $1 billion worth of OxyContin annually.

so, you trust nameless corporations to take the legalization of opiates and NOT put dollars over public health concerns?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917561897.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Nope I trust the democratization of Information. They were rational actors acting with an absolute monopoly on the information created by the war on drugs. I think the modern internet changes the game if we give people the freedom to actually discuss their own usage experience in public without the fear of being ostracized.

Alternately, if people had felt they could more freely discuss, the backlash would have happened before we got to the present scenario</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917128812.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Like bars set up to clean out peoples pockets with alcohol?

The addictivness isn't even in the same league, Opium and the like is a hundred times worse.

&amp;gt;  I think legal standing would open up public conversations  

We already talk about drugs and addictivness all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917356688.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>But not with actual information, just scare tactics and telling people they are powerless against the substances which is a ridiculous position IMO. I think it is important to remember that the vast vast majority of people who use opioids at some point in there life do not have any sort of addictive event. Also you do not have actual users participating in the public dialogue due to legal and social ramifications. The people that actually have experience are effectively silenced UNLESS they fit the government narrative of “I was so lost before but now I’m found”.

Opium specifically isn’t really much of an issue in our society. It is not addictive in anywhere near the same capacity that something like oxycodone or heroin have the potential to be. We have way way more alcoholics in the USA than opium addicts. These little distinctions are important &amp;amp; they are places where misinformation happens and turn potential issue a into massive issues.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
