<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31917046562.0" user="timwtuck" delta="False">
    <text>1. Why would it eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing? Illegal tobacco is a huge market. It might push the prices lower (capitalism!) but certainly wouldn't eliminate it.

2. I would suggest that culturally we don't shame people for reaching out, but we applaud them. We shame people for refusing help when they need it. It would destigmatize usage of hardcore drugs I guess, and therefore people wouldn't be shamed in using them, but is that a good thing? Opioids can be very destructive for a society, perhaps we want to deter use.

3. I guess this feels life a contradiction. If the urge is primal then it would be sort after regardless

If these reasons are truly your sole reasoning for legalisation, then maybe there is another way of achieving the same outcome: *incredibly severe* penalties for the sale, possession and use of these drugs. You would 1. Eradicate the customer and therefore the market 2. Almost all people would be so deterred they won't do illegal drugs 3. Again deterrent so that primal urge is controlled. I'm not suggesting we do this, but that is a means to the same outcome, why shouldn't we propose that instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917240964.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>People love to do what you tell them not to do. In other words, IMO punitive deterrence is a vastly overrated strategy for actually deterring socially destructive behaviors. 

1) the difference between buying illicit tobacco and legal tobacco is a terrible analogy with the difference between buying pharmacuetically manufactured opioids vs street heroin. Street heroin has no measurable dose, it could be cut with fentanyl greatly increasing cardio-respiratory depression or any number of other things. Commercially manufactured opioids are measurable which is very important if you would prefer not to ruin your life or die. Black market tobacco just means commercially manufactured tobacco was smuggled from a state with lower taxes to a place with higher taxes to undercut the retail market and make a margin.

The social stigma involved in admitting you like to use a drug can change the way you are treated when you need medical attention...it can change your prospect for earning enough money to live...and obviously there are legal ramifications all of which encourage users to stay in the closet. That amplified the negative impacts of the drug and creates a feeling of isolation that makes it hard feel like a part of society.

The primal urge bit is in the challenge of finding something despite the legal obstacles. Once again I’m stuck with anecdote but...but the experience of going to a legal dispensary doesn’t have anywhere near the “score” feeling linking up with your homie did in the days of illegal cannabis. No need to stress...it’s always going to be there. The black market adds that sense of urgency that makes the successful hunt much sweater and more addictive IMO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917471205.0" user="timwtuck" delta="False">
    <text>People love to do what you tell them not to unless the risk doesn't outweigh the reward. Punitive deterrents only work if the punishment is significant. Deterring drink driving has been a successful campaign because the consequence of being caught is so serious.

1. Why would someone addicted to a substance (which usually consumes their life) pay market price when an illegal dealer can significantly undercut it?

2. Maybe it justifiably affects job prospects as it will very possibly affect your ability to perform your job. If I was an employer I very much know who I would want to employ verses someone addicted to a substance which alters their mental capacity and someone who isn't, and that isn't down to stigma. With regards to getting medical help, a practitioner definitely should know if you have been using drugs that may have other side affects when diagnosing and giving treatment. The person may feel shame in admitting that, but that is perhaps because they must admit they are doing something illegal rather than the fear that they will be denied treatment as a result of their habit.

3. Doesn't that argue that the black market will always exist, a direct contradiction of point 1?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917590091.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>The same reason the vast vast majority or cigarette smokers buy them legally. Also you are using the term usually incorrectly...the vast vast majority of users do not have life consuming addictions...that propaganda not reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31917728061.0" user="timwtuck" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, you're right I should have said has the potential to rather than usually.

Ok, bare with me on this one. I'm thinking on my feet and haven't coherently thought this through, but anyway: If tobacco was made illegal tomorrow, would people continue to buy tobacco illegally? Would other people start smoking despite the fact it's illegal? My guess is the majority (if not virtually all) would quit. So the question is, do people not go through the illegal channel because there is a legal one ,or that people don't go through the illegal channel because they wouldn't do that anyway? Is the same true of drugs, especially hardcore drugs? Is your assertion therefore justified?

Also, do you have any thoughts on my other 2 points?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918149774.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>I’d say evidence would point to the contrary....did virtually all people quit drinking during prohibition? Did virtually all people quits marijuana when it was made illegal? Did virtually all people quit using LSD, Mushrooms, and Ecstacy when they were made illegal? Did the opioid crisis disappear when the DEA cracked down on doctors prescriptions in 2010-2011?

I hope that doesn’t come across as belittling because I made a long list just want to demonstrate a pattern.

I actually think the manner in which the state has handled tobacco has been a great success story for alternatives to criminalization. An education campaign based on science and factual information, plus advertising prohibitions has greatly reduced the presence of tobacco in our society. Where as the criminalized drugs have historically grown in popularity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918320698.0" user="timwtuck" delta="False">
    <text>Not belittling at all! This sub is all about challenging ideas, no offense taken at all.

I think the point I was trying to make is that tobacco is, whilst an addictive substance, not in the same category as other drugs. Although this can be argued, and probably fairly successfully, I see the short term buzz of nicotine in a different category to the mind altering affect of the majority of drugs, and therefore easier to stop people from using. 

Anyway, here's an article about people still buying illegal marijuana in states where it is legalized: https://www.google.com/amp/s/www.nytimes.com/2019/01/02/us/buying-legal-weed-in-california.amp.html
although there are maybe potential solutions, I think it shows that the problem isn't as straight forward legalising = no black market.

How about the other 2 points? I'd love to know if I've changed your opinion on 2 out of 3 of your points ;p</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918403677.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>Ok so I would agree that using the word “eliminate” is probably a reach. But there is a fundamental difference between some people trying to circumvent taxes vs. the entire supply chain being forced underground. In other words the black market for cigarettes probably services &amp;lt; 1% of the market. It’s like saying ending prohibition didn’t eliminate the black market in alcohol because a tiny percentage of people make moonshine. The industry of violent gangs supplying spirits is gone. If a 20 year old buys a bottle of whiskey through illicit means “black market” they don’t have to worry about it possibly having industrial chemical like they did in the 20’s. Does that make sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918461509.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>As for employment...I’m not terribly opposed to companies having their own policies.  I think this a sticky area, and in general should probably be left up to the market to sort out.

In terms of medicine I think we are talking about two differenr things. I don’t mean to say that you wouldn’t want to tell a doctor if there is something in your system at a moment of acute treatment. Im having a tough time figuring out how to verbalize it to someone who hasn’t experienced it though. I might have to take a stab at it in the morning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918206746.0" user="FearOfGoogle" delta="False">
    <text>https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=wJUXLqNHCaI
Please watch this video, might not change your opinion but it might give you some context. Both Portugal and Switzerland has a huge opioid crisis and solved the problem by building treatment facilities. It has worked before.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31918355659.0" user="rnewcomb32" delta="False">
    <text>❤️❤️❤️❤️❤️❤️</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
