<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708087535.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpkru7/cmv_all_drugs_especially_opioids_and_amphetamines/">
    <title>CMV: All drugs ESPECIALLY opioids and amphetamines should be available for recreational use through legal channels.</title>
    <original_poster>rnewcomb32</original_poster>
    <original_post>My ideal system would be something that included a meeting with a qualified expert in the field providing the user with accurate and appropriate information regarding the substance they are interested in using (much like the medical marijuana system before recreational was approved - except recreational).

This would eliminate the black market and unregulated manufacturing. It would eliminate the cost (societal and monetary) of the drug war. It would eliminate the shame currently involved with those reaching out for help &amp;amp; allow for more responsible decision making. It would also eliminate that primal hunter gatherer itch that gets scratched when you go out and score something you want.  

What do you all think?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31920411607.0" user="Quint-V" delta="False">
    <text>This is not a particularly interesting subject w.r.t. drugs like cannabis, so disregard those. What I want to talk about, is drugs that have proven to have generally destructive effects when used; when benefits only occur with medical expertise and precision, if they occur at all.

What do you do with proven addicts who destroy their own lives and hurt everyone who cares about them? Should we allow them to nonchalantly continue their self-destructive and generally destructive behaviour? Recreational use can and will at some point put some people out of commission and it is naive to allow these people to continue their harmful self-indulgence. 

In the same way that we do not permit people to drive in unreasonable manners, so are people not allowed to do whatever they want to with drugs, because that drug consumption hurts themselves and others. The worst of drugs do this in a very, very real manner.  There are plenty of stories where families are ruined by drugs --- do you think this would turn out differently if drugs were legal? Legalizing them just makes them more available.

A black market is less available than a legal one and therefore leads to less consumption, and information about harmful drugs are very much available anyway. And something else to consider: businesses that produce consumables in general have economical incentives to make people addicted, or start consumption which then leads to addiction. Misinformation and subverting research is a very real thing that happens; Exxon knew about pollution and estimated precise models for climate change. The NRA has lobbied for the Dickey Amendment which effectively prevents government-sanctioned research into gun violence, which in turn makes much of the gun debate useless because nobody has particularly good data or research into the issue.

As for whatever shame is involved with reaching out: doctors and therapists in general are locked into confidentiality and cannot reach out to law enforcement unless they believe that your behaviour is so destructive and irreparable that you have to --- beyond reasonable doubt --- be forcibly put into some institution. It takes a lot to get to that length.

Even if you wish to go to this extent I think there should be something like a blacklist of consumers for such products. E.g. if you have done some crazy shit while under influence or been an outright addict you should not be permitted to buy those again.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
