<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="708521265.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bpu2i9/cmv_chromium_should_be_the_reference_web_browser/">
    <title>CMV: Chromium should be the reference web browser implementation and maintained by an independent, non-profit organization.</title>
    <original_poster>vincentofearth</original_poster>
    <original_post>Warning: this is a bit technical and long-winded and you may not actually care.

&amp;lt;background&amp;gt;

The [web](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web) is built on a set of [standards](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_standards) that determine how web sites &amp;amp; apps are created, how they should be displayed, and how they should behave. Several organizations maintain and create these standards, like the [World Wide Web Consortium](https://www.w3.org/Consortium/), [Ecma International](https://www.ecma-international.org/default.htm), and many more (mostly with terrible websites).

The basic idea is that through these standards bodies, companies (Google, Microsoft, Apple), non-profits (Mozilla), and other internet stakeholders can come together and agree on some rules, recommendations, and conventions. Developers follow these standards when creating apps and websites. In turn, browsers agree to honor the standards. This is how you can create an app once and know that it's the same on all the latest browsers.

Except that last statement **isn't true**. Even a casual person on the web will know that [certain sites](https://twitter.com/AirbnbHelp/status/752829250198245376) just look weird on certain browsers. Weird bugs will pop up or some apps just don't work on browsers with a smaller market share. Some websites will even block specific browsers.

A lot of websites today are [built only for Chrome](https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/4/16805216/google-chrome-only-sites-internet-explorer-6-web-standards), and Firefox/Edge/Safari users can count themselves lucky if, by sheer luck, a website also works on their obscure browser. Google Chrome's [dominance](http://gs.statcounter.com/) (63% market share) and [other](https://electronjs.org/docs/tutorial/about) [factors](https://github.com/MicrosoftEdge/MSEdge/blob/master/README.md) mean that this will probably only grow worse in the future. Many [feel that this threatens](https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2018/12/06/goodbye-edge/) the open standards that the web is built on, as Google builds its own set of standards and becomes the ultimate gatekeeper to our online lives.

Standards can never cover all the bases. Each [browser engine](https://gizmodo.com/which-browser-engine-powers-your-web-browsing-and-why-d-1833935288) implements standards [differently](https://caniuse.com/), with just enough minor differences to matter. They don't always do it at the same pace, their users don't update at the same pace, and they sometimes add features that aren't even standard yet. So developers are left to adapt--to patch the gaps and create workarounds, or (as more and more are doing) just give up and assume their users are using Chromium (Chrome's engine) or block those that aren't.

&amp;lt;/background&amp;gt;

Many feel that the solution is for more browsers--or actually, more browser *engines*, with a healthier market share for each (basically, *more competition*). This will force developers to build for the whole internet, not just for Chrome. I think this is a pipe dream at this point.

My position: there should be a **reference implementation** of a web browser that is actively maintained by a single independent, non-profit organization with members from many different stakeholders. Developers should test their sites on this reference. Actual browsers (Chrome, Firefox, Safari) can add their own specific app features like a Download Manager, Extensions, Reading mode--anything that's not rendering the page. They can even deviate from the reference, but they must do so knowing that the reference stays the reference.

As things currently stand, the standards leave too much for browser vendors to decide. There are entire libraries devoted to solving the issue of incompatibility between browsers, and they haven't succeeded. This should not be the case. Competition is good, but it should be based on merit, not on how entrenched something is. As a user, I want to choose my browser based on its **features**, and I should just be able to assume that it can do the basic job of rendering a web page correctly, and (perhaps more important) consistently.

Edit: Added a final section I left out earlier, plus some additional clarification.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31921862598.0" user="Rpgwaiter" delta="False">
    <text>We have that already, it's called Firefox. It is developed and maintained by a non-profit organization. Ideally it would have the dominant market share and Mozilla would have the money to R&amp;amp;D the next generation of standards but this isn't the case. Why try to take the Chromium project away from Google instead of standardizing and supporting the already non-profit Mozilla?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31922126545.0" user="vincentofearth" delta="False">
    <text>Mozilla is great, but Firefox is still controlled by a single entity. If it's going to be a reference implementation, it needs to have the backing and input of many more internet stakeholders. Microsoft, Google, Samsung, Apple, etc. should all have a say. They already have a say in the current standards process, but what I want is for them to create a rendering engine instead of just a spec.

By the way, I'm totally for Firefox being the basis of a reference implementation in a fairy tale world. But I'm trying to be more realistic. *If* this were to actually happen, it's far more likely that Blink and V8 will be the first choice because they're already so widespread (and not just on the web).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
