<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="709135164.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bq7870/cmv_news_reporting_must_strictly_be_as_neutral/">
    <title>CMV: News Reporting must strictly be as neutral and factual as possible, instead of containing the reporter’s opinions and agenda.</title>
    <original_poster>Daberinos</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sometimes, when I watch or read a news report, I find that I notice many, or at least noticeable parts of the articles are not strictly of the information of the news report, but of the reporter’s opinions of the article. This leads to the reporter changing the meaning of, warping, omitting or highlighting certain parts of a report due to either subconscious opinion or conscious agenda pushing. Hence, many times have I read a news article and realise that I have been influenced by the way the reporter phrases the facts of the situation, and even outright puts their own opinion in the article. When a person who does not consciously make sure to watch out for subliminal messaging in news reports read them, their world views can seriously be affected. A good example is the “CNN vs Fox” meme where people poke fun at the fact CNN panders to democratic audiences and Fox panders to Republican audiences, and their reports of the same incident can be wildly different, and that’s where the opinions of the writer starts to show. Obviously I don’t believe that a report can be entirely without a second-hand opinion, in fact I think it’s impossible to produce a perfectly neutral news report. However I do believe that the situation right now could be remedied into a far better state than it is now. By having a opinion-wise neutral news report, it gives the reader a chance to developed their own opinions on the subject, and if the writer would want to give their view on the topic which I agree with, it should be segregated from the facts of the news report to warn news readers that what they read will be a third-person view of the report. Thus News reports and proper discussion of opinions can be properly distinguished. 

However, some people have told me that they disagree with what I said, thus I would like to know the general consensus of how people view this view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31936078974.0" user="KateCobas" delta="False">
    <text>I would question the legitimacy of any news organization that claims itself to be neutral. 

Neutrality treats all sides of an issue with equal weight and that can be a bad thing. 

Climate change scientists on equal footing with climate change deniers. NASA scientists on equal footing with flat earthers. Geologists on equal footing with young earthers. Biologists on equal footing with evolution deniers.

When you treat the issues as 50/50, you diminish the truth and give crackpots a huge boost.

I think a better way to go is objective reporting, as in reporting the facts and not giving crackpots a platform.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
