<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="709135164.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bq7870/cmv_news_reporting_must_strictly_be_as_neutral/">
    <title>CMV: News Reporting must strictly be as neutral and factual as possible, instead of containing the reporter’s opinions and agenda.</title>
    <original_poster>Daberinos</original_poster>
    <original_post>Sometimes, when I watch or read a news report, I find that I notice many, or at least noticeable parts of the articles are not strictly of the information of the news report, but of the reporter’s opinions of the article. This leads to the reporter changing the meaning of, warping, omitting or highlighting certain parts of a report due to either subconscious opinion or conscious agenda pushing. Hence, many times have I read a news article and realise that I have been influenced by the way the reporter phrases the facts of the situation, and even outright puts their own opinion in the article. When a person who does not consciously make sure to watch out for subliminal messaging in news reports read them, their world views can seriously be affected. A good example is the “CNN vs Fox” meme where people poke fun at the fact CNN panders to democratic audiences and Fox panders to Republican audiences, and their reports of the same incident can be wildly different, and that’s where the opinions of the writer starts to show. Obviously I don’t believe that a report can be entirely without a second-hand opinion, in fact I think it’s impossible to produce a perfectly neutral news report. However I do believe that the situation right now could be remedied into a far better state than it is now. By having a opinion-wise neutral news report, it gives the reader a chance to developed their own opinions on the subject, and if the writer would want to give their view on the topic which I agree with, it should be segregated from the facts of the news report to warn news readers that what they read will be a third-person view of the report. Thus News reports and proper discussion of opinions can be properly distinguished. 

However, some people have told me that they disagree with what I said, thus I would like to know the general consensus of how people view this view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31929194015.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>There is "the news" and there are opinion pieces. If your point is that these should be made clearer from an audience standpoint, yes. However, legally speaking, any given tv "news report" is either "news" or "opinion", but it doesn't have to be obvious to the audience which it is, only to the lawman. 

Much of - oh look Fox is being dumb again (and CNN and MSNBC) are legally opinion pieces not "news". Compare Fox between 3-4 pm to Fox between 7-9 pm. Night and Day, since between 3-4 Fox is legally "news".

Edit: more specifically, Fox is news:
Weekdays: 4am - 6am/ 9am - 12pm/ 3-4pm / 6pm - 7pm
Saturday: 12pm - 3pm/ 4pm - 8pm
Sunday: 12pm - 2pm/ 4pm - 5pm/ 6pm - 7pm

If you are watching any other time, it just straight up isn't news, it's "political commentary".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31929224961.0" user="Daberinos" delta="False">
    <text>My problem lies to where factual news sources and opinion pieces meld together, and that creates subtle opinions between the lines of facts placed by the author (subconsciously or intentionally) which can affect , no matter how little, your own opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31929277265.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know what your watching is "news"? It can says news in the corner, the anchor can say news verbally, the name of the program can contain the word news, and still it might not legally be news. Unless you Google the timesheet, there are no audio or visual clues in the programs themselves to distinguish news from fiction. 

This is the key problem. 

When it's actually the news, it's usually fine, the problem is there is no way to know if what your watching is actually news, unless the research the network.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31929305704.0" user="Daberinos" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t quite understand your point, unless you are trying to say what makes the difference between a news report vs a opinion piece, then yes I do know the difference, one being a main objective being reporting news and the other to explore opinions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
