<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710395649.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bqy8sh/cmv_its_easier_to_make_a_dogs_death_emotional/">
    <title>CMV: Its easier to make a dog's death emotional than a humans death in movies</title>
    <original_poster>romancandle4</original_poster>
    <original_post>So in movies it's pretty hard to make an audience emotional. I barely ever get emotional at humans deaths but when a dog dies I feel sad. I thought about it and I realized something. So one of the main things required to make a death scene emotional is to make the audience attached to the person or dog. And in the average 1 hour 30 minute to 2 hour run time it's hard to make the audience attached to characters at an emotional level. Here's where the dog has a distinct advantage with first impressions. When you walk down the street and a see a random person unless he is doing something that you like/dislike you tend to just think "that a guy/girl, that's a human" or other minor things. When you see a dog most people tend to think "awe he/she is cute or what a good boy/girl!" It's much easier to get attached to a dog than a person. Also another thing dogs have over humans is we tend to need to relate to humans in order to like them on an emotional level. For example if some one made a really nice and heroic character in a movies at first we would like him but since we ourselves tend not to be heroic and nice all the time we can't relate. Making a good human character like that is really hard because you need to have really good characteristics to make him likable but also a flaw that makes him relatable.  However we don't need to relate with dogs to love them we don't have much in common with dogs yet we still love them to death. In conclusion if you won't to make me cry from a movie death a dog is probably a better option.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944420933.0" user="PauLtus" delta="False">
    <text>There's a thing which tend to make it inherently more dramatic: they tend to be pretty helpless and non-understanding so killing them off is that more harsh. This however is not *necessarily* the case for dogs and is something that can be applied to other characters as well. Small children can have that same "quality" as well.

But the big thing is that it's just as relatable as seeing a human die in a film but we're simply *less used to it*. I really love dogs and I have lost one myself so it's not something I have trouble relating to but at this point (I watch a lot of films) I've seen it happen often enough where I just don't inherently care about a dog because it's a dog anymore.

Also:

&amp;gt;And in the average 1 hour 30 minute to 2 hour run time it's hard to make the audience attached to characters at an emotional level.

Not if you're a good writer. The general rule for any mainstream entertainment nowadays is to basically stockholm-syndrome people into caring about characters and then take it away (could be due to being incapable or having more content to sell) but you really don't need 10 hours to make people care. Being efficient with your story is a good thing. There's a reason people keep going on about [those first couple of minutes from Up](https://youtu.be/F2bk_9T482g), besides being very relatable it's also incredibly efficient which only makes it more effective than if it were to be stretched out to 2 hours.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
