<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710395649.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bqy8sh/cmv_its_easier_to_make_a_dogs_death_emotional/">
    <title>CMV: Its easier to make a dog's death emotional than a humans death in movies</title>
    <original_poster>romancandle4</original_poster>
    <original_post>So in movies it's pretty hard to make an audience emotional. I barely ever get emotional at humans deaths but when a dog dies I feel sad. I thought about it and I realized something. So one of the main things required to make a death scene emotional is to make the audience attached to the person or dog. And in the average 1 hour 30 minute to 2 hour run time it's hard to make the audience attached to characters at an emotional level. Here's where the dog has a distinct advantage with first impressions. When you walk down the street and a see a random person unless he is doing something that you like/dislike you tend to just think "that a guy/girl, that's a human" or other minor things. When you see a dog most people tend to think "awe he/she is cute or what a good boy/girl!" It's much easier to get attached to a dog than a person. Also another thing dogs have over humans is we tend to need to relate to humans in order to like them on an emotional level. For example if some one made a really nice and heroic character in a movies at first we would like him but since we ourselves tend not to be heroic and nice all the time we can't relate. Making a good human character like that is really hard because you need to have really good characteristics to make him likable but also a flaw that makes him relatable.  However we don't need to relate with dogs to love them we don't have much in common with dogs yet we still love them to death. In conclusion if you won't to make me cry from a movie death a dog is probably a better option.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31943061269.0" user="SFnomel" delta="False">
    <text>In Game of Throne's The Red Wedding, no one ever talks about Grey Wind's death, only the 3 other characters that died.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
