<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944198942.0" user="Rebecca_deWinter_" delta="False">
    <text>For what it's worth, it does read a bit as though you may simply not enjoy these subjects and therefore see less value in them.  

Your criticism about history classes focusing on memorization rather than critical thinking is more an issue of pedagogy rather than a problem inherent to the subject.  The subject of history is brimming with opportunities to develop critical thinking skills.  Questioning past decisions and events and the potential motives behind them seems to me to be an excellent way to develop those skills.

  More than that, history is important because it bridges the gap between the way life is in the present to the way life was for our parents and grandparents and thereby bridges the gap in understanding different generations.  I would argue that understanding the last 100 to 150 years of history is important for understanding political parties, social and racial divisions, views on our economic system, international relations and a whole host of other topics. 

 I also found that learning about various periods and historical events allowed me to develop empathy for the people in those situations. It is easy to learn that the Civil War took place in the 1860s, but quite another to imagine Gettysburg strewn with the bodies of over 20,000 soldiers.  

Students also have the opportunity to learn about modern issues in government or political science classes.

As for literature classes, I agree that everything should be done to incorporate engaging texts and books in class, but I also strongly see the value in analyzing important works of the past.  The plots and themes of Shakespeare can be found today in modern literature and movies.

  Many common books read in literature classes also tie in with important historical periods, for example, To Kill a Mockingbird and The Scarlet Letter.  And reading 1984 and Farenheit 451 are great novels to use to develop critical thinking skills.  

My high school literature classes also included public speaking, debating, and creating and presenting projects, which are all very important skills that tie in to a variety of future careers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
