<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945131791.0" user="shakeyjakey1706" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting to see this, because as a literature student I've always felt the same way about STEM subjects pre-degree level.

This may well be a case of we get value out of those subjects which we enjoy most/excel in. Throughout senior school and sixth form (I'm UK), my study of literature developed communication skills, writing skills, my awareness of society and context, taught me about history and the ways in which literature aided the development of society.

Though GCSE wasn't the kind of in depth analysis I wanted and I didn't like most of the texts I studied, the wide array of literature studied gave me a fantastic foundation knowledge on which to further my study and even my personal reading - it taught me about how to discern fact from opinion in writing, how to write persuasively, and the basics of linguistics. As a literature geek, writing and reading others work is one of the biggest means by which I connect with people and learn about others - the constant presence of literature in my academic life, though I wasn't always thrilled by the books and certainly didn't realise at the time, has made me an empathetic person who is better able to communicate. Fine tuning those skills doesn't happen overnight - it's taken me 20 years to get to where I am, and the years of work I was made to do in senior school are 100% a part of it even though at the time I sometimes wondered WHY I had to do what I was doing in class. The way I've been consistently guided in developing my literary awareness gave me space to grow as a student of literature and means that now, I'm prepared for my degree and further development. 

The subject matter in high school/GCSE courses might seem to be spread thinly, but the variation they provide means I have been able to map out a great array of literary career paths I know I'd be interested in.

However, I'm into literature - someone who isn't as drawn to literature, maybe not even generally but in an academic context, wouldn't garner the same value out of these foundation level courses provided to us at ages 12-18. They're there to set us up, not to teach us everything - the taste we are given of our subjects is designed to help us find out which ones we want to pursue. In the same way you might not have sensed the value or excitement of literature/history in your high school classes, I found chemistry/physics/maths utterly pointless. I fundamentally understand why we studied them, and I even tried to retain that STEM side by taking maths in my first year of sixth form (16-17) but ultimately, I gained nothing of value from those subjects. The critical thinking and logic skills I have were developed just as much by my study of design and arts subjects in which I applied them. 

So I'd argue that the perceived value of a subject is incredibly subjective. I don't believe that my senior school study of STEM gave me much of anything I didn't gain elsewhere, and ultimately the content was arguably as simplified and spread thin as any humanities subject. That taste of the subject simply allowed me to decide that STEM wasn't my path - I didn't pick up on the exciting little bits of the subjects like I did with literature because I'm simply not a STEM guy. Whilst they haven't been valuable in my life, they've clearly been valuable to many of my friends in setting them up for further study and  STEM career paths - in the same way literature courses are valuable to people like me. 

Whilst we can see the ways in which subjects we don't connect with try/are meant to be valuable, we simply don't all click with every one - and that's totally fine. But that value is still there, it's just someone else's to pick up and run with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
