<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="33" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945520388.0" user="bastard_swine" delta="False">
    <text>So I'm actually in school to be a high school English and Social Studies teacher in the US. I agreed with everything in your introduction...except your solution.

You offer valid criticisms of courses without context, which I was snapping my fingers too thinking you were going to get to how to *improve* these courses, but your conclusion seems to be to curtail these courses instead of improving them?

In my education classes the majority of what we discuss is how the old models aren't working and how we can improve lesson plans to foster critical thinking and contextual learning. I'm not going to dump semesters worth of educational strategies on you, but I'm curious as to why your first instinct is to throw out the baby with the bathwater.

Also, as others have said, time is a REAL problem. Sometimes you don't realize how valuable a wide swath of surface-level info is (especially for building context). For example, in university I had to take two courses called Reading Broadly and Reading Closely. Broadly was all about a wide array of literature for building context, which helped in Closely because we had reference points from Broadly with which to apply critical analysis and evaluation during Closely.

High school is a lot like Reading Broadly. Even by senior year when electives start to become more commonplace, there's huge gaps in student awareness about all the history and literature that's out there. Narrowing down your focus to what you really enjoy about literature and history so that you CAN study closely and critically is hard to do if you don't already have a wide smattering of familiarity with the totality of history and literature.

While it can be boring and not as intellectually rigorous, that is in part what college is for. Imagine trying to pick what courses you're interested in college if you didn't taste from a smorgasbord of different periods of literature and history in high school.

So yeah, context and critical analysis can sometimes be at odds with one another because one implies broad studying and the other implies close studying, and there's only so much time teachers have to cover this stuff. A balance can be struck, but it's difficult and by in large the mark of a *really* good teacher. Which is another point I forgot to mention. States and whatnot do have curriculum frameworks that guide teacher content, but the way the class itself is taught and the way content is covered is for the most part up to the teacher. It's possible you've just had bad luck with high school teachers, as I've had a handful of *really* good history and literature teachers in high school that were able to strike the balance.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
