<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944421450.0" user="berrieh" delta="False">
    <text>I teach English, though it's worth noting in *most* English courses, literature is a component of a well-rounded course, not the whole course. That makes sense for the "general" population. In my school system, a student who just seeks to graduate never has to take a "literature course," though does naturally have to read some literary fiction. Most general education ELA classes include grammar, writing instruction, literature, nonfiction (informational and rhetoric), speaking, and listening skills as well as often visual analysis of some kind, if you look at all the standards in said course. A whole literature class is usually only for AP (where they divide nonfiction and literature into Lang and Lit, rather than integrate them) or IB (which offers both a mixed Language and Literature English and a full Literature English --- and I believe that convention is the same in all languages). 

There *are* literature courses. I teach 2 of them, an IB one and an AP one, but they are for students seeking deeper learning in more rigorous courses. In the case of IB, I'd say it's also a programme that values the humanities for ideological reasons -- as part of its very premise and mission statement to "create a more peaceful world" where we create "intercultural understanding" and realize that "others, with their differences, can also be right." For the average student, I think taking a course like HL Literature but at their own level would probably do them good, but no such courses exist at my school. Taking a class where you read texts you cannot possibly understand because you read below level us obviously an issue, but the issue isn't "literature" -- it's that kids read below level. ELA foundations are not secured for a variety of reasons. None of which are improved by removing fiction from the curriculum. 

I think the value of literature is to develop empathy and perspective. The question of what literature you teach, and most importantly *how*, is always at play. If students hate literature because they have the experience of feeling disconnected and not understanding it, or doing tasks that undermine it's power, it can be less effective. But it can be the most relevant and effective tool students see all day. Literature can teach you how to see the world from a POV that is not your own. It can literally Change Your View! Studies show it develops empathy. But I don't need studies personally because I've *seen* it. I've seen students discuss texts in circles over the year and become better thinkers and, most of all, more empathetic people who consider a range of perspectives. 

Storytelling is also cited by experts now as a crucial 21st century workplace skill. Why? Because the human brain clings to narratives and it helps one to be understood to be able to put their points into stories. It helps in management roles. It helps in client relationships. It helps in job interviews. Readers of literary fiction tell better stories. Reading stories and thinking in a narrative sense are intertwined. That doesn't require reading a *particular* author but it involves reading high quality books, and I'd argue any high-quality book is literature.

This is a separate point wortg noting -- Not all the texts I use in AP or IB are old or anything. *Little Fires Everywhere* is literature too. *Persepolis* is literature. Lots of things I teach are new (like LFE) or varied in genre (like Persepolis, which is a graphic novel). Though older texts are often very engaging too and allow for the teaching of 2 specific things: intercultural understanding of another time when you consider the work in historical context AND a common cultural framework of allusions for generations. 

Anyway, so literature increases storytelling skills, empathy, and the ability to view the world from multiple perspectives. It allows catharsis and a way to experience things you don't actually go through yourself. It allows shared human experiences. Those are social-emotional skills from ELA literature units that I think go beyond anything else I teach in English classes. I think they also go beyond almost anything taught in high school, and I have some experience with other subjects. Why? Because they don't merely teach a "skill" -- they improve emotional and philosophical skills and reasoning holistically. They engage a student's humanity. Again, only if done well. 

Literary criticism also requires a higher level of abstract thought than research, rhetorical analysis, or mere comprehension, on average. When one expects actual literary criticism, that is. Now I have seen some terrible things done to all instruction, including ELA (maybe especially ELA as it is MORE tested than other subjects on average), including literature in this heavy testing era. But that's not a sign teaching literature is useless so much as the focus has become skewed by big testing. But creating a literary commentary at say the IB level requires being able to notice specific things in a text of any genre, analyze why the author does those things and what they add to the text, and fully engage with those ideas in writing. The literary terminology needed to do that might not be needed for life but that kind if engaged observation can be applied to any skillset and analyzing literature (where meaning is naturally and often intentionally obscured by form and must be "discovered") is simply more difficult than analysing informational text (where facts and ideas are put before form and clearly stated) or rhetoric (where a specific agenda is clearly established). It's more sophisticated thinking and leads to multiple interpretations of a work, which allows students to develop critical thinking skills. There is usually a very narrow range of thought or meaning within analyzing rhetoric, one can't even really "analyze" informational text except maybe for what it emphasizes, but literature opens up many possibilities for individual engagement and thought. 

Granted, many students actively avoid that by trying to get their opinions from the internet, each other, their parents, or even their teachers who are tricked into doing the analysis FOR them. But that's not a reason it's not valuable. It's a reason it may need to be valued more so you get experts who do it better. When people tell me they learned little by reading literature in English, I think it's mostly because of how it was taught rather than the content. I have taught history, which others have already discussed more extensively, and biology, and more focused skill-base elective classes (journalism, research, yearbook, ethics) and nothing I've taught is as difficult to teach well as literature. Nor as difficult to learn well. But the value literature has when taught well surpasses everything else I've taught.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946528999.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946630696.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/DADDYmilk – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+DADDYmilk&amp;amp;message=DADDYmilk+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/br74om/-/eoc4zjb/\)+because...).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
