<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944217261.0" user="MaroonTrojan" delta="False">
    <text>What's the educational value of a music student drilling scales over and over, if I've never seen a concert pianist perform scales in front of an audience?

What's the point of learning to write a 'hello world' program in a new programming language if you'll never be able to sell it on the app store?

What's the point of a pilot training on a flight simulator? Pilots fly *planes*, not simulators. 

What's the point of trying new foods when I already know I like chicken fingers?

Perhaps you can see the faulty thinking here. While you're not wrong that a lot of what you're asked to do as a high school student of literature or history doesn't seem to be the same as what professional literary scholars or historians do for their jobs, you must recognize that one must learn to crawl before learning to walk. The Canon of high school lit is arbitrary but for the fact that there are certain patterns that run deep, but in a way, that's the point. 

We've decided that everyone should at least *be given the option* to look at these great literary works and have the tools to understand what makes them good. Is Romeo &amp;amp; Juliet Shakespeare's greatest play? Not really. But if you wanted to come to a deeper appreciation of Shakespeare (or his contemporaries, or other plays, or acting/directing/stagecraft, or the other works Shakespeare alludes to), how could you do that without someone showing you to the door and opening it for you? If you think it's not for you, fine. You've learned something about yourself, and that's as valuable a lesson as it is for the people who encounter these works for the first time in high school, love them, and decide they want to travel a path where they can learn more about them. So you might need to think more carefully about what you mean by "meaningful educational value". You've learned you don't like reading high-falutin' novels; you prefer non-fiction writing and the sciences. Isn't that a valuable takeaway? How would you have learned that without English class? 

Here's the thing about high school: you may have surmised that it's bullshit and none of it really matters. And in a way, you're right; as much as people try to tell you otherwise, the material you're learning in high school is very surface-level, and it comes at you really fast. You're water-skiing. However, the idea is to water-ski you all over the "lake" (this includes academic subjects, extracurriculars, and social bonds) so you can form a sense of what spots you want to revisit with a snorkel, and then a scuba tank. *That's* how to make the most of your high school experience: keep your eyes open for something that interests you, and then go at it with all the force your young, weird, hormonal body can throw at it. Maybe it will be the thing you do forever; maybe it won't. But to be a jaded teen who thinks the only part of education that's "meaningful" is the part that puts you on the path to a job as a codemonkey is to fundamentally misunderstand the word "meaningful".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944334835.0" user="Dakkloehn" delta="False">
    <text>This is definitely something I learned after I learned college wasn't for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944403572.0" user="AusTF-Dino" delta="False">
    <text>This seems extremely flawed as an argument. I'm going to talk about English only here, because History is taught very differently in Australia (it's more about analysing why or sharing viewpoints on historical events rather than memorising dates - going through high school I did not need to memorise a single date of any historical event). 


I'm of the view that most of high school English is completely 100% useless - I don't know if it's different in America but in Australia all of high school English is poetry, essay writing, text analysis, and bullshit like that, while there is extremely little grammar development and literally zero spelling and persuasive writing, which, ironically, are the most important real world skills that people should be taking away from English.


Analysing old works such as Shakespeare's plays is completely useless. They are no longer relatable to real life. The entire world has changed since they were written - a lot of the concepts featured in Shakespeare's works such as regality and superstition are no longer effective and genius features that help to set a scene, but rather cheesy shit that we all look at and have to pretend like it's even remotely relevant or interesting. Even if you go into an English based career like journalism, you are not going to ever use Shakespeare's insight into how at the time witches scared people and helped to set a scene. This is one of the standout reasons why Shakespeare adaptations are almost always set in a high school - the concepts are so foreign in the modern day that people are forced to use the artificial and detached society of a high school to convey the story because of how ridiculous it would be if you tried to set it in real life.


In fact, in high school one of my English assignments was to write a creative piece relating to Macbeth, and I got full marks writing an opinion piece about how Macbeth is lacking and should no longer be used as a studied text in high school. 



So to conclude it's not really like a pilot flying a simulator instead of the real thing. It's more like a pilot driving a car to practice plane flying. The car is as detached from the plane as high school English is to real life. Related, yet not close enough to be useful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944691001.0" user="therocketbear" delta="False">
    <text>If the works of Shakespeare were in no way applicable to modern life then no one would read them or adapt them. I don’t really see how English could be completely useless, I’ll assume you’re being hyperbolic, however regardless of what you learned in English, you had to learn reading comprehension skills which you can transfer to other kinds of texts, there are skills for writing that transfer across genres, etc. A sentence is a sentence regardless of what genre you write in. 

Now could high school English be better, absolutely but calling it entirely useless is a stretch to say the least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945097357.0" user="AusTF-Dino" delta="False">
    <text>High school English is entirely or almost entirely useless (that is not a hyperbole). High school English involves no spelling, grammar, or persuasive writing. It has nothing to do with sentences or spelling, that is primary school English, and perhaps the most useful thing you will ever do.


&amp;gt; if Shakespeare's works were in no way applicable to modern life nobody would read or adapt them.



This is entirely not true. A story is a story. Take Star Wars for example, undeniably one of the best and most successful books and movies of all time. And guess what - it has zero application in the modern day. It is about futuristic knights with magic swords flying around in spaceships, and fighting robots and aliens. That does not stop it from being adapted and read/watched. There are a million more examples out there - a story is a story. 


Shakespeare is only chosen because of the historical and cultural value, but aside from that, it is completely useless. Hell, all of his work is written in broken, mostly incoherent English that people need definitions and notes to read because it's so foreign.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945973874.0" user="MaroonTrojan" delta="False">
    <text>Star Wars has zero application in the modern day? What about the literally thousands (perhaps hundreds of thousands) of people who work producing Star Wars related content? Apart from the films-- which support thousands of jobs in a wide range of fields-- there are the books, toys, merchandise, and all the marketing thereof. How do you suppose any of those things come to be? If someone loves Star Wars so thoroughly that they decide to make their life about it, that should be an option that's available to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948616434.0" user="AusTF-Dino" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about the story. The story has no relation to real life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948828245.0" user="MaroonTrojan" delta="False">
    <text>Who's ever been in deep personal conflict with their father?

Who's ever had to seek out a mentor and wonder if the advice he's giving is trustworthy?

Who's ever been betrayed by a friend?

Who's ever been called upon to do something way above their level of experience?

Who's ever found themselves developing feelings for someone outside their social rank?

Should I go on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946556509.0" user="JamFox" delta="False">
    <text>It's never just about the "futuristic robots, lasers and sentient monkeys doing summersaults while fighting." The music, characters, the robots, the story - it's all a vehicle for some message, even in Star Wars. Sure you can enjoy it for the "robots and other cool stuff" but it's really about say, good and evil, emotionality and a whole lot of other things. Same with Shakespeare, I doubt he ever wanted to just tell stories about tragic crybabies and ghosts, that's all just the vehicle for analysing the human condition. Since they all tackle with some variation of the question "what it means to be human?" that makes them timeless - both Shakespeare and Star Wars, even if they seem very different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948790201.0" user="therocketbear" delta="False">
    <text>If you look at the surface of the story you’re right, we don’t have magical knights gallavanting about space. But here’s the thing we can relate to the characters, I get that hate English but that’s like the point of stories to convey themes and meaning regardless of the stories setting, classic stories like Shakespeare’s or even Star Wars have themes you can relate regardless of time and place. It’s really not that hard</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946716677.0" user="Skyy-High" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Analysing old works such as Shakespeare's plays is completely useless. They are no longer relatable to real life.

Oof. You really think people 400 years ago were that much different from today? You look at Shakespeare's favorite themes (pride, love, jealousy, paranoia, indecision, lust, fate, revenge) and see nothing that is relatable to 21st century human society? That is, to be blunt, incredibly shallow. The fact that you don't bite your thumb but instead might flick someone off from across the street (and then pretend you didn't when you're called out on it) does not change the fundamentally human emotions behind that scene, that everyone can relate to. 

Someone who writes for a living but has no knowledge of Shakespeare will invariably end up sounding stilted in their prose, because they will be writing with the depth of emotion present in the Classical era, having skipped (or needing to re-invent it from scratch) all of what came afterwards.

Even if you never directly reference Shakespeare in your life again, your life will be more rich for having read his works and pondered, for even a few months of your formative life, on these deep emotional issues after being presented with works that are specifically designed to get you to think about them. Romeo and Juliet was written to entertain, and also to get you to see how artificial social barriers cause tragedy, and also to comment on how young "love" is irrational and potentially destructive. Those are all useful things for any teenager to think about, not just people who will grow up to be novelists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946921618.0" user="CREEEEEEEEED" delta="False">
    <text>A-fucking-men. How can someone say that Shakespear's works are detached from today? people still love, have family feuds, lie to each other and seek power just as much as they did 400 years ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944827484.0" user="deadman5551" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like you agree with OP; he says in his second clarification that he thinks these topics should be able to be pursued electively, which sounds like that’s the basis of your post (*”...be given the option to look at the great literary works”*). Seems like OP’s issue is that most high schools (in America) *require* 4 years of history and English/literacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945821215.0" user="MaroonTrojan" delta="False">
    <text>I mean *given the option* in the sense that students have a level of baseline knowledge that lets them seek out more knowledge, should they choose to. To compare it to the sciences, we had to do a year of chemistry, a year of biology, and a year of physics so that we could *have the option* to choose which subject we would study more intensely later on. 

Not knowing anything about a subject (or being allowed swear it off at the age of 15) is not the kind of option I'm talking about. I mean you need to have the tools to understand it well enough that you can learn more about it on your own, should you choose to. And to obtain those tools I think does take four years; actually, probably more than that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945929297.0" user="KingOfTheCouch13" delta="False">
    <text>By the time I was 15 I good done like 8 years of history and maybe 4 years of literature. I definitely knew by that point that I didn't like either. Still was required to take them every year all the way through my second year of college. That just seems like a waste.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
