<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944050818.0" user="CircleReversed" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of the things I learned in college humanities classes had long-lasting effects on the way I view the world and how I live my life. I wouldn’t have been able to jump into college-level humanities work without first having been trained in high school humanities. All of the greatest mathematicians had to learn arithmetic at some point.

By the way, the criticisms you have could be true at one high school and inapplicable at another. You only your your own high school experience, and maybe the experiences of some peers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944061044.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I don't necessarily disagree with you here, but my post is more about the failure of these classes to provide value to the general student population. I do believe they should be available as elective options for students who are interested.

I just don't think they help most students develop any sort of valuable skills that are better taught via debate or public speaking courses</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944070704.0" user="CircleReversed" delta="False">
    <text>Why is your opinion they should be electives, and not that they should be taught better so that they do provide value to the average student?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944088541.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>Because, as you stated, they can provide value specifically to students who plan to purse liberal arts degrees. But to the general population, learning about details of the Civil War provides no tangible benefits.

In the same way that many engineering specific courses like metal shop can be taken electively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944696305.0" user="beepbooplechuga" delta="False">
    <text>Cultivating a culture of ignorance about history is one of the worst things a country can do to itself.  The ramifications of the civil war are still being dealt with today, from confederate statues to free speech to federalism. Knowing history is essential to understating the present political and social landscape. Also, you seem to ignore that your public speaking and debate classes aren’t liked much more than history. Most of the population will be at a desk for their working career and their debates will be limited to Facebook. Why learn how to give a speech? I disagree with this because critical thinking is important, but so is knowing history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944187808.0" user="vettewiz" delta="False">
    <text>Probably because they have extremely limited value for life</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31947058969.0" user="peonypegasus" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. Literature is about questioning the human condition and finding meaning in life. Sure, it might not make you any money, but it gives you a context in which to think about what it is to live a good life.

High school calculus, biology, and chemistry have limited value for life. I have never been asked to use Rolle's Theorem outside of an academic setting, nor have I needed to calculate any molar masses or describe yeast reproduction.

Should we only teach students basic literacy and arithmetic skills, then send everyone to a specialized vocational school? Having a public with a well-rounded general knowledge background is useful in giving people a way to engage with the world and find something beyond their day-to-day experiences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946872400.0" user="xxxamazexxx" delta="False">
    <text>Why don’t we do away with Math and replace it with a tax workshop then? Oh, we can’t, because those students won’t even know enough mathematic operations or execute them well enough to properly fill out a tax form. 

How are you supposed to teach debate and public speaking, when students don’t have enough vocabulary and expressions, don’t know how to look for evidence and form persuasive arguments, and don’t have any cultural capital to draw on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946916073.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>You're misrepresenting my argument here. I'm not saying we don't teach history or literature. They are fundamental parts of education.

But math courses successfully teach math operations via lots of practice problems. History courses do not teach analysis of history well because the focus is heavily on details, not analysis. Same with literature. We don't focus on forming arguments but rather on abstract concepts like literary styles and literary structures like similes.

My argument is a failure to teach the necessary lessons, not that those lessons are unnecessary.

If I am taught that the colonists employed guerilla warfare and took advantage of home field advantage during the Revolution, I can go research details of specific battles if needed for a debate. The time spent learning about individual battles in the war could be better spent analyzing larger themes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31947027778.0" user="xxxamazexxx" delta="False">
    <text>Do you realize the problem is not with the subjects themselves but with the way they are taught at some places? Why then did you advocate getting rid of them altogether?

Also, never tell anyone that Math can’t be taught in similarly unproductive ways. You did not think this through.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31947070260.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I realized I didn't make it clear in the original post. If you look at my 2nd edit, I clearly state that I am not arguing to get rid of them altogether</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
