<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944119388.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I challenge your entire view of the education system.


The public education system is only designed for indoctrination and for teaching obedience. 

Not a single class has any meaningful educational value. They do not teach how to think. Only what to think. 

However. I would say history is a hard subject to say does not provide a meaningful educational value...

When taught correctly...history provides insight into why things are the way they are...and how things in the past have worked. This knowledge is extremely valuable. Not all history taught in schools is bullshit, which a good portion of it is though. But its more important to know history than opinions on literature.

Reading, however, and learning how to interpret language is a very valuable skill to learn....its just forced opinions on fictional writings are a terrible way to teach that. So i guess i disagree with you in more than one way. But agree in some too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944128832.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree on the premise of the education system being designed to teach us what to think. Are you arguing that this is what the system has become, or what it is intended for? The former may be true, but the latter I disagree with.

Also, my argument focuses on the belief that history/literature is not taught correctly. You mentioned the benefits when taught correctly, but I think the structure of the curriculum fails to deliver those benefits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944158976.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Thats entirely what it was intended for. 

To train obedience in the industrial era for factory workers. 

You also dont think a majority of history is important, and i argue that it is. Its a lot of government indoctrination bullshit that is taught. Events skewed. Thats why i dont think it is taught correctly. 

I think history is very important...to make a point... 

This fancy new wireless charging that seems to have become very popular in the last 2 years...was first conceived in the late 1800s.

Why would they avoid this type of history? Why would anybody? Because it doesnt fit the narrative. So in fact i argue that history all together is vastly more important....and needs more coverage in school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944345981.0" user="MaroonTrojan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Thats entirely what it was intended for.

&amp;gt;To train obedience in the industrial era for factory workers.

Uhh... Citation needed?

If anything, free public education was seen as a respite for children so they *wouldn't* end up as exploited factory workers. The earliest proponents of public education were Fabian Socialists, who rejected the industrial movement and fought for the (radical, at the time) notion that there was more to human dignity than wage slavery-- especially for children. 

And if you look at the literary canon most associated with high school lit, if there's one thing it has in common it's with a glorification of the superhuman power of the Everyman to rise above his circumstances and Do Something Great (aka achieve class mobility), as a direct response to the Soviet system of Gymnasiums, which were focused on funnelling students into particular industries. *To Kill a Mockingbird*, *The Great Gatsby*,  *Catch 22*, *Lord of the Flies*.

It sounds like you've got a chip on your shoulder and weak grasp on history. That's a bummer, because I can tell it's a subject that interests you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945897774.0" user="kittysezrelax" delta="False">
    <text>Oof. There is a very unfortunate misunderstanding of the history of education in this post. Education reform in the 1890’s was about providing alternatives to factory work for working class and immigrant children, wresting control of local schools from party bosses who absolutely did use the school system as a means of party indoctrination  (and rewarded the best students with patronage jobs within the party), and establishing educational opportunities for black children in the Jim Crow-era south.  At the height of the industrial era/guilted age, fewer than 10% of Americans graduated high school, which would make it a terrible way to indoctrinate the working classes since their absence from the education system was, according to progressive-era education reformers, the reason industry was able to continuously exploit them generation after generation. If anything, these reformers wanted to use education to produce the middle and professional classes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
