<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945320779.0" user="duckylilaa" delta="False">
    <text>I believe your stance is owed to this : you're missing the point of both History as a science and Literature as an art.

History is not there to teach us what not to do in the future. It is not a subject which ought to develop some sort of moral compass by defining which past events were "bad" and which were "good". It's not "let's study discrimination so we don't discriminate in the future".

In fact, a formal education in history and sociology would drive a mind away from such binary and simplistic views. 

History does one thing for individuals: it lets young minds understand an old world. It enables them to grasp context, to perceive nuances, to be aware of the weight of social, economical, artistic, technological, linguistic, political phenomena (for example) in the long term. 
It lets people do exactly the opposite of what you describe: refuse sweeping generalisations and be able to perceive not the familiarity of the past, but what makes it unique. 

Secondly, the teaching of literature is necessarily slightly separate from the leisurely reading each of us is experiencing, going by taste and inclination. It does tune one's appreciation. Beyond the practical uses of one's own rhetorical powers, which greatly benefit from the knowledge of figures of speech and artistic writing, the arts are valuable as a complement of the sciences and social sciences. They bear witness to a state of things now gone, and yet retain some universal value which is at the very centre of that thing we are so hard pressed to define: culture. It sharpens the critical mind in a different way : it lets us study, and value works for  other motives than " I like it".


What you seem to miss completely is that critical sense is not some purely individualistic journey. In fact, it is shaped by an understanding of things greater and broader than one's own tastes and one's own ability to persuade in a cheap debate. Critical sense relies on the ability to focus on something foreign.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
