<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="50" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946339204.0" user="throwaway1084567" delta="False">
    <text>I actually think the focus of high school history SHOULD be basic facts and dates, such that each student comes away with a foundation for more advanced critical thinking about history in college.  You just can't make any sense of history if you don't even know what happened when and where, it's like trying to understand literature without knowing basic grammar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946687601.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, but most students that don't pursue a liberal arts degree will not engage in advanced thinking about history in college. Which leads to a society of individuals where most of us cannot understand the similarities between things like the Civil Rights movement and the struggles of certain groups today. Or the historical damage done by wide sweeping nationalist politics.

If high school is the only time most people study history, it should not be used just to set the playing ground for future studies that likely never happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949817493.0" user="Love_on_crack" delta="False">
    <text>The vast majority of people will never use the theorems that they have to learn in mathematics classes or remember the periodic tables or equations drilled into their heads in science classes after they graduate.  Still they are important for a well rounded education, just as memorizing certain dates and events in history are.  All require route memorization, just as learning vocabulary and grammar does, whether people use their education to think critically ultimately is up to them.  It is the goal of an education system to provide people with the information to build their understanding of the world upon.  Whether that be understanding the molecular structure of chemicals or why the Roman Empire collapsed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949832227.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>But is the valuable part of history courses the historical facts or the lessons we take from history to apply to today's world?

I'm not saying history doesn't have value, I'm saying that it is taught ineffectively</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31950121518.0" user="Love_on_crack" delta="False">
    <text>The facts are the empirical evidence of history without learning the facts how could one possibly hope to understand or interpret history?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31950133585.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>Time to teach is a limited resource in high school. Ideally, we would teach historical facts forever. But for 4 years in high school, why dedicate all the time to teaching facts and very little to analysis?

The current approach focuses way too much on teaching facts and very little on interpreting</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
