<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="35" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945671638.0" user="alexzoin" delta="False">
    <text>I'll say, at least anecdotally, I was exposed to a lot of literature in highschool English classes that I otherwise would have never read. Things like Of Mice and Men, the Odyssey, Romeo and Juliet, Flowers for Algernon, the Most Dangerous Game, Anthem.

Though not completely, these books played a huge role in shaping my world view and giving me a positive outlook on classic literature. I don't know that I would like books as much as I do if it weren't for that exposure.

As for history, rather than making it taught in fewer classes why not just redo the classes in the same quantity? The history classes I took were terribly inefficient with the time they had. Add to that many useless rout memorization tasks like remembering dates, presidents, states, etc. It would be one thing if I'd retained a high percentage of information but all I'm left with is a vague familiarity. The important parts I do remember were all delivered in more of a story. The concepts are what's important. I don't think the classes focus on that enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946157289.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I 100% agree with you on the history portion. Maybe we don't need to replace the classes, but the reorganization is essential.

I am open to the argument you made on the literature side, but not yet convinced that the same effect exists for most students. I also know some people that really benefitted from the literature we studied, but anecdotally I know a lot more that got nothing out of it, became disinterested in reading, or skimmed/SparkNotes their way through the class.

I'm not trying to push anecdotes as evidence, but I used to be an avid reader in middle school, when the main requirement was just to read X hours a week. I'd read way beyond that from books of my choosing. But in high school, the time I used to alot to free reading was redirected to reading assigned literature, which was useless to me. Flowers for Algernon I read in middle school and found to be a short, simple read. The Scarlet Letter on the other hand was a massive waste of time for me. I still cannot name a meaningful lesson I learned from it, and I spent many years without picking up a book of my own will since high school literature reshaped my view of reading</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946585881.0" user="alexzoin" delta="False">
    <text>I will say I can relate to your not enjoying some assigned reading. I didn't like To Kill a Mockingbird at all. It was a bore for me. I'll also say that I think I got the most out of books when part of class time was dedicated to the reading and some class hours were just spent listening and following along.

There's something about viewing it as an assignment versus viewing as something I enjoy and can learn from. I think listening in class really made it *feel* like a fun easy hour and honestly led me to pay attention a lot of the time. If for no other reason than I didn't have to work too hard.

Which is a nice segway into the literacy part of the English class situation. I know I learned a lot from classes as far as writing and vocabulary and I think it's totally valuable. That doesn't change the fact that a lot of people didn't though and I don't know how to fix that.

It *seems* to me that making kids want to learn things for the sake of learning them is the best way to actually improve a student's skill in an area long term.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
