<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="40" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945961810.0" user="Nyxto" delta="False">
    <text>I think the crux of your issue is that you're assuming that these classes are supposed to improve critical thinking, and that's the only goal. Also,  you assume all of these classes are taught the same way. 

Any good teacher can make any subject great for critical thinking and get students excited about the subject.  Any bad teacher can make any subject into rote memorization.  No two teachers' methods are the same. So you have a flaw of a low sample size. 

As for critical thinking being the only goal,  imagine if that was the only goal in schools.  You'd learn nothing about math,  science,  art,  music,  etc,  and all classes would just be the philosophy of critical thinking.  Not only would that be useless,  but it wouldn't be effective. There's other important aspects to life,  even in stem fields. 

Classes are a vector for knowledge, as even if it's not directly important to your field, it can help develop skills related to it better than classes which are.  History teaches you how to research and be critical of sources,  and teaches you how to use vague data to get a fairly solid conclusion, and does so much better than math.  Literature teaches you how to interpret information which isn't blatantly obvious, and does so better than chemistry.  Art teaches non lateral problem solving solutions,  which science can't do. 

These skills are necessary to succeed in stem fields,  as well as other aspects of life, such as business,  social interaction,  etc. 

So,  not all of these classes are incapable of teaching critical thinking, as it varies per teacher,  and critical thinking isn't and shouldn't be the only goal in these or any other class. 

Source: father is a historian and was a history professor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946420550.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>You're arguing for the concept of history, which I already agree should be taught. I'm not arguing against the value of the topic.

I am saying that the way history is currently taught focuses less on analyzing sources, and way too much on learning useless facts.

Literature focuses too little on meaningful analysis and too much on finding similes and metaphors, or forced symbolism in texts that have very little relevance in the modern world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946733732.0" user="Nyxto" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I am saying that the way history is currently taught focuses less on analyzing sources, and way too much on learning useless facts.

And I'm saying you're wrong,  not all history classes are taught like this. I already covered that point above. 

&amp;gt;Literature focuses too little on meaningful analysis and too much on finding similes and metaphors, or forced symbolism in texts that have very little relevance in the modern world.

That's because the skills you learn by picking up on subtext are useful for problem solving, even in stem fields, and literature is probably one of the best ways to be a vector for that skill.  

You're wrong about it being irrelevant in the modern world because that skill is more useful than ever. With how we're communicating with more people more constantly from ask over the world, knowing how to pick up on subtext and the influence someone's situation and background have on a situation are more vital than any other point in human history. 

Even with analysis,  being able to pick up on things which aren't apparent and being able to ruminate on less than obvious solutions is a vital skill for innovation. A lot of solutions aren't obvious, as being able to pick up on the obtuse is key to finding them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
