<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="48" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946312529.0" user="A_Trip_into_oblivion" delta="False">
    <text>I've got to disagree with pretty much everything you've written here. For reference I'm a criminology professor, not a historian. However, history is integrally important to what I do. For example how do I study the affect of race on crime/criminal justice system without knowing the history underpinning lots of the movements? How does one understand the use of prison plantations in the south *today* without knowing how and why they were established? How do you understand de facto segregation without knowing about policies like redlining and how long they existed? How do you understand the reluctance of minorities to call police without knowing the conditions under which police and their policies were established (spoiler, proto-police in the south existed primarily to round up runaway slaves and later keep black peopled in their place)? You can't get all the facts in one class. Or two classes. Or three classes. They slowly build and lend themselves to more in-depth analysis, but one must walk before he runs. If you're in a STEM field you should be familiar with how this works in math and science subjects. You've got to learn basic arithmetic, algebra, and geometry before you tackle calculus. You need basic chemistry (relying on on basic algebra for stoichiometry to balance equations) before you can tackle more novel work. It all builds. If you didn't get that basic structure in high school you'd be screwed in college. It's the same in history and english/literature, it's just less obvious to you if you don't go in to one of those fields.

You need to understand some basic facts before you can do any meaningful critical thought on the subject, and with history there is so much basic fact that you need. Take the Israeli-Palestinian issue. Do you understand the conflict? Better question, do you know the factual history of the conflict? If you don't know the facts about the McMahon-Hussein Correspondence, Balfour Declaration, and Sykes-Pico Agreement you don't even know the ***basics*** of a major ongoing conflict that pretty much everyone has an opinion on. Politics in the 1800s? Well, I'd say things like the Missouri Compromise of 1820, Indian Removal Act of 1830, Fugitive Slave Act of 1850, and other big pieces of legislation are integral to understanding our current issues. The politics of that era (states rights issues, the role of government in ensuring equality, etc) continues to directly impact the lives of people today. Everyone has an opinion on these issues, precious few (to include members of government) actually understand the history of these issues, and thus fail spectacularly at addressing them. Take the completely different issue of terrorism. Do you know its history? Who has used it and for what purpose? How often has it resulted in success for the supposed terrorists? How do we even historically define terrorism? Seems like a simple question until you actually start working on history. What about our continued problems with Cuba? Or Venezuela? Those conflicts make a lot more sense with an understanding of historical relations between the US and those countries (it's not as simple as Communism=bad).

Once again these are issues for which you need an integral understanding of the facts before we ever get to meaningful critical thinking. There is so much historical fact to parse that people specialize in extremely small subsets of the field. The best we can really do to prepare people to do ***anything*** that might require some history background is to teach them as much of the basic facts as we can (usually with an emphasis on local history) as well as the skills necessary to find those facts on their own (i.e. those annoying history papers where basically all you do is regurgitate facts that you have to hunt down on your own). By doing this, students are prepared for more challenging tasks. To use STEM examples again, you could hardly be expected to create and study the applications of carbon nanotubes without basic chemistry. If you're not planning to work in chemistry then those facts seem useless to you.

No offense to you or other STEM people, but you the frequency of these sorts of posts indicate that people really need to step out of their bubble a bit. Everything in high school will not be specifically relevant to you. I haven't used most of my hard science stuff since I took my mandatory 2 natural science courses in undergrad over a decade ago. That doesn't mean I shouldn't have had to take them, that the facts were useless simply because they weren't useful ***to me***. My buddy who is an attorney can barely do basic algebra anymore. He knew he wanted to an attorney since he was a child. Should the more advanced math courses have simply been electives for him so he could've focused more on philosophy and English which have been far more useful to him in his profession? I think we both know the answer is no. Those basic skills probably served him in ways he can't even really fathom. The usefulness of information and skills gained from history and literature are less easy to identify than those from STEM, but they are really no less valuable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946524864.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I appreciate the depth of your reply, but you've conveniently misstated my argument to paint it as a pro-STEM, anti-liberal arts argument, which it is not.

I'm arguing that the courses are ineffective in their current state, not that topics like history and literature should never be taught.

In your example of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, it doesn't matter if I have an opinion on the conflict. I am not tied to it in any professional capacity, so it isn't very useful for me to have an incredibly informed opinion based on all the history you mentioned on that topic. I understand this sounds dense, but simply having an opinion on a topic doesn't require one to be fully educated on the details; otherwise we'd all be in school forever. I do my research on basic history of the topic and read articles/viewpoints about current events before projecting my opinion, and that is sufficient for my role.

The general public knowing the history of Israel would be similar to everyone knowing the architecture of turbopump engines. Excessive and unnecessary.

You can easily argue for the value of knowing some things vs. not knowing them, but that is not the issue at hand. School has a set resource, time, which should be best utilized. In the current setup, I believe time is wasted on useless details</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946596633.0" user="A_Trip_into_oblivion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In your example of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, it doesn't matter if I have an opinion on the conflict. I am not tied to it in any professional capacity, so it isn't very useful for me to have an incredibly informed opinion based on all the history you mentioned on that topic. I understand this sounds dense, but simply having an opinion on a topic doesn't require one to be fully educated on the details; otherwise we'd all be in school forever. I do my research on basic history of the topic and read articles/viewpoints about current events before projecting my opinion, and that is sufficient for my role.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;The general public knowing the history of Israel would be similar to everyone knowing the architecture of turbopump engines. Excessive and unnecessary.

But see I'm not saying you need to know the architeture of the turbopump engine. I'm saying you need to know the basics that go into that from high school so that you have the option of doing those things later. For the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, the things I listed are the genesis of the conflict. The very, very basics. Not knowing about them is akin to trying to understand the Civil War without slavery.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;I appreciate the depth of your reply, but you've conveniently misstated my argument to paint it as a pro-STEM, anti-liberal arts argument, which it is not.

I'm not framing it that way. I'm framing it as high school teaches very basic skills that you can then use later to do pretty much anything. Rather than getting much depth of any field you get enough breadth to do just about anything. That's my point. I'm talking about learning the basic facts that will allow you to do just anything. With history and literature that's a lot more just facts and reading that the application stuff you get to do in math and science.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31947033348.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>That last sentence is my point. That's what literature and history should be, but the way they are taught does not further said skills, but rather shoves facts down students throats</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
