<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="73" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31949530432.0" user="gutprof" delta="False">
    <text>I'm the chair of humanities at a professions-oriented university, and I hear this kind of argument almost daily, both from students and from fellow faculty who teach courses in professional majors. Especially with the cost of college these days, students understandably want to know if there is "value" in the general education courses they are "forced" to take. 

A common response to this argument is to argue that these courses teach "critical thinking skills" (just "thinking skills seems adequate to me to capture the idea), or reading/writing skills. I've just come home from a dinner with a group of faculty in the sciences and I can verify that they are aghast at their student's inability to comprehend basic English and respond in meaningful prose, even about things that are directly relevant to their majors. But the idea that humanities courses should be taken because they teach these basic thinking/reading/writing skills is easily dismissed by the simple observation that all serious courses that require students to think/read/and write can also hone these skills -- there is no real need to have students read philosophy, literature, art history, or anything else if our notion of value is simply about skills and career goals. So I think this response to the question is not very convincing to anyone who is already objecting to humanities courses.

One argument is that in a representative democracy or republic that allows voting, we want our citizens to have a certain amount of "liberal education" -- the Enlightenment idea that well-educated people will make more reasonable choices and be more empathetic to the perspectives of others. To be honest, I'm not convinced that studies show that exposure to literature and other perspectives has the desired effect of expanding horizons. It does for some people, of course, but statistically speaking it may be cheaper and more effective to encourage to travel and engage in cross-cultural experiences than to have them read literature, if perspective-taking is the skill that's desired. But I think there are soft skills that humanities courses do cultivate -- the arts of discussion, listening, and argument, that probably do help people in their future lives and careers.

But notice that all of these arguments, like the argument of the OP, is that the only kind of value for these courses is extrinsic value: these courses are conceived only as tools to give people practical skills. But if those skills can be had in a different way, it isn't a strong argument for the courses themselves.

I think there is only one really adequate answer to the OP's question, and that starts with the recognition that there are other kinds of values than extrinsic tool-like values. Perhaps these great works of art and literature, and the stories of history, and the parade of great philosophers and ideas through history have value in themselves. They don't need to be justified in terms of late-capitalist assumptions that the only good education is what can be used on the marketplace to earn money or power. We teach these things simply because they have intrinsic worth. The value of a forest or mountain isn't captured by how useful it is for wood or ore. They have aesthetic value for human beings who have the patience to experience them, and they have intrinsic value in and of themselves. When all human beings are dead and gone, Michelangelo's David will still have value for having existed, and Tolstoy's Anna Karenina will be amazing long after there is no one left who can read or understand it. 

Not everyone will be convinced by this argument, but plenty of us experience it to be true, and that when we read, think, and ponder these things it gives richness and meaning to our lives quite apart from (often instead of) useful and marketable skills.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949558923.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>But that's not the point I made. I clearly say I'm not discussing the career oriented or practical skills from these classes. I am arguing that they fail to teach literature or history in a meaningful context. Most of the curriculum focuses on ineffective teaching methods</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949888379.0" user="gutprof" delta="False">
    <text>Ok sorry I missed your point. But in that case I agree with those who are saying it’s not really much of an argument. It may be that many classes are taught in ineffective ways. 

If your main point is that classes should less often be surveys and more often be detailed studies of primary texts, I tend to think the same thing. 

My English colleagues emphasize literature, but the secondary education standards actually equally emphasize nonfiction texts, as you suggest.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
