<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="53" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946607267.0" user="MonsenorTickles" delta="False">
    <text>The purpose of teaching literature is three fold

* Teaching culture
* Teaching communication of ideas
* teaching critical thinking.

From your post you are, evidently, aware of these three, but I don't think you understand why/how literature serves this goal, and, more importantly, ignore the elephant in the room that is many teachers are poorly suited to teaching these three things.

Literature classes, by a high school curriculum, are in a no win scenario. It is teaching an abstract along a concrete rubric. The most unfortunate consequence to this is, is that it's entirely possible to check the boxes of a literature class while not actually learning what is suppose to be taught. As I said earlier, a part of this falls into just how hard this is to teach, but I'd be remiss in saying that incentivized laziness capitalized by students does place some blame on students, ie: if a craftsman only learned how to use a hammer in shop class, despite having a full tool box, some failure falls to them for not actually using the tools laid out for them. Or, to phrase it another way, you can lead a horse to water but you can't make it drink. You can blame the curriculum for not focusing on context, but given the abstract nature of what's, coupled with the end goal of teaching students to (if you can excuse the mixed metaphor) feed themselves, spoon feeding too much by way of focus nullifies the point entirely. 

To the first point is teaching culture. In the western cannon there are some stories that you are expected to have some familiarity with when engaging as a functional adult. In some areas, this is becoming obsolete. Thanks to the internet, it is entirely possible to understand the main points of culture through memetics. Just so, and I realize there is something circular in this, if everybody has read Shakespeare in high school, a lack of exposure to Shakespeare means you lack something everybody else around you has, the objective value of this something is moot to the fact of collective awareness. In the interest of logical consistency, while I think it would face initial push back, I foresee a future where film and animation will be taught along side literature because of their evident impact on culture.

Obviously, this what is culturally important is not a constant, as things fall in and out of curriculum. Many high schools (in America) today favor 20th century writers from the US and work more to translate relevant points from a generation and a half prior to the contemporary. In the 1930s it wasn't uncommon to read books set in the American Civil War, or reconstruction in schools, but these stories would be read by the grand children of civil war veterans. It wasn't teaching history (which is taught by a completely different paradigm) so much as elucidating the foundation for your community in its present state. You don't read Cats Cradle because the tribunal of elders decided it was the book to read, you read it because the atmosphere of distrust and apocalyptic conditions as consequence to that distrust was insanely relevant to the Cold War, and that zeitgeist didn't just go away with the Soviet Union; by reading the novel you are more fit to understand the mentality of politicians and peers that grew up in the Cold War. 

To the second point, and arguably the superficial purpose of literature classes (as it's near the only thing that can be properly graded), literature helps teach you communicate ideas by exploring different ways ideas can be communicated. Up through literature classes, students (should) be familiar with the rules that govern language and know how to structure a sentence, but just because you can do that doesn't mean you are good at communicating. A good literature class will explore audiences, and will often ask you to identify who a work was written for. The ability to contextualize what other people have done makes you better at contextualizing how you will communicate your ideas, and doing all of this through fictional text allows a litany of environments to explore different audiences and modes of presentation. If you find the writing style of Dickens obfuscating to how you retain a message, good, you have learned, subjectively, something to be avoided for communicating ideas and concepts as you understand them. If you find allegories and metaphors effective, good, you've learned a way to anchor future ideas you might share. You don't have to like the book to take the lesson, and sometimes we take the lesson best from the books we hate.

To the third point, and to wrap it along because I've said a lot, abstract thinking and critical thinking are not easy to teach, and some people are profoundly disadvantaged at learning them, but literature is one of the best ways to teach it to a full class for wont of one on one intensive course. As I'm sure you've sussed (specifically because of skills honed in literature classes), fictional prose helps teach abstract thinking because it only relays concepts from the abstract. There has never been a Jay Gatsby, but the ability to understand and empathize with this fictional character is something of value, and for many students, fictional books would never be read without a class that mandates it. Even if you hate the novel being read in class, the exposure to the novel has still forced you to apply comprehension skills (learned at earlier levels) to something alien. If you can't see the value in that, than I question your understanding of the scientific process you vaunt a bias with. 

Critical thinking, is, of course, a little harder to teach than with exposure alone. As I said earlier, this aspect is marred by the fact that some teachers themselves struggle with this, and in a lot of English classes it is the blind leading the blind, but this is not a fault of how it is taught so much as a fault of institutional management. Possibly the best way critical thinking is (attempted to be) taught in literature courses falls back to the dreaded "blue curtains." By now, I'm sure you've seen the classic, "what you're English teacher thought" vs "what the author intended" punctuated by a sardonic "The curtains are fucking blue." With this in mind, I will argue, any lit teacher worth their salt knows the curtains are fucking blue, but they're still asking you to think deeper (dare we say critically) about them to hone a critical thinking skill. It's not enough to just read the book, the idea is to get students to think about what they read. Yes, in some cases, its obvious over thinking, but by using shallow examples like color and emotion, you can teach the basics of critical thinking for students, many of whom never being taught critical thinking skills before the class, that can be graded across a curriculum that rewards an application of critical thinking, e.g.: essays graded for their ability to make an argument rather than the argument they're actually making.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
