<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="47" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946199738.0" user="TechnicallyMagic" delta="False">
    <text>K-12 school is about exposing the appropriate age group to as many things as possible, and to learning in general. History and literature are not necessarily about making sure everyone knows when, and by whom, things were done, as though that info will be directly part of adult life.

A high school classroom has a huge variety of students, sorted in by proximity and age. Their maturity level, areas of interest, IQ, ability to focus, and a thousand other factors are interacting non stop every day. Everyone will go out into the world in different directions and at different levels in every way. High school curriculum is designed to stick to as many interested parties as possible, at that level you're herding cats. The idea is to start the ball rolling as early as possible.

How do you propose to measure "meaningful educational benefits"?

History, by definition, exists for every area of interest there is. Appreciating the power of knowing what has come before, in general, gives people the opportunity to look into history they care about, and leverage it to their advantage, sometimes to everyone's advantage. For you, the history of STEM is its foundation and you rely on aspects of its history daily.

Literature is an art form. Art is as important to society as science, often the best of both is the product of both. Directly, or indirectly. Learning to appreciate the power of reading and writing is important, as it is a part of daily adult life. From communicating professionally, to avoiding scams and tricky language.

High School students look like adults but they are woefully ignorant children, and there needs to be some kind of measurement and testing, so the rote facts method is used heavily. There is more to it than reading and remembering things, in doing so, we expose as many interested parties to concepts they will explore when they're older.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
