<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944081723.0" user="jbt2003" delta="False">
    <text>Well, part of the original point of the humanities was to train students in “their” culture and to make them stewards for that culture’s preservation. Those courses exist so that a people understands its story and becomes an active participant in continuing that story. 

On an individual level, you’re probably right that it’s not that valuable to learn why Napoléon was important or what led to him fighting Waterloo. But on a societal level i think it certainly is important that people don’t forget their history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944116211.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you, but that's not the argument of my post.

I'm not arguing against the value of humanities, but rather the means by which they are taught. Learning about the Holocaust and it's causes and effects, then spending time analyzing that history (i.e. "what caused this movement on a psychological level'", "how could a disaster like this be prevented") would be much more valuable than learning the names of multiple camps and of the details of which battles turned the tide of the war.

We focus on meaningless details instead of on critical analysis</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944332066.0" user="cameronlcowan" delta="False">
    <text>High school isn’t the place for that. Let’s consider, at 14/15, these kids were just getting basic academic skills going. At 16, they have enough mastery to begin to apply those skills to some useful end in science and so on. By 17/18, you’re just reaching the stage where students have had enough exposure and enough skills mastery to maybe begin analysis. You can’t expect a 15/16 year old kid to have a pithy opinion on the holocaust or be prepared to have a discussion on moral relativism, the poisonous pedagogy culture of Germany or the influence of Hegel and Kant. That’s college level at best. A 16 year old is just getting exposure to this stuff. They can’t write a competent essay yet. They are just learning real history not the sanitized kid version. You have to get kids familiar with the story through those “meaningless details” and then dive deeper into those events in a way that examines them critically. 

Literature is much the same problem. I can’t talk about archetypes without starting with some older works to establish the concept and then use that as an way to build into a modern concept. Saying that The Golden Girls represent 3-4 aspects of femininity without establishing that first gets us nowhere. 

I’ve had this argument with so many stem people who were bored to death in humanities classes. You can’t do calculus without a solid command of algebra.  You don’t just wake up and start doing differential equations. The same goes for the humanities.  You have to learn the very basics before you can put those skills to use!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31947598635.0" user="icestreak" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're greatly underestimating high school kids. By high school, they are more than equipped to write a good essay - I mean, the AP tests are literally kids hand-writing a well structured essay in about an hour. In fact, some of the prompts in /u/dabears_24's comment I remember from my tests back in high school. They may not be able to relate their thoughts on the morality of the holocaust based on classic philosophers, but they can at least write about their own opinions in a persuasive argument while providing historical examples.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948017039.0" user="cameronlcowan" delta="False">
    <text>But that’s AP kids, a minority of the General high school population. I do agree they might be able to have an opinion on the subject but is that critical analysis? And what do we do with the 16 year old asshole who decides the holocaust was a swell idea?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948318339.0" user="icestreak" delta="False">
    <text>\~30% high schools kids took at least one AP course according to a quick google source. True it's a minority but that doesn't mean the other high school kids didn't have the same capability, it's possible they never got an opportunity or were just too lazy. 

High school is where kids start getting experience with critical analysis - is not a critical analysis basically an essay delineating reasons why their thesis is correct as well as factual evidence on those points? That's basically what I said. Tbh, not a teacher so don't know how they deal with those trolls, but hey, as long as they provide a factual basis for their reasoning that'd basically fulfill the point of the assignment even if they have logical fallacies.

Ultimately, just take a look at some high school debate competitions. I think they show that high schoolers are more than equipped to do critical analysis, and saying otherwise is just looking down on kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948411982.0" user="cameronlcowan" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve recently finished a book and one of my essays was about education. Many teachers believe that within education we need to focus on skills mastery. I don’t think this model of critical analysis fits that. I’d rather have kids with competent skills and an overview of history and literature rather than making everyone go through what is essentially a Roman Rhetor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949288539.0" user="Adamsoski" delta="False">
    <text>You are really underestimating children. At the age of 15/16 British kids are writing patt-analytical part-narrative essays in their GCSEs. Here's a question from a 2018 paper:

&amp;gt;Which of the following was the more important reason why white Americans 
travelled across the Great Plains in the 1840s and 1850s: 

&amp;gt;• religion 

&amp;gt;• economic opportunity? 

&amp;gt;Explain your answer with reference to both reasons.

When they are 17 or 18 they are doing their A Levels and writing in depth analytical essays. Here is an example, again from 2018:

&amp;gt;To what extent was there a ‘post-war consensus’ in Britain in the years 1945 to 1964?

I know that US schooling is generally less rigorous (and advanced), but I really think that analytical skills are things that every child is practicing to some extent, and definitely skills that every child is capable of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949563902.0" user="cameronlcowan" delta="False">
    <text>Having graded freshmen college essays where even basic English is a struggle sometimes, I think it’s just asking a lot of most high school students. I imagine that these tests are reserved for those on the university path. Those questions don’t require much analysis you can merely parrot the book. Same thing with a question like: 

“What were the principle policies of Reconstruction?”

If we want to analyze Reconstruction critically (like voting rights, land redistribution) I think that’s a very different way of teaching and could be quite difficult to get across with most students having just learned the history. 


Most US students aren’t on a university path. I seriously doubt most students would be able to confidently express an opinion. I just think that’s college level stuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949605387.0" user="Adamsoski" delta="False">
    <text>These tests are for everyone and are mandatory nation-wide (though not everyone would do the same subjects, the level of teaching would be the same). Analysis is required, and is a central part of the teaching - the example you give is a completely different kind of question which mistly requires reciting facts. College freshman are no good at writing proper essays probably because they've never done it before, not because they lack the base ability due to their age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949800568.0" user="cameronlcowan" delta="False">
    <text>To that point, I think in order to a accomplish a more critical analysis of history and lit, we’d have to start teaching that at a younger age. So what we might normally think of as freshmen/sophomore English and history would need to be pushed back to middle school. That way, students would arrive at high school with exposure to the subject for a deeper dive. At present, the way the school system works just doesn’t equip students for the kind of thinking or writing you propose.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949845060.0" user="Adamsoski" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, the American school system maybe. There is no such thing as 'the' school system - honestly there's no such thing as 'the American school system' either due to how decentralised education is in the US.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949904658.0" user="cameronlcowan" delta="False">
    <text>True, but most American schools follow a basic formula because they all buy the same books and there are now federal testing standards. Most students in the US don’t get exposed to this stuff until highschool. It’s hard to get students to that level given how things are structured now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31944625385.0" user="jbt2003" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever heard of Bloom's Taxonomy? It's a major concept in ed schools. Basically, the idea is that there are different types of knowledge, and types of thinking, that can be ordered from "basic recall" to "analysis." Unfortunately, lots of teachers tend to spend more time focusing on basic recall than on analysis, because it's easier to assess. Asking a question like "When did Hitler invade Poland?" is super easy to grade, because there's a right and a wrong answer. Asking "What lessons do modern politicians take from Hitler's invasion of Poland, and do you feel that those lessons were correctly learned?" is a much better question, but it's harder to grade. 

That being said, a lot of images of Bloom's taxonomy place basic recall as the foundation of a pyramid, because without any knowledge of a topic it's basically impossible to engage in critical thinking around it. If you don't know the chronology of the events of World War II, you're really likely to draw wrong conclusions about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946328983.0" user="VibraphoneFuckup" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Asking "What lessons do modern politicians take from Hitler's invasion of Poland, and do you feel that those lessons were correctly learned?" is a much better question, but it's harder to grade.

This thread is giving me a newfound appreciation for my (public high school) education. Looking back, everything was taught with an emphasis on synthesizing information to prove an argument. We were never tested solely on things like “list the intolerable acts enacted by the British.” Instead, our questions were along the lines of “How did legislation put in place by the British lead to revolutionary dissent?”

And my favorite, “Prove that the civil war was not about slavery.” Four years later, and I still remember that as being one of the most stimulating essay questions I have ever had to respond to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946746752.0" user="Djaja" delta="False">
    <text>Same! My history courses were thorough and heavily emphasized critical thinking. The more rote memory fact stuff was more in my earliest years</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945399330.0" user="PauLtus" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're original title implies something you're not saying. I honestly went from completely disagreeing with your title to completely agreeing with your comment.

&amp;gt;We focus on meaningless details instead of on critical analysis

Seems to be specifically why story criticism (which I'm really into) is really going down the drainpipe nowadays but to me it also seems a lot of ethical discussion seems to suffer similarly. There's an idiotic "facts don't care about your feelings"-mentality where moral values seem to be dismissed as meaningless sentimentalities.

I do also agree with u/comeronlcowan a bit though as I'm not sure whether teenages are really up to it. But I do prefer to give them a chance. It might be interesting to start giving a class hypothetical moral problems and let them write about it early on. Like before you start confronting them with big historical events. I actually think literature are better for that than history because stories can regularly condense certain moral values.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31945461687.0" user="wickerocker" delta="False">
    <text>When I was in high school, reading “Night” by Elie Wiesel was a requirement for every student. We learned the dates and details of the Nazis in history class, then learned about the effects of the Nazi regime on in literature class. Perhaps your experience was different, but this was in the U.S. public school system in Missouri in the early 2000s. 

I think that how I learned about the Nazis was actually very valuable, especially given the current political climate in the U.S.  You have to learn the boring details of a time period first in order to understand any literature that was written during or about that time. We had to know the different names and locations and when they were important so that when we read, in another book, about Auschwitz, we immediately recognized the name of that concentration camp because we had already read about it in history class. Without that name, and the dates attached to it, there would be no context for learning about the concentration camps. 

So there you have a combination of boring history combined with required reading, but at the age of 30 I have never forgotten about that book and have used it many times to discuss current issues with others using critical thinking. When I discuss the Nazis with someone else, the fact that they know when it happened, where it happened, and who was involved makes that conversation possible. How could we discuss Nazis if someone did not know who Hitler was? How could you indicate its relevance if the person you spoke with thought that the Nazis were defeated 2,000 years ago rather than less than a century ago? What if that person thought that the Nazis were Japanese? Those boring names and dates and places are *necessary* for any critical thought. The literature of those times gets life breathed into it when you know the context. “Night” has a totally different relevance when you realize that there are people still alive today that went through concentration camps, perhaps even your classmate’s grandparent. 

I, too, thought that what I was learning in high school was useless, but as I age I realize that all of that information is the foundation for critical thinking. I have watched modern remakes of “Romeo and Juliet” with people my age who shunned the required readings of Shakespeare, and it was impossible to discuss how the movie varied from the original story because they *hadn’t even read the original story!* Have you ever seen the movie “O Brother Where Art Thou?” Well, that is a variation of Homer’s Odyssey, another required reading for me. Knowing US history also makes that a better movie, because you need to understand who the KKK were and what they did, since the movie does not explain it for you. 

I could go on and on, but instead I will stop! I hope I gave enough examples to make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31948384607.0" user="sweetgreentea12" delta="False">
    <text>This was my experience in the UK up until 16. At college (16-18,) History switches to being more about source evaluation and general analysis with some marks available for date memorisation. At University level you absolutely have to demonstrate that you know the timeline in your analysis, but you'd probably be marked down for clunky writing if you put dates in willy nilly.  


I can only speak to my experience in the UK, but I would argue that is a general education problem, rather than something specific to History, (or English.)  
I can remember Maths and Science exams from high school, (up to age 16 here,) where we would have to memorise formula vs. post 16 education where we were given a formula book and we just had to know how to use the formula.   


Is it the same in the US?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
