<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944736174.0" user="uncreated_conscience" delta="False">
    <text>Think of STEM's domain as how-to-do, and the domain of History, Literature, and other Humanitites as what-to-do. Figuring out how to do things is a lot easier than figuring out what to do.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Additionally, how-to-do subjects are amenable to formalization (which simplifies the design of curricula), whereas what-to-do subjects necessarily involve creativity, openness, and argument. Note also that the frontiers of research in math, comp sci, biology, etc approach the what-to-do domain because the how-to-do has not yet been figured out.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If you are arguing that these humanities courses are not well done, your argument is not interesting. A cursory read of a US History textbook is enough to know they are shit. They are adulterated, jingoist, missing crucial context and perspective, and generally overconcerned with politics and war and less concerned with objectively larger problems of class, income inequality, sex, race, and more recently our climate emergency.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Remember that major education systems are still in their infancy (historically speaking), so History and Literature curricula will vastly improve. History classes, if done well, should force students' engagement with cultures other than their own, trace the trajectory of social and scientific progress, examine how good people can be manipulated into making horrible decisions, and explore how we can avoid the resurgence of fascism, racism, sexism, and other toxic political and social phenomena.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Speaking of Joyce's Potrait novel: that book's major themes are important to introduce to young minds, especially those who grew up in religious households. The book challenges formal assumptions about the novel (and expression in general), which mirrors the artist's revolt against the confines and moral bankruptcy of the beliefs of his religion and its executors. The book charges him with creating his own meaning, both for himself and society. This is one example, but good literature like Portrait improves empathy, gives readers privileged access to singular minds, and promotes discussion of difficult social, political, and philosophical subjects.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

At a larger level, these classes should teach students how to communicate, and--judging by the writing I see (both professionally and on social media)--there is plenty to improve.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I could go on (and apologies for the sloppy writing here, but this is the internet and I have other shit to do). But let's return to your question: how would you determine whether a History or Literature class has value? How would you select and design the criteria? What is the value of inhabiting the mind of another? What do you live for and why? What is your role in history? Are these questions and others like them not valuable to pursue together, and to press upon developing minds? And should we not understand these questions through history and through literature's articulate and unfettered expression of human experience?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Persuading you that these courses as currently taught--that's not going to happen. But that's not the point. Changing your mind in this instance should be about changing the questions you ask.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
