<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="55" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946863801.0" user="CREEEEEEEEED" delta="False">
    <text>Having taken History and English literature at A-Level, and now doing a mixture of classics and philosophy at university, I can confidently say you should really re-evaluate your position. I'll start with why they shouldn't change, at least from teaching the basic facts, then onto what meaningful education it does provide.

Try getting a university student to evaluate Hamlet without ever reading Hamlet. Try getting them to provide an in depth analysis, or even a basic analysis, of why the failure of Reconstruction led to a second oppression of African Americans, which led to the civil rights movement, which led to today, if they don't know things like: what amendments were passed in the wake of the civil war? Which presidents were in power, and what laws did they promote to help or hinder Reconstruction? Examples of the laws that negatively affected blacks and when were they being reintroduced, and what was occurring in the south at the time to enable those laws to be passed?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Try getting a 14-16 year old who's brain isn't fully developed to write any analysis of value even with that knowledge. Good fucking luck. Try getting anyone to analyse anything without the basic knowledge. Good fucking luck. Like one of the other commenters said, you cannot do complex calculus without a knowledge of basic algebra. You cannot analyse history or literature without knowing the facts upon which you make the analysis.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Also, asking teenagers to do proper analysis is pointless, 99% of them will not produce anything of value.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

That's my argument as to why they shouldn't change. As to why it provides value:

1. Everyone should know their own country's history, or they will not understand themselves or their surroundings. The same goes for important world events over the last 300 years, they are all still relevant to how the world is right now, and everyone has a right to be educated to at least a minor familiarity with these important events. This doesn't necessarily mean rote learning dates and names (although those are important), but some learning of historical fact is important for being informed. If you've never even heard of the battle of Gettysburg, how can you have any understanding of its impact on your country? Simple knowledge has value.
2. Everyone should know about their own country's literary cannon, if only because it informs today's popular culture, but rather more importantly because just reading a valuable text teaches you something, before the teacher has even gotten involved. Reading Hamlet teaches you something about death, family and morality. Reading The Great Gatsby teaches you something about the value of friends and family vs the value of money, and about how love can consume a person. Additionally, if the book selection is good, it's just interesting on its own merit.
3. The analysis that you start to do at 17-18 (or at least I did in the English system, I know you guys don't really have A-Level equivalents) is of tremendous value to shaping you as a person and starting your path to real analysis at university. And that analysis cannot, as I said, be done without knowledge learned over the previous years, and indeed during the last two years of school. The same of course goes for STEM subjects.

Edit: Quote form OP replying to another comment, " However, I think learning about the Battle of Stalingrad is extremely excessive." This is blatantly ridiculous, OP just doesn't enjoy history and has extended that to 'having a basic knowledge of history holds no value'. The entire thread is pointless when dealing with this.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
