<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="72" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31949516576.0" user="CosmoVibe" delta="False">
    <text>I'll explain one very direct application from personal experience.

In the GRE test (and maybe the SAT tests) one of the writing assignments is to write a response argument of a prompt, a technical analysis explaining why a particular proposal is flawed. Example:  [https://www.ets.org/gre/revised\_general/prepare/analytical\_writing/argument/sample\_responses](https://www.ets.org/gre/revised_general/prepare/analytical_writing/argument/sample_responses) 

Not long after practicing and taking the test, I had to go to a local vote, where the education board is deciding whether or not to approve increasing taxes to expand kindergarten from a half day to a full day. The description and overview of the bill is very similar in style to these prompts; they give you a high-level summary but leave out some of the details. But here's the kicker: if you read the fine print, they say that should the bill fail to be passed, they will cut funding to the kindergarten programs heavily. There is no option to neither increase nor decrease funding, it was either heavily increase or heavily decrease. While I was at the voting booth, I pointed this out but surprisingly no one else seemed to have read it in detail or caught this.

Having a fundamental understanding of history, politics, reading and writing skills, will allow people to be prepared to notice these issues and hold their leaders accountable. Without practicing reading and analyzing these historical events in detail, students will have little hope of being able to put these issues into context, let alone catch these tricks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949624526.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>But what you're saying should happen is not. Why did half of the country allow a nationalist agenda to put Trump in office when historical trends tell us that we are neglecting minorities? Why do we have Congressmen from the South involving religious beliefs in lawmaking when the founding fathers insisted on a separation of church and state?

If the current education works, then the others around you should have had the same skills as you to read the fine text. That's why I'm arguing that they are ineffective</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31950363139.0" user="CosmoVibe" delta="False">
    <text>This isn't necessarily correlated. Imagine we got rid of history and English studies. Perhaps I never would have even gotten to the point I'm at now, and maybe Trump's approval rating would be even higher. You could look at the situation and come up with the conclusion that it is even more important that we improve our history and English curriculum. 'Bad curriculum is bad,' not 'general history and literature curriculum is bad.'</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
