<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31944259835.0" user="machopikachu69" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re generally right that these courses could do far better in terms of stimulating critical thinking. Much of the liberal arts curriculum is actually pretty “edgy” in terms of contemporary sociopolitical standards (in both good ways like subverting the authority of corrupt institutions/ideologies and bad ways like how they can promote racist and sexist values), so there’s some degree of pressure on teachers to present/discuss it in a relatively superficial way. Also it’s hard to change the curriculum to be more modern, because while everyone can agree Shakespeare is “classic,” there are relatively few authors in the past 50 years who wrote serious literature whose works wouldn’t be controversial in the eyes of many parents. On top of that, I think many liberal arts teachers/professors are somewhat insecure about their knowledge base not being appreciated, so I think sometimes they have a tendency to jump straight to the most difficult texts/concepts to try to impress their audience. (This last point is a generalization.)

That said, I think your idea of what’s taught in these courses might be somewhat outdated. Eg you mention learning the dates of civil war battles—most specific dates and battles are not required learning for either the AP or SAT history exams. 

On the other hand, you also mention the politics of the early 1800s—this is actually very relevant to today’s political world, insofar as that was a time when the (still-relevant) issue of states rights vs federal government power was being seriously discussed. This is a good example of how history and literature can have contemporary value: they allow us to see the context around why our world is the way it is today. Thus they give us a knowledge base to challenge the way things are done based on the different context now (eg should we still have the bicameral legislature, given the much greater differences in population between states?). And although the old-style language can be annoying to deal with, looking back at historical documents and works of literature can often give us a picture of a more “primordial form” so to speak, of contemporary arguments/modes of life. This is useful because it helps clarify what’s probably essential vs what’s probably an accident of our time.

Finally, I think it’s important to recognize that many liberal arts teachers have their hands tied with regard to how relevant they can make the curriculum. Liberal arts have been under attack for a long time by the religious right, who have consistently pushed to defund liberal arts colleges and restrict the liberal arts curriculum in high school. What you’re saying amounts to “we’re losing this battle, so let’s surrender the field” rather than, “we’re losing this battle, so let’s send in reinforcements.” Maybe it would be better to focus on stem subjects (certainly America is slipping in that regard), but I don’t think it’s true that literature and history can’t be very relevant to critical thinking about contemporary issues. And I think it’s telling that one of the most socially regressive groups in our society is so against these subjects being taught.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
