<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="45" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946124904.0" user="GrandeBlu" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like what you are advocating for is the separation of technical and liberal arts colleges. The model used in Australia may have interest to you. The final year of secondary school is optional and is preparation for going to University. Students that are going to a polytechnic do not have to attend this year. I see value in this system and it is certainly underused in the US.

Coming from a STEM background myself I can understand your perspective and how it seems like these courses are a waste of time. I would caution you on such an attitude, because as I've advanced in my career, such knowledge has demonstrated value.

Specifically teaching the details of historical events provides the nuance that is required to truly understand them. Unfortunately this is often reduced to increasing detail of recall on specific dates. I.e. everyone should know that WW2 was from ~1939 to 1945 and teaching the specifics is important. However, testing for all of those specifics is probably unwarranted. for example, I know that VE was before VJ day however I do not recall the specific dates. Knowing that the war ended in Europe before the Pacific is relevant to the overall geopolitical dynamics.

As I mentioned elsewhere in the thread I think your root cause is the general mediocrity of liberal arts education and the way in which it is tested. A liberal arts education is less about value in work and more about value in society and as a citizen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946382558.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point, but I'm not arguing for the removal of liberal arts topics from high school. I'm saying that they are not taught effectively. Why do I need to know of separate battles in the American Revolution when the topic at hand is the concept of revolution and guerilla warfare?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
