<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="52" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946524153.0" user="ResidentIndependent" delta="False">
    <text>I’m going to keep this very, very brief. 

I agreed with you in high school, and strongly disagree now, three years out. At 16, you don’t have the base understanding of history, English, and literature to begin to do really in-depth critical analysis. Before you can really analyze something or write about it well, you need to have a concrete foundation of the events, the timelines, the players, etc. The minute details may not seem to matter to you know, but they will in the future. It’s training your brain to recall details quickly so in the future, when you’re asked a question about x historical event, you don’t need to google all the details— you can speak from a place of concrete knowledge. 

We are far too eager to debate and to form opinions today without having all the facts. Pay close attention in history, and you’ll have them, and it’ll make you a smarter, better, and more articulate writer, speaker, and thinker.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946544436.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a few years removed from high school, and I do see your point. However, you are arguing for historical details vs not knowing any history. Obviously the details are more valuable if compared to learning nothing else during that time.

But my view is that we would be better off if taught broader history and spending more time debating or discussing topics. Time spent on specific acts or battles could be realloted to debate about significant topics, which I argue would form better-thinking members of society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946620472.0" user="A_Trip_into_oblivion" delta="False">
    <text>You cannot debate what you do not know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946932049.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you're comparing knowing to not knowing, which is not the logical alternative. I am not arguing to remove history and not know any of it.

I am saying learning 70% of the history with a new 30% focus on how it compares to today's society would probably leave us better off than just devoting all that time to historical facts</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
