<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="26" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945182023.0" user="captain_manatee" delta="False">
    <text>Most of these answers are discussing the benefits of history and literature, so I’m going to try another tack. I think the issues you’ve outlined are entirely with teaching style, and not limited to those two subjects. STEM classes taught in that way are just as bad.

Many if not most high-school biology classes are also about rote memorization. Is it exceedingly helpful for me to know that organisms fit into a classification system that goes Domain Kingdom Phylum Class Order Family Genus Species? Or that mitochondria are the powerhouse of the cell? Or chemistry, when am I going to use knowledge of noble gasses or actual use a chemical equation? Or physics, why  do I need to know the gravitational constant, when would a layperson calculate the time a ball will spend in flight when thrown? Even math beyond basic algebra could be argued to not be particularly useful. How many people need to calculate the volume of a cone? Or analytically determine the rate at which a pool fills with water?

You mentioned enjoying STEM fields, so is it possible that you either had better teachers in those fields that did engage with critical thinking and problem solving, or that despite the poor teaching methodology the subjects themselves awakened an interest you took it upon yourself to pursue more closely? Isn’t it possible for that to also be true for History and Literature?

I personally was privileged enough to go to a very good high-school, and we covered the roots of different schools of political thought and philosophies as well as the origins of current countries and conflicts.  The memorization of dates of battles and plagues and economic catastrophes can help form a timeline and historical context for the truly important lessons in a similar way to how memorizing constants and formulae are most valuable when you also learn how to apply them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
