<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="34" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945659997.0" user="merpincorporated" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you on history, where it is too detailed and it doesn't analyze but just comes down to memorization. With literature however, I find it very important and useful. Even more useful than mathematics and science. I think it is the one class that connects with students, and helps with actual life problems. That is, if the student actually reads the material and shows up to class. Each new book has a different life lesson or issue, that can relate to their current problems or future problems. I think literature changes and helps students for the better. They could probably read things slower especially in AP classes, but it is a definite value.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946201818.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I am not arguing against the value of literature. Of course analyzing meaningful stories can have a valuable impact on students.

However, let's consider the way it is taught. Are A Scarlet Letter, Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man, The Great Gatsby, Grapes of Wrath really the best readings for a personal connection to students? And is focusing our time on the symbolism and metaphors hidden in the rambling stream-of-consciousness in James Joyce's novels really a meaningful use of our time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949627273.0" user="merpincorporated" delta="False">
    <text>Yes definitely. Those all have great themes. We also read Farhenheit 451, 1984, The Crucible, Brave New World, Walden, Lord of the Flies, To Kill a Mockingbird and many others as well. These all have great themes that truly help people if they read it. Especially teenagers who are going through a lot. I just turned 21, so I wasn't in high school too long ago. English was the one class that helped me more than anything at that time. I didn't have a great home life or a lot of friends, and a lot of high school students don't. Literature helps students connect with other people and other minds, it helps people understand what they are feeling and things that are happening around them. 

I think the one thing that could be changed in literature courses, is not focusing enough on emotional reactions and human nature. It depends on the teacher, there are some teachers who just want to get through the book and only focus on the curriculum. The teachers that focus on learning about the themes and how they compare to daily life, and our emotional response to these things is what makes literature such an important aspect of schools. It is the one place that really teaches you about life and understanding the world around us.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
