<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="71" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31949479351.0" user="Sherlock_Drones" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who is pursuing a career as a history professor. This post is a bit saddening. I don’t feel like we go into too much meaningless detail in history courses. Everything can be brought around to something. You mention not valuing the policies of the 1800. Yet (whatever side you fall on doesn’t matter) today we still have people saying things like, “slavery was so long ago just forget about it”. That is a 1800’s policy thing that we need to understand. When I was in AP World History, I remember our teacher saying to not memorize specific battles because for the most part they aren’t going to test you on it, like knowing how many people died and whatnot, which stood true. So for the most part they don’t go tooo in detail. But the few they do, it has reason. One battle I can think of that almost everyone knows is Custer’s Last Stand. That’s a pretty important battle to learn about especially since that battle has become a part of a phrase in our language. 

And of course just in general. If we don’t learn from the past we are doomed to repeat history. As I’ve grown older and look around us and learn more about history. It becomes ever so apparent that this will always be the case and there’s nothing you can do about it. But we still need to learn about it so that we can have a better understanding of ourselves. Learning about the roots of democracy and feudalism and slavery and all these topics is what will help us better understand our own government. Look at what’s going on in America. We are having such a big issue of separating church and state. A core belief of our founding fathers. Also we need to learn about nitty gritty things because changes golem constantly. And people need to be aware of this. When Trump first became president and the whole “Muslim ban” debacle was going on a lot of people I know and on YouTube were showing policies from 50/60 years ago which justified his actions. Which is great. Show me how our government is allowed to do something. But they failed to see that an amendment was made like 10 years later which tore that piece of justification down. People already do not know enough about former policies and yet bring it up during debates. 

Point being. Everything you learn in history is precedents on future generations. We need to learn as much as we can to get a better future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949547007.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>That's the thing though. I completely agree that the failure of people today to understand historical lessons is insanely frustrating. But I think the format of these courses is a huge part of the issue.

Learning about specific acts and battles doesn't mean as much when the analysis portion is glossed over</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949569843.0" user="Sherlock_Drones" delta="False">
    <text>Well then that’s just an issue with how our school system works. As of now we teach to pass tests. Not to analyze properly. This isn’t unique to just history and language courses. 

I think it’s easy to point to literature and history courses and say all this because as compared to sciences and maths, it’s more inferential rather than concrete and observation. It’s up to the person themself to analyze. But this isn’t be done if the students don’t care to</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949593072.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I specifically point out literature and history courses because of their abstract nature. Whether or not math topics are valuable, they are taught effectively. We emphasize practice problems until students understand the techniques. The same approach is not applicable to history and literature.

And the current approach to teaching these courses is not providing value</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949633796.0" user="Sherlock_Drones" delta="False">
    <text>Well if you acknowledge that these courses are abstract. And want a change in format. What exactly would that be? Because at least with history, the only way you can do that is just by memorizing dates and every amendment to the constitution and so on. Memorizing just the concrete part. But that strips any nuance. 

So I’m just genuinely curious. What type of a format would work? Because like I’ve said the only way to get people to care for these courses is to engage the students. And right now our education system is primarily based on passing benchmarks and not educating the student. Which is a problem with schools in general not specific courses. I mean why do you think *USUALLY* kids do good in electives. It engages them and much less is benchmarked. 

And before it’s said that these courses should be made into electives. I would disagree because the value of these courses itself is too high to be able to just choose to opt in or out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949692344.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I think specific courses like AP World History and AP Euro History should remain electives.

General history should be taught at a higher level (i.e. separate the Revolutionary War into phases based on larger themes (Britain dominates early, first colonial victories, France joins, etc)) and then spend the newly freed time with discussions or assignments based on topics like "How do our forefathers' visions for our government compare to today's government?" or "What lessons did the anti-Communist yellow fever time period teach about the nature of society?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949721217.0" user="Sherlock_Drones" delta="False">
    <text>I mean it seems like you have it the opposite. From what your saying. If you believe that these questions should be addressed (which it should). Then AP history courses should be enforced. Since a lot of times that’s exactly what they address.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949727539.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying that the general history curriculum should stay at a high level and emphasize analysis through discussions like the ones I mentioned. For anyone who wants to learn the details, AP courses are options</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
