<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="65" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31947796653.0" user="Rifleshoot" delta="False">
    <text>I can agree on literature, but I disagree on history.  High school history places our current situation in historical context.  It would be foolish to send our kids out into the world not understanding where we came from or why those events came to be.  Middle school and elementary school history tends to solely be the teachers telling the kids a list of events that happened with very little attention paid to why they happened.  High school history tends to go into detail about WHY historical events happen.  Why did the civil war happen?  And so, you go into more details about the divide between north and south, the cultural divide, and the growth of industrialization in the 1800s.  You go into the economic factors, the escalating events, all of the things that lead up to the event itself.  Then you talk about the aftermath and how that event caused the chain reaction that led to where we are right now.  If middle/elementary school history is about putting points on a timeline, high school history is about filling in the spaces between those points to fully understand why they happened.  

So as far as why that has value, there are a couple of things it does.  For one, it gives graduating students historical context for our current society, meaning that they will be better equipped to make decisions going forward with a fuller understanding of the mistakes of the past and why they happened.  It helps them recognize patterns from history in our own society and make choices for themselves and their families accordingly.  It helps them make better decisions politically as well.  

The second reason is something even more important to me.  It helps develop a student’s critical thinking ability by exercising their brains when it comes to cause and effect.  It helps them to be able to take a look at historical events, then piece together how those events may have led to other events, which helps them become better at that ability in their own lives.  It makes them better at seeing something happen today, then make a guess at how that event will affect tomorrow.  It helps them become better at extracting conclusions from a set of facts.   It develops their sense of logic and ability to think.  I think you’ll learn, as time goes on, that education actually makes a transition from middle school to high school.  It transitions from trying to teach you what to think to HOW to think.  Teachers try to get you to be able to take a series of facts and make a sound conclusion.  That is the goal, anyways.  Not every teacher is up to that task, unfortunately.  It’s much easier for some teacher to give the students a list of dates and events and make them memorize them than to teach them to think.  It’s easier to test as well.  

I think literature has the same thought behind it, but almost every lit class I ever had didn’t seem to do it well.  The class gets bogged down in talking about symbolism and usually the teacher has their own ideas about the symbols and can’t let go of them and forces them onto the students.  If literature is to teach someone to think, the teacher must let go of their own ideas and let the students explore their own, so long as they write down their logic behind it.  So maybe Literature does have a good purpose, it’s just that most lit teachers are pretty bad at teaching it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
