<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="38" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31945869701.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>History teacher here. Best practices and history frameworks try to get history teachers to teach critical thinking and applicable skills.

The big things history teachers are told to teach are extremely important.

Sourcing : who wrote this? What's their bias? What's this publications bias? Is this source trust worthy?

This is obviously extention important and relevant in the age of fake news. 

Historical perspectives and Moral relativity: what you value isn't necessarily what other people value and people generally adhere to the morality and behaviors of their environment. This is used to question students own values.

Stem is not sufficient on its own. We need to analyze multiple perspectives across cultures and identities when new ideas arise from science. For example eugenics is based in science but was not evaluated based on human or moral values. 

Cause and effect : how did slavery cause more problems? How did the industrial revolution lead to the rise of workers rights and socialism globally? Etc

There are more but I think these illustrate my point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31946229505.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>You're right but you're stating exactly what I believe. I don't think STEM should replace these classes, nor should history be removed from the curriculum. But the standard history classes focus on excessive details and takes away opportunities for critical analysis. I'm sure there are some teachers, perhaps yourself, that do effectively teach this mindset.

But on a broad scale, I don't think these courses are structured for that. Why do I need to be able to list the acts that drove the colonists to secede? Why do I have to know the names of multiple battles?

Isn't that time better spent in analysis of broader topics like you mentioned?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949439507.0" user="draculabakula" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that what you are talking about is to the current standard. It is the past standard.

Feel free to read the common core standards for social studies and English  [here] (http://www.corestandards.org/ELA-Literacy/RH/6-8/)

You will see they have nothing to do with the descriptions you gave and these are the federal standards for what should be focused on in English and Social Studies

I think your experience with social studies and English was likely not great but that doesn't mean that is the standard or the typical experience</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
