<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="75" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31949658132.0" user="Nic_Reigns" delta="False">
    <text>As a high school senior I think I have standing in this argument

It's not the teachers or the curriculum, it's the students. The people who want to learn can do so within the classes that are currently provided, but the ones who don't will not no matter the curriculum. What we have in place for literary and historical education is sufficient, but kids who don't care about history will only look at the surface level narrative of events which is meaningless, but kids who care about the underlying things that require thought can learn it from what is in place now.

The only way you could really force learning the underlying things that actually matter is by changing the testing methods, make more short answers on open questions than multiple choice fact sheets. But this is hard because a lot of it isnt objective, which makes testing and grading harder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31949722284.0" user="dabears_24" delta="False">
    <text>Well I think part of the education system's responsibility is to create the best environment for important skills to develop. If we accept that the onus is on the students to make the most of the education, then the system has failed. 

I agree that the testing standards heavily contiribute to the problem. Topics like math have aligned paths between testing and learning. Practice problems can be used to teach and test. For topics like literature and history, these paths don't align</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
