<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="710810230.0" index="44" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/br74om/cmv_high_school_literature_and_history_courses/">
    <title>CMV: High school literature and history courses fail to provide meaningful educational value</title>
    <original_poster>dabears_24</original_poster>
    <original_post>In their current form, high school courses focused on history and literature fail to provide meaningful educational benefits. 

These classes commonly have a goal of improving critical thinking skills and develop advanced literacy. However, the format of current history courses where students heavily analyze past events, does not emphasize critical thinking, but rather focuses on memorization of history that has little to no significance in the present. Literature classes that focus on deep analysis of *important* texts like Shakespeare's works, complex poetry, or stylistic writing (i.e. stream-of-consciousness in "Portrait of an Artist as a Young Man") do not develop readinc/writing skills applicable to students' lives or modern texts. They also tend to foster dislike for reading when students are forced to extract meaning from texts they do not value or understand.

I believe a courses in debate, critical analysis of nonfiction works (i.e. argumentative opinion pieces), or even literary analysis of more familiar works would all be better alternatives to detailed US history or general literature courses.

Since this is a broad statement with caveats, I'll clarify in a list:

- I am not arguing the classes offer zero value. The concept of being in an educational environment likely has benefits itself, so my view will not be changed by arguments of the form "all education has value".


- I acknowledge the value of basic history lessons in understand society, culture, and history that affects us today. I am arguing that there is little to no value in all students having to learn of details like specific battles of the Civil War, or the politics of the early 1800s. These topics should be pursed electively.


- I am not arguing that these classes lack value only because they do not tie to future careers. I believe these two courses majorly fail to provide value. I agree that math and science courses do not necessarily tie into future work, but I believe they accomplish their goals more effectively.

I admit I may display a STEM-favoring bias due to my field of study and work, so I am willing to accept arguments that show that my view is a function solely of my bias and not of reason.

EDIT: Want to clarify that I still think history should be taught at a general level in school. I don't think it should be as detailed or exhaustive as a part of the core curriculum. In other words, I think the necessary history can be taught in fewer total classes

EDIT 2: Pretty late in the cycle now, but I'll add this regardless since I've engaged with a lot of arguments that misinterpret my post. I am not arguing against the value of History and Literature. I am saying these classes are ineffective in their current forms</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31946074203.0" user="Telkk" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, I say keep it simple and do it the old Ron Swanson way.  One goal for the entire course of the year.  For literature and History, you have to write a short book that's either fiction or non-fiction and that's related to history or literature and enter it into a class competition whereby your work is assessed by your peers and you get a pass/fail grade depending on how many positive votes you get versus negative.  And the only thing the teacher will do is facilitate the process of creation and teach them real-life strategies for developing marketable content that can be created with knowledge in these subjects and other topics unrelated to any subject you'll learn in school.  You can even award them bonus points for publishing their work on Amazon and making at least some kind of a profit.

Okay, this is kind of a joke and would probably fail in a grade school setting, but there could be a lot of value in this structure for a 12th grade AP class or an undergraduate course because instead of teaching them facts, they can focus more on how to create meaning and value out of nothing along with other things like, how to teach and do things on your own, how to work towards solving a problem using multiple resources, and what it really means to succeed or fail in life.

Our grading system is fucked because it conditions young people to believe that getting a C or a B in life is acceptable.  Like, imagine an engineer doing an okay job on a bridge or a neurologist doing meh on removing your tumor?  That's why most kids coming out of high school and college fail because most fail to adapt to the real World and do great work.  It's like they said in the movie, "Whiplash".  The two worst words in the English language are "Good Job".  We've forgotten what it means to bleed on our work and do more than what we thought we were capable of.  Instead, we flock towards structure and jobs where we can get away with doing an okay job.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
