<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="717356186.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bv3fkq/cmv_competition_in_the_online_streaming_market_is/">
    <title>CMV: Competition in the Online Streaming Market is ultimately worse for consumers</title>
    <original_poster>Stark1162</original_poster>
    <original_post>Competition is generally a good thing in most markets. Having many companies in the same market fuels innovation and brings down prices. While this is true for most markets like Smartphones, Automobiles and Air travel, it's not the case for Online Streaming. 

When you subscribe to a streaming service like Netflix, you're offered access to a number of shows and movies, most of which are licensed from content producers. When there are fewer players in the market, a streaming service like Netflix can make licensing deals with a majority  of the original content producers out there, giving the consumers access to a multitude of content. But when number of Online Streaming services increases, the content is distributed among them due to 'exclusive' deals. So if you're interested in watching 10 different TV series that air on 5 different streaming services, you are forced to choose one of these three options:

1. Get subscribed to all 5 services which will cost a lot of money per month

OR

2. Give up on some of your favourite shows to keep your expenses down.

OR

3. Piracy: Which will ultimately harm the original content creators.

Moreover, an increasing number of production studios are getting into the streaming game, like HBO and  Disney with Disney+, making the scenario more fragmented, by offering their original content exclusively on their platforms.

This situation not only makes it more expensive for the consumers but the content producers as well who may be potentially losing viewership money because the consumers are forced to choose between several competitors</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32021865155.0" user="onetwo3four5" delta="False">
    <text>On the other hand, the competition drives prices down, and some people don't mind missing a few shows if it means they aren't paying for a bunch of stuff they aren't watching</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32022053258.0" user="IAmDanimal" delta="False">
    <text>This is the most important component of the argument. With no competition, prices rise until they get to a breaking point where increasing the price any higher would end up causing people to just stop subscribing to any online media at all. So if half of consumers were willing to pay $100/month for Netflix and the other half would only pay up to $25/month, then (assuming there are no other options for streaming content), you can bet your \*\*\* that Netflix would increase the price to $100/month.

On top of that, with the lack of competition you'd also have Netflix stop buying/creating content. They'd just sell subscriptions to their existing catalog of content and that would be it. Without competition, they have no incentive to spend money on new content. And speaking of incentive to spend money, they'd also have no incentive to provide high-bandwidth connections, no incentive to spend money on customer service, no incentive to do anything that would make consumers happy.

It all boils down to cost. With no competition, businesses have no incentive to spend any additional money unless that money translates directly into increased profits. But for online streaming, most consumers would rather have something terrible than nothing at all, so Netflix would just raise prices like crazy and pretty much stop spending money on anything except keeping the servers turned on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32023726832.0" user="Stark1162" delta="False">
    <text>But this is where big corporations win. Bigger companies like Apple and Amazon can drive down costs by subsidizing your subscription using money from their other products. This is exactly how Amazon kills competition in every market they enter. And this is also why Apple Music is really making it difficult for Spotify to make a profit. Once the 'big brands' kill all the competition in this way, what's to say that they won't raise the prices one again because now they have the turf for themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32024795250.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Once the 'big brands' kill all the competition in this way, what's to say that they won't raise the prices one again because now they have the turf for themselves.

This seems to directly refute your OP.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32025772735.0" user="Stark1162" delta="False">
    <text>Iam trying to refute the argument that 'zero competition will drive up costs'. The businesses won't do that because increasing costs to an unimaginably high degree is just an invitation for a bigger brand to swoop in and undercut them. Especially in these emerging service categories like streaming, companies are really cautious of increasing costs this way. I hope Iam making sense.

&amp;gt;Once the 'big brands' kill all the competition in this way, what's to say that they won't raise the prices one again because now they have the turf for themselves.

My argument wasn't meant to be taken at face value. It was supposed to be a rhetoric. I mean to imply that more competition will not always mean low prices because of predatory practices by bigger brands.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32025947578.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Iam trying to refute the argument that 'zero competition will drive up costs'. The businesses won't do that because increasing costs to an unimaginably high degree is just an invitation for a bigger brand to swoop in and undercut them. Especially in these emerging service categories like streaming, companies are really cautious of increasing costs this way. I hope Iam making sense.

I don't understand the distinction you are making. Streaming is a multi billion dollar industry now, so any company that gains a monopoly is a "big brand" almost by definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32026202224.0" user="Stark1162" delta="False">
    <text>I apologise if I wasn't clear enough. 
By 'big brand' I am referring to companies like Amazon and Apple. These companies are clearly bigger than Netflix or Hulu. Their bread and butter is not streaming and that is the difference. These companies use their profits from their main business and are able to enter new markets and offer their service at a cheaper rate, undercutting the competition. Ofcourse these companies can afford to do that because they have the money to do it. That's not the case for a company like Netflix because this is their only business and source of income.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32027843695.0" user="IAmDanimal" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Bigger companies like Apple and Amazon can drive down costs by subsidizing your subscription using money from their other products.

With no competition, why would they drive down costs? If there's no competition, what's their incentive to reduce costs? Increasing costs means they make more money, which is big company's main goal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32029087101.0" user="Stark1162" delta="False">
    <text>They drive down costs when they enter a new market space. With the sole intention of taking out the existing companies in that space or buying them off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32030187792.0" user="IAmDanimal" delta="False">
    <text>Well they would, but if there's no competition in that space (the whole point of your OP), then they don't need to drive down costs. Instead, they drive up costs to increase profits.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
