<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="717356186.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bv3fkq/cmv_competition_in_the_online_streaming_market_is/">
    <title>CMV: Competition in the Online Streaming Market is ultimately worse for consumers</title>
    <original_poster>Stark1162</original_poster>
    <original_post>Competition is generally a good thing in most markets. Having many companies in the same market fuels innovation and brings down prices. While this is true for most markets like Smartphones, Automobiles and Air travel, it's not the case for Online Streaming. 

When you subscribe to a streaming service like Netflix, you're offered access to a number of shows and movies, most of which are licensed from content producers. When there are fewer players in the market, a streaming service like Netflix can make licensing deals with a majority  of the original content producers out there, giving the consumers access to a multitude of content. But when number of Online Streaming services increases, the content is distributed among them due to 'exclusive' deals. So if you're interested in watching 10 different TV series that air on 5 different streaming services, you are forced to choose one of these three options:

1. Get subscribed to all 5 services which will cost a lot of money per month

OR

2. Give up on some of your favourite shows to keep your expenses down.

OR

3. Piracy: Which will ultimately harm the original content creators.

Moreover, an increasing number of production studios are getting into the streaming game, like HBO and  Disney with Disney+, making the scenario more fragmented, by offering their original content exclusively on their platforms.

This situation not only makes it more expensive for the consumers but the content producers as well who may be potentially losing viewership money because the consumers are forced to choose between several competitors</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32021671783.0" user="Armadeo" delta="False">
    <text>What is the proposed solution to this? The only one I can think of is to make it illegal to create exclusives and force content creators to sell their product to everyone. 

e.g. the creator of TV Show X has to set a market rate which they make it available to all streaming companies. 

This way the best 'service' wins on the back of the technology and user experience, not the content. Seems fine in theory but I cannot see this happening in the US. The result is the system we have today.

I think consumers have a pretty good run in the advent of Netflix in the start and will start to hit ceilings where they are no longer happy to pay more for extra services resulting in missing out on content and this is completely fine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32023655029.0" user="Stark1162" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe that if you make exclusive content illegal then the winner will be the one with the best technology. I believe that the winner will be the one who is the cheapest. And when cost is the factor, big companies like Apple and Amazon will definitely win. Because these big companies can easily subsidize the cost of their streaming service using their revenue from other products and this kills competition in a very unhealthy way</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
