<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32058982725.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>The one problem I see here is that you’re not specifying between specific drugs. I would agree that weed and psychedelics are harmless in the safety of your own home. However, most drugs that people take affect their decision making skills, and it’s very easy for somebody who’s drug of choice is an upper like meth or coke to suddenly decide after they take the drug, that they want to *leave* the safety and privacy of their home to go find trouble outside, and that is where the danger is. 

Also, the rate of abuse is not 10% across the board for all drugs. Certain drugs such as meth and heroin are so dangerous and damaging that essentially no amount of recreational use could be considered as “not abuse.” 

Also, there are other drugs that are *SO* addictive that most normal people can’t handle only using them occasionally. Opioids and Cocaine are like that. My dad has severe PTSD and is somewhat bipolar from childhood abuse and years of carnage and death witnessed as a firefighter. From the time I was about 7 until I was 15 he was severely addicted to Opioids, and you cannot tell me that that was just a small recreational habit to cope with his mental health. He was using more Opium than most heroin users. When he got clean, he had physical withdrawals for a month including a miniature cardiac arrest episode and multiple nights in the ER, and the psychological withdrawals were much worse and lasted longer. He’s happy and healthy now, treating his illness without substances (he has a diet and workout regimen that helps him process his emotions) but this isn’t to say that no drugs can be useful in helping these mental health issues. It’s just that *most* of the illegal drugs can’t. If your argument were only for weed and psychedelics, go ahead. But if you think that coke and meth are acceptable ways of dealing with mental health in the comfort of your home you’re not looking at the whole picture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059042909.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>My argument was that we need to fix the mental health before we release them into a world of drugs. I believe mental health issues are rising, why is a completely different discussion, but as a result abuse is rising.

Yes, I’ll edit, I remember heroin had about 20% in abuse rate. I found it astounding that about 80% of heroin users use it recreationally.

Edit: I’ve tried a plethora of drugs, and I can understand how they were more addictive in nature, however I didn’t start using them compulsively as I had no reason to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059048736.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but some drugs can not possibly improve their mental health anyway, and shouldn’t be used recreationally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059153385.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not saying they all improve your mental health, neither is that the goal. The goal is to know where the mind can go. Does drinking improve your mental health? Probably not. Does it expand your understanding of how the mind works within a different frame? Yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059162669.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>Nope, but your follow up about “why is it legal then?” Doesn’t work for two reasons: 

1. I don’t drink and wouldn’t care if it were banned (I would be kinda stoked honestly)

2. Drinking is nowhere near as harmful as drugs like crack, meth and heroin and most people can avoid addiction to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059207721.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>https://static.businessinsider.com/image/523f3399eab8ea2450efd35c-750.jpg

Alcohol is the most harmful drug out there statistically. Most likely however, because of it’s availability. 

Crack, meth, and heroin are very hard drugs. And there should be very strict regulations put in place, though I still believe they should be legal. Offering help instead of an arrest is the key, and monitoring use and dosage so that no harm is done would be a perfect way of going about it.

Imagine something like «drug cards» where there are quotas for each drug. Where drugs like heroin have to be measured and used on site to ensure that overdoses don’t happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059239276.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>What it the x axis on that graph? It doesn’t actually have any form of measurement so that graph is kinda meaningless. However, I would willingly believe that alcohol is the most destructive in general, but if you compare the amount of people hurt by alcohol to the amount who use it, and then compare the amount of people hurt by meth to the amount who use it, you’ll realize that meth is a MUCH more harmful drug. Thinking that alcohol is a worse drug is like thinking that driving a car is more dangerous than playing Russian roulette because more people have died driving than playing Russian roulette. The only reason alcohol looks like the worst is because it’s SO PREVALENT. I wish that weren’t the case. That doesn’t make any case for making other destructive drugs more legal though. 

Also, if you put a cap on how much a person can take, it doesn’t matter if the cap is “absolutely none” or “a little in a controlled environment” at some point the person using is going to want more than that cap allows them, and they’ll search for it illegally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059424367.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>As I said, the reason alcohol is so high on the chart is because of it’s availability and widespread use, I agree with you on that.

The cap argument is not really a problem. You’ll get a LOT of heroin before you reach the cap. They check your body weight, check out your medical record, and measure a dose that is safe for you. That dose can be quite high. Just below overdose.

The illegal market will be extremely shitty as well, the amount that buy goes down substantially, and so does the purity and availability. Why buy shitty heroin off the street when you can get 99% pure heroin at the clinic? As availability goes down the price goes up, so it’s most likely cheaper to get the best heroin ever, than the shit heroin in the streets.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059444224.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>Another problem there is the potential lawsuits that could occur. Example, the recommended dose of ibuprofen for adults is between 200-500mg per 6 hours. Now, I personally take 1200 mg for anything worse than a mild headache. Why? Because you can safely take upwards of 2000mg of ibuprofen in one single dose without fear of addiction or overdose or really anything going wrong. Why do drug companies prescribe such low doses? To avoid lawsuits. What makes you believe that companies offering heroin or cocaine wouldn’t feel exactly the same way about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061220324.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, most drugs that people take affect their decision making skills, and it’s very easy for somebody who’s drug of choice is an upper like meth or coke to suddenly decide after they take the drug, that they want to leave the safety and privacy of their home to go find trouble outside, and that is where the danger is.

Should alcohol be illegal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061237634.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I touched on this, I don’t drink and I wish it weren’t legal, but it already is and I understand the whole speakeasy situation we would have if it were made illegal. The difference here is the widespread use of alcohol versus the use of substances like meth or coke. There are a LOT more people drinking with no negative affects to themself or others than there are meth users with no negative affects. Just because humanity opened up the alcohol can of worms doesn’t mean we should do the same with meth or coke or any of the harder drugs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061265488.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the prohibition of drugs is working?

Do you know how many people have died fighting cocaine? Are they better off dead so that fewer people get a little high for a few hours?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061273266.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think that legalizing cocaine will make it less lethal to all those people. Alcohol proves that. It’s legal and still has killed millions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061322429.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>I’m talking about the people murdered by various world militaries to fight the war on drugs, not the people who overdose. The United States has firebombed whole fields to destroy the crop, has that done anything to stop it? No.

Not to mention the people murdered by the gangs and cartels that have sprung up in direct response to the legal actions.

The human toll of prohibition is *staggering*, not only death but in terms of imprisonment too. It’s a marketplace of death and destruction, all in the name of telling people that they’re not allowed to take some kind of drug.

Oh but you can pump as much sugar as you want into your body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061399971.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a very, very simplified take. You’re forgetting how many people have been killed in the name of promoting, growing and selling these same crops. The gangs and cartels aren’t killing people because they’re mad that the government doesn’t allow them to sell it legally. They kill to maintain their monopoly. They control all the land where the coca plant can grow. Coca doesn’t grow in the US, it wouldn’t be like how everyone grows weed in CO now. Legalizing cocaine would not lead to the cartels suddenly stopping operations and getting day jobs. Just making it legal doesn’t supply the companies who would be selling it, they still have to go try to make deals with the owners of the land used to cultivate coca (see: cartels) I don’t agree with the war on drugs or how it’s been handled either, but drugs that cause extreme damage to a person’s body, such as meth, coke and heroin, should not be legalized. That would not remedy the situation. I could see us being much more open to lowering the sentences and policing, and making it easier to seek medical attention, but that’s different from legalization.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061448241.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>The cartels represent unregulated capitalism.

The CEO of Coke doesn’t behead people, because he doesn’t have to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061469712.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>How exactly is the United States Government going to regulate the cartels? They operate in the tropics where Coca can be grown, in a bunch of third and second world countries with unstable governments and very religious people who would take another 100 or so years to decide to legalize cocaine and legitimize the cartels after the US legalized. That means that your regulated dealers still have to buy from unregulated producers in Colombia, Bolivia, Venezuela etc. The cartels don’t want to start paying taxes and making statements about their assets. And if you think those countries will forgive everything the cartels have done and just legitimize them and let them start selling regulated product them you have a bad case of having never lived in one of those countries. And what we legalize here in the USA has literally no legal bearing on those smaller countries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061484287.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>The policy of other countries is based on US policy. We arm them to fight the war on drugs.

&amp;gt; The cartels don’t want to start paying taxes and making statements about their assets. 

Why not? It’s better than having to shoot people all the time.

Edit: I will concede that pandora’s box is open. But that’s no reason to *keep* it open.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061495541.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the cartels care about shooting people? The wealth of the cartels is so huge that having to start paying taxes would mean giving up BILLIONS OF DOLLARS. The cartels would kill a runner for losing one thousand dollars, you think they wouldn’t start a literal civil war and destroy some of those countries if they tried to impose taxes on them or use some of their land to cultivate coca? The cartels care about maintaining their monopoly. Not to mention they are better armed then the militaries of many if not all of the countries they operate within.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061568316.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe they should be in charge?

I mean what’s, really, the difference? You act as though the instability of these areas isn’t almost entirely US caused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061578933.0" user="Spencerchavez125" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I’m sorry I thought that you cared about people dying? What about all the innocent people that those cartels have killed and will continue to kill to maintain their monopoly? Just because the USA sucks and has done bad stuff in the past doesn’t mean that we should let the cartels continue to do bad stuff in the future. The people who should be in charge in those countries are the people who actually live there not a puppet government appointed by either a Mexican drug cartel or the United States government.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32061593506.0" user="notasnerson" delta="False">
    <text>I do, but what if they didn’t have to kill?

I mean honestly, any more than any government would. They don’t kill for fun, they kill to maintain control.

Just like the US does.

Edit: To be clear I am not “pro-cartel” but imagine if the money went back to the people? Countries have major exports, why not drugs?

When we made the gangsters of prohibition a legal business they went away or moved on to other illegal avenues. But these Farrell’s are too powerful, what if they didn’t have to contend with a hostile government?

What if we turned them into google?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
