<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32060297118.0" user="pennydreams" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think anyone should be allowed to use drugs and simultaneously use any social welfare system. If they use any drugs beyond weed, then they shouldn’t have any help in food, housing, unemployment, healthcare, ect, and shouldn’t be allowed to work for the government or any government contractors. Why should we pay for someone’s fucked up life decisions? Does that give a new perspective?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32060773821.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>So khat is not allowed? LSD? Psilocybin? Coca leaves? There are tons of drugs that don’t really do any harm.

Someone spent their whole life gaming and eating shit food, and the government has to pay their health bills? My grandfather got so drunk he fell down the stairs and dislocated his hip, his shoulder and others many times. The government had to pay because of his drug use.

Someome gets addicted to pharmaceutic opiates and the government pays for their welfare. The list goes on.

This argument doesn’t really hold very well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32063393361.0" user="pennydreams" delta="False">
    <text>LSD and other hallucinogens don’t kill you when you take them but they absolutely destroy your mental health and ability to be productive in general. Cocaine in the leaves is still very bad for the cardiovascular system, like tobacco. There is no healthy drug, they all have side effects. 


I’m not sure where to put the line but I agree that many obese basement dwellers or people who abuse pharmaceuticals can be put into the same boat. Why not? Legally the line could be if a doctor recommended or OK’d it, then it’s accepted. So casual alcohol or weed use is fine but a doc is never going to say it’s fine to binge drink, eat 5000 calories a day or use heroin. 


If someone wants to shoot themselves in the foot, I don’t care but don’t come to me for help afterwards. Thats the principal that I think should be implemented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064030767.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>LSD and other hallucinogens destroy your mental health? Please, find me a source on that. Johns Hopkins and all the studies over the years say otherwise.

There was even a case in 1980 where a bunch of people snorted LSD, thinking it was cocaine. They snorted between 3000 doses to 12000 **each.** They were all discharged from the Hospital within 2 days.

I am however, biased when it comes to psychedelics. Because in my case they turned my life around for the better. Just as they did for the subjects at Johns Hopkins.

Taking cocaine a few times in your life is hardly shooting yourself in the leg. Same goes for a lot of other drugs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32067547228.0" user="pennydreams" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.healthdirect.gov.au/lsd-acid-and-mental-health


The fact that you are surprised about these hard drugs not having effects on mental health shows how ignorant you are on the subject. I have person experience with hallucinogens and they have to be respected and have massive negative side effects. I had a ton of anxiety and stress after using hallucinogens and it going poorly. The studies you are referring to are very preliminary, done only on a select few individuals who already have diagnosis of serious mental health disorders, done in very controlled settings and doses under strict supervision, set, and setting with psychological professionals monitoring and filtering who used and doesn’t use the drugs. This is not at all comparable to them being accessible to the general public or being used casually in a home setting. 


Again, just because they don’t require long inpatient stays from an overdose does not mean they are harmless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32067751016.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>First off the article you linked to doesn’t have any research papers in their sources.

Second, there is tons of research into the beneficial effects these substances can give you from the 40’s to the 70’s. Also, the Johns Hopkins study is quite large considering the amount of work that has to be done with these trials.

Third, some people cannot drink alcohol, as it always goes poorly. Some people can’t smoke weed, because they become anxious and paranoid. In just the same way; these subtances are not for everyone. People react to them differently.

Did you do as advised when you took these substances? Did you have a safe space to stay without disturbances? Did you drink enough water? Did you go in with a good mind set, and state of mind? Did you leave enough time after your session to process? These are powerful tools, and are not meant for recreation. 

They are therapy sessions, where you are your own therapist. And some people are told things they don’t like to hear, and try to escape it. Why did you become anxious? Were you shaken by a scary experience? Or was it something else? How long did you stay in that mental state after the experience?

It turned my life around. I got myself an education, a job, and started paying more attention to my health. And I’ve heard a plethora of stories that say the same. But those stories hardly make the headlines. «Guy took shrooms and is now an upstanding citizen!» sounds weird, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32068113062.0" user="pennydreams" delta="False">
    <text>Your doubling down in reaction to my comment is unsurprising. I find the handful of people who have had these types of revelatory trips delude themselves into seeing no downsides and think everyone should do acid. I’ve heard of many folks in my prior friend groups who have similar experiences as you and I definitely agree there is a place for hallucinogens in the clinic but don’t kid yourself about the downsides. I understand your argument about how weed and alcohol should also be considered when discussing drug abuse, and I agree. I’m not sure where to drawl the line but suggested a doctor could call it for the individual. But your excessive questioning about my use of hallucinogens exemplifies my point well. The specifics of my case are irrelevant and I would rather not discuss it. The vast majority of cases that people use drugs, they are not in controlled settings so there is a very high rate of the experiences going bad and a lower but still unacceptably high rate of the experiences leading to extreme consequences (lifelong ptsd, addiction, schizophrenia, suicide, ect). This ‘use in strictly controlled setting’ is not at all similar to the ‘open private use’ style of drug use you are arguing for. It will increase the number of irresponsible people abusing these pharmaceuticals, increase the rate of negative effects, and turn off many folks to the positive effects and clinical uses. It seems you want others to be able to experience what you experienced with hallucinogens and that you cannot share or suggest this revelation because the substance is illegal. I think that you have a point but it needs to be controlled or it will be ultimately rejected by good people and abused by immature and irresponsible people instead. We must tow the line until we have a better understanding of these hard drugs so we can prevent the clear negative effects in a controlled and predictable manner while setting up therapies for specific mentally ill populations. And I’m not sure if we’ll ever get to full legalization and that isn’t necessarily a bad thing. As long as we try to use what we can to get those in a rut out of it in a predictably healthy way, that’s way better than what we do now! 



Another link but just use common sense, it’ll tell you the same thing:
https://drugabuse.com/lsd/effects-use/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32071389119.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>My argument is that as with any drug, you don’t just take it without proper procedure. The problem with all these drugs being illegal is that the government or education system doesn’t talk about safe use and harm reduction practices, because the drugs are deemed illegal. But I think we can both agree that regardless of their legality this should be in place.

If a legal institution was responsible for the sale of these drugs in the situation they were made legal; we could make sure that people had gone through a course regarding safe use, and the effects of the drug they are buying.

I do agree that some of these drugs might seem volatile, but the lack of research is the problem here. Because these drugs are illegal, it is much harder to find unbiased information.

This goes for all of these drugs, if they are to be made legal. In fact it would be quite smart to do the research on those who buy the drugs. They’d fund the research themselves, and get to go on a roll.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32071750600.0" user="pennydreams" delta="False">
    <text>That institution already exists, it’s called the FDA. Those procedures for safe use already exist in the prescription system and being monitored by doctors. What it sounds like you really want is a restructuring or modification to FDA regulatory policies so that folks can do research on specific hallucinogens to find uses in the clinic for mental health diagnoses. That is happening, slowly I’ll say, but it is happening. This opinion is far from what you suggested in your title or post so I think your views have significantly changed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32073663262.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>No, what I am suggesting is that the state owns all the shops for selling these substances. I’m saying that the state should make it mandatory to be educated about the substance before taking it.

Also, these shops would be like dispensaries, owned and regulated by the state. In Norway we have this for all alcohol stronger than 7%. I believe the idea of legalising these drugs is good as long as it’s executed right.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
