<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32064103911.0" user="dinky-dink" delta="False">
    <text>Your premise rests on your rights as an individual to do what you want, which is granular. One of the reasons that drugs are controlled is because growing/making and distributing drugs causes negative effects for countless people, including murder, corruption, and overt force over others, such as gangs, cartels, and exploitation of individuals who are part of bringing them drug to you. This has repercussions for society on a grand scale that the government must then deal with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064133043.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>There are no gangs or cartels producing it if you produce it within legal institutions.

If you sell drugs illegally, you can’t call the cops if someone fucks you over, or steals from you, or gives you fake money. All you have is violence and fear tactics.

If you sell drugs in a pharmacy, or a shop, legally; you can call the cops. Instead of all this violence and criminality surrounding the production and distribution, you have actual jobs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064162391.0" user="dinky-dink" delta="False">
    <text>It then becomes the responsibility of the government to deal with the repercussions of addictions and other behaviors which result from drug use</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064308008.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>The government already deals with loads of addiction problems. And those problems are mainly on prescription opiates. 

We need to create a tighter social security net around the people struggling. Putting them in jail is futile. 

If your life is absolute shit, and you have no job, no friends, etc, do you really think being put in jail would help you? You’d only feel as if the world had turned on you. Your life would just feel even more shit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064466754.0" user="dinky-dink" delta="False">
    <text>As someone who works in mental heath/substance abuse, most addicts are not as a result of prescriptions. They are street drugs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064491823.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>Most drug related deaths in the US come from prescription opiates. What kind of people get treatment? Are the lower economic classes more prevalent etc?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
