<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32062633811.0" user="Joesepp" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but not all drugs. This is just one example, but coke literally highjacks your pleasure center and makes you only want more and more. Mice will refuse food and water, only seek out coke, and eventually die if they are given unlimited cocaine. And thats why we have people pushing for legislation on the more "safe" drugs. It might happen sooner than you think</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064147116.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>There’s an experiment which I believe you’ve heard of. A rat is put in a cage, with two water bottles. One bottle is just normal clean water, nothing special. The other has heroin mixed into it. Sure enough, the rat starts drinking the heroin water, after a while it drinks nothing but heroin water, and not long after it’ll drink until it dies from an overdose.

However, there’s a different experiment, called «Rat Park». In this experiment, a rat is put into a bigger cage, with many toys, lots of females to procreate with, all the food it can imagine, and at last, the two bottles. In this experiment, the rat uses the heroin occasionally, but it doesn’t use it compulsively. It has no reason to, because life is good. It’s social needs are fulfilled, and it has food and toys to play with. It has a good life, and therefore has no reason to abuse drugs.

The first experiment fails to check if it abuses these drugs because it is missing something else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064307592.0" user="Joesepp" delta="False">
    <text>Ah i see. Maybe if we can improve everybody's quality of life we can reach the point of complete legalization. Unfortunatley, especially where i live in the US, many people suffer terrible qol in order for others to live much more comfortably. Until we can fix that disconnect i dont know if its viable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32064359500.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. I believe this is because of a priority of money and profit over the well being of people. And obviously, this problem is quite large, and hard to surmount. 

In a country like Norway, where I’m from, these social foundation capacle of doing this. We have a security net, taking care of those who fall outside.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
