<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32058976149.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>*&amp;gt;  What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul.* 

As a landlord, I do not let any of my tenants use marijuana in any of my properties. While it may not harm people, the smell can permanently damage the walls of the house. So I think your claim should not apply to rental property.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32058992426.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>This should be obvious though. I’ll do it on my porch, or underneath a vent. Damaging your home as a result of recreational activity is nothing but stupid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059032622.0" user="lameth" delta="False">
    <text>What is obvious to you isn't obvious to everyone. There are still people that don't see a problem with smoking in hotels/motels even when they are very explicit with no smoking in the rooms.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059064981.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>Yup. Common sense is not common.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059869748.0" user="ReamusLQ" delta="False">
    <text>Do you also prohibit the type of food people can cook or the people you rent to based on their food preferences? 

My brother did maintenance on apartment complexes, and after an Indian family would move out, they would have to completely replace all of the kitchen cabinets and fixtures because the smell of curry was impossible to clean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32060207125.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>The South Asian tenants we have rented our properties to, even though they cooked every day, did not cause any such damage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32060281535.0" user="4entzix" delta="False">
    <text>If your making them pay a security deposit/move in fee this rule is rediculous. a $200 coat of paint is not a legitimate reason to ban weed smoking

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Im sure your losing more money from damage related to alchol then you would ever lose from people smoking weed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32060320349.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>Marijuana and cigarette damage is going to cost a whole lot more than $200 worth of paint to erase. It makes the house far less sellable.

Also, by banning marijuana I head off the problem of grow houses that are a major problem here in Colorado.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32060363627.0" user="4entzix" delta="False">
    <text>No one said anything about Cigarette smoke. That shit will destroy a house. Anyone who smokes cigs inside is an idiot

Marijuana wont do any permanent damage, I have smoked all the time in every apt I have ever had and people come in and out when I am not smoking and literally have never smelled anything. 

Also living, growing marijuana and smoked marijuana dont smell anything alike.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32060421882.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>It is not unusual for a marijuana smoker to be unable to detect a relatively faint odor of marijuana that is obvious to a non MJ user.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32063314601.0" user="brewfox" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, but you're wrong. Weed smell does not linger like tobacco, and is gone in a couple days at MOST. I've had extensive experience with this. 

Your tenants are doing it anyways, and you can't tell because the smell goes away. You're just a shitty landlord. Esp with people who have a medical card. 'my lease prohibits you from taking your medicine!'. Way to go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32063598443.0" user="NicholasLeo" delta="False">
    <text>I live in Colorado. It's an open secret that very few people with medical marijuana cards are actually using marijuana to treat an illness. This is why the doctors in medical complexes throughout the state have urged their medical complex landlords to evict any doctors whose business is "prescribing" medical marijuana. The docs don't want to be in the same complex as that scum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32063827540.0" user="brewfox" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like some good ol' marginalization of the people who DO need it. "You don't REALLY need that medicine, so I'm going to evict you if I smell a faint trace". Good thing you know better than actual doctors and enjoy kicking sick people out of your rental properties. You're the real scum.  

Even if it's only helping someone with stress or anxiety, who are you to decide? Because your precious property might need a day to air out? Cry me a river.  
  
And like I said before, people are still smoking weed in your properties. You just can't tell after 1-2 days. So if you DO happen to go in right after they lit up, you get to start the wonderful eviction process, taking time from you, and making it much harder for them to rent in the future. Instead of just assessing damages IF there are any (which of course there aren't). So, you are using you prejudice against 'drugs' and your position of power to strongly affect others lives and well being. Kudos landlord. Kudos to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32078794233.0" user="-Rogue-Tomato" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; who are you to decide? 

They own the place and they can decide to not allow anything that could cause damage to their property, such as but not limited to cats, dogs, children and smoking. 

Security deposits are there *just in case something happens* \- They're not there to cover any damage the landlord **expects** to happen, because if a landlord expected any damage from a new prospective Tennant, they wouldn't be approved to begin with. 

Before you say weed doesn't cause damage - Anything you set on fire in doors is capable of causing damage, for example you could drop your joint on the carpet and burn a hole in it etc. 

&amp;gt; people are still smoking weed in your properties. 

Sure, you're probably right. There is no way around it really - However since it's in their tenancy agreements that they're not allowed to, if they're ever found smoking weed then they'll be in breach of contract and will be evicted immediately and they'll lose their deposit. 

&amp;gt; making it much harder for them to rent in the future. 

Completely their own fault. If you're told not to do something because it will result in you being evicted and you go ahead and do that very thing you were told not to do, then what do you expect?

&amp;gt; Sounds like some good ol' marginalization of the people who DO need it. 

If someone needs to smoke it, then they'll just have to find accommodation that allows it. 

For the record, I've absolutely nothing against people who smoke weed and I think it should be legalised all over the world - However, if you rent then you have to abide by the rules of your tenancy, otherwise you're out. You can't just have a free ride and do whatever you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32081520352.0" user="brewfox" delta="False">
    <text>Many other things than weed can start a fire. Incense can leave a much more lasting smell (or ethnic cooking like someone mentioned), but isn't forbidden.  

Most states allow landlords to sue for damages above the security deposit. Even then, renters can pay for damages if they happen, just like with everything else.

My problem is when many wealthy homeowners, or many home-owning corporations, all institute this rule and it makes housing difficult to find for people who NEED MMJ to live a somewhat normal life. Even if they vape it and there's no smell (or smoke it, because the smell goes away very quickly, even OP said it was faint, come on). It's a dickish thing to discriminate against.  

Also, you often don't get to see these kinds of restrictions until you get the lease after you paid money to "apply". There's a fundamental power imbalance because of perceived damages (there really aren't any) which I would argue is code for prejudices. I would bet many people use this restriction to discriminate against minorities 'perceived' increased drug use rates.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
