<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32059302917.0" user="zlefin_actual" delta="False">
    <text>First, point of clarification: you say the government goes too far in deciding what to allow.  Which government?  there's a lot of countries in the world, each with different drug laws.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I've got 3 points:

1) In the US, we currently have around 48k deaths annually from Opioid overdose; which exceeds the annual deaths from car crashes or guns.  Many of these ultimately come from people who started on legal prescriptions and got hooked; some of those overdoses are directly on the legally prescribed medication.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

2) This paper estimates that prescription opioid abuse costs \~$80 billion/year for the US.  If they were more freely available, the number would likely be somewhat higher.

[https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5975355/](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5975355/)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

3) Many people do not live alone in their home.  They may have roommates, family members, or especially children in the household.  If the person becomes addicted to the drug, or overuses it, they could end up hurting those others. It would also be possible for children to get hold of the drug if it is not stored well (or if the person storing it is careless after taking it).  We currently have thousands of cases a year of children eating things like Tide Laundry Pods.  There are also people with Pica who may be at risk for eating inappropriate things (there's a lot of variation in Pica cases).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059392839.0" user="Cheezefebreeze" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and I believe the problem lies in Mental Health. The drug is simply a vent, an outlet.

There’s an experiment which I believe you’ve heard of. A rat is put in a cage, with two water bottles. One bottle is just normal clean water, nothing special. The other has heroin mixed into it. Sure enough, the rat starts drinking the heroin water, after a while it drinks nothing but heroin water, and not long after it’ll drink until it dies from an overdose.

However, there’s a different experiment, called «Rat Park». In this experiment, a rat is put into a bigger cage, with many toys, lots of females to procreate with, all the food it can imagine, and at last, the two bottles. In this experiment, the rat uses the heroin occasionally, but it doesn’t use it compulsively. It has no reason to, because life is good. It’s social needs are fulfilled, and it has food and toys to play with.

This subject is extremely deep, and the reason as to why mental health problems occur is extensive. But suppose we did meet their needs? Suppose we gave them therapy, a social network, and a job they liked. Would they still abuse drugs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32059500874.0" user="zlefin_actual" delta="False">
    <text>Hard to say; but given that we have some ten thousand overdose deaths annually from people who're on prescription opioids (and are thus eligible to get all those things) I question the feasibility of meeting those needs as a plan.  
Lots of people would like a good job and a good social network.  Is there a viable plan for giving them all one?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32065002897.0" user="donabean" delta="False">
    <text>The od numbers are not primarily from prescription opiates they are primarily from fentanyl. That is a problem because of illegality. This is why the od numbers continue to rise even as doctors continue to be burdened with more and more severe restrictions for several years. The number of people legally prescribed pain medicine that become addicted is in the single digits in every study done in the last 20 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32065045244.0" user="zlefin_actual" delta="False">
    <text>I know overall od numbers are mostly others; but I stand by my quote on deaths due to prescription ods.
https://www.drugabuse.gov/related-topics/trends-statistics/overdose-death-rates
figure 4; which seems to show 17k prescription opioid ods in 2017</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
