<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="721434128.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/bxiu4w/cmv_you_should_be_allowed_to_take_drugs_and_alter/">
    <title>CMV: You should be allowed to take drugs and alter your conciousness in the safety of your own home.</title>
    <original_poster>Cheezefebreeze</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that the government goes too far in deciding whether or not you are allowed to take drugs in the safety of your own home. You don’t stand to harm others, you only risk hurting yourself.

You can go rock climbing, skydiving, wingsuiting, rally driving and so on. 99% of the time nothing happens, and no harm is done. The same goes for drugs.

The war on drugs has done more harm than good. People who start out abuse drugs are usually doing pretty bad, and they cover up the void. That drug use only perpetuates the problem. You start failing economically, your social life declines, and the ditch just becomes too deep, so you can’t get out.

People have bad mental health, and self-medicate. I’ve been there. For me it was weed, for my grandfather it was alcohol, for some it is meth, and there are several other addictive behaviours in completely normal things, that are used to cover up a mental wound, something that hurts. Just like you get painkillers for a wound to numb the pain.

In every single drug, the abuse percentage is roughly 10%. Most users use it recreationally and only once in a while. A small part of users use it compulsively at some point in their lives.

The drug isn’t the problem, it lies in mental health. One in four people will suffer from a mental health issue during their lifetime.

Now, I don’t use drugs compulsively. I do it with friends sometimes. Sometimes I might light up a joint to unwind after work, and sometimes I take psychedelics, to expand my understanding of myself, and the world around me.

What I do at home harms doesn’t harm a single soul. What I do with my friend is nothing but bonding and fun. 

People should be allowed to do what they want, and even **if** it poses a risk, they should be allowed to do it, just as rock climbing or skydiving poses a risk.

I’d seriously like to expand my understanding of the arguments for why this shouldn’t be. We live in a world where it isn’t, and as such, I’d like to understand why.

Thank you.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32058909788.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>**Note:** Your thread has **not** been removed.
Your post's topic seems to be fairly common on this subreddit. Similar posts can be found through our [DeltaLog search](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/search?q=drugs+%7C+cannabis+%7C+weed+%7C+marijuana&amp;amp;restrict_sr=on&amp;amp;sort=relevance&amp;amp;t=all) or via the [CMV search function](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/search?q=drugs&amp;amp;amp;amp;restrict_sr=on).

Regards, the mods of /r/changemyview.

*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
