<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32116429213.0" user="shortadamlewis" delta="False">
    <text>2 points for you. 

ONE.If your point is primarily against "Sunday School", what are parents supposed to do with their children when they go to church?

TWO. If you are an atheist and purely against any religious doctrine, who do you think is more religious, someone who has been raised on God or someone who found God as an adult?

I personally am not religious, but would have not objections to my children finding faith. I have children, but trying to "hide" children from religion or tell them it is "wrong" seems like it would be just as bad as forcing religion on them from your point of view. I would never want to take that opportunity away from my children. At the same time, children who never go to church will still come home from school one day and ask you about God. Mind did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116570555.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If you are an atheist and purely against any religious doctrine, who do you think is more religious, someone who has been raised on God or someone who found God as an adult?

We don't care. 

It is impossible not to notice religion in this country, and that is OK. I am an atheist and I am certainly aware that when I raise my kids, even though I might encourage them to explore different faith systems for themselves, as a result of my atheism I will have anchored them a bit. That is OK. It isn't important to me that my kids are atheists, it is important that they see everyone as an individual *person* instead of a member of a particular faith. This sentiment is reflected by many religious people, but not practiced by that many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119284128.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>ONE. That's a fair logistical issue, but irrelevant to what I am arguing is the right thing to do for children regarding their ability to have reasoned faith.
TWO. Remember that I'm not actually arguing against religious doctrine. I am arguing against children being in a space where they can be emotionally coerced. If your children come home and ask you about God, you can absolutely tell them what you know, or even direct them to ask a pastor/priest/rabbi/imam etc. about it. Just don't encourage them to believe in a thing "just because". And if I'm right about organised religion being emotionally coercive, then don't let them get near that until they're ready to cut through that emotional appeal and rationally derive the belief.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
