<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32115177834.0" user="Tuxed0-mask" delta="False">
    <text>I'm also not religious and was raised outside of organised religion, but I kind of wish I had been. Here's why:

When I was living in the US, it was hard to miss what a significant cultural impact organised religions had on people's lives. It's a large component of people's identity, especially in the large city that I'm from. In the same way that children communicate in a different language with their parents, they also communicate in a taught cultural language.

Of course some religions are way more strict than others and some places impose more strictly faith based arguments than others. However, a large proportion of people practicing an organised religion are using it as a cultural tradition that helps connect them to a common history for people like them. Take for instance reformed Jewish people (non-orthdox). Some don't really keep all the kosher rules or they'll work late on a Friday night, but they still consider themselves religious.

People without these community organisations where we can learn shared rules and customs, like myself, are more isolated. Moving to a new place, people can use the place of worship as a safe space where they already know the rules and customs. Because religious denominations are somewhat standardised, people can move freely to different communities and still have an anchoring point to fit in. Children should be encouraged to learn about the culture of their parents from an early age because it helps to integrate them into a global society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115473236.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for sharing your personal experience; I can understand why you'd want to have that cultural immersion. I'd agree that's certainly a point for exposing children to religion, but I wonder if you'd also have a perspective on how that might intersect with my ideal of "reasoned faith". For instance, the fact that you wanted to be included in that religio-cultural tradition because it allows you to connect with people is a sort of peer pressure, or need for social acceptance. This would be an emotion-based reason - which could obstruct one's ability to engage with the religion in reasoned faith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115759713.0" user="Tuxed0-mask" delta="False">
    <text>Well emotions are part of it, but it's also social coding which pays out dividends later.

We all learn social codes, like manners, that when performed in front of specific people it expedites favourable outcomes from them. For instance, someone sees your kid making lemon squares for the church fête, and later on they help them get into a good high school. There are tangible benefits to belonging, and the more closely tied to a specific group some people are the more they are willing to help people like them.

Children benefit extraordinarily from learning as many social codes as they can, while they are still young enough to not develop biases. Me for instance, one posh mom, one city dad, two sets of rules which help me fit in in either place. Religion gives children an extra layer of tools to help them succeed. 

Absolutely there is a danger to religion in the forms of prejudice, and many of the incongruous things that damage people are first learned as children. Like I said, I wasn't raised religious, and the reason is my parents don't believe in religious authority over people. As kids, they absolutely were told to always trust nuns and priests and the consequences were disastrous for their peers.

If there was a rational, humanist religion, then no one would have an issue with it's rules. I don't think that the minority of cases where people suffer disproportionately from religion is worth stopping children from being exposed to that part of socio-cultural life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119201929.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>This strays a little from my original point, but I do have an issue (being generally anti-religious as I mentioned) with religion being tied to socio-cultural life, because that's where it becomes coercive. It's much harder to reject following the practices of your culture (particularly your ethnic culture), and if they happen to intersect closely with religion then you are in essence forced to go along with your religion.

So your point about learning social codes is well-taken, this is the reality of the world today. Perhaps what I'm hoping for that these can be learned outside of religion, since religion (as I state in some of my replies to other comments) has this coercive presence that limits a child's ability to develop reasoned faith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115701290.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>On the one hand... groups you can self identify with. On the other, more arbitrary lines to divide people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115855460.0" user="Tuxed0-mask" delta="False">
    <text>Well I don't think the lines are arbitrary. People grow up differently and have different histories. Doesn't mean that it's ever alright to then prejudice yourself against people based on those lines.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115781517.0" user="carmstr4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Children should be encouraged to learn about the culture of their parents from an early age because it helps to integrate them into a global society.

Purely anecdotal here, but my issue with this is that I am not at lol religious and my ex husband is . Our four year old is being immersed in the church every other weekend, and he is quickly using god as an answer for all things. This exposure and early belief makes it difficult for me to teach him anything about *my* beliefs because anything I say in contradiction comes across (to a four year old) as if I’m denying the existence of someone as cool as Santa Claus.  And he gets really angry. So I feel as if, in order to not upset my kid, I am forced to keep quiet while his dad continues to indoctrinate him with what I deem bullshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115847007.0" user="Tuxed0-mask" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah that is rough! My view of it is that religion is kind of like an ethnicity. So when people use it as a tool to try to prove things like it's a science that's just garbage :/

In the same way no one is like "you're Polish so the earth must be flat to you," is the same way that people shouldn't be like "God the Father wants you to do x".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119179679.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for sharing your experience, this is sort of why this issue bothers me so much. Sometimes this conviction that a belief is right can make adult believers impose their beliefs on the child - which I am arguing is not right at all.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
