<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32122765765.0" user="nutellas_rr" delta="False">
    <text>I somewhat agree with this. However I think that there are definitely religions more at fault than other. Of course the main three Christianity Islam and Judaism all generally teach the same thing and treat god as some almighty being that should shape how they live their entire life. Children nowadays do break away from this more but with these three. Not much. And one thing that is truly awful is that it cause people to doubt proven facts even down to simple science. Hell. Some people don’t get vaccinated because it’s not in the bible. However. Some religions. Like Buddhism. Parts of Hinduism. Etc. Don’t even rely on the belief of god. And although people change how they live their lives for these religions. It’s not for the worse. Teachings in these religions such as no violence are truly beneficial. I mean if you look at Ghandi. Without Hinduism the invention of a peaceful protest wouldn’t be what it is today. And these religions that are less constricting have a much less deep impact on children. Some children in more forceful religions genuinely believe it to be right to try and convert other people and to me that seems like parents brainwashing their kids into continuing this idea that religion should be a contest. Another issue  comes into this as well however. The idea that kids are basically parents property and that what they say to their children and what they make their children think is fine as the child is theirs. This is obviously wrong but religious parents don’t see teaching religion as the same thing as they genuinely believe it is beneficial. Although it’s definitely unrealistic to think that children won’t be exposed to religion in their lives before 16.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
