<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32115386869.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>There is no such thing as an absence of ideology, the absence is the ideology.

There is no default setting. By not raising your child with a religion, you are raising them as atheist.

Christians or some other group that sees their views as the default could use your same arguments and laws to ban exposing children to atheism until they are older.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115448550.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>I certainly agree with your point that any group could reverse the argument. Perhaps on this point my question then becomes what can we do to encourage reasoned faith in any belief (even secularism?). For instance, I would consider my faith in secularism reasoned because this belief has been developed as a result of engagement on a rational level with the beliefs underlying secularism - I do not merely accept them "just because" I was taught to do so as a child. If we are assuming that any belief (or lack thereof) is ideology, is there nothing we can do for the child to encourage them to develop reasoned faith?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115546142.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Is that your reasoned faith or theirs? What you are saying is that you think your belief system is the best but religious people think that as well, many will see your proposal as harmful to children, by not indoctrinating them in a religion you are damning their souls.

Faith is not rational, it fundamentally cannot be. All we can do is teach the people we are responsible for to accept other people's faiths and hope that others do the same and, if they don't, you have to accept it because it is literally impossible to prove someone's faith wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115690552.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All we can do is teach the people we are responsible for to accept other people's faiths

Nobody's faith inherently deserves respect. What they deserve is the right to have that faith, no matter how silly it might seem to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115708892.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Fine, change it respect people's choices, however:

&amp;gt;no matter how silly it might seem to be. 

This is the issue, no one's beliefs are silly from their own perspective, we've got to stop judging.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115727096.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>People have the right to believe that Xenu came to Earth billions if years ago and trapped souls inside human bodies for nefarious purposes. People don't have a right to expect others to not treat that as a silly belief. Scientology is still silly regardless of your right to believe it. Just like Islam, Hinduism, Christianity, etc...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115859758.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>And that show's a complete lack of respect for any theology, it's just as appropriate to think that atheism is silly, it's a reductive argument that gets you nowhere. accepting that your beliefs are no better than anyone else's is the only realistic way of coexisting with people with different beliefs..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115868195.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not. The best way to co-exist is to respect their right to *have those beliefs.* Beliefs don't deserve respect if they are silly and wrong.

And sure, people could consider athiesm silly, idc so long as they respect my *right* to not have a belief concerning god.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116026232.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>But you don't respect theirs so why should they respect yours?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116054675.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>Wtf are you talking about? Either English is not your primary language (understandable) or you are not reading what I wrote. (Not cool)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116288042.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>You have called other people's beliefs silly, that is disrespectful and in no way a qualified statement. If you are disrespectful of their beliefs, and they are disrespectful of yours, you're not going to get along, all you're going to do is argue with people like you're doing now and, especially when it comes to religion, arguments can turn nasty.

If you want to co-exist, stop calling other people's beliefs silly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116410008.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>Co-exist? Oh please stop with the dramatics. 

There is a fundamental difference between:

&amp;gt; That belief is silly

And

&amp;gt; That belief is silly, therefore I will not allow you to legally have it

Coexistence only requires the second statement not exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116619028.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Really? So there's no religious tension in any place where the law protects freedom of religion? We love in a world of religious intolerance, we have politicians exploiting it, people literally dying because of it, communities against each other.
All because everyone thinks each others ideas are 'silly'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116654410.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So there's no religious tension in any place where the law protects freedom of religion?

Stop. Misrepresenting. What. I. Am. Saying. Do I need to draw it in crayon for you?

Obviously people killing each other over religious beliefs are not respecting their *right to have that religious belief.*

It's not fucking complicated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32117052247.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>'Coexistence only requires the second statement not exist'. It's exactly what you said dude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32117081549.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry you are too stupid to understand the difference between "I don't respect your beliefs but respect your right to have them" and "I dont respect your beliefs or right to have them."

You sound like an authoritarians wet dream.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32118571300.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>I know the difference, I'm saying it's not good enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32118654559.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>You are wrong. You reason for it not being per your "logic" is:

"X is not enough, because X is not happening at location Z."

It's a simpletons argument and is not logically consistent. You might as well say that a freezer is not good enough to keep ice frozen because if you dont put the ice in the freezer it melts. No shit, sherlock.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116815649.0" user="throwaway68271" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;accepting that your beliefs are no better than anyone else's is the only realistic way of coexisting with people with different beliefs..

If I didn't think my beliefs were better than the alternatives, I wouldn't have those beliefs. I believe in them because I think they are true, which by extension implies thinking that different beliefs are false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32117057859.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Do you accept you may be wrong? If so, you're fine. If you don't then tension is inevitable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119088101.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>I see the confusion, allow me to clarify. As I defined reasoned faith, I'm not making any claim to objective truth (that a faith's beliefs are consistent with how reality actually is). Instead, I'm suggesting that the ideal for religious belief - and I think many religious people would agree with me on this - is that their belief is informed and justified by some manner of rational engagement with the underlying evidence justifying my belief, ie: I believe that God exists because of ____ and other evidence such as ____ does not contradict this belief. As opposed to: I believe that God exists because my mother told me OR I believe that God exists because duhhh. That would be unthinking faith, or blind faith. Feel free to challenge my assumption that reasoned faith is an ideal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32120302001.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure many religious people would say their belief is some manner of rational engagement, faith is fundamentally irrational, it's belief without (tangible) evidence.

I'm an agnostic who expects there's no God but I'm married to a girl who is religious and comes from a very religious family. Her nephews go to church every Sunday and have done so all their life. If I told my brother-in-law that what he was doing was somehow against the interests of his children he'd punch me in the face. And his children are wonderful, they're respectful, compassionate and smart, he's done a wonderful job of raising them.

To my brother-in-law, his children are getting the ideal, and that's the problem, people's perspective are completely different and there's no objectively correct answer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115684428.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There is no default setting. By not raising your child with a religion, you are raising them as atheist.

It would seem that means athiest IS the default setting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115725342.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>Atheism is a choice, technically Agnosticism is the default :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115737323.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>Athiesm and agnosticism are not mutually exclusive. Technically theism and agnosticism aren't either, but it's even more rare to see an agnostic theist than a gnostic athiest.

Agnostic athiest is the default. You are born without knowledge of if a God exists and also without a belief in god.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115883698.0" user="Subtleiaint" delta="False">
    <text>These are not states of being, they're ideologies, and, as ideologies, atheism and agnosticism are contradictory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32115908254.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>No, they are not. I know some people like to pretend that agnosticism represents some middle ground but it's not.

Atheism and theism have to do with *belief* 

Agnosticism and gnosticism have to do with *knowledge.*

Knowledge &amp;lt;&amp;gt; belief. 

It's like two people discussing the best tasting fruit and you pop into the conversation claiming to be the middle ground because you like carrots. Ok, good for you man, we aren't talking about vegetables though.

Same principle. The discussion of athiesm and theism is about belief. We aren't talking about knowledge.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116548370.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Athiesm and agnosticism are not mutually exclusive

Yes, they most certainly are. You can't be open to the idea of the supernatural (agnosticism) while believing that supernatural doesn't exist (atheists). If you are an atheist, like I am, you have made the decision that even if provided with 'proof' of the supernatural, there necessarily must be a natural explanation. In other words, if there is a God, then God is a natural phenomenon, no different than a human or a fission reaction. A complicated thing that can be explained in the natural world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116608506.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>No, I'm sorry but you are wrong.

Agnosticism is the position that you lack the knowledge to say if God does or does not exist.

Atheism is the position that you lack a belief in the existence of gods.

You are trying to posit that atheism makes a statement about knowledge, and more specifically the knowledge that God(s) does(do) not exist, it doesn't do that. It is only a statement of non-belief.

The position "I dont believe in God, but I don't know God doesn't exist for a fact" is a perfectly self consistent statement and is both a position of athiesm and agnosticism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116809537.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>- Atheism is the position that you lack a belief in the existence of gods.-

It isn't that simple, it isn't about gods, it is about at the very fundamental level of thinking there can and is a supernatural something and a thinking that nothing is supernatural. The defining characteristic of 'God' is supernatural. If you think there is a possibility that there is a supernatural, like an agnostic would say (in there case, that they don't or can't know) then you are not an atheist. My foundation of knowledge that supernatural doesn't exist is because it doesn't make any sense, if it is a thing that exists it must be part of the natural world. That is knowledge. 

There is a also a difference between saying this is "God" and that is "a God". If a species came along with such technological dominance that they could control every aspect of our lives, then they would be Gods to us, but they wouldn't be supernatural.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116864809.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>You can personally identify your atheism however you like, but atheism is only a lack of belief in God. It need not make any further statements on the super natural. One could believe in ghosts but not gods. 

I don't believe in God because I've not seen sufficient evidence for the existence of God. You appear not to believe in God because you don't believe in the supernatural. Both of these reasons are sufficient to define someone as an athiest but neither is necessary. 


&amp;gt; If a species came along with such technological dominance that they could control every aspect of our lives, then they would be Gods to us, but they wouldn't be supernatural.

Being like a God is not being a God. Being indistinguishable to us would not make them gods, as a sufficiently advanced species above them could determine that they are not gods.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32117104310.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>- Being like a God is not being a God. - 

Yeah, if you only believe in the narrow definition of "God" as it is defined from an Abrahamaic perspective that is common now, but a "God" is really definable historically is any creature with lots of power, the Greek Gods would be more easily defined by a species with sufficient technological prowess to control things uncontrollable to mere humans. They weren't 'all knowing, all beneficent, all etc', that is a modern view of God. In ancient Egypt the Pharaoh was a god, I know that sounds silly but to the peasant who had never seen a building over one story, someone who could create pyramids layered in marble is a god. 

You are parsing, very finely, the difference between a belief and knowledge, but I don't accept that because beliefs are founded by knowledge. To say I believe there is no god but I don't know there is no god is really a difference without a distinction. Your belief is founded on knowledge, so somewhere there is knowledge that says there is no God. In my case, that knowledge comes from the fact that if it exists it is natural, and thus cannot be a "God" like we think of today. This is similar to the theory of the void by the Greek atomists. You didn't need modern chemistry to understand why nothing can exist (I don't care what Zeno said) all you need to do is be able to observe motion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32127612930.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>Hardly. Kids by default are naturally religious.

I'll pull up a study and edit this comment when I get the chance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32127813439.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>Kids are naturally inquisitive and questioning, but its adults that fill their heads with nonsense answers of "god."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32128124804.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/your-brain-politics/201210/the-religious-brain-default-setting</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32128210507.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>Its pretty evident you went out and googled the answer you were looking for without actually reading the article. Because the actual content of this article does not support the title. 

What is supported in this article is that the human brain is wired for "teleological thinking." What it doesn't do is support the idea that "teleological thinking" is the same as religion. Its not. "teleological thinking" can give rise to religion, but that does not make religion the default. Such purpose based thinking gives rise to "there must be a purpose for X" but there is nothing in the article, or that you have presented that demonstrates that "X" is god in such thinking. This is actually to my point. Its the adults who fill the child's mind with a definition for X, but X could as easily be aliens, or that we are living in a computer simulation, and those types of conclusions fulfill the default tendency of the human mind to invoke purpose based reasoning in how they view the world, and without invoking god.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Essentially, you have confused the human brain being wired to accept religion with the human brain being wired with religion. That's a fundamental difference and an error in your thinking. Though ironically, the error, is likely a result of your own purpose driven brain which sets the purpose as the "why."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32128267033.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/politics/8510711/Belief-in-God-is-part-of-human-nature-Oxford-study.html

This article talks about the study I remember looking at. It was a while ago, which was why I had to look it up via google.

&amp;gt; What is supported in this article is that the human brain is wired for "teleological thinking." What it doesn't do is support the idea that "teleological thinking" is the same as religion. Its not. "teleological thinking" can give rise to religion, but that does not make religion the default. Such purpose based thinking gives rise to "there must be a purpose for X" but there is nothing in the article, or that you have presented that demonstrates that "X" is god in such thinking. This is actually to my point. Its the adults who fill the child's mind with a definition for X, but X could as easily be aliens, or that we are living in a computer simulation, and those types of conclusions fulfill the default tendency of the human mind to invoke purpose based reasoning in how they view the world, and without invoking god.

Sure. But then the creator of that simulation would also be considered a god. Or if there was an all-powerful alien, that could also fit the conventional definition of god.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32128283436.0" user="emjaytheomachy" delta="False">
    <text>But it's still not god. There are infinite number of explanations that could be offered, satisfy our flawed teleological thinking, and not be a god explanation. You've still failed address that there is fundamental difference between "wired for" and "wired with."

A strong man with great endurance is built for working in a mine, that still doesn't make him a miner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116533934.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;you are raising them as atheist.

No, you can't draw this conclusion. Atheism is a choice that says "I *know* that the supernatural is horse-shit", raising a child without religiosity is a different thing entirely. There are a lot of non-religious people, I dare say most, who aren't actually atheists. You know, the types that are generally turned off by religion and religious people but who still proclaim to believe in some sort of 'god' or 'higher power', those people are not atheists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32117908859.0" user="Ember56k" delta="False">
    <text>I am an implicit atheist, and im going to take a completely WILD guess and say you are an explicit atheist. Explicit atheism is believeing that there is no supernatural. I, as an implicit atheist, dont believe that there is OR isnt anything, simply because i have no proof of either being the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116775836.0" user="wedgebert" delta="False">
    <text>Atheism **is** the default setting, in the same way that not believing in Santa Claus is the default setting.

You have to be taught to believe in any particular religion because no one is born believing in a god, goddess, or pantheon.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
