<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32116005205.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, I think keeping kids out of church is essentially raising them atheist-ly. 

Then from there, I disagree with your assertion that atheism "occupies a neutral place in society." If atheism is neutral, what is beyond atheist? As I see it, the spectrum goes from full faith in religion to full confidence religion is fake. A neutral position would be halfway between those, but atheism is at the far end. Further, governments are not atheist....they are (or at least, should be) truly neutral. Accepting of all beliefs and not passing judgment is different from being confident they're all wrong.

So if you think that parenting should be neutral in the way governments are neutral, parents should expose kids to all possible beliefs, not pass judgment on any of them, and accept whatever the kids want to do/believe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116490669.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>\-  As I see it, the spectrum goes from full faith in religion to full confidence religion is fake. A neutral position would be halfway between those, but atheism is at the far end. -

I think you see it that way because religion is so prevalent in our culture, if you let that go a little bit, then you start to see that there really can't be a 'neutral' setting here, you either believe in 'supernatural' or you don't. Believe in something un-provable and suspiciously biased (religion) is something we can and very much *should* judge. You have to be able to teach your kids to be able to discern fantasy from reality, whether that fantasy is Jesus or Iraq's WMDs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116533347.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; then you start to see that there really can't be a 'neutral' setting here

I can see what you're saying. If there is no neutral, that still contradicts what OP is saying and agrees with me that non-belief is at one far end of the spectrum, not the middle.

&amp;gt; Believe in something un-provable

Is it possible to prove that a god *doesn't* exist? Both atheists and the religious believe in unprovable things. 

&amp;gt;whether that fantasy is Jesus

Experts agree that Jesus was a real person, so maybe that's not the best example for you to use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116841322.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>Couple of things here, I am not saying Jesus of Nazareth isn't real, I am saying the fantasy of Jesus is not real. In other words, he was conceived by sex, just like the rest of us, he never walked on water, and he never magically created food for thousands with a couple of fish and loaves of bread. Similarly, there were never any WMDs in Iraq (at the time) and all the made up evidence was a fantasy. But I am not arguing that Iraq is not a country or that it never existed in the first place. 

The question of proof is an interesting topic because we (and I am in another discussion with a different poster on this thread) inform our beliefs with actual knowledge, the two aren't separate. My perspective is that in order for me to internalize a belief (like gravity, light, nuclear fission) it has to be founded on something real. A regularly observable phenomenon. Those things ARE provable, therefore, to the extent we can know anything I believe in them. I also believe things that are generally true but not provable, like people act in their own best interest, men are reckless before they are thirty etc. To demand I believe something, or to look at me oddly because I am not convinced, of something that has no real provability is silly. I can't prove god doesn't exist, I don't have to, I am not trying to convince you of anything. You (maybe not you personally but someone trying to convince me my non-belief is a form of believing) need to prove to ME that god exists in order for me to 'believe'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32116878989.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; To demand I believe something, or to look at me oddly because I am not convinced, that has no real provability is silly. 

To be clear, I don't intend to do that - does it seem I am? I'll be more careful. 

In general, I don't disagree with anything you're saying, but I still see a difference between the atheist view "god does not exist" compared to "there's no evidence for god" that an agnostic may espouse. 

It's fair for you to believe that something doesn't exist because there's no evidence for it, but that's not a proper scientific conclusion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32117168562.0" user="Leucippus1" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, when I use "you" I meant a theoretical, you, a person who is not me who is arguing against my perspective. Not "you", the person behind the keyboard typing responses to me. 

There is a difference between an atheist and an agnostic, no question there. Agnosticism is probably the 'best' for a young person, since you are explicitly accepting that you don't "know", as a young person you "know" very little anyway, so it makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119264013.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>This is a useful discussion. So we've sort of arrived at the question of a belief being derived scientifically, through empirical observation, and whether that should lead to atheism or agnosticism. By my view, if children were told by their parents "god doesn't exist, none of the religions are true just because" that would be equally bad.

So maybe this leads to the question of how children could derive agnostic beliefs in a non-passive way, how they might arrive at that conclusion in a "reasoned faith" kind of way. Your view that agnosticism is best for a young person, Leucippus1, is probably acceptable to adults recognising the child's inherent naivete, but a child probably wouldn't accept that internally that they just "couldn't know".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32129842787.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>Experts do NOT agree that Jesus was  real person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32131321115.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Virtually all New Testament scholars and Near East historians, applying the standard criteria of historical-critical investigation, find that the historicity of Jesus is effectively certain</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32153936909.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>No they dont. Just Google it. "Extra biblical evidence for the existence of jesus." These scholars are not scholars but religious apologists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32154943462.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>That seems like a flimsy excuse to write off academic consensus. I could just as easily call anyone who disagrees an atheist apologist and disregard their opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32155027708.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>It's not at all. There is no good evidence for Jesus outside of the bible, and lots of evidence that the bible is contrived. Any claim that is made without evidence can be dismissed without reason. Your claim was that "scholars agree that jesus existed", my point is that they dont. https://youtu.be/mwUZOZN-9dc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119221942.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree that keeping children out of religious institutions is atheist. Parents could, for instance, keep religious books around the house for children to read if they're interested. I'm not saying "no religion, period". I'm simply suggesting that they be kept out of spaces where their exposure to (what I consider) emotional coercion is limited.

I have thought about the exposure of kids to all possible beliefs as an option, but if (as I stated in my original post) we do not trust children to be discerning in how they acquire their beliefs - rationally, as opposed to emotionally - then this practice because equivalent to a competition between the religious institutions you bring your child to where the religious institution with the strongest ability to emotionally coerce wins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119421537.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>I think books can be emotionally coercive too. Did you ever read Where the Red Fern Grows as a kid? That book wrecked me for days.

To me, it seems like parents being more active about discussing what children encounter is a good thing overall. Talk about what they were told in church, what they thought it meant, and present an alternative view on it if needed. Same thing for at school. Make sure they are learning correctly, and evaluating what they hear. Then the kids gain critical thinking skills, communication skills, bonding with parents, etc. Those conversations seem unequivocally good, and also don't require parents to raise their kids in a way counter to their beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119615864.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>Haven't read that book, no. Those sound like good ideas for encouraging children to engage in reasoned faith. Does that still mean you'd bring them to church, though, given all the issues that I've mentioned with organised religion's effect on children?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119773726.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>In this hypothetical, yes.

Though I may have missed something in the past day or so... Is there any evidence that organized religion is a net negative for kids' development, or just your admittedly biased perception?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32120747095.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>I think the question I originally posed wasn't about religion being a net negative for kids' development, but rather a net negative for kids' ability (at the time and all grown up) to engage with religious belief in a reasoned way. For that, I don't have any empirical evidence specific to this but I'd guess that it does have a negative impact on that based on our understanding of influence, peer pressure, children's moral development etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32121432055.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>So if you're coming at this from a standpoint of religious beliefs being a bad thing, would evidence of religious people being, say more charitable or wealthier change your mind at all? Or would your view still be that faith is illogical no matter the benefits?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32123314640.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is a common misunderstanding of what Atheism mean. An atheist simply does not assert belief in a God, he does not assert that one does not exist. An anti-theist would assert there is no God but as this would necessitate proving a negative, nobody could defend that position very well. We teach our children to be atheist about 1000s of gods, I have told mine stories of Thor and Zeus but I've never continued by saying "if you dont think these stories are true your going to burn in hell". Why not treat all religions the same way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32126998366.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't no conclusive faith either way be more agnostic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32128553361.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>No, another common misunderstanding of a word. Agnosticism refers to knowledge, in this case of a God. Atheism relates to belief (belief being subtly different from knowlage). Most atheists are also agnostics and most agnostics are also Atheist. "I dont know that God exists and I dont believe that God exists" would be a position that makes you both atheist and agnostic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32128944387.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>If we accept your definitions, then why would an agnostic atheist want to keep all kids out of all churches, if not to maintain the lack of faith in a god?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32129751659.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>They're not my definitions, they are just the definitions. 

It's an interestingly worded question. No child is born with a faith in God. The starting position of any child is of no faith in any gods. Putting kids into an environment where one particular God is taught as true and the penalty for doubting that is eternal torture seems weird to me. 

Even if it were practical to lie to children to engender good behaviour, I would still say it's wrong. 

Comfortingly, for me, secular morality appears to out perform religious morality by any measurements. 

If you think God is real, none of this makes any sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32129757555.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, how do you know it's a lie? I thought you said that atheists don't have an opinion either way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32129788732.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>Atheists have an opinion. Their opinion is that they dont believe a God exists. That isn't to say they dont. Teaching something as true, when you're not sure about it is a lie.

If my kids ask me if ghosts exist I say "I dont know". If somebody wanted to take my kids away for an hour each Sunday to teach them that ghosts were real I would disapprove.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32131314411.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If somebody wanted to take my kids away for an hour each Sunday to teach them that ghosts were real I would disapprove.

In OP's scenario, you would believe in ghosts and they would prevent you from teaching your kids about ghosts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32131321260.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>You can teach them about ghosts, that's fine. Just dont tell them that they are unquestionably true and that if you don't believe that then you will be tortured for eternity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32131324706.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>So then it sounds like both of us disagree with OP's proposal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32131317510.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the penalty for doubting that is eternal torture

For what it's worth, that is not a mainstream christian view. Doubting is seen as normal and even good, and does not affect salvation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32153968851.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>You think that people can go to heaven without believing in God? I'd say that's a bit less than mainstream. Sure you can doubt, but unless you accept Jesus as your saviour you are going to be tortured for eternity, unless I have catastrophically misread my bible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32154949548.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Sure you can doubt

So it sounds like we are in agreement that someone can be saved and still doubt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32154976952.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>Just to be clear, you think that you can to heaven without believing in Jesus?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32154978353.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>Doubt is different from disbelief</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32155003358.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>Ok then, I would not want children taught that disbelief will be punishable by torture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32155005556.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, and you want your religious beliefs to override the beliefs of all other parents?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32155913268.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>If their beliefs harm the child then yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32155921358.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>And you believe that all churches of any kind harm every child that goes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32155952982.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>I believe some are worse than others, but in essence, I do, which I believe was the point put forward by the creator of this thread. Religion teaches children to abandon their critical faculties in favour or faith. It then backs that teaching up with threats. I believe secular morality gives children a better psychological foundation that religious dogma. 

I dont expect you to agree with this because its obvious from your contributions, that you are a believer. 

Perhaps it would help you to think of it like this. 

Your new job takes you to a new country to live and work. When you get there all children are expected to attend Muslim Sunday school. I'm guessing you would be uncomfortable with this. If it were any God other than your personal God you would be uncomfortable. I am uncomfortable about all the same gods you are, plus 1.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32159143373.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>You have made inaccurate assumptions about me.

I am in favor of allowing parents to raise their kids how they see fit (with some restrictions on abuse, obviously), so I would oppose mandatory Islam just as I would oppose mandatory Christianity or mandatory secularism.

Beyond that, I appreciate the first amendment, which your/OP's proposal would require repealing. 

Do you have any conclusive evidence that kids going to a church is always harmful?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32162285040.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>I apologise for misrepresenting your position. I would say that raising children to believe something under the threat of torture constitutes abuse. Other than that we are on the same side.

Conclusive evidence of the damage done to children by religion is hard as most of it is benign but you could look at the proportion of the prison population that is religious against those that are not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32163434771.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Conclusive evidence of the damage done to children by religion is hard as most of it is benign

That seems inconsistent on your part then, doesn't it? You don't believe in a god because you don't have any evidence, yet you apparently don't need evidence to believe that children's church is abusive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32163840513.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that threatening children with torture is abuse, that is my evidence. If you think that it's OK then we are unlikely to reach consensus. You could make the argument that such threats are ultimately justifiable as they engender better behaviour or better morality. Even if that were the case, I would still say that abusing children is wrong physically or psychologically no matter what the outcome. It used to be the case that parents could legally beat their children, its now not illegal in many countries. I would say that that is a shift in the right direction and the treat of violence should also not be tolerated. As a sort of aside, here is some evidence that secular children exhibit superior moral behaviour. https://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/nov/06/religious-children-less-altruistic-secular-kids-study</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32163902363.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I believe that threatening children with torture is abuse, that is my evidence. 

Do you think that bringing a child into any church is the same as "threatening children with torture"? 

I fail to see how pasting construction paper animals onto a picture of an ark and learning about how god loved the animals that he saved them is abusive, especially when parents have the ability to temper any message they feel is improper. 

I haven't surveyed all Sunday school materials, but the focus seems to be heavy on the love from god and Jesus, and less on the "you're going to hell" part. 

&amp;gt; As a sort of aside, here is some evidence that secular children exhibit superior moral behaviour. 

I am not sure the experience of the 18 Buddhist or 5 Hindu kids they surveyed can accurately represent the 1.5 billion people in the world that belong to those religions. 

Even the 29 Jewish kids probably can't/don't represent the 6.5m Jewish population. 

Or did you feel those sample sizes were appropriate for you to draw your conclusion?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32164452747.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>It's an interesting interpretation of the Noah story, that God annihilating all but 2 of each animals on the planet would show how much God loves animals but lets not get into that:-)

I absolutely agree that pastors will not open with overt threats of torture, I also believe that most modern Christians have a nuanced reading of the bible, focusing on the passages that are kind and relevant and ignoring the bits about slavery, witches and homosexuality. 

However the central tenant of Christianity is that if you believe you will be rewarded and if you do not you will be punished for eternity. There is no other subject that you would teach to children in this way and so I don't condone it.

As for whether the study I shared is conclusive, no, it's not. It's just some evidence. You might also look at the prison populations of America and what percentage are atheist [&amp;lt;0.1%] versus theist. Also the divorce rates, teenage pregnancy rates, single parent family rates, murder rates and violent crime rates carried out by those of faith compared to atheists. I don't use this to suggest that atheists are more moral than theists, but rather to point out that there seems to be no evidence of a moral advantage in raising children with faith.

As I said, even if it were beneficial, I would disagree with threatening children, even if it provoked a positive response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32164574493.0" user="tomgabriele" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's an interesting interpretation of the Noah story, that God annihilating all but 2 of each animals on the planet would show how much God loves animals but lets not get into that:-)

I chose that on purpose to show how messages directed at kids are watered down focus less on the "you're going to hell" part....as I said in the following sentence. 

&amp;gt; However the central tenant of Christianity is that if you believe you will be rewarded and if you do not you will be punished for eternity. There is no other subject that you would teach to children in this way and so I don't condone it.

Wait, maybe I misunderstood your position. This whole time, I was thinking that you opposed bringing kids to any church of any faith in any place. Do you only oppose kids going to churches that preach some form of hell? Only Christian churches? Only american christian churches?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32166457930.0" user="ericlunt" delta="False">
    <text>You make a good point and a valid distinction. I fully encourage children being taught about a wide range ideas, religions, ideologies and beliefs. I am opposed to them being taught that xyz is unquestionably true, I object even further to that assertion being backed up with a threat. 

It is only religions, and then only some religions, that do this. If there were a big foot club that taught children that big foot exists and if you dont believe it then you will be tortured then I would resent it equally. As the only people I'm aware of who are doing this are the religious, and in huge numbers, its them who I'm concerned about.

Buddhism is better because there is no threat, and no dogma, Hinduism is also better by that standard. Scientology and the others  are probably better than the Abrahamic Faith's. There are probably some that are worse but I cant think of them.

I'd be happy though, if we could all just get past all of them, take the good teachings and figure out how to treat each other well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
