<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32117373772.0" user="MrWackoTaco" delta="False">
    <text>"Oh Jimmy, you want to go to the NASA camp because you want to become an astronaut? Well youre not old enough to make an informed decision like that. Those decisions are life changing. And once you make those decisions, you'll keep them for the rest of your life and never change them. That's why we dont celebrate Christmas. We want to wait until you turn the legal age of 16 to make an informed decision on whether Santa is real or not. We wont let you decide which friends to make because you're not old enough to know which friends are the best for you. We will let you have friends when you are old enough to know which ones are good and bad. Remember we also dont make you celebrate the fourth of July with the friends you want to make because we want you to wait until you're old enough to know if you want to be an American or not."

"But mom I'm 14"

"The legal age says 16 is the age to make decisions. Until then, no watching the news or presidential debates. We certainly dont want you participating in the debate club, you're not old enough to know how to debate because you can't make informed opinions. And when you go to chess club, remember to follow the openings I say are correct because you aren't old enough to know which opening is your favorite. And absolutely no going to church."

"But mom I like going to church, that's where the friends you wont let me make are. Plus, I find church to make me feel as a part of a community I have a hard time finding at school. It makes me feel safe and happy, which is why many adults do it too."

"Sorry, but OP says you aren't old enough to make your own decisions so we will have to deprive you of that experience."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119638720.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>So to sum up your rather sarcastic narrative, you're extending my policy to all and any decisions in life. Obviously this age of informed decisions thing doesn't apply every which way, only the things that are in the eyes of the law important.

As I've stated in numerous other replies, I don't think there's an issue with children attempting to engage in religion in a way that is rational. It's more to do with the way that organised religion tends to utilise its tools of emotional influence to get you to believe things without thinking about them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
