<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32120123468.0" user="diyage" delta="False">
    <text>FYI: I am a Christian and follow a specific religion. My religion influences much of what I do and believe in my life. My counterclaims are rooted in these facts. As I agree with most other comments to this thread I'm not going to repeat most of their ideas. Simply be aware that I support many of the other counterarguments made by other users. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

You give me the impression (correct me if I'm wrong) that you believe most religious people act in blind faith rather than informed or reasoned faith and that blind faith is somehow the standard that most religions would have their adherents follow. Because of this impression, I think that we first need to define what faith means and then give credit to the majority of religious people who exercise true or reasoned faith as opposed to blind faith. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Simply put, faith is believing or trusting in something you can't see or directly observe/interact with. By this definition, faith is a natural and necessary part of human existence. When a parent teaches a child that they should avoid touching the hot stove and that child listens, that child is acting in faith. That child has never experienced getting burned from the stove, but he or she has developed enough faith/trust in their parent that they will listen to what they say regardless of this fact. Children gain much of their knowledge simply by trusting what others tell them without gaining actual experience for themselves. Adults exercise faith as well. When you travel to a new country for the first time on vacation, you have no personal experience of what it will be like. But because of the pictures your friends showed you of their trip there, or from what you have read on travel blogs, etc. you act in faith and trust that you will enjoy your visit there. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Notice that this ties in with your argument that faith should be reasoned out. I definitely agree with you on that point as I feel most religious people would. Many religious people have personal reasons for believing what they believe, whether it's due to personal experiences, logical conclusions they have come to based on observing facts, hearing the experiences of others, or acting on their own desire to believe because of what they have felt. Those who are religious due to blind faith (or faith that lacks any kind of reason) are typically the minority. These people are usually reliant on others such as friends, family, religious leaders, etc. to help sustain this faith, and will typically abandon their religious beliefs if they are left to themselves. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Second, I don't think it's wise to separate faith from feelings/emotions whether it's religious faith or general faith as you do in the first paragraph of your argument. Human beings are emotional beings and our emotions are some of our most powerful motivators in any circumstance be it career choice, political opinion, religious affiliation, etc. We can't simply ditch our feelings and approach decision making only from a logical/fact based approach. To do so is to ignore a critical part of our humanity. There needs to be a balance between the two. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Third, "blind faith" is a necessary starting point to acquiring any knowledge. Children act in blind faith because they don't yet have the mental faculties to sufficiently reason through all of the information, experiences, and opinions they are fed each and every day. Children are expected  to simply trust and believe what their parents, leaders, teachers, etc. tell them without question. Once a child grows and develops the ability to reason and truly think for themselves, they can then look back on what they have learned/experienced and decide what they want to retain or continue to believe in, and what they want to abandon or disbelieve (and here I agree with you that children are very impressionable, and typically continue to believe what they were taught when they were younger. This does not mean they are blindly believing, rather that their blind belief has transitioned to belief due to a personal evaluation/choice/experience). For nearly everything aside from religion we don't argue with this concept because we understand that most parents have knowledge and wisdom far superior to that of a child so what that parent will teach can be trusted. For some reason, we treat religion differently and feel that blind faith is inappropriate and has no place in acquiring religious knowledge/belief.  

&amp;amp;#x200B;

To be clear, I'm not saying that blind faith is the ideal, but that it is a necessary and normal part of acquiring true faith in any religion. Faith will always be "blind" in some sense because, as stated above, it's a belief or trust in something you cannot see or directly observe. But as you act on that faith or that belief, you gain experience that helps you develop your own personal convictions independent of other people. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Fourth, religious education/Sunday schools is much more than simply telling kids God is good and to love Jesus. Parents and religious leaders are trying to teach children why God is good, and why to love Jesus. They are trying to teach their kids how God and Jesus can play a meaningful role in their lives and help them learn, overcome challenges, and grow. By and large, these parents and leaders have learned from their own observations/experience/evaluations etc. why these things are important and how they can help and bless a person's life. Consequently, parents and leaders will do what they can to impart these beliefs to their children while they are young. They know that when the child grows up they will eventually reach the point where they will have to do their own evaluation and choose for themselves whether or not to believe what they have been taught since they were a child. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

In conclusion, the proposal to keep kids as isolated from religion as possible doesn't make sense. Blind faith is a natural and necessary part of childhood learning and growth, be it with regard to religion or any other topic. As most parents and religious leaders are acting out of genuine faith and belief that religion will help their children live good, wholesome, and successful lives, they should be free to impart of these beliefs to their children and expose them to religious ideas and experiences, just like they should do with any other knowledge they find important aside from religion. Once children are old enough to reason for themselves, they can choose whether or not they want to substitute their "blind" faith for true faith, or if they want to abandon their faith all together. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Interested to hear your feedback and any counterclaims to these arguments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32135008574.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for your coherent and cogent counterargument. I'll go point by point as well for my feedback.

Point 1: I agree with your characterisation of faith, it definitely extends beyond religious faith as you say and I'd agree too that there are many people with religious faith that come into it for personal reasons. What I'd question is whether a majority of people do believe in religion with reasoned rather than blind faith. I don't necessarily have the statistics to back it up, but I think it's reasonable to assume that a majority of people in any given religious faith were substantially exposed to the religion as children. Now, if my argument that children have great difficulty "converting" blind faith into reasoned faith is correct, then it's likely that of this majority currently believes in religion out of blind faith. 
You do allude to this in your third point, so it seems like we are divided as to whether people actually do convert blind faith into reasoned faith. Do you have any particular reasons (or personal/anecdotal experiences to share) for why you think it is fair to assume that people do this "conversion"?

Point 2: I think it's fair to say that emotion is an important part of religious faith. What I am against is children being influenced in that manner. It's precisely because they are so vulnerable to emotional influence that it's easy for this faith to come "from the wrong place" (ie. because Mum gets upset if I don't). I think the freedom that we accord to adults means that we have no good reason to exclude emotion from the activity related to faith. I just don't think children are/should be accorded that same freedom.

Point 3: I think this is your strongest point. It's unavoidable that we do teach children to believe things "just because". I think ideally we would want children to learn things without being told "just because" (ie. touch the hot stove to learn why not to touch the hot stove), but I recognise that it's hardly pragmatic.

Why we treat religion differently probably relates to how people not of a given religion characterise religious knowledge/wisdom. It's harder to doubt what you can see with your own eyes, or "reason out" (say, a demonstration in chemistry class of an observable chemical reaction). But then again, we do begin in developing our understanding of chemistry with being made to believe in its tenets blindly. I think this is a whole other can of worms to delve into that will take more than a few posts, so I think we will have to agree to disagree on this point.

Maybe one way to move forward on this point is to compare the conversion of scientific blind faith to the conversion of religious blind faith. I think the difference lies in the extent to which it is encouraged, and how easy it is to identify people who haven't undergone that conversion. We are encouraged in our academics to understand science from the ground up, to do observational experiments and to understand how equations are derived - and so on. I don't know how much this is encouraged in religions, but my personal experience tells me that it's nowhere near to the same degree. Also, it's easy to evaluate whether someone memorised an equation or actually understood why the equation works the way it does; it's both rare and difficult to question whether someone is believing a given religion out of blind or reasoned faith.

Point 4: I think this might be just a difference in personal experience. I'm glad that your Sunday School carries out its religious education the way it does, I think that's a much less coercive way to encourage religious faith.

One quick issue I want to raise with your conclusion is the idea that parents think religion is a good thing for their children. The problem with this argument is that the same could be said for any number of objectively harmful things that parents might believe are good for their children - no vaccinations, refusal of medical intervention in emergencies, etc. (I hope this point doesn't attract ~that~ crowd...). So that cannot be the sole rationale, it has to be combined with other reasons.

This has been a stimulating reply to write, and I look forward to your reply as well :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32139163784.0" user="diyage" delta="False">
    <text>  

Long response as I had to think of the best way to phrase things. Apologies if I have neglected to address any of the points you brought up fully or if I go off topic anywhere. 

Point 1: I'm the same as you in that I don't really have any statistics to back up my claims as there hasn't really been a study focused on blind faith vs. authentic faith. I would, however, cite studies that show that younger people are generally less religious than older people (https://www.pewforum.org/2018/06/13/young-adults-around-the-world-are-less-religious-by-several-measures/). To me, this indicates that people are making their own personal choices to believe/disbelieve a religion rather than blindly follow what they have learned. I also have plenty of experiences with friends who grew up in the same religion as me that have chosen (from a pretty young age, in their teens) to abandon their religious beliefs. Some of these friends have come back to these beliefs on their own (i.e. acquired a personal/authentic faith as opposed to blind faith) while others continue to this day to be unaffiliated with the religion of their childhood. Are there people who still believe on blind faith? Yes, but my experiences and intuition tell me that this group is still a minority. With so many influences in the world today (from news, peers, experiences, etc.) most people are provided ample opportunities to question their beliefs. Unless a person lives in isolation or in a religious/ideological bubble, most people come to a point in their lives where they must evaluate their beliefs and choose whether or not to continue in them. 

Point 2: I'd make a similar argument as I did when arguing about the prevalence/necessity of blind faith to a child's learning/development. Parents (in general) love their children and care about their wellbeing. These emotions drive many of the decisions that they make in terms of rearing their children. Take the stove example again. If a parent saw that a child was going to touch a hot stove and then yelled at their child (whether out of anger, fright, etc.) to get away/not touch the stove, they are using emotion to influence the child (in addition to acting off of truths they already know for themselves, i.e. the hot stove will burn you). We teach children to pay attention to their feelings and the feelings of others so they know how to properly treat others. We use emotions as teaching tools alongside of facts to help reinforce what we are teaching. I don't think religion should be put on a different plane where we can't use emotional persuasion, especially when emotion is so intimately tied to religious belief. 

Point 3: I’ll focus on the last paragraph of your response for this point and agree to “agree to disagree” with you on the topic of the first two. 

You say, “We are encouraged in our academics to understand science from the ground up, to do observational experiments and to understand how equations are derived - and so on.” This is true, but in practice the professionals are the only ones who really do this. The average person may be aware of the scientific method, but they don’t often exercise it themselves. They instead trust what professional scientists publish because scientists use this method, generally smarter than the average person, and know what they are doing. When it comes down to it, most people have a superficial knowledge of scientific truths that isn’t produced from their own engagement with the scientific method. I don’t fault them for this however because we trust (i.e. put faith in) the scientists whose job it is to figure these things out. As such, if we allow the average person leeway to exercise faith in the information passed down by professional scientists, I think we need to allow religions the same courtesy and recognize that acting in faith (without a perfect knowledge) is alright.  

I think it’s important to note here that religion, while it can be approached in a scientific manner in many ways, is different from science in an important way. Science is a tool used to explain the “what’s” and the “how’s” of the physical world. Religion does touch on the “what’s” and “how’s”, but it is more importantly focused on the “why’s” of life. One of the reasons the scientific method works is that it produces repeatable experiments with repeatable results. This is how we come to establish the truth of something. The why’s of life cannot be analyzed in such a clear cut and objective way. There is no set of experiments with a specific/repeatable result you can use to answer such questions. Consequently, there is no set experiment and specific outcomes that a person can use to come to know if religious truths (answers to the why’s of life) really are true. Because of this, I agree with you that it’s easier to compare conversion from scientific blind faith/knowledge than it is to do the same for religious blind faith/knowledge. This is because they are inherently different. 

Everyone’s experience with religion is going to be unique to them. I think that for almost every religion this is the point. Religions don’t want to push blind faith on their adherents because it is not congruent with helping the adherent build and strengthen a personal connection with the divine. There are, however, certain common practices in every religion that adherents believe help to build that connection (e.g. meditation, prayer, scripture reading, congregational worship, etc.). Consequently, parents/leaders/etc. will push and encourage others to do these things. This is where I think the impression that religions push blind faith comes from. They are constantly encouraging people to do these things (i.e. follow a kind of religious scientific method where you try these things and see what kind of effect they have on your life) because it will strengthen that person’s individual connection to/belief in the divine. For a scientific comparison, it’s like having a student run through multiple practice problems each night for homework. The teacher encourages (or requires) the student to do this because it helps them understand the topics better and come to really internalize and solidify their personal knowledge. In the end, all we can really do is trust that if a person says they believe for themselves that they do. As you said, there’s really no way to prove that claim or not. 

As a final caveat, I want to emphasize that while most religions (the belief systems themselves) don’t advocate blind faith, individuals may choose to do so. A distinction needs to be drawn between what a religion in general preaches, and what an individual chooses to do with those teachings. This might mean we have to clarify other points we’ve discussed previously as they could apply to religious people or religious systems/organizations differently.   

Point 4: I see where you’re coming from, but this counterargument seems to be shifting us away from the original argument, which is that exposure to religion should be limited (primarily because of the assumption that blind faith is bad/detrimental to a person/society). You said in your post that you do have anti-religious bias but that you’ll try to suspend them for this debate (I would interpret this as taking the assumption that religion is neither good nor bad, but neutral). All other points have been successful at treating religion neutrally, but this last argument seems to assume that religion is a bad thing (i.e. via your objectively harmful comment). Putting my faith aside, I don’t think we can prove objectively that religions as a whole are either good or bad (we can probably identify some minor religions or sects that are exceptions, or point out specific/isolated beliefs/doctrines, but I don’t want to jump into a sub debate). One can produce evidence to support either position (for religions are bad think of holy wars, the inquisition, etc.; for good, think of the ideals most religions espouse, humanitarian aid, etc.). As such, I think for this debate we must maintain the assumption that religion is neither good nor bad, but neutral. As such, I think my argument that parents think religion is good for their kids is valid because I’m not arguing that religion itself is good, just that parents are acting in goodwill/faith in passing those beliefs on. 

In addition, I think that some of the examples you provided, while they agreeably are objectively harmful, are only the belief of a small minority of people, and while these beliefs can have detrimental effects on others in society, they largely only affect the adherents to such beliefs (for example, anti-vaccers are generally the ones falling ill with the recent measles outbreak, not those who have received the measles vaccine). As such, I find it problematic to use them as justification for the argument. I don’t think we should let the examples of such a small minority control the argument. 

I’m enjoying the conversation and look forward to any feedback.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32154978748.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>Was waiting for a decent period of free time to compose a reply, here it is now:

1. That's certainly one way to interpret it, although an alternative interpretation could be that irreligiousness in general is being encouraged among younger people. It does make me wonder whether studies have been done on parents' religiousness vs (adult) children's religiousness', would be enlightening. Thank you for sharing your experience with this, that is good for me to hear.
2. I think it's fair for you to say that emotional influence is necessary. Maybe this comes from the assumption I hold that emotional influence is a more insidious way to convince someone of something in general, and that religious teaching is highly practiced at wielding this tool. If you disagree with this assumption, then I can understand how this might be one of the roots of our disagreement about my original point.
3. I definitely agree with you about the issue regarding how the general population arrives at scientific knowledge. I want to focus on whether arriving at a "how" vs a "why" is different in the way you suggest. Let's take a different tack by considering ethics, which also focusses on the "why". For example, to answer "why is killing wrong?", I might say "because it deprives people of the liberty of life, because it relies on our more violent and evolutionarily ancient urges, because we see a cross-cultural revulsion to killing". These reasons can then be broken down into more specific questions, checked against each other for consistency, or reasoned out into a model for why killing is wrong. Can we not do all of these things with religious teachings? Taking Christianity as an example, can we not ask more specific questions of religious teachings, compare them to verses from the Bible for consistency, form a model out of different intetpretations of relevant Bible verses? (IIRC, this is pretty much what the field of Christian Ethics is). Do we not also use this approach in the sciences?
4. I think you might be misinterpreting what I meant in my quick point. The reason why I was comparing it to "objectively harmful beliefs" was not to say that they were likewise objectively harmful, but rather that the fact that since they can be justified the same way (ie. parents believe it is good) suggests that this is not a sufficient justification by itself. This makes no claim to the objective good or bad of religion.

Will edit this later to give this thread a delta for bringing up many well-reasoned points I didn't think about, though my view still isn't wholly changed. In any case, I'm glad we've been exploring this topic in a positive and civil manner :)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
