<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="726302567.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c0f6nb/cmv_childrens_exposure_to_religion_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Children's exposure to religion should be minimised</title>
    <original_poster>yup987</original_poster>
    <original_post>Disclaimer: I'm an atheist and generally anti-religious, so I'm obviously coming from a place of bias here. I will, however, try to make the arguments from the assumption that religion isn't all bad, that reasoned faith (as opposed to blind faith or faith solely based on emotion) in a religion is indeed an ideal. Reasoned faith (as I would define it, feel free to challenge this definition) is faith that is borne out of rational engagement with the dogma and knowledge of a given religion.

This view comes from my personal experience observing the activities of Christian Sunday schools. "Educational activities" usually involve drilling into children messages such as "I love Jesus" and "God is great", and children are encouraged by teachers and peers alike when they demonstrate a greater degree of fervent faith. I am arguing that such practices and other ways that children are exposed to religion, at best, teach children that blindly believing in their religion is an ideal, and at worst akin to brainwashing. Hopefully you fine redditors can broaden my view when it comes to other religions as well that I am less familiar with.

I have heard arguments from parents that their children want to go to church. And why wouldn't they? It'll make their parents happy seeing their child with such unshakeable conviction. Or they'll get to spend time with their friends. Children are not considered in the eyes of most laws globally to be able to give consent (in the broadest sense), or be held accountable and responsible for their actions. This is supported by our understanding of neurological development which tells us that a child's brain is vastly different from adult's. Given all these incentives to go to church unrelated to a commitment to recent faith, why should we bring the child to church, knowing that it will likely only develop their ability to blindly believe?

Thinking from the perspective of psychological development, we know that early childhood experience has a huge impact on behavior later in life. When we expose children to these beliefs with none of the nuance that accompanies (some) religious sermons and text, doesn't it make sense that many of these children will go on to believe that blind faith is the ideal, even if they're told otherwise as adults? We also see lots of children leaving religions as they mature, some comparing their childhood experiences with religion to brainwashing.

My policy proposal here is that children not be allowed to be involved with religion until they reach an age where they can make informed decisions regarding their beliefs (probably a recognised age of adulthood, although something as early as 16 might be safe). Failing that, some form of safeguards to ensure minimal appeals to emotion in any religious teachings directed at children.

I recognise the problem that you can't really insulate children from religion simply because religious parents will (consciously or otherwise) teach their children morals and beliefs linked to their religion. That's inevitable, but if we agree that children will have great difficulty taking up religion through reasoned faith, then the intent of my policy proposal still stands: minimising exposure of children to religion. I view organised religious activity as the best place to target.

In anticipation of those who might say that secularism is a religion too (thanks Naomi!), I acknowledge its history but will nonetheless assume it here to be the "default setting" (especially since many governments are secular) and argue that it occupies a neutral place in society.

Thanks for reading and I sincerely hope you can change my view!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32117116559.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>There are some major problems with your idea.
First is the blatant violation of the first amendment. "Government shall make no law regarding the establishment of religion." That would be a blatant government overstep and removal of our freedoms. Especially if you consider enforcement. 

The next big problem is there is no age at which some one can suddenly make an "informed" decision.  And here is what I mean,  we constantly change. And with that our beliefs and values.  I've seen rebellious kids come back when mature and the good religious kids drop it as adults.  And I've also seen adults drop and pick up religion as a kid life crisis.  There is no age of making informed decisions because what informs the decision is entirely subjective and constantly changing. 

Basically your position is that people shouldn't be allowed to believe anything until a random arbitrary age.  And you know that's ridiculous. And unenforceable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32118745915.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>IMO this is the core problem with the “don’t indoctrinate kids” argument. It would be über excessive entanglement at a personal level to actual enforce that no parent is teaching their kid religion in a way that violates the arbitrary rules laid out.

I take the position that whatever kids are taught, they eventually come to accept or reject what they were taught as they become conscious and active decision makers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32118755122.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with that.  But the Orwellian level government that these ideas mandate for implementation scare me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119318937.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>That's fair. I think I personally align more with "government should get involved where it would benefit people to do so".

I disagree that kids will eventually come to re-evaluate what they are taught when they grow up. Some kids certainly do, as evidenced by them leaving a religion, but I think it's generous of you to suggest that most people in a religion today are in no way influenced by the status quo of their childhood religious beliefs for why they stick with their religion today.

PS. Username checks out :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32120855901.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>This is probably where we disagree, but I’m not inclined to argue that a person believing (“going along with” more accurately) the religion they were taught is necessarily a bad thing. We all absorb influence from society—it’s impossible to truly be your own person in that you chose all of your beliefs from an impartial presentation without anyone’s influence.

I don’t know where you stand, and I’m not accusing you of anything, but to me it seems a lot of atheists feel they have a duty to “liberate” people from the “shackles” of religion/religious thought. The underlying belief of this is the idea that people should only have beliefs if they have chosen them or they can logically support them.

Personally, I understand this perspective, but I think it’s a bit overbearing or self-righteousness to argue that *every* person ought to agree with this. Most people simply don’t care enough to sort out and examine their beliefs. And unless it’s casual acceptance of violence or something, I see little reason to argue that this is wrong. I agree it’s *better* to have reasons why you believe in something, but I understand that most people are rather apathetic.

TL;DR my take on it is something like “if X bothers you, do your own thing, but arguing that *everyone* should be bothered by X can be problematic.”

Edit: the “would benefit to do so” is a vague criterion. There’s the concept of excessive entanglement from freedom of religion in schools which is a practical argument against this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32130728766.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;TL;DR my take on it is something like “if X bothers you, do your own thing, but arguing that everyone should be bothered by X can be problematic.”

Luckily religions do so too. They never object to things they are bothered by based on their religion, like evolution, homosexuality or abortion. Nor do they try to make laws based on those beliefs. So people believing a bronze age book does not influence the way the country is governed. /s


Personally I think you should look at the people that were raised in a religion and have a permanent fear of death. Religions like Christianity teach children to believe or burn forever. Believe and you will go to heaven. Of course there is no evidence for either these places, but young children are unable to realise this. OP wants to protect them from this emotional abuse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32130774109.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>That depends on what you consider “evidence,” but I made the point that children later can reexamine what they were taught when they get older. Honestly as a Christian myself I think Hell and brimstone “believe or be damned” teachings are seriously missing the point anyway and can be heavily criticized anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32130835538.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That depends on what you consider “evidence,”

Considering most religions can't even internally decide what is true, I don't think it depends.

&amp;gt;I made the point that children later can reexamine what they were taught when they get older.

And I make the point that this is hard to do of you are indoctrinated. The bible says that everything not professing Jesus is evil. If you are raised with that as truth, re-examining your beliefs feels as blasphemy and heresy, not as logical and critical analysis.

&amp;gt;Honestly as a Christian myself I think Hell and brimstone “believe or be damned” teachings are seriously missing the point anyway and can be heavily criticized anyway.

So if Christians can fix this among themselves, that would be great.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32131807563.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re putting too much emphasis on the “indoctrination” part. I was raised in a fairly conservative household and was “indoctrinated” by Sunday School, but as I’ve grown up I’ve had plenty of time and experience to think critically about my own beliefs. And if an “indoctrinated” person is happy believing in God, what exactly gives you the reason to impose your beliefs on that person? I’m a Christian but I’m friends with plenty of atheists. We can talk about religion in a respectful way even though we disagree on it.

I would argue that undoing any kind of “indoctrination” is one major function of public schools and universities: you can’t control how people raise their kids, because all parents try to pass on what they value to their children. But you can control what kids learn in schools, where they learn that the world is larger than what they know and there are many different beliefs out there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32132507637.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think you’re putting too much emphasis on the “indoctrination” part.

And I think you are putting too little emphasis on the indoctrination of vulnerable children part. This is where our viewpoints differ and I think we have to agree to disagree. If X is true, it's logical to teach X to your children. However if X is religion, I don't see enough evidence to accept it as true and  it should not be taught as such.

&amp;gt;And if an “indoctrinated” person is happy believing in God, what exactly gives you the reason to impose your beliefs on that person?

Do you care about what is true? I do, that is why I won't accept something as true without sufficient evidence. I'm not saying that God/god/gods don't exist, merely that I have yet to see sufficient evidence of one. However the moment you say "God exist and I know in my heart of hearts and nothing will convince me otherwise because I have faith" you are closing yourself from any new information and thereby the truth. I think this is harmful to society, as accepting one claim without sufficient reason, can lead to accepting other claims. (Such as young Earth)

Another way to look at it, if you had an incurable illness that would kill you in a year, would you want to know it? I would.

I merely ask them to substantiate their claim or acknowledge that they can't and treat it as such.

Also I gave a reason in my previous comment that you ignored, namely that their religion influences my life.

&amp;gt;I’m a Christian but I’m friends with plenty of atheists. We can talk about religion in a respectful way even though we disagree on it.

And I'm an (agnostic) atheist but I'm friends with plenty of Christians, Muslims and other religions. We can talk about religion in a respectful way even though we disagree on it. I don't see how this is relevant in regard to this CMV.

&amp;gt;I would argue that undoing any kind of “indoctrination” is one major function of public schools and universities

I agree, I also think schools should educate people more on the various religions. However children are very impressionable, see Santa Claus as an example. This CMV is that we shouldn't expose children to this indoctrination. Not expose them and maybe "fix" it later.

&amp;gt;you can’t control how people raise their kids

Which is why this is a mostly hypothetical debate/discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32132927978.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>I think the biggest disagreement is on what we consider truth and evidence—in my mind, faith is believing without seeing the proof.

That’s why I think it’s kind of missing the point when people demand to see scientific evidence for God—it’s a leap of faith that you are believing something is true that *can’t be proven by humans while we are living.* I think there’s a fundamental difference between believing in an afterlife and a judgement and believing the Earth is only 6,000 years old. You can prove the age of the Earth with science. You can’t prove Heaven and Hell with science or logic. That’s what makes it faith.

If that’s what you mean by substantiate it or acknowledge otherwise, I agree. I’m strongly secularist (separation of church and state, etc)  and not a huge fan of religious ritual. Most of the stuff we are presumably talking about like kids going to Sunday School doesn’t actually get you to Heaven either. It’s your personal faith that matters, and that can only come from making a conscious choice.

I actually agree with some of your criticism of religious “indoctrination” but for me it’s the *way* kids are taught about God is wrong, not that they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32133110842.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think the biggest disagreement is on what we consider truth and evidence—in my mind, faith is believing without seeing the proof.

By that definition, faith is believing without evidence, and as such unreasonable. To quote Matthew Dillahunty, I define faith as the reason people give when they don't have a reason, because if they did they would give that reason.

&amp;gt;it’s a leap of faith that you are believing something is true that can’t be proven by humans while we are living.

Why would you take that leap? Maybe this is because of my (atheist) upbringing, but I just can't understand why you would take something on faith. The best reason I found is a personal experience, but generally those have other explanations and aren't properly investigated.

&amp;gt;I think there’s a fundamental difference between believing in an afterlife and a judgement and believing the Earth is only 6,000 years old. You can prove the age of the Earth with science. You can’t prove Heaven and Hell with science or logic. That’s what makes it faith.

I don't think so. We have yet to see consciousness without a brain. When you die, your brain stops working. What of you remains? While this is not conclusive, it's an alternative hypothesis.

&amp;gt;I actually agree with some of your criticism of religious “indoctrination” but for me it’s the way kids are taught about God is wrong, not that they are.

Glad we can agree. I also want to stress that I'm not an anti-theist, nor do I think that religion is inherently evil. I just disagree with the methodology of religion, like taking things on faith.

Your statement raises the question, what is the correct way and how do we find it? Faith is not the answer, because you can take anything on faith. I would argue that the scientific method has proven to be the most reliable method we have to find the truth and/or described reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32133510290.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>So I draw a line between physical reality and metaphysics, which is the underlying cause of our disagreement. I believe that there are some questions that science and logic cannot answer.

Here’s why. It’s often accepted that science does not make moral judgments. Science can answer the how, but not the why. Science can tell me how I stay alive and that I have an evolutionary drive to eat, sleep, and mate, but it can’t tell me anything about my purpose in life beyond that. Same for everything: science can explain how the Earth formed and how the Big Bang happened, but they can’t answer why it happened—is there a purpose in everything existing? Science cannot answer a question like that because that’s not what it’s meant to do


“Truth” exists on two levels. There is physical truth and moral truth. When we’re searching for the physical truth of the world, I agree that science is the way to go. But with moral truth? Science doesn’t deal in morality, remember. Nor can it answer questions about purpose or anything beyond our comprehension.

The main assumptions I’m making are:

1. There ARE limits to what science can discover and to what humans can discover or comprehend

2. My life and the universe may well have a purpose beyond the material one, dictated by a creator

3. Physical truth and moral truth are fundamentally different and can’t be dealt with in the same way

When taking a leap of faith, I’m choosing to believe that there is more to my life, the universe, and existence than just what can be explained by my own eyes and scientific logic. I believe that I am more than a collection of tiny particles that wants to keep itself alive until it mates living in a universe formed from the probabilities of quantum fluctuations. I believe that humans have souls that are separate from their bodies, and that there is something after death. 

There are of course many potential answers to the challenges I’ve proposed, but I find the reductionist/nihilist view that is popular among atheists that we are nothing but matter governed by a random universe to be profoundly unsatisfying. I fully acknowledge that a statement like “God is beyond our comprehension” or “everything happens for a reason” sounds like a cop-out to a mindset that rejects faith.

I’m not going to pretend like I’m an expert, not a hypocrite, or that I’ve fully thought out all of my beliefs, but this is always my response to atheism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32133614547.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Science can answer the how, but not the why. 

This assumes there is a why. I think things have meanings because we treat them as such.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; When taking a leap of faith, I’m choosing to believe that there is more to my life, the universe, and existence than just what can be explained by my own eyes and scientific logic. 

I think I can agree and/or accept your points untill this point. The first issue I have here is that you still provide no reason to take this leap, other than wishfull thinking. The second issue is that there is no mechanism to determine moral truth, as opposed to the mechanism of the scientific method. Do you believe that moral truths are just opions or feelings? Is there a way to determine these truths?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; I believe that humans have souls that are separate from their bodies, and that there is something after death. 

So you keep explaining what you believe, but why do you believe it? Also could you please define what a soul is? I generally see it as a vague concept that covers what the brain does.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; There are of course many potential answers to the challenges I’ve proposed, but I find the reductionist/nihilist view that is popular among atheists that we are nothing but matter governed by a random universe to be profoundly unsatisfying. 

And I found the last season of Game of Thrones unsatisfying. Yet it is what it is. So we need reasons to believe what we believe or else we can just claim whatever we want. I want unlimited time to play D&amp;amp;D, that doesn't mean I have it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; I’m not going to pretend like I’m an expert, not a hypocrite, or that I’ve fully thought out all of my beliefs, but this is always my response to atheism. 

Forgive my ignorance, but I fail to see how this is an appropiate response. Modern atheism is defined as a lack of believe in a god. The way to adress this is to provide evidence. Merely asserting God exists, because it comforts you is not convincing without the previously mentioned indoctrination. How do I (or you for that matter) distinguish your faith from that of a Muslim, Hindu or a Neopagan? Add the other hundreds, if not thousands of religions, and you get my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32135330575.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, reasons. The problem is that faith isn’t about reasons, not in the sense I presume you mean. There a verse in the New Testament that encapsulates this.

“Faith is being sure of what we hope for. It is being certain of what we do not see.” Hebrews 11:1

Add that to the Christian perspective on moral truth:

“I am the way and the truth and the life. No one comes to the Father except through me.” John 14:6

As I’ve previously stated, building a scientific case for religious beliefs is missing the point. I think we’ll have to agree to disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32135446193.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are missing my point here. When you are born you don't have faith. So at a certain point you do get faith. Why? There has to be something, right? Even the bible says that you need a reason.

1 Peter 3: 15
&amp;gt;15 But in your hearts revere Christ as Lord. Always be prepared to give an answer to everyone who asks you to give the reason for the hope that you have. But do this with gentleness and respect,

I would definitely prefer a scientific case, but as you present it now, there is nothing but wishful thinking. That is delusional and should not be thought to anyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32135650768.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>The reasoning is exactly as I explained it: there is a higher power who created us with a purpose, and death is not the end. Faith is believing in that as it is described in the teachings of Jesus.

You can call this delusional, but again, science is incapable of “proving” things like this. That’s why “science can’t prove it so it’s wrong” is a flawed argument in my view. Any other proof I could offer is anecdotal (naturally, as faith is highly personal) which I recognize would not be accepted by you.

We obviously don’t see eye to eye about this, and that’s ok. What I do have a serious issue with though is mandating that faith and religion should not be taught to *anyone*. That’s a different discussion than the one we’ve been having. I find it distasteful because it is imposing your beliefs on everyone regardless of how they feel about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32135997044.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The reasoning is exactly as I explained it: there is a higher power who created us with a purpose, and death is not the end. Faith is believing in that as it is described in the teachings of Jesus.

That is not a reason, that is the claim. I ask why you claim it.


&amp;gt;Faith is believing in that as it is described in the teachings of Jesus.

I get that. So why do you have faith? Also how many miracles have you done? (John 14:12-14)


&amp;gt;You can call this delusional, but again, science is incapable of “proving” things like this. That’s why “science can’t prove it so it’s wrong” is a flawed argument in my view.

I already admitted that science can't prove everything. I already said that you don't need scientific proof. So please stop strawmanning me and provide the reason for your faith. Why do you have faith in Jesus and not in Odin? Somehow you made an assessment about this or you never thought about it.


&amp;gt;Any other proof I could offer is anecdotal (naturally, as faith is highly personal) which I recognize would not be accepted by you.

Why would you accept it? Do you accept the anecdotal evidence of a Muslim? We already know that personal testimony is flawed. How did you eliminate confirmation bias, hallucinations, misremembering and other factors? Is it repeatable or was it a one time thing?


&amp;gt;You can call this delusional, but again, science is incapable of “proving” things like this.

Science is not involved here. You make a claim, you have a burden of proof. Without science, your claims would still be unsupported.


&amp;gt;I find it distasteful because it is imposing your beliefs on everyone regardless of how they feel about it.

First off, what believe am I imposing? A lack of believe is not a belief, just like not playing a sport isn't a sport. I merely ask why you believe yours. I thinks empty and/or faulty claims should not be spread. If you have reason, I'm okay with it. We can disagree on the interpretation. Doesn't need to be scientific. Anything is better than nothing.

Secondly, when talking about truth, and by extension beliefs, feelings don't matter. No matter how I feel, grass will be green. No matter how I feel, an afterlife either exists or it doesn't. Claiming that it does exists, because it makes you feel good, gets you no closer to the truth. Empty claims should not be spread. Sorry if your feelings can't handle this, but this is what I mean by confirmation bias. In the end, this comes back to a question I asked previously. Do you care about the truth?


We can keep doing this, but I think it's very simple. My position is that I have yet to be convinced of any religions claims. To change this position, I would need to find evidence (in the broadest sense of the word) that would convince me.

You believe in the claims of Jesus, so I merely ask what convinced you. You dodge the question by claiming that it wouldn't convince me. So why did it convince you, if you think it wouldn't convince others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32140564470.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>I thought about it and here are the reasons I have, most of which depend on you accepting what is said about God in the Bible. I am merely explaining my beliefs, not arguing you should adopt them. In no particular order:

1. Truth
God is true. I do care about what is true. But all truth comes from God because God is true. I believe this is the Divine Command theory

2. Comfort
Life sucks and the world is broken. God promises comfort and hope in the darkness as well as purpose in the face of the void. God is my rock and comfort in the face of my troubles who gives me strength to overcome them.

3. Purpose
God created everything with a purpose that we can discover. Life has meaning because I am endowed with purpose from my Creator.

4. Afterlife
Death is not the end; the good will be rewarded and the evil will be damned. The only truth path to salvation is through relationship with Jesus Christ..

5. Love
God is love, so our ability to love comes from God as a reflection of our creator.

6. Goodness
God is good, and all that is good comes from and pleases God. God defines morality and is the ultimate judge of good and evil.

7. Creator
God is omnipresent and omnipotent, existing outside of time and space.  He created the universe—we can decipher HOW He did it, but I believe that the universe has a creator that purposefully made everything.

Ultimately these reasons depend on faith, not logic. One must be willing to accept that and venture into the unprovable. That is faith: believing without the assurance of human reason or logic.

Faith is fundamentally about surrendering control of your life to a higher power—I am admitting that I am flawed and broken, and cannot do things on my own. Science and society often supposes that humans can understand everything on the power of their own minds and bodies. Faith is about rejecting that and admitting that on our own we cannot do that—understandably unpalatable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32140653965.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>To adress your points briefly:

1. Claim, needs support
2. This is a reason. While anything could fill that role.
3. Claim, needs support. Second part is false, because atheist and people from other religions value life as well. Remember the Golden rule
4. Claim, also Jesus disagrees.
5. Claim, also brain chemistry. While we don't know everything about our brainchemistry, certain hormones are know to create bonding, such as oxytocin. (Primarily released during childbirth, breastfeeding and sex. It greatly causes bonding. When pregnant rats were given represants, the mothers displayed no motherly activity.)
6. Claim, and I happen to disagree with biblical morality and I hope you too. From a biblical standpoint, how many slaves should I have and what rod can you recommend to beat them. (Don't worry, I'll make sure they last a day or two)
7. Claim

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;I thought about it and here are the reasons I have, most of which depend on you accepting what is said about God in the Bible. 

Again, I feel like you miss my point. Most of the things you listed are claims made in the bible. I agree that if you accept the bible, those things should be true. What brought you to accept those claims over the ones of other religions? There are people that have faith in other deities. I don't ask what you believe, but why? What convinced you that the bible is true, other than being raised as such? 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think you summarized it the best. Faith is not rational or logical. If you don't have it, it's truly baffling why someone would. Those who have generally fail to convey why or what is good about it. I wonder, if we were created by a god, why would he give us the capabilities of reason and logic, while requiring us to abondon them to believe?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Also the divine command theory is that something is moral because God commands it. If God tells you to murder babies, that is moral because God said so. (like the Isrealians commiting genocide on the Medianites). Basically this is point 6.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32141370064.0" user="AntiFascist_Waffle" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think we’re going to make any headway here; I could write more about each point you raise, but frankly I feel I’ve presented as much as I can. There are others that could give better answers to your questions if you seek them, because this is not a new discussion.

 Agree to disagree but I appreciate the opportunity to examine my own beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32141775171.0" user="XePoJ-8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Agree to disagree but I appreciate the opportunity to examine my own beliefs.

I agree to disagree as well. Thanks for the conversation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119308530.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>The First Amendment is a uniquely American thing, and I wasn't specifically referring to America with this argument. But the intent behind it is well-taken, that we want to minimise government of religion. If, however, we take what I think is a fairly reasonable opposing view that people have the right to have freedom of choice of their religion, then my argument about children stands because it they would no longer be taking on the religious beliefs of their own free choice.

I do recognise the concern with the arbitrariness of the age. But laws do have to recognise a point at which a person has the ability to make informed decisions for themselves at some point - such as important medical decisions, or sexual consent - and clearly a two year old cannot do either of those things. So somewhere between an adult and a two year old lies the age that we start to trust people are making informed decisions. I am suggesting that religion, being an important decision, should be subject to that same policy regarding age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119321792.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>All those other things mentioned are activities,  things you do or have done to you.  Religion is different from those because it's about what you think and believe.  Your idea is realistically an attempt at making certain beliefs illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119417641.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>Don't these activities stem from beliefs? A 12 year old might think: "I like making people happy, and Teacher feels happy when I have sex with her". I'd argue we prevent children from making those decisions precisely because we are concerned about the beliefs those children have that influence their decision. Or we find that children's beliefs will change later on in life, that they'll come to regret the actions they took based on their beliefs as a child. Hence religious beliefs and thoughts are implicated as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119454465.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>Do you really need an explanation as to why there is a minimum age of consent for sex? Or what the difference between individual acts and beliefs are?

You admitted you have a bias. Are you going to let your bias force you into defending the completely false position of pedophilia being equivalent  to religious beliefs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119522083.0" user="yup987" delta="False">
    <text>You misunderstand my point. I'm simply pointing out here that when we set an age as a point at which children can make informed decisions, we are doing so because we are concerned with the beliefs underlying those decisions. Having sex with an adult isn't necessarily wrong, why we ban it is because we are concerned that children would not be doing so for the right reasons - or that children are unable to do so for the right reasons, because of emotional immaturity etc. I was simply setting up that obviously morally wrong example to demonstrate the reason why we set up a legal age in the first place.

I do hope my bias isn't coming into play here, I apologise if it has.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32119667889.0" user="direwolf106" delta="False">
    <text>See it really comes off as your bias coming into play.  The reason it does is because it's  blatantly false. 

Your point of lack of maturity is relevant to sexual acts and the like.

The reason it doesn't apply to religion is religion is belief.  People will always have a belief.  Where sexual acts can be traumatic, abusive, and life altering. 

Where the minimum age protects from mistakes, abuse,  and the like, a religion ban doesn't. 

I'm sure that's your intent,  but you're intent is an impossibility. And the attempt would result in massive oppression and abuse. You'd be creating abuse under the guise of preventing it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
