<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="740373078.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c8sriu/cmv_celebrities_rich_people_and_influencers_focus/">
    <title>CMV : celebrities, rich people and influencers focus on climate change and rarely on wages/inequality and that is fine with most governments because climate change is a vague long term issue that does NOT pressure current governments.</title>
    <original_poster>Flyingcar2077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Often, we hear about TV stars, movie stars, rich people, influencers making efforts or projects in order to tackle the climate change issue. Also, these people don't have a single clue about daily life of normal people, thus they wouldn't even think about taking about disfunctional public transports or low wages. 

Random activists also are given air time on big media when their fights are about climate change.

Protests on climate change are often encouraged and or seen as good by governments (I read an article explaining how the French government was fighting hard against the yellow vests protests - which are about wages, poverty, inequality - while AT THE SAME time let several huge protests about climate change doing their stuff in Paris, and the big pro government media in France were covering them in a positive way).

Even more, the yellow vests were also attacked with the argument that they are non environment friendly (the whole mess started with demands about gas prices). 

******'

My current ideas : there is a general consensus from western governments that protests about climate change are "harmless", they don't hit on the serious stuff (poor working people demand their government to stop pandering to their rich friends). As such, the whole narrative will shift and encourage media / global mind / trends to focus on "protesting climate change" instead of anything else.

I think that governments know that when "we" protests climate change we don't challenge our governments, we protest "the wind". 

In the near future, media and governments will push the narrative that the only valid protest is the one about climate change, if you protest anything else, you want to kill earth and bees. 

CMV Thx :=))</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32211085338.0" user="swalsh1114" delta="False">
    <text>Climate change was once a vague and far away problem, but no more. Think about the Paris accord. Countries are putting pressure on each other to implement specific and rapidly approaching goals. In the US, the Green New Deal has been a huge discussion topic among politicians for months; we've even got a democratic nominee basing their entire platform on climate change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32211191300.0" user="Flyingcar2077" delta="False">
    <text>No one is following these goals, such accords can be negated easily and removed.

Also while climate change is a serious ossue, the poor masses will suffer way before because of hardship.

No one living with minimum wage will choose to tackle climate change BEFORE  talking inequality. Nevertheless, governments and media and celebrities prefer to talk About climate.

Why did we have a Paris Accord, and no international conference about poverty and inequality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32212301183.0" user="KKRina" delta="False">
    <text>Both problems will probably never get enough spotlight and resolution like they should. But doing the little that we can to help ease poverty and give back can help. Whereas global warming is a much bigger factor. I am concerned about people losing their jobs and living on the street or in adverse situations. But let’s be reasonable, either you don’t understand how rapidly global warming is affecting us or you don’t seem it important. Because if we don’t deal with global warming, there will be no jobs or food for those poor people, or even fresh water for that matter. About 70% of the worlds fresh water lies in the big ice blocks that are currently melting and many of the species of animals that are dying are the same ones that help us humans by planting seeds for plants that we can eat.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
