<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="740373078.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/c8sriu/cmv_celebrities_rich_people_and_influencers_focus/">
    <title>CMV : celebrities, rich people and influencers focus on climate change and rarely on wages/inequality and that is fine with most governments because climate change is a vague long term issue that does NOT pressure current governments.</title>
    <original_poster>Flyingcar2077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Often, we hear about TV stars, movie stars, rich people, influencers making efforts or projects in order to tackle the climate change issue. Also, these people don't have a single clue about daily life of normal people, thus they wouldn't even think about taking about disfunctional public transports or low wages. 

Random activists also are given air time on big media when their fights are about climate change.

Protests on climate change are often encouraged and or seen as good by governments (I read an article explaining how the French government was fighting hard against the yellow vests protests - which are about wages, poverty, inequality - while AT THE SAME time let several huge protests about climate change doing their stuff in Paris, and the big pro government media in France were covering them in a positive way).

Even more, the yellow vests were also attacked with the argument that they are non environment friendly (the whole mess started with demands about gas prices). 

******'

My current ideas : there is a general consensus from western governments that protests about climate change are "harmless", they don't hit on the serious stuff (poor working people demand their government to stop pandering to their rich friends). As such, the whole narrative will shift and encourage media / global mind / trends to focus on "protesting climate change" instead of anything else.

I think that governments know that when "we" protests climate change we don't challenge our governments, we protest "the wind". 

In the near future, media and governments will push the narrative that the only valid protest is the one about climate change, if you protest anything else, you want to kill earth and bees. 

CMV Thx :=))</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32210963899.0" user="miguelguajiro" delta="False">
    <text>I think the issue is the specificity of demands and not the theme of the protests. Vague demonstrations about income inequality wouldn’t put a lot of pressure on governments either, whereas a specific movement, like the yellow vests, would.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32211162550.0" user="Flyingcar2077" delta="False">
    <text>I see... So it's more about the fact that climate change protests don't have very specific demands and deadline and less about the topic.

I would agree then. Thx</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
