<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32360813343.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I am a member of that sub and I do see some of them using really ugly words to describe kids. I usually skip past those posts because reading really angry stuff (on any sub) makes me feel unsettled and kind of sad. I suspect some of their anger is a result of the people in their lives who keep pressuring them to reproduce, and those feelings of anger get projected onto the beings (children) that they don't want to have. 

I don't use any ugly terms when speaking of kids. I don't hate kids, I just don't want to raise any of them myself. I'm 49 and have never done any babysitting and have never even changed a diaper and I don't want to, but I don't mind being in the presence of well-behaved kids whose parents do a good job supervising them in public. It doesn't affect my enjoyment of being in a store or restaurant etc just because kids are there. Some child free people DO feel that way, but I don't. In fact, my issue is more with parents who let them run wild and bother other people who are just trying to mind their own business and do their own thing. Children aren't born knowing good manners and knowing how to behave respectfully around others, so when kids behave like maniacs I don't blame the kids but the parents.

I know several couples whose small children are delightful. These parents are very diligent about monitoring their behavior and making sure they don't get in other people's personal space or try to grab things that don't belong to them. I respect parents who do this because they are raising good citizens and their kids will get along better in the world for having learned good manners and self-control and being taught to handle being told "no" from time to time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
