<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254409453.0" user="thirteenthfox2" delta="False">
    <text>r/childfree is a place to vent and not feel judged based on it. So yes if angry complaining is toxic to you then its toxic. It is a place to complain about things you cant really complain about in real life. It's not a debate sub it's a support sub, which is why when people try to argue against people's vents, they get banned/removed. The whole point is that the people there are allowed to vent without facing backlash in any way. 


The main arguement I have against it being a toxic sub is that you can sort out the rants. I recommend you try sorting by the rave tag or sorting out the rants if you do not like the complaining. They have a system in place for people to not view that content if they dont want to see it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254495628.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>I didnt know you could sort that stuff out thank you for that tip!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254544730.0" user="thirteenthfox2" delta="False">
    <text>There is also r/truechildfree which is much more discussion based and does not allow the epithets you mentioned. It's probably closer to something you are looking for if the ranting and humor turns you off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254554783.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah i saw that sub. Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32257561245.0" user="Irishman318" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The whole point is that the people there are allowed to vent without facing backlash in any way.

This is a double-edged sword. While it may be a place to vent, it's easy for that to slip into your belief system due to the only thing you see on that sub being vitriol towards children.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
