<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254478176.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254516458.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, and even when I see the rants I feel they are exaggerated to a degree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254555299.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/MugiwaraLee – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+MugiwaraLee&amp;amp;message=MugiwaraLee+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/-/etfhen4/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
