<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254254244.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254264156.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, they hate children to a degree I dont even know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254269940.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;online forums that are solely focused on opposition to something are at least a little fucked up.

Yes. This. And look at subs that *love* something. Generally super cool. Not a coincidence, I don't think.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254296499.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>Why are a bunch of coments getting removed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254344316.0" user="Exeter999" delta="False">
    <text>Based on your responses, it looks like they agreed with you. Top level comments have to challenge at least one part of your argument (it's in the rules)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254346343.0" user="AduItFemaleHuman" delta="False">
    <text>Hoooooly, that is a toxic sub. Comments are being removed because they don't challenge your post or are not meaningfully contributing. Kind of a hard view to change after a quick peek at that sub.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254311112.0" user="Ro-B0t" delta="False">
    <text>I think r/atheism is great example aswell because i feel it isn't about atheism any longer and more about hating on religions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254474700.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
