<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254335715.0" user="hurston" delta="False">
    <text>There is a different mindset amongst the child free, which is difficult to understand for people who like children. Take high pitched screaming. I think most of us can agree that high pitched screaming is unpleasant. When it comes to children however, this is somehow acceptable. Parent will say something like 'they can't help it', or 'they're just playing', or tell you off for complaining about the children. For those of us who don't hang around kids all the time, and can't tune out high pitched screaming through hundreds of hours of repetition, it can be quite painful. Not everyone can understand this though, so I will give you a comparable example to help you understand.

Imagine that random strangers occasionally punched you in the face in the street, and that this was socially acceptable. Imagine that if you complained, someone you know would apologise to the person who had punched you for your behaviour. Can you see how that might cause some resentment?

The sub is a support group. It's about letting off steam because people don't like being punched in the face, and the people who think punching is acceptable will never understand what it's like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254590325.0" user="giveme_moresleep" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding your "punch in the face" comment, I have worked for years with people with behavior issues and/or intellectual disabilities. Sometimes, they would do things like punch someone in the face. Now, these people I took care of would not get a punishment for such behavior like I would if I had done the same thing. there are different standards, and that's fine. I'm not saying that there were no repercussions at all, but they weren't as great. The same goes for children. We are supposed to teach them right from wrong, but they don't just come out of the womb knowing what society expects of them. So if a child is screaming, especially a toddler, it's just because they haven't learned any better yet.
Now I understand if some of these people on child-free get upset when a kid who is old enough to know better is acting like a little asshole, but what gets me is when they're angry at small children. Angry. I'm sorry that's weird. We were all children once, and someone had patience with us</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254802094.0" user="hurston" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; We were all children once, and someone had patience with us

This is another variant on "they can't help it". It doesn't matter that they can't help it, screaming/punching is still painful. It is a choice to have children and it is also a choice to inflict those children on people around you. Most of the rants on the childfree sub are about parents who are making no attempt to teach their children right from wrong, when it is obviously a situation when they should be. This is quite common behavior, hence the need for a support group for people who are not so jaded that this behavior has become somehow acceptable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255100182.0" user="giveme_moresleep" delta="False">
    <text>This is not meant as an attack whatsoever, but stating "inflicting those children on people around you" seems callous. It reminds me of when I was told by people in the general public that I shouldn't take people with intellectual disabilities out of their homes. Exactly how is someone supposed to learn societal expectations if there never out in society? I understand that there are places that are not appropriate for children, (or perhaps for those with intellectual disabilities) but how are these children supposed to learn if they're locked away?

The only way to teach children how to behave is to put them in situations where it's required of them. I personally don't want to hear a child screaming in the movie theater, which is why I don't usually take small children to movies that won't entertain them. But if you never take them to the movies, they won't know how to act.

The main issue that I have with the child free subreddit is that some of these people act like children shouldn't be let out in society whatsoever.  I have child-free friends that enjoy my children up to a point. And I understand that and respect it. I know a lot of parents don't, but I don't understand the hate on that subreddit toward children and not so much at the parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255201036.0" user="hurston" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but stating "inflicting those children on people around you" seems callous

And yet that is how it feels. I know you don't understand what it's like to feel like this. Faced with a society that thinks a screaming child is acceptable, we have nowhere else to turn. That is why there is a subreddit to vent frustration. I know they need to learn. It's irrelevant to how painful it is, because we are not accustomed to it, or we have misophonia, or we are not dosed up on enough hormones to take the edge off of it.

As to the hate of the children, it's quite reasonable. If someone punches you in the face repeatedly, and society says it's ok, you are going to hate them. How is that unreasonable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255235790.0" user="giveme_moresleep" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not trying to be rude, but are there children punching you in the face? If so, I think that the proper authorities need to be called, because most likely children like that are being abused in the home. If this is just an antidote, I'm sorry if having children around feels like a punch in the face. Again, not trying to be rude, but have you tried wearing headphones in public? Because that's the only way I can survive places like Walmart, and I do have children. So I do understand how maddening it can be. We cannot change every parent, and if those parents are awful we certainly can't change the children. But hopefully, those children will be surrounded by enough people who are supportive that they will turn into productive members of society.

And I know wearing headphones isn't the be all answer here, I'm just trying to help a little</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255285963.0" user="hurston" delta="False">
    <text>It's a useful metaphor, to help explain what it feels like to those who don't have the same experience of children as us, as it is difficult for people to understand how bad it is. Even headphones are not enough to drown out all of the screaming. Through punishment reinforcement, even the presence of children who are not screaming is uncomfortable, in the same way as being in the same room as someone who has punched you a couple of hundred times would be uncomfortable.

Your username is very relevant. Nice one!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255302502.0" user="giveme_moresleep" delta="False">
    <text>By the way, I enjoyed our little debate. It's not often that you get two people on the internet with some opposing views still being decent to each other.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
