<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254380240.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254420344.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure I understand your comment? I don't care that they are child free, I just think they are overly toxic of children in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254437644.0" user="johnnyhavok2" delta="False">
    <text>And that matters to anyone else because...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254487259.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254522100.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>Okay I'm being respectful and having a nice debate. dont get your panties in a knot. Theres no need.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254558886.0" user="Betterzen" delta="False">
    <text>You are neither and funnily the next thing you do is tell me what i am to do. The only problem here is your need to attitude police others - maybe this is the general problem here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254564558.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>Ok bud</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255844918.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>u/Betterzen – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+Betterzen&amp;amp;message=Betterzen+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/-/etfhlnf/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254552344.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>Why does a person need to like kids? I don't hate kids but think its hard to deny that they are dirty, loud, and require a ton of attention. For some reason society tends to give them a pass, and its considered taboo to even point out the negative qualities of children. 

They aren't sacred, and our culture would be improved if we stopped treating them as such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254856341.0" user="DocGlabella" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is important.  It really seems like a matter of word choice.  OP is calling it “toxic” to genuinely not like children.  r/childfree thinks there should be a space in society for people who genuinely don’t like kids. 

I’ll put it this way— I once stumbled on a sub for people who don’t like dogs.  I was shocked.  They called dogs all sorts of horrible things.  And I LOVE dogs.  But did I think it was toxic? No, because there is nothing in society that teaches us that dogs are sacred creatures that everyone must treasure or risk of being a bad person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254946919.0" user="Madauras" delta="False">
    <text>I don't use the phrase toxic and it confuses me somewhat, but I think you hit they nail on the head. I think the case for dogs being awesome is a lot clearer than the case for kids, especially under 5, is far weaker. However, simply stating, I think kids are annoying and overrated, gets met with shock and derision. 

I'm glad r/childfree is there to provide a space for people that don't fit the societal norm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255847191.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>u/Betterzen – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+Betterzen&amp;amp;message=Betterzen+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/-/etffb2o/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
