<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254281940.0" user="jt4" delta="False">
    <text>While I agree that it's toxic, I'd like to ask you what you feel /r/childfree should be talking about, if not about how the members don't like kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254292621.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>Something more productive that just straight up hating on children, maybe the stories could actually show something annoying that happened with chuldrem and not just hate on children that are near them. And they could just be less judgemental and respect other people opinions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254323109.0" user="jt4" delta="False">
    <text>I checked the top links on Childfree and many of them are memes (often about abortion), but a few stuck out to me: a story of an 85-year old childless woman, celebrations of childless Jennifer Aniston and Betty White, and a post complaining about the hateful comments on the sub. From reading through theses posts it's clear the members feel the rest of the world is judging them based on their choice not to have children, and that their opinion is not respected. And often when we don't get respect, we don't give respect back.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254541583.0" user="DocGlabella" delta="False">
    <text>A lot of the posts I have read are celebrations of how much they are enjoying their lives without children.   “On an amazing vacation that I couldn’t have afforded with kids!” and “came home drunk and about to have sex with my wife on the floor— couldn’t do that with kids!”  They are positive affirmations of a certain life style.   Now you might think of that as “being drunk all the time” and not want that lifestyle, but it’s certainly positive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254309802.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>Not having kids is not the same as not liking kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254370140.0" user="GfxJG" delta="False">
    <text>I'm Childfree, I fucking love kids! I just don't want them myself. Those 2 things are aboslutely not the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254432082.0" user="ImagineTheMammoth" delta="False">
    <text>May I just point out: I myself don't ever want to have children. I have several reasons for it and "hating children" is not one of them. I'm not gonna pretend I'm crazy about them, but to be fair I'm not crazy about most humans regardless of age. I have no problem to hang out with kids though or a problem with their existence, lol. Yes, there are children that are brats and terrible, but there are also adults that are those things and both are people I would avoid contact if I can. There are others that are actually pretty cool (both kids and adults)

So if I may answer your question (I don't participate in that particular sub because honestly find the title "child free" really silly). I would guess to be a supportive group for people that suffer pressure about this choice from their partners -- which I feel like if they are not okay with this, should not be their partner, but that's a whole another thing --, parents, even friends who all think can have an opinion and that think the person will eventually change their mind (which is fine if they do, is not fine to not respect that they made the choice in the first place). I also would expect help to keep an unplanned pregnancy to happen. As well talks in general about it and yeah, probably a meme here and there similar with Ellens joke "That's why I don't have kids".

Anyway, I don't know the sub and it's really possible to be just a hate group for kids, but I guess I just got a bit offended that you imply that people that don't want children = people that hate all kids. Which it may not even be your intention but it is a common misconception .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254468755.0" user="UnauthorizedUsername" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, there are some people on childfree who *hate* children, but I think the majority of it is people who hate that people keep pushing the idea that they *should* want children.

As a member of the sub myself, albeit one who mostly lurks and has very rarely posted there, I fall into that second group.  I don't hate children -- I have a few friends that have great kids, and I like playing with/hanging out with them from time to time.  I just hate that I'm expected to *want* children, and that it's expected that my or my wife's only  duty in life is to have kids.  Like, once you finish school, get married, and get a career, your life for *you* is over and it's time to dedicate yourself to raising a child for 18 years.  No, dammit, I want to enjoy all this shit I worked hard to get!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254439011.0" user="PhasmaFelis" delta="False">
    <text>This is one reason it's unfortunate that Reddit has displaced traditional web forums, IMO. Usually a forum dedicated to a specific topic would have at least one off-topic subforum where you can just shoot the shit about whatever, with the comfort of knowing that you have something in common with the people you're chatting with. Reddit subs *can* have a secondary off-topic sub, but most of them *don't,* so they tend to devolve into "who is most passionate about this topic" contests because there's nothing else to talk about, and that leads to extreme viewpoints.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
