<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254298211.0" user="Nicolasv2" delta="False">
    <text>Well, I find it pretty good that this kind of people motivate each other to avoid having kids, because clearly, they would be terrible parents. 

That plus the fact that the planet is already pretty crowded, and I find it good that people spread "anti-kids propaganda", it may counter-balance a bit the "God want you to have 15 kids" dogma on the opposite of the spectrum.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254307552.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>A few people deciding not to have kids isnt going to do anything for the planet. But I can see your argument, they most likely would be terrible parents as I keep on seeing posts about the just being drunk constantly.

Edit: Spelling</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254362844.0" user="Rpgwaiter" delta="False">
    <text>Every little bit helps my dude</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255761338.0" user="TotOverTime" delta="False">
    <text>There are a tonne of terrible parents out there. Difference is child free arnt making a child suffer their terrible parenting...parents are doing that. So what's with this fantasy "oh well you'd be terrible parents anyways!" When we literally arnt contributing to kids being brought up by terrible parents? Think that's some weird psychology to make us feel bad about not being good at something we don't want to do? Even though our standard of parenting is very high.

"That's okay...you'd be a terrible piano player anyways" "but I don't want to play the piano?"

Also I'm child free and I know I'd be a better parent than alot of parents I see. I just don't want to. 

Oh and I used to bar tend, parents also get drunk alot and leave their kids sat bored in the bar corner. Aswell as say how they can't afford much for their kids but they drink and smoke.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254385728.0" user="librarycynic" delta="False">
    <text>But isn't that how you get Idiocracy to become a documentary?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254398855.0" user="Nicolasv2" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, Idiocracy make all idiots reproduce till the end of the world. 

Childfree make some idiots stop reproducing, so we are slowing down our race toward Idiocracy world :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254640125.0" user="DankDoggos84" delta="False">
    <text>As a childfree person I'll confirm that I would be a terrible parent and that many of us know that we would be terrible parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254680613.0" user="Nicolasv2" delta="False">
    <text>So knowing that being childfree is possible and there are people like you may help you to resist the social imperative to do kids and avoid being a terrible parent which is a good thing, isn't it ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254727258.0" user="DankDoggos84" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it's definitely a good thing. I've known that I don't want to have kids ever since I was a kid but before going onto reddit I had never met anyone that shared my views and fully supported me. Also there are alot of posts on there from people that are going through rough times with being childfree from people being shitty or there partner changing there mind or revealing that they weren't really childfree. People post these stories from their life to get advice or support and  /childfree is the only place to voice those problems safely which is a good thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
