<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254961134.0" user="GreatswordIsGreat" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like r/MGTOW</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254963352.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254999838.0" user="GreatswordIsGreat" delta="False">
    <text>Incels pretending not to care and hating women</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255193952.0" user="garnteller" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/SosRashneer – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+SosRashneer&amp;amp;message=SosRashneer+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/-/etfrt08/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
