<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254590661.0" user="TotOverTime" delta="False">
    <text>I'm on child free and I do see these toxic posts and generally I put my two cents in to say how child free and child hating arnt the same thing.

I'm child free and am great with kids (I baby sit alot) and have good standards for how I think children should be raised.

I have raised the issue in child free about how blatant child hating isnt taken down as soon as possible. That being said I find people with these nasty ideals tend to be more active commenters rather than your average person who reads over and moves on. I find myself and others use child free posts as a reminder as to why we don't want children when you've maybe had a day of being pressured or that FOMO setting in.

At the end of the day though it is freedom of speech. Do I like people referring to kids as crotch goblins? No. Do I like people thinking I'm a child hater because I don't want kids? No. 

I find that child free people (not child haters) actually have better standards of how children should be raised as a group. Many posts on people furious that a friend/relative is choosing to have a child when they cannot afford/have a stable home life. When you see people complain "they came to my house and broke my shit!" It's not just about the material possession but about the fact this child who will one day grow into a adult and a member of society isn't being taught respect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255189692.0" user="giveme_moresleep" delta="False">
    <text>My best friend is child free and happy as a clam. I have more children (mine and adopted/taken into my home) than any sane human should have.  My  best friend thinks I'm nuts. She does not hate my kids, however, but she does not have The same tolerance that I do. I understand and respect that. She will watch my kids, and she loves them, but she certainly doesn't want to live with them. we both just have different views and that's okay.

Her attitude is a lot like yours, and I feel like everyone could reach a middle ground. now I understand being frustrated and angry at horrible parents. But it's hard hearing so much hatred directed at children. I think that's my problem with the subreddit. I know it's not everyone on child free, but it's enough that it's disturbing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32255240418.0" user="TotOverTime" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. I find people with the more messed up thoughts and approaches need to get that validation online because they can't in decent company in real life, thus their the loudest and most talkative. 

I did once think maybe a child hating sub reddit would be a better place for them to go but to be honest I'd rather their in child free. A child hating only sub reddit would be just a huge echo chamber and I fear would make these people worse and more intolerant. At least on child free they are usually met with resistance and sane opinions. Sadly all subs have their assholes. 

Plus these child haters I don't think are -just- intolerant to kids. I feel people with these strong opinions don't like anyone and kids are just one of their targets. All around just assholes in general to everyone who doesn't fit their ideals. 

So yeah we'll never be rid of them but if people do come to reddits and take the bad posts and ignore the mostly good posts as a blanket statement for all of us then their not much of a better person.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
