<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254355165.0" user="UnauthorizedUsername" delta="False">
    <text>While it seems a bit toxic at times, you have to remember that for a lot of people, it's a go-to place for them to vent after they've been hit with yet *another* "when are you having children?" or "well, you'll change your mind *when you get older*" or "what if you meet a man who wants to have kids?" or "you don't really *understand* because you don't have children" and so on.

The issue is that, especially for women, the cultural expectation is that they should *want* to have children, and that if they don't, either they'll change their minds or something is wrong with them.  Any time they express that they're not interested, their opinion and agency are invalidated because "why wouldn't anyone want children?"  

So going to the childfree subreddit is a way to vent some of that stress that builds up.  It's going to be a little angry, it's going to be 'toxic', but it's not meant as a discussion subreddit -- it's meant as a place to meme and shitpost about yet another moment that someone didn't take you seriously about not wanting kids.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254459766.0" user="Oreoloveboss" delta="False">
    <text>Every girl in their 20s also gets hit with the 'you're running out of time' or 'your biological clock is ticking' as if their only reason for existing is to incubate babies.

Men never get asked these questions, and if they do they can just be shrugged off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32257377078.0" user="DexFulco" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Men never get asked these questions, and if they do they can just be shrugged off.     

That's a generalization if I've ever seen one. I'm a guy and get the "when are you going to have children" *every* single time I see my mother's family side.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32259250484.0" user="Oreoloveboss" delta="False">
    <text>I get it a lot too, I just say when I want.

When my girlfriend gets asked it, she's told that she 'doesn't have much time left'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32275444375.0" user="_KONKOLA_" delta="False">
    <text>Be honest though, it's mainly women who ask.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32261460018.0" user="Raszagil" delta="False">
    <text>This.

I used to post on that sub almost daily for awhile, back when I lived near family and *every single damned time* I visited them I would be harassed about having kids. After we moved away the stress magically vanished and I stopped visiting that sub because I no longer needed it to detox, but it definitely has value as a place to rant.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
