<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32285033445.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; CMV: The USG can’t stop **all of us**, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action


&amp;amp;nbsp;


The problem with your plan is that **"all of us"** is not a united group of people.  If **"all of us"** were on the same page we wouldn't need a revolution in the 1st place, because **"all of us"** would have a voting supermajority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285976900.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>Medicare for all and the green new deal both have supermajority support, yet neither is being instituted. Our electoral system is broken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286233669.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>As a Democrat who personally supports Bernie's Medicare for all plan, I don't believe there is a supermajority of Americains who support Medicare for all. This democratic primary (2019-20) is the first time a majority of the candidates support it. 

&amp;amp;nbsp;

Our system has serious flaws, but it's not completely 'broken'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286251308.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>Factually, the overwhelming majority of all Americans support universal healthcare and have for a long time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286291440.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>See this highlights my point perfectly. The other
 commenter said Medicare for all, now you're saying Universal healthcare.

&amp;amp;nbsp;

Yes Medicare for all gives us universal healthcare. But universal healthcare does not necessarily mean Medicare for all. 

&amp;amp;nbsp;

You can see just in the current primary that all democratic candidates belive in universal healthcare but not all of them support Medicare for all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286315738.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>What difference do you think there is? first result when googling universal healthcare: "Universal health care is a system that provides quality medical services to all citizens. The federal government offers it to everyone regardless of their ability to pay."

also, the candidates might *say* they "support" universal healthcare, but the only person who has said "we need it right now and that's what I'm going to fight for" is bernie sanders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286485179.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>Just look at the Europe, you can easily see there are many different versions of universal healthcare. The UK and Germany are stong contrasts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286606935.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>so whats your point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286675828.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand your question. You asked what the difference between Medicare for all and Universal healthcare is. Europe is full of examples of universal healthcare that are different from Medicare for all. For example both the UK and Germany have universal healthcare. But Germany is a multi payer insurance system and multi provider. The UK in comparison is a nationalized health care system with single payer and single provider. Bernie's Medicare for all is a single payer multi provider system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286693263.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>well, no, my thing was correcting you that the majority of people want it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286718847.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>Where in you post did you say the majority support It?

&amp;gt; What difference do you think there is? first result when googling universal healthcare: "Universal health care is a system that provides quality medical services to all citizens. The federal government offers it to everyone regardless of their ability to pay."

&amp;gt; also, the candidates might *say* they "support" universal healthcare, but the only person who has said "we need it right now and that's what I'm going to fight for" is bernie sanders.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286969579.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Factually, the overwhelming majority of all Americans support universal healthcare and have for a long time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287095683.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>Okay I see we got of track. It's getting late for me so I'll leave you with a copy of a comment I posted in response to someone else making a similer point. 

&amp;amp;nbsp;

I wish it was that simple. In my perfect world Bernie would win and get Medicare for all passed. But it's more complicated. Small changes in how you word the question give massively different results. https://www.realclearpolitics.com/articles/2019/05/15/poll_medicare_for_all_support_is_high__but_complicated_140327.html

&amp;amp;nbsp;

&amp;gt; “Do you support or oppose Medicare for All, which is a system that will eliminate all private health insurance companies, and where all Americans, not just older ones, get health insurance through the government’s Medicare system?” Even with that caveat, 55% were in support, with 34% opposed.

&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now you can bet that come election season when the GOP is ~~lying~~ campaigning, they will be screaming about raised taxes and death panels just like they did with the Affordable care act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287108258.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I wish it was that simple. In my perfect world Bernie would win and get Medicare for all passed.

THEN JUST SUPPORT HIM. HAVE A FUCKING SPINE. DO YOU THINK THE REPUBLICANS COMPROMISE ON WHAT THEY WANT? YOU WANT MEDICARE FOR ALL, JOIN US! STAND HAND IN HAND WITH US AND DEMAND IT! WE CAN GET MEDICARE FOR ALL, BUT NOT IF WE KEEP COMPROMISING OUR DEMANDS BEFORE WE GET ANY PUSHBACK! JOIN THE SIDE YOU WANT TO BE ON</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286266491.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>70% of Americans support Medicare for all. 

https://thehill.com/hilltv/what-americas-thinking/412545-70-percent-of-americans-support-medicare-for-all-health-care</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286588905.0" user="keanwood" delta="False">
    <text>I wish it was that simple. In my perfect world Bernie would win and get Medicare for all passed. But it's more complicated. Small changes in how you word the question give massively different results. https://www.realclearpolitics.com/articles/2019/05/15/poll_medicare_for_all_support_is_high__but_complicated_140327.html

&amp;amp;nbsp;

&amp;gt; “Do you support or oppose Medicare for All, which is a system that will eliminate all private health insurance companies, and where all Americans, not just older ones, get health insurance through the government’s Medicare system?” Even with that caveat, 55% were in support, with 34% opposed.

&amp;amp;nbsp;

Now you can bet that come election season when the GOP is ~~lying~~ campaigning, they will be screaming about raised taxes and death panels just like they did with the Affordable care act.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286719354.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>Even by the lowest polls it's still above water by 5%.

Republicans changing minds by lying is exactly what I mean when I say the electoral system is broken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286602388.0" user="rollingrock16" delta="False">
    <text>Until you start asking the questuon with various details.

&amp;gt;But if they were told that a government-run system could lead to delays in getting care or higher taxes, support plunged to 26 percent and 37 percent, respectively. Support fell to 32 percent if it would threaten the current Medicare program.

https://www.apnews.com/4516833e7fb644c9aa8bcc11048b2169

Medicare for all sounds great as a slogan.   The devil is in the details and i highly doubt 70 percent would support the eventual bill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286709340.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>When you lie to people about Medicare, their support drops. Weird.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286819248.0" user="rollingrock16" delta="False">
    <text>No lies that i can see.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286868907.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>Medicare for all doesn't "threaten the current Medicare system." What would that even mean? 

We could pay for Medicare for all without taxing most Americans another cent. M4a would save Americans trillions by eliminating private healthcare costs, meaning any extra tax would be more than eclipsed.

Wait times don't increase in single payer systems once you count private insurance appointment scheduling as a "wait time."

Somehow, every other developed country on earth guarantees healthcare. Every single payer system on earth is wildly popular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286988177.0" user="rollingrock16" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Medicare for all doesn't "threaten the current Medicare system." What would that even mean? 

If it wholesale replaces the existing program with a new program i could see people not supporting that.

&amp;gt;We could pay for Medicare for all without taxing most Americans another cent. 

That is absurd.  Id love to see your numbers.

&amp;gt;M4a would save Americans trillions by eliminating private healthcare costs, meaning any extra tax would be more than eclipsed.

How does eliminating private costs save any money?

&amp;gt;Wait times don't increase in single payer systems once you count private insurance appointment scheduling as a "wait time."

Many single payer systems suffer from wait time issues especially with specialists.  You are not going to handwave that concern away.

&amp;gt;Somehow, every other developed country on earth guarantees healthcare. 

Yet the solutions to that vary quite a bit.  Not everyone has single payer or M4A type systems.  This point says absolutely nothing about M4A.

&amp;gt;Every single payer system on earth is wildly popular.

I doubt that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287085535.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>Expanding Medicare for all wouldn't endanger it. That's plainly absurd. 

Sanders plan would cost just over 1 trillion a year:

https://www.crfb.org/blogs/how-much-will-medicare-all-cost

Americans pay almost 1 trillion a year for private healthcare:

https://www.pbs.org/newshour/economy/making-sense/how-americans-spend-much-more-on-health-care-than-they-realize

The military budget is 800 billion a year. 

This means we could pay for m4a easily by cutting military spending and taxing people well under their current premiums, saving them money overall. Sanders' plan hardly taxes the middle class and lower:

https://www.vox.com/2019/4/10/18304448/bernie-sanders-medicare-for-all

&amp;gt;Many single payer systems suffer from wait time issues especially with specialists.  You are not going to handwave that concern away.

So does current insurance. Besides, 44% of Americans don't go to the doctor because they can't afford to. I think people would rather wait for guaranteed care than not go to the doctor at all. The only reason they wouldn't is because talking heads pretend Canadians die waiting for healthcare. 

An example of how popular single payer is is the NHS. 66% of UK citizens consider it their country's greatest achievement. 

https://www.theguardian.com/society/2018/jul/02/is-the-nhs-the-worlds-best-healthcare-system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287190063.0" user="rollingrock16" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;Sanders plan would cost just over 1 trillion a year:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;https://www.crfb.org/blogs/how-much-will-medicare-all-cost

You mean Sanders says it will cost that much.  Reading through your source shows that is extremely optimistic.  Plus from the source Sanders plan calls for 11 trillion in new taxes so i really dont get how you think this source supports your premise that taxes will not go up.

&amp;gt;Americans pay almost 1 trillion a year for private healthcare:
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/economy/making-sense/how-americans-spend-much-more-on-health-care-than-they-realize

This is misleading.  That is just the cost consumers spent.   That completely ignores private plans paying out another trillion.

&amp;gt;The military budget is 800 billion a year. 
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;This means we could pay for m4a easily by cutting military spending and taxing people well under their current premiums, saving them money overall. Sanders' plan hardly taxes the middle class and lower:

Again im not seeing actual numbers here so this seems wishful thinking at best.   Plus this thread was about popular support for the plan.  Start cutting military funding and watch those poll numbers you tout drop like a rock

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Many single payer systems suffer from wait time issues especially with specialists.  You are not going to handwave that concern away.
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;So does current insurance.

Not really.

 Besides, 44% of Americans don't go to the doctor because they can't afford to.

Source?

&amp;gt;An example of how popular single payer is is the NHS. 66% of UK citizens consider it their country's greatest achievement. 
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2018/jul/02/is-the-nhs-the-worlds-best-healthcare-system

A cherry picked poll on one nation's system is not really support for your previous claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287286807.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.forbes.com/sites/brucejapsen/2018/03/26/poll-44-of-americans-skip-doctor-visits-due-to-cost/

The cost to consumers is exactly the point. If Americans don't have to pay for healthcare, they could pay higher taxes and still save money. 

The cost estimate comes from the congressional budget office, not Sanders himself. 

Here's a good breakdown of the wait time lie: https://askepticalhuman.com/politics/2018/9/10/debunking-right-wing-healthcare-myths-wait-times-rationing

NHS popularity isn't cherry picked, it's just the first system that came to mind. 80% of canadians support expanding their single payer system: https://www.healthcare-now.org/blog/new-poll-shows-canadians-overwhelmingly-support-public-health-care/


I can't find polls for Australia or Finland, but Business Insider published some very positive testimonials. If you can find a poll showing single payer to be unpopular in any country it's been tried in, I welcome you. I suspect that won't be possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287457472.0" user="rollingrock16" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;https://www.forbes.com/sites/brucejapsen/2018/03/26/poll-44-of-americans-skip-doctor-visits-due-to-cost/
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;The cost to consumers is exactly the point. If Americans don't have to pay for healthcare, they could pay higher taxes and still save money. 

You realize private plan spending still needs to be accounted for right?  It just doesnt go away.  Where do you think that money covering that cost currently comes from?

&amp;gt;The cost estimate comes from the congressional budget office, not Sanders himself. 

No it doesnt.   From your source.

&amp;gt;While the campaign itself estimated that plan would cost the federal government about $14 trillion over a decade, most other estimates that we are aware of are at least twice that high.

I dont see anywhere where you figure is quoted as coming from the cbo.  What am i missing?

&amp;gt;Here's a good breakdown of the wait time lie: https://askepticalhuman.com/politics/2018/9/10/debunking-right-wing-healthcare-myths-wait-times-rationing

That page is ridiculously biased.   Sorry not worth my time to go through that.


&amp;gt;I can't find polls for Australia or Finland, but Business Insider published some very positive testimonials. If you can find a poll showing single payer to be unpopular in any country it's been tried in, I welcome you. I suspect that won't be possible.

I looked briefly.  Surprisingly there doesnt seem to be a wealth of polling out there.   Closest i found to anything comprehensive is this.

https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/news-polls/global-views-healthcare-2018

I cant say this paints a picture of "wildly popular" but several single payer countries get good marks.   So fair enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287553239.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>
If people stop privately spending on healthcare, they save that money. I'm convinced you're intentionally misunderstanding me.

My source says Sanders m4a bill was estimated at 14 trillion for the first decade. That bill gets costed by the budget office. 

The page might be biased, but the facts aren't. And honestly, if I applied your standard to you, you wouldn't be worth my time. You have a clear bias and have provided exactly 2 sources for your claims. 

You dropped the first claim about harming Medicare, and somewhat conceded the last. Even if you disagree with me about everything else, that means 2 of the 4 caveats your poll introduced to Medicare are misleading.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287747946.0" user="rollingrock16" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If people stop privately spending on healthcare, they save that money. I'm convinced you're intentionally misunderstanding me.

You say Americans spend 1 trillion on healthcare.   That is simply not true unless you think somehow that the spending that private plans spend which obviously includes employer paid benefits doesn't count as Americans spending money on healthcare.

&amp;gt;My source says Sanders m4a bill was estimated at 14 trillion for the first decade. That bill gets costed by the budget office.

No you source plainly says that Sanders's campaign estimates that cost.   The budget office did not come up with the 14 trillion dollar figure anywhere that I can see.  Plus your own source says that other estimates that have costed it have put it twice as much.

&amp;gt;The page might be biased, but the facts aren't. And honestly, if I applied your standard to you, you wouldn't be worth my time. You have a clear bias and have provided exactly 2 sources for your claims.

This is me and you talking.   We're both allowed and expected to be biased.   If i gave you a source from Crowder or Rush Limbaugh to support my point I would expect a similar response from you.  To put it frankly I do not trust that this person is sourcing his facts accurately and am not inclined to spend the time to check him.

&amp;gt;You dropped the first claim about harming Medicare, 

I didn't drop it.   Your point added nothing for me to respond to.   If you can't see how some people would not want their current plan to change and could see it as a threat then I don't know what else I could say.    You obviously think M4A would be better but someone that is happy with their current plan may not agree.

&amp;gt;Even if you disagree with me about everything else, that means 2 of the 4 caveats your poll introduced to Medicare are misleading.

I wouldn't say I conceded the point.   You never backed up your original large claim.   There just seems to be insufficient data that is quickly accessible to make it worth debating.  Further I do not know what that has to do with my original poll or why that is a caveat that makes it misleading.  The poll didn't ask about how popular other country's systems are.  

Anyway I don't appreciate your insinuation that I'm posting in bad faith here so I'll end it with this one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287896577.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/economy/making-sense/how-americans-spend-much-more-on-health-care-than-they-realize

This report says Americans spend 980 Billion dollars annually on healthcare. Even if that includes employer provided care, if employers stopped spending that money, they could be taxed to cover m4a and still save in the end. I wasn't only referring to private citizens.

https://www.cbo.gov/system/files/2019-05/55150-singlepayer.pdf

Here is the CBO report on m4a. It gives an estimated cost and a few plans for how to pay for it. Many of the possibilities do not include heavy tax increases, and again, almost all tax increases are offset by healthcare savings.

I was not giving that link as an irrefutable source, but as a longer and sourced version of the argument I am making about wait times. If I had copy pasted the arguments and sources, you would have presumably responded as normal. Why should linking to another argument make it less valid than copying it directly?

Anyone who is happy with medicare would be happy with medicare for all. Medicare for all cannot under any circumstance (unless it is bastardized beyond recognition) hurt current medicare. That hypothetical is patently absurd. If you can give me an example of how m4a would or could change medicare while remaining m4a, I will concede.

My original claim is that single payer is wildly popular. I provided two top-level polls of two international single payer systems, both of which showed above 2/3rds support. You responded with a single, more modest report which did not poll directly on the question of support, and even that report concluded single payer systems are popular. If your entire objection to my point is that I used the word "wildly," then I happily change my claim. They're just popular. That still suggests m4a would be popular here.

I don't think you are posting in bad faith so much as I think you have already decided your position on m4a. This is a discussion about a single poll that I found deeply manipulative. You have disagreed with me on unsupported grounds -- again, you've provided one single piece of evidence to this conversation.

Please reconsider your point of view. Medicare for all would mean 44% of Americans can start going back to the doctor. Frankly, unless you think people without money deserve to suffer and die from preventable illnesses (or spend their lives in bankruptcy after getting sick) single payer is the only moral option.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289557043.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The military budget is 800 billion a year. 

&amp;gt;This means we could pay for m4a easily by cutting military spending and taxing people well under their current premiums, saving them money overall. Sanders' plan hardly taxes the middle class and lower

There is a hidden danger in this line of reasoning.  It makes sense to do it on paper but what's going to happen is your going to bring a bunch of trained killers back home with no meaningful employment to be had.  You can imagine how things might go south from there and this is why I think the US is in a perpetual state of war until the empire ends, because we have hollowed out our middle class and outsourced all our good paying jobs</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291666367.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>I agree it's dangerous but the alternative is forever war and weak social services. I think that's more dangerous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32292645166.0" user="Tailtappin" delta="False">
    <text>Wait a second here... you seem to be suffering from some sort of cognitive dissonance. You just said that and therefore must acknowledge how powerful the US military is. Yet, for some reason, you seem to think that we could all just somehow storm the Bastille. Am I missing something here? Yes, they most certainly could stop "all of us" (although I don't know who you think that that is considering at least half the population is already %100 for certain not on your side of this and I many who you might actually think are probably aren't either)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32292729165.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>Direct action can work in combination with electoralism. Electoralism alone will never succeed. 

I don't think a violent revolution against the USA with no electoral support would work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32292630969.0" user="Tailtappin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Wait times don't increase in single payer systems once you count private insurance appointment scheduling as a "wait time."

Well, that one is just pulled directly out of your nether regions. It most certainly does. In Canada, getting to see a specialist takes from 2 to 6 weeks on average. Not to mention that there was a time not all that long ago where people were literally dying in hallways. They even coined a term for it called "hallway medicine". Don't tell me that wait times won't increase.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32292739424.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>Call your insurance company right now and ask how soon you could see a specialist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
