<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32285030834.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>The United States military is absurdly powerful.  Assuming the military are all loyal to the state, they could quash a violent rebellion in a heartbeat if they really needed to.   
  
Plus, consider the fact that there are a very diverse array of opinions in the US. Every citizen is not passionate enough to go risk their lives over a single issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285043507.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>A single issue? It’s not a single issue. It’s that food, shelter, clothes, education, and medical care are things everyone human needs to grow and be happy. 

Instead there’s a large number of people who will work the majority of their lives In poverty, trying there hardest to not die in the street.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285161612.0" user="svenson_26" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so maybe America isn't doing the best in a wide variety of issues. Maybe, to any individual person, there is at least one issue that they are passionate enough to join a mob over.  
  
So what's your plan? Everyone in America grab your guns and pichforks and march into Washington and murder every politician?   
  
Then what?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
