<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32285082951.0" user="hsmith711" delta="False">
    <text>They don't have to stop "all" of us. ~30% of adults in the US are completely fine with all the things you said. (most of those 30% have guns and wouldn't hesitate to use them against you).

Of the other ~70%, as long as people have access to food, water, shelter, healthcare... they will not see the issues as dire. They will not believe where this road could lead until it is too late. 

Look at how much we've accepted to this point.. it was bad before trump. Look at how much more shit we've accepted as reality since he was inaugurated. It's going to take a WHOLE lot more before more than 2% of the nation cares enough to do anything about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285095655.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe. I also think if billionaires and politicians didn’t feel safe anywhere in this country, that might help also.

Leftists have guns to, but we keep them for the reasons described in the constitution</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285121801.0" user="hsmith711" delta="False">
    <text>Hate to be the one to deliver the bad news.. but if it comes down to war between the US government/military and republicans versus the liberals, the liberals have a 0% chance of winning without support from other countries. Our best hope in that case would be us becoming the United States of England.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285135509.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, liberals are not leftists</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285149338.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>No true scotsman</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285154653.0" user="hsmith711" delta="False">
    <text>Okay... same story.. if it comes down to war between the US government/military and rightists versus leftists.. leftists lose. Badly. 

Does that help?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285155527.0" user="CrinkleLord" delta="False">
    <text>Considering leftists are almost entirely under 26, you aren't near as numerous,  or popular,  or even taken very seriously as you appear to think.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
