<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32289091546.0" user="Typographical_Terror" delta="False">
    <text>I actually happen to agree with you. I suspect future historians will look upon this time period as the lead up to Civil War II.

I think it's important to note that to this day, even including WWII and all that, more Americans lost their lives on the battlefields of the U.S. Civil War than ALL the wars that came after combined.

So not only will this be hard, it will be bloody, and it will not end well for a lot of us. This is even assuming some outside country doesn't take the opportunity to maybe kick us in the face while we're down, which is entirely possible as well.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_military_casualties_of_war#Wars_ranked_by_total_number_of_U.S._military_deaths</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
