<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32292596083.0" user="Tailtappin" delta="False">
    <text>Let's go point by point here:

Which institutions are we talking about exactly and how do they compare on an international metric?

"Capitalist overlords" is such a cliche. The other, and most problematic issue with the statement is that it betrays an ignorance of what capitalists have done for you. Oh, they didn't do it because they actually cared about you but it was through their actions and harnessing some of their success that we have things like public schools systems, roads and hospitals. You do realize that that fraction of the population actually pays most of the bills, right? And what would you replace it with? It's, **by far** the greatest system we've yet come up with. It's done far more to prevent war than anything we've ever dreamed up before. It's advanced our scientific knowledge by order*s* of magnitude. It's led to the life you get to live now. 

Now, concerning the prison population...well, the thing is, is it the largest prison population because it's unfair or because other countries just don't bother enforcing their laws? This is actually a very important question because it's always overlooked. 
South Africa, for example, probably has just as many rapes and murders (actually, it's undoubtedly more) than the US does in an average year. However, their prison population doesn't compare. Now, is that because South Africa's so safe or because they just don't have the resources to imprison their criminals? Anybody looking at it objectively can tell you it's the latter. I know this because the murder rate is 7 times higher and the rape rate is the same. Yet they manage to square up against the big boys despite having less than a sixth of the population. Hmmmm....

Concentration camps never left. That's the first thing. Secondly, ask a Holocaust survivor where he or she would rather be and see if he or she even considers these camps to be any sort of punishing environment. To them it's a resort hotel. In fact, ask anybody who's ever been in an actual concentration camp what they think of what you're referring to and see if they don't just go off on a loud tirade.

You think this is a hellscape? Seriously? You need to read about what life was like for even the most powerful people on earth up until just a couple hundred years ago. You live a life far better than the highest king in the richest country of the most just land lived up until relatively recently. You genuinely have no idea how good you have it. What's worse is that you don't know how it ever got to be so good for you.

Anyway, it's not enough to say "let's destroy the system!" I mean, first of all, it's completely illogical to want to destroy the system that has done so much to provide you with so many luxuries your entire life. Secondly, **what are you going to replace it with?** Don't just say "eat the rich, disband the police, strike the legal system and start it all over again from scratch!" That can only end one way and it rhymes with "bass burder".

That's a terrible, horrible inhumane idea. How do we know how bad an idea it is? Because we've done it countless times before. I live, in fact, in one of those places where it was recently (in historical terms) done. You have no idea how bad an idea what you propose is.

I'm really not saying any of this to be condescending or rude to you. I really mean simply that you are ignorant of history and haven't put any real thought into this idea. I don't understand why you want it or what you hope you to achieve but mostly I don't see any plan to make things better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
