<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32285812053.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>The US armed forces absolutely can kill all of us. 

If for some reason, all 325 million Americans got into a war against the US armed forces - I would put my money on the US armed forces. They have helicopters, tanks, submarines, aircraft carriers, nukes ......

&amp;amp;#x200B;

While I don't think they would take killing civilians on this scale lightly, they wouldn't want to do it - but if the shit really did hit the fan - they would win. 

This idea that "if we all work together we can win" - is insane. The only thing giving "us" any chance would be the military not wanting to shoot, their own urge to hold back. But once that's gone, any hope of victory is lost.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285900462.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>Idk about that. The US  no longer has a great history of winning wars. 

The US military has a few recent wins that nobody could rationally call wins</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
