<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32285316619.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>If you’re planning to start a socialist revolution I think that you need to be aware that this has never turned out to actually help common people.
I agree, America is pretty corrupt and it would be better to change the system for it to be more democratic but from what I’ve seen in this post, you seem to actually have a socialist revolutionary mindset.
Please tell me if I’ve misunderstood you and keep in mind that I don’t want to offend you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285344173.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>You haven't. Check his profile.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285352514.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285352865.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>I’m certainly not offended. I think you hit the nail on the head, when it comes to my mindset. 

I’ve lived a very American life so far, I’ve made money, I’ve lived in poverty, I’m an army veteran. And it might not work, but I don’t believe reforms will ever give me my right to existence, so I want to take it. By any means necessary</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285435927.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, reforms will not help because of the way the American system is set up. However, by implementing a socialist government, all you’ll do is change the minority that’s in charge. The only thing that can help in such a situation is more democracy. Removing the barriers that stand in the way of a true “rule of the people” is the way to go. All you have to do as a someone who truly cares about the people (and I think you do) is make the system as fair as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285466862.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>That seems reasonable to me. I think the only place we differ is how it gets accomplished</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285480412.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>If my post seems reasonable, you should describe yourself as a liberal proponent of democracy, not a socialist revolutionary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285484979.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>I’m somewhere between a socialist, communist, and anarchist

E: the reasonable part is power to the people. I’m not interested in any ruling minority</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285493308.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>You say that you are, but the fact that we agree on this topic says differently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285514676.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>Well what do you call someone who wants housing, food, education, clothes and medical care to be human rights. 

Who wants there to be no law prohibiting what any person chooses to put into or do with their own body, and believes the ruling class should hung for their acts against humanity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285564238.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>Your first paragraph is 100% understandable and logically foolproof.
The second paragraph contains the axiom that people are divided into oppressors and oppressed and that therefore the oppressors should be killed. This mentality is pathological and has often led humanity to horrible crimes because it channels tribalism, reinforces victimisation  and assumes that people are what group you assign to them. This inevitably leads to discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285645573.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>A billionaires existence is inherently violent. I couldn’t possibly see it any other way

I do appreciate your willingness to talk about it tho</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285801593.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>How is a billionaire violent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285880868.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>It’s impossible to amount that kind of wealth without exerting it from peoples labor and recourses. 

They are hoarding wealth, while real people go hungry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285892874.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>Not necessarily. Take Bill Gates, for instance. Software companies pay their employees pretty well, and many of their CEOs donate money to charities on a pretty regular basis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285930270.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>Statistically regular people give way larger percentages of their wealth away, than any of the super rich, what’s a million dollars when you have seventy billion?

Also Bill is an investor in Geo Group, which runs private prisons and concentration camps</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285952844.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>Not saying that he's perfect by any means, I'm just saying that he and many other people that you feel deserve execution have done more good than bad for people. 


Also a bit off topic, but you should do more posts here. You seem to have a lot of viewpoints that the sub doesn't get enough of, and I'm sure that the people here would enjoy debating them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285986777.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>That mentality is demonstrable. What's pathological is your refusal to recognize the existence of economic classes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289415877.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>Communism is a flawed idea. If it worked I’d be a communist myself. I don’t deny that capitalism creates a divide between rich and poor but your class mentality leads to violence and discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291672171.0" user="mboop127" delta="False">
    <text>It's not our class mentality. The classes and the violence already exist. You don't want the violence to end, you just prefer that the capitalist class can wield that violence without retribution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291740013.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>You got me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32292652952.0" user="Tailtappin" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly, I think you might be high right now. I don't mean that as an insult or to dehumanize or dismiss you. I just mean that your ideas are so poorly thought out that the only explanation must be drugs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286284383.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;this has never turned out to actually help common people

Factually incorrect, in Cuba for example everyone is extremely well fed, they’re the most literate country in the world, they have free healthcare for all, the most doctors per capita, 85% of them own their homes, they’re very happy. You’ve been literally propagandized to believe it’s never worked, because the rich people who control our media are protecting their own economic interests. Can’t let the people realize their lives would be extremely better if we restructured the way society is ran</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32286896994.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>Really?  How did you find this out?  China and Russia were collosal failures under communism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287076283.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>I found it out reading history. If you don't believe me you can google it, cuba has been a massive success. they're always in the news for sending doctors and medical supplies to countries suffering natural disasters.

Yeah, china definitely was, but russia definitely wasnt a massive failure until gorbachev

american propaganda absolutely never teaches you where russia was before the revolution. what criticisms have we heard? they have no democracy, they had no food, etc etc etc. well, right before the revolution, they were living under an emperor! they were feudalist! they had famines every five years, they had no electricity or running water, they absolutely didn't have any democracy. then the revolution happened and the bolsheviks industrialized *the entire country*. Suddenly, people weren't dying from the cold, they weren't starving to death, they were learning to read, they were given leisure time for the first time in the world. AND, they beat Germany, arguably the most developed country in the world at the time, in a massive world war. AND they staved off counter-revolutionaries trying to sabotage them. AND they supported revolutions worldwide. AND they stopped the CIA from their millions of attempts to tear them down (at least until the late 20th century). AND they eventually industrialized so unbelievably rapidly, they took on the united states in the space race. Think about that! In the span of a few decades, they went from being a frozen hellscape under the brutal rule of an emperor, to a wellfed, educated, industrialized country pioneering the race into space.

look at this list of their space accomplishments from wikipedia:

1957: First intercontinental ballistic missile and orbital launch vehicle, the R-7 Semyorka

1957: First satellite, Sputnik 1

1957: First animal in Earth orbit, the dog Laika on Sputnik 2

1959: First rocket ignition in Earth orbit, first man-made object to escape Earth's gravity, Luna 1

1959: First data communications, or telemetry, to and from outer space, Luna 1.

1959: First man-made object to pass near the Moon, first man-made object in Heliocentric orbit, Luna 1

1959: First probe to impact the Moon, Luna 2

1959: First images of the moon's far side, Luna 3

1960: First animals to safely return from Earth orbit, the dogs Belka and Strelka on Sputnik 5.

1961: First probe launched to Venus, Venera 1

1961: First person in space (International definition) and in Earth orbit, Yuri Gagarin on Vostok 1, Vostok programme

1961: First person to spend over 24 hours in space Gherman Titov, Vostok 2 (also first person to sleep in space).

1962: First dual manned spaceflight, Vostok 3 and Vostok 4

1962: First probe launched to Mars, Mars 1

1963: First woman in space, Valentina Tereshkova, Vostok 6

1964: First multi-person crew (3), Voskhod 1

1965: First extra-vehicular activity (EVA), by Alexsei Leonov,[19] Voskhod 2

1965: First probe to hit another planet of the Solar System (Venus), Venera 3

1966: First probe to make a soft landing on and transmit from the surface of the Moon, Luna 9

1966: First probe in lunar orbit, Luna 10

1967: First unmanned rendezvous and docking, Cosmos 186/Cosmos 188.

1968: First living beings to reach the Moon (circumlunar flights) and return unharmed to Earth, Russian tortoises and other lifeforms on Zond 5

1969: First docking between two manned craft in Earth orbit and exchange of crews, Soyuz 4 and Soyuz 5

1970: First soil samples automatically extracted and returned to Earth from another celestial body, Luna 16

1970: First robotic space rover, Lunokhod 1 on the Moon.

1970: First data received from the surface of another planet of the Solar system (Venus), Venera 7

1971: First space station, Salyut 1

1971: First probe to impact the surface of Mars, Mars 2

1971: First probe to land on Mars, Mars 3

1975: First probe to orbit Venus, to make soft landing on Venus, first photos from surface of Venus, Venera 9

1980: First Hispanic and Black person in space, Arnaldo Tamayo Méndez on Soyuz 38

1984: First woman to walk in space, Svetlana Savitskaya (Salyut 7 space station)

1986: First crew to visit two separate space stations (Mir and Salyut 7)

1986: First probes to deploy robotic balloons into Venus atmosphere and to return pictures of a comet during close flyby Vega 1, Vega 2

1986: First permanently manned space station, Mir, 1986–2001, with permanent presence on board (1989–1999)

1987: First crew to spend over one year in space, Vladimir Titov and Musa Manarov on board of Soyuz TM-4 - Mir

The only way you could say communism was a failure in russia is if you've been lied to by your capitalist government. unironically.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287172017.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>Ok I'm willing to hear some arguments about Cuba but I don't know how you can say Russia was a success pre Gorbachev.  They utilized the Gulags until Gorbachev dismantled them and they had the Holodomor genocide under Stalin</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287177155.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>come on man, i put a lot of effort into that comment and you just dismiss everything i said?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287215799.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>Okay take all their accomplishments and add in 20 million people starving to death and I can't see any way that would be considered success.  Besides I want some information on Cuba here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287269760.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>do you realize how much more frequently people starved to death under feudalist russia? the communist revolution led to all of the accomplishments i listed, AND greatly greatly reduced the staggering amounts of people starving to death. and, for the record, the one famine they had one time was because capitalists organized mass crop burnings to sabotage the revolution. i wonder why they dont teach you that in school! the CIA actually researched how well russians were eating and found they ate the same amount of food but were more nutritious than americans, then classified the report because it was damaging to america. they recently declassified it, here's a link: https://www.cia.gov/library/readingroom/docs/CIA-RDP84B00274R000300150009-5.pdf 

so, we have industrialization, more freedom, more education, more food. can you at least level with me that maybe the capitalist government might have taught us lies about the country they were at war with? 

here's a my favorite video about cuba, it's very short https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U103EBC4mvk</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287441859.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>We're the Gulags real?  Was the Holodomor real?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287464318.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>You’re refusing to listen to what I’m saying</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287557802.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>You posted a link to a document that says people ate well under the Soviet Union.  There are several other documents written by Russians that lived through this period that say millions of people starved to death in forced labor camps ( gulags ), and millions starved during a government induced famine ( Holodomor ).  Clearly both can't be true, so which is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287746900.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>Considering that people who are from the USSR all say that they didn't eat much, and the link is basically the CIA copying a cherry picked Russian statistic, my money is on the starvation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287954918.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>74% of Russians think the fall of the Soviet Union was a tragedy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287971200.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>Because they A) liked being seen as a world power and B) fell for USSR propaganda, not because they liked starving. Look at people from captured countries (Ukraine, Poland, etc.), and see how that statistic holds up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287990049.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288026315.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>I commented one thing, and it was from a post that you made a few days ago. Making one comment hardly counts as "stalking"

Also, it's convenient that you forgot to give a meaning to counterargument, and just resorted to insults.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288138122.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>i did give a meaning to my counterargument, it was that what you said was ridiculously stupid because you're a stupid person 

"uhhhh actually the government brainwashed people into thinking they weren't actually starving" okay dude whats more likely, the overwhelming evidence that says russians actually were fed very well, or your galaxybrain idea that the government somehow managed to brainwash people into forgetting they were starving all the time</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288212234.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>Oh! Insulting people who don't understand an intentionally vague argument is fine!

I didn't mean that the USSR didn't brainwash people into thinking that they weren't starving. I meant that the USSR made people think that everyone else was worse, hence the whole tragedy thing.

&amp;gt;Overwhelming evidence says the Russians were fed very well

https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soviet_famine_of_1932–33

This was just *one year* of the USSR's history. Granted, it was a particularly bad one, but there were others, too. (Like this! https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soviet_famine_of_1946–47)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288228372.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288246408.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288262392.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/CaptainNacho8 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+CaptainNacho8&amp;amp;message=CaptainNacho8+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/etzl6dk/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32288265059.0" user="tbdabbholm" delta="False">
    <text>u/friendoftaargus – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+friendoftaargus&amp;amp;message=friendoftaargus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/etzksgk/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289489834.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>Your “overwhelming evidence” consists of a highly questionable CIA report and a wonky YouTube video by a channel called “Socialist Party of Youtube”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289525116.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t say I listed overwhelming evidence, I said there is overwhelming evidence. Clearly you’re never going to be convinced, even when the facts are at your fingertips. It’s depressing how much of the world is full of lost causes like you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289584197.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>Where is this overwhelming evidence then? I looked for it but didnt find anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289597660.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289611911.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>No people like me who don’t believe in the credibility of communism are the reason we don’t have a second Soviet Union.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289618289.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>A second Soviet Union would save us from environmental collapse and a descent into fascism. Liberalism leads to fascism! Fascism leads to death! People like you are killing us and you don’t fucking realize it!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289625030.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>Do you know what gulags are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289633259.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>Oh my fucking god i would pay a hundred bucks for you to completely realize how fucking stupid you’re being 

People like you are literally going to be our demise. Holy shit we’re fucked</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289656430.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>Too bad for you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289802797.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289808900.0" user="ImInTheMaytricks" delta="False">
    <text>If by growing up you mean ignore historical facts and become a communist revolutionary then no thank you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289835317.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289867837.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289927716.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289932955.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289938148.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289938173.0" user="AutoModerator" delta="False">
    <text>u/friendoftaargus, your comment has been automatically removed as a clear violation of Rule 2:

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).


*I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please [contact the moderators of this subreddit](/message/compose/?to=/r/changemyview) if you have any questions or concerns.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289943822.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32290099763.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>u/friendoftaargus – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+friendoftaargus&amp;amp;message=friendoftaargus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/eu0l7ok/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291447697.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ImInTheMaytricks – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+ImInTheMaytricks&amp;amp;message=ImInTheMaytricks+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/eu0jxh9/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291435368.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/friendoftaargus – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+friendoftaargus&amp;amp;message=friendoftaargus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/eu0j8dx/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291433590.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>u/friendoftaargus – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+friendoftaargus&amp;amp;message=friendoftaargus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/eu0ijal/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32291449642.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>u/friendoftaargus – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+friendoftaargus&amp;amp;message=friendoftaargus+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/-/eu0e50c/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32287980705.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>I really tried to have a conversation about this with you, but you’re too closed minded. Thanks for wasting my time. 

74% of Russians regret the collapse of the Soviet Union. Admit to me that PERHAPS the United States spread lies about the country they were at war with to make it sound worse than it was, and maybe we can continue this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289648166.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>of course no response

typical

reach out to people, tell them the truth, they dont listen

we're so fucked</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289667177.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>Look in the mirror friend</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32289800303.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>you cant even admit a government would tell lies about the country they're at war with</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32290029457.0" user="jcamp748" delta="False">
    <text>Look man these are accounts from actual Russians that lived through it, not some report put out by the CIA or something.  There are many countries in the world that have officially recognized that these events happened.  Just look at what's happened to Venezuela since their socialist take over, it is a reminder of how dangerous these ideas can be and how they just don't work</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32290062167.0" user="friendoftaargus" delta="False">
    <text>you cant even admit a government would lie about the conditions in a country they're at war with, and you think you're so intelligent. people like you are the reason why we're a fascist country now. jesus christ man i am so fucking *exhausted* having to deal with this shit. no one but the left realizes what's currently at stake. no one realizes how liberals are exasperating it. we're so fucked, and im going to tell you directly we're so fucked, and you're going to forget about this in two days. you're gonna go through life wondering why stuff like ICE agents literally raping fucking children keeps happening and have no explanation for it, because you're plugging your ears and ignoring everything im begging you to listen to me about

it fucking sucks man, it really fucking sucks. we're all doomed because no one is listening to us.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32294615861.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>I checked the other guy's profile. As I understand it, he's unwilling to accept other sources than the ones that he listed, and probably should be avoided in arguments if possible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
