<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32288931166.0" user="luxembourgeois" delta="False">
    <text>Revolution, properly understood, involves violence as the final and least significant step in its final culmination. Even if the entire populace of the U.S. wanted to overthrow the government, what we would end up with tomorrow would look more like fascism or regime change, not any positive type of change in my opinion.

You are correct that most reforms will not empower the average person. Even positive reforms (like social security, medicare, food stamps, etc.) in our society are usually meant to blunt struggle against the oppressive status quo, and therefore reinforce it. But there is a myriad of things we can do, large and small, to change our lives and improve society that don't involve combat and weapons training.

Some of these things include:

1. Setting up community gardens.
2. Attending protests for policies which improve the lives of working people.
3. Unionizing and organizing your coworkers.
4. Leading a strike for the social, economic or political empowerment of you, your coworkers, and (if you're really good) your community.
5. Organizing your community into self-defense councils. Note that self-defense encompasses far more than patrolling the streets with a rifle.
6. Getting involved in or building tenant's unions.
7. etc.

Of course, some actions are more cost-effective than others. I won't dogmatically presume to know which actions are best for you to take and which ones aren't. But the actions which tend to work best from my reading of history and personal experience are those that empower not just you, but others as well. The more broadly you spread your power, the better off you'll be.

The LAUSD teachers have demonstrated the capacity for positive change through organizing *par excellence* in my opinion. Honestly, their victory, no matter how short lived it may be, is something we all need to keep in mind.

 [https://www.dsausa.org/news/los-angeles-teachers-win-big-after-massive-strike/](https://www.dsausa.org/news/los-angeles-teachers-win-big-after-massive-strike/) 

 [https://socialistworker.org/2019/01/18/the-la-teachers-strike-shows-us-how-to-win](https://socialistworker.org/2019/01/18/the-la-teachers-strike-shows-us-how-to-win) 

The USG is definitely an enemy of the people. We have concentration camps, a fascist in the white house, the working poor are getting poorer, our planet is going to be uninhabitable, etc. etc. etc. Few politicians are offering solutions to these issues that will work even in the short term.

But, we must resist the temptation to whip out the guns and get angry. We need to inspire hope, courage, determination and most of all, solidarity among the world's working people. Angrily fighting with the cops while yelling about oppression won't accomplish that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
