<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="749170415.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ce1blb/cmv_the_usg_cant_stop_all_of_us_we_could_change/">
    <title>CMV: The USG can’t stop all of us, we could change this country tomorrow with direct action</title>
    <original_poster>zodadoza</original_poster>
    <original_post>The institutions they run the US are horrendous.  

We have the worlds largest prison population, which maintains legal slavery.

Capitalist overlords hoard the majority of wealth while the working poor is real and growing.

For not the first time in kinda recent history concentration camps are back. 

My entire life I’ve been told things are the way they are, and there’s nothing to be done about it.  But that’s fucking bullshit. 

I don’t believe for a second that reforms will ever give power, real power to the people of this world. The teachers, the workers, the families that will grind through this hellscape as best they can for their entire lives, just trying not to go hungry on the streets.  

The State has a monopoly on violence. If we break that monopoly up, if we use that power for ourselves, against the enemies of humanity, maybe the world gets better sooner rather than later.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32285011051.0" user="DexFulco" delta="False">
    <text>If you truly feel this way, why are you posting on Reddit about it instead of starting a revolution?     

Maybe overthrowing the status quo isn't as easy as you make it out to be?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285027690.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think it’s easy. I think it’s hard, but necessary.

I’m posting on reddit because I think, the idea of actually changing the status quo should be on peoples minds. 

Myself or any other one person can’t do it. It’ll take a lot of us, maybe most of us. But it starts here. By talking about it, by growing ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285042234.0" user="DexFulco" delta="False">
    <text>What makes you think anyone supports your idea? Maybe this CMV should be you trying to change our mind</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285047383.0" user="zodadoza" delta="False">
    <text>lol. Willem shared my views</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285110543.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>I hope you're not referring to [Willem Van Spronsen](https://www.google.com/amp/s/heavy.com/news/2019/07/willem-van-spronsen-emma-durutti/amp/), the fringe anarchist who tried to set fire to an ICE detention center before being killed. If this is the basis for your revolution, you actually don't have 'all of us' as you claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285137622.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>I checked his profile. He is, and he also seems to idolize the man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285170775.0" user="beachedwhale1945" delta="False">
    <text>Two of his most recent posts are his last statement in different subreddits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285213823.0" user="CaptainNacho8" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't be surprised if he's just trying to spread his opinion, then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285269984.0" user="nicfection" delta="False">
    <text>People like OP can’t comprehend things so they think the whole system has to be gotten rid of with violence or a coup. It’s a simpler solution for them to understand because they don’t want to take the piece by piece approach to change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32285262877.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I’m posting on reddit because I think, the idea of actually changing the status quo should be on peoples minds.

why do you want people to try to change your view?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
