<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="75326877.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18uil9/i_think_nonviolent_criminals_shouldnt_be_sent_to/">
    <title>I think non-violent criminals shouldn't be sent to prison. CMV?</title>
    <original_poster>dichotomie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think anything that isn't stuff like murder, rape, arson, robbery (but not burglary) or the attempt or intention to do those things shouldn't be given prison time right off the bat.

I think there should be some sort of three strike system where you could be fined, put on house arrest, or probation before receiving jail time. I think this could be a better system because we wouldn't be mixing relatively okay people with career criminals and it would be less of a strain on our prison system which is already overcrowded due to things like mandatory minimums and the war on drugs.

This is something I just thought about on a whim so I'd like to hear the negatives and why something like this wouldn't work in practice.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26635702529.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Fines are tricky. How can you fine someone with no assets? If a homeless man breaks into your store, causing a few thousand dollars worth of damage, there's no recompense, no wages to garnish. The only things people all have are time and bodies. We can punish them by taking their time, with prison, or we can punish by taking their bodies, through some system of corporal punishment.

I mostly agree with you, but I think that jails should instead be segregated- property crimes and drug crimes have a lower cost to the fabric of society than anything involving violence or the specter of violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26635956886.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>How is taking their time recompensing the person who's property was damaged, though? It's actually costing them additional money via taxes. Better that they should have to do some sort of restitution or community service.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
