<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="75326877.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18uil9/i_think_nonviolent_criminals_shouldnt_be_sent_to/">
    <title>I think non-violent criminals shouldn't be sent to prison. CMV?</title>
    <original_poster>dichotomie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think anything that isn't stuff like murder, rape, arson, robbery (but not burglary) or the attempt or intention to do those things shouldn't be given prison time right off the bat.

I think there should be some sort of three strike system where you could be fined, put on house arrest, or probation before receiving jail time. I think this could be a better system because we wouldn't be mixing relatively okay people with career criminals and it would be less of a strain on our prison system which is already overcrowded due to things like mandatory minimums and the war on drugs.

This is something I just thought about on a whim so I'd like to hear the negatives and why something like this wouldn't work in practice.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26635580914.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I like where you are going, but, may I suggest you change your view slightly: how about we make non-violent victim-less crimes no longer crimes(buying/selling drugs, sharing files, etc) ? That way we would leave peaceful people alone and they would be free to do as they please and we would also reduce the strain on taxpayers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26635617160.0" user="dichotomie" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you on decriminalization/legalization of drug use but I do believe copyright laws have their place (even if I don't follow them). 

An artist is totally entitled to having their works protected and making a profit off them although fining some poor bastard millions of dollars is really unreasonable and there should definitely be reforms in how we stop and prosecute piracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26635772236.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>a) that wouldnt be a victimless crime in the purest sense

b)i disagree, property rights only make sense when when they are scarce, this isnt true of ip </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
