<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="75326877.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/18uil9/i_think_nonviolent_criminals_shouldnt_be_sent_to/">
    <title>I think non-violent criminals shouldn't be sent to prison. CMV?</title>
    <original_poster>dichotomie</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think anything that isn't stuff like murder, rape, arson, robbery (but not burglary) or the attempt or intention to do those things shouldn't be given prison time right off the bat.

I think there should be some sort of three strike system where you could be fined, put on house arrest, or probation before receiving jail time. I think this could be a better system because we wouldn't be mixing relatively okay people with career criminals and it would be less of a strain on our prison system which is already overcrowded due to things like mandatory minimums and the war on drugs.

This is something I just thought about on a whim so I'd like to hear the negatives and why something like this wouldn't work in practice.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26635551336.0" user="rhydeble" delta="False">
    <text>You might want to ask when someone is "relatively okay". Is a crime boss, that did not kill anyone himself, relatively okay? What about large scaled fraud that destoyed the life of thousands of people? Prison time serves as punishment, and to remove people from society. 
I'm not saying mandatory minimums and the drug war aren't ridiculous, but there are pretty of nonviolent but dangerous people around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26635574430.0" user="dichotomie" delta="False">
    <text>This is good point but I would say overall people like that shouldn't be in prison, at least not initially. Instead they could be heavily monitored and have restrictions like not being able to leave the country or state (maybe even counties) or not be able purchase certain things or work in certain industries. 

And in a system like this there would obviously be exceptions to the rule depending on how devastating their crimes were. Like someone like Bernie Madoff would get instant jail time. 

Also in the case of a crime boss if they associated with having other people killed or whatnot I would still say that's a violent crime because that would be conspiracy to murder. But say if it was someone who solely dealt in the large scale movement of drugs (although they usually overlap at this level) I would say that this person does not belong in jail.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
