<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="756614563.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cigvj7/cmv_it_should_be_illegal_to_have_a_pitbull_that/">
    <title>CMV: It should be illegal to have a pitbull that isn't spayed or neutered</title>
    <original_poster>Kalergi_Plan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Should be self-explanatory. I don't think we should straight up ban the breed, but getting such a dog fixed should be a legal requirement for owning one. Un-neutered dogs are \[responsible for the vast majority of serious attacks\]([https://www.avma.org/Advocacy/StateAndLocal/Pages/dogbite-summary.aspx](https://www.avma.org/Advocacy/StateAndLocal/Pages/dogbite-summary.aspx)) according to the AVMA. This would also result in a pit bull population decline which would reduce the huge number of pits clogging up shelters.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32358272810.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This is just a breed ban with extra steps. Require it for all animals that aren’t licensed as breeders or require it for none.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32358286054.0" user="Kalergi_Plan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is just a breed ban with extra steps

Yes, it kind of is. That's the point. It would be best if pit bulls slowly die off naturally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32358354577.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	slowly die off naturally.

That’s not natural. Are you advocating for a reduction in the breed’s population or the elimination of the breed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32358387853.0" user="Kalergi_Plan" delta="False">
    <text>In theory I'd probably like to see them eliminated but realistically that's not going to happen. The real-life effect of this would be to reduce the population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32358419640.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>There is no basis for selective elimination of dog breeds. Pits aren’t any more predisposed to violence as any other breed.

They’re just very popular among people who can’t train their dog, or specifically intend to make it hate people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32358773883.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>You may be against the selective elimination of a dog bread and that’s a very fair position to take but it is disingenuous to say there is no basis. 

You yourself acknowledge that they are sought after by bad dog owners. The reason they are is because if they do attack they are much more able to maim or kill a human or another dog. So while selectively eliminating a breed might not reduce the number of dog attacks it could reduce the number of fatalities and the severity of injuries from the attacks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32358954621.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	it is disingenuous to say there is no basis.

You can easily be mauled by a Chihuahua. There is no basis, [they are media induced fear.](https://web.archive.org/web/20090802143641/http://www.abanet.org/genpractice/magazine/2009/jul_aug/pitbull.html) You think Pitbulls are more effective killers because that’s what they use in the movies. They’re not. They’re better at being trained and vaguely look meancing when snarling.

“There is no evidence that breed-specific laws, which are costly and difficult to enforce, make communities safer for people or companion animals.” [source](https://www.aspcapro.org/resource/disaster-cruelty-animal-cruelty-animal-fighting/are-breed-specific-laws-effective)

[They are baseless and ineffective.](https://www.avma.org/news/javmanews/pages/171115a.aspx) It would be a much better use of time and effort figuring out how to police terrible owners than eliminating a “meanacing” looking breed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32359100332.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>You provide good reasons to be against a breed specific ban but I can’t take you seriously if you can’t acknowledge that being attacked by a pitbull is not significantly more dangerous than being attacked by a chihuahua.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360451086.0" user="Ghostface215" delta="False">
    <text>What about German Shepards? Or labradors? Or boxers? They’re all big dogs and can be just as violent as Pitbulls (there’s a reason German Shepards are the breed predominantly chosen by police officers).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360520741.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not taking a side on which if any breeds should be banned. The person made decent points about not banning pit bulls. It’s just silly though to act like pit bulls aren’t especially dangerous if (not when) they attack.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32364005280.0" user="MechanicalEngineEar" delta="False">
    <text>He isn’t arguing Pitt bull vs chihuahua because that is pointless and obvious.  Nearly any full size dog can be highly dangerous.  Nearly any human can be far more dangerous than a pit bull.  My neighbor has a pit bull that is very dosile and gets bullied by their cats.  If the dog gets into something the cats want they will hiss and swipe at her and the pit will pout and go back to its cage in the utility room and lay down there to get away from the cats.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360880345.0" user="Aggravating_Role" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  They’re all big dogs and can be just as violent as Pitbulls 

They break down into something non functional if abused. Pitbulls become something evil themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360897772.0" user="Ghostface215" delta="False">
    <text>I highly doubt that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32361853931.0" user="phcullen" delta="False">
    <text>This is not true. My friend recently got a pitbull rescued from a puppy mill, very abused (still has scars).  She was meek and afraid for the first 6 months and is now a well trained dog like any other. I have never seen her be violent.

Now if you have a dog that was abused by being trained to dog fight. Then yeah it will probably be violent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32370551098.0" user="CoyotePatronus" delta="False">
    <text>I've seen plenty of dogs become vicious things that will attack anything if abused. Most of them labradors, believe it or not. I've also seen pitbulls that have been horribly abused and would still never dream of biting. 

I've handled all sorts of dogs in my life, abused and not, from all kinds of breeds including pitbulls, labs, border collies, dachshunds, pomeranians, terriers, chihuahuas, etc. Of them all, the dachshunds and chihuahuas were the most likely and persistent at trying to bite and the only dog that has ever succeeded in actually biting me and doing any kind of damage was a pug-beagle mix that clamped onto my hand after she'd been hit by a car. Only time she ever even tried to bite someone, and I very nearly needed surgery for it.

If you want to stop traumatized victims of animal abuse from attacking, stop the trauma of animal abuse by addressing the abusers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32371349822.0" user="Hero17" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like feels</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360422623.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can easily be mauled by a Chihuahua

Please, post some news about someone being mauled to death by a Chihuahua.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360482222.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>It’s actually a sad story. [chihuahua attack](http://www.pocho.com/man-mauled-by-chihuahuas-survives-attack-but-not-humiliation/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360524087.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>That's not what you said:

* The man in the story killed himself out of shame, was not mauled to death

* The man was attacked by a pack of chihuahuas, not one.

* The man was only hurt, his life was not in risk from the attack.

Please, post a source on someone having been mauled to death by a Chihuahua (like the hundreds of news of people being mauled to death by a pitbull or similar) or accept that you said something ridiculous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360581051.0" user="wallnumber8675309" delta="False">
    <text>I’m the one that said that it was disingenuous to act like pit bulls weren’t dangerous. I just ran across the story and thought it illustrated the absurdity of being “mauled” by a chihuahua.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32360932083.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, didn't read your username.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32363208448.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think that? Pit bulls are one of the sweetest and good-natured breeds you can find. If you get rid of pit bulls, then the next toughest breed would be picked up by scumbags, used for fights, left in the streets, and cause feral dog attacks. Pit bulls aren't the problem. Shitty people are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32368707987.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32369634870.0" user="Mr-Ice-Guy" delta="False">
    <text>u/NyLiam – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+NyLiam&amp;amp;message=NyLiam+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cigvj7/-/evbhqxf/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32370562183.0" user="CoyotePatronus" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. When I was young before everything became about pitbulls, it was Rottweilers and Dobermans who were the 'dangerous dogs that could snap and tear your throat out without warning'. They even excused it by saying that Dobermans had such narrow heads that it squished their brains and made them violent, and it wasn't a matter of 'if' but 'when' a given doberman or rottie would kill someone.

That's because dobies and rotties were the 'nasty breed of choice' by thugs before they turned to pitties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32372887683.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>Funny thing is, Poodles are far more aggressive than all those breeds. They just don't have the same strength behind them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
