<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="756614563.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cigvj7/cmv_it_should_be_illegal_to_have_a_pitbull_that/">
    <title>CMV: It should be illegal to have a pitbull that isn't spayed or neutered</title>
    <original_poster>Kalergi_Plan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Should be self-explanatory. I don't think we should straight up ban the breed, but getting such a dog fixed should be a legal requirement for owning one. Un-neutered dogs are \[responsible for the vast majority of serious attacks\]([https://www.avma.org/Advocacy/StateAndLocal/Pages/dogbite-summary.aspx](https://www.avma.org/Advocacy/StateAndLocal/Pages/dogbite-summary.aspx)) according to the AVMA. This would also result in a pit bull population decline which would reduce the huge number of pits clogging up shelters.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32358490181.0" user="phdissonance" delta="False">
    <text>So I did a small project for this in my epidemiology class in grad school. So I found that pitbulls aren't actually that aggressive to people. Their rate of attacking humans are pretty similar to other common breeds. However, due to their originally bred purpose for full and bear baiting they have incredibly powerful jaws. Because of this bites from pitbulls tend to lead to more hospitalizations and fatalities. 

Also, a majority of hospitalizations are children. Thos is for 2 reasons, 1 kids are dumb and will provoke a dog. And 2 kids faces are close to dog faces due to kids being shorter than adults so attacks usually require hospitalization.

https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0168159108001147

The link is paper on dog attack rates by breed. If you need other sources I can provide more on the statements I made

Tldr: pitbulls arent more aggressive to people than other breeds, their strong jaw just tends to lead to more hospitalizations, thus they seem more aggressive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
