<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26650749592.0" user="ellobaldy" delta="False">
    <text>I come from quite a privileged family, but hear me out because I think many people really need to try consider things from our side rather than making assumptions. 

Most people who aren't rich (and some who are) seem to think that rich people are rich because they a) get all their money from their parents; b) are rotten, cheaty business people; c) are celebrities; or d) a combination of the above. I won't say those are never the case because as someone who has had to socialize with other rich people all my life, I can tell you many of these people are snooty fucking bastards who don't deserve anything they have.

However, a certain case of rich motherfucker who certainly deserves everything she has and more is my mom. My mom did indeed come from a rich family, but they haven't given her a penny since middle school. In high school she worked her ass off; she worked nights and weekends and made straight A's in school, and worked every fucking day during the summertime. With the money she made then and the scholarships, she put herself through college and medical school, where she also worked her ass off with a job and straight A's. Needless to say, she was very smart and handled her money well. Let me remind you that she did all this with no help of her parents—even when she lived with them during part of college, they made her pay rent and bills, and kicked her out once when she couldn't pay up. They were harder on her than actual landlords. Even compared to how hard her parents made life in college, the real word wasn't any easier. This is because after (or during, I'm not sure) med school she married her first husband and moved to one of the worst financial places possible in America: Ft. Lauderdale. They weren't doing so well. My mom was exhausted as fuck working on completing her residency (ask any doctor, that is no easy feat) while her husband was basically just partying a lot and working *sometimes*. They divorced. Many many years later she was a doctor, doing not so well, as it was Ft. Lauderdale where the economy sucks and doctors aren't paid that well for doctors. She met my dad and they married and had me. He was the domestic one; he had a little travel business but didnt really bring in a lot of money. We were living in an apartment, then got kicked out because no money. We then stayed at my dad's friend's house, literally, Crazy Pete. He kicked us out because my mom left a lightbulb on, which was ridiculous because *she* was paying for the electricity. Crazy fucking Pete, man. I was three months old!  We lived on my dad's itsy bitsy sailboat for a while until we got sorta on our feet financially and got a place, which was in a pretty bad neighborhood. For roughly 9 years, I—a little girl—lived right next door to a registered sex offender who had been to prison for multiple counts of rape against little girls like me. It was bad, and i was extremely sheltered, but we had no other choice. Finally, my mom moved us to economically stable Texas, and now she, my dad and my little bro are living the good life while I'm in college working my ass off with naught a penny from her—not to worry, I had 8 good years of fancy living. 

While I personally do not wish for a much riches as I've had in the past, I am so damn proud of my mom for what she's done. She even stayed with my dad after they divorced so that my brother and I could have a parent there to raise us while she worked rather than a nanny (he lives in the guest room, it's a bit odd but it works). 

So now that you understand that not *all* rich people are undeserving snobs, the ones who have tasted dirt poor as well as filthy rich definitely help the poor. Basically, don't make assumptions based on nice clothes and pretty cars. They might care just as much as you. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
