<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26643691594.0" user="Democritos" delta="False">
    <text>I'm gonna assume you're talking about the very common "Lets tax the rich a bit more" sentiment but not the very uncommon "X is literally the devil for being rich and not giving it all away".

The socialist arguments are many but some of the most pervasive is how did they amass their wealth? Did they live off the land and hunt their way all alone for wealth eventually to become as rich as they are? Nope. They lived in a society made up of everyone where they used the schools, roads, health care just like everyone else. This is what allowed them to get the opportunity to even get as rich as they got. Which is why they should give something back. 

Another argument is simply results. Social democracy has worked wonders for the Nordic countries that are now on the top of pretty much every chart for the quality of life imaginable. Meanwhile studies are showing time after time that probably the most important aspect of a nation is the distribution of wealth, the bigger the gap the lower the quality of life (life expectancy, crime rate, overall happiness, you name it) *for everyone*, even the rich. 

Then there's the fact that the top 1% are actually paying a *far* smaller percentage than the average Joe. Warren Buffet (formerly the richest man in the world, now third) once famously stated that his tax rate was lower than his secretary's which thought was simply ridiculous. 

Honestly though a lot of it is sensationalism. I must admit that personally I fall for it but I can very well understand why not everyone does. That simply while there are people starving on the streets it's a bit douchy to bath in your champagne while fighting tooth and nail against every and any possible tax raise. 

Edit: Tl;dr: Basically an explanation and expansion on would you rather have 5 rich people and 5 poor vs 10 pretty comfortably middle class?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643712511.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>True but all those things should managed by the government by implementing diff tax rates for diff incomes, wealth distribution etc... not the generosity of rich people, right? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643715432.0" user="Democritos" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, you're right. It's a closely related idea but not quite the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643723150.0" user="Democritos" delta="False">
    <text>You are talking about that they should willingly give it up? Then I kinda fall back on the last point, you don't *need* a private jet, or a mansion, or a 20.000$ pearl necklace. On the other hand a person *needs* food. Like someone else pointed out in this thread, if 10 poor people are literally starving and we want them fed (why? Because having starving people sucks) and we want to decide who feeds them then it makes sense to pick the person who won't feel it as much. Ie. if you pick the average Joe and tell him to feed an extra 10 people he'll go bankrupt in no time. If you'd do the same to Bernard Arnault he wouldn't even notice it without you letting him know beforehand. He simply has so much that to feed these extra people becomes irrelevant. 

But *why* do we really not want people starving? Is it acceptable to give up someone else's (presumably) hard earned wealth to guarantee that everyone has shelter for the night? Those are hard questions, however I personally think it's unacceptable to leave people without food or shelter. Everyone should contribute each according to his ability. The people that can feed 10 people without it really affecting them should give more away than the person who can barely afford to add a dog.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643734238.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>Now again, this falls under the governemnts responsibility. The rich pay taxes just like us, I realize that they pay less percent, but even then... if you pay 30% and they pay 5%, they will still be puttin in more money than you will, hence they are helping others more than the average blow already....

Haha I understand what you are trying to say but I still dont agree with it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644074226.0" user="Valkurich" delta="False">
    <text>They are putting in more total but less percent of their work and income.. Your saying they're still helping more is like my saying that superman running two marathons is more difficult for him than me running one.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
