<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26643758216.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>To gauge where you're at before I craft an argument fitted to you, can I ask a hypothetical?

Imagine that two people are instantly transported into a cave with no memories of who they are or how they got there. They each find they're wearing backpacks. One of them has only a single saltine and the other has a pack crammed with sandwiches and all sorts of non-perishable, tasty foodstuffs and bottled water.

A sign on the wall says they'll be let out in a week.

Should the person with the full pack share his food?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643763655.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>He does not HAVE to,  but most people will. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643765034.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>Of course he doesn't have to. But would you think less of him if he didn't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643766851.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>Does it matter? He still has no obligationto give the food. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643775069.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say your answer would automatically entail an obligation. I said at the beginning of my first post I'm trying to figure where your head is at so I can make an argument crafted just for you.

So I think it does matter. Would you think less of a person who didn't share their food in the example above and let their cave-mate starve to death when there was plenty for both of them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643782202.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. There are tons of people doing that right now, to a lesser extent. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643784113.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>Then you've got no empathy and nothing will convince you otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643788537.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>Haha no, Im just a moral nilhist. I prefer pragmatic views. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643791416.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a moral anti-realist. But I have an emotional connection to my fellow humans.

It doesn't take an objective moral position to think that choosing to condemn another human to death for no reason is icky and does not befit the sort of person one might like to hang out with.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643795098.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>I am def the most "icky" person I know too! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644215390.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'd disagree. Considering he's a nihilist and that HVC up in the post above, I would say that no *emotional* argument would convince him otherwise, because as a nihilist, he doesn't attach any importance to emotions whatsoever.

however, if you used a *logical* argument to show how unhappy poor people could affect him, as /u/amemut did up above, then you could easily change his view, considering he's open to other viewpoints.

TL;DR: OP isn't really open to ALL other viewpoints, just logical ones because those are the only ones he cares about. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644210714.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Answer the question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644335288.0" user="breauxstradamus" delta="False">
    <text>What if there is only enough food for one of you to make it for the week, but if divided, you'd both starve to death?
If you were the one without the food, would you expect the man to just give it to you? I know, I would try to find something to hunt or fish.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644368446.0" user="Cavemonster" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What if there is only enough food for one of you to make it for the week, but if divided, you'd both starve to death?

That's not the hypothetical.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26651360836.0" user="Dieddoingsafetydance" delta="False">
    <text>This question assumes neither did anything to earn what they have, such a scenario makes it very easy to demonise a selfish man whilst the real world is not so simple. I believe a large part of the wealthy today worked for that and that the poor and not so wealthy wound up in their situation on account of their own decisions. Your model suggests this is impossible and brings about only one possible answer, of course the man should share. 

If we expanded the concept wherein both individuals made choices which directly resulted in what they had in their backpacks we simply asked what should happen (should one die whilst the other lives, should the plentiful man be forced to share ect) we would have a far more revealing and less biased question.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
