<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26644038440.0" user="salami_inferno" delta="False">
    <text>Ok say I found you in an extremely dangerous situation and could save your life with no risk to my own. Would you be ok with me just saying I don't want to and walking away and saying screw you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644344495.0" user="breauxstradamus" delta="False">
    <text>I'd think you were a prick, but I wouldn't kill you for it if I escaped. Though if you had put me in that situation, the story would be different. Everyone seems to forget, that capitalism is supposed to be win win. You have something I want more than I want my money, so I will pay you for it. I have too much food to eat, so give me money and I will trade you and equal value of food. Everybody wins! I hate when people start hating on Walmart, and the "Capitalist Pigs." Because without them, nobody would have any fucking food, and the food we did have would certainly not be cheap.
EDIT: Rich people are rich, because they provided something of worth, and everyone paid them for it. We need a new adjective for the Bankers that are regulating the economy and fucking everyone over. They're the real reason the economy sucks and everyone is poor. It's not because of people like Bill Gates and Sam Walton</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
