<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26643837826.0" user="cat_mech" delta="False">
    <text>The wealthy, all the way up to and including the wealthiest echelon of society- the capitalist class- (which is not the same capitalism as your common business owner- the capitalist class is entrenched capitalism as a class structure, exists purely off the profit of others and produces nothing nor ever labours or engages in labour) not just benefit from the poverty of others but in truth actually needs poverty to exist and absolutely requires the poor in order to maintain their existence and way of life.   
      
This concept- that the rich must ensure that a certain level of poverty exists constantly- is a basic tenet of Marxism.   
        
Without a steady stream of impoverished labour, it becomes increasingly difficult to find workers to fulfill the myriad of mundane occupations that, when performed for the benefit of the upper class, free the wealthiest from the standard toils of subsistence living. Things like farming, mining, construction, waste disposal and energy maintenance are all the responsibility of lesser classes, but of which the wealthy benefit.   
       
This allows the wealthy to dedicate their time to whatever they desire, giving them a complete freedom of life direction.    
        
In order to maintain this freedom, the wealthy must ensure- varying from one society to the next- certain standards to the labour class that keep them relatively content enough to continue labouring in the best interests of the capitalist class. Depending on each society, failing to meet certain expected societal standards become unacceptable to allow en masse and in turn lead to the labour pool re-dedicating it's time towards resolving self interests. (Food shortages, illnesses, hostile environments, etc)    
      
In short, without the poor to do their work for them, the wealthy would lose the benefits of their class, and thus have a vested interest in maintaining standards deemed acceptable to the health and well being of the labour pool/impoverished.    
       
Also, helping others is generally considered a natural impulse, not an anomaly, and more often than not simply a side effect of having a fucking soul.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
