<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26643679398.0" user="Eishkimo" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, cancer isn't exactly a disease that favours poor people over rich people, so I find the example of that as being a bit misplaced in the context of the rest of your post.

Otherwise, what do you mean, exactly, by *obligation*? Social? Moral? Existential?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643682508.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry for the terrible example, but I am talking about social obligations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643706877.0" user="Eishkimo" delta="False">
    <text>Well, in terms of a social obligation, then, it's very hard to change your view as it's pretty clear that there is no obligation as such.

That said, there are certainly plenty of arguments as to why more affluent people would give more than less affluent people to charitable causes.

The obvious one is altruism &amp;amp; empathy, of course. There's very little to be expanded upon there.

A more utilitarian approach is to consider that $10,000 to a super-rich person is worth less than $10,000 to someone less wealthy. Even $5 dollars to me is worth so much more to someone without much expendable income (or no income). Someone like Bill Gates (who's very charitable with his money---probably for this exact reason) will be impacted almost imperceptibly by losing denominations as large as tens of thousands, if not more, but the impact of that money goes up when given to someone for whom that denomination is still relatively big.

Where PR is a concern, there's something to be said for putting up some sort of façade of having a social conscience. People like to feel like they're making some sort of moralistic contribution to the world, so if such-and-such a company is fairtrade, or helps such-and-such a collection of downtrodden people, they will draw in more customers. The extra hype from publicising charitable donations might even draw in more money than is involved in the donations. If not, it certainly will draw at least a solid consumer-base who are loyal to the brand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26644341328.0" user="breauxstradamus" delta="False">
    <text>I agree the rich should help the poor, my point of concern is why does anyone else get to decide what their money is worth to them? Oh $10,000 to a rich guy is nothing, but to me I could live half a year. So what? So you deserve that guys money? Aside from the .1% rich people, usually wealthier people, have nicer homes and cars and higher bills. They don't just walk around with all this pocket cash, just spending away while everyone suffers. They pay taxes, and you'd be surprised how many are charitable. Fuck anyone who would tell them, they can't live in that house because they're not helping enough poor people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
