<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="766921320.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/colsa0/cmv_the_argument_that_free_college_will_devalue/">
    <title>CMV: The argument that free college will "devalue post secondary education" does not make sense and should never be used when debating whether or not college should be free.</title>
    <original_poster>JoahTheProtozoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I totally understand people who don't want college to be free just due to the sheer amount of money it would cost the government (even I am on the fence about the issue), I have often heard the argument that it will devalue post secondary education and find that ridiculous.

Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college. Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive. Plus the argument seems borderline to be saying "if college was free, I would have to compete with poor people who before didn't have the means to compete for my job, making it more difficult for me to be employed." I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

I've seen this argument made enough times that I'm wondering if there's any actual substance to it and I'm missing something or if their's something about job applications I don't understand.

Edit: Grammar

Edit: I understand my definition of devalue was a bit iffy. I was using it more of the sense that although the price of bread can change depending on how much of it their is, its value for treating hunger is still always constant, so bread can't be devalued. I've already given out a delta for my definition being flawed so no more will be given out for explaining the same thing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32442636824.0" user="eatmoarpotatos" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college.

That's not entirely true. The average IQ of a college student has fallen drastically. The admissions opened up as soon as the government guaranteed loans to anyone that wanted them. Now almost anyone can get in after a semester of community college. 

Businesses know that college *does not* train you for the various jobs out there for the most part. (barring med school, law, nursing and other professional occupations) 
College simply takes the role of screening applicants. Instead of a company having to fairly evaluate any and every application for employment, they allow the college to screen applicants via the admissions process. 

The bitter reality is that you don't have to be very intelligent to do most jobs. However, intelligent people can do those jobs more effectively and streamline them along the way. Businesses have a vested interest in hiring the best and the brightest. College is supposed to be a very high hoop to jump through. It's innately meritocratic given that scholarships exist for those who are insanely talented despite a lack of resources. 

If you let anyone in to college, it doesn't properly filter future applicants. All a college degree will say is that you spent four years not working. 
The university is a business and wants students, so they have an interest in making it more attainable. 

People make an argument now that college graduates weren't properly screened. 
When I was in college all you had to do was ramble off some cliff notes about a book you didn't bother reading anyway.  In my experience college was too easy. I'm not very intelligent at all, and I managed a 3.2 on top of the workload of a full time job. 
When I look back at going to college, I wonder why I thought sitting next to some purple haired womanchild was worth the debt.
I could have started my career earlier.  If anything it held me back not only from the debt to go, but also the time and energy I could have spent on just my career and charging forward in my role.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442687562.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>The ability to pay for college has nothing/very little to do with your intelligence or grit which is the thing that employers look for. Making college free doesn't mean that there would be no admissions process. Colleges will still be able to screen applicants, regardless of whether or not they are free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442942782.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The ability to pay for college has nothing/very little to do with your intelligence or grit which is the thing that employers look for

it is true that some people are in more lucky situations than others. However, I think you've got a pretty cookie cutter idea about kids who are born privileged, vs. kids who are not. There is in fact a wide range of financial difficulties that people face, and not all of them are equal. However, the people who have legitimately no financial concern, when it comes to a financial situation as significant as tuition, is a smaller group than you seem to be indicating. 

I did not grow up wealthy, but I by no means grew up poor either. My financial situation is still very much my responsibility, and my ability to pay for things, is very directly related to how good my decisions are. You might think that there are also plenty of people born richer than me, who would not have to say the same, but financial concerns are the norm for young people. There isn't 1 camp of young people, who can barely afford to eat, and then another camp of young people who have whatever they want handed to them. 


While financial barriers are not applied in equal measure to everyone's life, they are still applied to enough people's lives, to the point where it might not be accurate for you to just look at it as something that effects 1 of 2 general camps.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442967677.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>**Δ** for the fact that being good at managing finances would be something the jobs look for in an employee. I hadn't considered that, and while I'm sure there must be other ways to test for this, college would be one of them. Out of curiosity, do you think many employers care about this (obviously excluding jobs in finance) or is it a relatively minor concern?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443036684.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>imagine if I were an employer, and I had to choose between 2 applicants. They both came from the exact same impressive school, and they both god identically impressive grades. However, 1 of them was just a little out of shape, and the other was a successful student athlete. Being a successful student athlete would matter to me, and I don't see that as shallow at all. You've got to consider that he'd have to put in all that effort, and commitment, in order to keep his body, and his athletic skills sharp. He'd also have to commit to all the scheduling related to his team. If he managed to do all that successfully, and STILL get the same academic results as the other applicant, that would mean something. Yes, being a student athlete isn't relevant to the cariculum, or the grades, but it's another factor, which impacts that student's engagement with the curriculum, and the grades. 

ideally, at least in theory, the curriculum is there to equip the students with knowledge, and hopefully it does do that, but on top of that, the curriculum is there to provide students with a situation, where in they can demonstrate what they have to offer as people. The students try to reach a certain end goal, and along that journey, they grow. They don't just grow because of the material. The growth is an all encompassing exercise. an all encompassing exercise, wherein the financial commitment/considerations play a role.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443073429.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>Following that logic, wouldn't that mean that colleges would hire someone who was poorer because their college life was more difficult, but I've never heard of people doing that. (Maybe they have and I just haven't heard of it).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443149846.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>It's harder to apply that logic to economic background, as opposed to being a star athlete. Being a successful star athlete, and being successful at it, without having worse grades to show for it, is something which you can very simply say, reflects well on those grades. There is no reason, based strictly on those 2 bits of information (their success as an athlete, and their grades) that the commitment to sports makes that applicant any LESS favorable as a person. There might be other things about them, that make less favorable, but not their commitment to sports.

if you have 2 applicants with equal grades, from the same school, and one of them is poorer, it could very well be the case that that speaks to them being the better applicant, as it means that they could've had a tougher rode. So, based on that, you could draw a parallel to academics, and economic status (less so if college was free however) However, while poverty MIGHT indicate that, unlike with the example of an athlete, you can't stop there as far as the things that their poverty might indicate about them. 

Economic status can be linked to the stability of ones, family, and so the stability of their upbringing, both in terms of parental guidance, and otherwise. Just take that as one example. I'm not saying that that necessarily means you should be more skeptical about hiring a poor person. There are perspectives that could make their poverty reflect well on them, and there are perspectives that might not. Neither perspective necessarily deserves to win out, but unlike with the example of a student athlete, the possible perspectives aren't all necessarily flattering.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443521410.0" user="eatmoarpotatos" delta="False">
    <text>Here's an easy argument then..  Higher education is not a right. You're not entitled to the lectures, exams or knowledge that college provides.  If you truly desire those things, put your money where your mouth is. Not everyone can write a check for college, but everybody can take out loans for tuition and books.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443555638.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>The fact that higher education should not be a right is an opinion not a fact. If you're going to state it like it is one, you need to have some reasoning behind it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32445104068.0" user="eatmoarpotatos" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say 'should' I said it isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32446782665.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>What if one believes higher education should be a right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32447922605.0" user="eatmoarpotatos" delta="False">
    <text>I'd say push for policies that recognize higher education as a human right. But understand that many of us would find that ridiculous. Human rights are not trivial pieces of legislature. At some point, you're devaluing the term. It's already recognized by the UN that the right to work and attain an education is an inherent human right. I don't think a particular sect of institutions should be narrowed down as a right as well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
