<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="766921320.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/colsa0/cmv_the_argument_that_free_college_will_devalue/">
    <title>CMV: The argument that free college will "devalue post secondary education" does not make sense and should never be used when debating whether or not college should be free.</title>
    <original_poster>JoahTheProtozoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I totally understand people who don't want college to be free just due to the sheer amount of money it would cost the government (even I am on the fence about the issue), I have often heard the argument that it will devalue post secondary education and find that ridiculous.

Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college. Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive. Plus the argument seems borderline to be saying "if college was free, I would have to compete with poor people who before didn't have the means to compete for my job, making it more difficult for me to be employed." I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

I've seen this argument made enough times that I'm wondering if there's any actual substance to it and I'm missing something or if their's something about job applications I don't understand.

Edit: Grammar

Edit: I understand my definition of devalue was a bit iffy. I was using it more of the sense that although the price of bread can change depending on how much of it their is, its value for treating hunger is still always constant, so bread can't be devalued. I've already given out a delta for my definition being flawed so no more will be given out for explaining the same thing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32442603792.0" user="Roflwaffle10" delta="False">
    <text>Whenever you make something free its value is inherantly devalued. When speaking of education, it's something I like to call "education inflation". If college if free for everyone, then most people will have a degree. If most people have a degree, that value of that degree in a competitive work environment is devalued. That's not really an opinion, that's just basic economics.

And to say that something "should never be used when debating" is just asking for anyone to counter with a free speech comment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442638697.0" user="tit_wrangler" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; f college if free for everyone, then most people will have a degree.

Why do you assume that free tuition equals colleges expanding their population quotas and dropping academic standards/prerequisites?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32444532263.0" user="Roflwaffle10" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say that, you did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32444635165.0" user="tit_wrangler" delta="False">
    <text>Ok then. Why do you assume that there would be more degrees? If the cost of college is subsidized, why would colleges admit more people than they currently do? As it currently stands, colleges are largely funded by the student populations (plus endowments, plus some subsidies for state colleges). So if anything, the current model would encourage colleges to expand their population to reap more money. But if colleges were very largely funded from taxes--to the point where students did not pay tuition or board--that would necessitate a pretty finite amount of resources and therefore student population. In turn, colleges would still have to maintain a certain quota for students and the academic standards inherent in the admission process. Moreover, there would still be different colleges with different standards/levels of prestige, which would not at all make every degree equal. Ultimately, there's nothing to suggest that a lower cost for students would result in colleges admitting more students or devaluing all degrees. 

I'm sorry if it sounds like I'm making assumptions about your argument, but your argument has a lot of unsaid assumptions that, without some explanation, forces me to invent some logic in other to attempt to address it; your logical steps, on their own, doesn't really line up with how the reality of upper education works.

&amp;gt; That's not really an opinion, that's just basic economics. 

It's neither. The valuation of an educational degree is not only not a matter of economics, it's not even a good analogy. But first, you still have to prove your first assertion that lower cost for students=more degrees.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442665492.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>To your first point, see my edit. To your second point, I clearly didn't mean it should legally be prevented from being used in an argument. I was saying that it is not productive to argue that point.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
