<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="766921320.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/colsa0/cmv_the_argument_that_free_college_will_devalue/">
    <title>CMV: The argument that free college will "devalue post secondary education" does not make sense and should never be used when debating whether or not college should be free.</title>
    <original_poster>JoahTheProtozoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I totally understand people who don't want college to be free just due to the sheer amount of money it would cost the government (even I am on the fence about the issue), I have often heard the argument that it will devalue post secondary education and find that ridiculous.

Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college. Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive. Plus the argument seems borderline to be saying "if college was free, I would have to compete with poor people who before didn't have the means to compete for my job, making it more difficult for me to be employed." I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

I've seen this argument made enough times that I'm wondering if there's any actual substance to it and I'm missing something or if their's something about job applications I don't understand.

Edit: Grammar

Edit: I understand my definition of devalue was a bit iffy. I was using it more of the sense that although the price of bread can change depending on how much of it their is, its value for treating hunger is still always constant, so bread can't be devalued. I've already given out a delta for my definition being flawed so no more will be given out for explaining the same thing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32442470644.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it would just mean that other people are now more competitive.


This is the same as a devaluation of a degree. If there is more competition it nessecerily means there is less opportunities to go around.

&amp;gt; I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

Its a valid concern. Objectively, an increase in the availability of labor depresses wages. Its very plain to see, that in states where illegal labor is prevalent the wages are so depressed for those industries, they have been all but conceded to immigrant workers. Now a common argument is that "people don't want to do that work." But the wages did not rebound to reflect legal minimum wages. This is especially true in California, where illegal labor is nowhere near the $15 an hour minimum wage we have.

Now, I will come in right at the average personally, 30k in student loan debt. I don't want to make double or triple on that, I want to make like 35x on that investment over my life time. But the thing I keep hearing from my advisers and other support coordination staff and that's really scary, and wasn't the case when I entered college is that a degree is not the guarantee of personal security it used to be, and college isn't even free yet. Back in the 60s, a high school degree used to be enough to live comfortably and retire on. Now we are at the cusp of having to entertain that same discussion for Master's degrees. So yes free college is a legitimate concern, especially if it does not come coupled with student loan forgiveness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442539569.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>At the risk of getting off topic from my original argument, if a high school degree used to be enough to live comfortably and high school was free, now that many think a college degree is required to live comfortably, shouldn't that be free?

Also, I don't see how illegal immigrants are relevant since the work that an illegal immigrant does and the work that a college graduate does don't really overlap.

I do see how the amount that wages are depressed for some jobs might not equal the amount of wage gained by others and could seeing that being used as an argument, especially by those who don't prioritize increasing social mobility so I will give you a **Δ** for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443269428.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;At the risk of getting off topic from my original argument, if a high school degree used to be enough to live comfortably and high school was free, now that many think a college degree is required to live comfortably, shouldn't that be free?

The key difference, and one that plagues many people, and one that won't change is that the biggest hurdle to college is the *opportunity cost* it presents. High school students are minors, and have an obligation of care from their parents, but that doesn't exist for adults/college students. I don't think free tuition even begins to solve this issue, because for many its not that they can't afford the dollar amount of tuition. Loans exist for that *its everything else*. For example, my brothers are terrified of taking on debt because they don't understand it. Now California pays their tuition (Bog waiver) and they are still having to work 35 hours a week *to attend school.* That 35 hour work obligation is cutting into their academic capacities, it means that they are taking less units a semester and that protracts into a greatly increased cost. It means their salary tracks will be impacted when they seek out career level work (less time before retirement.) It also means that they are losing time on earning a potentially higher rate of pay sooner because it will take them 2-4 additional semesters to complete college (summer semesters do help mitigate this length) Wheras I took on debt, and took 17-20 unit semesters and will likely be completed in less time overall (I attended college much later than them due to previous career opportunities and the economic climate at the time.)

Now, if you are advocating for more comprehensive financial aid packages that's one thing. *But politicians aren't.* Most politicians are advocating for *just free tuition and among those a greater deal are only talking about associates degrees which are pretty worthless these days.*
 That means everything else (Books, Rent, food etc.) is still on the student to pay for, and thus the burden of opportunity still exists. In fact, I'd argue that in California at least Tuition is the lesser of my costs. I pay $3300 a semester ($6600 a year) to attend full time. My BA will have only costed me $12000 in  strictly tuition. Keeping my car running while I commute to school, paying my bills and everything else is actually what's prohibitive about attending school.

&amp;gt;Also, I don't see how illegal immigrants are relevant since the work that an illegal immigrant does and the work that a college graduate does don't really overlap.


Its relevant because again it will depress wages due to the availability of labor. You can replace it with literally any example, its just more pronounced with illegal immigrant work because they can be paid below minimum wage and can't demand more because there are too many workers available.



&amp;gt;I do see how the amount that wages are depressed for some jobs might not equal the amount of wage gained by others and could seeing that being used as an argument, especially by those who don't prioritize increasing social mobility so I will give you a Δ for that.

You also have to consider that a good deal of un-specialized jobs have a great deal of degree overlap. An English Major and a History Major can both be paralegals or secretaries. Whereas a logistics major and a computer science major have almost no overlap (but both are much smaller fields of study than the former.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443471821.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't your first point an argument for free college and financial assistance?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443548424.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>No, its an argument against. Policy should *solve a problem.* If it can't solve a problem we shouldn't even be evaluating it. Now like I said, if you are advocating for improved financial aid that's one thing. 

But "Free college" as a colloquialism does not include improved financial aid, just low/no cost tuition.

The rest of my point is there to illustrate that despite having tuition fully paid for, the current amount of support still makes college completion difficult. We either need policy that accounts for the difference, or we shouldn't be offering free college, because millions of students with half a degree isn't actually going to benefit the public, which is what our tax dollars should be doing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443593982.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>I meant isn't it an argument for free college WITH financial assistance? (sorry)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443728989.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but then I reiterate: Politicians are *not* advocating for that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443266667.0" user="MelodicConference4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If there is more competition it nessecerily means there is less opportunities to go around.

Presuming finite consumption. Human desire isnt finite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443518737.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>Setting aside the fact that over consumption shouldn't be promoted (its a key flaw of capitalism.)

Human Desire absolutely has diminishing returns, otherwise billionaires would live well in excess of what they do. People clearly don't buy a 10th Jet ski even when they can't afford it, most barely buy a *second* jet ski.

Your argument is essentially a platitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443547370.0" user="MelodicConference4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Setting aside the fact that over consumption shouldn't be promoted 

It should be. That "over consumption" has now made running water and electricity a mainstay instead of a luxury

&amp;gt; Human Desire absolutely has diminishing returns

On the individual, sure. We are talking about how it affects society as a whole though, and those individual diminishing returns add up to incredible accomplishments. Just look at what we have done in regards to medical research in the last 50 years - we have done absolutely nothing groundbreaking, but a lot of tiny individual steps which have brought medicide to a hell of a lot higher quality</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443561394.0" user="championofobscurity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It should be. That "over consumption" has now made running water and electricity a mainstay instead of a luxury

Yeah and it's also causing our polar ice caps to melt and we are facing impending death by burning globally. Or yknow putting plastic particles in our salt, that we cannot distinguish making plastic a part of the human experience.

&amp;gt; Just look at what we have done in regards to medical research in the last 50 years - we have done absolutely nothing groundbreaking

Literally invented gene editing but okay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443658624.0" user="MelodicConference4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah and it's also causing our polar ice caps to melt and we are facing impending death by burning globally.

No, we are facing a foot of sea level rise, which can be dealt with easily. 

&amp;gt; Literally invented gene editing but okay.

That wasnt one invention, that was hundreds.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
