<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="766921320.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/colsa0/cmv_the_argument_that_free_college_will_devalue/">
    <title>CMV: The argument that free college will "devalue post secondary education" does not make sense and should never be used when debating whether or not college should be free.</title>
    <original_poster>JoahTheProtozoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I totally understand people who don't want college to be free just due to the sheer amount of money it would cost the government (even I am on the fence about the issue), I have often heard the argument that it will devalue post secondary education and find that ridiculous.

Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college. Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive. Plus the argument seems borderline to be saying "if college was free, I would have to compete with poor people who before didn't have the means to compete for my job, making it more difficult for me to be employed." I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

I've seen this argument made enough times that I'm wondering if there's any actual substance to it and I'm missing something or if their's something about job applications I don't understand.

Edit: Grammar

Edit: I understand my definition of devalue was a bit iffy. I was using it more of the sense that although the price of bread can change depending on how much of it their is, its value for treating hunger is still always constant, so bread can't be devalued. I've already given out a delta for my definition being flawed so no more will be given out for explaining the same thing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32443811821.0" user="2plus24" delta="False">
    <text>It also means colleges could be more picky on who they let in, making them more competitive.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
