<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="766921320.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/colsa0/cmv_the_argument_that_free_college_will_devalue/">
    <title>CMV: The argument that free college will "devalue post secondary education" does not make sense and should never be used when debating whether or not college should be free.</title>
    <original_poster>JoahTheProtozoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I totally understand people who don't want college to be free just due to the sheer amount of money it would cost the government (even I am on the fence about the issue), I have often heard the argument that it will devalue post secondary education and find that ridiculous.

Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college. Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive. Plus the argument seems borderline to be saying "if college was free, I would have to compete with poor people who before didn't have the means to compete for my job, making it more difficult for me to be employed." I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

I've seen this argument made enough times that I'm wondering if there's any actual substance to it and I'm missing something or if their's something about job applications I don't understand.

Edit: Grammar

Edit: I understand my definition of devalue was a bit iffy. I was using it more of the sense that although the price of bread can change depending on how much of it their is, its value for treating hunger is still always constant, so bread can't be devalued. I've already given out a delta for my definition being flawed so no more will be given out for explaining the same thing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32442183822.0" user="Flexit4Brexit" delta="False">
    <text>*"Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive."*
 
When people talk about devaluation, they're talking about economic devaluation, i.e.: wages. I think you're assuming there's a broader definition than is the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442257420.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, I agree that average wage would go down for college students, but I still don't think that should be used in an argument unless one also argues that average wage for everyone would go down. Is there an argument to be made that and average wage decrease for college students would be bad and if so what would that be?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442334516.0" user="Flexit4Brexit" delta="False">
    <text>The idea is that there's a return on a college degree. For example, you pay $30,000 for the degree, and it boosts your lifetime earnings by $40,000, therefore getting the college degree puts you $10,000 ahead than you would be otherwise. 

There are two possibilities. 1. The college degree is making you better off, in which case, why aren't you paying for it - *you're* becoming better off! 2. The college degree isn't making you better off, in which case, why is *anybody* paying for it - your life isn't better!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442374320.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>For option 1: You might not be able to obtain the loan, but that is off topic as option 1 is a legitimate argument against free college that does not have to do with devaluing post secondary.

For option 2: Unless I'm misinterpreting what you're saying, nobody would go to college if they didn't think it would make them better off so option 2 is a non-issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442430390.0" user="Flexit4Brexit" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't explain option 2 very well. Let's imagine a hypothetical scenario. Say, going to Caltech costs $30k. However, going to Caltech only boosts your lifetime earnings by $20k. Therefore, by attending Caltech you're -$10k. (It's irrational to attend.)

However, if you shift payment to the taxpayers, it will be rational for you to attend, because now you're +$20k. (It's rational to attend.)

Nonetheless, it's ridiculous, because taxpayers have paid $30k to boost your lifetime earnings by $20k. Cutting you a cheque for $21k would make *you* better off (because $21k &amp;gt; $20k) *and* it would make the taxpayers better off (because $21k &amp;lt; $30k). I.e.: The taxpayers and the tax recipient are better off *if* we do something else. (It's suboptimal to attend.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442473274.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>In a timeline where only primary school was free right now, couldn't someone make the exact same argument about making secondary school free? And yet, most people agree that free high school is a good thing. Why does this argument work for college but not for high school?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442523229.0" user="Flexit4Brexit" delta="False">
    <text>It's an economic argument, it works for anything. The question is whether or not we should listen to it for everything. For example, sports science might tell us that taller kids are going to be better at basketball, but we let everyone play basketball during PE. In short, everyone has a soft spot for kids, we cut them all kinds of breaks, and we're glad to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442559378.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>I just realized that the "devaluing of post secondary education" argument can be used as a roundabout way for getting to the "free college would be too expensive" argument, and while I still don't think the former should be if it just leads the the latter, I can see how some people would find it important to use. **Δ** for you</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442591707.0" user="Flexit4Brexit" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442532953.0" user="defactron" delta="False">
    <text>If college is for you solely a tool to "boost your lifetime earnings" then something is probably wrong don't you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32442569167.0" user="Flexit4Brexit" delta="False">
    <text>Possibly, or possibly something is wrong with college, e.g.: it's marketing itself as something it's not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32445364804.0" user="Akitten" delta="False">
    <text>Why? In most countries, education is generally seen as a way to boost earnings in the end. Why are you different?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
