<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="766921320.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/colsa0/cmv_the_argument_that_free_college_will_devalue/">
    <title>CMV: The argument that free college will "devalue post secondary education" does not make sense and should never be used when debating whether or not college should be free.</title>
    <original_poster>JoahTheProtozoa</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I totally understand people who don't want college to be free just due to the sheer amount of money it would cost the government (even I am on the fence about the issue), I have often heard the argument that it will devalue post secondary education and find that ridiculous.

Employers don't want you to have a college degree because it shows how much money you have, they want you to have one because it shows you had enough grit to get through college. Even though free college would mean that more people have college degrees, this wouldn't mean that your post secondary education was devalued, it would just mean that other people are now more competitive. Plus the argument seems borderline to be saying "if college was free, I would have to compete with poor people who before didn't have the means to compete for my job, making it more difficult for me to be employed." I know people aren't actually thinking this when making the argument, but it seems to me that that is unconsciously their main concern.

I've seen this argument made enough times that I'm wondering if there's any actual substance to it and I'm missing something or if their's something about job applications I don't understand.

Edit: Grammar

Edit: I understand my definition of devalue was a bit iffy. I was using it more of the sense that although the price of bread can change depending on how much of it their is, its value for treating hunger is still always constant, so bread can't be devalued. I've already given out a delta for my definition being flawed so no more will be given out for explaining the same thing.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32443055272.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Right now, we let pretty much anyone into college - dumb or smart, poor or rich.  People who are both uninterested in academics *and* poor usually don't bother because it's a heck of a lot of money to pay back and college is a waste for them.

If we had a functioning government we could solve this problem: make college free but shut down half the schools and thus raise standards.  I don't think our government is capable of doing that, so instead we'd have free college for anyone who wants.  More colleges will take advantage of the free money and admit students whose time there is wasted because "hey, the government is paying".  And those students may even get some free laptops and other kickbacks in exchange for enrolling.  That *will* devalue education in every sense of the word, as more people will enroll and be graduated with no intention of receiving an actual education - school gets money, student gets kickbacks, it's mutually beneficial.  Again, a functional government could easily avoid this.  I don't think anyone realistically expects the *US* could.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443087483.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>Sure anybody who wanted to could get into their local community college and coast, but it would still take effort to get into and succeed in and school past the base level, and interviewers would much rather hire someone from a top tier school than a local community college.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32443128780.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, and it won't devalue Stanford or community colleges.  It's the lower tier 4 year colleges that will be devalued.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32444984643.0" user="ihatepasswords1234" delta="False">
    <text>Right now NJ has a program that requires certain hurdles but if you meet those hurdles your education is free.

Maintain a certain GPA in high school and you can get to community college for free.

Maintain a certain GPA in the community college and graduate with your associate degree, you can go to Rutgers for free.

Maintain a certain GPA and the government will pay for your time at Rutgers until you graduate.

Why is this not a better system than making Rutgers free to all?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32444989484.0" user="JoahTheProtozoa" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say it wasn't.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
