<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="78227727.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1akowf/i_think_that_black_people_in_america_are_often_a/">
    <title>I think that black people in America are often a victim of their own culture more than a victim of discrimation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tomjoad76</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: I say black, not African-American. Many black people possibly have a longer history of ancestry in the U.S. than I do, and I never ask to be called a European-American.

I know this sounds terribly racist, and I apologize for offending people because I really do understand that people are often going to meet what expectations you set for them and not much more.

I am an open-minded and liberal white Southerner who has grown up with little exposure to black culture. However, what little I have seen seems to support criminal or irresponsible behavior. This is not to say that black people are all criminals or irresponsible, just that the general culture encourages these activities.

Hip-hop, the predominant choice of music for many black Americans, often promotes organized crime, prostitution, gun use, drug use, etc.

Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

Granted I do not know many black people, but of the ones I do know, it honestly seems like black people are typically much lazier (but I know some black people who do not fit this definition at all). I know that's not a scientific study at all, but a much higher percentage are unemployed, heavy drug users or alcoholics, or never try very hard in school, even in college. Unemployment rates are much higher among blacks than any other race. Again, I find it hard to believe this is entirely due to discrimination.

Black people are often more disrespectful than any other group (just a reminder, this is in my experience. I won't pretend like this is a scientific fact). There is a large black population on my campus, and anytime I have a class with a group of black students, it seems like those students will be very disrespectful to the professor or other students, e.g. interrupting class, coming in late, listening to music so loud on their headphones that everybody in the room can hear it. It's such an unfailing stereotype for me that I've come to dread anytime I see a large group of black students in my classes.

I know there are bad apples and good apples in every orchard. I feel bad because I often have these kinds of thoughts, and I am honestly no quicker to judge a black person I meet as a bad person than any other race. It simply seems to me like there is a black culture in the U.S. that encourages many vices.

I want to stop feeling racist. Help me change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26662841916.0" user="theorymeltfool" delta="False">
    <text>Well, while I agree that Black 'culture' has an absolutely negative influence (especially the blatant consumerism; you just can't be black unless you buy tons of sneakers, gold chains, music cds, etc.), but I think there's more to it than that.

I'd like to Change Your View that black people are *only* victims of their own culture. It's not just the culture that has a negative influence, but the Government that hands out benefits based on race (instead of need) and locks up 1 out of every 9 black men. It's a self perpetuating downward cycle that basically starts with Government discrimination. [The Last Psychiatrist has an excellent article about this.](http://thelastpsychiatrist.com/2010/04/why_is_it_so_hard_to_find_a_go.html) I know the culture may influence the crime, but then it becomes a chicken/egg type of thing. And the "Great Society" programs came before rap music, so maybe that's the cause. 

I'm not saying that all black people are like this, as there are lots of poor white people and poor people of other races that engage in the same type of behavior. I know several successful black engineers that act nothing like what you described.

Edit: What's with the downvotes? Please explain why you think I'm wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663075268.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Probably because of your first paragraph. I've noticed that people in this sub are a lot less tolerant of opposing opinions than they used to be. I think we're starting to develop a hivemind, and that REALLY worries me, because I came here to escape that. I think we should get rid of the downvote system. It might not solve the problem, but it would help a bit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663889510.0" user="_xXx_no_scope_xXx_" delta="False">
    <text>Just remember the only thing that matters is the delta!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663904380.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I sure hope so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663629615.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>why do people like you not know what culture is?

Mass advertising is part of culture but.. come on man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663676549.0" user="theorymeltfool" delta="False">
    <text>What are you talking about?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663692020.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm talking about you defining culture in a way that fits your argument, while ignoring the majority of what culture actually is in your response. 

You're either being self-serving, or ignorant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663952605.0" user="theorymeltfool" delta="False">
    <text>I never gave a definition of culture. 

&amp;gt; You're either being self-serving, or ignorant. 

Are you here to discuss things, or just insult people? If the latter, why not just go back to /r/politics. If I've gotten something wrong, just point it out. No reason to be an asshole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26664150823.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>errrr....  

Why is using the word self-serving or ignorant offensive?  How about you unbunch your panties there and grow up. 

That's what you're doing, can you suggest other words that would be less offensive to you?

ignorant isn't being an asshole, I'm ignorant about lots of stuff, so are you, so is everyone else. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26664175537.0" user="theorymeltfool" delta="False">
    <text>I took it that way because you didn't explain yourself or provide more information. Again,

&amp;gt; If I've gotten something wrong, just point it out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26664192789.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You have, and I already did.  Your description of why black people are not a victim of their culture, doesn't address black culture accurately at all. 

This leads me to the logical conclusion that your answer was either misinformed (here's me trying to be more polite, although I still think ignorant is the proper word), *or* that you purposefully interpreted culture as you did, to fit with your conclusion.

This is standard argument, that doesn't need to be hostile, I'm not sure why you are getting so upset / why you think I'm not contributing anything. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26664202448.0" user="theorymeltfool" delta="False">
    <text>Okay. Can we go back to the start? Please use the "&amp;gt;" symbol to copy &amp;amp; paste my points, so that I know what you're responding to.

&amp;gt; My statement

Your rebuttal

&amp;gt; My second statement

Your rebuttal.

I just want to make sure I know where I goofed on this. Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
