<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="78227727.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1akowf/i_think_that_black_people_in_america_are_often_a/">
    <title>I think that black people in America are often a victim of their own culture more than a victim of discrimation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tomjoad76</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: I say black, not African-American. Many black people possibly have a longer history of ancestry in the U.S. than I do, and I never ask to be called a European-American.

I know this sounds terribly racist, and I apologize for offending people because I really do understand that people are often going to meet what expectations you set for them and not much more.

I am an open-minded and liberal white Southerner who has grown up with little exposure to black culture. However, what little I have seen seems to support criminal or irresponsible behavior. This is not to say that black people are all criminals or irresponsible, just that the general culture encourages these activities.

Hip-hop, the predominant choice of music for many black Americans, often promotes organized crime, prostitution, gun use, drug use, etc.

Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

Granted I do not know many black people, but of the ones I do know, it honestly seems like black people are typically much lazier (but I know some black people who do not fit this definition at all). I know that's not a scientific study at all, but a much higher percentage are unemployed, heavy drug users or alcoholics, or never try very hard in school, even in college. Unemployment rates are much higher among blacks than any other race. Again, I find it hard to believe this is entirely due to discrimination.

Black people are often more disrespectful than any other group (just a reminder, this is in my experience. I won't pretend like this is a scientific fact). There is a large black population on my campus, and anytime I have a class with a group of black students, it seems like those students will be very disrespectful to the professor or other students, e.g. interrupting class, coming in late, listening to music so loud on their headphones that everybody in the room can hear it. It's such an unfailing stereotype for me that I've come to dread anytime I see a large group of black students in my classes.

I know there are bad apples and good apples in every orchard. I feel bad because I often have these kinds of thoughts, and I am honestly no quicker to judge a black person I meet as a bad person than any other race. It simply seems to me like there is a black culture in the U.S. that encourages many vices.

I want to stop feeling racist. Help me change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26663787974.0" user="_xXx_no_scope_xXx_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

&amp;gt; Here's question you might find interesting: Why is it you focus on race when you say that "Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males?  Why not focus on the fact they're *male*?

&amp;gt; I ask this because obviously males commit way more crimes than females.  Most rapists and murderers are men.  Most drug dealers, car thieves, child molesters, too.  The list is long.  Is it due to their war-like culture?  To their zombie-fied emotional states?  Is it video games?  It makes me wonder if men had a decent culture like women do, if maybe the crime rates wouldn't drop.  Female culture, with its emotional openness, promotion of touch and tenderness, really gives opportunities for individuals to become more fully human, rather than violent trolls.

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;  Men are often more disrespectful than any other group

&amp;gt; I know it's terrible.  Men tend to fail to recognize the subtle cues in a conversation.  Often they'll just drone on and on when all my girlfriends are rolling their eyes, like, 10 minutes ago.  When the professor makes a point, the boys will throw up their hands and act like they know it all.  They don't know how to sit still and listen.  They don't have any respect.  Isn't it time we stopped pandering to men, and started demanding respect?

IN RELATED NEWS

If you look around you'll find an interesting statistic.  Wherever there exists a longstanding cultural antagonism with a visible minority, you will find the males of that visible minority over-represented in the prison population.  Not 5%, but 20%.  Not 10%, but 40%.  Why?  

You either have to accept that that visible minority group is intrinsically criminal, or that society somehow filters those individuals into the criminal justice system.  Which is it?

According to you it's not because of discrimination.  Does that leave you holding the big prize: that blacks are intrinsically criminal?

But again, why not say men are intrinsically criminal?

How did you end up here?

NOW FOR SOMETHING COMPLETELY THE SAME

A slightly cleaned up version of OP's title:

&amp;gt; Black people in America are more often a victim of their own culture than a victim of discrimination by others / society.

In other words, the problems black people experience derive from their own community, and not from the wider community.

So the first move is to focus on black failures.  The second move is to generalize these failures as representative of black people as a whole, and perhaps even the destiny of blacks in general.  Finally, the responsibility for this failure is shifted to black people themselves, who are "more" responsible than society.  Society, its tolerance exhausted, justifiably wields only harsh punishment in the face of blacks destined to failure.

I think this is a miniature portrait of a racist ideology.  Much depends on the shift of responsibility.

In your defense, it is not wrong to say black culture is responsible.  It would be irresponsible of us to say culture has no influence.  What makes it racist in my view is the obsession that demands closure to questions that have no easy answers.  You want black culture to be responsible, so you can enjoy the portrait of self-inflicted failure for which you (even in an abstract sense) have (little or) no responsibility.  You want to see them as cows that have driven themselves into the ditch.

FINALLY

I don't like anti-racism that accuses anyone annoyed at things a group actually does.  If in your experience black people tend to disrupt class, who am I to say you are wrong?  The question is what do you do about it?  I think adding half-baked observations to your actual observations is not the way to go.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663838313.0" user="tomjoad76" delta="False">
    <text>I have to respond to this post because I think you went completely on the defensive, dismissed my point with little to no consideration, and tried to paint me as a closet racist to discredit me.

&amp;gt;Here's question you might find interesting: Why is it you focus on race when you say that "Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males? Why not focus on the fact they're male?

Because my post was not about gender. It was about race/ethnicity. Crime rates are much higher among black males than white males, Hispanic males, or Asian males.

&amp;gt;If you look around you'll find an interesting statistic. Wherever there exists a longstanding cultural antagonism with a visible minority, you will find the males of that visible minority over-represented in the prison population. Not 5%, but 20%. Not 10%, but 40%. Why? 

Why is the same not true for Hispanic males? Hispanics comprise a larger portion of the overall population than blacks and a smaller portion of the prison population. 

&amp;gt;You either have to accept that that visible minority group is intrinsically criminal, or that society somehow filters those individuals into the criminal justice system. Which is it?

&amp;gt;According to you it's not because of discrimination. Does that leave you holding the big prize: that blacks are intrinsically criminal?

You have taken false-dilemma to the extreme. I actually presented an alternative to those two ideas in my original post. I believe that there is a culture in black communities that promotes criminal activities. Furthermore, I never claimed that the discrepancy in crime rates was entirely unrelated to discrimination. I said that I find it hard to believe that it is due to discrimination and discrimination only. 

&amp;gt;But again, why not say men are intrinsically criminal?

That's 120% completely irrelevant to my post. First, I never said black people are intrinsically criminal. You said that. I said that there is a culture in many black communities that encourages crime. Furthermore, I think one could make a fairly good argument that men *are* in fact intrinsically criminal compared to women. Some studies have shown that men are naturally more aggressive than women. I was speaking of a **cultural** issue in **black communities**, not a **psychological** issue in **males**.

&amp;gt;In other words, the problems black people experience derive from their own community, and not from the wider community.

When did I say that the problems black people experience derive from their own community? I said that often black people are a victim of their culture more than discrimination. Does that mean that every problem black people face is because of their community? No. Does it mean that *most* of their problems stem from their community? No. It means that *often* their problems stem from their community.

&amp;gt;So the first move is to focus on black failures.

No. The first move was to identify a problem, i.e. disproportionately high crime rates among black people.

&amp;gt;The second move is to generalize these failures as representative of black people as a whole

No. The second move is to identify the cause of the problem. You seem to think that there is only one cause, and that cause is discrimination. I find that hard to believe, and I gave my reasoning above.

&amp;gt;and perhaps even the destiny of blacks in general

WUT???? Straw man much?

&amp;gt;What makes it racist in my view is the obsession that demands closure to questions that have no easy answers.

I have no idea what the obsession, closure, questions, or answers you speak of are referring to. You will have to elaborate.

&amp;gt;You want black culture to be responsible, so you can enjoy the portrait of self-inflicted failure for which you (even in an abstract sense) have (little or) no responsibility. You want to see them as cows that have driven themselves into the ditch.

I think you need to slow down. You didn't like what I had to say, so you tried to paint me as a racist to discredit my views. I actually don't want black culture to be responsible. I think you need to get to know me a little bit. 

I grew up in a very liberal family. My dad is one of the most anti-police people I have ever met. I grew up hearing stories of my dad being harassed, beaten, and illegally incarcerated and I have had a distrust of police officers since an early age. At the same time, while I had little exposure to black people, my parents raised me to believe that all people are equal, regardless of race or ethnicity. Believe it or not, they even raised me to believe that ALL of the problems black people faced were problems caused by discrimination from white people and police, in particular. This was a view that I held until very recently. It was actually very troubling for me to question this view because it went against everything I had been taught since a child. Initially, I, like yourself, thought that this was some sort of deeply hidden racist tendency coming out in me. 

Then I realized that culture =/= race. There are many more black people who are very good and respectable people than there are blacks who are criminals. Furthermore, black culture is not a product of black people alone. In fact, I think past discrimination is much more responsible for these issues in modern black culture than anything. None of that changes my view that there is a culture in black communities that encourages criminal or irresponsible activities, no matter what created that culture.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663876489.0" user="_xXx_no_scope_xXx_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I have to respond to this post because I think you went completely on the defensive, dismissed my point with little to no consideration, and tried to paint me as a closet racist to discredit me.

Hostile much?

I don't need to go on the defensive.  It's *your* view.

1. **"my post was not about gender."** The purpose of repositioning your language on men is that (a) it's basically true, and (b) it's obviously the wrong way to go unless you're a man-hating feminist.  Since you claim you don't want to be a crypto-racist anymore, I thought that might help jar you out of your juvenile analysis.

2. **"Why is the same not true for Hispanic males?"** Suddenly you're an expert in crime rates.  Well, it's well known Hispanics were not slaves.  Not only might that explain the difference between black and Hispanic experience, but definitely means Hispanics are not the visible minority we are looking for.  They don't count as the visible minority experiencing *the* longstanding cultural antagonism of America.

3. **"First, I never said black people are intrinsically criminal."** I didn't say you did.  I asked if you were caught holding that bag.  There's a big difference.  The most important difference is the question form which ought to give rise to a thinking process on your end.

4. If it sounds like I've made you look racist, it's because you made racism the central issue of your CMV.  To wit:  *I know this sounds terribly racist. ... I want to stop feeling racist. Help me change my view.*  So you sound terribly racist, and you feel racist, but if I paint you as a closet racist that's wrong?  Maybe by highlighting the way I think racism creeps into your post, I'm trying to intensify your awareness and reaction against what does indeed sound racist.  Maybe it's part of my rhetorical technique.  

5. **"and perhaps even the destiny of blacks in general" "WUT???? Straw man much?"** When you generalize, you impart a destiny to a thing.  For example, if you say that all swans are white, you are saying that whenever you come across a swan, it will be white.  If we throw swan eggs into the mix, you are further claiming a destiny for that egg, that it will become a swan that is white.  White becomes a destiny for the swan egg.  It's no straw man at all.  "Destiny" is why thinking people try not to make broad generalizations about groups of people.

6. **"You want to see them as cows that have driven themselves into the ditch."**  Here you sound very defensive, bringing up personal history as a method of distancing yourself from what I think is a pretty solid analysis of your point of view, as gleaned from this one post you made.  You are so obviously obsessed with the idea that you believe in equality of all people, which acts as a counter-measure to your own self-disclosed racist feelings.  All I did was explain what those racist feelings amounted to.  But you reject this.

7. **Then I realized that culture =/= race.** What I'm saying is that shifting responsibility to culture serves your crypto-racism rather nicely.  Oh, it's not that you hate blacks.  It's their culture you hate.  I think that arrow struck you.  I think I was right about obsession.  You'd think that this means I'm getting personal.  But I'm not.  I'm diagnosing your racism through your own language.  And apparently it stings.

**Since it means a lot to you, let's return to the question of your title:**

&amp;gt; I think that black people in America are often a victim of their own culture more than a victim of discrimation.

First off, you admit you have " little exposure to black culture," which suggests to me that you would need some pretty solid evidence to back up your claims.  I'm not going to just accept sweeping generalizations without evidence.  What evidence have you provided?

&amp;gt; what little I have seen seems to support criminal or irresponsible behavior

Admitting you have seen little of black culture should ring a bell reminding you to do your duty.  Before you condemn another culture, maybe examine it more carefully.  

&amp;gt; This is not to say that black people are all criminals or irresponsible, just that the general culture encourages these activities.

See, this is what I'm talking about.  With "little exposure to black culture" you have no authority to make claims about "general culture".  Let me bring destiny back in here.  On the mere sliver of black culture (whatever that is), you want to make claims about black culture in general, and link this up to bad traits and bad behavior of black people.  Culture -&amp;gt; bad behavior of black people.  This is what I mean by destiny.  Culture is the egg that grows these criminal black assholes you don't like.

&amp;gt; Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

This is the falsest of false dichotomies, which you smuggle in thinking nobody will notice.  Here's what you are saying: Either the higher crime rate of black males is due to 

1. to racial discrimination, or

2. to black culture.

You can't weasel your way out of this by saying that, well, I never said it had nothing to do with discrimination, because the dichotomy is bullshit.  There are many other possible explanations, such as the fact blacks are incredibly poor compared to whites, that they live in poor neighborhoods abandoned by affluent groups, that policing has been militarized the past 30 years, various drug epidemics.  You can't summarize all these material conditions as "black culture".  Do blacks choose to be poor because it's hip and urban?  No.

&amp;gt; Granted I do not know many black people

Oh really?

&amp;gt; but of the ones I do know, it honestly seems like black people are typically much lazier (but I know some black people who do not fit this definition at all).

Here's the problem.  You want to get a positive statement (blacks are lazy), then weasel out of it by claiming knowledge that saves *your* epistemic position (not all blacks are lazy), but which does not save the black people you want to make generalizations about (still lazy).  See, that's what I call racism.  

&amp;gt; I know that's not a scientific study at all, but a much higher percentage are unemployed, heavy drug users or alcoholics, or never try very hard in school, even in college.

Actually there are scientific studies on all these topics, but you are too lazy to look them up.

&amp;gt; Again, I find it hard to believe this is entirely due to discrimination.

Again, the falsest of false dichotomies.  Again, there are many factors besides black culture and discrimination at play here.

&amp;gt; Black people are often more disrespectful than any other group (just a reminder, this is in my experience. I won't pretend like this is a scientific fact). 

Again, getting a positive statement, then weaseling out to save your good name.  By making generalizations, you are treating it as a fact.

&amp;gt;  It simply seems to me like there is a black culture in the U.S. that encourages many vices.

The greatest thing about your post is that you've provided absolutely zero evidence that links the behavior you mention to black culture.  Not one study, not even one reasonably coherent account linking a cultural artifact to a behavioral outcome.  

Can you name one hip hop song that promotes disrespecting your college professor?  If not, then there is nothing coherent in your claim that black culture grounds black misbehavior like disrespecting college professors.  What, do you think I should do all the work, comb through the entire history of hip hop, and serve you up little tid bits that justify your point of view?  No, this is called "Change my view."  

edit.  For the sake of completing the thought:

Since you haven't made a coherent account linking black culture to bad behavioral outcomes, you can't accomplish the comparison between claims that discrimination or culture causes the bad behavioral outcomes.  Not that you even attempted to make the comparison.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
