<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="78227727.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1akowf/i_think_that_black_people_in_america_are_often_a/">
    <title>I think that black people in America are often a victim of their own culture more than a victim of discrimation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tomjoad76</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: I say black, not African-American. Many black people possibly have a longer history of ancestry in the U.S. than I do, and I never ask to be called a European-American.

I know this sounds terribly racist, and I apologize for offending people because I really do understand that people are often going to meet what expectations you set for them and not much more.

I am an open-minded and liberal white Southerner who has grown up with little exposure to black culture. However, what little I have seen seems to support criminal or irresponsible behavior. This is not to say that black people are all criminals or irresponsible, just that the general culture encourages these activities.

Hip-hop, the predominant choice of music for many black Americans, often promotes organized crime, prostitution, gun use, drug use, etc.

Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

Granted I do not know many black people, but of the ones I do know, it honestly seems like black people are typically much lazier (but I know some black people who do not fit this definition at all). I know that's not a scientific study at all, but a much higher percentage are unemployed, heavy drug users or alcoholics, or never try very hard in school, even in college. Unemployment rates are much higher among blacks than any other race. Again, I find it hard to believe this is entirely due to discrimination.

Black people are often more disrespectful than any other group (just a reminder, this is in my experience. I won't pretend like this is a scientific fact). There is a large black population on my campus, and anytime I have a class with a group of black students, it seems like those students will be very disrespectful to the professor or other students, e.g. interrupting class, coming in late, listening to music so loud on their headphones that everybody in the room can hear it. It's such an unfailing stereotype for me that I've come to dread anytime I see a large group of black students in my classes.

I know there are bad apples and good apples in every orchard. I feel bad because I often have these kinds of thoughts, and I am honestly no quicker to judge a black person I meet as a bad person than any other race. It simply seems to me like there is a black culture in the U.S. that encourages many vices.

I want to stop feeling racist. Help me change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26662768414.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>I am an open-minded conservative white Southerner who has grown up with a moderate amount of exposure to a variety of American Subcultures, and I'm going to strongly disagree with the assessment that culture is root of the problem.

Hip-hop songs that promote crime, prostitution, and drug use aren't the same ones that are current among the most musically inclined, but are rather mass marketed versions created and distributed by a music industry that is sorely out of touch in general, and this segment in particular. Not saying that it isn't influential, but rather it's influential and ubiquitous because music producers THINK it's what people are looking for. Contrast, if you will, the topics of Tupac and many of the pioneers of the form of music to what is released on most major labels. I would argue that labels are distorting the message.

Crime rates aren't just due to racial discrimination. A lot of it is a statistical artifact relating to demographics. People who live in dense urban cores are more likely to be caught for crimes, and people who grow up in poverty are more likely to commit them. This is true for all ethnicities, but a greater proportion of black people grow up in those conditions than other races. If anything black culture is *responding* to this reality as opposed to *causing* it.

It's not true of the people I know at all. Many of them have better records than I do in school and a higher proportion of my black acquaintances own their own businesses than my white ones. Entrepreneurship is inherently incompatible with laziness. I would argue that higher unemployment rates are an artifact of high poverty rates with both makes it difficult to commute to distant jobs, restricts residency to low opportunity areas, and limits opportunity for education.

I haven't observed black students being more disrespectful. I am unable to comment on this one.

I would argue that many of the perceived problems with "black culture" don't stem from the culture, but the culture's response to historic and persisting poverty. Correlation doesn't imply causation, and many of the problems supposedly stemming from race occur in the poorest segments of other races as well.

We can't afford to overplay distinctions of race or class. The things that help anyone else succeed in business, science, and art aids us all. The things that help us fight poverty as a matter of course, as opposed to heroic government effort, aids us all. We are American. They are American. What else matters?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663628726.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to have equated culture to music which is ... about 1% of the issue.  Just wanted to point this out, you haven't mentioned anything significant about culture so... </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663674284.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, I was addressing the OP's commentary point for point. I didn't mean to myopically focus on music, but it was the original example used.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26663690681.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>excellent use of myopically.  Continue on my smart brother. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
