<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="78227727.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1akowf/i_think_that_black_people_in_america_are_often_a/">
    <title>I think that black people in America are often a victim of their own culture more than a victim of discrimation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tomjoad76</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: I say black, not African-American. Many black people possibly have a longer history of ancestry in the U.S. than I do, and I never ask to be called a European-American.

I know this sounds terribly racist, and I apologize for offending people because I really do understand that people are often going to meet what expectations you set for them and not much more.

I am an open-minded and liberal white Southerner who has grown up with little exposure to black culture. However, what little I have seen seems to support criminal or irresponsible behavior. This is not to say that black people are all criminals or irresponsible, just that the general culture encourages these activities.

Hip-hop, the predominant choice of music for many black Americans, often promotes organized crime, prostitution, gun use, drug use, etc.

Crime rates are MUCH higher among black males than any other demographic in the United States. I find it extremely hard to believe that this is entirely due to racial discrimination.

Granted I do not know many black people, but of the ones I do know, it honestly seems like black people are typically much lazier (but I know some black people who do not fit this definition at all). I know that's not a scientific study at all, but a much higher percentage are unemployed, heavy drug users or alcoholics, or never try very hard in school, even in college. Unemployment rates are much higher among blacks than any other race. Again, I find it hard to believe this is entirely due to discrimination.

Black people are often more disrespectful than any other group (just a reminder, this is in my experience. I won't pretend like this is a scientific fact). There is a large black population on my campus, and anytime I have a class with a group of black students, it seems like those students will be very disrespectful to the professor or other students, e.g. interrupting class, coming in late, listening to music so loud on their headphones that everybody in the room can hear it. It's such an unfailing stereotype for me that I've come to dread anytime I see a large group of black students in my classes.

I know there are bad apples and good apples in every orchard. I feel bad because I often have these kinds of thoughts, and I am honestly no quicker to judge a black person I meet as a bad person than any other race. It simply seems to me like there is a black culture in the U.S. that encourages many vices.

I want to stop feeling racist. Help me change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26662734336.0" user="pezz29" delta="False">
    <text>You should probably discount your experience. The mere fact that you're trying to apply your findings to an entire race implies you've either not examined your privilege or you don't have nearly enough experience with black people. You're basically doing [this](http://xkcd.com/385/) but with a race instead of a gender.

Regarding crime: [sociologists don't think it's just their culture](http://www.amazon.com/The-New-Crow-Michelle-Alexander/dp/1595586431/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1363646942&amp;amp;sr=8-4&amp;amp;keywords=prison+industrial+complex).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
