<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583839854.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? 

Virtually all of these have real life analogs in various European countries, which have capitalistic systems. (Indeed, that's basically the idea behind democratic socialism- you keep capitalism by large,  and catch people who fall through the gaps).

The semi-exception is M4A, which would be noncapitalistic, but at this point, there is ample evidence that capitalism uniquely fails at providing healthcare. However, the rest of the economy is capitalism, and it still leverages capitalistic effects from medical suppliers (it's only the demand side that changes) so can still capture many of the benefits.

&amp;gt;1.) The wealth tax

Only kicks in after $50million in wealth. So you'd have to believe that people who are on the cusp of $50million in wealth would somehow be less motivated, which clashes with reality. 50mil is intentionally picked to be the point where it's extremely hard to argue it's not just intrinsic motivation.

On top of the fact that other countries have a wealth tax, you also have to grapple with the fact that we already have forms of wealth taxes (in the form of propertie taxes), and argue that wealth taxes are somehow more disincentive than income taxes. And thats ignoring thornier parts like inflation,which is essentially a wealth tax.

Is a 2% wealth tax really a bigger disincentive than a 35% income tax?

&amp;gt;2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

This already exists in Germany. 

Notably, 40% is not a majority, which means that employees can't ransack the company for their benefit. In addition, employees can actually have valuable "on the ground" insight into how to improve the company.

&amp;gt;3.) Breaking up big tech companies

The United States already has anti-trust law, granted it's currently weak, but the break up of Bell Labs provides a frame work for what would happen. We didn't see companies abandon the sector- it's still wildly profitable.


It's funny you use Warren, because most of her plans are specifically designed to work *with* capitalism. They're not about destroying it, but fixing parts where it goes awry from the theory. The things that make capitalism powerful (competition, access to price info, new companies, bargaining power) are in many aspects enhanced by the proposals. To pick just the 3rd point, the goal of capitalism isn't to foster big monopoly companies. It's just for most industries, competition arises naturally. So it makes sense for areas where that competition doesn't come along naturally, to do what capitalism is already supposed to do.

The idea is that we got kind of lucky with how capitalism worked back in the 60s etc. Were now finding that a lot of the things we assumed were inherent to capitalism were a special case,and now need a bit of a nudge to recover</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
