<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33423818586.0" user="S629A" delta="False">
    <text>I think every serious Democratic candidate except for Marxist Bernard Sanders will preserve capitalism.  Yes, that includes Elizabeth Warren, who is very much a FDR style reformer than an anti-capitalist.   1 and 3 are very much in the reformist capitalism viewpoint, both Teddy Roosevelt and FDR worked to reform capitalism in order to save it.  Warren has effectively dropped the extremist Medicare for All position and is now ok with people keeping private insurance as an option.  #2 is the only problematic position that I see with Warren.  I'm not against a wealth tax, although I suspect it will be far less effective that the proponents think it will be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33423852291.0" user="S629A" delta="False">
    <text>I will also say this, though.  Supporting socialism or opposing capitalism is against the Constitution and should be banned, even speech.  Marxist Bernard Sanders is a direct threat to capitalism and to American society in general (and far worse than Trump).  People should read the following article.

[https://gregolear.substack.com/p/vote-for-bernie-why-not-just-write](https://gregolear.substack.com/p/vote-for-bernie-why-not-just-write)

I am a person of color and a small business owner, and vote Democrat. But I would vote for David Duke over Marxist Bernard Sanders (whom I believe should be executed for treason).  I've fired every BernieBro that I could find at my business, and cut off their health care and unemployment benefits as well.  And yes, I do blame Sanders and his BernieBro scum for Trump's election. In fact, he was far more responsible than anyone else, including Russia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577036991.0" user="StripedRiverwinder" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing says defending the Constitution like executing those with different political beliefs than you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577623746.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577625214.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>u/S629A – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+S629A&amp;amp;message=S629A+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/-/ffb90aq/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577880244.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33578053039.0" user="ZeroPointZero_" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/rapasvedese – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+rapasvedese&amp;amp;message=rapasvedese+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/-/ffbei7o/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577934179.0" user="yungwean" delta="False">
    <text>What part of the Constitution exactly?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33604734191.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33604997368.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/BMP_Quicks – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+BMP_Quicks&amp;amp;message=BMP_Quicks+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/-/ffre2un/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33576660362.0" user="TheMadUncleJeff" delta="False">
    <text>Gonna go out on a limb and say you have no idea on earth what Marxism is.

The American political Overton window is shit and you’re a product of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577626970.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33577929788.0" user="ViewedFromTheOutside" delta="False">
    <text>u/S629A – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 2: 

&amp;gt; **Don't be rude or hostile to other users.** Your comment will be removed even if most of it is solid, another user was rude to you first, or you feel your remark was justified. Report other violations; do not retaliate. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_2).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+2+Appeal+S629A&amp;amp;message=S629A+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://old.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/-/ffb92sa/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
