<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583615537.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>Social democracies are not the same as socialism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583658708.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>when the holocaust took place, that was of course an act of anti-Semitism. Imagine if there was another government, in another country, which made the proposition that all jews should be rounded up, and put into a special state that was designated for them, so that they could live among their own, and stay away from normal people. Would that not also be anti-Semitism. I'm sure you'd see an ideological commonality, between that, and the holocaust, but while they share similar ideological roots, they are not in fact the same political policy. 

So with this hypothetical situation that I've laid out, would there, or would there not be a case e to be made, that it was a continuation of the legacy (is there word for "legacy" that doesn't have a positive connotation) of the holocaust? Well, that depends on specifically what you're claiming. If you're saying that it is an attempt, to continue the specific system, that was put into place during the holocaust, that's just factually not true. If you're saying that it is a continuation of the values, and ideology laid forth by the holocaust, you wouldn't be wrong.

there is the idea, that if a large government advocate, does not put forth a policy proposition, which is identical to a policy proposition put forth by Marx, that that means it doesn't deserve to be associated with the defaming anti capitalist ideals of socialism. 

You wouldn't say that you have to put jews in gas chambers to be guilty of antisemitism. You also don't have to strictly follow the communist manifesto verbatim, in order to be anti-capitalist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583679623.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>Not all socialists are marxists and I think you forget that social democracies practice capitalism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583700333.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>there are 2 sides to the issue of Islam. The side that feels it deserves criticism, and the side that thinks it should be defended. There is a common catphrase/meme mocking those on the side that defends islam, stating "islam has nothing to do with islam". This quote, is of course not literal. Nobody's claiming that the side which defends islam, literally says "Islam has nothing to do with Islam". It's just an exaggerated act of satire, meant to cartoonishly capture the spirit, of those who defend islam. 

with regards to the people who defend socialism, it's not even a caricature. their defenses of socialism, are the complete equivalent of "socialism has nothing to do with socialism" there not nearly as good at saying what defines socialism, as they are at saying what doesn't define socialism. If you don't accept Marx as the one who put forth the definitive ideology, that is behind socialism, then there is no definitive ideology that defines socialism. 


all your left with, is a general attitude about the economic system, and a vague idea of a broad direction that you think would be a good idea. Even that, can't even be portrayed in a way, which diverges significantly from Marxism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583716866.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>Most socialist ideas are usually regarded as not as collectivist as Marxism or any other denominations of Communism are though you're slowly straying from the original discussion which was socialism vs social democracy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583731763.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>okay. I'm not disputing the premise that most proclaimed socialists, don't follow Marxism to the letter. As you said yourself "Most socialist ideas are usually regarded not as collectivist" The key word there is "most". It implies a plurality of ideas. If socialism, outside of marx, is concrete, then there has to be some cohesion among various socialist ideals. Something which links the various socialist ideas you are referring to, and gives all these people a reason to share the label of socialist, regardless of their unidentical ideas. 

You can't portray socialism as cohesive, by putting forth that commonality that justifies them all sharing the name, without putting forth a commonality that could apply to Marxists also.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583749744.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>Indeed all socialist ideals do focus on certain core values, the most important is collectivism; however, saying that Marxism is another word for socialism due to those core beliefs ignores the other denominations. None of this actually matters though because the original argument was whether social democracies and socialist nations are the same which they aren't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583771660.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>i don't think that the term Marxism, necessarily has to be interchangeable with socialism, or that Marx necessarily has to define socialism. I'm simply saying that if he doesn't, nobody does. If you disqualify Marx from being the prime authority on what the concept of socialism definitively is, you could look at every single socialist individually, and you'd have no less reason to disqualify them. 

Then you are left with nobody to provide a definitive illustration of socialism, and therefore, it is not system in the sense that it provides any tangible solutions, or specific policy. it's just a general sentiment about economics. Being a general sentiment, many policies, including the policies for the majority of the democratic candidates can fit the description.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584578145.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>I disqualify Marx from being the prime authority of what socialism is because he didn't come up with socialism and he deviates enough from most others to make him not the prime authority. Both him and Engel believed in a world revolution and absolutely zero private property, but many socialist figures such as Robert Owen didn't believe in that sort of radical ideals. Socialism, by definition, is the collectivising of the economy and although many of the democrats this year believe in some nationalization of certain aspects of the market none of them believe in total control. Due to this allowing of capitalism it is clear that they are anti-capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584814922.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;it is not system in the sense that it provides any tangible solutions, or specific policy

it's not a matter of radical or nonradical, if you are going to let the bare bones standard definition of socialism, define the concept. If that's the case, than anything that fits the definition, radical or not, is just as much of a reflection of socialism. because if you go by the definition, socialism is not a specific solution, or policy. It's a general idea. If Marx fit the definitions of being a socialist you can't call it "not real socialism"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585374865.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>I never said Marxism is not real socialism I said Marxism and socialism aren't interchangeable terms. Using Marxism in place of socialism creates the idea that all socialists are Marxists which is a false equivalency. A good comparison I can make is interchanging the term Lutheran and Christianity. Yes Lutherans are Christians just like how Marxists are Socialists, but not all Christians are Lutherans just like how not all Socialists are Marxists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586647242.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>I saw the orange envelop and thought "okay, in 3, 2, 1. I'm going to hear something starting with "I never said..." followed by something that doesn't address what I just said. we are way past this aspect, and you're going back to it, going all the way back to it, because you have to clap back with SOMETHING, and that's how far you have to reach. instead of going 3 comments deep to bring up something that I've already touched on

&amp;gt;don't think that the term Marxism, necessarily has to be interchangeable with socialism, or that Marx necessarily has to define socialism. I'm simply saying that if he doesn't, nobody does

address what I just said. 

&amp;gt;it's not a matter of radical or nonradical, if you are going to let the bare bones standard definition of socialism, define the concept. If that's the case, than anything that fits the definition, radical or not, is just as much of a reflection of socialism. because if you go by the definition, socialism is not a specific solution, or policy. It's a general idea. If Marx fit the definitions of being a socialist you can't call it "not real socialism"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586827494.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>I've already addressed how social democracies aren't anti capitalist and I brought up the Marxism debocol because I wanted you to understand what I was talking about; in your quote it says:


&amp;gt;I'm simply saying that if he doesn't, nobody does

This implies that what I was talking about before was that Marxism isn't socialism and I've already provided you with one proponent of socialism before Marx and Engel published the "Communist Manifesto". Once again you say:

&amp;gt;If Marx fit the definitions of being a socialist you can't call it "not real socialism"

Which I addressed within the first sentence of my response idk if that just flew over your head or something, but clearly you missed it so let me show it to you again:

&amp;gt; I never said Marxism is not real Socialism, I said Marxism and Socialism aren't interchangeable terms.

So now that that's out of the way let me show you again how social democracies are not anti-capitalist which may I remind you it was me who was trying to get you to get back on track only segwaying at the end since you seemed to have misunderstood my past argument. We've already established that Socialism requires collectivism of all industries, hence why they are anti-capitalist in nature; now if we agreed on this than we can simply see if countries built on the idea of Social Democracy collectivizes all of the industry in the nation. When examining their economies you can very much see that most of the country's industry is privately owned, now if they were anti-capitalist then this wouldn't be the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586884330.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So now that that's out of the way

NOW that it's out of the way. I addressed that several responses ago. All of your incohesive blithering is a distraction from addressing what I've said. Now do it.

"I just did" No you didn't. I've covered every base that you're trying to mention, and you're flatly pretending that I didn't, so you can maintain the worldview that you've contrived

&amp;gt;I don't consider our society socialist, even though we have regulations in place, which fit my definition of anti capitalist. Just as I don't think that everyone is obese, just because everybody has some body fat, and just as I don't think that you're a raging alcoholic, if you have a few beers on the weekend. Having anti-capitalist regulations does not automatically make a society anti-capitalist, just as you do not deserve to be classified as fat, just because you have body fat, even if you are in excellent shape.

&amp;gt;Yes. I do see the benefit of some government regulations, and I will say that in those specific cases, I am engaging in an anti-capitalist mentality. Some anti-capitalism is good, just as it's sometimes good to unwind with a beer, or get some social lubrication. a raging alcoholic, engages in the same vice, but due to the degrees, differentiates themselves from a sober person. Socialists/Democrats, engage in anti-capitalism, and differentiate themselves from me, through the scope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32587010791.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>Buddy you were the one who kept mentioning Marxism and you were the one who said that I believed that Marxism isn't real socialism, so you kind of forced me to correct you. I'm not too sure where you got that "I just did" quote which is making it difficult to understand the context. Now based on your other discussion I already understood that you believe that anything that goes against Laissez Faire Capitalism is inherently anti-capitalism, I'm merely trying to convince you as to why I don't see it that way. In order for something to be truly the antithesis of something it should contradict everything it has laid out otherwise it wouldn't be really the antithesis of it. I'm going to guess that your reasoning behind this is because you believe that Laissez Faire Capitalism is what capitalism is, therefore anything that tries to regulate the market in some way shape or form is anti-capitalist. The reason that I see it differently is because as time goes on ideas change and things get tweaked. Just like how socialism has many branches that separate all built on a core idea, capitalism has many branches that separate all built on a core idea this time the idea being private ownership. If you accept that interpretation then it's not hard to see how social democracies are a branch on that tree; although being inspired by socialism most of the economy is privately owned. It's your choice if you want to take this interpretation or not, but it's how I see things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32587270671.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In order for something to be truly the antithesis of something it should contradict everything it has laid out otherwise it wouldn't be really the antithesis of it.

and everything which fits the category of socialism, does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32587278105.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>Did I not already cover why socialism and social democracies aren't equivalent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32588563388.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>you attempted to, yes. Now you're bringing it up again, so that you can take this in circles, until you get the last word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32589438815.0" user="OverlyFriedRice" delta="False">
    <text>I brought it up because that was the original argument, what did you think we were talking about in the firdt place?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583683527.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>Socialism has a definition: collective ownership of the means of production. The policies Bernie wants put into place are just social programs like the ones we already have. He just wants more of them. If what Bernie wants was socialism, the US would already be socialist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583719926.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>"narcotic" has a definition. if you take cocaine, you are taking a narcotic. If you take Adderall, it is every bit as true, if I make the claim that you are taking a narcotic. The fact that Adderall, and cocaine are not one and the same, does not mean that they can't both live up to the same standard, if that standard is framed in a broad enough sense.

"the collective ownership, of the means of production" is a concept that is very wide in scope, and it is perfectly possible for large number of political policies to be in keeping with that ideal. 

If you're with a group of 10 people, and you're voting whether you should watch movie A, or movie B, Movie A gets 6 votes, and movie B gets 4 votes, then you are simply in a position, where movie A is on, and movie B is not. With regards to the issue of whether or not a society is upholding capitalist values, that is far more multifaceted, and it does not make for a black and white outcome like that. a location within that society could be living up to ideals, while another location isn't. The location that is, could be upholding those ideals in some ways, but not others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583815651.0" user="zomskii" delta="False">
    <text>Your analogy of anti-semitism is a false equivalence. From the mid 19th century anti-semites discussed what they called "The Jewish Question". One suggested solution was the method used for centuries, expulsion. The method eventually used by the Nazis was extermination.

Marxism is also a suggested solution to a problem. The problem is inequality of wealth and power in a post industrial society. Your argument seems to be that any suggested solution to the problem of inequality is equivalent to Marxism, which is obviously not true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583952886.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that any proposed solution to inequality is comparable to Marxism. 

I think that if a proposed solution, is related to economic inequality, is based on the assumption that this economic inequality, is overwhelmingly influenced by injustice, and the proposed solution to this injustice, is to forcibly interfere with the free market, then that is anti-capitalism. If it is anti-capitalism, then it is not ideologically identical with Marxism, but linked to Marxism, in the way that matters most. 

I can see your next contention coming, as I hear something to the same effect often. "Going by your definition that interfearing with the free market, is what defines anti capitalism, we ALREADY live in an anti capitalist society, because we ALREADY have legal regulations, so you should consider our society socialist"

I don't consider our society socialist, even though we have regulations in place, which fit my definition of anti capitalist. Just as I don't think that everyone is obese, just because everybody has some body fat, and just as I don't think that you're a raging alcoholic, if you have a few beers on the weekend. Having anti-capitalist regulations does not automatically make a society anti-capitalist, just as you do not deserve to be classified as fat, just because you have body fat, even if you are in excellent shape.

Yes. I do see the benefit of some government regulations, and I will say that in those specific cases, I am engaging in an anti-capitalist mentality. Some anti-capitalism is good, just as it's sometimes good to unwind with a beer, or get some social lubrication. a raging alcoholic, engages in the same vice, but due to the degrees, differentiates themselves from a sober person. Socialists/Democrats, engage in anti-capitalism, and differentiate themselves from me, through the scope.

They cross a line, and where exactly is that line. Hard to quantify, because it's largely arbitrary, but that's not my fault. That's just the nature of it, when you're dealing with a concept that is either overly broad, or has no cohesion among those who try to get more specific.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584795366.0" user="zomskii" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be saying that there is a linear scale by which we can measure society. At one end of the scale is capitalism and the other end is Marxism. You're saying that capitalism means zero regulation of the market, and **any** regulation takes society towards Marxism.

But there is plenty of regulation which has nothing to do with Marxism. For example intellectual property, health and safety regulations, licensing, accounting principles, anti-discrimination laws, etc. There are plenty of regulations which actually benefit big business, so have more to do with corporatism than communism.

Influencing the free market does not always push society in the direction of Marxism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584822020.0" user="anonymousZRJ" delta="False">
    <text>yes. Those are called laws. I didn't say that laws were anti capitalist. I specifically mentioned the particular issues, that SOME laws were trying to address, and defined them as anti capitalist.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
