<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583633951.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>Those seem to be the sort of thing you said that you support - government checks to regulate capitalism and alleviate some of its negative effects. Warren isn't advocating getting rid of corporate boards entirely; just making them more representative of the company. She's not going to destroy private enterprise; she's just breaking up companies with a monopoly on an area (like other Presidents have done before) because monopolies are *harmful* to free enterprise. State provision of healthcare is a perfectly reasonable policy enacted in almost all European countries, all of which continue to have healthy free markets. And the wealth tax wouldn't stop people in high positions having more wealth than others, but would simply remove a proportion of the entirely unnecessary wealth which they hold and do not need. Two-thirds of a multi-million dollar salary is still an immense incentive.

Nobody - not Warren, Sanders, or any other candidate - is advocating an end to capitalism. All of these policies exist to improve the lot of less powerful people *within* America's capitalist system. They're making changes within the system, not replacing the system itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583681527.0" user="ChronoPsyche" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Warren isn't advocating getting rid of corporate boards entirely; just making them more representative of the company.  

Yes, true, but it is a step toward complete or majority employee ownership. The question is, will that be the end of it, or will the next president try to take it a step further? That is what concerns me.

&amp;gt; She's not going to destroy private enterprise; she's just breaking up companies with a monopoly on an area (like other Presidents have done before) because monopolies are *harmful* to free enterprise. 

I agree with going after monopolies. My concern is that I have hard time seeing the technology companies as monopolies, since they haven't actually acquired their competition, they just happen to the most popular for their respective services.  Although, I am open to arguments as to how they do fit the definition of a monopoly.

&amp;gt;  State provision of healthcare is a perfectly reasonable policy enacted in almost all European countries, all of which continue to have healthy free markets. 

Most European countries have a combination of private and public health insurance (excluding the Nordic countries), although correct me if I'm wrong. Sander's plan would do away with private insurance entirely and while Warren hasn't released a plan yet, she has endorsed Sander's plan. The problem with only a public option is that it removes competition and makes the country reliant on one single system, that may or may not end up being flawed. The other problem with Medicare for All that is specific to Sander's plan is that it is simply an expansion of Medicare. Medicare is known for paying lousy rates to doctors and hospitals, which could cause doctor shortages and hospitals to close down if it was the only insurance.

&amp;gt; Two-thirds of a multi-million dollar salary is still an immense incentive. 

My issue with it is that it is not a tax on their salary but on their net worth, but most of billionaire's and ultra-millionaire's net worth is in investments. So let's take Jeff Bezos for an example. Let's say he is worth $100 billion. Now he is taxed 5% on 99 billion of that (which I believe is what the ultra-millionaire tax would do). That is close to $5 billion, but he might not even have that much money in cash. So then he has to go and sell a ton of his stock to get enough cash to pay that money. Now extend this to all billionaires and ultra-millionaires. If they are all having to sell lots of their stock in order to pay this tax, how does that affect the market? Additionally, what if someone's net worth remains constant? This is a tax on total wealth, not annual income, so if someone isn't increasing their wealth, they could have their wealth consistently reduced every year until they are below the threshold for the tax.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583757266.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, true, but it is a step toward complete or majority employee ownership. The question is, will that be the end of it, or will the next president try to take it a step further? That is what concerns me.

40% doesn't necessarily lead to 60%. You aren't being asked to vote based on what policies Warren *might* support in ten years' time; you are being asked to vote on her current policies. If she starts advocating majority employee ownership in the next election, then you can stop voting for her.

&amp;gt;I agree with going after monopolies. My concern is that I have hard time seeing the technology companies as monopolies, since they haven't actually acquired their competition, they just happen to the most popular for their respective services. Although, I am open to arguments as to how they do fit the definition of a monopoly.

If oil is newly discovered in a closed economy, and one company rushes in to buy up all of that land, that country had a monopoly despite not acquiring its competition. Amazon, Google, and Facebook have too much power within their industries to allow healthy competition.

&amp;gt;Most European countries have a combination of private and public health insurance (excluding the Nordic countries), although correct me if I'm wrong. Sander's plan would do away with private insurance entirely and while Warren hasn't released a plan yet, she has endorsed Sander's plan. The problem with only a public option is that it removes competition and makes the country reliant on one single system, that may or may not end up being flawed.

I live in the UK, and as far as I know, most countries have compulsory public healthcare schemes, funded through insurance or general taxation, and then optional private healthcare on top of that. The public part, in Britain and France, at least, is both compulsory and sufficient, and the only reason a person would use private healthcare would be for unessential operations like plastic surgery or for nicer facilities for long-term stays in hospital. Competition doesn't really work in the healthcare industry like it does in other areas, because you have no ability to choose not to use the service - if your leg is broken, you can't just refuse treatment. Consumers are a captive market, and that in itself prevents the free market working as it should. A state-run system that can regulate costs has far more of an incentive to provide a decent service, because it's ultimately run by politicians who want re-election.

&amp;gt;The other problem with Medicare for All that is specific to Sander's plan is that it is simply an expansion of Medicare. Medicare is known for paying lousy rates to doctors and hospitals, which could cause doctor shortages and hospitals to close down if it was the only insurance.

Then they'd increase the rates that Medicare pays doctors. It isn't set in stone.

&amp;gt;My issue with it is that it is not a tax on their salary but on their net worth, but most of billionaire's and ultra-millionaire's net worth is in investments. So let's take Jeff Bezos for an example. Let's say he is worth $100 billion. Now he is taxed 5% on 99 billion of that (which I believe is what the ultra-millionaire tax would do). That is close to $5 billion, but he might not even have that much money in cash. So then he has to go and sell a ton of his stock to get enough cash to pay that money. Now extend this to all billionaires and ultra-millionaires. If they are all having to sell lots of their stock in order to pay this tax, how does that affect the market? 

I don't know enough about economics to predict how that would affect the market, but the ownership of capital and stock being less concentrated hardly seems detrimental to capitalism.

&amp;gt;Additionally, what if someone's net worth remains constant? This is a tax on total wealth, not annual income, so if someone isn't increasing their wealth, they could have their wealth consistently reduced every year until they are below the threshold for the tax.

That would take years with a 5% tax, and even then they would still be left with huge wealth once they passed below the threshold. Certainly they'll have more than enough for a comfortable retirement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586088728.0" user="yumyumnom" delta="False">
    <text>On the wealth tax front, the issue isn’t really that billionaires “won’t have enough money” or something if it’s passed, but rather that it’s an awful way to redistribute wealth that’s rife with unintended consequences, conflicts of interest, and bad incentives. 

Just one angle you can discuss is how the tax would be paid. 

1. You force the person to sell their shares. This is somewhere in the neighborhood of 3 million shares in Bezos’s case, which to put that in perspective is more than the entire volume if shares traded today at present time. Also, he has to disclose that the shares are going to be sold under rule 144, so people are going to know he’s selling them. It’s a market manipulation nightmare. Oh and by the way it’s also a taxable event, which is a pretty obvious conflict of interest. 

2. The government takes control of the shares, which would mean that the government basically slowly gets control of a large number of public companies in the US. This is also obviously a massive conflict of interest.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586201830.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1. You force the person to sell their shares. This is somewhere in the neighborhood of 3 million shares in Bezos’s case, which to put that in perspective is more than the entire volume if shares traded today at present time. Also, he has to disclose that the shares are going to be sold under rule 144, so people are going to know he’s selling them. It’s a market manipulation nightmare. 

Since you seem to know more about this than me, I wonder if you can explain the implications. What would be the problem with those shares suddenly being traded? What would happen?
 
&amp;gt;Oh and by the way it’s also a taxable event, which is a pretty obvious conflict of interest.

What are the interests that are conflicting, given that politicians don't personally benefit from taxation? The government encouraging taxable activity, thus providing more funds for services, seems a reasonable policy to me.


&amp;gt;2. The government takes control of the shares, which would mean that the government basically slowly gets control of a large number of public companies in the US. This is also obviously a massive conflict of interest.

Personally I've no problem with nationalisation, although admittedly it would undermine my argument about Warren's capitalism. But, again, I don't understand why this is a "conflict of interest". I thought that was when politicians use their power as politicians to enrich *themselves*, and I don't see how this is that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586283366.0" user="yumyumnom" delta="False">
    <text>1. Simplistically, imagine there’s an apple market, and every day people come to buy and sell apples. On average, 100 apples are bought and sold on average every day. Now, one of the biggest apple owners tells everyone, several days in advance, that he’s going to show up with 300 apples he needs to sell in one day. You can imagine that this is not going to be good for the market mechanics.

Now, without getting into too much complexity, imagine there is also a large group of people that trade agreements for future apple transactions today, and that they ALSO know that all of these apples are going to be changing hands, and there is another group of people who trade fruit agreements, of which apples constitute a part, etc.. Basically, you’ve got open season on people trading on the expectation of the market going down in apples, which leads to a feedback loop that drives the price down even more. 

2. It leads to the government being incentivized to make the tax bigger to connect more fringe benefits/ enforce certain tax lot requirements for the sales. That’s not getting into the ways it can further distort the market depending on how the wealth tax is levied and paid, for example corps giving the execs options to pay the tax ex post facto. 

3. You don’t understand how the government owning companies is a huge conflict of interest? They basically get to seize as much of the firm as they want every month and then vote on how it is being run. Would you like that as an owner?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586341804.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1. Simplistically, imagine there’s an apple market, and every day people come to buy and sell apples. On average, 100 apples are bought and sold on average every day. Now, one of the biggest apple owners tells everyone, several days in advance, that he’s going to show up with 300 apples he needs to sell in one day. You can imagine that this is not going to be good for the market mechanics.

&amp;gt;Now, without getting into too much complexity, imagine there is also a large group of people that trade agreements for future apple transactions today, and that they ALSO know that all of these apples are going to be changing hands, and there is another group of people who trade fruit agreements, of which apples constitute a part, etc.. Basically, you’ve got open season on people trading on the expectation of the market going down in apples, which leads to a feedback loop that drives the price down even more. 

Again, I can't really argue, not understanding the issue, but presumably Bezos wouldn't be selling all of those shares suddenly on tax day; he could spread it through the year to ensure he possesses sufficient cash for the tax. Would that still cause significant disruption to the market?

&amp;gt;2. You don’t understand how the government owning companies is a huge conflict of interest?

No, I don't, given that politicians don't personally benefit from taxation so long as they are democratically elected.

&amp;gt;They basically get to seize as much of the firm as they want every month and then vote on how it is being run. Would you like that as an owner?

Probably not, but as a worker, I *would* like my company to be run in the interests of me and my colleagues rather than the dozen people who own it. The government is accountable to the people, while private corporations are not; it seems obvious which is more likely to run the company in the public interest. I would happily disadvantage the top 20% if it would benefit the lower 80%. Not, obviously, that I think Sanders or Warren are genuinely proposing anything like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32586355259.0" user="yumyumnom" delta="False">
    <text> No, he can’t, because he basically always has material non-public information. He has to file to sell in advance with the SEC and the exchange. Now, he could set up a trading plan to spread the sale out, but that plan again has to be done ahead of time, people will know. 

I guess we fundamentally see business in a different light if you feel that the government arbitrarily seizing ownership in firms is a good idea (or good for workers in any way), so I’ll leave my response at that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
