<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583787213.0" user="MrStrange15" delta="False">
    <text>None of the American candidates are socialists. While Sanders and Warren can definitely both be argued to be what we would either define as center right in Europe or as social democrats, they are nonetheless both still capitalists. I've noticed that you in another comment made a point out of Sanders calling himself a socialist, but to the best of my knowledge of socialism, this is either an uninformed opinion of his or a way to brand himself. Since none of the candidates seems to put forward a position that is actually socialist, then it's a bit fair to say that neither of them are. However, regarding your points:

1.) A wealth tax is not anti capitalist. Since taxes are already an integral part of the capitalist system, then why would a different one be non-capitalistic? Wealth taxes also already exists in many western democratic capitalist countries, such as France and the Nordics.

2.) I see your point about this being a step closer to workers ownership of the means of productions, however, being on the board does not make you an owner, you just become a decision maker. For it to actually being a step closer to socialism, one would have to make it so the workers got 40% of the stocks of the company. The structure of companies will still exist if Warren or Sanders is elected and the capitalistic system will still be protected, there will just be more workers representation.

3.) Breaking up big companies, who have gotten a monopoly, no matter how they achieved it, is healthy for capitalistic system, especially liberal democracies, as it helps create a fair free market, where everyone can compete.

4.) Universal healthcare is also not a socialist policy. It is a bare necessity, which people need to function in society and to have equal opportunities. Universal healthcare has also been supported by many prominent liberal scholars in  the past, such as Rawls. Since for everyone to be able to compete fairly in a capitalist environment and as such to make the system the most efficient it can be, you need to make sure that people's bare necessities are covered and that they are not trapped in poverty. It also helps further upwards mobility, which is a key part of capitalism.

Lastly, I will point out, that Sanders and Warren are actually much better protectors of capitalism than Biden. This is because, when you moderate capitalism, as has been done in Europe, then people become more satisfied with the system and makes it so that they are less likely to discount the entire system itself and replace it with a new system. This was generally the fear in west after the Russian revolution and in the cold war, which lead to a lot of countries reforming their system to become more fair and equal, which in turn helps suppress revolutionary movements, because why would anyone revolt and disrupt the system, when their needs are covered? This is essentially how things like universal healthcare and the 38 hour week came to be, as it insulated the capitalist system against popular revolt. This is also why some (far from all) socialists were against universal healthcare, because they saw it as a way to keep their revolutions at bay.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32605772047.0" user="exsnakecharmer" delta="False">
    <text>2 days late, but if I had gold I'd give it to ya. What a great response. :)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
