<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583622077.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>40% of corporate boards elected by employees is meaningless isn’t it? What practical difference can that make apart from being a gutless promise to the more socialist dems?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583624570.0" user="darkplonzo" delta="False">
    <text>Is this comment saying that it can't happen or that if it does happen nothing will come of it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583626804.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>Kinda both, if it is possible it has no effect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583642743.0" user="darkplonzo" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that it's pretty hard to see how it would ever be passed, but like I find it hard to believe that all of a sudden 40% of the board now basically answering to the employees wouldn't end in different results in at least some votes? These boards have power over the corporation so these decisions will hopefully end up with some better descisions for the workers. Can you tell me what parts you disagree about my reasoning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583649652.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>They aren’t answering to the employees though, the employees are electing a representative to trust in understanding the nuances of board level decisions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583664090.0" user="darkplonzo" delta="False">
    <text>But like, it's not like a board position is a thing you hold for the rest of your life. A lot of companies elect their board members anually. So if a board member wants to keep their perks they'd have to be someone that the employees want to elect, which leads to them answering to the employees, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583678887.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>In theory yes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583685449.0" user="darkplonzo" delta="False">
    <text>So, where do you see the issue happening?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583700322.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>In reality, most boards of directors aren’t heartless bastards, and generating profit normally results in expansion and more jobs. Is that better than protecting the interests of a few jobs? I don’t know, I’m just saying that its a meaningless change that will have zero net benefits in my opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583638663.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>Presumably employees' representatives on the board could influence the company's policies in favour of employees. Decisions would be made with those dependant on the company for their livelihoods in mind, rather than purely the profit motive at all costs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583642185.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, in theory that all sounds good. In reality the morality of the wealthy and the poor are pretty indistinguishable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583648797.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>It's not about morality as such. Just that if only the wealthy are represented, then the wealthy will inevitably be benefited at the expense of the poor.   More balanced representation would mean fairer decisions. The poor aren't inherently better people, but they are people and therefore deserve a say in how their company is run.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583651668.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>Their company?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583653512.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>The company upon which they depend and to which they contribute, yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583664489.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>I depend on lots of things i have no right to control</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583668111.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>But wouldn't it be a better world if you did have the ability to stop them working against you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583676236.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>Unions?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583681826.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>Excellent idea. But there's a limit to unions' influence. Why not representation on boards as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583692249.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>Because , like unions, its only representation by proxy really. Coupled with the problem that the only benefits rely on the current situation being corrupt, which I don’t believe it is, i think not giving people (business  owners) control of the direction their companies go can ultimately lead to more job loses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583767136.0" user="Paracelsus8" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because , like unions, its only representation by proxy really.

Representation by proxy *is* representation. It's how every democracy works. 

&amp;gt;Coupled with the problem that the only benefits rely on the current situation being corrupt, which I don’t believe it is

Not necessarily corrupt, just driven by the profit-motive to the exclusion of all else. Because of the way the economy is structured, corporate boards will gladly disadvantage the vast majority of people dependant on the company if it will increase shareholder value. That isn't good for most people.

&amp;gt;i think not giving people (business owners) control of the direction their companies go can ultimately lead to more job loses.

The employees have as much motive as anyone else to ensure the company remains healthy. It's their jobs on the line.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583830241.0" user="duckiepoos" delta="False">
    <text>I just don’t see the overall benefit, I’m prepared to give it a whirl if thats the way it has to head, but I’ve absolutely no hope it will bring any change for the better.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
