<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583773614.0" user="Sayakai" delta="False">
    <text>None of those things threaten capitalism. Most of them don't even scratch capitalism, i.e. the private ownership of the means of production.

&amp;gt; 1) The wealth tax.

This already exists for parts of wealth, namely, your home - i.e. property tax. The wealthier you are in terms of real estate owned, the more you are being taxed. That's just expanding existing taxation law to all wealth.

This can also be considered a presumtive income tax, as most wealth will be invested and as such automatically generate more wealth, which frequently is subject to tax evasion.

&amp;gt; 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

This doesn't concern the ownership structure at all. It's also already implemented law in other capitalistic countries, such as Germany (where it's even 50% for companies with more than 2000 employees).

&amp;gt; 3.) Breaking up big tech companies

This has [precedent](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breakup_of_the_Bell_System). It can be considered necessary action to avoid monopolization of the market, because a competitive market is crucial for capitalism to properly work.

&amp;gt; 4.) Medicare-For-All

That's the only policy here that can be considered socialistic, in that it nationalizes health insurance to some degree. Though I'm not sure why you have trouble coming around to it, given that pretty much every other developed country using a socialized healthcare system has shown lower cost and better results.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
