<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32584185402.0" user="KateCobas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. 

Maybe on paper, but for the vast majority of Americans, it just doesn't work. All of the money is flowing up to the 1%.

&amp;gt;my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system.

We don't want to preserve the system that isn't working for the majority of Americans. Biden is part of the problem.

&amp;gt;his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president.

What makes him so unappealing is his pandering to wall street. He favors corporations and ignores the poor and middle class. Biden is running on a Hillary 2.0 strategy.

&amp;gt;but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders.

You should take the time to learn the difference between socialism and democratic socialism, specifically the kind Bernie is actually advocating for.

Calling Bernie a *"socialist"* without context is a right wing attack point.

&amp;gt;How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not?

They can't and that's the point. Capitalism in America doesn't work for the vast majority so it needs an aggressive overhaul. Biden will not make these needed changes, he's too busy kissing the asses of corporations.

&amp;gt;Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism?

He probably would preserve it in its current broken form.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584531509.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  vast majority of Americans, it just doesn't work.

That vast majority enjoys prosperity far superior to what even north western Europe does.The "1%" is just a stupid slogan as realistic as "build the wall" an easy scapegoat for the crowd but it is easy to blame your faults on someone else especially that unlike half of Europe US has no experience with real socialism</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584652294.0" user="KateCobas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That vast majority enjoys prosperity far superior to what even north western Europe does.

Comparing our bad situation to an even worse situation doesn't negate the fact that we're in a bad situation. 

It's a piss poor attempt at whataboutism.

&amp;gt;it is easy to blame your faults on someone else

Are you seriously suggesting all the wealth going to the top 1% is our own fault and not the fault of corrupt politicians bribed by corporations?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584687522.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Comparing our bad situation to an even worse situation

Dude US is the wealthiest major nation on the planet only city states are richer than 300 million people+ living in the states.North western EU is the second richest region.You are literally wishing for a utopia while living in the best region on the planet

Who is the 1%?
Mostly people that provide incredible amounts of value to other and make 300k/y not a caricature fat cat capitalist smoking cigars and doing nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584738412.0" user="KateCobas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Dude US is the 

Your blatant attempt at whataboutism is dismissed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584818279.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; whataboutism

What kind of metric describes the qol in your opinion?
Or you could claim that Ukraine is not a worse place to live than Switzerland because it has a lower income?

By basically any relevant metric majority of Americans live incredibly prosperous lives.Capitalism works and trust me the alternative does not many nations not so long ago had the "luck" of trying it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584835718.0" user="KateCobas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What kind of metric describes the qol in your opinion?

This [red herring fallacy](https://www.logicallyfallacious.com/tools/lp/Bo/LogicalFallacies/150/Red-Herring) is not relevent to the topic at hand. Please return to the topic of capitalism not working for most Americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585206101.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Please return to the topic of capitalism not working for most Americans

US offers it's citizens a very high standard of life and freedom nearly unmatched globally and only small city states tax heavens or oil states beat US on some of these metrics.Americans live in bigger homes have access to more goods and services than any major nation on earth.

https://www.worlddata.info/cost-of-living.php

https://data.oecd.org/earnwage/average-wages.htm

http://www.oecdbetterlifeindex.org/countries/united-states/

Clearly it is working for most Americans</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585239805.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585262667.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>Capitalism that has provided US citizens with the highest standard of living on the planet is openly attacked by multiple candidates in Democratic primaries.

The argument is that Biden is the only candidate of the top 3 that is not openly hostile toward the foundation of US prosperity.And you claim that capitalism is not working for majority in the US and while data shows otherwise.

So please tell me how it is not the topic?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585385410.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585399539.0" user="Mr-Ice-Guy" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ChronoPsyche – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+ChronoPsyche&amp;amp;message=ChronoPsyche+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/-/eywhwaq/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Do not reply to this comment by clicking the reply button, instead message the moderators ..... responses to moderation notices in the thread may be removed without notice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585444489.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585402567.0" user="Mr-Ice-Guy" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/KateCobas – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+KateCobas&amp;amp;message=KateCobas+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/-/eywery5/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Do not reply to this comment by clicking the reply button, instead message the moderators ..... responses to moderation notices in the thread may be removed without notice.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
