<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583624876.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>Places like Norway and Sweden are still capitalist countries. Sanders and Warren just want us to look more like them. 

If you want to preserve capitalism (I don't personally feel strongly about that, but it is the premise of your OP), you've got to update it. That's what Warren and Sanders wish to do. They are not socialists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583634843.0" user="Grandfunkwizard" delta="False">
    <text>Sweden are Norway also have strict boarder policy, homogenous culture, small population, small net migration and a much wealthier population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583642486.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>And Sanders and Warren are (hopefully) not interested in making America more similar to those nations in those particular ways. My point remains exactly the same (and also you haven't cited anything so I have no idea if half those claims are true).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583656608.0" user="Crankyoldhobo" delta="False">
    <text>I have no idea where they get the notion Sweden has a "homogenous culture" when roughly a [quarter of the Swedish population is from a foreign background](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demographics_of_Sweden#Migration). Immigration in Sweden is actually a hot-button issue for both the left *and* right in Europe; one side believing there's more work to be done and the other believing things have gone too far already.

What a strange thing to say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583662182.0" user="Grandfunkwizard" delta="False">
    <text>My point is you cannot have broader socialist policies without a homogenous culture that strictly controls its migration.
Sanders and Warren simultaneously want to open up migration whilst spending more on public goods. That will create more stress on services, more free riders migrating and diminishing quality of service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583671678.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any evidence for any of that? I don't think any of what you are suggesting will happen, and you still haven't cited your sources for those claims about Norway and Sweden (I'm inclined to believe the other commentor who just claimed you're outright wrong).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583693144.0" user="Grandfunkwizard" delta="False">
    <text>The general point still remains that socialist policies are only as effective as it suits the economic conditions.
Such a vast and mixed economy with a huge population like the USA would struggle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584295465.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>Every policy is only effective in so far as it suits economic conditions.

Again, do you have any evidence that it wouldn't work here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584904516.0" user="Dog-Penis" delta="False">
    <text>Why would the population of the U.S. hinder more socialist policies? You saying that shows how little you understand of the topic. Like medicare for all for example. The way insurance works is that the larger the risk pool the greater the benefit to the society and you get a larger risk pool the more people who buy in, so it's false that that wouldn't work due to popultion, that's contradictory. It's like this:in you had a jar of candy and needed insurance insurance on it would you more likely get it replaced if there were 100 other people with inurance or if there were 10000? Clearly the 10,000. You don't have any evidence that a large economy would suffer with socialist policies you're just saying random stuff you think is right without thinking further. Meanwhile your current(mostly) free market healthcare leaves 30million uninsured, nearly 80million would not be able to afford a major health problem, 30-45k people a year die due to not having healthcare and you will have 500,000 medical bankruptcies this year. This doesn't happen in other developed countries. I live in Canada and the amount of misinformation you guys have about social democratic policies is scary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583714087.0" user="ChronoPsyche" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Places like Norway and Sweden are still capitalist countries. Sanders and Warren just want us to look more like them. 

They also have much smaller and homogeneous populations. What works for them might not work for a country that is much larger. 

&amp;gt; They are not socialists. 

Well, Sanders for one, calls himself a socialist. I realize that his policy proposals do not meet the definition of true socialism, but this is just the first set of things he wants to do. How do I know he wouldn't go even further when and if his 2020 policy proposals are accomplished?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583750516.0" user="darkplonzo" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How do I know he wouldn't go even further when and if his 2020 policy proposals are accomplished?

Do you honestly think a president Sanders would accomplish all his goals in not only under 4 years, but in addition have time to spare to implement new goals?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584517505.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Sanders and Warren just want us to look more like them.

Until recently US CIT rate was at 35% while Sweden was at 22% i have never heard anything even close to reducing corporate tax rate from Sanders&amp;amp;co let alone to dropping it to match Sweden something that Trump tax cut did.And i heard plenty of lamenting by left wing democrats about that tax cut in regard to CIT</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32584660837.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's fairly clear I was referring to their social programs. And regardless the main point stays perfectly in tact</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585245583.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>Problem is also that they are repeating things that US left wants to hear and not the reality of Scandinavian model because promising that "millionaires and billionaires will pay for xyz" is a better slogan than promising middle class taxes above 50 % and that companies byzantine tax and immigration system has to be simplified in the US making it cheaper and faster to run business.These are not things that Sanders+ is promising just the opposite</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585250801.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>You're really gonna need to specify and cite the things you're referring to. You seem to be making broad generalizations about entire swaths of economies and political structure</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585299755.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>Just a small element of lack of reality in Sanders plan.https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-07-02/sanders-health-care-pitch-oversells-benefits-of-10-000-tax-hike

Also the Scandinavia that is described by left in the US must be a different region from the one in Europe because things like Denmark not having any central minimum wage are in direct opposition to the platform of the left wing of the democratic party.
Nordic model works drastically different from how Sanders and his peers describe them and also you can't use solutions that work in Norway in any other place on earth because it is a tiny oil state with smaller population than LA that is located on a mountain range enjoying heavy rain all year round</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32585383889.0" user="TheVioletBarry" delta="False">
    <text>There is so much to unpack about how the link you just posted is interpreting the information, and it's all totally irrelevant to the discussion at hand, so I really don't feel like unpacking it. If you are desperate to argue about health insurance, please summarize it in your own words, and I'll get back to you.

I'm really not interested in debating whether these things listed exist in those places exactly how we want to implement them here (and if you want me to debate with you about it, you've really  gotta start citing more sources, because it's gonna take me like an hour of research to verify all the stuff you just blurted out without a second thought, and I really don't feel like doing that labour for you).

This discussion is about whether Sanders is a socialist. Either stay on topic or make concise bullet points for me to respond to. I'm not gonna do the 'big paragraph full of a dozen different claims' game today.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
