<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32584011731.0" user="Barnst" delta="False">
    <text>One point I haven’t seen other people make—whatever you think of their specific policies, you’re dramatically overestimating the power of the President to preserve or undermine capitalism.  We could elect a raging communist and the country wouldn’t suddenly become the USSR.

So if you have trouble with some of Warren’s more radical proposals (which I don’t think even reach the level of undermining capitalism, but others have made that point), then other people will have trouble to.  And some of those people will be in Congress and the Courts.   If she does manage to pull off any big controversial things, she’ll probably pay for it in the 2022 midterms, just like every President since Clinton.

The nature of our system is that Warren won’t get to do *all* of the big things she says she wants to do.  She’ll have to pick and choose a couple of them, and the rest she’ll be doing at the margins with tools like writing regulations, executive orders, etc.  Those marginal things might seem like huge deals in our current politicized partisan climate, but they don’t fundamentally change anything about the US system.   Even some of the more ambitious stuff she could do, like more aggressively pursuing anti-trust against big tech companies, is well within the historical scope of American capitalism.   The more novel ideas, like M4A or a wealth tax, need to go to Congress, which is generally where novel and ambitious ideas go to die, for better or worse.

At the end of the day, temperament and decision making style matter as much, if not more, than specific policy proposals.  The President is not just a singular source of policy ideas.  They are the CEO of massive and unique bureaucratic enterprise.  An effective President doesn’t just have good ideas, they have they skills to manage and drive that enterprise.   Whether or not the next President has those skills will be far more impactful in terms of effective governance than whether or not they seek to preserve capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
