<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32624329370.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, 

This is untrue.  Rape is far from eliminated in countries that mandate modest dress for women, and not only blamed socially but even legally prosecuted for rape while the rapists walk free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32624538620.0" user="wood6558" delta="False">
    <text>Hes a tool, the countries with highest levels of rape happen to be islamic...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625477973.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>It's funny because I just read an article stating that "Rise in Sweden's rape stats can't be tied to refugee influx".

So on one hand you have liberals defending Muslim ideology, and on the other hand you have them claiming their culture promotes rape. Amazing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625531721.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>Liberals fundamentally do not defend Muslim ideology - that's a lie conservatives tell.  Liberals defend people's freedom to choose - including the freedom to choose to be Muslim.  Liberals also believe that each person should be judged individually based on their individual actions, not just based on what other people of the same religion have done.  None of that is support for Muslim ideology.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625701616.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Liberals fundamentally do not defend Muslim ideology

The term "Islamophobia" exists solely to protect against criticism of said ideology.

&amp;gt; Liberals also believe that each person should be judged individually based on their individual actions, not just based on what other people of the same religion have done. None of that is support for Muslim ideology.

This is incorrect. Muslims definitely judge people individually. However, the big difference is that the Liberal believes more in individuality than they do collectivism. Muslims impose their beliefs on others because they think it will benefit the collective as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625793396.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The term "Islamophobia" exists solely to protect against criticism of said ideology.

No it doesn't.  Liberals can and do criticize Islamic ideology.  I'm doing so literally right now, and so does the vast majority of other liberals.  Islamophobia is when you automatically hate/fear someone for being a Muslim, rather than for what that individual Muslim has said or done.

&amp;gt;This is incorrect. Muslims definitely judge people individually. 

That has nothing to do with the point I was making.  I was saying that liberals do not defend Islamic ideology, liberals defend people's freedom to be a Muslim if they want.  These are two separate and unrelated things.

&amp;gt;Muslims impose their beliefs on others because they think it will benefit the collective as a whole.

If so, they are wrong.  Imposed Muslim beliefs do not benefit society, as I and many others have explained.  Muslim countries are less happy, less successful, less educated, more violent, and pretty much any other negative metric you could find compared to countries that prize individual freedom.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626009142.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Islamophobia is when you automatically hate/fear someone for being a Muslim, rather than for what that individual Muslim has said or done.

But the hate/fear is based on what said population believes in which in turn effects their behavior...

&amp;gt; I was saying that liberals do not defend Islamic ideology, liberals defend people's right to be a Muslim if they want. These are two separate and unrelated things.

You see the contradiction here, right? Please tell me you do.

&amp;gt;  Imposed Muslim beliefs do not benefit society, as I and many others have explained. Muslim countries are less happy, less successful, less educated, more violent, and pretty much any other negative metric you could find compared to countries that prize individual freedom.

According to who? You?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626130653.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You see the contradiction here, right? Please tell me you do.

There is no contradiction.  Defending people's freedom to make their own choices is an entirely separate thing from defending the ideology those people choose to follow.  As the classic quote goes, "I disapprove of what you say, but I will defend to the death your right to say it."  I don't agree with Islamic ideology, but I absolutely defend people's right to choose to be Muslim.  There is no contradiction here.

&amp;gt;According to who? You?

According to all relevant statistics on each of those things.  You are the one saying Muslim countries are better off - it should be easy for you to produce actual evidence this is the case if that were true, but I haven't seen any.  There are a bunch of different studies of happiness, education levels, poverty rates, life expectancy, violent crime rates, etc by country, and Muslim countries are not high on these rankings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626208597.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't agree with Islamic ideology, but I absolutely defend people's right to choose to be Muslim. 

Do you hold the same stance when it comes to white supremacists?

&amp;gt; it should be easy for you to produce actual evidence this is the case if that were true

But I have in another response. I pointed out that Muslim countries don't even make the top 10 list of highest rapes per capita. Now someone else pointed out that this could be due to rapes being largely un-reported. The gray area in this debate just gets larger the more we dig in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626409742.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you hold the same stance when it comes to white supremacists?

Yes I do.  As long as they are not advocating violence, they absolutely have the right to say whatever they want.  And I have the right to call them idiots.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
