<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32625054702.0" user="alfihar" delta="False">
    <text>
First of all I think youre seriously misrepresenting large elements of muslim culture and practice but ill ignore that for now. I dont want to argue that we should or shouldnt adopt islam, I want to argue that any decline you see is not due to the reasons you are indicating. 


So you're worried about some potential decline of Western Civilization and your solution is to roll back the enlightenment with it's humanist move away from religion, and generally abandon the liberal tradition, our rationalist philosophies, civil rights and the scientific revolution?

What parts of Western culture do you want to keep?


I do find your reasons oddly specific though I can't for the life of me see the causal chain linking them. 




First off the idea of “white displacement” is fucking bonkers.  Race is not a scientifically recognized category, so there are no whites to be displaced.  Those that do believe in such a concept are usually angry about having to accept things like muslim culture in their society. 

That feminism and social justice movement are leading to the downfall of society isn't a particularly original complaint.

Ill state right off that im not a feminist. I agree with some things feminists argue for, and disagree with others.   What I do agree with in general is the value of establishing a society that is socially just. 

So what is Social justice?  Most basically it's the fair distribution of wealth, oppertunity and privelidge in society, and the elimination of arbitrary discrimination.

And this is why I dont get the hatred towards feminism and the social justice movement.   I can understand that you might not like a particular way social justice is being pursued.  Social change can be frightening, especially when it's demanding you change your behavior.  
But I don't understand those who feel that social justice is some kind of evil that is ruining society. 

Honestly what kind of person would say “no thanks, that idea isn't for me” when asked if society should have a fair distribution of wealth, opportunity and privilege?  Why wouldn't you want major institutions, companies and schools invested in the idea of social justice?

Society has had to change, and for the most part it's the behavior of “whites” and males which needed to be modified so that they stopped treating women and minorities like inferiors.  I do see “whites” and males being blamed a lot and I don't agree with that as it's just the culture we were handed, however we also must recognize that we can't allow it to remain as it was and should be working to make it more just. 

A whole heap of social and cultural institutions need to be reworked or eliminated and shit like that scares the fuck out of people.  Rather than claiming such changes represent some sort of ‘decline’ in our society however I argue that it's a vital step in societies advancement. 


Ill even admit that I think there's a fair chance that feminism and things like it are to blame for groups like incels and mgtows (and those who fear the white displacement).  Old courtship rituals and gender roles are essentially being eliminated by feminism, so there's a whole heap of confusion on how one is actually supposed to find a partner and what role one is supposed to have in a relationship. 

Sure before feminism courting was much more regulated and so incel/mgtow were less common.   This doesn't mean that feminism is bad for pushing these changes, because the changes needed to be made so that women could be equal members of society and in control of their own destiny. 

So after feminism we have frustrated incels and mgtow.  I recognise they are parts of our society that need assistance adjusting to the new way things are, but without feminism and sj work in changing old norms instead of incels and mgtow we would be going back to vast numbers of beaten housewives and overwhelming racial and sexual discrimination.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
