<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32624488574.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'm not saying MGTOW=Incel

I will. MGTOW are the incel equivalent of 'you cant fire me, I quit' mentality. They are just incels who say it's by their choice.

&amp;gt; Kahbib is the only man who should see her half naked and you know what, I agree

There is a big fucking line between 'half naked' and 'literally forced to cover their entire body'. The fact that you think they are comparable at all is ridiculous premise from the start. My work uniform (which the women I work with also wear) is long pants and a tee shirt. Is this too much skin for them?

&amp;gt; [arranged marriages] ensure both bodies are pure and their pair bonding has not been demolished

Pair bonding does not get 'demolished' through having sex before marriage. You can have a close relationship with a partner regardless of previous partners.

And on the subject of arranged marriage: what about gay people? Are they also part of the 'downfall' of western society?

&amp;gt; divorce isnt a thing in Muslim countries

So... why is that good? Marital rape is a thing, you know. Domestic abuse is a thing. Just not being compatible with someone is a thing. There are plenty of valid reasons to want a divorce.

And feminism isnt to blame for courts favoring women usually in custody cases. First off, most divorces dont go to court over custody. And when they do, what's done is whatever is in the best interest of the child for who is the better caregiver.

Moms are more likely to sacrifice work and social lives for their kids than dads are. So usually the mother is the better caregiver. Feminism seeks to abolish gender roles, and one result would be that parents would (ideally) have equal responsibility for the childcare. This means that this thing you see as one of the key parts of the downfall of society is actually something feminists want to fix.

&amp;gt; Do you discipline a man... or do you let him be free? 99/10p times I would choose the former

Good for you. But not everyone would choose the former. So, you can have your freedom to not drink and do drugs, and everyone else can have their freedom to make the choice for themselves. And just so you know, I dont drink or smoke or anything. So I'm not saying this as some sort of junkie or alcoholic.

&amp;gt; white males are at the brunt of accusations, and are made to feel guilty about all these things

No one is asking you to feel guilty for being a white man. I'm a white man, and also a feminist. According to you I should be hanging myself right now out of shame or something.

Asking someone to recognize that certain groups are more privileged than others isnt demanding you feel guilty for it. It isnt your fault specifically that men are more likely to be promoted than women of equal or even better qualifications. It isnt your fault white people and black people have different experiences with police officers. But that doesnt mean you should just ignore it, either. Recognize privilege, but you dont have to apologize for it because you personally didnt do anything wrong by choosing to be a white man.

&amp;gt; they effectively removed male biological forces by forcing women to cover up

Babies get raped, even though they have no sexual appeal at all, since they're *babies*. Women in countries where they're forced to cover up get raped. Hell, some people rape animals. And you know whose to blame for all of that?

Rapists. Not the babies. Not the women. Not the animals, or men in prison, or literally anyone who has been raped. It is the fault of the rapist for doing it. Demanding that women cover up to 'stop' rape is not only an awful thing to tell anyone who has been raped by implying its their fault, but also it doesnt actually solve anything. Especially if it's their husband, and your ideal world doesnt allow divorce.

Not to mention: men can and are also raped, quite a bit actually. So what would you suggest to them that they did wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625868693.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I will. MGTOW are the incel equivalent of 'you cant fire me, I quit' mentality. They are just incels who say it's by their choice.

MGTOWs are mostly men who have been divorced. That's the polar opposite of incel.

&amp;gt; My work uniform (which the women I work with also wear) is long pants and a tee shirt. Is this too much skin for them?

No but it begs the question; why are you required to wear a uniform at all? Is this oppressing to you?

&amp;gt; Pair bonding does not get 'demolished' through having sex before marriage. You can have a close relationship with a partner regardless of previous partners.

Sure, you can have a close relationship in that situation, but let me ask you a question. Let's say you have two couples:

- Couple A were both virgins when they got married and lost their virginity to one another.
- Couple B had both been divorced and have had numerous sexual partners before they got married.

Which of these couples will be closer? Which relationship is more likely to last?

&amp;gt; And on the subject of arranged marriage: what about gay people? Are they also part of the 'downfall' of western society?

I'm not really for or against gay marriage, I just don't see the point in it.

&amp;gt; So... why is that good? Marital rape is a thing, you know. Domestic abuse is a thing. Just not being compatible with someone is a thing. There are plenty of valid reasons to want a divorce.

Domestic abuse exists everywhere. I also disagree with "plenty of valid reasons" for divorce. Divorce should only be allowed if there is a very big reason for it, rather than "I fell out of love" or "I was unsatisfied". You entered a contract which is supposed to be for the rest of your life.

&amp;gt; And feminism isnt to blame for courts favoring women usually in custody cases. 

I can't argue with that. Men are the ones who came up with these laws for sure.

&amp;gt; First off, most divorces dont go to court over custody. And when they do, what's done is whatever is in the best interest of the child for who is the better caregiver.

What's better for a child - an intact marriage with both parents or a single mom with limited financial resources and a part-time father?

&amp;gt; Moms are more likely to sacrifice work and social lives for their kids than dads are. So usually the mother is the better caregiver. Feminism seeks to abolish gender roles, and one result would be that parents would (ideally) have equal responsibility for the childcare. This means that this thing you see as one of the key parts of the downfall of society is actually something feminists want to fix.

But you just contradicted yourself. If mom's biologically make better parents, that is in direct support of women staying home to take care of the children while the men work.

&amp;gt; Good for you. But not everyone would choose the former. So, you can have your freedom to not drink and do drugs, and everyone else can have their freedom to make the choice for themselves. And just so you know, I dont drink or smoke or anything. So I'm not saying this as some sort of junkie or alcoholic.

Drinking and doing drugs has enormous societal impacts. Drug addicts constantly commit crimes for a fix. Drunks get violent and beat their wives and other citizens on a regular basis. Being an alcoholic doesn't just effect the drinker.

&amp;gt; No one is asking you to feel guilty for being a white man. I'm a white man, and also a feminist. According to you I should be hanging myself right now out of shame or something.

Except for the enormous political campaigns asking for things like reparations when most white men even back then were not slave owners and actually suffered as a result of slavery due to jobs being taken for pennies per hour.

&amp;gt; Asking someone to recognize that certain groups are more privileged than others isnt demanding you feel guilty for it. It isnt your fault specifically that men are more likely to be promoted than women of equal or even better qualifications. It isnt your fault white people and black people have different experiences with police officers. But that doesnt mean you should just ignore it, either. Recognize privilege, but you dont have to apologize for it because you personally didnt do anything wrong by choosing to be a white man.

These things you're stating are extremely complex issues. For example, men *are* better at a lot of jobs than women. Check this out: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A75r7cXQMds

As for black experience with police officers, this is very complex. Blacks do commit more crime but it is essentially because they have no choice. They have no way to make a living, because things like rampant single motherhood have effectively destroyed their communities and access to the work force. It's a perpetual cycle.

&amp;gt; Babies get raped, even though they have no sexual appeal at all, since they're babies. Women in countries where they're forced to cover up get raped. Hell, some people rape animals. And you know whose to blame for all of that?

This is missing my point. I've already repeated it so many times I recommend you check out my responses to other feminists.

&amp;gt; It is the fault of the rapist for doing it.

I'm not here to defend rapists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625931221.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="False">
    <text>I wear a work uniform to appear more professional.

Me and many others would prefer partners with sexual experience. Who do you think has more fun during sex- two people who have had sex before, or two people where the boy doesnt even know women have orgasms yet?

The 'point' of gay marriage is for gay people to express love the same way straight couples have always been able to.

The fact is, arranged marriages will have more 'fall out of love'/incompatible marriages than without them. So why not just let people choose for themself?

And yes, abuse exists everywhere- that's my point. Forcing people into marriages with a stranger who you have no chance to get a feel for isnt going to decrease abuse.

Obviously an intact marriage is better. But not all marriages end perfectly, and in that case the kid should have what is best *and most realistic* for them in that moment.

Ah, you misread me. I didnt say women are biologically better parents- rather, social roles expected of women push them to be the ones who sacrifice their job for the kids. I don't think its biological, but social. So no contradictions- again, feminism is a way to hopefully end this double standard for moms vs dads.

Yes, they are complex issues. That's the point. You cant make broad claims like 'all feminists want white men to suffer'. As for your point about black people committing more crimes- they do, but the rate of which black people are arrested compared to white people is even higher than the rate they commit crimes. So there is a clear difference of treatment.

I dont think you are here to defend rapists. But you are acting as if rape only happens because women arent covering up 24/7, with some of your statements in the original post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626147120.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Who do you think has more fun during sex

I think this kind of approach to validating your points won't really work in this context as a huge reason I argued in favor of Muslim ideology was its removal of this hedonistic selfish pleasure.

&amp;gt; The 'point' of gay marriage is for gay people to express love the same way straight couples have always been able to

You don't need a state-backed contract in order for love to exist.

&amp;gt; why not just let people choose for themself

This is a great question. It is because arranged marriages are put together by people who have more wisdom in life and will be able to make a better decision in the long run. That's really what it boils down to.

&amp;gt; social roles expected of women push them to be the ones who sacrifice their job for the kids

But these roles are rooted in biology. They didn't just come into existence because a bunch of men sat down at a table one day 6000 years ago and said, "hey all these sluts need to stay at home while we go pump oil".

&amp;gt; You cant make broad claims like 'all feminists want white men to suffer'.

Perhaps you're right in that not all feminists are the extremists that the media constantly covers.

&amp;gt;  As for your point about black people committing more crimes- they do, but the rate of which black people are arrested compared to white people is even higher than the rate they commit crimes. So there is a clear difference of treatment.

This treatment is a result of the first criteria you mentioned. Blacks commit more crime, therefore cops assume they're more guilty, and the cycle continues on and on and on.

&amp;gt; But you are acting as if rape only happens because women arent covering up 24/7

I'm not saying rape would *never* happen, I'm saying there are certain things society as a whole can implement in order to reduce it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32657120218.0" user="CaptainAhabz" delta="False">
    <text>I just wanted to tell you that divorce is a thing in Muslim countries. I am Muslim and am living in a majority muslim country. Egypt.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
