<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32624636500.0" user="s_wipe" delta="False">
    <text>This is the burden of freedom.

It might be easier for some living in a very restrictive society, but its only if you manage to comply to its rules.

But this very restrictive society hinders development.

The muslim world is ridden with violence, if you look at the Wikipedia page for ongoing armed conflicts, you will see that apart from the south american drug wars, most conflicts around the world have islamists taking part in it.

The only reason to think what you think, is when you are a man, who thinks he will be better off in such a violent environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625218506.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>Well the majority of resource-based economies are Muslim so I don't think correlation = causation in this instance. Of course if you live in territory where the means of survival is dependent upon controlling said resources within, then violence over said territory is inevitable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625578509.0" user="s_wipe" delta="False">
    <text>With so much access to higher education and growing manpower, staying resource-based is a bad sign.

Its a bad sign of a government that doesnt know how to utilize its manpower, and instead, utilizes its resources to buy arms in order to stay in power.

Its not a good thing...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625770944.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; staying resource-based is a bad sign

Nations with no access resources are doomed.

Japan was mentioned and its an interesting point. However, if you look at the reasons behind Japan becoming wealthy, it was actually due to their lack of resources. No country could be bothered to fuck with them because there was no direct benefit. During times of war, they were used as a type of port for superpowers in order to impose their will upon other nations.

That's how Japan got rich, and now that Japan is rich, they can impact other economies through imports and the like. Once the finite resources of the world begin becoming scarce, Japan will be one of the first nations to collapse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625903017.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>Japan is rich because their people are well educated and hard working.  They use that human capital to produce value.  This is true of all 1st world countries.  A third world country has only it's natural resources.  A 2nd world country uses the wealth created by those natural resources to educate their population, build infrastructure, and all the other things that create sustainable wealth for the country.  Once that process is complete, it is a first world country.  Islamic countries seem content to just remain 3rd world countries with maybe the occasional dabbling in being a second world country(which when it is done has universally came alongside moderating their religious laws), which is why once the Middle East's oil runs out (or the world economy shifts away from reliance on oil), they will return to poverty, while 1st world countries will continue doing just fine.  And the world is rapidly shifting towards renewable resources anyway, so there is no reason to think that we are going to run out of resources.

As Sheikh Rashid bin Saeed Al Maktoum famously said, "My grandfather rode a camel, my father rode a camel, I drive a Mercedes, my son drives a Land Rover, his son will drive a Land Rover, but his son will ride a camel".  There is no lasing value being created out of the wealth generated by oil in the middle east.  So once the oil is gone, there will be nothing of value there.  This is not a culture that should be emulated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626201348.0" user="sclsmdsntwrk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Nations with no access resources are doomed.


That's just not true. First of all you might want to look up the so called Dutch disease which usually affects these economies that are largely dependent on one or a few natural resources.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626214135.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>So is your argument that a nation with a higher IQ is superior to all others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626352778.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>...What?  Where did you get that from what he said?  As I explained above, there are a lot of things that contribute to a country's wealth - education levels, infrastructure, trade agreements, regulatory environment, industry development, monetary policy, investment capital, etc.  Having abundant natural resources helps, especially in the early stages of a country's economic development.  But it is not necessary for a country to be successful.  The fact that most Islamic nations have chosen to rely virtually entirely on non-renewable natural resources is a negative thing though.  They have not done a good job of developing their country to ensure continued success after the oil runs out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626958848.0" user="sclsmdsntwrk" delta="False">
    <text>What does anything I said have to do with IQ?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
