<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32624493205.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>I suspect that you haven't spent much time in Muslim countries or communities so some of the things you've written here are not really accurate. In no particular order:

* Divorce totally is a thing in Islam. Without going into all the details, marriage in Islam is a legal contract that can be nullified if one or both parties fail to uphold their commitments. Women are owed their marriage dowry, sometimes a considerable amount of money or property, if the man is found to have failed as a husband in some respect - abuse, infidelity, marrying another wife without permission, breaking some promise written into the marriage contract, or even insufficiently performing in bed. Women can give up their claim to their dowry in order to get divorce consent without a reason. This is still a highly patriarchal system that favors men in nearly every instance, but women have some rights and divorce is one of them. If you have the time, [Divorce: Iranian Style](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yYaRb070r8E) is a fascinating watch. 

* There's plenty of frustration in these cultures as well. Even with arranged marriages (which are not actually so frequent these days in many countries), marriage is very expensive, and a husband is expected to provide for a wife and a new family soon after marriage. What this means in practice is that unemployment and debt force many men to delay marriage.  

* While drinking and drug use are frowned upon by legal and religious authorities, Muslims in many countries have long operated under the idea that what happens in private isn't anybody's business. There's drinking and drug use in every Muslim country, even those where it is outright banned. Rates of drinking and alcoholism may be lower, but many of these countries more than make up for this with rampant tobacco use resulting in very high rates of related cancers, as well as a growing diabetes problem. 

* I can also assure you that clothing does exactly nothing to "remove male biological urges." In fact, street harassment and cat-calling is a rampant problem in many Muslim countries, regardless of what the women are wearing. Sexual violence is also a frequent occurrence in some of these places although it is probably under-reported.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625728873.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Divorce totally is a thing in Islam.

The divorce rate in Muslim nations is enormously lower than it is in the West. Thanks for the additional information.

&amp;gt; What this means in practice is that unemployment and debt force many men to delay marriage.

Seems perfectly valid. Marriage is fundamentally about having children, children whom require resources. That's what I believe, anyways.

&amp;gt; Rates of drinking and alcoholism may be lower

Nothing is perfect. Prohibition doesn't stop alcoholism, but it definitely reduces the overall consumption.

&amp;gt; I can also assure you that clothing does exactly nothing to "remove male biological urges."

I'll take your word for it that cat-calling is a rampant problem in Muslim countries. However, I went over this in response to a couple of feminists already in this thread. Please read those responses as I don't want to repeat the same thing over and over.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625973851.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Nothing is perfect. Prohibition doesn't stop alcoholism, but it definitely reduces the overall consumption.

It doesn't do that either.  Alcohol consumption went up during Prohibition in the 1920's in America.  It also encouraged the growth of the mob and a lot of other consequences that much more than outweighed any possible positive societal effects.  This is why Prohibition was ended - it doesn't work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626103263.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>Alcohol consumption fell by 70% during prohibition.

What you're arguing here is a Nirvana fallacy. If it can't be perfect then it can't be good at all?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
