<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32624374746.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries

You outright admit that Muslim countries encourage all forms of oppression, so how can you possibly simultaneously argue that this is the superior ideology?

Liberals defend people’s freedom to live as they choose - this includes people’s right to be Muslim if they wish and to wear whatever clothes they want to wear.  But that’s the critical part - only as long as it is what they want.  

You are trying to solve fairly minor problems like incels by taking away a huge number of people’s freedoms (mostly women).  How is that a good idea?  Literally everything you present as a positive is actually a negative because it requires oppressing people and taking away their freedom to choose.  If a woman wants to wear fully covering clothes, that’s her choice.  If she wants to wear very skimpy clothes, that’s also her choice, and it should be a choice she’s allowed to make.  You are supporting outright oppression of everyone to force them to follow *your* moral beliefs.  That’s inherently wrong - people have their own moral codes, and as long as they aren’t hurting other people, you can’t just force them to follow yours.  Or you shouldn’t - if that was acceptable, why shouldn’t I force you to follow my moral code instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625416709.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You outright admit that Muslim countries encourage all forms of oppression, so how can you possibly simultaneously argue that this is the superior ideology?

Because you immediately assume that these things are "oppression". Throwing this label on restricting negative human behavior doesn't immediately make it a pejorative.

Morality is extremely important and we make use of it regularly. While I admit there are huge flaws with the legal system in the West, a lot of the laws make sense and breaking said laws should results in some form of punishment or rehabilitation, if possible. For example, if you break into a bank at night and steal a ton of money while simultaneously not harming anyone, should that be allowed?

What I got from your response was you basically implying we should do away with law because it oppresses people, which I fundamentally disagree with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625571251.0" user="MyNameIsKanya" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because you immediately assume that these things are "oppression". Throwing this label on restricting negative human behavior doesn't immediately make it a pejorative.

Of course! How could it be oppression if I just choose to ignore it! It can't be that bad if I just ignore the downsides! 

Great argument pal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625594374.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>I never said it should be ignored, quite the opposite.

For example, if a child wants to eat candy until he/she vomits, and a parent steps in to take their candy away, has that child been oppressed? The child wasn't doing anything to harm others.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625654640.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>It is the parents job to make sure the child doesn't hurt themselves, because the child doesn't know any better at that point.  The government should not treat citizens like children, with children's degree of control over their own lives.  If they do, yes, that's oppressive.  The government should not tell adults they cannot eat candy because it's bad for them.  That's none of the governments business.

All laws should compare the degree to which they limit the freedom of the people compared to the degree of harm they prevent.  A law that highly limits freedom for very little reduction of harm to society is a bad law - you are trying to push for a LOT of bad laws, because that's what is required in a religious state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625925710.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The government should not tell adults they cannot eat candy because it's bad for them. That's none of the governments business.

It is though, especially in countries with socialized healthcare. If people are eating tons of candy and getting diabetes, that creates longer times for treatment of people with legitimate medical conditions of which were not in their control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625961011.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>As far as I'm aware this has not been done anywhere.  Yeah, someone being fat does cause extra healthcare costs, as does smoking and a lot of other things.  So the government sometimes does things to encourage people to get healthier, but they don't just force everyone to eat healthy meals, exercise, etc to keep healthcare costs down.  That would be oppressive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626084376.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>Is it oppressive to force cigarette companies to put warnings on their packaging?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626454096.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>That's just making sure people are informed.  Giving more information to consumers is not oppressive.  Banning cigarettes might be considered somewhat oppressive (though far less than what you are suggesting), but not just including a warning.  Preventing companies from misleading people about what they are buying is a reasonable thing for the government to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625674435.0" user="MyNameIsKanya" delta="False">
    <text>The child were harming them self though. And this is a shitty example because doctors can back up the claim that excessive sugar is bad for you with science. No science can verify the claim that women should cover up in order to not be sexually assaulted. If women being modest meant they wouldn't get raped, should the rape rate at beaches or pools or even locker rooms be very high? Shouldn't sexual assault rates increase in the summer and decrease during winter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625935185.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Shouldn't sexual assault rates increase in the summer and decrease during winter?

I actually looked this up and couldn't find a single study. I'd bet that sexual assaults do decrease during winter. Perhaps because of the weather conditions as well, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625984051.0" user="MyNameIsKanya" delta="False">
    <text>Not how crime works..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625573517.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>Religious laws forcing people to live by religious beliefs that they may not share is inherently negative, yes.  Laws exist to protect other people, but you are suggesting adding a bunch of laws which hugely oppress a massive number of people, all to try and fix a few comparatively incredibly minor issues.  Your 'solution' is much, much, much worse than the problem.  I mean we could gather and freeze semen from every teenage boy then castrate them, and that would 'solve' the problem with incels too (and also rape and a lot of other violent crime too), but it's an insane way to try and solve the problem.

And robbing a bank hurts lots of people - it takes money from others (either directly if it's not FDIC insured, or by forcing higher taxes for the government to be able to cover it if it is).  It reduces trust in the financial system as well, which causes a lot of further problems for society.  And if robbing banks were legal, the entire financial system would collapse, causing hundreds of millions of deaths.  So that's a law that is extremely valid because it limits people's actions in very small ways to prevent extremely large problems.  You are trying to limit people's actions in incredibly huge ways to prevent very small problems.  That's oppressive, and it never makes a society better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625745827.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; all to try and fix a few comparatively incredibly minor issues

Rising divorce rates and single motherhood are not minor issues, and they are rapidly on the rise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625842972.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>They are much more minor issues compared to the systematic oppression of all women in almost every way imaginable.  Also divorce rates have actually dropped some lately, so it's not an increasing problem.  The rate of single motherhood has also stabilized and is no longer increasing.  Both of these things are issues that are being handled fine without any massive society altering (much less society destroying) consequences.  These issues do not even remotely close to justify the systematic oppression of 170 million people that you are supporting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626070148.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also divorce rates have actually dropped some lately, so it's not an increasing problem. The rate of single motherhood has also stabilized and is no longer increasing. Both of these things are issues that are being handled fine without any massive society altering (much less society destroying) consequences.

The rates of single motherhood increase significantly every decade: 

https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/pub/11-630-x/11-630-x2015002-eng.htm

You appear to be correct about divorce rates dropping recently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32626447070.0" user="Kythorian" delta="False">
    <text>This study appears to have ended in 2011.  I can't find where I read it previously off-hand, but the rate of single motherhood has stabilized in just the last decade.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
