<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="793889471.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d4nt1b/cmv_the_original_bioshock_is_one_of_the_most/">
    <title>CMV: The original BioShock is one of the most overrated video games of all time, and doesn't deserve a fraction of the praise it receives.</title>
    <original_poster>Chainsmoker88</original_poster>
    <original_post>**tl;dr:** The game had some great ideas. They just weren't executed properly imo. Allow me to elaborate.

BioShock's "Welcome to Rapture" level is one of the best introductions to any game ever. Rapture, Andrew Ryan, the splicers, Big Daddies, Little Sisters, Atlas' character, and plasmids are all explained to you in a perfectly executed 25 minute level. The tone is set for the game, there's a mystery from the very start about your character. Unfortunately, this is the only level in the game in which  the splicers have any personality, a lot of the levels in Rapture lack personality because they all look the same, our character isn't really expanded on until the Rapture Control Room level. To make it worse, the Big Daddies/Little Sisters are all just copied/pasted from level to level, which makes them feel like they're only there so that we can get upgrades and not because they are living, breathing characters.

 Fast-forward some 30 minutes and I am facing my first Big Daddy, and I have absolutely no idea what I'm doing. Nothing I do to it seems to be very effective and it all ends with me running around like a headless chicken, spending about 4-5 medkits and at least as many EVE syringes spray-n-praying through that ordeal. The game, as far as I can see, have given me absolutely no clues as how to deal with this guy, and this is not the first time either. I took this encounter as the worst example of many situations where it seems there simply is no good solution. I mean, the zap+whack works great for 1v1 encounters, but what about when there are multiple enemies with machine guns? I mean, yes, I could waste 40 machine gun bullets taking them down, but that hardly seems like the optimal solution and I also feel like that is not the way it should work as a survival horror. Entering a fight with Mr. Bubbles knowing he will fuck me up and I don't have anything to say in the matter really does not make me wanna continue playing. 

 I also think BioShock is a lazy game with the way that characters are presented. Yes, the characters are well written but unfortunately the creators of BioShock don't understand the old saying, "show, don't tell". Any kind of exposition is given to you in the same format of an audio diary. Don't get me wrong, I do like the inclusions of audio diaries and I think they can be used to great effect, I don't think they should be used to give exposition for every single thing in the game. The amount of character interaction in this game is laughable for a game that is praised for character development and while I understand the lack of characters may be there to give the effect of a horror game, BioShock fails at this due to the game not being able to find its own identity. I mean, does anyone actually consider BioShock a horror game? 

BioShock's story seems interesting enough. However, the way in which it's told is something the game's creators didn't quite get right. There is A LOT of backtracking in BioShock, and the story feels really contrived and convoluted at times. Right after the "Welcome to Rapture" level, you have to go through a whole series of events just to progress the story a tiny amount. You have to go get a plasmid to melt a lump of ice blocking your path so you can get a plasmid that will let you clean obstacles out of your way so you can go Dr Steinman so you can get a key from him so you can open a locked door. If that isn't contrived storytelling, I don't know what is. This isn't the only time this happens in the game, it happens several other times as well.

Then you get to the plot twist, which I won't spoil for anyone who may be reading this, and the game feels like it is hitting a turning point. Will there actually be any character development? Will there be any real interaction? The answer is obviously no. Unfortunately you wake up in Tenenbaum's safe house, yet the exposition is always the same (picture in bottom right with a voice clip played). This is laughable because she's in the other room, but this comes across to me as lazy and takes me out of the game due to the fact that I feel that the characters aren't real. The characters don't seem real, because they don't act like how normal humans would. It wouldn't of hurt them to have Tenenbaum actually talk to the player like a normal human interaction would happen, but it's never face to face in Bioshock, even when it should be which makes it feel very inhuman. 

Then for the second half of the game, Fontaine is constantly throwing insults at the player in a way which reminds me of a moustache twirling villain who is just doing it for the sake of it. This would work but I feel that Fontaine should be doing this much later on (kind of like Malak in KotOR). You do some fetch quests for an hour so that your brain won't tell your heart to shut off (ha!) and then you have to do something which still puzzles me how people let it slide. 

You have to become a Big Daddy. Now while this isn't a bad idea, just like everything else in Bioshock it's executed poorly. You become a Big Daddy to get through to Fontaine (who is a rehashed splicer model, just like everyone else in this game). Sounds fine. Then when you go to face Fontaine, the Big Daddy suit is suddenly gone (No big deal right? not like we just spent the last hour invested in this plot point, which really should have had a big effect.) Maybe it would have been interesting if they wrote it so that turning into a Big Daddy would have had a big emotional effect, where Jack has to sacrifice his free will to stop Fontaine, but no. Nothing at all.

Then the boss fight happens, where the boss can be perma-stunned. I don't even have to explain how bad this boss fight is, as everyone usually agrees about this point. Now to the endings. The good ending, while quite touching is unfortunately extremely short. The moral choice for this game comes from the save/kill little sisters, but this fails because all of the little sisters feel void of character, as they are just copied and pasted between levels, so to have them as the big moral choice is astonishing. Why doesn't anyone discuss how linear this choice is anyway? I mean, you harvest one little sister and you get the bad ending. Is this not the definition of a black and white choice? I'm not even going to discuss the bad ending, because it's so shitty that it's not even worth discussing.

I'll award a delta to anyone who convinces me to give this game another chance, or that any of what I just said is objectively wrong. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32676627442.0" user="imbalanxd" delta="False">
    <text>When exactly did you first experience this game? Are you keeping central in your mind the fact that this game came out 12 years ago?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32676787131.0" user="Chainsmoker88" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, and I was aware that it felt a little dated, but I was willing to look past that due to how much hype surrounded the game.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32676808561.0" user="imbalanxd" delta="False">
    <text>Well the amount of hype surrounding a game like Doom is infinitely greater. Even Doom is completely irredeemable from the perspective of a modern gamer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32676817200.0" user="Chainsmoker88" delta="False">
    <text>Your point being?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32677869079.0" user="dontbajerk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Even Doom is completely irredeemable from the perspective of a modern gamer.

I'd actually disagree.  Doom is still visceral fun.  It has aged far better than many other considerably newer shooters - try going back to play many of the significantly newer 3D-based FPS games on the original Playstation for instance.  They're slow, clunky, and awkward in comparison, and have really boring and bland level designs in comparison..</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
