<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="795564867.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d5nps3/cmv_teenage_climate_change_protestations_are/">
    <title>CMV : Teenage Climate Change Protestations are Useless</title>
    <original_poster>AsteroidSnowsuit</original_poster>
    <original_post>So around the world, there are a lot of protestations by teenagers that want to fight climate change. 

While this is a good cause I believe in (and that I try to fight for), is it really that useful ? You get thousand of students to block major roads in big city, pissing off a lot of people on the way. You can scream all you want at the leaders, but the real power to make a change is with your vote. 

Instead of spending hours outside, skipping school for no real good reason (hell, some students lie saying that they go to the protest, but they just go home instead), pissing off a lot of people on the way, why don't all of these students organize to pick up trash around their school, convince their parents to vote for people who are more green.

If every student that came to these manifestations spent all this time trying to make a change locally, the impact would have been bigger. When they grow up, they can have a real impact by voting for a party that is green.

The people who deny climate change won't tell themselves that climate change is real, they will only opposite strongly to the whole thing (because of the inconvenience caused by the protests).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

TL;DR : I don't get why people protest when there are way easier ways to make a change.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32690436750.0" user="i_mcd" delta="False">
    <text>Here's my view of this: protests are supposed to piss people off, theyre supposed to be disruptive. Not only does the disruption force government officials to take some form of action, but it also draws alot of attention to the issue of climate change and how much young people care about it- which encourages parties to support action against environmental issues in order to gain the young people's vote.

As for making everyday changes and picking up litter, that's almost worthless- yes it will improve your local area and make a small difference,but to truly make a difference you need to go to the people with power and get them to fight for you, especially as most of the environmental issues arent from ordinary people littering, but are actually from large corporations who care little about the environmental impact they have.

Furthermore, your point on voting for change is very true, but its a little more complicated than that depending on your democratic system- for example, in the uk, you vote for a party for your constituency, meaning if you live in a conservative area (like me), then your only choices are the tory party or the next biggest party that could combat them (lib dems). Simply voting green would do nothing because id essentially be throwing away my vote.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
