<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="795564867.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d5nps3/cmv_teenage_climate_change_protestations_are/">
    <title>CMV : Teenage Climate Change Protestations are Useless</title>
    <original_poster>AsteroidSnowsuit</original_poster>
    <original_post>So around the world, there are a lot of protestations by teenagers that want to fight climate change. 

While this is a good cause I believe in (and that I try to fight for), is it really that useful ? You get thousand of students to block major roads in big city, pissing off a lot of people on the way. You can scream all you want at the leaders, but the real power to make a change is with your vote. 

Instead of spending hours outside, skipping school for no real good reason (hell, some students lie saying that they go to the protest, but they just go home instead), pissing off a lot of people on the way, why don't all of these students organize to pick up trash around their school, convince their parents to vote for people who are more green.

If every student that came to these manifestations spent all this time trying to make a change locally, the impact would have been bigger. When they grow up, they can have a real impact by voting for a party that is green.

The people who deny climate change won't tell themselves that climate change is real, they will only opposite strongly to the whole thing (because of the inconvenience caused by the protests).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

TL;DR : I don't get why people protest when there are way easier ways to make a change.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32690361587.0" user="IlluminatusUIUC" delta="False">
    <text>Picking up trash has next to nothing to do with climate change, so raising as an easier way to make a change is misguided. And I would guess that lost of these kids have parents who are already left-leaning.

But the important part here is that climate change policy is both abstract and feels to many older voters to be too far away to worry about now. Talking about how there will be major effects in 50 years doesn't move the needle for a 65 year old voter. But the hope is that pointing out that people are fucking over their own grandkids might be enough to prompt a change.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
