<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="795564867.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d5nps3/cmv_teenage_climate_change_protestations_are/">
    <title>CMV : Teenage Climate Change Protestations are Useless</title>
    <original_poster>AsteroidSnowsuit</original_poster>
    <original_post>So around the world, there are a lot of protestations by teenagers that want to fight climate change. 

While this is a good cause I believe in (and that I try to fight for), is it really that useful ? You get thousand of students to block major roads in big city, pissing off a lot of people on the way. You can scream all you want at the leaders, but the real power to make a change is with your vote. 

Instead of spending hours outside, skipping school for no real good reason (hell, some students lie saying that they go to the protest, but they just go home instead), pissing off a lot of people on the way, why don't all of these students organize to pick up trash around their school, convince their parents to vote for people who are more green.

If every student that came to these manifestations spent all this time trying to make a change locally, the impact would have been bigger. When they grow up, they can have a real impact by voting for a party that is green.

The people who deny climate change won't tell themselves that climate change is real, they will only opposite strongly to the whole thing (because of the inconvenience caused by the protests).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

TL;DR : I don't get why people protest when there are way easier ways to make a change.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32690377141.0" user="Elicander" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re missing the point of protesting, the whole point is to be “inconvenient”. The point of protesting in the street isn’t to convince people in power that you’re right, it is to be so loud and many that people in power can’t ignore you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32690519703.0" user="thelawlessatlas" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree completely. It's true that the attitude of modern protesters is to just cause as much mayhem as possible, but that's not the point of a protest nor does it do anything for your cause. Three people can stand in the middle of a street and cause inconvenience, that doesn't mean their cause is noble or even valid. Being intentional a**holes is easy and only makes people hate you and your cause. What gives protests power is numbers, not inconvenience. If you clog the streets with your 20 person protest when you could easily go to the park down the street you're just pissing people off. The people in power will pay attention long enough to make you leave. If you clog the streets and inconvenience everyone because you have 2,000 people that don't fit in the park that you reserved, then the people in power will actually pay attention - But it takes time and effort to raise awareness and get large numbers of people out to your protest so the modern lazy protestor just takes the easy way out by spending 2 minutes to make a Facebook post and then standing in streets for no reason.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
