<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="795564867.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d5nps3/cmv_teenage_climate_change_protestations_are/">
    <title>CMV : Teenage Climate Change Protestations are Useless</title>
    <original_poster>AsteroidSnowsuit</original_poster>
    <original_post>So around the world, there are a lot of protestations by teenagers that want to fight climate change. 

While this is a good cause I believe in (and that I try to fight for), is it really that useful ? You get thousand of students to block major roads in big city, pissing off a lot of people on the way. You can scream all you want at the leaders, but the real power to make a change is with your vote. 

Instead of spending hours outside, skipping school for no real good reason (hell, some students lie saying that they go to the protest, but they just go home instead), pissing off a lot of people on the way, why don't all of these students organize to pick up trash around their school, convince their parents to vote for people who are more green.

If every student that came to these manifestations spent all this time trying to make a change locally, the impact would have been bigger. When they grow up, they can have a real impact by voting for a party that is green.

The people who deny climate change won't tell themselves that climate change is real, they will only opposite strongly to the whole thing (because of the inconvenience caused by the protests).

&amp;amp;#x200B;

TL;DR : I don't get why people protest when there are way easier ways to make a change.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32690459128.0" user="grautry" delta="False">
    <text>Quite some time ago, some assistant to a politician wrote a comment on reddit about their routine and how their guy took input and what they paid attention to(sorry, I don't remember the link, so you'll have to take my word for it, but I'm reasonably sure it was /r/bestof'ed if someone wants to dig through reddit history).

So, how do you capture a politician's attention? Email sucks. A physical letter is much better, but still so-so.

You know what they really pay attention to? Local news. If you make headlines of even your small, local newspaper? That's the kind of thing that politicians don't disregard - and a big protest is exactly the kind of thing that will have the eyeballs of your city's local newspaper/news station/etc.

You don't need to change the world, the nations or even the state, after all, for your protest to have meaning to it. If you "merely" convince your local mayor or city council to enact some local green laws, you've *made a difference*.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
