<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32702278858.0" user="ItsDevilsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies 

See you can say all those things, but they have little basis in reality. The adoption of capitalism actually correlates with the opposite; the increase in the rights and conditions of workers, the increase in the quality of life of the average person, and the reduction of poverty. As for climate change, that is not really a problem caused by capitalism, it is a problem caused by human prosperity. Which I suppose you can attribute to capitalism, as it has allowed people to flourish and populations to boom, but if that is your argument then your argument is against the flourishing and growth of the human race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702329605.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>So Amazon doesn't mistreat its warehouse workers? Sweatshops don't exist? These are very real.

Capitalism supports the business owners, and when business owners have hundreds of billions of dollars, do they still need that support to help the human race flourish?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702390419.0" user="ItsDevilsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you jump to extremes? I never said they bad conditions don't exist, but they are less prevalent now then ever before. That's the point, capitalism has increased the **average** conditions of everyone. If you think for a second that any single amazon worker has it worse than the average worker in the USSR or a serf in any of the thousands of per-industrial feudal societies, or even any factory worker in the early 1900s, you are sadly mistaken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702407883.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>It has certainly increased the average conditions, especially when compared to serfs, but there are people who fall below that average who don't have a voice since cash is king.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702457725.0" user="ItsDevilsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>So what is your point then? There will always be those who fall below the average, that is the nature of average. Capitalism has increased the average and continues to do so. I fail to see how an increasing in the average quality of life, working conditions, and poverty conditions has no place in our current world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702599221.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that our current system doesn't address those below the average. People who can't afford their needed medications, who can barely afford a roof over their head, etc.

That being said, as people have pointed out, while the system is lacking in some arguably serious areas, that doesn't necessarily mean the whole system needs to be thrown out, but it could certainly stand to use a few updates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32707016489.0" user="WeepingAngelTears" delta="False">
    <text>Other systems don't address the "below averages" by lifting them out of their conditions. They simply lower everyone else down so that the majority is at an equal low.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702404991.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So Amazon doesn't mistreat its warehouse workers? Sweatshops don't exist? These are very real.

Compare it to a feudal serf or a communist ~~slave~~ proletariat

The last 200 years of Capitalism have been by multiple orders of magnitude the most prosperous in human history, especially for the average person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32705055506.0" user="Lox-droplet" delta="False">
    <text>Warehouse workers everywhere make poor amount of money because it is not a skilled occupation.They however live on a very good standard compared with laborers in the USSR</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702350984.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As for climate change, that is not really a problem caused by capitalism, it is a problem caused by human prosperity. 

I don't necessarily agree with OPs main point, but I don't agree with this, either.

The profit motive is certainly to blame for the over-production of greenhouse gases, and of course for the resistance to any regulations that would have curtailed the production of those.

Government officials who weren't being bribed by wealthy industrialists, who could focus on the big-picture issues, would certainly be better stewards of the environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702424221.0" user="ItsDevilsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The profit motive is certainly to blame

I completely disagree, it's not the profit motive at all. It's not greedy people seeking profit that cause carbon emissions, it's the average person, the average person who finds that products and services which emit greenhouse gasses increase their quality of life, i.e. allow them to prosper. Global warming isn't a problem if all of the average person doesn't want to heat their home, global warming isn't a problem if all of the average person doesn't want to travel far from their home, global warming isn't a problem if all of the average person doesn't want products that can't be sourced locally. Global warming is a problem because the average person(not just the average but everyone, poor and rich included) wants the products which allow them to prosper, not because of any greedy individual, corporation, or profit motive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702561840.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It's not greedy people seeking profit that cause carbon emissions,

No, it really is people seeking profits.

I agree the people want things.

But it's people wanting to make money satisfying those wants, who are actually over-producing as they all vie for the biggest piece of the pie, that are dangerous.

that was why I mentioned government officials who can focus on big-picture issues.

Regulations based on what experts consider necessary are easier to get when the profit motive isn't there to stand in the way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702656339.0" user="ItsDevilsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>Except profit motive doesn't exist, literally at all, without the consumer demand. People "wanting to make money" aren't over producing, they are producing what the people want in the quantities that they want them. I get your point that regulation can change incentives, this is true. But I think my point still stands that the profit motive isn't a root motive, it only exists because of the underlying demands and motives of the consumer. Capitalism only allows the freedom of people seeking the "profit motive" to supply consumers with the things they want. Perhaps regulations can decrease the incentives for people to want certain things, by artificially making them more expensive thus decreasing demand. But again that doesn't decrease the profit motive directly, it decreases it indirectly by de-incentivizing the consumer. It all stems from the wants of the consumer, there is no profit and no incentive to seek profit without an underlying demand from the consumer. Thus blaming profit motives, and those supplying consumer demands, is shortsighted as the root cause of any sort of production is ultimately demand for products. If there is no demand for a product then there is no profit motive to supply that product.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702912164.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Except profit motive doesn't exist, literally at all, without the consumer demand

Yeah. I said that.

But the profit motive does exist under capitalism.

&amp;gt;they are producing what the people want in the quantities that they want them.

 No they don't. We overproduce like crazy. 

&amp;gt;But I think my point still stands that the profit motive isn't a root motive, it only exists because of the underlying demands and motives of the consumer.

No, it's still the cause, because you *can* satisfy the people's needs without it, but it being there causes all these problems.

&amp;gt;Perhaps regulations can decrease the incentives for people to want certain things, by artificially making them more expensive thus decreasing demand. 

No, regulations don't affect people's demand at all - they only affect the ability to supply.

Making things expensive reduces purchases, but not the wanting.

&amp;gt;If there is no demand for a product then there is no profit motive to supply that product.

This is true, but not relevant.

"If things were different, they wouldn't be the same."

Facts are people *do* want things, and allowing the people who supply them to be affected by the profit motive has shown to be detrimental to the environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32703074182.0" user="ItsDevilsAdvocate" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No, it's still the cause, because you can satisfy the people's needs without it, but it being there causes all these problems.

If let's say a pure communist society supplied all of the peoples needs(hypothetically) you would still have the same problem because the people would still want power, travel, and goods. All of which require the burning of fossil fuels to acquire, thus causing the environmental problems you are talking about. You see the only way to not have these problems is to either change what people want or to not supply the demand. If you are assuming that under different motives some alternative to the detrimental ways that we supply these needs, i.e. burning fossil fuels, would be found you are sadly mistaken. So unless socialist motives(or whatever other motives) could miraculously invent ways to supply these demands in ways which do not negatively effect the environment what is likely to happen is that A) the peoples needs go unmet, B) society collases. No suprise that this is actually the exact scenario that plays out in every socialist country ever.

&amp;gt; No, regulations don't affect people's demand at all - they only affect the ability to supply

Regulations decrease demand by artificially increasing price. Regulations make it harder to provide services and goods, when goods and services are harder to provide the price of them goes up. Higher price reduces demand. If a flight to Europe is $500 more people are going to travel to Europe than if the ticket price is $1500. With the higher price more people will decide that it's not worth the cost. Thus demand is reduced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704679962.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>Look, my argument has nothing to with socialism being better than capitalism, so examples of problems with socialism just arent relevant.

We are talking about the profit motive and it's effects.

As for regulations, you have for *some* reason switched from saying 'people want things' to using a definition of 'demand' that means what people can afford.

Something being expensive doesn't stop people from wanting it.

Is it really so hard to agree with me on this point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702427749.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The profit motive is certainly to blame for the over-production of greenhouse gases

Then why was East Germany such a catastrophe?

The issue is that during the industrial revolution all our tech was based on fossil fuels. By the time we realized we needed to switch we had over a hundred years of built up fossil fuel infrastructure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702479680.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>But that infrastructure is incredibly slow to change since it's making a nice profit. It doesn't have to change if it can buy politicians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702495006.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Then why was East Germany such a catastrophe?

I don't understand.
I never suggested that every possible socialist country must therefore perform better than any possible capitalist one.

&amp;gt;The issue is that during the industrial revolution all our tech was based on fossil fuels. By the time we realized we needed to switch we had over a hundred years of built up fossil fuel infrastructure.

How it started wasn't part of my argument.

Once we found out what was causing it, the profit motive encouraged people to ignore the problems and in fact make them worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32703009141.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't understand. I never suggested that every possible socialist country must therefore perform better than any possible capitalist one.

Every socialist nation has been an absolute train wreck on all fronts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704658242.0" user="Burflax" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Every socialist nation has been an absolute train wreck on all fronts.

If you mean communist, then i largely agree.

I never suggested otherwise, and that doesn't contradict my point.

A person can criticize capitalism without suggesting communism is a utopia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702351033.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>Haven't you forgot some things here? Colonialism, Slavery, Unions and revolutions, the continued use of slavery by "outsourcing" production to third world countries in order to circumvent labor laws and effectively still use slavery? The problem that the industrialization of the third world and developing countries is necessary for them and understandable from a rational position but a) only necessary because the first world isn't cooperating but competing and b) is only detrimental because the first world already almost exceeds the cap of emission long before those entered the game?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702437844.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Colonialism, Slavery 

Those things have two things in common. They started long before capitalism and it was capitalism that ended them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702454277.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>I would say it's unfair to attribute those changes to capitalism. In the US, there was a war fought over whether not states should decide if slavery can exist. It was legislation that ultimately changed that.

A group of workers that don't cut into your profits? That's every business owners dream.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702474200.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on your definition of capitalism...
&amp;gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_capitalism</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
