<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32703331372.0" user="Mnlybdg" delta="False">
    <text>I think you mean crony capitalism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32703576546.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>Is that really so different than what we have now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32703734194.0" user="bendiboy23" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if that is the case, then an argument could be made that maybe its not capitalism that's the issue, but perhaps it's the perverted form of democracy which our political system has?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32706080688.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that perverted form of democracy the very result of capitalism: money in politics, lobbyism aso.

The free market place of ideals, values, morals, ethics, spines and integrity, all for sale, buy one get one free...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32707341234.0" user="bendiboy23" delta="False">
    <text>The central tenets of capitalism are the free market/for exchange of goods and the right of individuals to private property (including the means of production) if attained from the free market. Both of these are completely to do with the economic management and functioning of society, and neither of them inherently involve themselves in crony capitalism. 

In other words, while often times people associate capitalism with freedom of having basically anything up for sale, what it really involves is freedom to exchange goods and services. Nowhere does it state that there should be freedom to bribe public officials, as a means to gain unfair uncompetitive advantages in the free market. When many conservatives argue for the right of companies and individuals to donate/lobby politicians, it's not so much due to capitalism or free markets, it's because they ascribe to a more individualistic world-view where they believe one should be able to do what one likes as long as they're not hurting others. 

So I think it would be unfair to say crony capitalism is inherent to capitalism, just as it would be unfair to say that political intrigue is inherent to socialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32709007766.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The central tenets of capitalism are the free market/for exchange of goods and the right of individuals to private property (including the means of production) if attained from the free market. 

Coming with the asterisks that no property originally was obtained in a free market but that our modern societies are build upon the ruins of older empires that employed violence, slavery and other atrocious means to build those empires and that the free exchange with those empires means/meant condoning, supporting or even participating in those atrocities. Trading with a thieve doesn't make the acquired property any less of an act of theft.

And while you might come up with a moral framework that argues in favor of letting people keep the fruits of their labor. One would have to acknowledge, that this doesn't really give any grounds for the appropriation of the means of production and that this is in somewhat of a contradiction when in comes to wage labor. Where the fruits of people's labor go to the capitalist who then redistributes **some** of those fruits or the profits made from them, back to the worker. However always less than what was originally created because he has to pay himself as well. Which is a system that is inherently exploitative as owning capital can generate you "effortless wealth" (meaning other people have to work for that wealth). Which in turn is indicative of a power imbalance. Because why should people participate in such an exploitative system

As as you might have guessed it, given equal needs but unequal distribution of resources means that you either have to take by force or exchange with someone who has what you need. Now if you don't have anything of value to them, you have to prostitute yourself, sell your heart and soul, your body, your time, your dignity, your creativity, your knowledge, your strength or simply put your "work force". Obviously you're expected to sell yourself cheap as the capitalist wants (and somewhat even needs; it's an inherently flawed system not a failure of an individual) to make a profit.

&amp;gt;In other words, while often times people associate capitalism with freedom of having basically anything up for sale, what it really involves is freedom to exchange goods and services.

That's the thing, you don't have to mandate that everything is for sale. All that you have to do is create conditions in which the needs of the people can technically be fulfilled (or at least to an extend that mitigates suffering) but aren't, due to an imbalance in wealth. And what will happen is that people will sell out "voluntary". Don't fool yourself here, the need to survive in order to escape excruciating pain and suffering or the fear for those without it won't make sense to continue existence is anything but "voluntary". But if you only care for the lack of explicit violence and ignore that coercion can happen without explicit violence and that the most awful torture is one that breaks the mind not the bones, then you're probably "fine" with your "morals".

So all you need for that to happen is to protect private ownership of the means of production, as that ensures an imbalance of wealth, due to the exploitative nature of the business. Seriously a worker can never make as much as a person employing and profiting from thousands/millions/billions of workers, whether direct or indirectly by being supplied with energy and resources produces by thousands/millions/billions of workers. 
And without a limit on what can be for sale as long as it's "a free exchange" and "voluntary" (which as said are terms that mean absolutely nothing as the status quo is already a tipped scale and anything but voluntary or fairly acquired) that means that anything can be and **is** for sale, without a necessity to demand that. It's an inherent feature of the system based on private property over the means of production and "liberal" (in the literal meaning not the political) use of the words "free" and "voluntary".

Seriously I've currently a "nice" discussion with a market radical who literally advocates for "voluntary slavery" and "rape contracts" as long as they are voluntary and believes that they could ever be and that you can sign away your rights and that this makes anything following "consensual"...

&amp;gt;Nowhere does it state that there should be freedom to bribe public officials, as a means to gain unfair uncompetitive advantages in the free market.

No, but in a free market you can freely exchange favors. I mean in politics it's painfully obvious that being a politician is a position of power, that doesn't come from the politician itself but from the people choosing a person to represent them, the same is technically true in terms of companies and their leaders. But the more indirect, representative and less accountable that becomes, the more the politician or CEO or owner becomes the actual figure of power. And in terms of economics that is already so commonplace that people don't even think about it and in politics that inherently leads to bribery being the logical conclusion. If the politician is not just a projection space for his constituents but if the power of his constituents is his private property, then it's his free choice to exchange his service for money.

There are also other ways to influence politics by using the stranglehold over the economy to threaten politics, like "if you don't do XYZ I'll move my wealth/company/jobs/... to place ABC" or by continuously lowering the budget of the government so that positions of power are de facto sold out to the private sector. Healthcare, education, military contractors and so on, making the private sector the de facto state and depriving the sovereign (the people) of it's power...

&amp;gt; When many conservatives argue for the right of companies and individuals to donate/lobby politicians, it's not so much due to capitalism or free markets, it's because they ascribe to a more individualistic world-view where they believe one should be able to do what one likes as long as they're not hurting others.

Yeah and politicians never lie... Seriously conservatives regularly cheerish nationalism and the military both being very collectivist (not collective) ideas that make no sense on the level of an individual. Seriously if you go to war, you're likely to die or come home with PTSD and leave your family that needs you in stake, there is no reason from an (individualist perspective) to subjugate yourself to someone else's command and to fight for THEIR benefit (as it is clearly not yours...). Same with nationalism, there is no reason for that on the individual level. Capitalists regularly screw over "their own people", but when it comes to defending their wealth, logistics and influence, then it's suddenly "your country" or "our country"... 

The word your searching for isn't individualist it's selfish. An individualist cares for the individual, a selfish person only cares for **one particular** individual (or the small peer group that he likes for his pleasure).

And of course that is hurting others. If you speculate with crops that is killing people, if you make money with war and tobacco, that is killing people, if you take away peoples jobs and healthcare, that is killing people. Just because you don't put a gun to someone's head doesn't mean you're not killing people.

&amp;gt;So I think it would be unfair to say crony capitalism is inherent to capitalism, just as it would be unfair to say that political intrigue is inherent to socialism.

crony capitalism is inherent to capitalism and capitalism itself is a derogatory term coined by early socialists and anarchists for a system in which money rules the world and in which people who work don't own the means that they are working with... Literally, look it up. 

Morality under capitalism doesn't exist because of it, but despite of it. The only hopeful thing is that it takes law and order, propaganda and massive media brainwashing to even make people like the name. And with all it's efforts it still isn't able to kill human decency in favor of more profits. Also political intrigues will probably always be a thing, it's just that they work better within hierarchies and systems with institutional positions of power rather than systems where the people manage themselves, so actual socialism (meaning democratic ownership of the means of production) it should actually be mitigated to some extend. Of course that is not the case if that ownership is relegated to a dictator...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32709639978.0" user="bendiboy23" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, I just wanted to say I really appreciate you taking the time to write out such a long and well-thought out response and I hope we can continue this discussion!

&amp;gt;Trading with a thieve doesn't make the acquired property any less of an act of theft.

Ok in response to this, I concede that pretty much all property and land etc, was at one point stolen through war or violence and the people who originally appropriated/created the resource didn't get the justice they deserve. That being said, while I believe societies have a responsibility to rectify such injustices as much as pragmatically possible, it's simply unreasonable to return all property to their rightful owners and the best we can do is compensate victimised groups of injustice that still exist today, and prevent such injustices from happening in the future. So I don't believe this argument invalidates capitalism, because there are certain practical limitations we must acknowledge.

&amp;gt;And while you might come up with a moral framework that argues in favor of letting people keep the fruits of their labor. One would have to acknowledge, that this doesn't really give any grounds for the appropriation of the means of production and that this is in somewhat of a contradiction when in comes to wage labor.

Correct if I'm wrong, but it seems to me you are coming from the perspective of the Labour Theory of Value, and while I'm no expert on it, I believe it has already being discredited by modern economists with a few simple arguments. Firstly, the concept of economic value is subjective and therefore, the value of labour that goes into making a product is inherently subjective and can't be measured simply by how many hours that is put into making it. Another major issue with LTV, and more relevant to the points you brought up, is it fails to account for the value of capital. The workers in a factory undoubtedly provides value, but the machinery in the factory makes the process more efficient, and provides its own form of value. Therefore, the individual who owns the factory, should have a share of the profit even if they aren't putting any effort into the production process, since they're still providing value by renting out the factory.

In regards to the capitalist being able to choose how to redistribute profits to workers, this is since there's in general a greater supply of workers than capital, and as such capitalists will usually be the one who gets to set the contract, since so many workers compete for the same job. However, this isn't true of every industry, as capitalists who lease out business offices don't get to decide how to split up profits, and only gets income in the form of rent (effortless wealth).

&amp;gt;Now if you don't have anything of value to them, you have to prostitute yourself, sell your heart and soul, your body, your time, your dignity, your creativity, your knowledge, your strength or simply put your "work force"  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Don't fool yourself here, the need to survive in order to escape excruciating pain and suffering or the fear for those without it won't make sense to continue existence is anything but "voluntary"

True in the sense capitalism has no guarantee of positive liberties, and is only focused on ensuring negative liberties are kept...However, I've never been an advocate the radical free market, since market failures are inevitable in certain industries leading to monopolies and a lack of perfect competition. This is why I believe some level of government intervention is required to make markets run more efficient and remain competitive. And competitive markets ultimately lead to improvements of living standards for workers and don't remain the hellscapes of torture you believe them to be.

&amp;gt;And without a limit on what can be for sale as long as it's "a free exchange" and "voluntary" (which as said are terms that mean absolutely nothing as the status quo is already a tipped scale and anything but voluntary or fairly acquired) that means that anything can be and **is** for sale, without a necessity to demand that

I apologise if my next argument comes off a little cliche-y or overused, but I believe it does ring true in this case. The wealth pie isn't a fixed concept. The imbalance of wealth doesn't necessitate poverty or suffering. Wealth (not in the monetary concept) is constantly growing as technology and innovation improves. Individuals living in a society with extremely low wealth inequality back 3000 years ago, might not have the same standard of living as the poorest person in an extremely materialistically unequal society 3000 years into the future.

&amp;gt;Seriously I've currently a "nice" discussion with a market radical who literally advocates for "voluntary slavery" and "rape contracts" as long as they are voluntary and believes that they could ever be and that you can sign away your rights and that this makes anything following "consensual"...

Well, I'm sorry you had to deal with the extremists who unfortunately are associated with the political ideas I'm an advocate of.

&amp;gt;And in terms of economics that is already so commonplace that people don't even think about it and in politics that inherently leads to bribery being the logical conclusion.

I disagree, a corruption of political institutions simply because politicians fall prey to greed by exchanging political favours for wealth isn't the logical conclusion of capitalism. Apologies if I'm misunderstanding your argument, but I don't see the link between how a system of economics has to necessitate the corruption of democracy, which has a completely different system of rights and obligations. In regards to corporations threatening to leave the country to blackmail politicians into crony capitalism, while this is disruptive to markets in the short-term, in the long run other firms will take its place in the name of profit and bring back market efficiency and equilibrium.

&amp;gt;Seriously if you go to war, you're likely to die or come home with PTSD and leave your family that needs you in stake, there is no reason from an (individualist perspective) to subjugate yourself to someone else's command and to fight for THEIR benefit (as it is clearly not yours...). Same with nationalism, there is no reason for that on the individual level.

Well, this seems to come from an implied premise that the current system is one of exploitation and subjugation and therefore losing the war won't hurt one's livelihood at all (unless you're a capitalist). I disagree with that premise since belonging to collective groups in times of violence and anarchy, is the most effective way for individuals to survive. But I concede conservatives can be hypocrites sometimes.

&amp;gt;If you speculate with crops that is killing people, if you make money with war and tobacco, that is killing people, if you take away peoples jobs and healthcare, that is killing people. Just because you don't put a gun to someone's head doesn't mean you're not killing people.

Yes true speculation on prices can sometimes hurt people, through sheep/trend following behaviour where prices are pushed to inefficient and disequilibrium levels. However, this is rectified in the long run and to minimise damage I believe governments should step in immediately to ensure greater efficiency of markets and maximum benefit. The other points you raised doesn't put enough emphasis on the inherent virtue ethics of those actions and judge it too narrowly by just the eventual outcome. Again, while I believe a successful government would ensure a reasonable level of healthcare, not giving someone healthcare is not the same as killing them, because it makes killing someone the moral equivalent of being an inactive bystander.

In regards to your last paragraph, yes I agree capitalism is a flawed system and in many ways over enable greed...But I believe its alternatives aren't much better, and I'd be happy to discuss that considering I believe you to be an advocate and probably quite knowledgable on the socialist or communist system (apologies if my assumptions are incorrect)

And I'd prefer to be able to play some offence here considering I've been playing defence for the entirety of this post haha...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32717843092.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>Part I
&amp;gt;it's simply unreasonable to return all property to their rightful owners

I mean the initial question is "are there rightful owners" to begin with. That is, could and should things such as land, water, minerals and all kinds of resources, as well as the results of collective work, be (private) property to begin with. Meaning should there be an exclusive right to exploit beyond reasonable and immediate usage? Because if you grant that property, you can also take it away (legally) or use your superior starting position to "fairly" buy it. An example would be third world countries with rich reservoirs of natural resources. Legally the resources belong to the country in which they reside, technically that means they belong to "the government", so if you practically make a regime change in which a dictator takes the power (becomes "the government" and thereby "the owner"), you can use the fact that he is reliant on international support to make him sell the resources, either directly to you or to the "free" market in exchange for international approval. Leaving the dictator relatively rich, the first world in a de facto colonialist position without the necessity of an empire (the dictator does the dirty work and is regularly condemned without taking any actions) and the people in the country poor and oppressed...

&amp;gt;So I don't believe this argument invalidates capitalism, because there are certain practical limitations we must acknowledge.

Well capitalism relies a great deal on the private property of the means of production, so much in fact that Ludwig von Mises (Austrian school economist and fan of Mussolini's fascism) said:

&amp;gt;The program of liberalism, therefore, if condensed into a single word, would have to read: property, that is, private ownership of the means of production... All the other demands of liberalism result from this fundamental demand.

However if you take into account that this property, when followed to its roots, is nothing more than a claim for something, either backed up by some pseudo-religion of "natural rights" that cannot be discussed and have to be taken as-is, by a claim of "fruits of labor", which is dubious as just working on a field doesn't create the field or in the most pure and essential version, by nothing more than the violent threat (by an individual or more often an institution such as a state) to use coercive means if you'd resist that claim. Then it's pretty obvious that morally, ethically and even logically the whole foundation of that ideology stands on very shaky grounds and it's staunch resistance towards redistribution, theft and changes in the distribution of property of any kind are essentially just a conservative position that tries to keep the status quo that favors a wealthy minority over a relatively or absolutely poor majority. Which is also evident in politics where (classical) liberals often side with conservatives and if they need to even with fascists, because no liberty is "holier" to them than that of private property and so they'll throw every other liberty under the bus to preserve that most precious to them...

&amp;gt;LTV: Firstly, the concept of economic value is subjective and therefore, the value of labour that goes into making a product is inherently subjective and can't be measured simply by how many hours that is put into making it. 

I'm not an expert on LTV either, but as far as I know that is not the point. Something doesn't get an inherent value by putting work into it. It's rather that you within that framework you make the assumption of a distinction between "use value" (consumption; which creates the "subjective" fluctuation) and "exchange value", which is essentially just the relation between goods within a society and there you basically exchange a value of "abstract labor" that went into these products. Giving away your labor (time) for money makes you entitled to other peoples time to a comparable extend... Where abstract labor is the idea that if you'd standardized the process how long it would take on average to create a product. Meaning if you slack off and take twice as long the value isn't increasing or if you rush it in half the time the value isn't decreasing. So given that the technical advancements are more or less killing the unique work of craftsmen and instead make products more and more similar and standardized, that would actually be applicable (in many if not most areas). 

And in terms of the factory, well no it doesn't add any abstract labor to the product. It's rather that it is itself a product of abstract labor (namely by the people who built it and provided the parts aso). I mean the factory doesn't produce on it's own, it still needs an energy source and that energy source is most likely human labor, either direct (workers) or indirect (supply chain). So if you'd build your own factory you could just as well utilize that boost in efficiency... So essentially the moment the capitalist makes a profit by getting more off that bonus per item than he's invested, the moment the other end makes a loss over not having build the factory themselves (collectively). 

Also a more sinister version is that both LTV and marginal utility are wrong (or just partially applicable) and that prices are essentially just the product of power relations. That most luxury stuff is valueless for the most part and just serves to convey power and superiority: status symbols. It's not about the product itself, the ability to waste money and still be strong, is like the gorilla punching his chest...
 Or if you depend on your local agrarian or otherwise you'd starve, that person can set the price as arbitrarily high as he wants. Aside from the fact that at some point you'll simply say fuck it and take what you need whether he wants that or not, meaning the price rather reflects the ability to enforce violence rather than any inherent economic ideas. Money entitles you to other peoples time (morally in an equal exchange) and is a surrogate for the coercive power (in an unequal exchange). So a lot of the times it doesn't have to be explicitly coercive, but the bigger the inequality the less abstract it becomes. And that's not confined to absolute poverty, that power imbalance also would work if we'd assume paradise like environmental conditions and just that inequality.

&amp;gt;In regards to the capitalist being able to choose how to redistribute profits to workers, this is since there's in general a greater supply of workers than capital

I'd disagree. The problem here is not the amount of capital, but it's its distribution. For the sake of argument let's assume that the capitalist owns 99% of the capital (no matter how much or how little that is in absolute things). Then he's in the position of power to determine what jobs are being paid (or paid well) for. It's not a lack of work (there is always something to do and if not... well relax...) or a lack of means to pay for the work, it's simply that this position of power that allows to create that bottleneck in which "work" is a scarce product and in which workers have to compete. However that competition doesn't have to be a natural one but can be purely artificial. And for obvious reasons it benefits capitalists more than the workers to have that competition. As they can pick the one offering the best work/price relation or best fit overall fit for the job and if they let them show their skills before hiring them, they might even get their project done without hiring anybody at all... If you control the means of production, you control what work is valuable, what work is worth and cynically also WHO is valuable and worth something. Namely those that are fit for the job that you deemed worthy. So even under ideal conditions that would be a problem in terms of social tension.

&amp;gt;And competitive markets ultimately lead to improvements of living standards for workers and don't remain the hellscapes of torture you believe them to be.

I mean I see how competition is better than a dictatorship (monopoly). However competitions are ultimately not a good idea (for the most part). They create redundancy (which is both an inefficient use of resources as well as a fail safe; so good and bad), they lead to secrecy and reinventions of the wheel, they incentivize slow progress as anything that is out there will be copied and having a "joker" is beneficial, they even lead to monopolies as cities, districts, countries and regions may support local monopolies (global players) rather than regulating their markets (tech giants and tax havens), which in turn use their power to play countries against each other (who offers lower labor laws and lower wages, more subsidies and lower taxes, aso). I mean if there are 2 options and no idea what is better, well fair enough let them compete under rules that measure performance and not simply pick "the winner". But competitions are not a fit all solution and actively detrimental in most contexts, aren't they?

&amp;gt;The wealth pie isn't a fixed concept.

No it isn't, but with competitions and "winner-takes-all" rewards and a heavily distorted wealth distribution you can turn it back into a zero-sum-like game, as explained above. If the surplus value only adds to the capitalist, it's the same as if it wasn't added at all. Also people don't live in the past or the future but in the now and if you're a slave it doesn't matter that slavery 1000 years ago was even worse, it's still not good right now and that is what matters. A wealth imbalance is always a power imbalance and a power imbalance is always detrimental no matter how luxurious your prison cell is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32717847428.0" user="Us3rn4m34lr34dyT4k3n" delta="False">
    <text>Part II
&amp;gt; Apologies if I'm misunderstanding your argument

The argument was that a individual takes credit for a collective effort. A CEO for a company or a politician forgetting that he's just a representative. Also in a competition there is always an incentive to tinker with the rules and if the politician is of the assumption that it's "his" power that he's wielding, corruption is the logical conclusion. The question is not whether competitors will try to tinker with the rules, the question is will you let them.

&amp;gt;while this is disruptive to markets in the short-term, in the long run other firms will take its place in the name of profit and bring back market efficiency and equilibrium.

Correct but both people without a job and politicians wanting to be re-elected are very concerned about "short-term" changes. As they might still be too long.

&amp;gt;Well, this seems to come from an implied premise that the current system is one of exploitation and subjugation and therefore losing the war won't hurt one's livelihood at all (unless you're a capitalist). I disagree with that premise since belonging to collective groups in times of violence and anarchy, is the most effective way for individuals to survive.

Well being an average soldier **is** a position of exploitation and subjugation... and what ever you have to lose, for the time of your employment, you've already lost that. You'll leave your family, your possessions and even your agency behind and face the real threat of loosing your life as well. So unless you're fighting against some fascist lunatics who simply want to kill you because you exist (which is likely what you're being told no matter whether that is true or false), it's likely not a good idea to be a soldier, at least from an individualist perspective.
Though I got to give you the point that it depends on where the war is being fought. Because I agree that forming a collective actually improves the overall chance to survive which also improves the individual chance to survive. However the military is basically the antithesis to a mutual collective (milita?). Apart from the higher ups, few people see the bigger picture (deliberately scarce information management), so it's rather trust and order and obedience.

&amp;gt;The other points you raised doesn't put enough emphasis on the inherent virtue ethics of those actions and judge it too narrowly by just the eventual outcome.

Could you elaborate what you mean by this?

&amp;gt;it makes killing someone the moral equivalent of being an inactive bystander.

What's the difference? I mean you can obviously find exceptions like, having to put yourself in danger or not being in the position to be more than a spectator to begin with. Ought implies can. But given a situation in which you could help and in which it would be little more than a minor inconvenience for you, why shouldn't refusing to do so be seen as morally equivalent to killing someone? I mean you made the deliberate decision that your inconvenience is more important than this other person's life. Or is that some fate based argument? 
I mean sure a person in the first world is basically playing a million dimensional trolley problem every day, as there are so many people dying and one could help them, but would have to sacrifice others and oneself aso. And it helps no one if one takes moral responsibility for the killing of all these people and feels bad about that **without actually doing something about it**, because whatever you do is by default not enough (not just a problem of the individual). But that doesn't mean that one is excused from any responsibility when being an inactive bystander, does it?

&amp;gt;In regards to your last paragraph, yes I agree capitalism is a flawed system and in many ways over enable greed...But I believe its alternatives aren't much better, and I'd be happy to discuss that considering I believe you to be an advocate and probably quite knowledgable on the socialist or communist system (apologies if my assumptions are incorrect)

It's not just that capitalism enables greed or that greed is an individual vice. Any competition, with something significant on the line, **incentivizes** greed and cheating. And a truly impartial judge must not be involved in the competition. However capitalism is a competition with basically **everything** on the line and no one is detached from that competition. So the idea that this could work in the first place is insane to begin with. 

You can try to set up impartial institutions like democracies which set rules and mitigate the self-destructive nature of capitalism, but at the end of the day everyone participating in democracy is also participating in capitalism and as such has an incentive (or is told to have an incentive) in undermining the safeguard and produce a "small government" in which cheating and greed reign supreme. 

And again that doesn't have to come from a place of being evil. If you want to escape the downwards spiral that is wage labor, you might be required to take a loan. Which requires you to grow and make a profit, so thinking greedy and taking more than what is necessary doesn't have to be greed it's what is required from you within the system. The idea of a "moral capitalist" requires a level of doublethink that matches a split personality (I think Brecht wrote a play on that "The Good Person of Szechwan"). Because on the one hand your "efficiency", effectively means taking advantage of others, whether that is workers, environment, supply chain or customers and on the other hand you are expected to care for those people that might be worse of because of you. So greed and growth aren't vices in this system, they are "virtuous" and a necessity to keep the wheel spinning because without them, the whole debt economy that is built on sand would collapse. And with it probably also a good amount of currencies and international trade. It's not bad humans corrupting a good system but rather average humans being corrupted by a bad system.

&amp;gt;And I'd prefer to be able to play some offence here considering I've been playing defence for the entirety of this post haha...

I'd like to but I'm not sure if I'm the right person for that. The thing is I'm looking at that mainly from an anarchist perspective and as such perceive capitalism as a very hierarchical system that is anything but free and equal. And I don't think capitalism will transform on it's own without being pushed and pulled. I think the communist criticism of capitalism is mostly valid and that in order to progress in a way that isn't detrimental to a huge portion of the people one needs to get rid of capitalism and towards something more cooperative and less competitive. On the other hand I'm neither a fan of dictatorships nor hippie communities which effectively might deteriorate into cults, with strong but informal hierarchies. I see a strong point in having mutual collectives of individuals and self-organization as that allows for positive symbioses which benefits the collective and the individual, but I'm not a fan of "for the greater good", because usually that leads to a dictatorship in which a person or small group defines that greater good.

I could point out some frameworks as to how alternatives to capitalism could look like, although going into too much detail is difficult because conceptually it makes no sense for an idea of a free and equal society to have a blueprint how each individual has to behave as that would be neither free nor equal. Probably sounds like a cop-out but it's actually easier to model a dictatorship than a democracy as a democracy needs "democrats" (people who actually want to take the power and responsibility, instead of mindlessly following orders).

And the other thing is that it is kind of difficult to get out of a situation of totalitarian conflict. And that's what capitalism is: It's a cold civil war. "Competition" is seen as a virtue despite being a vice. And if you stop participating and struggle, likely an external or internal force will simply overrun you as has happened multiple times in history. Whether that is an outright invasion, external support for reactionary forces, a splintered left wing that attacks itself rather than progresses (social democrats undermining socialist revolutions, "communists" killing anarchists (also communists), aso) or simply the total exclusion from international community, which throws countries into a position where they need to go for autarky while their competitors have access to the "neo-colonial free market" and as such a much bigger pool or power and resources.

So no matter what you plan, unless we are able to make global restrictions on capitalism, every experiment of any kind will only ever be a niche existence outside of scale or it will be under constant threat of extinction. 

Hope that's enough for now. God I need to stop writing such long walls of text...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32731351494.0" user="bendiboy23" delta="False">
    <text>Okkk alright that's definitely a lot to think about and I will try and get back to you when I can...and yes its probably enough for now haha</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
