<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32704179864.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations

The main problem here is that there are no property rights on things like rivers and the atmosphere. Rivers are owned by the State and that's why they are dirty (politicians's friends are allowed to throw there whatever trash they want) Imagine if you owned a share on it. If someone was polluting it, you'd take him to court! The same applies to the atmosphere. Factories spit carbon dioxide there because it belong to nobody, so why shouldn't they?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Starting new businesses is hard because of licenses, taxes... That's why the existing ones can abuse the workforce: they have no competitors. No one would work for Amazon in lousy conditions if he could just find a different company to work instead! That's why I think free-market Capitalism (rather than the current crony-Capitalism) is necessary to improve the worker's life.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?

It is not a coincidence that the countries with freer markets are often wealthier. Take a look at [this ranking](https://www.heritage.org/index/ranking) that measures economical freedom across different countries. Of course it is not perfect, and some critiques and refinements can be done, but it's OK to get an overall idea. Do you see any poor countries at the top of the list? Even rich countries that we often call "socialist" rank pretty high on economical freedom, so maybe they are not as "socialist" as we think!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
